<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 08:25:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 08:25:22 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I Want to Fix Goodreads]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 322 | Comments 164 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24454221">thread link</a>) | @prepend
<br/>
September 12, 2020 | http://prepend.com/culture/2020/09/fixing_goodreads.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://prepend.com/culture/2020/09/fixing_goodreads.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="post">
  

  <article>
    <p>I use <a href="https://goodreads.com/">goodreads</a> a lot because I like to read books and want to find more books to read. This morning I was reading a <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24451428">thread on hackernews</a> on <a href="https://www.newstatesman.com/science-tech/social-media/2020/08/better-goodreads-possible-bad-for-books-storygraph-amazon">Sarah Manavis’s NewStatesman article</a> and it reminds me of how much I want, I yearn, for useful book recommendations. I think about this pretty much every time I open the goodreads page or app and hope that maybe this is the day they finally fix recommendations, so I figure I would capture some ideas I have for fixing their recommendations.</p>

<h2 id="i-love-goodreads">I Love Goodreads</h2>

<p>First, I love Goodreads. My <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/9499790-brian">profile</a> says I joined May 2012. But I think that’s just whenever I started this profile and I have multiple, old profiles that I can’t find. My memory says I started using them soon after launch, but maybe I’m misremembering. But I’ve used them for a long time because I like to read books. I love browsing bookstores and libraries looking for new books. I experience joy finding a 50 or 100 year old book that I didn’t know about. One of my favorite things is reading a book so good that I can’t go to bed, or want to walk an extra mile. But that’s pretty rare for me, I’m lucky if I get one of those a year.</p>

<p>I have goodreads on my <a href="http://prepend.com/stack.xml">link stack</a> with the tag <a href="https://www.prepend.com/future/technology/2020/01/purdah.html">“purdah”</a> that I think means it is part of the stuff I do that uniquely identifies me.</p>

<p>Any time I get a recommendation from a friend or article or wherever, I add it to my “to read” shelf on goodreads. That helps me when I’m trying to buy a new book. So at least I can read through the 245 books that at least a past me wanted to read. This works well and is better than a vanilla list.</p>

<p>I also like seeing what my friends read and especially what they like or dislike. My friends have different tastes so it’s not as simple as just reading everything they read, but it helps a little. It’s one of the few places that I think facebook helps because at least I get to find out facebook friends who also are on goodreads. Every once in a while I find a new book through this feed, maybe once every 2 years. This might be because I don’t have many friends on goodreads (only 42), but I think it’s also because different people have different tastes in books.</p>

<p>I also like that goodreads will tell me when an author I’ve read releases a new book, or is having a book chat or something. Although I wish they would tell me when they come to a local book signing.</p>

<h2 id="the-problem-as-i-see-it">The Problem As I See It</h2>

<p>This gets me to what I think is wrong and want to fix. I have read and rated 802 books with my average rating of 3.97. This makes sense as I’m probably only going to read books I think I’ll like, but I think this is the average goodreads rating, not the average of my ratings. Looking at what I rated, I’ve only given out 3 one stars, 42 two stars and tons of five stars. I keep scrolling on and on.</p>

<p>The user interface for goodreads is pretty bad- information is hard to find, layout is wasted, search doesn’t work well, hard to tell ads from user content- but that’s not what I’m talking about here. The main problem is in finding books that I will like. Maybe a UX overhaul from a great designer would help, but not that much. A craigslist interface would be great if they could just solve this one problem…</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>What is the single book that I will love most in all the world?</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<p>I want to find the next amazing experience. Books are great because they are cheap and portable. It’s not like wine where the best is more than I’ll ever pay. Or travel where a first class flight can cost $20k. If I can find a book, I can read it. And maybe someone I know can read it too.</p>

<p>If I can mix in more wonderful books, my life will be better. My family’s life will be better. Etc etc. Maybe this is the answer to world enlightenment. Probably not, but it will be great, I think.</p>

<p>When I click on <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/recommendations">recommendations</a>, goodreads shows me five books that I don’t want to read. And it’s weirdly bad. Some of it makes since why it’s bad. They recommend different versions of books I’ve read. They recommend two different versions of <em>Lord of the Rings</em> (one of my favorite books), but I guess they don’t know these are the same book. That’s just a waste of time and it’s weird that amazon isn’t smart enough to avoid duplicative books.</p>

<p><img src="http://prepend.com/assets/images/goodreads_recommendations.png" alt="Screenshot of goodreads recommendations page"></p>

<p>But then they recommend stuff like Stephen King’s <em>The Long Walk</em>. This is perplexing because I only have one book that goodreads knows I’ve read from King and I rated it two stars. I don’t have any of his books in my “to read” list. Why would they recommend this book? Two of my friends rated it four stars and one even wrote a recommendation. So maybe that’s why. I’m aware of this book and don’t want to read it. But other books like <em>Shoe Dog</em> by Phil Knight has no relationship to me. Why would they recommend this? I also know about this book and don’t want to read it. I wish there was some way to note books that I don’t want to read. Then at least they would stop showing me the same book over and over.</p>

<p>So it seems like goodreads is making pretty basic, rules-based recommendations. And they don’t help me pick new books.</p>

<h2 id="my-perfect-wish">My Perfect Wish</h2>

<p>My idea for an 11-star experience <sup id="fnref:brian_chesky" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:brian_chesky">1</a></sup> in finding new books is that Goodreads knows me even better than I know myself and constantly recommends the perfect book. They recommend books that teach me, that spark enlightenment, that I hate but teach me to appreciate other books, books for when I want to be happy, and books for when I need to be sad. I want something like Jane from Ender’s Game who experiences everything I know but is fixated on finding me a good book. So the output of a book sommelier whose passion is seeing me sit there and love a book.</p>

<p>That’s what I would like.</p>

<h2 id="a-little-story-about-jeff-bezos">A Little Story About Jeff Bezos</h2>

<p>Once I was lucky enough to go to TED. It was great on so many levels, I highly recommend it and 2/3 of the cost was tax deductible. It was full of great stuff. I got to wait in the registration line in front of Neil Gaiman and Amanda Palmer, that was neat.</p>

<p>Anyway, one night Neil Gaiman was doing in a midnight ghost story reading in some neat four story townhouse type building <sup id="fnref:vancouver_club" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:vancouver_club">2</a></sup> that was totally empty and spooky and a great place for the event. The reading was on the top floor and there was a huge crowd waiting for the single elevator in this place. The lights were off and there weren’t any staff around so it was maybe 100 people waiting to go up three at a time. So I looked around the corner and took the stairs. About 2 or 3 other people had the same idea so we started racing up the stairs to get to the top and avoid the crowds.</p>

<p><img src="http://prepend.com/assets/images/vancouver_club.jpg" alt="Vancouver Club street view">
<em>photo by <a href="https://fineartamerica.com/profiles/2-joe-fox">Joe Fox</a></em></p>

<p>This building was awesome. It seemed 100 years old, rare in Vancouver, and as we went up the stairs we saw each floor. The stairwell opened up to a big room that could probably seat a 50 person wedding dinner. The lights were off, and someone had opened a few windows and the white, wispy curtains were blowing with a little breeze. Even though it didn’t feel like a breeze. I said “cool, haunted house” and stopped climbing the stairs to look around. The person next to me said “yeah, cool” and we started quickly running around checking out the empty room. We did this on the third floor too and me and this random person did quick 60 second explorations of this spooky house.</p>

<p>It all happened quickly. Maybe 3 minutes to go up the stairs, run around each floor, and get to the top. About halfway through I realized this random dude was Jeff Bezos. I thought that was neat. I’ve bought books from Amazon since 1995 and I’m pretty sure I telnetted into it to order some books (although maybe that was cdnow before they bought them), so it was cool to think that Jeff Bezos likes haunted houses and still likes exploring empty buildings.</p>

<p>We got to the top and went into the venue and were maybe the first 10 people. Comically got there maybe after two or three elevators full of people. We went to the front where Gaiman was setting up at the podium. I got a comfy chair right in the front about five feet in front of Gaiman. Jeff Bezos sat in the chair to my left. The chair on my right had Neil’s wife, Amanda Palmer, who was carrying a ukelele case. I didn’t know it was a ukulele case until she told me. She also said she might play, but she didn’t.</p>

<p>Gaiman finished setting up and came up to talk to Bezos. Bezos asked if Gaiman got the books he sent. Gaiman said he did and they were really great and he enjoyed reading them. It seemed like this was the most recent in a series of book shipments.</p>

<p>Aside from nerd joy from getting to witness this small talk of people who interest me, I thought, at the time and many times since,</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>How cool is it that Neil-freaking Gaiman is still finding new books that are great, and how cool would it be to get book recommendations from Jeff Bezos. I bet he has access to the best book recommendations in the world.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Also, TED has something called the “TED book club” where they mail you this box of books a month before the conference. This was the closest I’ve come to my dream. They maybe sent 10 and 5 are still on my bookshelf. But not the shelf behind me, so I don’t remember them specifically. I’ll look them up one day.</p>

<p>That’s probably better than Jane making recommendations. Amazon had just bought goodreads a year earlier and I was hopeful that any day, goodreads would roll out a wonderful recommendation engine any day now.</p>

<h2 id="what-i-want-to-do-to-fix">What I Want to Do to Fix</h2>

<p>What I would like to do is to just get a data dump of mine and everyone on goodreads recommendations. I don’t need to know the identities, just to know what recommendations go with what individual. It would be neat to protect privacy and find individuals to potentially follow them on goodreads, but I think for the analysis I want to do, I don’t need to know the actual identities.</p>

<p>I think if I have this data, I could try to find people who rate a few hundred books like I have, then look at what books they’ve read the most, or books that they’ve rated highest. I think that would be a good signal that I might like it.</p>

<p>It would also be cool to see …</p></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://prepend.com/culture/2020/09/fixing_goodreads.html">http://prepend.com/culture/2020/09/fixing_goodreads.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://prepend.com/culture/2020/09/fixing_goodreads.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24454221</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 18:06:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[From Rust to TypeScript]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 206 | Comments 137 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24453007">thread link</a>) | @valand
<br/>
September 12, 2020 | https://valand.dev/blog/post/from-rust-to-typescript | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://valand.dev/blog/post/from-rust-to-typescript">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Edits:</em></p>
<ul>
<li><em>HN discussion here: <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24453007#24454277">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24453007#24454277</a>. Thank you HN folks for the corrections, kind responses, and insightful discussion.</em></li>
<li>*fixes in Getting Rid of Exceptions snippet 1.</li>
</ul>
<p>I was introduced to Rust in 2018 and has been enamored since. Rust is a system programming language, much like C++. Unlike C++ though, being relatively new, its language design is more modern and sophisticated. Writing with can feel more like writing TypeScript or Haskell. Not surprising since, despite being a language with a very minimum runtime and no GC, it derives many principles of functional programming such as immutability, type inference, higher-order functions, pattern-matching, etc. Over the course of tinkering things with Rust, I realized that writing Rust code makes me a better coder in other languages. This article will describe how my attempt to push the best in Rust's language design into TypeScript, my main language, without altering the language itself.</p>
<h2>Getting Rid of Exceptions</h2>
<p>The first thing that strikes me the first time I learnt Rust is that there are no straightforward to write exception-like code in Rust. For someone used to exceptions after using many languages like C++, Java, JavaScript and TypeScript, this seems like an incomplete language. But Rust's lack of straightforward exception-like is actually thought out in advance.</p>
<p>Exceptions feel neat the first time you understand it. A thrown exception skips code execution into the <code>catch</code> block. By doing that you can ignore the rest of code in the function. The rest of the code in the function represents positive case, which may seem irrelevant when an error happens. Here's a piece of code:</p>

    <div data-language="text/typescript">
      <pre><code><span>function</span><span> </span><span>foo</span><span>(</span><span>someNumber</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>number</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>{
</span><span>  </span><span>if</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>someNumber</span><span> </span><span>===</span><span> </span><span>0</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>{
</span><span>    </span><span>throw</span><span> </span><span>new</span><span> </span><span>Error</span><span>(</span><span>"Error: foo"</span><span>);
</span><span>  </span><span>}
</span><span>  </span><span>return</span><span> </span><span>someNumber</span><span> </span><span>+</span><span> </span><span>1</span><span>;
}
</span><span>function</span><span> </span><span>bar</span><span>(</span><span>someNumber</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>number</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>{
</span><span>  </span><span>return</span><span> </span><span>foo</span><span>(</span><span>someNumber</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>+</span><span> </span><span>1</span><span>;
}
</span><span>function</span><span> </span><span>baz</span><span>(</span><span>someNumber</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>number</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>{
</span><span>  </span><span>return</span><span> </span><span>bar</span><span>(</span><span>someNumber</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>+</span><span> </span><span>1</span><span>;
}
</span><span>baz</span><span>(</span><span>0</span><span>);</span></code></pre>
    </div>
<p>When <code>baz</code> is called it will throw an uncaught exception. By reading the code you know that <code>foo</code> throws an Error. Debugging this snippet is a piece of cake, right?</p>
<p>Now let's see another snippet. In the snippet below you are importing a function that can throw exception.</p>

    <div data-language="text/typescript">
      <pre><code><span>import</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span> </span><span>callMe</span><span> </span><span>}</span><span> </span><span>from</span><span> </span><span>"somePackage"</span><span>;

</span><span>try</span><span> </span><span>{
</span><span>  </span><span>
</span><span>  </span><span>callMe</span><span>();
}</span><span> </span><span>catch</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>exception</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>{
</span><span>  </span><span>
</span><span>  </span><span>
</span><span>  </span><span>
</span><span>  </span><span>console</span><span>.</span><span>error</span><span>(</span><span>exception</span><span>.</span><span>message</span><span>);
}</span></code></pre>
    </div>
<p>Compared to the first snippet, this one is harder to debug. It seems so because 1.) You don't know that <code>callMe</code> will throw an error or not. 2.) If it throws an exception you will not know what is the type of the exception. The more modular your code is, the harder it is to debug exceptions.</p>
<p>Why is that? If you noticed, in the first snippet, you know which function is throwing what because the <code>throw</code> and the caller are in one file. You don't need to switch files or even scroll that far to see what's wrong. Furthermore, unlike in other language like java, TypeScript exceptions are not typed. Because of that, unlike return values, the compiler could not deduce if a function will throw an exception or not, and that's bad. Combined with the fact that an exception propagates up until they are caught. That means exception can be n-level deep. The deeper it is from, the harder it is to debug it.</p>
<p>If you're familiar with statically-typed language, deferring what's supposed to be done in compile-time to run-time is bad. It hands over problems from the compiler to the user.</p>
<p>There are best practices for writing <code>try/throw/catch</code>, such as developers should throw <code>Error</code> objects instead of nullish values. But pushing everyone to apply best practice is not enough. You cannot assert control toward what is being written in external dependencies. There are not many points introducing law when enforcers are nowhere to be found.</p>
<p>Only when you have dealt with complex codebase you will understand why <a href="https://wiki.c2.com/?DontUseExceptionsForFlowControl">we should not use exception for flow control</a>.</p>
<p>So how Rust does this? Rust encourages us to return errors instead of throwing it by providing a data type called <code>Result</code>. It is a tagged union which can either be <code>Ok(IdealData)</code> or <code>Err(NonIdealData)</code>. With this, a function can communicate the situation of a a call to its caller. For example:</p>

    <div data-language="rust">
      <pre><code><span>fn</span><span> </span><span>main</span><span> () {</span><span>
</span><span>    </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>number</span><span>: </span><span>Result</span><span>&lt;</span><span>u8</span><span>, </span><span>_</span><span>&gt;</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>"1"</span><span>.</span><span>parse</span><span>();</span><span>
</span><span>    </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>non_number</span><span>: </span><span>Result</span><span>&lt;</span><span>u8</span><span>, </span><span>_</span><span>&gt;</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>"a"</span><span>.</span><span>parse</span><span>();</span><span>
</span><span>    </span><span>println!</span><span>(</span><span>"{:?}"</span><span>, &amp;</span><span>number</span><span>);      </span><span>
</span><span>    </span><span>println!</span><span>(</span><span>"{:?}"</span><span>, &amp;</span><span>non_number</span><span>);  </span><span>
</span><span>}</span></code></pre>
    </div>
<p>The function <code>.parse()</code> converts a <code>string</code> into <code>u8</code>. There are scenarios where parsing a <code>string</code> into a <code>u8</code> can result in failure, one is if the parsed string is not a numeric string. Because <code>.parse()</code> has a negative case, it returns <code>Result&lt;u8, _&gt;</code>.</p>
<p>In Rust, <code>Err</code> does not jump like exceptions. Regardless the result is <code>Ok</code> or <code>Err</code>, the program will simply execute the next line. To handle the error the programmer has to check the return value is <code>Ok</code> or <code>Err</code>. Early return is encouraged instead of throw. Rust has the <code>?</code> syntax which help making early returns more concise to write and read.</p>
<p>To adopt this feature to TypeScript, these are the important things:</p>
<ol>
<li>Errors are returned instead of thrown</li>
<li>Errors types are known</li>
</ol>
<p>To simulate this behavior I am going to use tagged union too. I found this helpful library, <a href="https://github.com/gcanti/io-ts">fp-ts</a>. It covers a great deal of functional programming experience by leveraging TypeScript's type system, but I will only use a small portion of it.</p>
<p><code>fp-ts</code> has <code>Either&lt;Left, Right&gt;</code> data type. It is like Rust's <code>Result</code> but more flexible. <code>Either</code> is a tagged union value container. <code>Either</code> is <code>Left</code> or <code>Right</code>, usually <code>Right</code> represents the ideal case and <code>Left</code> represents the non-ideal case but both can be used with any types. Below is the type definition of <code>Either</code>.</p>

    <div data-language="text/typescript">
      <pre><code><span>type</span><span> </span><span>Either</span><span>&lt;</span><span>L</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>R</span><span>&gt;</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>Left</span><span>&lt;</span><span>L</span><span>&gt;</span><span> </span><span>|</span><span> </span><span>Right</span><span>&lt;</span><span>R</span><span>&gt;</span><span>;
</span><span>type</span><span> </span><span>Left</span><span>&lt;</span><span>L</span><span>&gt;</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span> </span><span>_tag</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"left"</span><span>;</span><span> </span><span>left</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>L</span><span> </span><span>};
</span><span>type</span><span> </span><span>Right</span><span>&lt;</span><span>R</span><span>&gt;</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span> </span><span>_tag</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"right"</span><span>;</span><span> </span><span>right</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>R</span><span> </span><span>};</span></code></pre>
    </div>
<p>What's cool about <code>Either</code> is that TypeScript actually supports deducing tagged union from its tag. For example inside this block <code>if (someEither._tag === "left") { }</code> TypeScript knows that <code>someEither</code> is a <code>Left</code>. If there's a <code>return</code> in that block, TypeScript will deduce that for the rest of the function block, <code>someEither</code> data type is <code>Right</code> and not <code>Either</code> anymore.</p>
<p>Let's make a called <code>tryCatch</code>. It is used to wrap a function into Either. <code>fp-ts</code> actually provides this function, but let's write it so that we know what's under the hood.</p>

    <div data-language="text/typescript">
      <pre><code><span>const</span><span> </span><span>tryCatch</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>&lt;</span><span>T</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>E</span><span>&gt;</span><span>(</span><span>fn</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>()</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span> </span><span>T</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>onError</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>error</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>unknown</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span> </span><span>E</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span> </span><span>{
</span><span>  </span><span>try</span><span> </span><span>{
</span><span>    </span><span>
</span><span>    </span><span>return</span><span> </span><span>right</span><span>(</span><span>fn</span><span>());
</span><span>  </span><span>}</span><span> </span><span>catch</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>error</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>{
</span><span>    </span><span>
</span><span>    </span><span>return</span><span> </span><span>left</span><span>(</span><span>onError</span><span>(</span><span>error</span><span>));
</span><span>  </span><span>}
};</span></code></pre>
    </div>
<p>With our newly created <code>tryCatch</code>, creating a URL from string for example can be done like this.</p>

    <div data-language="text/typescript">
      <pre><code><span>export</span><span> </span><span>class</span><span> </span><span>InvalidURLError</span><span> </span><span>extends</span><span> </span><span>Error</span><span> </span><span>{}
</span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>makeURLFromString</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>str</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>string</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span>
</span><span>  </span><span>tryCatch</span><span>(
</span><span>    </span><span>()</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span> </span><span>new</span><span> </span><span>URL</span><span>(</span><span>str</span><span>),
</span><span>    </span><span>()</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span> </span><span>new</span><span> </span><span>InvalidURLError</span><span>()
</span><span>  </span><span>);</span></code></pre>
    </div>
<p>Calling the function will look like this. The following snippet receives a string called <code>maybeUrl</code>. If <code>maybeUrl</code> is not a valid URL it returns an error. If the URL is not calling "example.com" it returns an error. Otherwise, it returns a promise from the <code>fetch</code> call.</p>

    <div data-language="text/typescript">
      <pre><code><span>export</span><span> </span><span>class</span><span> </span><span>NotExampleDotComError</span><span> </span><span>extends</span><span> </span><span>Error</span><span> </span><span>{}
</span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>callThisMaybeUrlIfItIncludesExampleDotCom</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>(
</span><span>  </span><span>maybeUrl</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>string</span><span>
):</span><span> </span><span>Either</span><span>&lt;</span><span>InvalidURLError</span><span> </span><span>|</span><span> </span><span>NotExampleDotComError</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>Promise</span><span>&lt;</span><span>any</span><span>&gt;&gt;</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span> </span><span>{
</span><span>  </span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>urlResult</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>makeURLFromString</span><span>(</span><span>maybeUrl</span><span>);
</span><span>  </span><span>
</span><span>  </span><span>if</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>isLeft</span><span>(</span><span>urlResult</span><span>))</span><span> </span><span>return</span><span> </span><span>urlResult</span><span>.</span><span>left</span><span>;

</span><span>  </span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>url</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>urlResult</span><span>.</span><span>right</span><span>;
</span><span>  </span><span>if</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>url</span><span>.</span><span>origin</span><span> </span><span>!==</span><span> </span><span>"example.com"</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>return</span><span> </span><span>left</span><span>(</span><span>new</span><span> </span><span>NotExampleDotComError</span><span>());

</span><span>  </span><span>return</span><span> </span><span>right</span><span>(</span><span>fetch</span><span>(</span><span>urlResult</span><span>));
};</span></code></pre>
    </div>
<p>There's a bit more line of codes here, but it is great that the TypeScript compiler now can deduce the error type and you have more control over the flow. You can even deduce if the variable <code>error</code> is <code>instanceof</code> <code>NotExampleDotComError</code> or <code>InvalidURLError</code> for cases like printing different errors.</p>
<h2>Safe TypeScript</h2>
<p>If you have played an early 2000s FPS games and tried to cheat, usually you will find the <code>noclip</code> command. It makes your avatar fly through walls and grounds. Sometimes, though, you take a shortcut and triggers the wrong script. When that happens, you can't finish your level and must restart to make it work again.</p>
<p>That's how I see Rust's <code>unsafe</code> and TypeScript's <code>any</code>.</p>
<p>These two features solve a similar problem. In Rust's case, it enables developers to temporarily unlock the power of handling raw pointer in case someone needs it. In TypeScript's case, someone might need to escape into the free-typed JavaScript world. And in both, it is the programmer's responsibility to make sure everything is fine before the program goes back to the safe system.</p>
<p>Unsafe to safe Rust is like <code>any</code> type to typed TypeScript. Unlike Rust, TypeScript's type only works until you compile it to JavaScript code. Rust has <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/beta/rust-by-example/conversion/try_from_try_into.html">TryInto/TryFrom</a> trait to convert raw data into a data type. But in TypeScript's case, if you inject a value that does not match TypeScript's type annotation, TypeScript can't do anything. This comes from TypeScript team's decision to make it only a thin layer on top of JavaScript. They thought it is best if for people to write TypeScript like JavaScript and the compilation result to look almost the same as the source code.</p>
<p>My approach for this would be securing all external hole of my application, which are:</p>
<ul>
<li>WebAPIs, which consist of DOM, deserializable user inputs, fetch API, etc.</li>
<li>External Dependencies which returns <code>any</code></li>
</ul>
<p>When I was trying this approach, I was lucky to find <a href="https://github.com/gcanti/io-ts">io-ts</a>, created by the same author as <code>fp-ts</code>. This library helps me create a runtime type checker, or "codec" as the library's author calls it. Instead of writing:</p>

    <div data-language="text/typescript">
      <pre><code><span>type</span><span> </span><span>User</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span> </span><span>username</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>string</span><span>;</span><span> </span><span>userId</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>string</span><span> </span><span>};</span></code></pre>
    </div>
<p>I wrote the codec for User:</p>

    <div data-language="text/typescript">
      <pre><code><span>const</span><span> </span><span>UserCodec</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>ioTs</span><span>.</span><span>type</span><span>({</span><span> </span><span>username</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>ioTs</span><span>.</span><span>string</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>userId</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>ioTs</span><span>.</span><span>string</span><span> </span><span>});
</span><span>type</span><span> </span><span>User</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>ioTs</span><span>.</span><span>TypeOf</span><span>&lt;</span><span>typeof</span><span> </span><span>UserCodec</span><span>&gt;</span><span>;</span></code></pre>
    </div>
<p>Again, this is longer, but this is very useful if we want to secure those holes.</p>

    <div data-language="text/typescript">
      <pre><code><span>export</span><span> </span><span>class</span><span> </span><span>InvalidTypeError</span><span> </span><span>extends</span><span> </span><span>Error</span><span> </span><span>{}
</span><span>export</span><span> </span><span>class</span><span> </span><span>Fet…</span></code></pre></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://valand.dev/blog/post/from-rust-to-typescript">https://valand.dev/blog/post/from-rust-to-typescript</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://valand.dev/blog/post/from-rust-to-typescript</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24453007</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 15:03:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Review of Language Learning Tactics]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 69 | Comments 44 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24452418">thread link</a>) | @laybak
<br/>
September 12, 2020 | https://knowledgeartist.org/article/language-learning-tips | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://knowledgeartist.org/article/language-learning-tips">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          <p><span>In my journey learning 9 languages over the years, I tried all sorts of different methods to make my learning more effective. Here are some of the notable approaches, along with why they work (or don't work). It </span> <a href="https://knowledgeartist.org/article/how-long-does-it-take-to-learn-a-language" target="_blank"><span>will be a long learning journey</span></a> <span>, I hope this article will make yours more fun and effective. </span></p> <p><span>Let's jump right in.</span></p>  <p><h3><span>Moving to the Target Country</span></h3></p> <p><span>In my experience learning a language, immersion is powerful. Being in a country where your target language is spoken is ideal. Your learning becomes always on, even if you don't realize it. </span></p> <p><span>I moved to Tokyo and worked at an all-Japanese company a few years ago. At the beginning I knew very little Japanese. But with this sink-or-swim approach and the daily immersion, I became comfortable with basic conversations within three months.</span></p> <p><span>Now, it is not always possible to just pack up and move to a different place. Read on for other tips I tested from my own experience. </span></p>  <p><h3><span>Language Exchange Meetups</span></h3></p> <p><span>You can only get so good at speaking a language without talking to native speakers. Language exchange groups are a great way to get that conversational practice. In a typical event, you would get paired up/grouped with native speakers of your target language, who are themselves looking to level up on your native tongue. </span></p> <p><span>For half of the time, the group would converse in one language, and then switch to the other language half-way. If you live in a major city, there are usually quite a few of these groups for the common languages. </span> <a href="https://www.meetup.com/" target="_blank"><span>Meetup</span></a> <span> is a great place to look for these events. This is an effective way to practice in your home city, or when you are already in your target country. </span></p>  <p><h3><span>Online Language Exchange</span></h3></p> <p><span>If you are unable to attend in-person meetups, online language exchange can be effective as well. Though in-person conversations would always feel more organic, you still get the instant feedback and practice with online language exchange calls. </span></p> <p><span>I have made a few friends along the way, while practicing my German, French, and Japanese. I previously had a pleasant experience using </span> <a href="https://www.italki.com/" target="_blank"><span>iTalki</span></a> <span>, where I could easily find language partners and schedule 1-1 Skype calls with them. It was entirely free. But at the time of writing, it appears they may have removed the free partner option.</span></p>  <p><h3><span>Learning Entire Phrases</span></h3></p> <p><span>I found it effective to memorize entire sentences, and pull them out when I need to. There are several benefits to this. When you are communicating in realtime, having phrases already memorized can reduce your stumbling. It can make you appear fluent and keep the conversation flowing. This also makes you feel more comfortable, knowing what to say or how to respond in a given situation.</span></p> <p><span>These familiar phrases serve as important anchors as well, for learning about the structure of the language, and for easily swapping out components to adapt to new situations. For example, after memorizing the phrase "After a few months of travelling, I am happy to finally be able to work with everyone", you can substitute some of the words and use it in a new scenario.</span></p> <p><span>Phrase books can be somewhat useful for this purpose, though it can sound scripted and unnatural. What feels more natural is writing down and remembering the response of native speaker in a real-life situation or in a movie.</span></p>  <p><h3><span>Movies/Shows in Your Target Language</span></h3></p> <p><span>Movies and TV shows are a great source of natural-sounding phrases (though overly dramatic sometimes) to add to your knowledge bank. This is great for a number of reasons: </span></p> <p><li><span>You can usually figure out what the movie is about (especially if you first watch it in your native language).</span></li></p> <p><li><span>It is enjoyable, which means you will stick with it</span></li></p> <p><li><span>You get to learn about the culture behind your target language</span> <strong> </strong> <span>as well.</span></li></p> <p><span>And if you are watching it on TV, I find that even the commercials in your target language are interesting. Not only is it good practice, you get a better sense of what kinds of products local people buy and the messaging that appeals to them. With the growing selection of international shows/movies on Netflix, along with audio and/or subtitles, this is a fun and easy way to make progress.</span></p>  <p><h3><span>Interviews with Subtitles and Translations</span></h3></p> <p><span>In addition to movies/shows, interviews are the perfect content for getting exposure to natural conversations, where people use casual everyday language. </span> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/magauchsein" target="_blank"><span>Easy Languages</span></a> <span> on YouTube is hands down one of my favourite language resources. They interview people on the streets on a different topic each episode, and provide subtitles in the original language + English. Over the years, they have built up an amazing collection of content in many (!) languages.</span></p> <p><span>Here's a taste of their content for German learners: </span></p> <div><p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hLoatpfE7VM?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0" frameborder="0"></iframe></p></div>  <p><h3><span>Passive Background Looping</span></h3></p> <p><span>This is one of the most effective hacks I developed to maximize my time spent learning a language. As I work, I would put on a familiar track of native speakers talking (much of the time it would be Easy Languages) in the ground. This way, I can get a lot of listening practice without spending much time. By picking content that you are already familiar with, you already know what is being talked about. And the looping gets you more "reps" for each phrase. It also helps you memorize entire phrases that you can use with ease later.</span></p>  <p><h3><span>Podcasts </span></h3></p> <p><span>This one can be tricky. I have tried quite a few podcasts and many podcast formats aren't that conducive to learning a foreign language. Either I don't understand what's going on, or there is too much repeating over the often dry content. But for Japanese learners, I highly recommend </span> <a href="https://bilingualnews.libsyn.com/" target="_blank"><span>Bilingual News</span></a> <span> hosted by Michael and Mami. It features the hosts talking about interesting topics in the news, with Michael speaking only English and Mami speaking only Japanese. The conversation always moves forward and remains engaging, and you can usually easily fill in the words you missed from the context. </span></p>  <p><h3><span>Ask a Native Speaker "How do I say X?" Wherever Possible</span></h3></p> <p><span>If you have friends (or better yet, roommates) from other countries, you can definitely get some practice in as you hang out. When you are trying to say something, why not learn to say it in your target language too? Anytime is learning time! You'll remember it much better than other methods because the learning takes place in real-life expeirences. I used to worry this may come off as annoying, but in my experience most people are happy to help, and appreciate the ernest effort you make to understand their language/culture. </span></p>  <p><h3><span>Changing Your Phone's Language</span></h3></p> <p><span>One easy way to squeeze out an extra bit of language immersion is to simply change your mobile phone to your target language. Doing so should automatically update the language in all your apps as well. Since you likely already know how to navigate through most apps anyway, in most cases you can guess the meaning of new words that you don't yet know. With this, even Facebook notifications become good practice. </span></p>  <p><h3><span>Taking classes</span></h3></p> <p><span>I have never been a fan of learning a language in a classroom, having taken Russian, French and Mandarin classs. This one is a bit of a hit or miss. The classroom environment has always felt a bit too artificial for this purpose. Typically, there is also limited practice, limited individual attention (and hence </span> <em>feedback</em> <span>). And the separation between the classroom learning context and the real-life situations makes it hard to apply the knowledge.</span></p> <p><span>That said, there are some amazing teachers out there who excel at teaching and building curriculum. And for some people, the structure of learning in a group guided by a competent instructor is just what they need. For Chinese learners, </span> <a href="https://www.excelmandarin.com/" target="_blank"><span>Excel Mandarin</span></a> <span> is an example of educators who have created an effective learning system for their students. Though not from my personal experience, I have heard nothing but positive reviews about these folks. </span></p>  <p><h3><span>Duolingo</span></h3></p> <p><span>There was a time when I would have a long-running practice streak on the popular free app </span> <a href="https://www.duolingo.com/" target="_blank"><span>Duolingo</span></a> <span>. I would use the app daily, and almost completed the curriculum for Brazilian Portuguese, Spanish, and German. I felt great. I felt engaged. I felt like I was making progress. But that's the dangerous part about apps like these that try to "gamify" the language learning process. it makes you feel productive, even if it may not reflect reality. </span></p> <p><span>It is all too easy to slip into auto-pilot mode, where you just rush to the finish line of each exercise. This is similar to how one would "speed read" a book in an hour and retain nothing from it. The app also trains you to get used to the machine-generated bad pronunciation, which is counter-productive for your listening skills. On the bright side, Duolingo can be helpful for exposure to new words, and adding some structure to your learning, especially if you are not following a curriculum or textbook.</span></p>  <p><h3><span>Reading Textbooks</span></h3></p> <p><span>Reading a textbook for the purpose of language learning is perhaps the best way to learn the formal structure of a language. But it is not effective for conversational purposes. Grammar rules are clean, but conversational languages are messy. Similar to the discussion above about taking classes, textbooks tend to give a similar passive understanding of rules, as opposed to the ability to apply that knowledge in real-time. </span></p>  <p><span>The best approach is the one you actually take and follow through with. One that fits your learning objectives and learning style. The more you can align your learning with your intrinsic motivation, the more likely it is that it will stick. </span></p>         


          
            
            <p><em>Each week, I send out a newsletter where I share my learnings, new ways to see things, and new ways to feel.</em></p>
            <p><em>Enter your email below to subscribe.</em></p>

            
          
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://knowledgeartist.org/article/language-learning-tips</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24452418</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 13:54:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why do so many people want us back in the office?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 351 | Comments 486 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24452280">thread link</a>) | @ingve
<br/>
September 12, 2020 | https://paulitaylor.com/2020/09/12/why-do-so-many-people-want-us-back-in-the-office/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://paulitaylor.com/2020/09/12/why-do-so-many-people-want-us-back-in-the-office/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>After the sudden and miraculous shift to remote work in March – the office fightback has well and truly begun.</p>



<p>Four months ago I wrote that – surprisingly- there was no fightback from technophobe hold-outs barricading themselves into their offices. They simply packed up their laptop and went home with the rest of us. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://paulitaylor.com/2020/04/06/did-a-virus-just-bring-about-the-end-of-the-office/" target="_blank">How </a><a href="https://paulitaylor.com/2020/04/06/did-a-virus-just-bring-about-the-end-of-the-office/">premature</a><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://paulitaylor.com/2020/04/06/did-a-virus-just-bring-about-the-end-of-the-office/" target="_blank"> I was</a>. </p>



<figure><div>
<div><blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>2019: millenials are wasting all their money on buying sandwiches </p><p>2020: THE ECONOMY WILL COLLAPSE IF YOU DON'T BUY MORE SANDWICHES</p></div>— Sam Grinsell (@samgrinsell) <a href="https://twitter.com/samgrinsell/status/1299288101743886336?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 28, 2020</a></blockquote></div>
</div></figure>



<p>If you thought that 2020 couldn’t get any crazier – it seems some people really are suggesting that businesses should alter their workplace strategies in order to save…sandwich shops.</p>



<p>OK, I’m exaggerating for effect. But there really has been a hand brake applied to the move to remote/hybrid working , or my favoured term,<em><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://medium.com/work-futures/the-future-is-minimum-office-not-zero-office-821928abdba2" target="_blank"> minimum office</a></em> in recent weeks. </p>



<p>An <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2020/08/27/go-back-work-risk-losing-job-major-drive-launched-get-people/" target="_blank">article in the Daily Telegraph</a>&nbsp;suggested&nbsp;that employees who continue to work at home will be more vulnerable to redundancy, with bosses finding it far easier get rid of people they don’t physically see.</p>



<p><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://twitter.com/KirstieMAllsopp/status/1290987043829489666?s=20" target="_blank">Kirstie Allsopp</a> led the anti-remote work charge on Twitter, suggesting that if your job can be done from home, it can be done from anywhere in the world. Who would have thought that a couple of months of working in shorts and a T-Shirt has made us more susceptible to being replaced by less expensive folk in India, Myanmar and China? </p>



<p>A debate that is framed around saving sandwich shops and an already dying high street isn’t helpful or progressive. Cynically I might suggest the real subtext here is about propping up commercial property investment portfolios. Realistically though, we won’t see anything like a return to the same number of offices, and although few will shed tears for commercial real estate investors many small businesses will suffer a big hit and go out of business unless they can pivot very rapidly.</p>



<p>Clearly there are two groups emerging, those who are desperate for the pandemic to be viewed as a temporary event before everything returns to ‘normal’ and those embracing the true long term disruption that is occurring.</p>



<p>Thank heavens then for more balanced thinkers like Tom Cheesewright who has an uncanny ability to pan back and take the long view. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://tomcheesewright.com/were-still-human/" target="_blank">Writing on his website</a> about the current over-confidence in the possibilities for remote working he says:</p>



<p><em>“There is something different about being there, in person, with all of your senses engaged. It’s what I called a few years ago, ‘<a href="https://tomcheesewright.com/the-unbeatable-bandwidth-of-being-there/">the unbeatable bandwidth of being there</a>‘. What gets transmitted and received through the screen and headset, mediated by a million miles of fibre optic cable, is not the full experience of meeting. Nor does it allow for all the things that happen around those meetings. <a href="https://tomcheesewright.com/aftershocks-and-opportunities/">I’ve talked at length about the need for peer support, the subtler parts of staff training, and the mutual inspiration that happens when you’re sharing a physical space</a>.”</em></p>



<p>I’m a remote working, or at least a minimum office, enthusiast. I’ve written on this site for years about the worst aspects of office life and <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://paulitaylor.com/2014/07/31/why-the-death-of-the-office-cant-come-too-soon/" target="_blank">the most popular post on here applauds its impending doom</a>.  Six years on though I’d admit it’s a deeply flawed argument. The idea that constant interruptions and back to back meetings were a symptom of being in a corporate building has been well and truly busted by…Microsoft Teams. </p>



<p>In truth the problem with work is not the tools or the physical location, but <a href="https://paulitaylor.com/2020/01/03/ending-our-obsession-with-leadership/">the obsession with leadership</a> , an undue focus on work about work, an overbearing hierarchy and the lack of true digitisation of the enterprise. Deeper, more complex problems.  </p>



<p>It’s ironic that it has taken a pandemic to reveal what was good about the office. “The things that happen between meetings” that Tom writes about reveal our innate desire for human contact – the need to get <em>our senses fully engaged</em>. Wasteful? Quite often. But we dismiss this at our peril. It may seem logical that workplace chatter stifles productivity, but studies show the opposite to be true. </p>



<p>A narrow focus on efficiency in the workplace and a flawed view of what makes people productive is similarly regressive and likely to drag people back to the old normal. As Stowe Boyd writes the backlash against minimum office is in full flow , as detailed in <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/companies-start-to-think-remote-work-isnt-so-great-after-all-11595603397?mod=trending_now_pos1">Companies Start to Think Remote Work Isn’t So Great After All</a>, as executives want to get people back in the office:</p>



<p>“<em>An increasing number of executives now say that remote work, while necessary for safety much of this year, is not their preferred long-term solution once the coronavirus crisis passes.</em></p>



<p><em>“There’s sort of an emerging sense behind the scenes of executives saying, ‘This is not going to be sustainable,’” said Laszlo Bock, chief executive of human-resources startup Humu and the former HR chief at Google. No CEO should be surprised that the early productivity gains companies witnessed as remote work took hold have peaked and leveled off, he adds, because workers left offices in March armed with laptops and a sense of doom</em>.”</p>



<p>Perhaps it’s simply we haven’t yet matched our colleagues roles, and their specific work preferences, within our existing organisational design never mind considered a future state. Working from home (managed and supported appropriately) <strong>can</strong> be more productive than going into the office.</p>



<p><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://email.mg2.substack.com/c/eJwlUMuOwyAM_JpySwQkNHDgsJf9jYiA27BNIDKmVf5-aStZHsv2-DHeEdwznvbIhVgtgHMMdtRSX1nDILTSLJb5hgC7i5slrMCOumzRO4o5vdu1Mdqw1YZJTmJYQC9SaR8kv3IlBmcmM_qgRsXeS2ZXQ4TkwcIT8MwJ2GZXoqNchp-L_G22LthnvLdIcskbcN0cQgGHfu0eKb82CHfoXhkfgKVzCN2emzswh-opPqG7Yd67Ne_Aon2P4YYPQiiteC_6M_0JzqezJnMZ-X6XfalLIecfvc87Q3u4up0kWnGhmAgwAX1K7fW54V5TpHOG5JZ2ylcV-or4eZLOA2yCV9mAGvubbFIZOWmuWNsWctMzfShljTf6B3tch00" target="_blank">A HBR study published in August</a>&nbsp;contrasted surveys of knowledge workers from 2013 and 2020, found that remote working was in fact helping address long-held frustrations about the rhythm of office work. </p>



<ol><li>Lockdown helps us focus on the work that really matters. We are spending 12% less time drawn into large meetings and 9% more time interacting with customers and external partners.</li><li>Lockdown helps us take responsibility for our own schedules. We do 50% more activities through personal choice — because we see them as important — and half as many because someone else asked us to.</li><li>During lockdown, we view our work as more worthwhile.&nbsp; We rate the things we do as valuable to our employer&nbsp;<em>and</em>&nbsp;to ourselves. The number of tasks rated as tiresome drops from 27% to 12%, and the number we could readily offload to others drops from 41% to 27%.</li></ol>



<p>The key phrase here is: <em>managed and supported appropriately</em>. Certainly managers need to reinvent themselves as mentors to this style of working and then – forgive me – get the hell out of the way. </p>



<p>The office as the default way of working is dead. But the office itself isn’t dead. With working from home, what we gain in work-life balance we might lose in innovation and creativity. There are people who could directly challenge that sentence but I suspect they will come from highly mature companies who have fully mastered the remote working learning curve. Many of us are still at the stage of doing what we did in the office , just remotely. The timorous amongst us may use the lack of productivity net gains as a reason to regress rather than push through the ‘pain barrier’ <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://paulitaylor.com/2020/07/11/nirvana-or-business-as-usual-navigating-the-new-future-of-work/" target="_blank">as Matt Mullenweg describes it.</a> </p>



<p>We can do so much better, for ourselves, our customers and society if we stop being so frightened or so certain of the future. </p>



<p>We are going to have fewer offices and spend more time at home. </p>



<p>Our efforts would be a lot better spent improving the experience and outcomes of both rather than arguing about preserving a status quo whose time has truly run out. </p>



<p><em>The office versus remote work?</em> It’s not a binary choice we need to make. </p>



<p>The best thing you can do in any period of change is to bet on neither black or white. The future will be made up instead of shades of grey where few things are certain and <em>the best you can do to prepare is to be endlessly adaptable</em>. </p>



<hr>



<p><em>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@bchild311?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Benjamin Child</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Unsplash</a></em></p>
			
			
				</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://paulitaylor.com/2020/09/12/why-do-so-many-people-want-us-back-in-the-office/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24452280</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 13:32:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
