<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 10]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 10. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 08:32:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-10.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 08:32:12 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Embracing Functional Programming in Ruby (2017)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 18 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26201237">thread link</a>) | @mooreds
<br/>
February 19, 2021 | https://kellysutton.com/2017/09/13/embracing-functional-programming-in-ruby.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://kellysutton.com/2017/09/13/embracing-functional-programming-in-ruby.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <div>
        <div>

  

  <article>
    <p>At <a href="https://gusto.com/">Gusto</a>, we’ve been knee-deep in a substantial refactor of our system for running payrolls.</p>

<p>Running a payroll requires taking several different inputs such as how much an employee should get paid, where did they work, how much did they work, how much taxes should they pay, how much taxes have they paid this year, and so on and so on.</p>

<p>As a company that offers a payroll service, keeping this piece of the system in tip-top shape is important for the business. Customers love Gusto for its simplicity and speed when it comes to running payroll.</p>

<p>Over the years, this system grew beyond its original mandate. Rather than just serve payroll for one state, it now serves them for all 50 states and the District of Columbia. Although customers love our payroll, internally new engineers had a difficult time understanding the code and making changes safely. This system needed a tune up, so we embarked on a sizable refactor.</p>

<p>Because the process of calculating what you need for a payroll is one big formula, we set the goal of making this system “more functional” as in functional programming. We wanted to take the process of calculating a payroll and make it one big stateless operation.</p>

<p>The server-side code at Gusto is written in Ruby, a language usually known for its object-oriented and metaprogrammatic roots. Nonetheless, we wanted to integrate some more functional concepts into our code in the hopes of increasing the system’s safety and clarity. The result has been maintainable code that is easier to reason about and safer to change.</p>

<h2 id="embracing-the-pfaao">Embracing the PFaaO</h2>

<p>Ruby is an expressive language, but it does not lend itself to some common functional practices. Although Ruby allows for closures and first-class functions via <code>Proc</code>s, one does not see many <code>Proc</code>s passed around as objects in idiomatic Ruby.</p>

<p>Throughout our work, we discovered that you can create expressive interfaces with clean internals by embracing both OO and functional aspects of Ruby.</p>

<p>To do this, we used a pattern called <a href="https://www.tomdalling.com/blog/ruby/pure-function-as-an-object-PFAAO-pattern/">Pure Function as an Object (PFaaO)</a>. Essentially, you design objects as you would a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pure_function">pure function</a> but dress them up as Ruby classes.</p>

<p>A pure function is a function without observable side effects that always returns the same value for a given set of inputs. That means no talking to the database, no modifying the state of other objects, no accessing the system clock, etc. When we write a PFaaO in Ruby, we want to build an object that has no side effects.</p>

<p>A simple PFaaO might look like the following:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>class</span> <span>PayrollCalculator</span>
  <span>def</span> <span>self</span><span>.</span><span>calculate</span><span>(</span><span>payroll</span><span>)</span>
    <span>new</span><span>(</span><span>payroll</span><span>).</span><span>calculate</span>
  <span>end</span>

  <span>def</span> <span>initialize</span><span>(</span><span>payroll</span><span>)</span>
    <span>@payroll</span> <span>=</span> <span>payroll</span>
  <span>end</span>
  <span>private_class_method</span> <span>:new</span>

  <span>def</span> <span>calculate</span>
    <span>PayrollResult</span><span>.</span><span>new</span><span>(</span>
      <span>payroll: </span><span>payroll</span><span>,</span>
      <span>paystubs: </span><span>paystubs</span><span>,</span>
      <span>taxes: </span><span>taxes</span><span>,</span>
      <span>debits: </span><span>debits</span>
    <span>)</span>
  <span>end</span>

  <span>def</span> <span>paystubs</span>
    <span># ...</span>
  <span>end</span>

  <span>def</span> <span>taxes</span>
    <span># ...</span>
  <span>end</span>

  <span>def</span> <span>debits</span>
    <span># ...</span>
  <span>end</span>
<span>end</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>There’s quite a bit going on here, so let’s break it down bit by bit.</p>

<p>First, our class has only one effective public interface: <code>PayrollCalculator.calculate</code>. Because we’ve declared the constructor private using <code>private_class_method :new</code>, the instance method <code>#calculate</code> is effectively private.<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup></p>

<p>This means that all of the other instance methods we declare are implicitly private, even though there is no explicit <code>private</code> block within this class. Because there’s no way to <code>.new</code> up an instance, there is not a vector to call any instance methods.</p>

<p>Our method only has one public interface and its designed operation is effectively stateless, therefore we only need to exercise one interface in our tests. Put some data in, assert that the data coming out is what we expected.</p>

<h2 id="referential-transparency-for-free">Referential Transparency for Free</h2>

<p>In our above example, let’s say that the process of calculating taxes is expensive from a time perspective.<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2">2</a></sup> Thus, we want to make a time/space tradeoff to consume more memory to minimize the number of times we need to compute taxes. In our example, calculating both <code>#paystubs</code> and <code>#debits</code> will require the result of <code>#taxes</code>.</p>

<p>Now because each of these private methods is a pure function, we have referential transparency. This means we can replace a method and its parameters with its return value. Think of it like algebra: Given the function <code>f(x) = x + 5</code>, you can safely replace any occurrence of <code>f(2)</code> with the value <code>7</code>.</p>

<p>What does this mean for a Rubyist? Free and safe memoization:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>def</span> <span>paystubs</span>
  <span>calculate_paystubs</span><span>(</span><span>taxes</span><span>,</span> <span>...</span><span>)</span>
<span>end</span>

<span>def</span> <span>debits</span>
  <span>calculate_debits</span><span>(</span><span>taxes</span><span>,</span> <span>...</span><span>)</span>
<span>end</span>

<span>def</span> <span>taxes</span>
  <span>@taxes</span> <span>||=</span> <span>calculate_taxes</span><span>(</span><span>@payroll</span><span>)</span>
<span>end</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Memoization is a form of caching, and can be fraught with issues if the memoized value does not actually come from a pure function. But because we make everything within the PFaaO pure, we can safely memoize this method call.</p>

<p>This is interesting because it looks like this class is no longer stateless: it now assigns local values. However the only interface is the single <code>.calculate</code> class method, each instance of our PFaaO is single-use. Any intermediate state can never be accessed by externally. Because this cached state is not observable externally, our function is still technically pure.</p>

<p>Much in the way a developer can abstract synchronous and asynchronous behavior, you can do the same with functional purity. Any local state changes are irrelevant in the lifecycle of the PFaaO. These local state changes are not observable from the outside world.</p>

<h2 id="expanding-pfaaos">Expanding PFaaOs</h2>

<p>As I’ve grown in my career, I have become less interested in how software is written but how it is maintained. Software maintenance is the blessing and the curse of any successful project: <em>Congratulations!</em> You have a business with lasting value. <em>Our condolences!</em> You must now pay for all of your mistakes. Nonetheless, it is always preferred to have a business that exists with technical debt, than to have a bankrupt company with a pristine code base.</p>

<p>PFaaOs in Ruby are great because they are easy to maintain. Not only are they easy to test, but they are predisposed to healthy growth.</p>

<p>What do I mean by that?</p>

<p>Let’s again take the example of our <code>#taxes</code> method. Early in Gusto’s history (back when it was still known as ZenPayroll), we only offered payroll services in California. Thus, we only needed to worry about payroll taxes for California.</p>

<p>In the grand scheme of things, California is a simple state when it comes to payroll taxes. Our taxes method might have looked like nothing more than the following:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>def</span> <span>taxes</span>
  <span>federal_taxes</span><span>(</span><span>@payroll</span><span>)</span> <span>+</span>
    <span>california_taxes</span><span>(</span><span>@payroll</span><span>)</span> <span>+</span>
    <span>local_taxes</span><span>(</span><span>@payroll</span><span>)</span>
<span>end</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Now let’s say we expanded into a new state, New York. Now our method grows a little bit:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>def</span> <span>taxes</span>
  <span>federal_taxes</span><span>(</span><span>@payroll</span><span>)</span> <span>+</span>
    <span>california_taxes</span><span>(</span><span>@payroll</span><span>)</span> <span>+</span>
    <span>new_york_taxes</span><span>(</span><span>@payroll</span><span>)</span> <span>+</span>
    <span>local_california_taxes</span><span>(</span><span>@payroll</span><span>)</span> <span>+</span>
    <span>local_new_york_taxes</span><span>(</span><span>@payroll</span><span>)</span>
<span>end</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>As we expand into every state,<sup id="fnref:3" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:3">3</a></sup> this method will grow to be quite large! Furthermore, each of these methods adds to the length of our <code>PayrollCalculator</code> class. Without constant gardening, the class could become difficult to understand.</p>

<p>But because each of our methods within a PFaaO is itself a pure function, we are able to extract classes as we see fit and make each one a new PFaaO. We can safely replace our growing methods with new PFaaOs:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>def</span> <span>taxes</span>
  <span>PayrollCalculator</span><span>::</span><span>Taxes</span><span>.</span><span>calculate</span><span>(</span><span>@payroll</span><span>)</span>
<span>end</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>As we tease apart these different PFaaOs, we also get a much better idea of the input requirements for these service classes. Our <code>@payroll</code> is a large parameter object, and each extracted PFaaO probably only needs a subset of its data.</p>

<p>So we can get away with something like:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>def</span> <span>taxes</span>
  <span>PayrollCalculator</span><span>::</span><span>Taxes</span><span>.</span><span>calculate</span><span>(</span>
    <span>@payroll</span><span>.</span><span>only_pay_and_location_data</span>
  <span>)</span>
<span>end</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Here we assume that the <code>Payroll#only_pay_and_location_data</code> returns a slice of the total data within the instance as a new <a href="https://martinfowler.com/bliki/ValueObject.html">Value Object</a>. This Value Object represents only the data required to calculate the taxes part of running a payroll.</p>

<h2 id="data-is-immutable-by-default">Data is Immutable by Default</h2>

<p>Another important ingredient for scalable PFaaOs is the requirement that all data be immutable by default. <em>This is a drastic change from how most folks traditionally write Ruby.</em></p>

<p>Every time you reach for your <code>=</code>, you’ll need to replace it with a <code>#set</code> or <code>#put</code>. Rather than modifying objects in place, you will get used to returning new copies with new values. (<a href="https://github.com/hamstergem/hamster/">Hamster</a>, which provides great immutable data structures, can help you from having to hand-roll FP functionality.)</p>

<p>What does this mean for Rails? It will often mean creating functions or classes that take <code>ActiveRecord</code> objects and convert them into immutable value objects. For us, we carve out these value objects into the namespace of what we’re doing. For example, here are the two representations of a payroll in our system:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span># app/models/payroll.rb</span>
<span>class</span> <span>Payroll</span> <span>&lt;</span> <span>ActiveRecord</span><span>::</span><span>Base</span>
<span>end</span>

<span># app/services/payroll_calculator/payroll.rb</span>
<span>class</span> <span>PayrollCalculator::Payroll</span> <span>&lt;</span> <span>ValueObject</span>
<span>end</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The <code>ActiveRecord</code> version of a payroll represents the data that lives in the database. It is a superset of the data required for actually running a payroll. Although they have the same name, they do not have the same attributes. For example, the <code>ActiveRecord</code> version of <code>Payroll</code> will have a <code>processed_at</code> attribute, whereas the <code>Payroll</code> that lives in the calculation domain does not.</p>

<p>In the words of <a href="https://kellysutton.com/2017/06/07/domain-driven-design.html"><em>Domain-Driven Design</em></a>, each namespace here is a different Bounded Context. We implement adapters to take <code>ActiveRecord</code> payrolls and turn them into <code>PayrollCalculator</code> payrolls, and vice versa.</p>

<p>The upside of this is the same that you might see in any other large system with well-defined abstractions; changes in models don’t cross domains. In our example, we can change the structure of the <code>Payroll</code> in our database without needing to change the calculation code. We would only need to change our adapter. Furthermore, this context is entirely separate from the machinations of Rails. We could easily and safely pull this into its own …</p></article></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://kellysutton.com/2017/09/13/embracing-functional-programming-in-ruby.html">https://kellysutton.com/2017/09/13/embracing-functional-programming-in-ruby.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://kellysutton.com/2017/09/13/embracing-functional-programming-in-ruby.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26201237</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 03:30:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Draw an iceberg and see how it would float in water]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 695 | Comments 88 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26201160">thread link</a>) | @raldi
<br/>
February 19, 2021 | https://joshdata.me/iceberger.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://joshdata.me/iceberger.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    
    <p>Draw an iceberg and see how it will float.</p>
    <p>(Inspired by a <a href="https://twitter.com/GlacialMeg/status/1362557149147058178?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">tweet by @GlacialMeg</a>)</p>

    <canvas id="canvas">
    </canvas>

    <p>In reality, an iceberg wouldn’t float <i>exactly</i> like this. Its three-dimensional distribution of mass and its relative density compared to the water are both significant factors that are only approximated here.</p>

    <hr>

    <p>Inspired by a tweet by @GlacialMeg:</p>
    <blockquote data-partner="tweetdeck"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Today I channeled my energy into this very unofficial but passionate petition for scientists to start drawing icebergs in their stable orientations. I went to the trouble of painting a stable iceberg with my watercolors, so plz hear me out.</p><p>(1/4) <a href="https://t.co/rtkCYub38b">pic.twitter.com/rtkCYub38b</a></p></div>— Megan Thompson-Munson (@GlacialMeg) <a href="https://twitter.com/GlacialMeg/status/1362557149147058178?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 19, 2021</a></blockquote>
    


    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://joshdata.me/iceberger.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26201160</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 03:16:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[My Life in E-Ink]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 143 | Comments 77 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26200630">thread link</a>) | @HaoZeke
<br/>
February 19, 2021 | https://rgoswami.me/posts/my-life-in-eink/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rgoswami.me/posts/my-life-in-eink/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><blockquote><p>Collection of odds and ends relating to e-readers including personal reminisces</p></blockquote><h2 id="background">Background</h2><p>Reading has been a huge part of my life. The written word has had arguably more of an impact on my life than anything I have experienced in person. As a kid back in early 2000’s; this meant a lot of library trips and saving for paperbacks. I also caught the first wave of the e-ink revolution. Nothing beats a real book, in terms of textures and scents; but e-ink devices and the fantastic tools outlined here should make reading digital books much more palpable&nbsp;<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>.</p><p>I have been reading on my <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kobo%5FAura%5FHD">Kobo Aura HD</a> for almost a decade now, ever since its release. This means my setup is about as stable as its going to get in the near future. As good a time as any to collect my thoughts&nbsp;<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup>. The focus is on e-ink devices and auxiliary tools; not on all digital content; so there are no mentions of syncing or reading on the go (with a phone) or of monitors which are good for reading on.</p><h3 id="the-content">The Content</h3><p>In general; my e-ink reading habits can be broadly broken into the following categories:</p><dl><dt>Light Reading</dt><dd>Practically this includes <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/33462912-rohit-goswami">anything I review on Goodreads</a>; these are not often re-read; nor read very deeply; since they are read for pleasure. They are however, rarely deleted</dd><dt>Required Reading</dt><dd>Anything which typically requires me to take notes or practice / write out proofs; these are most often considered to be either coursework (for someone somewhere) or research monographs. These are typically large (in size) and unwieldy (in that they often lack TOCs) and are read multiple times; with a focus on highlights and notes</dd><dt>Active Research</dt><dd>These are the most ephemeral of my reading habits; and also the most numerous; I do not typically store these on my e-reader; and rarely need to make notes on the reader&nbsp;<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup>. These are often tiny; but require special work due to the metadata involved</dd></dl><table><thead><tr><th>Content Type</th><th>Software Stack</th><th>Deletion Rate</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Light Reading</td><td>Calibre</td><td>Rare</td></tr><tr><td>Required Reading</td><td>Calibre</td><td>Never</td></tr><tr><td>Active Research</td><td>Calibre + Zotero</td><td>Frequent</td></tr></tbody></table><p>Though I am a huge proponent of RSS feeds (with <a href="https://gitlab.com/news-flash/news%5Fflash%5Fgtk">Newsflash</a>) and read online content voraciously with both a <a href="https://app.getpocket.com/">Pocket</a> and <a href="https://www.diigo.com/user/rgoswami">Diigo</a> subscription<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup>; I sincerely do not believe blog stuff or anything tailored for the web should have a presence on an e-ink device; so there shall be no mention of those parts of my reading habits<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup>.</p><h2 id="hardware">Hardware</h2><p>My primary e-reader is still my <a href="https://www.kobo.com/koboaurahd?%5F%5F%5Fstore=au&amp;style=onestore">Kobo Aura HD</a> (complete with a snazzy <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Cover-Up-eReader-Natural-Cover-Function/dp/B00DZJ5VM0">hemp sleep-cover</a>), and has been my go to for almost a decade now since its release. Recently I have augmented my workflow with the <a href="https://remarkable.com/store/remarkable-2">reMarkable 2</a>; though I have yet to break it in very well; mostly because I tend to gravitate towards typing out my thoughts&nbsp;<sup id="fnref:6"><a href="#fn:6" role="doc-noteref">6</a></sup> instead of writing.</p><p>The Kobo Aura HD is still the pinnacle of reading technology to me; mostly because the firmware is easy to bypass; and there is a vibrant community of developers on the <a href="https://www.mobileread.com/forums/showthread.php?t=210800">MobileRead Forums</a>. Display and spec aside; the biggest reason for never replacing it has been been the simple fact that most modern e-readers no longer support SD cards; and much of my workflow depends on storing insane amounts of material offline&nbsp;<sup id="fnref:7"><a href="#fn:7" role="doc-noteref">7</a></sup>.</p><figure><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/d393a91160884052b7717a31a565283336a03ccf/eb437/ox-hugo/2021-02-20_01-39-20_screenshot.png" alt="Figure 1: Primary reading device with Koreader"><figcaption><p>Figure 1: Primary reading device with Koreader</p></figcaption></figure><p>Personally, I never use Nickel (the default Kobo interface), and it would probably choke trying to scan my 200 GB of content; so I haven’t updated the firmware in forever. My interactions are almost always in <a href="https://koreader.rocks/">Koreader</a>; and my launching poison of choice is the now no longer developed <a href="https://www.mobileread.com/forums/showthread.php?t=293804">Kobo start menu</a>&nbsp;<sup id="fnref:8"><a href="#fn:8" role="doc-noteref">8</a></sup>.</p><h2 id="software">Software</h2><p>Broadly speaking; the main parts of the software pipeline from digital book to brain are simply the syncing mechanism and the UI/UX/OS of the device in question; though it is often best to consider pre-processing books for devices too. These are covered in the order used.</p><h3 id="k2pdfopt">k2pdfopt</h3><p>The thought of reflowing text for an optimal reading experience, especially given the slightly limited processing power of my primary reading device is an enticing prospect. <a href="https://www.willus.com/k2pdfopt/">K2pdfopt or the Kindle 2 PDF Optimizer</a> is as criminally underrated as it is fantastic. An approach which works well for my device involves setting up <a href="https://github.com/HaoZeke/Dotfiles/blob/master/dotfiles/common/.local/bin/fileHelpers/docK2pdf">a simple shell script</a> (part <a href="https://github.com/HaoZeke/Dotfiles">of my Dotfiles</a>) for optimizing files on the fly before sending them through <code>calibre</code>.</p><div><pre><code data-lang="bash"><span>#!/usr/bin/env bash
</span><span></span><span># Get a filename</span>
<span>case</span> <span>"</span><span>$#</span><span>"</span> in
0<span>)</span>
      <span>echo</span> <span>"No arguments, so enter the filename, WITH the extension"</span>
      <span>read</span> -p <span>'Document: '</span> docfile
      <span>;;</span>
1<span>)</span>
      <span>echo</span> <span>"OK, using the filename"</span>
      <span>docfile</span><span>=</span><span>"</span><span>$1</span><span>"</span>
      <span>;;</span>
*<span>)</span>
      <span>echo</span> <span>"Illegal number of parameters"</span>
      <span>exit</span>
      <span>;;</span>
<span>esac</span>
<span># Get basename</span>
<span>basename</span><span>=</span><span>"</span><span>${</span><span>docfile</span><span>%.*</span><span>}</span><span>"</span>
<span>ext</span><span>=</span><span>"</span><span>${</span><span>docfile</span><span>##*</span><span>\.</span><span>}</span><span>"</span>
<span>echo</span> <span>"Basename </span><span>${</span><span>basename</span><span>}</span><span> with </span><span>$ext</span><span> from </span><span>$docfile</span><span>"</span>
<span>echo</span> <span>"Making a local store for the outputs"</span>
mkdir -p <span>"</span><span>$HOME</span><span>/auraHDopt"</span>

<span>case</span> <span>"</span><span>$ext</span><span>"</span> in
<span>"djvu"</span><span>)</span>
      <span>echo</span> <span>"Converting djvu to pdf via ps and running k2pdfopt"</span>
      djvups <span>"</span><span>${</span><span>basename</span><span>}</span><span>.djvu"</span> <span>"</span><span>${</span><span>basename</span><span>}</span><span>.ps"</span>
      ps2pdf <span>"</span><span>${</span><span>basename</span><span>}</span><span>.ps"</span> <span>"</span><span>${</span><span>basename</span><span>}</span><span>.pdf"</span>
      <span># The newline is for simulating the Enter key</span>
      <span>echo</span> <span>|</span> k2pdfopt <span>"</span><span>${</span><span>basename</span><span>}</span><span>.pdf"</span> -wrap -hy -ws -0.2 -dev kbhd -x
      <span>echo</span> <span>"Cleaning up"</span>
      mv <span>"</span><span>${</span><span>basename</span><span>}</span><span>_k2opt.pdf"</span> <span>"</span><span>$HOME</span><span>/auraHDopt"</span>
      rm -rf <span>"</span><span>${</span><span>basename</span><span>}</span><span>.{ps,pdf}"</span>
      <span>;;</span>
<span>"pdf"</span><span>)</span>
      <span>echo</span> <span>"Converting pdf with gs and running k2pdfopt"</span>
      gs -sDEVICE<span>=</span>pdfwrite -dCompatibilityLevel<span>=</span>1.4 -dPDFSETTINGS<span>=</span>/screen <span>\
</span><span></span>              -dNOPAUSE -dQUIET -dBATCH -sOutputFile<span>=</span><span>"</span><span>${</span><span>basename</span><span>}</span><span>gs.pdf"</span> <span>"</span><span>${</span><span>basename</span><span>}</span><span>.pdf"</span>
      <span>echo</span> <span>|</span> k2pdfopt <span>"</span><span>${</span><span>basename</span><span>}</span><span>gs.pdf"</span> -wrap -hy -ws -0.2 -dev kbhd -x
      <span>echo</span> <span>"Cleaning up"</span>
      rm <span>"</span><span>${</span><span>basename</span><span>}</span><span>gs.pdf"</span> -rf
      mv <span>"</span><span>${</span><span>basename</span><span>}</span><span>gs_k2opt.pdf"</span> <span>"</span><span>$HOME</span><span>/auraHDopt"</span>
      <span>;;</span>
*<span>)</span>
      <span>echo</span> <span>"Illegal file type"</span>
      <span>exit</span>
      <span>;;</span>
<span>esac</span>
</code></pre></div><p>The outputs can also be further processed with an <a href="https://github.com/HaoZeke/Dotfiles/blob/master/dotfiles/common/.local/bin/fileHelpers/isOcr">OCR (Optical Character Recognition) script</a> if required, and then edited in <a href="https://code-industry.net/masterpdfeditor/">Master PDF Editor</a> or something similar to add the table of contents interactively as well.</p><div><pre><code data-lang="bash"><span>#!/bin/bash
</span><span></span><span># Use as  find . -type f -name "*.pdf" -exec isOcr '{}' \;</span>

<span># Shamelessly kanged from here:</span>
<span># https://stackoverflow.com/questions/7997399/bash-script-to-check-pdfs-are-ocrd</span>
<span># Only searches for text on the first 5 pages</span>
<span># Modified to have red text. Also to possibly ocr the thing.</span>

<span># -*- mode: shell-script-mode -*-</span>

<span>MYFONTS</span><span>=</span><span>$(</span>pdffonts -l <span>15</span> <span>"</span><span>$1</span><span>"</span> <span>|</span> tail -n +3 <span>|</span> cut -d<span>' '</span> -f1 <span>|</span> sort <span>|</span> uniq<span>)</span>
<span>if</span> <span>[</span> <span>"</span><span>$MYFONTS</span><span>"</span> <span>=</span> <span>''</span> <span>]</span> <span>||</span> <span>[</span> <span>"</span><span>$MYFONTS</span><span>"</span> <span>=</span> <span>'[none]'</span> <span>]</span><span>;</span> <span>then</span>
    <span>echo</span> <span>"</span><span>$(</span>tput setaf 1<span>)</span><span>NOT OCR'ed: </span><span>$1</span><span>"</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>[[</span> -x <span>"</span><span>$(</span>which ocrmypdf<span>)</span><span>"</span> <span>]]</span><span>;</span> <span>then</span>
        <span>echo</span> <span>"</span><span>$(</span>tput setaf 4<span>)</span><span>"</span>
        <span>echo</span> <span>"Converting to </span><span>${</span><span>1</span><span>%.*</span><span>}</span><span>_ocr.pdf with ocrmypdf"</span>
        <span>echo</span> <span>"</span><span>$(</span>tput setaf 7<span>)</span><span>"</span>
        ocrmypdf --deskew --clean --rotate-pages <span>\
</span><span></span>            --jobs <span>4</span> -v --output-type pdfa <span>"</span><span>$1</span><span>"</span> <span>"</span><span>${</span><span>1</span><span>%.*</span><span>}</span><span>_ocr.pdf"</span>
    <span>elif</span> <span>[[</span> -x <span>"</span><span>$(</span>which pypdfocr<span>)</span><span>"</span> <span>]]</span><span>;</span> <span>then</span>
        <span>echo</span> <span>"</span><span>$(</span>tput setaf 2<span>)</span><span> Looking for config files at </span><span>$XDG_CONFIG_HOME</span><span>/pypdfocr/config.yml"</span>
        <span>echo</span> <span>"</span><span>$(</span>tput setaf 3<span>)</span><span>"</span>
        <span>if</span> <span>[[</span> -e <span>$XDG_CONFIG_HOME</span>/pypdfocr/config.yml <span>]]</span><span>;</span> <span>then</span>
            <span>echo</span> <span>"Using configuration settings"</span>
            <span>echo</span> <span>"</span><span>$(</span>tput setaf 4<span>)</span><span>"</span>
            pypdfocr -c <span>$XDG_CONFIG_HOME</span>/pypdfocr/config.yml <span>"</span><span>$1</span><span>"</span>
        <span>else</span>
            <span>echo</span> <span>"Using default settings"</span>
            <span>echo</span> <span>"</span><span>$(</span>tput setaf 4<span>)</span><span>"</span>
            pypdfocr <span>"</span><span>$1</span><span>"</span>
        <span>fi</span>
        <span>echo</span> <span>"</span><span>$(</span>tput setaf 2<span>)</span><span> You might want to get pypdfocr"</span>
    <span>fi</span>
<span>else</span>
    <span>echo</span> <span>"</span><span>$1</span><span> is OCR'ed."</span>
<span>fi</span>
</code></pre></div><p>The end result is:</p><ul><li>A directory with perfectly <code>pdf</code> files re-flowed text<ul><li>Possibly OCR’ed for string searches</li></ul></li></ul><p>TOC editing is still rather janky; but this is also because the OCR process is still rather spotty.</p><h3 id="calibre">Calibre</h3><p><a href="https://calibre-ebook.com/">Calibre</a> is an excellent library software, and there are very few alternatives which offer all the salient features:</p><dl><dt>Syncing</dt><dd>Apart from working well with a plethora of official devices, Koreader is also pretty well supported, and mounting folders allows for easy management of a secret library (e.g. <code>.Library</code>) on an SD card to prevent Nickel from reading and choking on large libraries</dd><dt>Multiple Libraries</dt><dd>I personally keep one for fiction, one for non-fiction, and one (transiently populated) one for papers</dd><dt>Good metadata collection</dt><dd>Nothing beats rich metadata, and with third party plugins, all the best content providers can be leveraged for blurbs; plus most purchased books come with metadata which <code>calibre</code> can read</dd></dl><p>It isn’t perfect, there are far better <a href="https://opds.io/">OPDS (Open Publication Distribution System)</a> servers like the fantastic <a href="https://github.com/seblucas/cops">COPS (Calibre OPDS)</a> project, and there have been <a href="https://anarc.at/software/desktop/calibre/">some security concerns in the past</a>, but it is really usable and is <a href="https://github.com/kovidgoyal/calibre">under active development</a>; plus it has a <a href="https://kovidgoyal.net/">fun developer</a>. I also personally find the file conversion lacking, compared to <code>k2pdfopt</code>, but as a library management system it is really good.</p><h3 id="zotero-sync">Zotero Sync</h3><p>Calibre provides a handy <a href="https://www.mobileread.com/forums/showthread.php?p=3339191#poststop">ZMI (Zotero Metadata Importer) plugin</a> which allows for exported papers to be imported into <code>calibre</code> and from then into the e-reader as expected. Combined with the folder mounts facilitated by <code>calibre</code> this allows for a painless way to ensure a quick export; optimize; sync; read and delete workflow.</p><h3 id="koreader">Koreader</h3><p>Koreader is probably the best thing to happen to e-ink devices since sliced bread. It replaces the need to use any cables with an e-reader; since newer versions have a nice SSH server, and can also update itself. Since this is mostly used as is; and all the information required is on the <a href="https://github.com/koreader/koreader/wiki">Github Wiki</a>, there’s not much else to say here.</p><p>It is probably worth noting that the in-built re-flow options do tend to cause major artifacts on older hardware, and is best avoided. Almost equivalently, and at a far lower cost in terms of performance, page contents can be fit to width and zoomed in automatically, which is almost as good as working with <code>k2pdfopt</code> in some special cases.</p><h2 id="conclusions">Conclusions</h2><p>Given my unfortunate separation from my library back home; it is likely that my e-ink devices will continue to be my primary source of reading material. Plus the long retarded color e-ink market finally seems to be moving out of its stupor&nbsp;<sup id="fnref:9"><a href="#fn:9" role="doc-noteref">9</a></sup>. The only possible addendum to this methodology would probably involve integrating <code>orgmode</code> and the reMarkable 2 sometime. E-ink is here to stay. This setup would probably need revisions involving <code>rclone</code> or <code>syncthing</code> if I ever gave …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://rgoswami.me/posts/my-life-in-eink/">https://rgoswami.me/posts/my-life-in-eink/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/my-life-in-eink/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26200630</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 01:46:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A request for Pinboard old-timers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 225 | Comments 104 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26199676">thread link</a>) | @Alex3917
<br/>
February 19, 2021 | https://www.prettyfwd.com/t/XiK8ArVIT6uVItPGeH3lzA/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.prettyfwd.com/t/XiK8ArVIT6uVItPGeH3lzA/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.prettyfwd.com/t/XiK8ArVIT6uVItPGeH3lzA/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26199676</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 23:56:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[F’: Flight Software and Embedded Systems Framework]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 135 | Comments 26 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26199346">thread link</a>) | @zeristor
<br/>
February 19, 2021 | https://nasa.github.io/fprime/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nasa.github.io/fprime/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main_content_wrap">
      <section id="main_content">
        <p>F´ is a software framework for rapid development and deployment of embedded systems and spaceflight applications.
Originally developed at NASA’s Jet Propulsion Laboratory, F´ is open source software that has been successfully deployed
for several space applications. It has been used for, but is not limited to, CubeSats, SmallSats, instruments, and
deployables.</p>

<p>F´ has the following features:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Component architecture with well-defined interfaces</li>
  <li>C++ framework providing core capabilities like queues, threads, and operating-system abstraction</li>
  <li>Tools for designing systems and automatically generating code from systems design</li>
  <li>A standard library of flight-worthy components</li>
  <li>Testing tools for unit and system-level testing</li>
</ul>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>F´ Resources</th>
      <th>&nbsp;</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>Features</td>
      <td><a href="https://nasa.github.io/fprime/features.html">Features</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Projects</td>
      <td><a href="https://nasa.github.io/fprime/projects.html">Projects</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Installation</td>
      <td><a href="https://nasa.github.io/fprime/INSTALL.html">INSTALL.md</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Tutorials</td>
      <td><a href="https://nasa.github.io/fprime/Tutorials/README.html">Tutorials</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>User Guide</td>
      <td><a href="https://nasa.github.io/fprime/UsersGuide/guide.html">User Guide</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Repository</td>
      <td><a href="https://github.com/nasa/fprime">https://github.com/nasa/fprime</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Community Forum and Mailing List</td>
      <td><a href="https://groups.google.com/d/forum/fprime-community">https://groups.google.com/d/forum/fprime-community</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Community GitHub Organization</td>
      <td><a href="https://github.com/fprime-community">https://github.com/fprime-community</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Standard Reference Application</td>
      <td><a href="https://github.com/nasa/fprime/blob/master/Ref/README.md">Ref</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Raspberry PI Reference Application</td>
      <td><a href="https://github.com/nasa/fprime/blob/master/RPI/README.md">RPI</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Architecture Overview</td>
      <td><a href="https://nasa.github.io/fprime/Architecture/FPrimeArchitectureShort.pdf">Architecture</a></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h2 id="f-system-requirements">F´ System Requirements</h2>

<p>In order to develop applications with F´, the following requirements of the user’s system must be met.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Linux or Mac OS X operating system (or Windows Subsystem for Linux on Windows)</li>
  <li>CMake <a href="https://cmake.org/download/">https://cmake.org/download/</a> available on the system path</li>
  <li>Bash or Bash compatible shell</li>
  <li>CLang or GCC compiler</li>
  <li>Python 3 and PIP <a href="https://www.python.org/downloads/">https://www.python.org/downloads/</a></li>
</ol>

<h2 id="quick-installation-guide">Quick Installation Guide</h2>

<p>F´ can be quickly installed and ready to use by cloning the GitHub repository, installing Python code (typically in a
virtual environment), and building on of our reference applications. For full install instructions please see:
<a href="https://nasa.github.io/fprime/INSTALL.html">INSTALL.md</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Clone and Install</strong></p>
<div><div><pre><code>git clone https://github.com/nasa/fprime.git
cd fprime
pip install --upgrade wheel setuptools pip
pip install Fw/Python Gds/
</code></pre></div></div>
<p><strong>Build the Ref Application</strong></p>
<div><div><pre><code>cd Ref
fprime-util generate
fprime-util install
</code></pre></div></div>
<p><strong>Run the Ref Application</strong></p>


<h2 id="further-references">Further References</h2>

<p>Full information on the code and F´ are available at our Github page:
<a href="http://github.com/nasa/fprime">http://github.com/nasa/fprime</a>.</p>

<p>To start with, follow the <a href="https://nasa.github.io/fprime/INSTALL.html">installation guide</a>. Then inspect
either the <a href="https://github.com/nasa/fprime/blob/master/Ref/README.md">reference application</a>, 
<a href="https://github.com/nasa/fprime/blob/master/RPI/README.md">rapberry pi reference</a>, or the
<a href="https://nasa.github.io/fprime/Tutorials/README.html">tutorials</a>.</p>

      </section>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nasa.github.io/fprime/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26199346</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 23:16:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[IDOM – It's React, but in Python]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 22 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26199008">thread link</a>) | @xdze2
<br/>
February 19, 2021 | https://rmorshea.github.io/articles/2021/idom-react-but-its-python/article/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rmorshea.github.io/articles/2021/idom-react-but-its-python/article/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-md-component="container">
      
      
        
      
      <main data-md-component="main">
        <div>
          
            
              
            
            
              
            
          
          <div>
            <article><a download="" href="https://rmorshea.github.io/articles/2021/idom-react-but-its-python/article/article.pdf" title="PDF Export"><svg style="height: 1.2rem; width: 1.2rem;" viewBox="0 0 384 512" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path d="M224 136V0H24C10.7 0 0 10.7 0 24v464c0 13.3 10.7 24 24 24h336c13.3 0 24-10.7 24-24V160H248c-13.2 0-24-10.8-24-24zm76.45 211.36l-96.42 95.7c-6.65 6.61-17.39 6.61-24.04 0l-96.42-95.7C73.42 337.29 80.54 320 94.82 320H160v-80c0-8.84 7.16-16 16-16h32c8.84 0 16 7.16 16 16v80h65.18c14.28 0 21.4 17.29 11.27 27.36zM377 105L279.1 7c-4.5-4.5-10.6-7-17-7H256v128h128v-6.1c0-6.3-2.5-12.4-7-16.9z"></path></svg></a>
              
                
                
                
<p><a href="https://github.com/idom-team/idom" target="_blank">IDOM</a> is a new declarative Python
package for building highly interactive user interfaces.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/idom-team/idom"><span><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 496 512"><path d="M165.9 397.4c0 2-2.3 3.6-5.2 3.6-3.3.3-5.6-1.3-5.6-3.6 0-2 2.3-3.6 5.2-3.6 3-.3 5.6 1.3 5.6 3.6zm-31.1-4.5c-.7 2 1.3 4.3 4.3 4.9 2.6 1 5.6 0 6.2-2s-1.3-4.3-4.3-5.2c-2.6-.7-5.5.3-6.2 2.3zm44.2-1.7c-2.9.7-4.9 2.6-4.6 4.9.3 2 2.9 3.3 5.9 2.6 2.9-.7 4.9-2.6 4.6-4.6-.3-1.9-3-3.2-5.9-2.9zM244.8 8C106.1 8 0 113.3 0 252c0 110.9 69.8 205.8 169.5 239.2 12.8 2.3 17.3-5.6 17.3-12.1 0-6.2-.3-40.4-.3-61.4 0 0-70 15-84.7-29.8 0 0-11.4-29.1-27.8-36.6 0 0-22.9-15.7 1.6-15.4 0 0 24.9 2 38.6 25.8 21.9 38.6 58.6 27.5 72.9 20.9 2.3-16 8.8-27.1 16-33.7-55.9-6.2-112.3-14.3-112.3-110.5 0-27.5 7.6-41.3 23.6-58.9-2.6-6.5-11.1-33.3 2.6-67.9 20.9-6.5 69 27 69 27 20-5.6 41.5-8.5 62.8-8.5s42.8 2.9 62.8 8.5c0 0 48.1-33.6 69-27 13.7 34.7 5.2 61.4 2.6 67.9 16 17.7 25.8 31.5 25.8 58.9 0 96.5-58.9 104.2-114.8 110.5 9.2 7.9 17 22.9 17 46.4 0 33.7-.3 75.4-.3 83.6 0 6.5 4.6 14.4 17.3 12.1C428.2 457.8 496 362.9 496 252 496 113.3 383.5 8 244.8 8zM97.2 352.9c-1.3 1-1 3.3.7 5.2 1.6 1.6 3.9 2.3 5.2 1 1.3-1 1-3.3-.7-5.2-1.6-1.6-3.9-2.3-5.2-1zm-10.8-8.1c-.7 1.3.3 2.9 2.3 3.9 1.6 1 3.6.7 4.3-.7.7-1.3-.3-2.9-2.3-3.9-2-.6-3.6-.3-4.3.7zm32.4 35.6c-1.6 1.3-1 4.3 1.3 6.2 2.3 2.3 5.2 2.6 6.5 1 1.3-1.3.7-4.3-1.3-6.2-2.2-2.3-5.2-2.6-6.5-1zm-11.4-14.7c-1.6 1-1.6 3.6 0 5.9 1.6 2.3 4.3 3.3 5.6 2.3 1.6-1.3 1.6-3.9 0-6.2-1.4-2.3-4-3.3-5.6-2z"></path></svg></span> https://github.com/idom-team/idom</a></li>
<li><a href="https://idom-docs.herokuapp.com/"><span><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 448 512"><path d="M448 360V24c0-13.3-10.7-24-24-24H96C43 0 0 43 0 96v320c0 53 43 96 96 96h328c13.3 0 24-10.7 24-24v-16c0-7.5-3.5-14.3-8.9-18.7-4.2-15.4-4.2-59.3 0-74.7 5.4-4.3 8.9-11.1 8.9-18.6zM128 134c0-3.3 2.7-6 6-6h212c3.3 0 6 2.7 6 6v20c0 3.3-2.7 6-6 6H134c-3.3 0-6-2.7-6-6v-20zm0 64c0-3.3 2.7-6 6-6h212c3.3 0 6 2.7 6 6v20c0 3.3-2.7 6-6 6H134c-3.3 0-6-2.7-6-6v-20zm253.4 250H96c-17.7 0-32-14.3-32-32 0-17.6 14.4-32 32-32h285.4c-1.9 17.1-1.9 46.9 0 64z"></path></svg></span> https://idom-docs.herokuapp.com</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/idom-team/idom/discussions"><span><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path d="M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zM262.655 90c-54.497 0-89.255 22.957-116.549 63.758-3.536 5.286-2.353 12.415 2.715 16.258l34.699 26.31c5.205 3.947 12.621 3.008 16.665-2.122 17.864-22.658 30.113-35.797 57.303-35.797 20.429 0 45.698 13.148 45.698 32.958 0 14.976-12.363 22.667-32.534 33.976C247.128 238.528 216 254.941 216 296v4c0 6.627 5.373 12 12 12h56c6.627 0 12-5.373 12-12v-1.333c0-28.462 83.186-29.647 83.186-106.667 0-58.002-60.165-102-116.531-102zM256 338c-25.365 0-46 20.635-46 46 0 25.364 20.635 46 46 46s46-20.636 46-46c0-25.365-20.635-46-46-46z"></path></svg></span> https://github.com/idom-team/idom/discussions</a></li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://github.com/idom-team/idom"><img alt="idom logo" src="https://github.com/idom-team/idom/raw/929d07ff4a643320a6148336613621242284f8d2/docs/source/branding/idom-logo.png"></a></p>
<p>IDOM takes inspiration from <a href="https://reactjs.org/" target="_blank">React</a>, and wherever
possible, attempts to achieve parity with the features it copies more directly. Nowhere
is this more evident than the version of React's often lauded
<a href="https://reactjs.org/docs/hooks-intro.html" target="_blank">"Hooks"</a> that IDOM
implements in Python.</p>
<p>At a glance, the similarities between IDOM and React are rather striking. Below is a
React component which defines a simple <code>Counter</code> displaying the number of times a button
has been clicked:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>import</span> <span>React</span><span>,</span> <span>{</span> <span>useState</span> <span>}</span> <span>from</span> <span>"react"</span><span>;</span>
<span>import</span> <span>ReactDOM</span> <span>from</span> <span>"react-dom"</span><span>;</span>

<span>function</span> <span>Counter</span><span>()</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>const</span> <span>[</span><span>count</span><span>,</span> <span>setCount</span><span>]</span> <span>=</span> <span>useState</span><span>(</span><span>0</span><span>);</span>
  <span>return</span> <span>(</span>
    <span>&lt;</span><span>div</span><span>&gt;</span>
      <span>&lt;</span><span>button</span> <span>onClick</span><span>=</span><span>{()</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>setCount</span><span>(</span><span>count</span> <span>+</span> <span>1</span><span>)}&gt;</span><span>Click</span> <span>me</span><span>!</span><span>&lt;/</span><span>button</span><span>&gt;</span>
      <span>&lt;</span><span>p</span><span>&gt;{</span><span>`Click count: </span><span>${</span><span>count</span><span>}</span><span>`</span><span>}&lt;/</span><span>p</span><span>&gt;</span>
    <span>&lt;/</span><span>div</span><span>&gt;</span>
  <span>);</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>ReactDOM</span><span>.</span><span>render</span><span>(&lt;</span><span>Counter</span> <span>/&gt;,</span> <span>document</span><span>.</span><span>getElementById</span><span>(</span><span>"root"</span><span>));</span>
</code></pre></div>

<p>And this is the same component implemented in Python using IDOM:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>import</span> <span>idom</span>

<span>@idom</span><span>.</span><span>component</span>
<span>def</span> <span>Counter</span><span>():</span>
    <span>count</span><span>,</span> <span>set_count</span> <span>=</span> <span>idom</span><span>.</span><span>hooks</span><span>.</span><span>use_state</span><span>(</span><span>0</span><span>)</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>idom</span><span>.</span><span>html</span><span>.</span><span>div</span><span>(</span>
        <span>idom</span><span>.</span><span>html</span><span>.</span><span>button</span><span>(</span>
            <span>{</span><span>"onClick"</span><span>:</span> <span>lambda</span> <span>event</span><span>:</span> <span>set_count</span><span>(</span><span>count</span> <span>+</span> <span>1</span><span>)},</span>
            <span>"Click me!"</span>
        <span>),</span>
        <span>idom</span><span>.</span><span>html</span><span>.</span><span>p</span><span>(</span><span>f</span><span>"Click count: </span><span>{</span><span>count</span><span>}</span><span>"</span><span>)</span>
    <span>)</span>

<span>idom</span><span>.</span><span>run</span><span>(</span><span>Counter</span><span>)</span>
</code></pre></div>

<p>Which, when displayed in your browser, should look something like this:</p>
<p><img alt="click-counter-example" src="https://rmorshea.github.io/articles/2021/idom-react-but-its-python/click-counter.gif"></p>
<h2 id="why-do-we-need-idom">Why Do We Need IDOM?</h2>
<p>Over the <a href="https://www.npmtrends.com/react-vs-angular-vs-vue" target="_blank">past 5
years</a> front-end
developers seem to have concluded that programs written with a
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yGh0bjzj4IQ" target="_blank">declarative</a> style or
framework tend to be easier to understand and maintain than those done imperatively. Put
more simply, mutable state in programs can quickly lead to unsustainable complexity.
This trend is largely evidenced by the
<a href="https://gist.github.com/tkrotoff/b1caa4c3a185629299ec234d2314e190" target="_blank">rise</a>
of Javascript frameworks like <a href="https://vuejs.org/" target="_blank">Vue</a> and
<a href="https://reactjs.org/" target="_blank">React</a> which describe the logic of computations
without explicitly stating their control flow.</p>
<p><img alt="npm download trends" src="https://rmorshea.github.io/articles/2021/idom-react-but-its-python/npm-download-trends.png"></p>
<p>So what does this have to do with Python and IDOM? Well, because browsers are the de
facto "operating system of the internet", even back-end languages like Python have had
to figure out clever ways to integrate with them. While standard
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Representational_state_transfer">REST</a> APIs are well
suited to applications built using HTML templates, modern browser users expect a higher
degree of interactivity than this alone can achieve.</p>
<p>A variety of Python packages have since been created to help solve this problem:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/jupyter-widgets/ipywidgets" target="_blank">IPyWidgets</a> - Adds
  interactive widgets to <a href="https://jupyter.org/" target="_blank">Jupyter Notebooks</a></li>
<li><a href="https://plotly.com/dash/" target="_blank">Dash</a> - Allows data scientists to produces
  enterprise-ready analytic apps</li>
<li><a href="https://www.streamlit.io/" target="_blank">Streamlit</a> - Turns simple Python scripts
  into interactive dashboards</li>
<li><a href="https://docs.bokeh.org/" target="_blank">Bokeh</a> - An interactive visualization
  library for modern web browsers</li>
</ul>
<p>However they each have drawbacks that can make them difficult to use.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Restrictive ecosystems</strong> - UI components developed for one framework cannot be
   easily ported to any of the others because their APIs are either too complex,
   undocumented, or are structurally inaccesible.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Imperative paradigm</strong> - IPyWidgets and Bokeh have not embraced the same declarative
   design principles pioneered by front-end developers. Streamlit and Dash on the
   otherhand, are declarative, but fall short of the features provided by React or Vue.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Limited layouts</strong> - At their initial inception, the developers of these libraries
   were driven by the visualization needs of data scientists so the ability to create
   complex UI layouts may not have been a primary engineering goal.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>A future article will address specific comparisons to each of the projects mentioned
above, but for now, we'll just focus on IDOM and its solutions to these problems.</p>
<h2 id="ecosystem-independence">Ecosystem Independence</h2>
<p>IDOM has a flexible set of core abstractions that allow it to interface with its peers.
At the time of writing, both Jupyter and Dash are supported, while Streamlit and Bokeh
are in the works:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/idom-team/idom-jupyter" target="_blank">idom-jupyter</a> (try it now
  with
  <a href="https://mybinder.org/v2/gh/idom-team/idom-jupyter/main?filepath=notebooks%2Fintroduction.ipynb" target="_blank">Binder</a>)</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/idom-team/idom-dash" target="_blank">idom-dash</a></li>
</ul>
<p>By providing well defined interfaces and straighforward protocols, IDOM makes it easy to
swap out any part of the stack with an alternate implementation if you want to. For
example, if you need a different web server for your application, IDOM already has 3
options to choose from or, use as blueprints to create your own:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/sanic-org/sanic" target="_blank">Sanic</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/pallets/flask" target="_blank">Flask</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/tornadoweb/tornado" target="_blank">Tornado</a></li>
</ul>
<p>You can even target your usage of IDOM in your production-grade applications with IDOM's
Javascript <a href="https://github.com/idom-team/idom-client-react" target="_blank">React client library</a>. Just install
it in your front-end app and connect to a back-end websocket that's serving up IDOM
models. IDOM's own
<a href="https://idom-docs.herokuapp.com/docs/index.html" target="_blank">documentation</a> acts as
a prime example for this targeted usage - most of the page is static HTML, but embedded
in it are interactive examples that feature live views being served from a web socket:</p>
<p><img alt="live-examples-in-docs" src="https://rmorshea.github.io/articles/2021/idom-react-but-its-python/live-examples-in-docs.gif"></p>
<h2 id="declarative-components">Declarative Components</h2>
<p>IDOM, by adopting the hook design pattern from React, inherits many of its aesthetic and
functional characteristics. For those unfamiliar with hooks, user interfaces are
composed of basic <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTML_element" target="_blank">HTML elements</a> that are
constructed and returned by special functions called "components". Then, through the
magic of hooks, those component functions can be made to have state. Consider the
component below which displays a basic representation of an
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AND_gate" target="_blank">AND-gate</a>:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>import</span> <span>idom</span>

<span>@idom</span><span>.</span><span>component</span>
<span>def</span> <span>AndGate</span><span>():</span>
    <span>input_1</span><span>,</span> <span>toggle_1</span> <span>=</span> <span>use_toggle</span><span>()</span>
    <span>input_2</span><span>,</span> <span>toggle_2</span> <span>=</span> <span>use_toggle</span><span>()</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>idom</span><span>.</span><span>html</span><span>.</span><span>div</span><span>(</span>
        <span>idom</span><span>.</span><span>html</span><span>.</span><span>input</span><span>(</span>
            <span>{</span><span>"type"</span><span>:</span> <span>"checkbox"</span><span>,</span> <span>"onClick"</span><span>:</span> <span>lambda</span> <span>event</span><span>:</span> <span>toggle_1</span><span>()}</span>
        <span>),</span>
        <span>idom</span><span>.</span><span>html</span><span>.</span><span>input</span><span>(</span>
            <span>{</span><span>"type"</span><span>:</span> <span>"checkbox"</span><span>,</span> <span>"onClick"</span><span>:</span> <span>lambda</span> <span>event</span><span>:</span> <span>toggle_2</span><span>()}</span>
        <span>),</span>
        <span>idom</span><span>.</span><span>html</span><span>.</span><span>pre</span><span>(</span><span>f</span><span>"</span><span>{</span><span>input_1</span><span>}</span><span> AND </span><span>{</span><span>input_2</span><span>}</span><span> = </span><span>{</span><span>input_1</span> <span>and</span> <span>input_2</span><span>}</span><span>"</span><span>),</span>
    <span>)</span>

<span>def</span> <span>use_toggle</span><span>():</span>
    <span>state</span><span>,</span> <span>set_state</span> <span>=</span> <span>idom</span><span>.</span><span>hooks</span><span>.</span><span>use_state</span><span>(</span><span>False</span><span>)</span>

    <span>def</span> <span>toggle_state</span><span>():</span>
        <span>set_state</span><span>(</span><span>lambda</span> <span>old_state</span><span>:</span> <span>not</span> <span>old_state</span><span>)</span>

    <span>return</span> <span>state</span><span>,</span> <span>toggle_state</span>

<span>idom</span><span>.</span><span>run</span><span>(</span><span>AndGate</span><span>)</span>
</code></pre></div>

<p><img alt="and-gate-demo" src="https://rmorshea.github.io/articles/2021/idom-react-but-its-python/and-gate.gif"></p>
<p>Here's a very high level summary of how it works... the first time a view of the
component above is rendered, the <code>AndGate</code> function is called where its initial <code>state</code>
for <code>input_1</code> and <code>input_2</code> is <code>False</code>. The function then returns a series of HTML
elements with callbacks that respond to client-side events. Machinery behind the scenes
subsequently realizes that declaration and displays two checkbox buttons with the text
<code>False AND False = False</code>. Later, when a user clicks the now visible checkbox buttons,
client-side events are triggered, the associated callbacks respond by inverting the old
<code>state</code> from <code>False</code> to <code>True</code>, and a re-render of the component is scheduled. When
re-rendering, the function is again called, this time though, where <code>input_1</code> and
<code>input_2</code> have been updated to reflect the new <code>state</code>, thus causing the displayed text
to change.</p>
<p>In the code above, consider the fact that it never explicitely describes how to evolve
the frontend view when events occur. Instead, it declares that, given a particular
state, this is how the view should look. It's then IDOM's responsibility to figure out
how to bring that declaration into being. This behavior of defining outcomes without
stating the means by which to achieve them is what makes components in IDOM and React
"declarative". For comparison, a hypothetical, and a more imperative approach to
defining the same interface might look similar to the following:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>layout</span> <span>=</span> <span>Layout</span><span>()</span>

<span>def</span> <span>make_and_gate</span><span>():</span>
    <span>state</span> <span>=</span> <span>{</span><span>"input_1"</span><span>:</span> <span>False</span><span>,</span> <span>"input_2"</span><span>:</span> <span>False</span><span>}</span>
    <span>output_text</span> <span>=</span> <span>html</span><span>.</span><span>pre</span><span>()</span>
    <span>update_output_text</span><span>(</span><span>output_text</span><span>,</span> <span>state</span><span>)</span>

    <span>def</span> <span>toggle_input</span><span>(</span><span>index</span><span>):</span>
      <span>state</span><span>[</span><span>f</span><span>"input_</span><span>{</span><span>index</span><span>}</span><span>"</span><span>]</span> <span>=</span> <span>not</span> <span>state</span><span>[</span><span>f</span><span>"input_</span><span>{</span><span>index</span><span>}</span><span>"</span><span>]</span>
      <span>update_output_text</span><span>(</span><span>output_text</span><span>,</span> <span>state</span><span>)</span>

    <span>return</span> <span>html</span><span>.</span><span>div</span><span>(</span>
        <span>html</span><span>.</span><span>input</span><span>(</span>
            <span>{</span><span>"type"</span><span>:</span> <span>"checkbox"</span><span>,</span> <span>"onClick"</span><span>:</span> <span>lambda</span> <span>event</span><span>:</span> <span>toggle_input</span><span>(</span><span>1</span><span>)}</span>
        <span>),</span>
        <span>html</span><span>.</span><span>input</span><span>(</span>
            <span>{</span><span>"type"</span><span>:</span> <span>"checkbox"</span><span>,</span> <span>"onClick"</span><span>:</span> <span>lambda</span> <span>event</span><span>:</span> <span>toggle_input</span><span>(</span><span>2</span><span>)}</span>
        <span>),</span>
        <span>output_text</span>
    <span>)</span>

<span>def</span> <span>update_output_text</span><span>(</span><span>text</span><span>,</span> <span>state</span><span>):</span>
    <span>text</span><span>.</span><span>update</span><span>(</span>
        <span>children</span><span>=</span><span>"</span><span>{input_1}</span><span> AND </span><span>{input_2}</span><span> = </span><span>{output}</span><span>"</span><span>.</span><span>format</span><span>(</span>
            <span>input_1</span><span>=</span><span>state</span><span>[</span><span>"input_1"</span><span>],</span>
            <span>input_2</span><span>=</span><span>state</span><span>[</span><span>"input_2"</span><span>],</span>
            <span>output</span><span>=</span><span>state</span><span>[</span><span>"input_1"</span><span>]</span> <span>and</span> <span>state</span><span>[</span><span>"input_2"</span><span>],</span>
        <span>)</span>
    <span>)</span>

<span>layout</span><span>.</span><span>add_element</span><span>(</span><span>make_and_gate</span><span>())</span>
<span>layout</span><span>.</span><span>run</span><span>()</span>
</code></pre></div>

<p>In this imperative incarnation there are several disadvantages:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Refactoring is difficult</strong> - Functions are much more specialized to their
   particular usages in <code>make_and_gate</code> and thus cannot be easily generalized. By
   comparison, <code>use_toggle</code> from the declarative implementation could be applicable to
   any scenario where boolean indicators are toggled on and off.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>No clear static relations</strong> - There is no one section of code through which to
   discern the basic structure and behaviors of the view. This issue is exemplified by
   the fact that we must call <code>update_output_text</code> from two different locations. Once in
   the body of <code>make_and_gate</code> and again in the body of the callback <code>toggle_input</code>.
   This means that, to understand what the <code>output_text</code> might contain, we must also
   understand all the business logic that surrounds it.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Referential links cause complexity</strong> - To evolve the view, various callbacks must
   hold references to all the elements that they will update. At the outset this makes
   writing programs difficult since elements must be passed up and down the call stack
   wherever they are needed. Considered further though, it also means that a function
   layers down in the call stack can accidentally or intentionally impact the behavior
   of ostensibly unrelated parts of the program.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="virtual-document-object-model">Virtual Document Object Model</h2>
<p>To communicate between their back-end Python servers and Javascript clients, IDOM's
peers take an approach that aligns fairly closely with the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Model%E2%80%93view%E2%80%93controller" target="_blank">Model-View-Controller</a>
design pattern - the controller lives server-side (though not always), the model is
what's synchronized between the server and client, and the view is run client-side in</p></article></div></div></main></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://rmorshea.github.io/articles/2021/idom-react-but-its-python/article/">https://rmorshea.github.io/articles/2021/idom-react-but-its-python/article/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rmorshea.github.io/articles/2021/idom-react-but-its-python/article/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26199008</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 22:43:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Meth Kingpin Was Director of Operations at US Air Force Combat Controller School]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 12 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26198555">thread link</a>) | @AndrewBissell
<br/>
February 19, 2021 | https://narco.news/meth-kingpin-was-director-of-operations-for-combat-controller-school | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://narco.news/meth-kingpin-was-director-of-operations-for-combat-controller-school">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-v-6d96295c=""><div data-v-6d96295c=""><p>On the skydiving forum <em><a href="https://www.dropzone.com/forums/topic/222999-weekend-raeford-pics/?tab=comments#comment-439487">Dropzone</a></em>, a post from 2002 shows a picture of an individual identifiable as Tim Thacker along with his siblings. </p><figure><div><div><p><img src="https://publish.narco.news/content/images/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-11-at-12.35.02-PM-3.png" width="1214" height="1130"></p><p><img src="https://publish.narco.news/content/images/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-16-at-4.59.19-PM-2.png" width="488" height="606"></p></div><div><p><img src="https://publish.narco.news/content/images/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-19-at-1.21.51-PM.png" width="1572" height="1252"></p><p><img src="https://publish.narco.news/content/images/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-19-at-1.31.10-PM-2.png" width="1274" height="990"></p></div></div><figcaption><em><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tim-thacker-8b173b71/">LinkedIn</a></em>;<em> <a href="https://www.facebook.com/PoliceWarsaw/posts/yesterday-may-11-2016-officers-with-the-warsaw-police-department-responded-to-a-/960425930732138/">Facebook</a></em>;<em> <a href="https://www.dropzone.com/forums/topic/222999-weekend-raeford-pics/?tab=comments#comment-439487">Dropzone</a> (<a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20210219184359/https://www.dropzone.com/forums/topic/222999-weekend-raeford-pics/">archived link</a>)</em></figcaption></figure><p>The user SkymonkeyONE identifies Tim Thacker as the subject and lists his username on the <em>Dropzone</em> forum: "USSkydiver". Curiously, the user USSkydiver identifies himself as "Tim Tennant" in several of his <a href="https://www.dropzone.com/profile/1794-usskydiver/content/page/3/?all_activity=1">posts</a>, including one from <a href="https://www.dropzone.com/forums/topic/184982-it's-my-last-day-at-work---and-i-am-not-sad!/">February 4, 2005</a>, in which he states that he will officially retire from the United States Air Force on April 1, 2005 after 25 years of active duty service.</p><figure><div><div><p><img src="https://publish.narco.news/content/images/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-19-at-1.30.33-PM.png" width="2176" height="732"></p></div></div><figcaption><a href="https://www.dropzone.com/forums/topic/184982-it's-my-last-day-at-work---and-i-am-not-sad!/?tab=comments#comment-86729">Link</a></figcaption></figure><p>In an <a href="https://www.socom.mil/TipOfTheSpear/June%202004%20Tip%20of%20the%20Spear.pdf">article</a> from the June 2004 issue of U.S. SOCOM's <em>Tip of the Spear</em>, a publication about the U.S. special operations forces (SOF), Master Sgt. Tim Tennant, United States Air Force, is listed as the Director of Operations for the USAF's Combat Controller School at Pope AFB, which is part of the Fort Bragg military complex near Fayetteville, NC. The USAF Combat Controllers (CCT) are an elite SOF unit that specialize in airborne warfare. According to a <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130628090639/http://www.af.mil/information/factsheets/factsheet.asp?id=174">fact sheet</a> published by the USAF about CCT:</p><blockquote>Air Force Special Operations Command's combat controllers, or CCT, are Battlefield Airmen assigned to special tactics squadrons. The CCT mission is to deploy undetected into combat and hostile environments to establish assault zones or airfields, while simultaneously conducting air traffic control, fire support, command and control, direct action, counter-terrorism, foreign internal defense, humanitarian assistance and special reconnaissance.</blockquote><figure><div><div><p><img src="https://publish.narco.news/content/images/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-19-at-1.07.40-PM-2.png" width="1008" height="1302"></p></div></div><figcaption><em><a href="https://www.socom.mil/TipOfTheSpear/June%202004%20Tip%20of%20the%20Spear.pdf">U.S. SOCOM</a></em></figcaption></figure><p>In August of 2019, Tim Thacker of Raeford, NC was sentenced to 40 years for his role in a large-scale, multi-state <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-ednc/pr/hoke-county-man-sentenced-forty-years-drug-distribution">methamphetamine distribution</a> conspiracy going back over a decade, which he ran out of the municipal airport, P K Airpark-5w4, owned by the Thacker family, the same airport implicated in a massive cocaine trafficking conspiracy in 1984. His father, Gene Paul Thacker, a former Green Beret and Vietnam War veteran, was acquitted essentially on the basis of his character despite "overwhelming" evidence implicating him, <a href="https://www.sun-sentinel.com/news/fl-xpm-1985-05-31-8501210917-story.html">according</a> to the prosecutor.</p><figure><div><div><p><img src="https://publish.narco.news/content/images/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-19-at-3.13.26-PM.png" width="1234" height="700"></p><p><img src="https://publish.narco.news/content/images/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-19-at-3.12.41-PM.png" width="1234" height="700"></p></div></div><figcaption>Google Maps</figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://publish.narco.news/content/images/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-19-at-1.30.33-PM-3.png"></figure><p>On the <a href="https://www.dropzone.com/forums/topic/184982-it's-my-last-day-at-work---and-i-am-not-sad!/">Dropzone forum</a>, when asked about his plans after retirement from the Air Force, Tim mentioned that he would continue fighting the global war on terror with his old unit as a contractor.</p><figure><div><div><p><img src="https://publish.narco.news/content/images/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-19-at-3.25.33-PM.png" width="1082" height="554"></p></div></div><figcaption><em><a href="https://www.dropzone.com/forums/topic/184982-it's-my-last-day-at-work---and-i-am-not-sad!/">Dropzone</a></em></figcaption></figure><figure><div><div><p><img src="https://publish.narco.news/content/images/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-20-at-2.27.46-PM-1.png" width="1056" height="1100"></p><p><img src="https://publish.narco.news/content/images/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-16-at-4.59.19-PM-5.png" width="488" height="606"></p></div><div><p><img src="https://publish.narco.news/content/images/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-20-at-2.44.08-PM.png" width="632" height="662"></p></div><div><p><img src="https://publish.narco.news/content/images/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-20-at-2.41.42-PM.png" width="822" height="746"></p></div></div><figcaption><em><a href="https://www.facebook.com/PoliceWarsaw/posts/yesterday-may-11-2016-officers-with-the-warsaw-police-department-responded-to-a-/960425930732138/">Facebook</a> ;</em><a href="http://www.omniskore.com/comp/2003/nats/teams_pics/702.htm"><em>Omniskore</em></a><em>; </em><a href="https://www.dropzone.com/forums/topic/222999-weekend-raeford-pics/?tab=comments#comment-439487"><em>Dropzone</em></a></figcaption></figure></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://narco.news/meth-kingpin-was-director-of-operations-for-combat-controller-school</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26198555</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 21:57:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Stompenberg FX: Testing guitar effects pedal remotely]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 13 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26197848">thread link</a>) | @xavieralexandre
<br/>
February 19, 2021 | https://www.thomann.de/blog/en/stompenberg-effects/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.thomann.de/blog/en/stompenberg-effects/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h3>The idea</h3><p><strong>Stompenberg.</strong> Sounds like a brand of Swedish outdoor clothing, but also like a villain in the next James Bond film – but in this case it’s actually a mash-up of two things. Stompenberg is the hybrid of <strong>“stomp boxes”</strong> and <strong>“Heisenberg”,</strong> which made the impossible possible after a long time of <strong>screwing</strong> and <strong>soldering.</strong>&nbsp;It’s a Thomann <strong>online app</strong> that allows musicians to<strong> test out real effect pedals</strong> with their own equipment, either <strong>from home</strong> or <strong>on the go</strong>. Below you will get a brief idea of the concept, development and implementation and of what <strong>Stompenberg</strong>&nbsp;is capable of… 💥🎶</p><hr><h3>Growing pains</h3><h4><strong>Planning&nbsp;</strong></h4><p>The <a href="https://www.thomann.de/gb/stompenberg_devices.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>selected pedals</strong></a> travel to the<strong> Thomann partner laboratory</strong> in <strong>Erlangen, Germany</strong> where they undergo some <strong>operations</strong> and <b>transformations&nbsp;</b>by our men in white with the <strong>license to solder.</strong></p><p>The following happens: A pedal is first deprived of its <strong>shell</strong>, <strong>pots</strong> and <strong>switches.</strong> The pots are measured to see what they do (whether they are <strong>linear, logarithmic,</strong> etc.) and replaced with <strong>digital pots</strong> and <strong>switches.</strong></p><p>Then, for reasons of shielding, the original <strong>housing</strong> is put back on. Everything is recognisable as a pedal again, but now, instead of pots and switches, <strong>ribbon cables</strong> hang from the orphaned holes.</p><h4><strong>The construction</strong></h4><p>This ever-growing Frankenstein is mounted on a <strong>rack drawer,</strong> which houses not only the <strong>power supply</strong> but also a <strong>mini-computer</strong> specially developed for this purpose, per pedal.</p><p><strong>Ribbon cable</strong> runs to the computer, audio cable into the pedal, everything is beautifully adjusted and balanced and then off to the rack!</p><p><img src="https://www.thomann.de/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/1-1-300x200.jpg"></p><p><img src="https://www.thomann.de/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/2-1-300x200.jpg"></p><p><img src="https://www.thomann.de/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/4-300x200.jpg"></p><p><img src="https://www.thomann.de/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/3-1-300x200.jpg"></p><hr><h3>Connection to the shop</h3><h4><strong>The longest guitar cable in the world…</strong></h4><p>… is available from <strong>Thomann</strong> in the <strong>shop,</strong> but not from <strong><a href="https://www.thomann.de/gb/stompenberg_devices.html">Stompenberg</a>.</strong> From now on the <strong>soldering iron</strong> gets put away and is replaced by a <strong>PC</strong> and <strong>keyboard</strong> in Thomann’s Treppendorf. This is where our <strong>developers</strong> and <strong>designers</strong> sit, brooding over the visualization of the pedals and the interface that allows the pedals to be operated from anywhere in the world. From the logo to the controls to each button, everything comes from Thomann’s teamwork.</p><p>When you turn the <strong>virtual knob</strong> at home, the <strong>digital knob</strong> on the pedal in the Thomann lab is adjusted via this interface, while your sound runs through exactly this pedal and comes back to you with effect. There are<strong> 3</strong> <strong>modes</strong> and a lot of <strong>UI tricks</strong> to discover.</p><p><img src="https://www.thomann.de/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/lava-150x150.jpg" width="275">&nbsp; <img src="https://www.thomann.de/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/6-1024x682.jpg" width="412"></p><hr><h2><strong>The Interface</strong></h2><h4><strong>The effect device</strong></h4><p>Design and development flow together here with loving attention to detail: Every <strong>knob</strong> can be rotated, every <strong>footswitch</strong> can be stepped on and every <strong>lever</strong> is slidable. This replica <strong>behaves exactly like the real pedal</strong> in the lab, right down to the smallest <strong>LED,</strong> and can therefore be operated in exactly the same way.</p><h4><strong>The three modes: PLAY, REC &amp; LIVE</strong></h4><p><strong>PLAY:</strong> You feed <strong>pre-recorded samples</strong> or specially <strong>uploaded sounds</strong> through the pedals and operate the controls with <strong>both hands</strong> (if using a <strong>touchscreen)</strong> while the sound loops through the effect pedal.</p><p><strong>REC:</strong> If you want to go a step beyond, you can <strong>record your own riffs</strong> and loop them through the pedal of your choice!</p><p><strong>LIVE:</strong> The ultimate experience – here you <strong>play live</strong> and get the result back directly from the Thomann lab. So you can try out the pedal, live, from the comfort of your bedroom, with just a small <strong>latency,</strong> but that’s not bad considering the signal travels virtually at the speed of light&nbsp;through the<strong> whole of Germany or even the whole of Europe.&nbsp;</strong></p><p>The bright side: Even if your pedal is busy and you end up in the waiting queue, you don’t have to listen to the dude in front of you butchering a cover of Stairway To Heaven 😉</p><h4><strong>And the rest of my equipment?</strong></h4><p>If you want to know exactly how the distortion in front of your own amp is done, you might need a <strong>reamping box.</strong> But under certain circumstances the line output of the interface does the trick too, just turned down low. The result reads like a poem:</p><p>You play your own guitar</p><p>through a real pedal (which is somewhere else)</p><p>through your amp</p><p>through your cabinet or speakers</p><p>at the volume you want</p><p>and you can turn, shift and control all the knobs as you like.</p><p>… and get a pretty accurate picture if this pedal will be your new one or if you prefer another one (which you tested with Stompenberg). No need to drive to Treppendorf, to send cardboard boxes back to Thomann halfway around the world, or to listen to annoying comments from the people waiting in line.</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.thomann.de/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/8-1.jpg" alt="" width="1400" height="626" srcset="https://www.thomann.de/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/8-1.jpg 1400w, https://www.thomann.de/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/8-1-565x253.jpg 565w, https://www.thomann.de/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/8-1-300x134.jpg 300w, https://www.thomann.de/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/8-1-768x343.jpg 768w, https://www.thomann.de/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/8-1-1024x458.jpg 1024w, https://www.thomann.de/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/8-1-215x96.jpg 215w" sizes="(max-width: 1400px) 100vw, 1400px"></p><hr><h3><strong>The Future</strong></h3><p>The conversion is in full swing and while <strong>Stompenberg</strong> is running, our partners in <strong>Erlangen</strong> are taking more pedals apart every day to make them digitally accessible. There is plenty of room for <strong>growth</strong> – ultimately, your <strong>demand</strong> determines the <strong>supply</strong> of pedals. So let’s go, the smiles of satisfied guitarists are what keep us motivated!</p><p>Your Thomann R&amp;D Team</p><hr><h2><a href="https://www.thomann.de/gb/stompenberg_devices.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Get stompin’ at Stompenberg now</a>!</h2><p>Our<strong> YouTube</strong> host <strong>Felix Fleer</strong> took a closer look at Stompberg. Enjoy the <strong>video</strong> and try out the tool yourself!</p><p><span><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/1lBYRQUTzYk?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;fs=1&amp;hl=en-GB&amp;autohide=2&amp;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></span></p><div><p><img alt="Author’s gravatar" src="https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/c9e90005014b2194675c8a066705c293?s=90&amp;d=blank&amp;r=g" srcset="https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/c9e90005014b2194675c8a066705c293?s=180&amp;d=blank&amp;r=g 2x" height="90" width="90" loading="lazy"></p><p> Joe has been singing since he can remember and started playing guitar when he was 10. He's been using it as a songwriting tool ever since. He is passionate about melody and harmony and admires musicians who create these in unique ways. Check out his alternative / indie projects Best of Feelings and Zef Raček.</p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.thomann.de/blog/en/stompenberg-effects/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26197848</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 20:46:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Koo, India’s free-speech Twitter alternative]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 97 | Comments 168 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26196588">thread link</a>) | @donohoe
<br/>
February 19, 2021 | https://restofworld.org/2021/how-koo-became-a-right-wing-darling-in-india/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://restofworld.org/2021/how-koo-became-a-right-wing-darling-in-india/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			<!-- Article Start -->
			
<p>It hasn’t been a quiet few weeks on Twitter in India. The country’s capital city has seen over four months of protest after Prime Minister Narendra Modi’s government enacted agricultural laws that would adversely affect farmers across India. <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-india-55899754">The farmer protests</a>, as the movement has come to be known, has taken to social media platforms like Twitter and Facebook to make the cause heard globally — and it’s worked. Earlier this month, celebrities like <a href="https://www.dw.com/en/greta-thunberg-under-fire-for-tweeting-about-indian-farmers-toolkit/a-56458306">Greta Thunberg</a> and <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-india-55931894">Rihanna</a> weighed in with their tweets of support. Backlash <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-india-55931894">soon followed</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the government’s ire against global critics of Modi’s Hindu nationalist party has turned to Twitter itself. Citing threats to public order, on February 1, Indian authorities <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/pranavdixit/indian-government-block-critics">appeared to have requested Twitter to suspend or remove</a> dozens of accounts on its platform. Twitter briefly complied but, after public outcry, reinstated the accounts and then <a href="https://www.cjr.org/the_media_today/twitter-stands-up-to-india-and-refuses-to-block-journalists.php">refused to remove</a> hundreds more.</p>



<p>It’s in the middle of this battle that Aprameya Radhakrishna’s 10-month-old social media platform was thrust into the spotlight. Soft-spoken and studious, Radhakrishna is a serial entrepreneur: in 2015, <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/magazines/panache/taxiforsure-founder-aprameya-radhakrishnas-life-after-sell-off/articleshow/48078627.cms">he sold his first company</a>, a ride-sharing app called TaxiForSure, to local giant Ola for $200 million. His latest venture is an app called Koo, <a href="https://www.kooapp.com/">a microblogging platform similar to Twitter</a> but for local-language speakers in India, a country with more than 20 languages and over 700 dialects.&nbsp;</p>



<p>After weeks of battling with Twitter, some of India’s most prominent Hindu nationalist politicians took to their social accounts and instructed their followers to leave Western social networks for Koo, a local, free-speech platform. “I am now on Koo,” <a href="https://twitter.com/PiyushGoyal/status/1359058583934013442">tweeted</a> India’s minister of commerce and industry, Piyush Goyal. “Connect with me on this Indian micro-blogging platform for real-time, exciting and exclusive updates.” Many of his <a href="https://twitter.com/PiyushGoyal">9.6 million followers</a> obliged. More right-wing politicians <a href="https://twitter.com/rsprasad/status/1360067772571545606?s=20">followed suit</a>, as did some of <a href="https://twitter.com/KanganaTeam/status/1361421114220576768">Bollywood</a>’s biggest stars.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Overnight, the platform went from a relatively obscure app to <a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/koo-lines-up-indian-investors-as-popularity-surges/articleshow/80867206.cms">headline news</a> and bagged <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/tech/funding/microblogging-platform-koo-bags-4-1-million-in-funding/articleshow/80685024.cms">$4.1 million in series A funding</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Radhakrishna and his platform are in a curious position. The founder insists he’s apolitical — he’s appeared in both <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/video/news/news/koo-app-everything-you-need-to-know-about-koo-the-indian-alternative-to-twitter-575160">left-leaning</a> and <a href="https://www.opindia.com/2021/02/rahul-roushan-aprameya-radhakrishna-koo-co-founder-twitter-alternative-made-in-india-interview/">right-wing</a> outlets in the days since Koo has found the limelight — but is happily embracing the sudden rush to his app: Koo crossed <a href="https://www.livemint.com/technology/apps/koo-sees-10-fold-increase-in-downloads-this-week-crosses-3-million-users-11613038170243.html">3 million users </a>this month, fueled in large part by Modi’s party.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And while it’s unclear whether Koo will follow in the path of other social platforms <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/tech/2020/11/11/parler-mewe-gab-social-media-trump-election-facebook-twitter/6232351002/">that espouse “free speech” ideology</a>, it’s likely more Indian apps like Radhakrishna’s will follow. Prominent among Modi’s mantras for his vision of India is <em>Atmanirbhar Bharat: </em>a self-sufficient India. That vision <a href="https://restofworld.org/2021/indias-hashtag-war/">extends to the internet and social media</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Six months before prominent right-wing politicians began heralding his app as India’s Twitter, Radhakrishna and his team submitted Koo to a government <em>atmanirbhar </em>social media challenge, <a href="https://navbharattimes.indiatimes.com/business/business-news/koo-app-wins-pm-modi-aatm-nirbhar-app-innovation-challenge/articleshow/77432196.cms">and won</a>.</p>



<p>Radhakrishna spoke to <em>Rest Of World </em>over Google Meet from Bangalore. This conversation has been edited for length and clarity.</p>



<hr>



<h4><strong>Tell me a bit about how you came up with the idea for Koo.&nbsp;</strong></h4>



<p>We started building it in November 2019 and launched it in March 2020. The idea behind it was that Twitter is existing in English in India, but the language speakers of India are not on Twitter. Let’s build a deeper experience for the language speakers. And because we built a deeper experience for the language speakers, we were able to make a very localized community.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We started with Kannada, then we did Hindi, then Telugu, Marathi, then Tamil: we launched all of these languages. Then, we started noticing Twitter was getting into trouble in the U.S. We said, Maybe we should just have English as well as the local languages, if ever Twitter gets into trouble or users want a separate option.&nbsp;</p>


		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/IMG-20210218-WA0009-1-40x71.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/IMG-20210218-WA0009-1-600x1066.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/IMG-20210218-WA0009-1-400x711.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/IMG-20210218-WA0009-1-600x1067.jpg 600w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 300px" alt="Aprameya Radhakrishna, a serial entrepreneur sold his first company, a ride-sharing app called TaxiForSure, for $200 million.">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				<span itemprop="copyrightHolder">Aprameya Radhakrishna</span>
			</figcaption>
		</figure>


<h4><strong>When you started Koo, how soon were you approached by government officials who saw the </strong><a href="http://www.makeinindia.com/about"><strong>“Make in India”</strong></a><strong> potential for the app?&nbsp;</strong></h4>



<p>We were a two-month-old app when we applied to the <a href="https://innovate.mygov.in/app-challenge/">[<em>Atmanibhar Bharat</em>]</a> challenge. We got into that challenge at the last minute, almost. Nobody approached us or anything. We applied just like any other startup — there were something like 7,000 social media startups that applied. We won that challenge, so that put us into the limelight: Oh, there’s an alternative microblogging platform that promotes local language<em>.&nbsp;</em></p>



<h4><strong>Walk me through how the last two or three weeks have been for you. Did you know that Piyush Goyal and the Ministry of Electronics and Technology would be encouraging their followers on Twitter to move to Koo en masse?&nbsp;</strong></h4>



<p>No. It’s been totally surreal for us. It’s totally welcome at Koo. We as a company are benefiting from the love that users who are shifting [from Twitter] are showing us. We weren’t expecting it, but it’s a pleasant surprise. We’re happy this move is happening.&nbsp;</p>



<h4><strong>Were you prepared for the sudden influx of users on the back end?&nbsp;</strong></h4>



<p>Not at all. Scaling 10x suddenly, in a week, is a challenge for any company, especially a 10-month-old startup. But we’ve come through it; we are able to scale faster.&nbsp;</p>



<h4><strong>What were the user numbers like? Can you tell me how quickly they grew after the events of this month?&nbsp;</strong></h4>



<p>We were very small, we were sub-100,000 DAU [daily active users]. Now we’re close to a million DAU. Close, not a million yet but close.&nbsp;</p>



<h4><strong>By virtue of chance, or deliberate action, there’s an ideological framework under which Koo has been positioned. You don’t seem bothered by the fact that Koo is heralded </strong><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-india-56037901"><strong>as the right-wing’s answer to Twitter</strong></a><strong>. Politics has played a role in the sudden attention that Koo has received. Have you considered the risks of embracing the way your app has been politicized?&nbsp;</strong></h4>



<p>It depends on the actions on the app. That first community [we built] in Kannada was built in a slower manner, and it has people from all parties in Karnataka.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we are seeing is that India wants to be more self-reliant. India includes everybody. Our app doesn’t understand “left” or “right.” <em>I </em>don’t understand “left” or “right.” I’m an entrepreneur; I’m extremely apolitical. And I’m all for the development of the country. If Koo as a statement can make us self-reliant on our own social networks and technology, then we should be cheering for it. We shouldn’t unnecessarily politicize it.</p>



<h4><strong>Social media is shaped by its users and early adopters. Most of Koo’s early video content partnerships with, say, Republic TV [a channel </strong><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2020/dec/23/indian-news-channel-fined-in-uk-for-hate-speech-about-pakistan"><strong>notorious for its allegiance</strong></a><strong> with the ruling Hindu nationalist party] or Mitron [a short-form video app that Modi supporters </strong><a href="https://www.techradar.com/news/mitron-app-gives-tiktok-a-challenge-will-it-sustain-though"><strong>have embraced after the ban on TikTok</strong></a><strong>] have come to associate the app with a particular ideology. Are you worried Koo might get too polarized too quickly?&nbsp;</strong></h4>



<p>Not at all. In Karnataka, we have everybody [on Koo], as I said. As a business, we keep looking for partners to grow our business. Now, the partners who come aggressively and see the vision that we’re seeing as a free-expression platform and embrace the platform, we’re happy to welcome them. Why would I say no to somebody who wants to use our platform? Republic [TV] came first, that doesn’t mean I don’t want everybody else.&nbsp;</p>


    <figure>
      <div>
				<ul>
					<li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KooPhone1-40x67.png" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KooPhone1-600x1066.png" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KooPhone1-400x667.png 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KooPhone1-600x1000.png 600w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li><li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KooPhone3-40x67.png" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KooPhone3-600x1066.png" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KooPhone3-400x667.png 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KooPhone3-600x1000.png 600w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li><li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KooPhone4-40x67.png" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KooPhone4-600x1066.png" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KooPhone4-400x667.png 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KooPhone4-600x1000.png 600w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li><li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KooPhone2-40x67.png" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KooPhone2-600x1066.png" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KooPhone2-400x667.png 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KooPhone2-600x1000.png 600w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li>
				</ul>
			</div>
      <figcaption>On Koo’s Hindi language setting, it’s easy to find the accounts of several of India’s biggest Hindu nationalist politicians next to celebrities and right-leaning media channels. The majority of the app’s top trending hashtags in Hindi are pro-Modi.</figcaption>
    </figure>


<h4><strong>In a recent BBC report about your app, there’s a rhetorical question, </strong><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-india-56037901"><strong>“Is Koo India’s Parler?”</strong></a><strong> What do you make of that comparison?&nbsp;</strong></h4>



<p>Each platform comes into being for different reasons. I’ve already explained my story. We were doing this irrespective of whether Twitter existed, got banned, got into trouble, or flourished in India.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We started in November 2019 because we said the voice of the Indian user who doesn’t speak English is not there. We are building an inclusive social media network for India. So what was your question?&nbsp;</p>



<h4><strong>My question was what do you make of Parler and—</strong></h4>



<p>Parler came into existence because there was an anti-Trump thing, and they wanted to do a pro-Trump thing. We don’t exist because of some anti or pro thing. We are existing today irrespective of whether Twitter gets into trouble or not, irrespective of one ideology being there or not. We exist because we want to give a voice to every Indian. The purpose of our existence is very different from what a Parler is.&nbsp;</p>



<h4><strong>What do you make of the “Make in India” push, considering Facebook and Twitter have </strong><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/14/technology/trump-facebook-twitter.html"><strong>an undeniable influence</strong></a><strong> in our current political discourse?</strong></h4>



<p>Every social media [platform] has to be responsible, to a certain extent, of what they bring into a country because it defines a lot of things in the country, like youth culture or how citizens of a country react to a situation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When a company is registered elsewhere and doesn’t take into consideration the nuances of the local culture, I think it can be dangerous. Indian entrepreneurs building for Indian cultural nuances is better than somebody who doesn’t understand the cultural nuances trying to build for India.</p>



<figure><blockquote><p>“Indian entrepreneurs building for Indian cultural nuances is better than somebody who doesn’t understand the cultural nuances trying to build for India.”</p></blockquote></figure>



<h4><strong>The way Indian internet is shaping, </strong><a href="https://restofworld.org/2021/indias-hashtag-war/"><strong>an extreme version of “Indian apps for India”</strong></a><strong> is an entire separate internet for India, the way China has Weibo and its own social network. Do you think that kind of internet would be a good thing for India as a whole?&nbsp;</strong></h4>



<p>Absolutely, we should have our own <em>atmanirbhar</em> platforms. We …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://restofworld.org/2021/how-koo-became-a-right-wing-darling-in-india/">https://restofworld.org/2021/how-koo-became-a-right-wing-darling-in-india/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://restofworld.org/2021/how-koo-became-a-right-wing-darling-in-india/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26196588</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 18:58:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Cleaner parallel curves with Euler spirals]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 124 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26196470">thread link</a>) | @raphlinus
<br/>
February 19, 2021 | https://raphlinus.github.io/curves/2021/02/19/parallel-curves.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://raphlinus.github.io/curves/2021/02/19/parallel-curves.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <!-- I should figure out a cleaner way to do this include, rather than cutting and pasting. Ah well.-->




<p><img src="https://raphlinus.github.io/assets/euler-parallel-flower.svg" alt="Many parallel curve of an Euler spiral, resembling a flower"></p>

<p>Determining <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parallel_curve">parallel curves</a> is one of the basic 2D geometry operations. It has obvious applications in graphics, being the basis of creating a stroke outline from a path, but also in computer aided manufacturing (determining the path of a milling tool with finite radius) and path planning for robotics. There are plenty of solutions in the literature by now, but in this post I propose a cleaner solution.</p>

<p>A good survey paper is <a href="https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/Comparing-Offset-Curve-Approximation-Methods-Elber-Lee/9ac1978746ec54bdd555b906e2ea1eb922cd6ffd">Comparing Offset Curve Approximation Methods</a>. The main difference between these approaches is the choice of curve representation. An example of a curve representation highly specialized for deriving parallel curves is the <a href="https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/Pythagorean-hodographs-Farouki-Sakkalis/e20aeb60de908061797b6eaf3af79fdc7e5acdd7">Pythagorean Hodograph</a>. This parallel curve of a Pythagorean Hodograph is an exact parametric polynomial curve, but approximation techniques are still needed in practice, both to convert the source curve into the representation, and because the resulting curves are higher order rational polynomials, which require further approximation to convert into, say, cubic Béziers.</p>

<p>Specifically, this blog proposes piecewise Euler spirals as a curve representation particularly well suited to the parallel curve problem.</p>

<p>There’s an implementation of many of these ideas (currently still in PR stage) in <a href="https://github.com/linebender/kurbo/pull/169">kurbo</a>. I also used a colab notebook to explore a bunch of the math, and I’ve made a <a href="https://github.com/raphlinus/raphlinus.github.io/blob/master/assets/Euler_spiral_scratchpad.ipynb">copy of that available</a> as well.</p>

<h2 id="the-cusp">The cusp</h2>

<p>One of the things that makes parallel curves special is that cusps often appear. In particular, a cusp appears whenever the radius of curvature of the source curve matches the offset. This is classified as an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cusp_(singularity)">ordinary cusp</a> and is a feature of many curve families – we’ll quantify that a bit more below.</p>

<p><img src="https://raphlinus.github.io/assets/euler-parallel-cusp.svg" alt="Parallel curve of an Euler spiral, showing the cusp"></p>

<p>A common feature of algorithms for computing parallel curves is identifying the location of the cusp, and subdividing there. That basically means solving for the specific value of curvature (the reciprocal of the offset distance). If the source curve is a cubic Bézier, there can be up to four such cusps, and finding them requires some nontrivial numerical solving.</p>

<h2 id="curvature-as-a-function-of-arclength">Curvature as a function of arclength</h2>

<p>A theme of my approach to parallel curves (and much of my curve work in general, including my <a href="https://www.levien.com/phd/phd.html">thesis</a>), is to consider the relationship of curvature to arclength. A concrete intuition is that it is the position of the steering wheel as a car drives along the curve at constant speed. For some curves, curvature can be represented as a closed-form analytical formula as a function of arclength (the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ces%C3%A0ro_equation">Cesàro equation</a>), but in general determining the relation requires numerical techniques. For example, in the <a href="https://levien.com/euler_explorer/">Euler explorer</a>, there’s a plot of curvature as a function of arclength below the interactive cubic Bézier. Experimenting with that is an excellent way to develop intuition.</p>

<p>One curve that <em>does</em> have an especially simple Cesàro equation is the Euler spiral. An Euler spiral segment has this formula:</p><p>

\[\kappa(s) = \kappa_0 + \kappa_1 s\]

</p><p>(A note for those trying to follow along with the detailed math and code: most of the math and numerical code uses $-0.5 \leq s \leq 0.5$ because it helps exploit even/odd symmetries, but the convention for parametrized curves, including the <a href="https://docs.rs/kurbo/0.8.0/kurbo/trait.ParamCurve.html">ParamCurve</a> trait in kurbo, is $0 \leq s \leq 1$. Thus, you’ll frequently see offsets of 0.5. Similarly, you’ll see various scaling to the actual arc length, while the parametrized curve convention assumes an arc length of 1. In this blog, we’ll skim over such details, as the goal is to provide intuition without too much clutter from details.)</p>

<h2 id="the-parallel-curve-of-an-euler-spiral">The parallel curve of an Euler spiral</h2>

<p>In general, most curves do not have a simple formula for their parallel curve. The obvious exception is a circular arc, for which the parallel curve is another circular arc. Another curve family with tractable representation for its parallel curve is Pythagorean Hodographs.</p>

<p>Thanks to its exceptionally simple formulation as a Cesàro equation, the Euler spiral is one of the rare curves with a simple closed-form equation for its parallel curve. That equation was first published in a 1906 paper by Heinrich Wieleitner, <a href="https://books.google.com/books?id=UvpZAAAAYAAJ&amp;pg=PA373&amp;lpg=PA373&amp;dq=%22Die+Parallelkurve+der+Klothoide%22&amp;source=bl&amp;ots=fuY39VdPpd&amp;sig=K0AbL03rXAm_g4J9KsheQbbxyaA&amp;hl=en&amp;sa=X&amp;ved=2ahUKEwiUrcD1poTfAhVvFjQIHVthBPoQ6AEwAnoECAMQAQ#v=onepage&amp;q=%22Die%20Parallelkurve%20der%20Klothoide%22&amp;f=false">Die Parallelkurve der Klothoide</a>. For those who don’t read German, <a href="https://github.com/Rahix">Rahix</a> has kindly provided a translation into English: <a href="https://raphlinus.github.io/assets/clothoids.pdf">PDF</a>, <a href="https://raphlinus.github.io/assets/clothoids.text">TeX source</a>.</p>

<p>Going over this math, I see Wieleitner missed an opportunity for further simplification. The style at the time was to write the Cesàro equation in terms of the <em>radius</em> of curvature (the reciprocal of curvature), but especially for the Euler spiral and its parallel curve, using curvature directly yields a much simpler equation. With the cusp located at $s_0$, the equation is gratifyingly simple:</p><p>

\[\kappa(s) = \frac{c}{\sqrt{s - s_0}} + \frac{1}{l}\]

</p><p>The equation is graphed below, and clicking on it links to a <a href="https://www.desmos.com/calculator/qznzk9xnac">Desmos calculator graph</a> with sliders for the parameters.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.desmos.com/calculator/qznzk9xnac"><img src="https://raphlinus.github.io/assets/euler-spiral-parallel-cesaro.png" width="400" height="400"></a></p>

<p>Here $c$ is a coefficient dependent on the parameters of the spiral. To connect it to the notation in the Wieleitner paper, $c = a / \sqrt{2 l^3}$, and $s_0 = -a^2/{2l}$. I’ve also made a <a href="https://www.desmos.com/calculator/imvqywsb8o">Desmos calculator graph</a> that interactively demonstrates the equivalence of this equation and the more involved one from the Wieleitner paper.</p>

<p>There are a number of other curves that have a cusp similar to the above, with characteristic inverse-square root curvature. The clearest connection is the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Involute">circle involute</a>, which is the same but without the $1/l$ term, or in other words the Euler spiral parallel curve approaches the circle involute as the offset goes to infinity. This provides intuition for the fact that a circle involute is its own parallel curve. The circle involute is perhaps most famous as the optimized profile for meshing <a href="https://ciechanow.ski/gears/">gear</a> teeth, transferring force smoothly with no slop or friction.</p>

<p>Other curves with a similar cusp include the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cycloid">cycloid</a> (as well as its many variants including epicycloid, hypocycloid, astroid, deltoid, cardioid, and nephroid), as well as the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semicubical_parabola">semicubical parabola</a>. The latter is of particular interest because it can be exactly represented as a case of a cubic Bézier (it is when the control arms form a symmetrical X).</p>

<p><img src="https://raphlinus.github.io/assets/semicubical_parabola.svg" alt="semicubical parabola"></p>

<p>The parallel curve of the Euler spiral is perfectly cromulent, and, following the tradition of Pythagorean Hodograph curves and their higher-order rational polynomials, we could simply require everything downstream to simply deal with them. But to make that downstream processing easier, we will convert back to piecewise Euler spirals, a more tractable representation.</p>

<h2 id="geometric-hermite-interpolation">Geometric Hermite interpolation</h2>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hermite_interpolation">Hermite interpolation</a> is a well known technique. In its simplest form, it is used to generate a piecewise polynomial approximation to some function, where the parameters for each polynomial segment are determined from the values and derivatives of the endpoints. For example, in cubic Hermite interpolation, a cubic polynomial is determined from the values and first derivatives at the endpoints – four values, corresponding to four coefficients for the polynomial. The result is C1 continuous as the derivatives exactly match (and are equal to the source curve).</p>

<p>In 2D, there is a distinction between C1 and G1 (geometric) continuity. In C1 continuity, the full derivatives must match, both direction and magnitude. For applications such as animating motion curves, the magnitude is important (it represents speed of motion), but for curves, it is not. G1 continuity requires that the tangents match, but does not specify the magnitude of the derivatives.</p>

<p>In these applications, geometric Hermite interpolation is more efficient, as all parameters of the curve are available to make the shape fit. The Euler spiral is especially well suited to geometric Hermite interpolation, and there is literature on this topic. For reasonable assumptions of smoothness (excluding fractal curves but including simple cusps), the accuracy scales as $O(n^4)$ – a doubling of the number of subdivisions reduces the error by a factor of 16. This scaling is the same as cubic Hermite interpolation of a 1D function, not surprising as an Euler spiral segment approximates a cubic polynomial when $y$ values are small.</p>

<p>Section 8.2 of my <a href="https://www.levien.com/phd/phd.html">thesis</a> provides a secant method for determining the Euler spiral parameters from the G1 Hermite constraints, and that’s implemented in the <code>fit_euler</code> method in the <a href="https://github.com/linebender/kurbo/pull/169">kurbo PR</a>. That’s a good technique and its convergence is excellent (quadratic, as typical for Newton-style solvers for near-linear problems), but I’ve also been experimenting with ways to do it better. The linked notebook explores a polynomial approximation (based on 2D Taylor’s series) that is much faster – 7ns vs 240ns in my measurements, and should be very accurate over a wide range of parameters. I’m not quite done making the error bounds rigorous, but this approach should help make the overall algorithm lightning-fast.</p>

<p>Geometric Hermite interpolation works well to approximate the parallel curve of an Euler spiral segment with another Euler spiral segment:</p>

<p><img src="https://raphlinus.github.io/assets/euler-parallel-approx.svg" alt="Approximation of the parallel curve of an Euler spiral segment"></p>

<p>The true parallel curve is in blue, and the approximation in red. It has the same rough shape, but bulges out in the middle. We need to be able to estimate that error in order to make a more accurate approximation.</p>

<h3 id="a-simple-accurate-error-metric">A simple, accurate error metric</h3>

<p>The most common approach to approximation given a target error bound is adaptive subdivision: approximate the error, and if it exceeds the target, subdivide. Evaluating the error is not always easy; most generally, it’s based on numerical techniques such as evaluating the curve at several points along its length and testing how near those points lie to the source curve.</p>

<p>Fortunately, for approximating an Euler spiral parallel curve using an Euler spiral, there is an extremely simple formula for the error. In fact, it’s possible to avoid the adaptive subdivision altogether, and precisely predict how many subdivisions are needed to meet an error bound, as well as analytically place the subdivisions so each segment has the same error.</p>

<p>Normalized to a chord length of 1, where the arc …</p></div></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://raphlinus.github.io/curves/2021/02/19/parallel-curves.html">https://raphlinus.github.io/curves/2021/02/19/parallel-curves.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://raphlinus.github.io/curves/2021/02/19/parallel-curves.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26196470</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 18:49:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Researchers looking for mRNA were ridiculed by colleagues]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 292 | Comments 99 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26196372">thread link</a>) | @fortran77
<br/>
February 19, 2021 | https://www.macleans.ca/society/science/scientists-mrna-covid-vaccines/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.macleans.ca/society/science/scientists-mrna-covid-vaccines/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Sixty years ago, the scientists who were pioneering the technology that would make today's COVID-19 vaccines possible were mocked and dismissed</p><div>
																		<p>A few days before Christmas, Matthew Meselson, a 90-year-old professor at Harvard, called his university’s health service to inquire about being vaccinated against COVID-19. He was eager for his shot. Meselson felt imprisoned in his Cambridge apartment, just blocks from the campus where he’d worked for six decades. He’d officially retired from teaching at the beginning of 2020, but continued his research as much as possible throughout the pandemic, wearing a K95 mask to work in his lab.</p>
<p>He longed to re-engage in the world around him. He missed his weekly date with close friends over lunch at Boston’s best French restaurant; they’d switched to Zoom, but staring into a computer screen is no replacement for lingering at linen-covered tables. He longed for his wife of 32 years, Jeanne Guillemin, who died from cancer late in 2019. Meselson was still figuring out how his world worked without her, and isolation made this hard task harder.</p>
<p>The person on the other end of the phone apologized to the professor. “We don’t have a vaccine schedule yet,” she told him.</p>
<p>The first two COVID-19 vaccines to be approved for use in North America were developed, tested and delivered into freezers before many jurisdictions figured out how to administer them. The vaccines from Pfizer-BioNTech and Moderna are the first approved vaccines ever to employ modified mRNA, which is delivered sealed in a lipid shell. The mRNA slips into our cells, carrying instructions to make antibodies that target SARS-CoV-2. The vaccines function almost like a wanted poster: if you see these guys, get ’em. Then, the mRNA degrades, leaving no trace.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>READ:&nbsp;<a href="https://www.macleans.ca/news/covid-19-vaccines-curbing-pandemic-vaxx-populi/">How quickly will the COVID-19 vaccines start curbing the pandemic in Canada?</a></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>The fact that mRNA is the basis of these vaccines contributed to their rapid development. In November, the <em>New York Times</em> reported that within two days of China releasing the genetic sequence of SARS-CoV-2, scientists at Moderna Inc., a 10-year-old company headquartered not far from Meselson’s home in Cambridge, “plugged that data into its computers and came up with a design for an mRNA vaccine.” Meanwhile, BioNTech, a small biotech company in Germany that had been working on mRNA flu vaccines with the pharmaceutical powerhouse Pfizer, soon similarly turned its resources to generating an mRNA COVID vaccine.</p>
<p>But these fastest vaccines in history have been decades in the making. They’re the product of generations of scientists who built on one idea after another, and kept at it despite failed experiments, rejections, threats of deportation, a lack of funding and skepticism from contemporaries. They were inspired by the discovery of DNA: in 1951, a young English physical chemist named Rosalind Franklin took X-ray photographs that captured DNA’s helical shape; two years later, James Watson and Francis Crick of Cambridge University published the first report describing DNA’s double helix, for which they received the Nobel Prize. (Franklin died of ovarian cancer in 1958; her contributions were largely overlooked in her lifetime.) And they were driven not by a race to halt a raging pathogen or by the chance to patent a multi-billion-dollar drug, but by one big, irresistible question: What makes life?</p>
<p>“These weren’t people who wanted to solve little problems,” says Meselson. “These were people who wanted to solve a great big problem.”</p>
<p>He was one of them.</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>Born in Colorado in 1930, Meselson zipped through the sciences at a young age. By 16, he enrolled at the University of Chicago. In 1957, while doing post-doctoral work at the California Institute of Technology (Caltech), Meselson and Frank Stahl demonstrated how DNA replicates itself, a model that had been suggested but never shown. Science historian Frederic Lawrence Holmes later characterized their work as “the most beautiful experiment in biology,” having revealed how life worked.</p>
<p>But many unanswered questions remained about what happens inside our cells. Meselson and colleagues knew that DNA resides in the nucleus, a compartment barricaded off from the rest of the cell by a membrane. On the other side of the membrane is the cytoplasm, a gelatinous liquid that fills the remainder of the cell. This is the home of tiny granules called ribosomes, which house RNA.</p>
<p>Around the same time that Meselson and Stahl published their groundbreaking work on DNA, French scientists discovered that cells made proteins through the ribosomes. DNA, despite holding the critical codes for life, is a relatively passive molecule. Ribosomes do the busy labour, building proteins to carry out the biological processes of survival. The question was how?</p>
<p>One of the French scientists, Dr. François Jacob, theorized that there must be an “unstable intermediary” that went between the DNA and the RNA—sending messages from the DNA to the RNA, and then disappearing.</p>
<p>Jacob, a physician who’d been forced from medical school when Germany invaded France in 1940 and spent the war years fighting with Charles de Gaulle’s Free French Forces, called this theoretical intermediary “X.” Other researchers “rolled their eyes in horror” when he presented his theory, Jacob recalled in his memoir, <em>The Statue Within</em>. “With a little encouragement, my audience would have jeered and left,” he wrote.</p>
<div id="attachment_1216833"><p><img data-sizes="auto" src="https://www.macleans.ca/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/MATTHEW-MESELSON-DNA-FRANGOU-FEB02-766x431.jpg" alt="Meselson at Caltech in 1958 (Courtesy of the Caltech Archives)" width="766" height="431"></p><p>Meselson at Caltech in 1958 (Courtesy of the Caltech Archives)</p></div>
<p>In spring 1960, Jacob wrote to Meselson with a proposal: he and Sydney Brenner, a South African biologist at the University of Cambridge, would meet at Meselson’s lab at Caltech to find X. Meselson, who was in his first year on faculty, had developed a technique to track smaller molecules inside a cell. Jacob believed this technique would help identify X. That summer, with Jacob and Brenner in his lab, Meselson set up initial cultures and tests. Brenner took over the operations, while Jacob sat in a chair taking notes—pain from bomb fragments in his legs was worsened by the California humidity, says Meselson. For three weeks, they met with one failure after another. The ribosomes kept falling apart. Other scientists poked their heads in periodically and asked sarcastically for news of X. Jacob wrote that they “came to visit as one would visit the zoo.” On the trio’s very last scheduled day in the lab, Meselson, having given up on X, left. He flew to Boston to propose to his first wife.</p>
<p>Dejected, Jacob and Brenner went to Malibu Beach. The duo lay on the beach, watching huge waves of the Pacific crashing onto the sand and contemplating where their idea had gone wrong. Jacob wrote in his memoir: “Suddenly, Sydney gives a hoot. He leaps up, yelling, ‘The magnesium! It’s the magnesium!’ ” They raced back to the lab to run the experiment one last time, with additional magnesium. The result was spectacular. X existed.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>READ:&nbsp;<a href="https://www.macleans.ca/news/theres-a-new-strain-of-covid-19-will-the-vaccines-work-against-it/">There’s a new strain of COVID-19. Will the vaccines work against it?</a></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>The pair gave a seminar the same day at Caltech to demonstrate X. Even then, no one believed them. They contacted Meselson in Boston that night to tell him. He was delighted. “It didn’t occur to me that they would figure out what was going wrong on the very last day,” he says. When the trio published their findings in 1961, they renamed X as messenger RNA.</p>
<p>They did not imagine that their finding would be used for therapeutics or a vaccine. Their questions were more philosophical. Meselson says, “We wondered what is it that allows you to put together the atoms of the ordinary periodic chart and end up with something that’s alive?”</p>
<p>Their work became the central tenet of molecular biology: DNA makes RNA makes protein makes life. It took another generation of scientists to find a way to harness RNA to treat and prevent illness.</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>As a kid in Kisújszállás, Hungary, Katalin Karikó watched her father, a butcher, dismember the carcasses of pigs. It was her first introduction to science. In the 1970s, while studying biochemistry at the University of Szeged, Karikó heard about a new report from London: interferon, a type of protein made by the body to trigger a defence against a virus, was mediated by an RNA called 2-5A. Karikó remembers a mentor talking to her about the discovery and being thrilled by the possibilities. He suggested to her that if they could make a synthetic version of a 2-5A molecule, they might be able to treat cancer or viral disease. “I immediately thought that what I was doing was tremendously important,” she says. It was the start of a 40-year quest to make synthetic RNA that could cure illness.</p>
<p>But she couldn’t secure funding in Hungary. Married with a two-year-old daughter, Karikó saw no way to continue her work in her home country. She wrote to professors throughout Europe about joining their labs, but no one could hire her. In 1985, she received an offer from Temple University in Philadelphia. If she could get to the United States, a job was waiting for her.</p>
<p>At the time, Hungarian money could not legally be converted to another currency and taken out of the country. Worried about how their family would survive until her first paycheque, Karikó and her husband, Bela Francia, sold their Russian-made car and converted the proceeds on the black market for a total of 900 British pounds. They sewed the money into their daughter’s teddy bear to smuggle it out of the country. The teddy bear’s owner, their daughter, Susan Francia, grew up to become a two-time Olympic gold medallist for the United States in rowing.</p>
<div id="attachment_1216834"><p><img data-sizes="auto" src="https://www.macleans.ca/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/KATALIN-KARIKO-MRNA-COVID-19-FRANGOU-FEB02.jpg" alt="Karikó at home in Pennsylvania (Rachel Wisniewski)" width="820" height="547"></p><p>Karikó at home in Pennsylvania (Rachel Wisniewski)</p></div>
<p>In their new home, things did not go as planned. Karikó’s bosses changed, she couldn’t get funding and she lost her job. Her supervisor cited her for deportation. Desperate to stay in the United States as her daughter entered first grade, Karikó accepted a researcher post in Bethesda, Maryland. She commuted from Philadelphia every Monday morning at 3 a.m. and …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.macleans.ca/society/science/scientists-mrna-covid-vaccines/">https://www.macleans.ca/society/science/scientists-mrna-covid-vaccines/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.macleans.ca/society/science/scientists-mrna-covid-vaccines/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26196372</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 18:41:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Nyan Cat on the Blockchain]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 89 | Comments 88 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26196027">thread link</a>) | @awaxman11
<br/>
February 19, 2021 | https://foundation.app/NyanCat/nyan-cat-219 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://foundation.app/NyanCat/nyan-cat-219">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Nyan Cat is the name of an animation uploaded on April 2 2011, and became a viral internet sensation. The design of Nyan Cat was inspired by my cat Marty, who crossed the Rainbow Bridge but lives on in spirit.</p><p>I am the original artist behind the iconic GIF and have remastered the image for its 10 year anniversary.  Owning this piece grants the following stats:</p><p>Charisma +10<br>Luck +10<br>Happiness +15</p><hr><p>1400x1400 - 12 Frames</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://foundation.app/NyanCat/nyan-cat-219</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26196027</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 18:12:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why Hotwire Could be the Future of Front-end Dev]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 13 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26195969">thread link</a>) | @timdl
<br/>
February 19, 2021 | https://wizville.fr/en/blog/a-product-guys-take-on-hotwire-vs-vue-react/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://wizville.fr/en/blog/a-product-guys-take-on-hotwire-vs-vue-react/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
						
							<p><span>I’ve had the chance of talking directly to <a href="https://twitter.com/dhh" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@DHH</a>&nbsp;himself, creator of Ruby on Rails, on the 28th of January, mostly about Hotwire (video at the end of the post). Just writing this, as a product guy who never shipped a line of Ruby in production, still feels completely crazy.&nbsp;</span></p>
<h2><b>How it happened</b></h2>
<p><span>It all started as a joke. At <a href="https://wizville.fr/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WizVille</a>, like most startups, we struggle to hire Fullstack Rails developers that match our (rather high) expectations. Which is a problem when your whole strategy is based on changing the way your customers go about their business through technology and innovation. Especially when you feel like you’ve&nbsp;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/15/wizville-local-monitor-helps-small-shops-track-google-maps-ratings-of-competitors/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cracked it</a> and start having stronger traction than ever, both nationally and internationally, and have had <strong>3 senior Software Engineers positions open for 4 months (see our&nbsp;<a href="https://www.welcometothejungle.com/fr/companies/wizville/jobs/ruby-on-rails-developer-experimente-e-h-f-x_paris">remaining open position</a>)</strong>…&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>So one night, I call Clément, our CTO, and tell him : « Let’s ask DHH to come talk at our first ever WizVille-hosted tech event!». The idea would be to make a powerful statement to the Rails community in France: « WizVille means business, and takes inspiration from the best, you should join us! ».</span></p>
<p><span>Clément laughed and answered, « well, that’s a crazy idea, but he just launched Hotwire and a new version of Turbo today ». I open Hacker News, « <a href="https://hotwire.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hotwire: HMTL over the wire</a> » is the #1 post. I find out about the tech and realize that not only Hotwire is a potential game changer, but also that this is the perfect opportunity.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>It just took one email, I offered to gather as much of the French Rails community as possible for an event during which he could spread the word about Hotwire, and he accepted within 24 hours. I think he did because the email transpired the fact that I was maybe the most determined guy out there to be willing to gather as much of the Rails community for a dedicated event about HW.&nbsp;</span></p>
<h2><b>Not just another front-end framework</b></h2>
<p><span>At first, I thought Hotwire wasn’t meant to take over the front-end development game in David’s mind. But <strong>I was shocked by his answers and the displayed pureness of his ambition</strong> on why he created it and shipped HW for the world to use.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>We all know David for his game changing vision with Rails, and his radical approach to working described in Rework and how it influenced the way the tech world sees work. But Rails was launched at a different time, when you’d think the competing technologies were “rather clearly” retrograde.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>We also know how powerful frameworks like Vue and React are today. </span> <span>So, assuming the potential limitations of Hotwire, since it’s HTML-based, and the incredible contenders there are in the front-end development world (lead by the likes of Facebook, Google…), I never thought David was going to pitch us an upcoming shift in the way apps are created… even though it kinda feels obvious now that he’s described it to me.&nbsp;</span></p>
<h2><b>Why Hotwire could be the future&nbsp;</b></h2>
<ol>
<li aria-level="1"><span>You can learn Hotwire over a week-end according to David. On average it takes about a month or two with React. With V ue, about 2 to 4 weeks.&nbsp;</span></li>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Having to code everything in Javascript on the front-end has never been a free choice</b><span>: it’s always been a choice made out of the absence of alternatives. With HW, app builders won’t have to deal with the complexities of having developers specialized in a completely different technology. And will use the needed technology for the appropriate goal. That will dramatically increase the developer’s satisfaction since he will be able to use his preferred language and also manage most of the spectrum of web app building himself.&nbsp;</span></li>
<li aria-level="1"><span>Hotwire is an independent project from Rails, which means it works with any back end development framework.&nbsp;</span></li>
<li aria-level="1"><span>Hotwire also works on mobile. Out of Hey’s mobile app’s +100 screens, only one of them is built in native languages. There’s also a misconception about Strada (not released at the moment I’m writing this): it will just give developers a more conventionalized approach for interacting with their native apps, but that’s it.&nbsp;</span></li>
<li aria-level="1"><span>Hotwire works for every kind of app, save for apps that really require javascript’s abilities as a technology, and need to work independently in the client (calendars or apps like Figma). That kind of app is a very small fraction, and Hotwire can be combined with a JS framework like React or Vue if needed.&nbsp;</span></li>
</ol>
<p><b>So there you have all the ingredients to replace any front-end framework:</b></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><span>Speed: get your developers up to speed on your front-end framework faster, and therefore potentially ship your product faster</span></li>
<li aria-level="1"><span>Simplicity: easier for back-end developers to do otherwise complex front-end work</span></li>
<li aria-level="1"><span>Coherent technology choice : use complex front-end frameworks only when needed for some features</span></li>
<li aria-level="1"><span>Compatibility : works with all back-end frameworks and all types of web apps</span></li>
</ul>
<h2><b>Main concerns to date&nbsp;</b></h2>
<p><span>The main concerns are mostly related to <strong>how little time it’s been since Hotwire has been released</strong>. This means smaller community and stack overflow threads, and also fewer plugins. The most advanced design framework you could use is <a href="https://tailwindcss.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tailwind</a>, a CSS framework. Which may have us coding our own animations or having to combine with other libraries…? </span><span>Also, having to combine front-end frameworks in some cases, doesn’t feel ideal.</span></p>
<p><span>David told us that Hotwire was up to a much stronger start than Rails, so we could expect to have most of those concerns solved along the road.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><b>But the mere fact that David Heinemier Hansson deeply believes that his personal mission is to liberate developers from the grip of Single-Page-Apps with Hotwire should definitely have everyone’s attention in Tech. And it definitely has ours at WizVille.&nbsp;</b></p>
<h2><b>About the event&nbsp;</b></h2>
<p><span>The event was called « Hotwire &amp; Startups: Dreaming bigger With Rails in 2021 » and you can enjoy David’s 1 hour fireside chat mainly about Hotwire below:&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><iframe width="669" height="376" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GtWc-xo9ZBo?start=4347&amp;feature=oembed&amp;enablejsapi=1&amp;origin=https://wizville.fr" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>We also asked their opinions about Hotwire to <a href="https://twitter.com/sylvainutard?lang=fr">Sylvain Utard</a> (AI General Manager @&nbsp;<a href="http://algolia.com/">Algolia</a>), and Nicolas Denayer (VP Engineering @&nbsp;<a href="http://doctolib.com/">Doctolib</a>) along with our own CTO, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/clement-bruchon-37319545/?originalSubdomain=fr">Clément Bruchon</a>, see the video of the panel here (in French):</p>
<p><iframe width="669" height="376" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GtWc-xo9ZBo?start=296&amp;feature=oembed&amp;enablejsapi=1&amp;origin=https://wizville.fr" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><span>We plan on hosting a 2022 edition of a similar event and are sure to have even more to say on the matter of Hotwire vs React &amp; Vue.&nbsp;</span></p>
<h2><strong>About the author&nbsp;</strong></h2>
<p><a href="http://twitter.com/timdl">Timothée de Laitre</a>&nbsp;is CEO &amp; Head of Product @ <a href="http://wizville.fr/en">WizVille</a>, a 30 people SaaS startup developing a Customer Feedback Platform dedicated to Retail Chains. See our currently open positions <a href="https://www.welcometothejungle.co/companies/wizville/jobs" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here.</a></p>

							</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://wizville.fr/en/blog/a-product-guys-take-on-hotwire-vs-vue-react/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26195969</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 18:07:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Brave Browser leaks your Tor / Onion service requests through DNS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 341 | Comments 84 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26194764">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
February 19, 2021 | https://ramble.pw/f/privacy/2387/brave-browser-leaks-your-tor-onion-service-requests-through | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ramble.pw/f/privacy/2387/brave-browser-leaks-your-tor-onion-service-requests-through">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              <div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Edit: (Since this is gaining traction elsewhere.) I'm not trying to shit on Brave. I'm just wanting to help protect end-users who may use Brave for it's Tor feature to do stuff over Tor that should only be done with the actual Tor browser. If you're using Brave you probably use it because you expect a certain level of privacy/anonymity. Piping .onion requests through DNS where your ISP or DNS provider can see that <em>you</em> made a request for an .onion site defeats that purpose.</p>
<p>I'm also no NetSec expert but you don't have to be to replicate this. I'm just a dude with some websites and projects and I'm not certain I would have taken notice of this if it wasn't reported to me by a partner on another project who witnessed this behavior when monitoring his local requests leaving his network. He'll be doing his own write-up and is more equipped to discuss this in length than me.</p>
<hr><p>Testing out something that was noted a week or so ago, and wanting to replicate it for the purpose of this post.</p>
<p>Some of you know I'm working on an ad, tracker, and other BS blocking VPN service for an unrelated project to this site. Go to <a href="https://ramble.pw/f/incoghost">/f/incoghost</a> (<a href="https://incog.host/" rel="nofollow">website</a>) for more because I try to keep these things separated.</p>
<p>Anyhow, it was reported by a partner that Brave was leaking DNS requests for onion sites and I was able to confirm it at the time. Decided to spin up a VM with Brave and test with this site's Onion service (though it will do this for any .onion)</p>
<p>Example:</p>
<pre><code> Feb 18 12:02:25: query[A] rambleeeqrhty6s5jgefdfdtc6tfgg4jj6svr4jpgk4wjtg3qshwbaad.onion from 104.244.xx.xxx
</code></pre>
<p>What this entry shows (simply) is that the request made for the domain rambleeeqrhty6s5jgefdfdtc6tfgg4jj6svr4jpgk4wjtg3qshwbaad.onion made it to the DNS server and is tagged with the IP of the requester, which in this case is just the test / dev VPN. This shouldn't happen. There isn't any reason for Brave to attempt to resolve a .onion domain through traditional means as it would with a regular clearnet site.</p>
<p>This is especially worrisome for those of you who use Brave browser from your normal residential IP and (for whatever reason) use the Tor feature built into the browser to access Tor sites. Your ISP or DNS provider <em>will</em> know that a request made to a specific Tor site was made by <em>your</em> IP. With Brave, your ISP would know that you accessed <em>somesketchyonionsite.onion</em> .</p>
<p>TL;DR: If you're going to use Tor, use the Tor Browser and not Brave. The Tor browser itself doesn't leak these requests like Brave does.</p>
<hr><p>Edit: To clarify, the VPN service we're working on is no-logging but during this dev and testing period we're logging DNS requests while we work out the kinks in the blocklists. This has also allowed us to witness .onions being passed through which is a fault of Brave.</p>
<hr><p>Edit 2: Screenshot: <a href="https://images2.imgbox.com/98/46/1i084PbC_o.png" rel="nofollow">https://images2.imgbox.com/98/46/1i084PbC_o.png</a></p>
<p>That was me loading duckduckgo in a different container, with brave, while live fetching DNS requests made to the DNS server. I blurred out the non-onion requests. (Different VPN test location than in the above example so 209.x.x.x IP instead of the 104.x.x.x one in the original example.</p>
<hr><h3>EDIT 2: The mods of /r/privacy won't let this be posted. They say:</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>While we (vastly) prefer the Tor Browser over the Brave one, you'll need a better source than the one you found. Can you find something from a more widely recognized NetSec expert? Something along the lines of Bruce Schneier's blog or something at that level of credibility?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>and</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The problem with screenshots is that they can be faked, trivially. There are also a host of approaches that credible writers/reporters do in the NetSec space do before a line of text appears in print. It's this kind of journalism that we have to trust, since we humble Mods don't have the time or resources to vet. So, we'll need something better sourced. Sorry!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>and</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There are new posts everyday "warning" people of things that aren't legitimate, hence the caution. This is not a "security" subreddit. A moderator's job is to ensure that the subreddit doesn't devolve into conspiracy theories and misinformation. Security announcements should be vetted and confirmed, not independent claims that the mods have no time to independently verify.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I can post the steps on how to easily replicate this by using pi-hole on their local networks. Anyone is capable of verifying this.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Great. Please do so on r/brave, r/netsec, r/infosec, and other places where this is both directly relevant and appropriate to seek others confirmation. Once vetted by the community (and republished by professionals), you're welcome to post those official responses.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>/r/brave is private, invite only. I posted on netsec and infosec so we'll see. I guess /r/privacy must love Brave and not allow anything against it since it's so god damned easy to verify this...</p>
<p>All you have to do to VERIFY that this is happening is A.) Use Brave B.) Go to an Onion site C.) Observe DNS traffic. Install Pi-Hole on a Raspberry Pi or in a Virtual Machine on your desktop and run your DNS requests through it for ease of use and you can verify it. Not sure why they're so hesitant to inform their subscribers of this.</p>
<hr><p>Edit 3: Tested on both a Debian 10 and Ubuntu desktop. I'm not esteemed NetSec researcher and I'm not setting up a 100 different scenarios.</p>
</div>
            </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ramble.pw/f/privacy/2387/brave-browser-leaks-your-tor-onion-service-requests-through</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26194764</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:27:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[We are starting to operate our CNC machines remotely]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 119 | Comments 93 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26193769">thread link</a>) | @Sharapolas
<br/>
February 19, 2021 | https://1d.works/how-we-started-operating-our-cnc-machines-remotely/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://1d.works/how-we-started-operating-our-cnc-machines-remotely/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
                <div>
                    <h2 id="introduction"><strong>Introduction</strong></h2><p>Not only COVID-19 has brought many challenges to our daily lives, but it also has inspired a lot of change in how we work and do things. Some professions transitioned to remote work more easily than others. Factory workers and machine operators have been less lucky in this regard and that also applies to us in our CNC-based micro-factory.</p><p>Allowing more people to work remotely opens up many opportunities for businesses. Not only you can bring talent from anywhere in the world, but also you have more choices where to house the hardware allowing to optimise on cost. Furthermore, reaction times can be reduced if travel to the worksite can be eliminated. Quite a few IT professionals have been doing a good job from spectacular locations and we should strive to let more people experience that.</p><p>Another important aspect of structuring work such that it can be done remotely is that it is the first step to automating it. Local to remote, and remote to autonomous allows for a smoother transition than local to autonomous straight away. In the future, we plan on coupling our remote system to AI so if you’re interested, make sure to follow us on LinkedIn or Facebook!</p><p><strong>WARNING! </strong>Running machinery unsupervised is dangerous and must be avoided. This article is elaborating on how to operate machines more efficiently with more staff working remote, but does not suggest running machines without supervision or people on-site.</p><h2 id="how-corona-showed-us-an-opportunity"><strong>How Corona showed us an opportunity</strong></h2><p>Before the COVID-19 hit our workflow for a CNC job has been as follows:</p><ol><li>Make CAD/ CAM in the office;</li><li>Finalise CAM in the shop;</li><li>Run CNC jobs in the shop.</li></ol><p>However, during the quarantine at times it has become difficult to proceed this way because of the travel restrictions ( our CNC lab and office are based in different districts and district travel is cumbersome during quarantine ). We took up this challenge and used it as an opportunity to do the first step towards our micro-factory automation by doing more of the shop work remotely.</p><h2 id="the-cnc-lab-problem"><strong>The CNC lab problem</strong></h2><p>Running a CNC job required:</p><ol><li>Prepare the CAD/CAM files;</li><li>Setup the CNC machine for the job;</li><li>Loop: place the material, run the program, take out the cut parts, clean the table</li></ol><p>In our team, a single person has been doing all of these things. However, is it wise to use a skilled designer/ operator to be in charge of moving material and parts? Not really, because those skills could be invested in something with a much better return on investment (ROI).</p><p>Why don’t we have an unskilled person doing that work? Because CNC jobs are prone to small and costly mistakes, so to ensure high quality and safe operation, that person has to have some skills. Those skills need to either be brought in or be taught and as soon as a person has those skills we are back at having a skilled person doing a large amount of unskilled work.</p><h3 id="iteration-1">Iteration 1</h3><p>Our first step towards a solution was finding an unskilled person to be at the shop while we remote into the PC which controls the CNC machine. This has greatly improved our ROI and created a truly win-win situation because not only we are more efficiently using our time resources, but also created a new job position.</p><p>Still, there were issues to be solved. Coordination was done by phone and in order to operate the machine safely, we had to do multiple repeated questions making sure that it is safe to run the machine. Setup was particularly tricky because misunderstandings led to tool breakage and material waste. Lastly, making sure that the operation is proceeding smoothly was tricky as well since it required experienced evaluation and experience we did not have on-site.</p><h3 id="iteration-2">Iteration 2</h3><p>Having drawn conclusions from iteration 1, we’ve decided to upgrade the CNC lab with a camera for more efficient and higher quality feedback. And it is surprising how much easier work became then!</p><figure><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*ukzIoHs74MRrQd9Xu3ZBJQ.png" alt=""><figcaption>Figure 1. CNC shop&nbsp;camera</figcaption></figure><p>Much less coordination was required and we were much more confident operating the CNC machine knowing that the site was safe for operation. Setups became easier because we could verify that the right measurements were made.</p><p>Soon enough we’ve found many things that could be improved:</p><ul><li>Running cameras in one window and remoting in on another tended to be inconvenient on a single screen workstation;</li><li>Although monitoring was much better, the single-camera setup did not allow to evaluate the quality of the finish or how smoothly the work was progressing;</li><li>When we were executing tool adjustments (eg. changing a bit in the tool chuck ) it was still hard to be sure that the right tool was where it needed to be;</li><li>It has become very apparent that some of the tasks could be semi-automated using feedback from the on-site worker. For example, at the beginning of each session, the machine needs to be initialised by moving it to reference and calibrating all the tools which involved checking if the site was clear for action and then going through a sequence of clicks;</li><li>Measurements still took a while to explain and then took a while to do properly.</li></ul><h3 id="iteration-3">Iteration 3</h3><p>Taking into account the inefficiencies we’ve identified, we’ve decided to work on a cohesive platform with an intuitive dashboard which would merge all the systems we have and provide the base for automation to be built upon.</p><p>First, was the network setup. We needed to merge multi-site networks into a mesh topology network where all the nodes could be interconnected which was solved using a hub and spoke topology VPN. Although, it does have its own drawbacks it had a good cost-benefit ratio when it comes to setup and deployment and is working for us for now.</p><p>Next, was building the dashboard which not only required the making of the UI but required figuring out how we’re going to expose and manage resources in our shop network. We decided to build the backend in the spirit of Kubernetes, so it is easy to manage at scale with the addition of new sensors, machines and full-blown sites themselves.</p><figure><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*JYyqKIXsBTgfg8A-ENR-xw.png" alt=""><figcaption>Figure 2. CNC shop dashboard prototype</figcaption></figure><p>For the GUI we choose to go with Python’s Tkinter package in order to be able to rapidly iterate and once it reaches a stable state we’re planning to move it into a web app for easy access from any device. The dashboard is set up such that one could interface with the embedded CNC software by just doing the relevant actions on the dashboard.</p><h3 id="conclusions">Conclusions</h3><p>Based on our experience using the shop dashboard, it has helped us improve our process in the CNC shop by a mile. We are significantly more confident running remote jobs, have more oversight and control and the process is much more efficient with time.</p><p>It has also opened the possibility to (semi)-automate processes involved in running a CNC shop, which we are continuing to work with and will be posting later. We have a few ideas on how to couple the camera and control system with AI and that is an exciting prospect!</p><p>One key feature that the system requires is being able to remotely access the CNC control software. We are lucky to have it running on a PC which we can easily remote-in, but in case of embedded software, some middleware might be needed to control it remotely.</p><p>Allowing the machine operator to work remote adds value to our business as we could easier relocate the shop to cheaper areas, further from the cities or have talented engineers from nearly anywhere in the world away from work with us. That is why we will continue on this journey and will share it with you as we go!</p><hr><h3 id="check-out-more-">Check out more:</h3><ol><li><a href="https://1d.works/welcome-to-1d-works-cnc-lab/" rel="noopener">Welcome to 1D.works CNC Lab</a></li><li><a href="https://1d.works/object-oriented-computer-assisted-machining/" rel="noopener">Simplifying CAM workflow with Fusion 360</a></li><li><a href="https://1d.works/unique-products-at-scale-with-ai-infused-cad/" rel="noopener">Unique products at scale with AI-infused CAD</a></li></ol><p>and more in our <a href="https://1d.works/blog/" rel="noopener">blog</a></p><hr><h3 id="connect-">Connect!</h3><p>At <a href="https://1d.works/" rel="noopener nofollow noopener noopener">1D.works</a> we’re excited about the potential of AI to improve businesses and people’s lives. CAD and CAM are two of the largely unexplored territories we’re invested in. If you think you can benefit from a decade-long experience of applying machine learning to business processes, <a href="https://1d.works/" rel="noopener nofollow noopener noopener">get in touch</a>!</p><hr><figure><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*ZttLaS6wTmFLgKZ6_9LeeA.png" alt=""></figure>
                </div>
            </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://1d.works/how-we-started-operating-our-cnc-machines-remotely/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26193769</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 14:53:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[CC Academy (Free Fellowship) opens its doors to the 3rd cohort of ML/FE/UX folks]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 19 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26193517">thread link</a>) | @billnyetheai
<br/>
February 19, 2021 | https://www.notion.so/Chronic-Coder-Academy-Season-3-dbd4a42c517a4902b345a7fb7287cedf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.notion.so/Chronic-Coder-Academy-Season-3-dbd4a42c517a4902b345a7fb7287cedf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.notion.so/Chronic-Coder-Academy-Season-3-dbd4a42c517a4902b345a7fb7287cedf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26193517</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 14:31:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Brave Browser leaks your Tor / Onion service requests through DNS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 27 | Comments 14 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26192574">thread link</a>) | @input_sh
<br/>
February 19, 2021 | https://ramble.pw/f/privacy/2387 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ramble.pw/f/privacy/2387">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              <div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Edit: (Since this is gaining traction elsewhere.) I'm not trying to shit on Brave. I'm just wanting to help protect end-users who may use Brave for it's Tor feature to do stuff over Tor that should only be done with the actual Tor browser. If you're using Brave you probably use it because you expect a certain level of privacy/anonymity. Piping .onion requests through DNS where your ISP or DNS provider can see that <em>you</em> made a request for an .onion site defeats that purpose.</p>
<p>I'm also no NetSec expert but you don't have to be to replicate this. I'm just a dude with some websites and projects and I'm not certain I would have taken notice of this if it wasn't reported to me by a partner on another project who witnessed this behavior when monitoring his local requests leaving his network. He'll be doing his own write-up and is more equipped to discuss this in length than me.</p>
<hr><p>Testing out something that was noted a week or so ago, and wanting to replicate it for the purpose of this post.</p>
<p>Some of you know I'm working on an ad, tracker, and other BS blocking VPN service for an unrelated project to this site. Go to <a href="https://ramble.pw/f/incoghost">/f/incoghost</a> (<a href="https://incog.host/" rel="nofollow">website</a>) for more because I try to keep these things separated.</p>
<p>Anyhow, it was reported by a partner that Brave was leaking DNS requests for onion sites and I was able to confirm it at the time. Decided to spin up a VM with Brave and test with this site's Onion service (though it will do this for any .onion)</p>
<p>Example:</p>
<pre><code> Feb 18 12:02:25: query[A] rambleeeqrhty6s5jgefdfdtc6tfgg4jj6svr4jpgk4wjtg3qshwbaad.onion from 104.244.xx.xxx
</code></pre>
<p>What this entry shows (simply) is that the request made for the domain rambleeeqrhty6s5jgefdfdtc6tfgg4jj6svr4jpgk4wjtg3qshwbaad.onion made it to the DNS server and is tagged with the IP of the requester, which in this case is just the test / dev VPN. This shouldn't happen. There isn't any reason for Brave to attempt to resolve a .onion domain through traditional means as it would with a regular clearnet site.</p>
<p>This is especially worrisome for those of you who use Brave browser from your normal residential IP and (for whatever reason) use the Tor feature built into the browser to access Tor sites. Your ISP or DNS provider <em>will</em> know that a request made to a specific Tor site was made by <em>your</em> IP. With Brave, your ISP would know that you accessed <em>somesketchyonionsite.onion</em> .</p>
<p>TL;DR: If you're going to use Tor, use the Tor Browser and not Brave. The Tor browser itself doesn't leak these requests like Brave does.</p>
<hr><p>Edit: To clarify, the VPN service we're working on is no-logging but during this dev and testing period we're logging DNS requests while we work out the kinks in the blocklists. This has also allowed us to witness .onions being passed through which is a fault of Brave.</p>
<hr><p>Edit 2: Screenshot: <a href="https://images2.imgbox.com/98/46/1i084PbC_o.png" rel="nofollow">https://images2.imgbox.com/98/46/1i084PbC_o.png</a></p>
<p>That was me loading duckduckgo in a different container, with brave, while live fetching DNS requests made to the DNS server. I blurred out the non-onion requests. (Different VPN test location than in the above example so 209.x.x.x IP instead of the 104.x.x.x one in the original example.</p>
<hr><h3>EDIT 2: The mods of /r/privacy won't let this be posted. They say:</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>While we (vastly) prefer the Tor Browser over the Brave one, you'll need a better source than the one you found. Can you find something from a more widely recognized NetSec expert? Something along the lines of Bruce Schneier's blog or something at that level of credibility?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>and</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The problem with screenshots is that they can be faked, trivially. There are also a host of approaches that credible writers/reporters do in the NetSec space do before a line of text appears in print. It's this kind of journalism that we have to trust, since we humble Mods don't have the time or resources to vet. So, we'll need something better sourced. Sorry!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>and</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There are new posts everyday "warning" people of things that aren't legitimate, hence the caution. This is not a "security" subreddit. A moderator's job is to ensure that the subreddit doesn't devolve into conspiracy theories and misinformation. Security announcements should be vetted and confirmed, not independent claims that the mods have no time to independently verify.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I can post the steps on how to easily replicate this by using pi-hole on their local networks. Anyone is capable of verifying this.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Great. Please do so on r/brave, r/netsec, r/infosec, and other places where this is both directly relevant and appropriate to seek others confirmation. Once vetted by the community (and republished by professionals), you're welcome to post those official responses.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>/r/brave is private, invite only. I posted on netsec and infosec so we'll see. I guess /r/privacy must love Brave and not allow anything against it since it's so god damned easy to verify this...</p>
<p>All you have to do to VERIFY that this is happening is A.) Use Brave B.) Go to an Onion site C.) Observe DNS traffic. Install Pi-Hole on a Raspberry Pi or in a Virtual Machine on your desktop and run your DNS requests through it for ease of use and you can verify it. Not sure why they're so hesitant to inform their subscribers of this.</p>
<hr><p>Edit 3: Tested on both a Debian 10 and Ubuntu desktop. I'm not esteemed NetSec researcher and I'm not setting up a 100 different scenarios.</p>
</div>
            </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ramble.pw/f/privacy/2387</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26192574</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 12:51:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[“I will slaughter you”]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 516 | Comments 225 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26192025">thread link</a>) | @ingve
<br/>
February 19, 2021 | https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2021/02/19/i-will-slaughter-you/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2021/02/19/i-will-slaughter-you/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>You might know that I’ve posted funny emails I’ve received on my blog several times in the past. The kind of emails people send me when they experience problems with some device they own (like a <a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2018/02/16/why-is-your-email-in-my-car/" data-type="post" data-id="10856">car</a>) and they contact me because my email address happens to be visible somewhere.</p>



<p>People sometimes say I should get a different email address or use another one in the curl license file, but I’ve truly never had a problem with these emails, as they mostly remind me about the tough challenges the modern technical life bring to people and it gives me insights about what things that run curl.</p>



<p>But not all of these emails are “funny”.</p>



<h2>Category: not funny</h2>



<p>Today I received the following email</p>



<pre>From: Al Nocai &lt;[redacted]@icloud.com&gt;
Date: Fri, 19 Feb 2021 03:02:24 -0600
Subject: I will slaughter you</pre>



<p>That subject.</p>



<p>As an open source maintainer since over twenty years, I know flame wars and personal attacks and I have a fairly thick skin and I don’t let words get to me easily. It took me a minute to absorb and realize it was actually meant as a direct physical threat. It found its ways through and got to me. This level of aggressiveness is not what I’m prepared for.</p>



<p>Attached in this email, there were seven images and no text at all. The images all look like screenshots from a phone and the first one is clearly showing <a href="https://github.com/curl/curl/blob/master/include/curl/multi.h">source code I wrote</a> and my copyright line:</p>



<div><figure><a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image0.png"><img loading="lazy" width="295" height="640" src="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image0.png" alt=""></a></figure></div>



<p>The <a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/al/">other images</a> showed other source code and related build/software info of other components, but I couldn’t spot how they were associated with me in any way.</p>



<p>No explanation, just that subject and the seven images and I was left to draw my own conclusions.</p>



<p>I presume the name in the email is made up and the email account is probably a throw-away one. The time zone used in the <code>Date:</code> string might imply US <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/time/zones/cst">central standard time</a> but could of course easily be phony as well. </p>



<h2>How I responded</h2>



<p>Normally I don’t respond to these confused emails because the distance between me and the person writing them is usually almost interplanetary. This time though, it was so far beyond what’s acceptable to me and in any decent society I couldn’t just let it slide. After I took a little pause and walked around my house for a few minutes to cool off, I wrote a really angry reply and sent it off.</p>



<blockquote><p>This was a totally and completely utterly unacceptable email and it hurt me deep in my soul. You should be ashamed and seriously reconsider your manners.</p><p>I have no idea what your screenshots are supposed to show, but clearly something somewhere is using code I wrote. Code I have written runs in virtually every Internet connected device on the planet and in most cases the users download and use it without even telling me, for free.</p><p>Clearly you don’t deserve my code.</p></blockquote>



<p>I don’t expect that it will be read or make any difference.</p>



<p>Update below, added after my initial post.</p>



<h2>Al Nocai’s response</h2>



<p>Contrary to my expectations above, he responded. It’s not even worth commenting but for transparency I’ll include it here.</p>



<p><em>I do not care. Your bullshit software was an attack vector that cost me a multimillion dollar defense project.</em></p>



<p><em>Your bullshit software has been used to root me and multiple others. I lost over $15k in prototyping alone from bullshit rooting to the charge arbitrators.</em></p>



<p><em>I have now since October been sandboxed because of your bullshit software so dipshit google kids could grift me trying to get out of the sandbox because they are too piss poor to know shat they are doing.</em></p>



<p><em>You know what I did to deserve that? I tried to develop a trade route in tech and establish project based learning methodologies to make sure kids aren’t left behind. You know who is all over those god damn files? You are. Its sickening. I got breached in Oct 2020 through federal server hijacking, and I owe a great amount of that to you.</em></p>



<p><em>Ive had to sit and watch as i reported:</em></p>



<ol><li><em>fireeye Oct/2020</em></li><li><em>Solarwinds Oct/2020</em></li><li><em>Zyxel Modem Breach Oct/2020</em></li><li><em>Multiple Sigover attack vectors utilizing favicon XML injection</em></li><li><em>JS Stochastic templating utilizing comparison expressions to write to data registers</em></li><li><em>Get strong armed by $50billion companies because i exposed bullshit malware</em></li></ol>



<p><em>And i was rooted and had my important correspondence all rerouted as some sick fuck dismantled my life with the code you have your name plastered all over. I cant even leave the country because of the situation; qas you have so effectively built a code base to shit all over people, I dont give a shit how you feel about this.</em></p>



<p><em>You built a formula 1 race car and tossed the keys to kids with ego problems. Now i have to deal with Win10 0-days because this garbage.</em></p>



<p><em>I lost my family, my country my friends, my home and 6 years of work trying to build a better place for posterity. And it has beginnings in that code. That code is used to root and exploit people. That code is used to blackmail people.</em></p>



<p><em>So no, I don’t feel bad one bit. You knew exactly the utility of what you were building. And you thought it was all a big joke. Im not laughing. I am so far past that point now.</em></p>



<p><em>/- Al</em></p>



<h2>Al continues</h2>



<p>Nine hours after I first published this blog post , Al replied again with two additional emails. His third and forth emails to me.</p>



<h3>Email 3:</h3>



<p><em><a href="https://davidkrider.com/i-will-slaughter-you-daniel-haxx-se/">https://davidkrider.com/i-will-slaughter-you-daniel-haxx-se/</a><br>Step up. You arent scaring me. What led me here? The 5th violent attempt on my life. Apple terms of service? gtfo, thanks for the platform.</em></p>



<p>Amusingly he has found a blog post about my blog post.</p>



<h3>Email 4:</h3>



<p><em>There is the project: MOUT Ops Risk Analysis through Wide Band Em Spectrum analysis through different fourier transforms.<br>You and whoever the fuck david dick rider is, you are a part of this.<br>Federal server breaches-<br>Accomplice to attempted murder-<br>Fraud-<br>just a few.</em></p>



<p><em>I have talked to now: FBI FBI Regional, VA, VA OIG, FCC, SEC, NSA, DOH, GSA, DOI, CIA, CFPB, HUD, MS, Convercent, as of today 22 separate local law enforcement agencies calling my ass up and wasting my time.</em></p>



<p><em>You and dick ridin’ dave are respinsible. I dont give a shit, call the cops. I cuss them out wheb they call and they all go silent.</em></p>



<p>I’ve kept his peculiar formatting and typos. In email 4 there was also a PDF file attached named <code>BustyBabes 4.pdf</code>. It is apparently a 13 page document about the “NERVEBUS NERVOUS SYSTEM” described in the first paragraph as “NerveBus Nervous System aims to be a general utility platform that provides comprehensive and complex analysis to provide the end user with cohesive, coherent and “real-time” information about the environment it monitors.”. There’s no mention of curl or my name in the document.</p>



<p>Since I don’t know the status of this document I will not share it publicly, but here’s a screenshot of the front page:</p>



<div><figure><a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screenshot_2021-02-20-BustyBabes-4-pdf.png"><img loading="lazy" src="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screenshot_2021-02-20-BustyBabes-4-pdf.png" alt="" width="358" height="462"></a></figure></div>



<h2>Related</h2>



<p>This topic on <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26192025">hacker news</a> and <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/lnhcrc/i_will_slaughter_you_daniel_stenberg_got_a_quite/">reddit</a>.</p>



<p>I have reported the threat to the Swedish police (where I live).</p>
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2021/02/19/i-will-slaughter-you/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26192025</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 11:36:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to be more productive without forcing yourself]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 248 | Comments 120 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26191516">thread link</a>) | @vitabenes
<br/>
February 19, 2021 | https://www.deprocrastination.co/blog/how-to-be-productive-without-forcing-yourself | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.deprocrastination.co/blog/how-to-be-productive-without-forcing-yourself">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article><p><img src="https://www.deprocrastination.co/assets/illustrations/work_bad_rect.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" alt="How to be more productive without forcing yourself"></p><p>Imagine you could work more and be wildly productive. And the best thing about it? You wouldn’t need to force yourself to work.</p><p>There are people exactly like that who sit down and work without pushing themselves to do it. They even look forward to working. The good news is that you can learn to do it too.</p><p>Let’s get to it.</p><p>Most people have a negative mindset about work. People see work as an annoyance that keeps them from doing whatever they really want to do. They also think that resting and having nothing to do is an ideal state they’d like to be in forever. This leads to thinking that you need to push yourself to work. You need to use willpower to get yourself to do it.</p><p>It’s simple to understand where this attitude comes from:</p><ol><li>People usually want things they don’t have and think that grass is greener on the other side.</li><li>Everyone talks about how work is hard.</li><li>In comparison to dead-end or corporate jobs without impact or freedom, neverending leisure looks like paradise.</li></ol><p>In reality, most people who try to be in this nothing-to-do state for a long time become unhappy, depressed, and bored. Rich people who “made it” report how soon they become restless again.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/StopGaming/">People who game all the time</a>&nbsp;realize how empty it feels. Too much leisure isn’t satisfying for long.</p><p>On the other hand, there is a certain group of people who work a lot and enjoy it. Let’s call this group&nbsp;<em>producers</em>. By this, we don’t mean workaholics who escape from their whole life by working all the time. Producers have a healthy work-life balance. So what do they do that people who hate work don’t?</p><p>First, they tend to think about work differently.</p><p>For them, work is&nbsp;<a href="https://www.deprocrastination.co/blog/what-is-a-positive-feedback-loop-and-why-it-matters">a virtuous cycle of positive feedback loops</a>. Producers see&nbsp;<strong>work as a source of meaning and satisfaction</strong>. They see work as something that allows them to savor deserved leisure. They see rest as something that increases their life happiness and fuels their motivation towards work.</p><p>Second, their work is usually:</p><ul><li>Interesting</li><li>Meaningful</li><li>Well-defined</li></ul><p>If you check at least 1 or 2 boxes somehow, something magical happens:</p><p><strong>You don’t have to push yourself towards work anymore.</strong></p><p>Well-defined, meaningful, and especially interesting work is easy to look forward to.</p><p>Non-producers often think that these producers are lucky because they stumbled upon work like this. In reality, producers often go a long way to make their work fun.</p><h2>How to make work more interesting</h2><p>This is the crucial factor in whether work gets done.</p><p>You don’t have to see any meaning in your work for it to be interesting.</p><p>Even if the task is totally undefined, complex, and difficult, curiosity can carry you to its completion.</p><p>So how can you develop this curiosity towards work?</p><p>You have to give the work a chance to become interesting. How? By combining these 3 steps:</p><h3>1. Have less exposure towards super fun things</h3><p>Video games, surfing the internet, porn, alcohol, and drugs etc. make work significantly more difficult. Why?</p><p>They establish a certain standard of mental stimulation. Anything that’s not super fun will seem boring.</p><p><img src="https://www.deprocrastination.co/assets/illustrations/stimulation_standard.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" alt="We develop a Stimulation Standard"></p><p>Unfortunately, work often falls in the “feels bad” category. In comparison to games or social media, work can feel uninteresting or annoying.</p><p><img src="https://www.deprocrastination.co/assets/illustrations/stimulation_work_distractions.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" alt="Switching from distractions to work is hard"></p><p>You might argue that there are people who work just fine even while drinking alcohol, playing video games etc.</p><p>However, consider that there are two types of people: ones who can moderate their consumption and others who can’t. The latter society often describes as addicts.</p><p>Basically, if you’re addicted to any of the high-dopamine, low-effort activity, please quit it. At least temporarily so you can reestablish a healthy relationship to work. The more experienced we’re about the topic, the more obvious this is. There is no other way than to temporarily quit the addiction. If your vice is gaming, we’ve covered&nbsp;<a href="https://www.deprocrastination.co/blog/should-i-quit-video-games">video gaming addiction here</a>.</p><p>Some can have a healthy relationship with, for example, gaming.</p><p>However, for some people gaming is kryptonite. Here are some signs that super-fun activities have a detrimental effect on your work:</p><ol><li>You rush and half-ass everything else in order to get to your super-fun activity.         When I (Mat) was addicted to gaming, everything during the day was half-assed so I could finally start playing.</li><li>You keep postponing or forgetting everything that isn’t urgent in order to get to your super fun activity. You have this book that you want to read but you never get to actually reading it.</li><li>Your orderliness suffers once you start with the super fun activity.        Most people who come back to gaming report how their sense of orderliness starts to depreciate rather quickly. Their room gets messy, they start skipping workouts, stop meal-prepping, start eating more junk food, stop organizing their days.</li></ol><p>If the points above describe you, it might be time to quit your super fun activity. At least for a while.</p><p>Once your brain is not constantly hyper-stimulated, it’s easier to find mundane activities like work or tidying more interesting.</p><h3>2. Get bored more often</h3><p>When you get bored, everything else becomes more interesting.</p><p>Don’t believe us? Try this little experiment. Turn everything off. Set a timer for 15 minutes. Sit on a chair and stare at a wall. Don’t move. Don’t consume any information. Don’t talk. Don’t write anything down. Just stare at the wall.</p><p>Except for zen masters, most of us will become restless after a few minutes. Often, our brain starts dreaming and imagining things. For the first few minutes, you might feel alright, thinking about your day. However, after 5 or 10 minutes, you’ll be itching to do something, anything really. Suddenly, creating a website, writing an article, or drawing a picture sounds like more interesting, more fun.</p><p><img src="https://www.deprocrastination.co/assets/illustrations/stimulation_work_boredom.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" alt="Switching from boredom to work is easier"></p><p>If you feel like you never stop scrolling and consume content all the time, schedule a 15 minute boredom window for tomorrow right before you want to start working.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.deprocrastination.co/blog/how-to-use-boredom-to-procrastinate-less">Use boredom strategically.</a></p><h3>3. Dive deep into a topic</h3><p>It’s fun when we can connect the dots. When we can draw new connections between ideas, we get a rush.&nbsp;<em>Oh, I can see how this historical event contributed to an uprising…</em></p><p>The more connections we can draw within a topic, the more interested we become. This is what curiosity is all about.</p><p>If you take the time to watch a documentary related to what you’re working on, read a book about it, or find a couple relevant articles. You’ll collect more dots to connect. You’ll see how everything fits together.</p><p>When you do feel like watching something or have a free evening, instead of watching random videos or reruns of old TV shows, steer your attention to something related to what you need to do.</p><p>Give yourself time to develop an interest.</p><h2>How to make work more meaningful</h2><p>It's hard to feel motivated when you don't have a personal reason to do something.</p><p>However, “meaningful work” has become something of a buzzword.</p><p>Everyone is trying to find meaning in their work. This can be wasted energy, especially if you work in a corporate or a dead-end job. We say this so you don’t dwell on it and don’t feel frustrated because you can’t figure out how to save the world by doing what you do.</p><p>In any case, whatever your work is, you can make it meaningful enough to start.</p><p>Let’s say you have to study for an exam. You don’t find this particular class enjoyable. If you remind yourself why you chose to take the class and why studying is important for you, you will have an easier time persuading yourself to push through.</p><p>The fact is that some things simply need to be done. It's better if you find a compelling and personal reason to do them and get them over with as soon as possible, instead of putting them off forever.</p><p>When something is boring, ask yourself: Why do I need to do this? Find and reinforce the why behind the work.</p><h2>How to make work well-defined</h2><p>If you have a recipe that tells you step-by-step how to cook a meal, it is usually quite easy to follow. You know exactly where to start and how.</p><p>In today’s creative work, this often isn’t the case. There are no recipes for the work we need to do, or they don’t make the work any easier because the recipe would be too complex to understand.</p><p>Additionally, we often hamper our enthusiasm towards work by ourselves. How often do you find yourself with vague and unhelpful to-dos like “write the essay” or “make a video.”</p><p>There are so many steps in “make a video” that this vague task definition only causes anxiety and procrastination.</p><p>We always say that it’s more difficult to start working than to keep working. Therefore we should make starting easier by defining well&nbsp;<em>how</em>&nbsp;to begin and&nbsp;<em>what</em>&nbsp;to begin with.</p><p>The better you can define how to start working, the easier it’ll be to actually do it.</p><p>Basically, you do this in 3 steps:</p><h3>1. Always define exactly where you’ll start</h3><p>This means you write down the next physical action to take.</p><p>Do you need to write an essay?</p><p>The next physical action is: Open the scientific study and start reading</p><p>Or: Create a document → Create a rough draft in the next 15 minutes</p><p>Do you want to start learning coding?</p><p>The next physical action should be: Open freecodecamp.org → Start solving the first challenge</p><p>It might sound silly to define the next physical action, but it isn’t. Finding it is easy, and you can do it immediately.</p><p>What’s the next physical action you need to take?</p><h3>2. Start with only having to work for 5/15 minutes</h3><p>You probably don't feel like creating a 20 slide presentation right now from scratch, and then presenting it in 2 hours.</p><p>You don't feel like writing a whole final thesis on a topic you barely know.</p><p>You don't feel like running a marathon.</p><p>But you might feel like looking up a couple pictures or articles for the presentation.</p><p>Or feel like writing a paragraph or two before lunch break.</p><p>Or feel like taking a 1km walk.</p><p>Those are the small steps along the longer journey.</p><p>We often underestimate the power of small steps, but they are essential because they help us get into the right routine.</p><p>If you start running a couple miles every other day, you'll get familiar with the routine and then you'll naturally want to start increasing the …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.deprocrastination.co/blog/how-to-be-productive-without-forcing-yourself">https://www.deprocrastination.co/blog/how-to-be-productive-without-forcing-yourself</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.deprocrastination.co/blog/how-to-be-productive-without-forcing-yourself</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26191516</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 10:27:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Where Everything Went Wrong: Error Handling and Error Messages in Rust (2020)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 148 | Comments 181 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26191006">thread link</a>) | @lukastyrychtr
<br/>
February 19, 2021 | https://msirringhaus.github.io/Where-everything-went-wrong/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://msirringhaus.github.io/Where-everything-went-wrong/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p><strong>Today you are frustrated.</strong></p>

<p>This is so annoying. Youâ€™ve written a Rust crate and now that you want to test it for the very first time, <em>it doesnâ€™t work!</em></p>

<p>Come on, Rust! How dare you? You promised that once one gets past the compiler, it.<br>
<em>Just.<br>
<strong>Works!</strong></em><br>
And now this!</p>

<p>Ok, ok. You calm yourself down. Lets start from the beginning. You want to create so called <a href="https://docs.sentry.io/platforms/native/guides/minidumps/">minidumps</a>. This is a file that contains information about a crashed program (like stacks of all threads, CPU registers, system info, etc.).
The minidump consists of various sections, such as the minidump header (including time of day, versions and basically a table of contents), a thread section (including all threads of the process and their stacks), memory mappings and libraries, etc. [Just to give some context, as all of this is actually not really important.]</p>

<p>For this, you created a <a href="https://github.com/msirringhaus/minidump_writer_linux">crate</a>. One section gets written after the other, while information about the targeted process is retrieved from the system. You even created a nice, simple API. You hand in a process ID and an open file, where the minidump should be written to. like this:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>    <span>MinidumpWriter</span><span>::</span><span>new</span><span>(</span><span>pid</span><span>,</span> <span>blamed_thread</span><span>)</span>
        <span>.dump</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>mut</span> <span>dump_file</span><span>)</span>
        <span>.expect</span><span>(</span><span>"Dumping failed!"</span><span>)</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>You can also hand in user specified memory regions that should be included in the dump, like so:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>    <span>let</span> <span>app_memory</span> <span>=</span> <span>AppMemory</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>ptr</span><span>:</span> <span>some_address</span><span>,</span>
        <span>length</span><span>:</span> <span>memory_size</span><span>,</span>
    <span>};</span>

    <span>MinidumpWriter</span><span>::</span><span>new</span><span>(</span><span>pid</span><span>,</span> <span>pid</span><span>)</span>
        <span>.set_app_memory</span><span>(</span><span>vec!</span><span>[</span><span>app_memory</span><span>])</span>
        <span>.dump</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>mut</span> <span>tmpfile</span><span>)</span>
        <span>.expect</span><span>(</span><span>"Dumping failed"</span><span>);</span>
</code></pre></div></div>



<p>But when you run your nice library code in an application, you get <code>'Dumping failed: "Failed in ptrace::read: Sys(EIO)"'</code>.</p>

<p><em>How useless is that?!</em></p>

<p>Okay, maybe you could enhance your library error handling, a little. And by enhance, you mean â€œimplement one in the first placeâ€�.</p>

<h2 id="state-of-the-dart">State of the dart</h2>

<p>Your current approach is to define</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>type</span> <span>Error</span> <span>=</span> <span>Box</span><span>&lt;</span><span>dyn</span> <span>error</span><span>::</span><span>Error</span> <span>+</span> <span>std</span><span>::</span><span>marker</span><span>::</span><span>Send</span> <span>+</span> <span>std</span><span>::</span><span>marker</span><span>::</span><span>Sync</span><span>&gt;</span><span>;</span>
<span>pub</span> <span>type</span> <span>Result</span><span>&lt;</span><span>T</span><span>&gt;</span> <span>=</span> <span>result</span><span>::</span><span>Result</span><span>&lt;</span><span>T</span><span>,</span> <span>Error</span><span>&gt;</span><span>;</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>and using <code>Result&lt;T&gt;</code> in all of your functions as the return value and handing all of them to the parent function using <code>?</code>. Thus the original error pierces through your callstack like a dart throughâ€¦.jelly (Yes, you are good with words and you know it.).</p>

<div><div><pre><code>    <span>pub</span> <span>fn</span> <span>init</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>mut</span> <span>self</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Result</span><span>&lt;</span><span>()</span><span>&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>self</span><span>.read_auxv</span><span>()</span><span>?</span><span>;</span>
        <span>self</span><span>.enumerate_threads</span><span>()</span><span>?</span><span>;</span>
        <span>self</span><span>.enumerate_mappings</span><span>()</span><span>?</span><span>;</span>
        <span>Ok</span><span>(())</span>
    <span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>In Rust parlance, this is also called bubbling up errors.</p>

<p>Usually, you just bubble up errors from libraries you use, but for the rare errors you have to define yourself, you currently just do</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>Err</span><span>(</span><span>"Found no auxv entry"</span><span>.into</span><span>())</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Well, now you know there is an error, at least. And that it has <em>something</em> to do with your usage of <code>ptrace</code>. But you have no idea where that happens. You use that functionality in various places. Is it during the init-phase? During one of the sections? And if so, which one? What are you trying to read? And from where? Or in short: <strong>What is going on?!</strong></p>

<h2 id="shoes-off-get-some-tea-research-time">Shoes off, get some tea: Research time!</h2>

<p>Well, Rust has been around for quite some time now and they always boast about how error handling is a first class citizen and all that. So error handling should be a done deal, right? With a canonical way of dealing with errors, officially documented and all that should be right there, correct?</p>

<p>Oh boy, were you wrong.</p>

<p>Turns out, this is a very active field ofâ€¦mhâ€¦experimentation, lets say. There has been <a href="https://blog.yoshuawuyts.com/error-handling-survey/">a survey</a> recently, listing and quickly describing most the different libraries and ways for error handling that emerged, fallen out of favor, got forked, died anyways, got superseded, fallen out of favor again, etc.
And the opinions seem to change frequently, if you should use <code>error-chain</code> or <code>failure</code> or <code>fehler</code> or <code>snafu</code> or <code>thiserror</code> or <code>anyhow</code> or <code>eyre</code> orâ€¦</p>

<p>You opened a can of hornets there, or whatever that saying is.</p>

<p>Then you find <a href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/inside-rust/2020/11/23/What-the-error-handling-project-group-is-working-on.html">this gem</a> and donâ€™t know if you should laugh or cry. Almost six years after Rust hit 1.0 an error handling project group is formed. Six. Years. <em>(heavy breathing)</em></p>

<p>Well, okay. At least they are sorting it out now. Problem is, you needâ€¦.<em>SIX YEARS? Are you serious?</em>â€¦ahem, sorryâ€¦Problem is, you need helpful error messages now.</p>

<p>After reading a few decent blogs on the topic (like <a href="http://www.sheshbabu.com/posts/rust-error-handling/">this</a> or <a href="https://nick.groenen.me/posts/rust-error-handling/">that</a>), there seems to emerge a consensus, at least for libraries: Return something that derives from <code>std::error::Error</code>. Either implement them by hand, or use a crate that does it for you, using macro magic. like <code>thiserror</code>. Which method you use depends on your level of laziness plus your patience regarding compile times.</p>

<h2 id="examples-vs-reality">Examples vs. Reality</h2>

<p>Another post highlighted <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/rust-by-example/error/multiple_error_types/wrap_error.html">error wrapping</a>, a particularly intriguing idea to you.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, all the articles have the understandable, but rather annoying tendency to use very simple example code for illustration purposes. Unrealistically simple, you might even say. They have callstacks of depth 1, return only three kinds of error in total in their API, and their errors are obvious and easily describable (e.g. â€œInput file XY not found in your â€˜counting wordsâ€™ programâ€�).</p>

<p>You have a more complicated callstack, with tons of different errors and code reuse in different places. For example, the function you think is to blame for the above error is <code>copy_from_process()</code>, which calls <code>ptrace::read()</code>, which probably returns something like <code>Failed in ptrace::read: Sys(EIO)</code>.
This function is used in multiple places in your code, e.g.:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>â”œâ”€ init()
â”‚   â”œâ”€ read_auxv()
â”‚   â”‚  â”œâ”€ open(format!("/proc/{}/auxv", self.pid))
â”‚   â”‚  â””â”€ some_parsing()
â”‚   â”œâ”€ ...
â”‚   â”œâ”€ enumerate_mappings()
â”‚   â”‚  â”œâ”€ open(format!("/proc/{}/maps", self.pid))
â”‚   â”‚  â””â”€ some_parsing()
â”‚   â”‚
â”‚   â””â”€ some_more_checks()
â”‚      â””â”€ copy_from_process()
â”‚
â””â”€ dump()
   â”‚
   â”œâ”€ sections::header::write()
   â”‚
   â”œâ”€ sections::thread_list_stream::write()
   â”‚  â””â”€ copy_from_process()
   â”‚
   â”œâ”€ sections::mappings::write()
   â”‚  â””â”€ elf_identifier_for_mapping()
   â”‚     â””â”€ copy_from_process()
   â”‚
   â”œâ”€ sections::app_memory::write()
   â”‚  â””â”€ copy_from_process()
   â”‚
   â””â”€ ...
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Same goes for opening files, which happens in multiple places (two examples of which are shown in <code>init()</code>), so getting <code>FileNotFound</code> without context is going to be equally fun, and so on.</p>



<p>Wrapping errors still sounds like a nice idea, but one layer alone is not going to <del>wrap it</del> cut it.
Going with <code>copy_from_process()</code> as an example, you see a few possibilities:</p>
<ol>
  <li>Wrapping the <code>ptrace</code> error into an <code>CopyFromProcessError</code>, but that gives you nothing (except maybe some context, if you add some)</li>
  <li>With <code>InitError</code>s and <code>DumpingError</code>s that wrap the <code>ptrace</code> errors, you will still not know which section failed and why, but know if it was during <code>init()</code> or not.</li>
</ol>

<p>You might add context to option 2 as well (see below on how), but each section has a variety of reasons why it could fail. Some unique to the section, some shared among a few, some among all of them.</p>

<p>Complex problems sometimes require complex solutions, maybe?</p>

<h2 id="inc-err-ption">Inc <em>Err()</em> ption</h2>

<p>Using <code>thiserror</code> and the fabulous <code>#[from]</code> macro, you quickly define a plethora of errors and wrappers, starting from the deepest, darkest places in your callstack, wrapping your way up:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>#[derive(Debug,</span> <span>Error)]</span>
<span>pub</span> <span>enum</span> <span>PtraceDumperError</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>#[error(</span><span>"nix::ptrace() error"</span><span>)]</span>
    <span>PtraceError</span><span>(</span><span>#[from]</span> <span>nix</span><span>::</span><span>Error</span><span>),</span>
    <span>...</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>#[derive(Debug,</span> <span>Error)]</span>
<span>pub</span> <span>enum</span> <span>SectionAppMemoryError</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>#[error(</span><span>"Failed to copy memory from process"</span><span>)]</span>
    <span>CopyFromProcessError</span><span>(</span><span>#[from]</span> <span>PtraceDumperError</span><span>),</span>
    <span>...</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>#[derive(Debug,</span> <span>Error)]</span>
<span>pub</span> <span>enum</span> <span>DumpError</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>#[error(</span><span>"Error during init phase"</span><span>)]</span>
    <span>InitError</span><span>(</span><span>#[from]</span> <span>InitError</span><span>),</span>
    <span>#[error(transparent)]</span>
    <span>PtraceDumperError</span><span>(</span><span>#[from]</span> <span>PtraceDumperError</span><span>),</span>
    <span>#[error(</span><span>"Failed when writing section AppMemory"</span><span>)]</span>
    <span>SectionAppMemoryError</span><span>(</span><span>#[from]</span> <span>SectionAppMemoryError</span><span>),</span>
    <span>...</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The fun part is: You have to touch very little of your existing code, thanks to the automatic conversion from one error to the other, conveniently provided by <code>#[from]</code>:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>- pub fn init(&amp;mut self) -&gt; Result&lt;()&gt; {
</span><span>+ pub fn init(&amp;mut self) -&gt; Result&lt;(), InitError&gt; {
</span>     self.read_auxv()?;
     self.enumerate_threads()?;
     self.enumerate_mappings()?;
     Ok(())
 }
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>or</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>- pub fn get_stack_info(&amp;self, int_stack_pointer: usize) -&gt; Result&lt;(usize, usize)&gt; {
</span><span>+ pub fn get_stack_info(&amp;self, int_stack_pointer: usize) -&gt; Result&lt;(usize, usize), DumperError&gt; {
</span> // snip

    let mapping = self
        .find_mapping(stack_pointer)
<span>-        .ok_or("No mapping for stack pointer found")?;
</span><span>+        .ok_or(DumperError::NoStackPointerMapping)?;
</span>    let offset = stack_pointer - mapping.start_address;
    let distance_to_end = mapping.size - offset;
  // snip
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>If you run your test binary again, you now get</p>
<div><div><pre><code>Failed when writing section AppMemory
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>which isâ€¦.<em>(Throws a stack of papers from the desk)</em>â€¦short. Too short, and not that much more helpful, actually. Well, you know which section is failing. Thats good. But where are all the nice error messages you specified in your errors?</p>

<p>Hm, you do only use <code>println!("{}", error);</code>. Maybe <code>{:?}</code> is better?</p>
<div><div><pre><code>SectionAppMemoryError(CopyFromProcessError(PtraceError(Sys(EIO))))
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Aha! Now you are getting somewhere! Tiny, tiny, painfully <strong>tiny</strong> steps, but you are getting somewhere! No error texts, but at least a chain!</p>

<p>Normal printing doesnâ€™t seem to recursively go through all the wrapped errors, but stop at the top most. For this, you need to either go through all the errors yourself by hand, or use a crate that does this for you. There are a number of them that provide this, but <code>anyhow</code> will do (its by the same author as <code>thiserror</code>, so interoperability shouldnâ€™t be an issue).</p>

<div><div><pre><code>    <span>println!</span><span>(</span><span>"{:#}"</span><span>,</span> <span>anyhow</span><span>::</span><span>Error</span><span>::</span><span>new</span><span>(</span><span>error</span><span>));</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>aaaaand:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Failed when writing section AppMemory: Failed to copy memory from process: nix::ptrace() error: EIO: I/O error
</code></pre></div></div>

<p><em>Collects papers from the …</em></p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://msirringhaus.github.io/Where-everything-went-wrong/">https://msirringhaus.github.io/Where-everything-went-wrong/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://msirringhaus.github.io/Where-everything-went-wrong/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26191006</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 08:57:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[12 requests per second: A realistic look at Python web frameworks]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 473 | Comments 227 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26188765">thread link</a>) | @gilad
<br/>
February 18, 2021 | https://suade.org/dev/12-requests-per-second-with-python/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://suade.org/dev/12-requests-per-second-with-python/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://suade.org/dev/12-requests-per-second-with-python/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26188765</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 02:21:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Squad: Forth on Chip-8]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 69 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26188165">thread link</a>) | @RodgerTheGreat
<br/>
February 18, 2021 | https://internet-janitor.itch.io/squad | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://internet-janitor.itch.io/squad">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2>Squad</h2>
<p>Squad is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Forth_(programming_language)" rel="nofollow noopener">Forth</a> interpreter that runs on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CHIP-8" rel="nofollow noopener">SCHIP</a> virtual machine. It extends the 8-bit operations of this host machine to 16 bit "cells", per tradition, which also allows pointers to be easily transported and manipulated on the stacks. The parameter and return stacks have room for 32 cells apiece, and at startup there is a bit over 1kb of free space available for user definitions.</p>
<p>While many niceties are missing from the built-in lexicon, due to space constraints, Squad is a fairly complete Forth environment, with a conventional outer and inner interpreter, immediate words, and a mutable return stack.&nbsp;Squad's functionality compares favorably to&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/JohnEarnest/chip8Archive/blob/master/src/applejak" rel="nofollow noopener"></a><a href="https://internet-janitor.itch.io/applejak">Applejak</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://internet-janitor.itch.io/bulb">Bulb</a>.</p>
<p>Dictionary entries consist of a pointer to the previous entry (or 0 for the root entry), a "type" cell (see "&gt;type") which distinguishes immediate words with its high byte and word classes with its low byte, the name of the word as a string (see "&gt;name"), and the body of the word itself (see "&gt;body"). Strings are represented with a custom encoding in which each character is a byte, and strings are null-terminated by the byte 0xFF. Properly-formed characters should be multiples of 5, and represent indices into the following alphabet:</p>
<pre>0123456789abcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz+-&lt;&gt;=!@.,:;[]
</pre>
<p>Source code and other materials are also available on <a href="https://github.com/JohnEarnest/chip8Archive/tree/master/src/squad" rel="nofollow noopener">the CHIP-8 Archive</a>.</p>
<h2>Controls</h2>
<p>The ASWD keys and E are always interchangeable with the arrow keys and space.</p>
<p>The outer interpreter will prompt the user for a token at a time, and then either append it to the current definition or execute it, based on "mode". Whenever text is drawn with an inverted background, it is a pending input. Pressing right-arrow or space will confirm a selection, while the up and down arrows cycle between available options.</p>
<p>First, the outer interpreter will ask the user to choose between several coarse categories- a number ("num"), or one of six categories of word, described in detail below. Numbers are always shown in 16-bit hexadecimal. The up and down arrows will increment or decrement the number, while 2 and X will increment or decrement the the number by 256 at a time, to ease entering pointers and large values. If the user is ever prompted to enter a previously unused word name (see "name"), the entry can be terminated by choosing a space character (which will confirm the name up to but not including the space), or by pressing space (which will confirm the name up to and including the present pending character). Pressing Q while entering a new name will back up one character.</p>
<p>At the top level of the outer interpreter, the user may also press `Z`, which is a shorthand for entering ".s"; it will print the current contents of the parameter stack on a new line without modifying it.</p>
<h2>Simple Examples</h2>
<p>Bump allocator:</p>
<pre>: allot here @ + here ! ;</pre>
<p>Calculate and print some terms of the Fibonacci sequence imperatively:</p>
<pre>: fib  0 1 loop dup . swap over + dup 100 &gt; until ;</pre>
<h2>Vocabulary</h2>
<p>The following word lists include stack effects in parentheses. The names to the left of the "--" sign are the input arguments, bottom to top,&nbsp;and the names to the right are the results, if any, bottom to top.</p>
<h3>IO</h3>
<p>Input and output words. Type code 1.</p>
<ul><li>emit ( char -- ) print a single character to the terminal. The high byte of "char" is ignored.</li><li>space ( -- ) print a space to the terminal.</li><li>cr ( -- ) advance terminal output to a new line.</li><li>erase ( -- ) un-print a single character from the current line of terminal output.</li><li>type ( str -- ) given a string (as described above), print it to the terminal.</li><li>untype ( str -- ) erase a string, by issuing "erase" for each character.</li><li>num ( -- n ) prompt the user to enter a 16-bit number.</li><li>name ( -- ) prompt the user to enter a string for a new word name, appending this string to "here".</li><li>word ( type -- xt ) prompt the user to select the name of an existing word. If "type" is 0, any word. Otherwise, it should be the type code of one of these categories.</li><li>token ( -- x flag ) prompt the user for a token, as in the outer interpreter. If "flag" is 0, "x" is a number. Otherwise it's a dictionary entry ("xt").</li></ul>
<h3>Core</h3>
<p>Fundamental forth primitives. Type code 2.</p>
<ul><li>dup ( x -- x x ) copy the top of the parameter stack.</li><li>drop ( x -- ) discard the top of the parameter stack.</li><li>over ( x y -- x y x ) copy the second item on the parameter stack.</li><li>swap ( x y -- y x ) exchange the top two items on the parameter stack.</li><li>r&gt; ( | x -- x | ) move an item from the parameter stack to the return stack.</li><li>&gt;r ( x | -- | x ) move an item from the return stack to the parameter stack.</li><li>! ( x addr -- ) write a 16-bit value x to "addr".</li><li>c! ( x addr -- ) write an 8-bit value (the low byte of x) to "addr".</li><li>@ ( addr -- x ) read a 16-bit value from addr.</li><li>c@ ( addr -- x ) read an 8-bit value from addr.</li><li>not ( x -- flag ) logically invert the flag x.</li><li>&gt; ( x y -- flag ) is x greater than y?</li><li>&lt; ( x y -- flag ) is x less than y?</li><li>= ( x y -- flag ) is x equal to y?</li><li>xor ( x y -- z ) bitwise XOR of x and y.</li><li>and ( x y -- z ) bitwise AND of x and y.</li><li>or ( x y -- z ) bitwise OR of x and y.</li><li>- ( x y -- z ) difference of x and y.</li><li>+ ( x y -- z ) sum of x and y.</li></ul>
<h3>Mem</h3>
<p>Words concerning working with memory and dictionary entries. Type code 3.</p>
<ul><li>here ( -- addr ) a variable containing the address of the first available cell of memory.</li><li>head ( -- addr ) a variable containing the xt of the most recent dictionary entry.</li><li>mode ( -- addr ) a variable containing 0 during interpretation or 1 during compilation.</li><li>, ( x -- ) write a cell to here, incrementing here by 2.</li><li>,c ( x -- ) write a byte to here, incrementing here by 1.</li><li>,ret ( -- ) append an exit to the current definition. This word performs tail-call elimination if the exit follows a threaded code subroutine call.</li><li>,lit ( x -- ) append a literal (push a number) to the current definition.</li><li>,jump ( addr -- ) append an unconditional branch to threaded code at addr to the current definition.</li><li>,jump0 ( addr -- ) append a conditional branch (branch if top of parameter stack is 0) to threaded code at addr to the current definition.</li><li>,call ( xt -- ) append a subroutine call to the current definition. This word will do the right thing whether the provided xt is a "native" (built-in) or threaded code subroutine.</li><li>&gt;type ( xt -- n ) given a dictionary entry, get its category. High byte is the immediate flag, low byte is the category type code.</li><li>&gt;name ( xt -- str ) given a dictionary entry, get the address of its name (suitable for "type").</li><li>&gt;body ( xt -- addr ) given a dictionary entry, get the address where its body begins.</li><li>create ( -- ) prompt for a name, and create a new dictionary entry with that name.</li><li>exec ( xt -- ) given a dictionary entry, execute the word. interpretation counterpart to ",call".</li></ul>
<h3>Flow</h3>
<p>Immediate words, mostly for dealing with control flow and compilation state. Type code 4.</p>
<ul><li>if ... (else) ... then: basic conditional control structure. if consumes a boolean flag.</li><li>loop ... (again | until | while): basic infinite and conditional loops. until and while consume a boolean flag.</li><li>:imm ( -- )&nbsp;prompt for a new name, and then begin defining an immediate word. Counterpart to ":".</li><li>: &nbsp;( -- )&nbsp;prompt for a new name, and then begin defining an ordinary word.</li><li>; &nbsp;( -- )&nbsp;terminate a word and stop compiling.</li><li>exit ( -- )&nbsp;early return from a word; do not stop compiling.</li><li>[ &nbsp;&nbsp;( -- )&nbsp;switch to interpreting. Use with "]" and ",lit" to pre-evaluate constant expressions, for example.</li><li>] ( --&nbsp;)&nbsp;switch to compiling.</li></ul>
<h3>Env</h3>
<p>Helper words for maintaining and inspecting the Forth environment. Type code 5.</p>
<ul><li>free ( -- x ) how many bytes of memory are available?</li><li>forget ( -- ) prompt for a word name, and destroy that dictionary entry as well as all later definitions. This can really donk up your interpreter if you apply it to internal bits of Squad.</li><li>.s ( -- ) display the contents of the parameter stack without altering it.</li><li>words ( -- ) list all available words.</li></ul>
<h3>User</h3>
<p>"User-defined" (non-primitive) words. Type code 6.</p>
<pre>:    1+     1 +    ; ( x -- y )
:imm quote  0 word ; ( -- xt )</pre>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://internet-janitor.itch.io/squad</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26188165</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 01:06:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
