<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 20]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 20. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 08:23:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-20.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 08:23:10 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Cell Signaling Technologies – Detailed 3D model of human cells]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 76 | Comments 23 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25055908">thread link</a>) | @ozten
<br/>
November 10, 2020 | http://www.digizyme.com/cst_landscapes.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.digizyme.com/cst_landscapes.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="u6389-bw">
     <div id="u6389"><!-- column -->
      <div id="u6389_align_to_page">
       <!-- m_editable region-id="editable-static-tag-U6264-BP_infinity" template="cst_landscapes.html" data-type="html" data-ice-options="disableImageResize,link,txtStyleTarget" -->
       <p><span id="u6264">Cell Signaling Technologies</span></p>
       <!-- /m_editable -->
       <!-- m_editable region-id="editable-static-tag-U6399-BP_infinity" template="cst_landscapes.html" data-type="html" data-ice-options="disableImageResize,link,txtStyleTarget" -->
       <p>Molecular Landscapes</p>
       <!-- /m_editable -->
       
       
       
      </div>
     </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.digizyme.com/cst_landscapes.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25055908</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 06:02:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Exodus of Silicon Valley]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 57 | Comments 78 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25052818">thread link</a>) | @Reedx
<br/>
November 10, 2020 | https://breakingground.us/exodus/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://breakingground.us/exodus/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-4180">
					
					
					
					
					<div>
					<p>On the day the sun didn’t rise in San Francisco, the early warning signs came through the screen. The 6:30 a.m. Zoom always requires unnatural light, making the outlines of faces fuzzy. The natural morning light, combined with the “Touch Up My Appearance” feature on 2020’s preferred video conferencing system, hides the marks of age and sleeplessness that most of us seek to mask. But by 9:00, the fluorescent light was still dominating the screen, and the darkness outside our windows had turned to infernal orange.</p>
<p>The scientific explanation for our sunless day in September is pretty dull. The clouds of soot from the largest California wildfire in history intermixed with the Bay Area’s perennial fog, turning the usual sepia hue of dirty global cities into an apocalyptic blood-orange sky. Though Twitter blamed the hellscape on far more menacing forces, the direct cause of our Blade Runner Day was mostly carbon clinging to the blue-light hues while letting the red pierce through.</p>
<p>If we were more like ancient peoples, many joked, we would assume the gods were enraged. We’d be running for the hills to escape their wrath, or at least head straight for our prepper bunkers. That we are unlike ancient people is actually the only myth, as this is exactly the exodus that is happening in Silicon Valley right now—and will continue for the next few years as true believers deliver themselves from this promised land.</p>
<p><a href="https://breakingground.us/from-ashes/">It’s time to build</a>, yes. But it’s also time to leave.</p>
<p>The battle over tech’s supremacy has been waged and all of our premonitions came true: We wanted flying cars and got vertical take-off innovation hubs from every car maker in America. Software has not only eaten the world, but feasted on your screen-weary eyes. It has swallowed your children, your church, your bank, and your politics, and somehow it all feels inevitable. That these feats of human progress—of instant connectivity in a now homebound world—became the scapegoat of our time is another symptom of the era’s end, cueing the quiet exodus of builders who had bigger aspirations than the same-day shipping that keeps our households afloat.</p>
<p>Now, Silicon Valley is witnessing a reckoning, but it’s not the long-awaited one predicted by the New York press, or the antitrust bonanza that Washington longs for because too many people seem satisfied getting their news from Facebook. The reckoning is more of a realization that tech exceeded expectations and somehow squandered the fruit of its own garden, and that a city on a hill that could have supported so much innovation was not Florence in the Renaissance nor the Athenian Academy with MacBooks. Rather, it became a government-sponsored needle exchange, a haven for the homeless and forgotten that put government’s paralysis on display downtown on Market Street.</p>
<blockquote><p>2020 is not the great reckoning predicted in the book of Revelation, despite the fires, the plagues, and the wailing on Twitter. It is the resignation and determination of Exodus, of a dogged people packing up U-Hauls and fleeing this frontier state to seek an even newer, more eternal world.</p></blockquote>
<p>San Francisco had four times as many deaths from overdose this year as it did from the COVID-19 virus.</p>
<p>2020 is not the great reckoning predicted in the book of Revelation, despite the fires, the plagues, and the wailing on Twitter. It is the resignation and determination of Exodus, of a dogged people packing up U-Hauls and fleeing this frontier state to seek an even newer, more eternal world.</p>
<p>* * *</p>
<p>The computer revolution of the late twentieth century has yet to be named as an epoch, but we can assume that nomenclature will begin in the coming years, alongside the battle for what it all really meant.</p>
<p>What we now call our “technological age” was supposed to be a full-throated and enduring argument for the future, not unlike previous epochs in history that pushed art, science, philosophy, and religion forward in dizzying ways that run counter to ordinary time. The Enlightenment. The Renaissance. The French Revolution. These movements now sit as categories on our bookshelves with clear beginnings and ends, and more importantly, clear hubs and cities of frenetic building that drove the ethos forward. Many books assume that contemporary critics or philosophers were blissfully ignorant to the unraveling of their revolutions, but we should not assume that contemporaries did not feel the same twilight setting. The figurative orange skies always creep in before dawn.</p>


<p>Which brings us to the supposed death of Silicon Valley, a fate that has long been predicted but with data now finally catching up. San Francisco apartment rents in 2020 have deflated by 20 percent after an up-up-and-away decade that made the city truly unlivable. Home inventory has reached a fifteen-year high in a city blighted by restrictive housing policy that makes construction cranes as miraculous as stumbling upon a burning bush. The growth in online sales-tax collection, according to the <em>San Francisco Chronicle</em>, is the lowest of all counties in the state of California. And public tech companies, such as Pinterest, paid upwards of $90 million to break its lease in downtown San Francisco. Some would argue this is a clear end to Bay Area tech dominance, while others would point to the many new unicorns that popped up this year despite the once-in-a-century pandemic. No one’s living here, yet somehow the companies are still growing.</p>
<p>Silicon Valley doesn’t really have cultural critics to weigh in on whether this era is officially over, but we do have venture capitalists. And our Nostradomuses are telling us that change is afoot.</p>
<p><em>Do we really need this office? The founders all have left.</em></p>
<p><em>Their entire partnership is now living in Montana. It’s only a two-hour flight away!</em></p>
<p><em>Denver seems like a good option, but Reno has no state income tax.</em></p>
<p>The weirdness of this exodus is that it is not driven by fear. Technologists weren’t <em>really </em>driven out by plague or fire or San Francisco’s insatiable need for higher tax revenue. Those ills were always apparent, and yet people stayed to carry the torch.</p>
<p>The exodus of tech’s true believers may be that the covenant is finally fulfilled. That when America—along with the rest of the world—met their darkest hour and turned inward, the technology that was long ridiculed as frivolous or dangerous led us to relative normalcy. The Zooms. The Tiger Kings. The Signal chats. The Slack jokes. An election news cycle that plowed ruthlessly forward on Twitter. Though inconvenient, mothers and fathers set their children in front of screens to occupy them for <em>just</em> long enough to survive a terrible year. And maybe, just maybe, the same-day-shipping racket that made Jeff Bezos the richest man alive was actually a feat of human genius that held the country together when public infrastructure and the social fabric were fraying at the seams. Perhaps our lowly software revolution was actually the fruition of a long-held California dream, when the physical world forced us inside and virtual life prevailed.</p>
<blockquote><p>Silicon Valley is no longer a place, they’ll say. It’s a way of being, of building, and the latest embodiment of belief in human progress. And it’s spreading faster than the viruses and the wildfires and the apocalyptic threats that mire our physical world.</p></blockquote>
<p>For that triumph, the nerds can now smell the impending scapegoating of their success. And like so many of history’s prophets and heretics, those who believe most fervently in the promise of technology are beginning their long march away from the Valley.</p>
<p>And they will substitute the virtual world for the physical space that once defined this movement. Silicon Valley is no longer a place, they’ll say. It’s a way of being, of building, and the latest embodiment of belief in human progress. And it’s spreading faster than the viruses and the wildfires and the apocalyptic threats that mire our physical world.</p>
<p>Silicon Valley is over. The exodus is just beginning.</p>
					</div> <!-- .entry-content -->

				
				</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://breakingground.us/exodus/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25052818</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 22:19:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Flaws of “Subscription Fatigue”, “SVOD Fatigue”, and the “Streaming Wars”]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 21 | Comments 19 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25051292">thread link</a>) | @bschne
<br/>
November 10, 2020 | https://www.matthewball.vc/all/misnomers | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.matthewball.vc/all/misnomers">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-block-type="2" id="block-96dbb3b03808a860d80e"><div><p>When we consider the state of tech-media in 2020, there are a few common narratives. The most inescapable is the “Streaming Wars”. In November, I argued that <a href="https://www.matthewball.vc/all/minedmedia">this term was a misnomer</a>. Digital/streaming/OTT video is really just <em>a</em> battle in a much larger war: the “ecosystem war”. And for the most part, this war is fought asymmetrically. Apple and Amazon both sell digital media devices, third-party media content, and their own original content, for example. However, Apple isn’t an e-retailer nor a diversified enterprise cloud services provider, and Amazon doesn’t even have a smartphone, personal computer, watch or non-video app store. I’ll come back to this idea, but understanding the differences between these companies and their motivations is helpful when considering two other popular phases that are unhelpful at best and misleading at worst: “subscription fatigue” and “SVOD fatigue”.</p><p><strong>“Subscription Fatigue”</strong></p><p>The “subscription economy”, by definition, presumes that the overall “economy” – from products, to services, content, transportation, labor and more – is shifting over to “subscriptions”. Thus, to claim that consumers have “subscription fatigue” is to say that they have “spending fatigue”.</p><p>As always, most consumers will say they wish they spent less money, bought fewer things, and enjoyed lower prices. However, it makes little sense to say that the decision to buy TV subscriptions, radio subscriptions, toothbrush subscriptions, video gaming subscriptions, dog food subscriptions, car subscriptions, or productivity software subscriptions should drive “subscription fatigue” or mean each subscription competes with one another. For decades, consumers have bought TV, music, toothbrushes, video games, dog food, cars and Microsoft Office. What’s new is that they all have similar models – digitally-based, predominantly D2C subscriptions. This changes nothing about the individual value or baseline need for them.</p><p>Of course, the “subscription economy” does mean that step one of a recession will be to “re-evaluate all subscriptions”. However, this does not mean subscription <em>fatigue</em> should be considered a real “thing”, let alone a defining element of modern-day competition. Furthermore, payment model – upfront v. recurring, subscription v. á la carte, online v. offline – is irrelevant to what’s “re-evaluated” and not. Some subscriptions are “necessities”, like toilet paper, while others are concerned with discretionary spend, such as Office 365 or Netflix or Tinder. This latter group isn’t competitive because they’re “subscriptions”, but because there is, as always, finite spending money for non-essential items. </p><p>To this end, it’s important to highlight subscriptions are often a <em>preferred</em> buying path for consumers. Most would rather (or can only afford) $10 a month for a multi-year license to Microsoft Office for $300. Subscriptions also meaningfully reduce the cognitive burden of repeat decision making. No longer do you need to “track” your toothbrush for wear, risk “running out” of toilet paper and then be forced to overpay for a small-volume purchase, or need to scan and hoard coupons to ensure a great deal. Similarly, many consumers would rather marginally overpay for an all-you-can-eat subscription than optimize for specific tiers of use. In fact, most of us have caustic responses to per unit pricing, often to the point of irrationality (e.g. $40 for 35 loads of laundry detergent v. $1.00 per load). Amazon Prime is based on the <em>need</em> to get shipping fees out of the way once, versus fight them over and over and over and over, even if the effective shipping cost went up for a consumer, or the lack of shipping costs led to unnecessary purchases.</p><p>The rise of fully flexible monthly commitments also means that consumers no longer have to worry about having made a bad decision and being stuck with it. In this sense, every subscription is still á la carte, but unlike in the analog era, the default outcome of “doing nothing” is to keep getting value you enjoy rather than running out of a thing you need. </p><p><em>(Note that none of this means that a digital subscription business is a “good” one. Many sub-categories of CPGs and foodstuffs, not to mention music or fitness equipment, weren’t good business before the shift to subscription. The fact they shifted to subscriptions doesn’t inherently change this, just as it doesn’t mean they suddenly compete with all other subscriptions).</em></p><p><strong>“SVOD Fatigue”</strong></p><p>Of course, the nuances of “subscription fatigue” is separate from the question of “Subscription <em>VOD</em> fatigue”. It is obvious consumers don’t need 20 Netflixes. However, they’re not being asked to buy 20 Netflixes. It’s wrong to treat Fox Nation, Netflix, ESPN, and Twitch as competitors, let alone interchangeable “units of SVOD”. They serve very different functions and offer very different content. Just as Spotify and the <em>New York Times</em> and Amazon Prime shipping each do.</p><p>Amazon and Apple TV+, meanwhile, aren’t Netflixes – not in monetization, content volumes, or strategy. Now, if Amazon or Apple’s SVOD services can monetize so dramatically better through the Prime and iOS ecosystem than Netflix can via direct consumer spend and a singular focus, they can, in theory, “kill” Netflix – should they so choose – but that has nothing to do with SVOD fatigue nor the number of viable SVODs.</p><p>The question of SVOD fatigue isn’t about “how many SVODs will the average household have”. It’s really about “how many different roles are there to be played in video”. And the answer here is mostly path dependent – it depends on the innovation, risk taking, and discovery that happens in the marketplace, as well as timing. No one knew “live streaming video games” was an opportunity until Twitch, for example. And while Twitch likely steals <em>time</em> away from the video ecosystem, the viability of the Twitch subscription doesn’t mean that the number of viable OTT services has reduced.</p><p><strong>The Question</strong></p><p>All of which is to say what matters in SVOD is simple and not unique to SVOD: <span>A service will succeed if (1) it addresses a real, outstanding customer want/need; (2) at an appropriate price or value to the consumer; and (3) while generating sustainable economics</span>. </p><p>Quibi is a good example here. The company believes that there is an outstanding need for a new type of content, focused on a different time and place, under a different viewing behavior and focused on a specific audience. If it is right, and it can build up a defensible leadership position before other players replicate it, a new subscription will be possible and it doesn’t matter how many SVODs a customer already has (just as whether they have NYT or Spotify doesn’t matter). But of course, if you ask consumers “do you wish you had fewer subscriptions” or “fewer SVODs”, they will say yes – especially if they don’t really know what the new “thing” is. Note, too, that Pay-TV studies have been promising that 10%–30% of subscribers will cancel each year. They never do… because enough value remains. </p><p>More broadly, this three-point framework is well established (it actually has nothing to do with video). Over the past forty years, we have seen countless examples of “networks” launching into hyper-saturated marketplaces with hyper-specific but unproven (and often openly derided) theses regarding outstanding consumer wants and needs. Almost all of these have succeeded. In fact, they usually spawned several direct competitors – showing that the unmet want was even larger than originally anticipated. &nbsp;</p><p>For example…</p><ul data-rte-list="default"><li><p><em>1972: HBO launched a network focused on the most valuable TV time, Sunday night, with an unprecedented monetization model (á la carte consumer spend and no advertising), and focused only on reruns of Hollywood movies. It was ultimately bought by 25% of TV homes, became the most profitable network in the world and the market leader in quality. And this was despite the launches of Showtime (1976), Starz (1994) and Epix (2009).</em></p></li><li><p><em>1977: Nickelodeon launched 24/7 content only for kids. No longer was kids content relegated just to afternoon and Sunday morning blocks. In the 2000s, Nickelodeon became the most watched cable network, despite having spun-off several other Nick-branded channels and seen the launch of The Disney Channel in 1983.</em></p></li><li><p><em>1979: ESPN launched a 24/7 sports channel, ultimately with the highest programming budget in the world. In 2019, it brought in more than $2.5B in profits, with an annual revenue of roughly $9B. In 2009, Fox launched its own suite of 24/7 Fox-branded sports networks.</em></p></li><li><p><em>1980: CNN launched a 24/7 news channel. Today, it generates an estimated $800MM a year in cash flow on $2B in revenue, and several other 24/7 networks exist.</em></p></li><li><p><em>1981: MTV launched a 24/7 music video and culture channel that focused only on young audiences. The result was the first new Hollywood film/TV conglomerate in decades. Within years, MTV had launched several other 24/7 networks, while competitors launched even more focused versions, such as CMT.</em></p></li><li><p><em>1983: BET launched a 24/7 network focused on black American audiences. In 2001, the company was sold to Viacom for $3B. Several other black-focused networks exist today. </em></p></li><li><p><em>1996: Fox News launched a 24/7 news channel… only for half of news watchers. It now generates more than $1.5B in cash on $2.5B+ revenue</em></p></li></ul><p>Of course, this sort of logic can be used to justify faulty assumptions around what opportunity exists, where, how large it might be, how durable it is, etc. In addition, these specifics gaps were open because of technological limitations. A network like ABC could only air one thing at a time – and therefore there were structural impediments to serving “everyone”. Netflix, meanwhile, can air anything, at any time, to every viewer, and on an individual basis.</p><p>But the crucial point here is that it’s wrong to think about the “number” of subscription video services, just as it was wrong to think about how “many” networks were in the cable bundle in 1980, 1985, 1990, and so on. In fact, it’s incredibly close …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.matthewball.vc/all/misnomers">https://www.matthewball.vc/all/misnomers</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.matthewball.vc/all/misnomers</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25051292</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 20:18:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Burnout can exacerbate work stress, further promoting a vicious circle]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 282 | Comments 181 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25048455">thread link</a>) | @rustoo
<br/>
November 10, 2020 | https://www.uni-mainz.de/presse/aktuell/12451_ENG_HTML.php | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.uni-mainz.de/presse/aktuell/12451_ENG_HTML.php">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
            <!-- Hier kommen Imagescroller und ZGN, sowie... -->
            <!-- Offene Universität Scroller --><!-- Default Row -->
            <!-- Spaltenlayout gemäß Einstellungen für option_schalter_linke_spalte, option_schalter_rechte_spalte -->
            <!-- Ende linke Spalte -->
            <article id="spaltemitte">
               <!-- Beginn Inhalt Spalte Mitte -->
               <!-- Indexüberschrift:  -->
               <h3>
                  Work stress and burnout are mutually reinforcing / Surprisingly, the effect of work stress on burnout is much smaller than the effect of burnout on work stress
               </h3>
               <p>
                  10 November 2020
               </p>
               <p>
                  Stress and overload in the workplace are increasing worldwide and are often considered a cause of burnout. Indeed, a new study shows that work stress and burnout are mutually reinforcing. However, contrary to popular belief, burnout has a much greater impact on work stress than vice versa. "This means that the more severe a person's burnout becomes, the more stressed they will feel at work, such as being under time pressure, for example," said Professor Christian Dormann of Johannes Gutenberg University Mainz (JGU). Employees suffering from burnout should be timely provided with adequate support in order to break the vicious circle between work stress and burnout.
               </p>
               <p>
                  Symptoms of burnout include exhaustion, cynicism, and reduced performance. "The most important burnout symptom is the feeling of total exhaustion – to the extent that it cannot be remedied by normal recovery phases of an evening, a weekend, or even a vacation," said Dormann. "To protect themselves from further exhaustion, some try to build a psychological distance to their work, that is, they alienate themselves from their work as well as the people associated with it and become more cynical," added Dr. Christina Guthier. She conducted the study as part of her doctoral thesis in Dormann's research group and was awarded with the dissertation prize of the Alfred Teves Foundation in 2020. The study has recently been published in <em>Psychological Bulletin</em>.
               </p>
               <p>
                  For the joint publication with Professor Christian Dormann and Professor Manuel Völkle of Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin, Christina Guthier evaluated 48 longitudinal studies of burnout and work stress comprising 26,319 participants. The average age in the initial survey was about 42 years, 44 percent of the respondents were men. The longitudinal studies from 1986 to 2019 came from various countries, including predominantly European countries as well as Israel, the USA, Canada, Mexico, South Africa, Australia, China, and Taiwan.
               </p>
               <h4>
                  Stopping the downward spiral and reducing the effect of burnout on work stress
               </h4>
               <p>
                  The results challenge, or at least relativize, the common perception that work stress is the driving force behind burnout. "Burnout can be triggered by a work situation, but that is not always the case," Dormann pointed out. Once burnout begins, it develops only very gradually, building up slowly over time. Ultimately it leads to work being increasingly perceived as stressful: The amount of work is too much, time is too short, and work stress is too great. "When exhausted, the ability to cope with stress usually decreases. As a result, even smaller tasks can be perceived as significantly more strenuous," explained Guthier, the first author of the article. "We expected an effect of burnout on work stress; the strength of the effect was very surprising," she noted. The effect of burnout on perceived work stress can be somewhat mitigated if employees have more control over their own work and receive support from colleagues or superiors.
               </p>
               <p>
                  According to Dormann, a new research area is emerging on the basis of this unique data because the strong boomerang effect of burnout on work stress has not yet been investigated. Key questions that need to be addressed are: how can the effects of burnout on perceived work stress be reduced and how can the development of this vicious circle be prevented? Dormann and Guthier suggest that the place to start is with management behavior. Employees should have the opportunity to give feedback on their work stress at any time and be appreciated. Last but not least, proper recovery could also help to stop the downward spiral.
               </p><!-- Ende Inhalt Spalte Mitte -->
            </article>            <!--Ende-->
                     </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.uni-mainz.de/presse/aktuell/12451_ENG_HTML.php</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25048455</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 17:25:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Gods on Hacker News]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 303 | Comments 157 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25047838">thread link</a>) | @ivm
<br/>
November 10, 2020 | https://www.riknieu.com/the-gods-on-hackernews/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.riknieu.com/the-gods-on-hackernews/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
				<p>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@tank_ghisletti?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Francisco Ghisletti</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/greek-gods?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Unsplash</a>)</p><p>(This post is mostly fun and tongue-in-cheek, please contain your indignation.)</p><p>Every so often I encounter a comment on HackerNews that involuntarily makes my jaw drop, head shake and eyes water. It's usually concerning what some on HackerNews consider a 'worthwhile' amount of money you can earn as an solopreneur or maker VS being an employee. </p><p>Obviously, it's probably a small minority of the silent masses who scroll through HN daily who have these views, but comments like the following, or a variant of it comes up so often I can't help but feel that a decent part of the community is <em>ridiculously</em> out of touch with the rest of humanity. </p><p>Behold.</p><!--kg-card-begin: html--><blockquote><p lang="und" dir="ltr">😂 <a href="https://t.co/mg1UFHxp08">https://t.co/mg1UFHxp08</a></p>— Pete from No CS Degree (@petecodes) <a href="https://twitter.com/petecodes/status/1326144308706209798?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 10, 2020</a></blockquote> <!--kg-card-end: html--><p>$1000 per month from a side project is considered meh. 😳 🙃</p><p>And here's another from the same day,</p><figure><img src="https://www.riknieu.com/content/images/2020/11/soundslikealot.png"></figure><p>And from the same user a few scrolls later,</p><figure><img src="https://www.riknieu.com/content/images/2020/11/FANG.png"></figure><p>My god. Look, the commenter had the self awareness to bring up regional cost of living and that not everyone can work at the FAMANGs of the world, but really? Getting $3.7 million dollars for just 7 years of work is, like, a bad deal?</p><p>To consider making $500K pa as a doable, realistic salary to be taken into account when deciding between starting a company or just seeking a job... Like us millennials say, "I can't. Even." </p><p>That annual salary far outstrips what I can reasonably expect to earn in a decade, and I'm a developer working for a fintech startup with a good couple of years under my belt. For most people in the world, $500K pa is a <em><strong>preposterous</strong></em> amount of money. </p><p>I'm too lazy to go dig up more examples, but I'm sure you'll find some more gems like these if you go digging around on past threads.</p><p>This kind of poo-pooing of what most - and I'm talking 90% of the US population, never mind the rest of the world! - would consider rather large amounts of money is incredibly mind-blowing and makes my head spin.</p><p>Now I'm sure that in commenters like the above's worlds, that kind of money is indeed average and peanuts, but I wanted to write this article for myself and the rest of us to just try and deal. </p><p>I'm trying to make sense of the fact that I'm on this forum, interacting with people everyday, talking about current events and issues, that make more money per year than I can even imagine. In a way we're peers, but more realistically they're like the gods of Olympus who occasionally slum it with the rest of us.</p><p>So if you're like me, and you consider even a $1000 as lot of money, let's look at this as average mortals should.</p><h2 id="1-1000pm-is-a-flippen-lot">1) $1000pm is a flippen lot</h2><p>Let's go with the $1000 pm example, because figures like $3.6 million is, to be frank, in the realms of La-La land for me and almost everyone I know personally. </p><p>And let's - for the sake of simplicity - assume that you can take home 60% of that revenue as net earnings. And that the project doesn't take up more free time with maintenance and support issues than you can handle on your own. That's $600 per month. Extra. From a thing on the side. </p><p>I realise that I live in one of those cheap, unappealing parts of the world, but that kinda money would easily cover me and my family's rent every month, and then some. Do you realise how much of a mental weight that can take off a persons shoulders? To know rent is covered over and above your day-job earnings?</p><p>Away with your $1000-is-not-worth-it malarky!</p><h2 id="2-making-money-with-your-own-products-is-hard-">2) Making money with your own products is HARD.</h2><p>Take a look at <a href="https://www.indiehackers.com/post/holy-heck-this-is-hard-8ebe864174">this post</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/mccrmx">Chris McCormick</a>, titled "<a href="https://www.indiehackers.com/post/holy-heck-this-is-hard-8ebe864174">Holy heck this is hard</a>". </p><p>When he last checked, 12 solo founders out of 17207 made more than $10K MRR. Only 54 products made more than $2000pm. I don't think I need to express that in ratios for you to see the probability of making a profitable project.</p><p>Starting a product and <em>actually earning money from it</em> is hard. Insanely hard. Hell, if you manage to make even $100pm from a side project you've got my respect. You've got me beat by a lot!</p><p>When I see makers on IndieHackers or Twitter celebrate $100 in sales I get genuinely excited for them. It's really an incredible feat. Bravo to them, I wish them luck and more success in the future.</p><h2 id="that-1000-per-month-can-grow">That $1000 per month can grow</h2><p>Another thing to consider is that earning a $1000 pm means your project is basically validated and ready to explode. With work, you could probably scale it to much higher multiples. </p><p>Sure, the money it makes is negligible to the higher beings in Silicon Valley, but for us regular plebs that's a <em>strong</em> signal that your project potentially has legs. It might even be a project you could sell for $3.7 million dollars in 7 years time, if you put the work in and get a little lucky.</p><h2 id="ya-but-rik-cost-of-living">Ya, but Rik, cost of living</h2><p>Sure, things cost more in the States. And more so in SanFran. But I can't just up and go live in the States. Nor pretty much anywhere else in the First World. A heck of a lot of the people frequenting HN, TW and IH on a daily basis could probably not either.</p><p>So for people like us, it's inspiring to read about some rando making a $1000 pm, on their own, independently. It gives us hope that some dude in Alabama could start a thing and sell it for more money than we could expect to earn in a lifetime as a salaried employee. Because maybe that means we could too.</p><p>Because they used the same tools we have access too(except for Stripe 😝). They had access to the same markets we could reach. </p><p>And they make the kinds of money with those tools that could buy people like us freedom. Freedom from being chained to a job, freedom from financial stress, and possibly even the freedom to move our families to better places in the world. Places that others just get born in.</p><p>So when you see smarmy comments on HackerNews new putting down the success of others, take a step back and realise, it's not meant for you. It's not personal. </p><p>These are merely the musings of a few lucky, privileged gods, reflecting on the toils of the mortals.</p><p>Thanks for reading. If you have any comments or suggestions, follow and contact me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/riknieu">@RikNieu</a>.</p><p>If you want to read more of my rants, sign up below and I'll mail you when I post new stuff. 👇</p>
			</section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.riknieu.com/the-gods-on-hackernews/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25047838</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 16:34:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Origins of the youtube-dl project]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 492 | Comments 50 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25047818">thread link</a>) | @rg3
<br/>
November 10, 2020 | https://rg3.name/202011071352.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rg3.name/202011071352.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
<div>
<h3><a href="https://rg3.name/202011071352.html">Origins of the youtube-dl project</a></h3>
<p>Posted on <time>2020-11-07T13:52Z</time>. Updated on <time>2020-11-10T16:28Z</time>.</p>


<p>As you may know, as of the time this text is being written <a href="https://github.com/ytdl-org/youtube-dl">youtube-dl’s repository at GitHub</a> is blocked due to a <a href="https://github.com/github/dmca/blob/master/2020/10/2020-10-23-RIAA.md">DMCA takedown letter</a> received by GitHub on behalf of the RIAA. While I cannot comment on the current maintainers' plans or ongoing discussions, in light of the claims made in that letter I thought it would be valuable to put in writing the first years of youtube-dl as the project creator and initial maintainer.</p>
<div>
<h4 id="_copper_thieves">Copper thieves</h4>
<p>All good stories need at least a villain so I have arbitrarily chosen copper thieves as the villains of the story that set in motion what youtube-dl is today. Back in 2006 I was living in a town 5 to 10 kilometers away from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Avil%C3%A9s">Avilés</a>, which is itself a small city or town in northern Spain. While people in Avilés enjoyed some nice infrastructures and services, including cable and ADSL Internet access, the area I lived in lacked those advantages. I was too far away from the telephone exchange to enjoy ADSL and copper thieves had been stealing copper wires along the way to it for years, causing telephone service outages from time to time and making the telephone company replace those wires with weaker and thinner wires, knowing they would likely be stolen again. This had been going on for several years at that point.</p>
<p>This meant my only choice for home Internet access so far had been a dial-up connection and a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Modem#Standardized_56k_(V.90/V.92)">56k V.90 modem</a>. In fact, connection quality was so poor I had to limit the modem to 33.6 kbps mode so the connection would be at least stable. Actual download speeds rarely surpassed 4 KB/sec. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/YouTube">YouTube</a> was gaining popularity then to the point it was purchased by Google at the end of that year.</p>
</div>
<div>
<h4 id="_up_all_night_to_get_some_bits">Up all night to get some bits</h4>
<p>Watching any YouTube video on the kind of connection I described above was certainly painful, as you can imagine. Any video that was moderately big would take ages to download. For example, a short 10 MB video would take, if you do the math, 40 minutes to download, making streaming impossible. A longer and higher-quality video would take several hours and render the connection unusable for other purposes while you waited for it to be available, not to mention the possibility of the connection being interrupted and having to start the download process again. Now imagine liking a specific video a lot after watching it and wanting to watch it a second or third time. Going through that process again was almost an act of masochism.</p>
<p>This situation made me interested in the possibility of downloading the videos I was trying to watch: if the video was interesting, having a copy meant I could watch it several times easily. Also, if the downloader was any good, maybe the download process could be resumed if the connection was interrupted, as it frequently was.</p>
<p>At the time, there were other solutions to download videos from YouTube, including a quite popular <a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/greasemonkey/">Greasemonkey</a> script. By pure chance, none of the few I tested were working when I did, so I decided to explore the possibility of creating my own tool. And that is, more or less, how youtube-dl was born. I made it a command-line program so it would be easy to use for me and wrote it in Python because it was easy thanks to its extensive standard library, with the nice side effect that it would be platform independent.</p>
</div>
<div>
<h4 id="_an_ethereal_start">An Ethereal start</h4>
<p>The initial version of the program only worked for YouTube videos. It had almost no internal design whatsoever because it was not needed. It did what it had to do as a simple script that proceeded straight to the point. Line count was merely 223, with only 143 being actual lines of code, 44 for comments and 36 of them blank. The name was chosen out of pure convenience: youtube-dl was an obvious name, hard to forget, and it could be intuitively typed as “Y-O-U-TAB” in my terminal.</p>
<p>Having been using Linux for several years at that point, I decided to publish the program under a free software license (MIT for those first versions) just in case someone could find it useful. Back then, GitHub did not exist and we had to “make do” with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SourceForge">SourceForge</a>, which had a bit of a tedious form that you needed to fill to create a new project. So, instead of going to SourceForge, I quickly published it under <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20060812055952/http://www.arrakis.es/~rggi3/youtube-dl/">the web space that my Internet provider gave me</a>. While not usual today, it was common for ISPs to give you an email address and some web space you could upload stuff to using FTP. That way, you could have your own personal website on the net. The first ever version made public was 2006.08.08, although I probably had been using the program for a few weeks at that point.</p>
<p>To create the program, I studied what the web browser was doing when watching a YouTube video using Firefox. If I recall correctly, Firefox didn’t yet have the development tools it has today to analyze network activity. Connections were mostly HTTP and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wireshark">Wireshark</a>, known as “Ethereal” up to that year, proved invaluable to inspect the network traffic coming in and out of my box when loading a YouTube video. I wrote youtube-dl with the specific goal of doing the same things the web browser was doing to retrieve the video. It even sent out a User-Agent string that was verbatim copied from Firefox for Linux, as a way to make sure the site would send the program the same version of video web pages that were used to study what the web browser was doing.</p>
<p>In addition, YouTube used <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adobe_Flash">Adobe Flash</a> back then for the player. Videos were served as Flash Video files (FLV), and this all meant a proprietary plugin was required to watch them on the browser (many will remember the dreaded <code>libflashplayer.so</code> library), which would have made any browser development tools useless. This proprietary plugin was a constant source of security advisories and problems. I used a Firefox extension called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flashblock">Flashblock</a> that prevented the plugin from being loaded by default and replaced embedded content using the plugin, in web pages, with placeholder elements containing a clickable icon so content would be loaded only on demand and the plugin library was not used unless requested by the user.</p>
<p>Flashblock had two nice side effects apart from making the browsing experience more secure. On the one hand, it removed a lot of noisy and obnoxious ads from many web pages, which could also be a source of security problems when served by third parties. On the other hand, it eased analyzing how videos were being downloaded by the video player. I would wait until the video page had finished downloading completely and then start logging traffic with Wireshark just before clicking on the embedded video player placeholder icon, allowing it to load. This way, the only traffic to analyze was related to the plugin downloading the video player application and the application itself downloading the video.</p>
<p>It’s also worth noting the Flash Player plugin back then <a href="https://www.nirsoft.net/articles/copy_flash_flv_temp_file.html">was already downloading a copy of those videos to your hard drive</a> (they were stored in <code>/tmp</code> under Linux) and many users relied on that functionality to keep a copy of them without using additional tools. youtube-dl was simply more convenient because it could retrieve the video title and name the file more appropriately in an automated way, for example.</p>
</div>
<div>
<h4 id="_ahh_fresh_meat">Ahh, fresh meat!</h4>
<p>The Flash Player plugin was eventually <a href="https://www.omgubuntu.co.uk/2010/09/saving-flash-videos-in-linux-tmp-no-longer-works">modified so videos wouldn’t be so easily available to grab</a>. One of the first measures was to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unlink_(Unix)">unlink</a> the video file after creating it, so the i-node would still exist and be available to the process using it (until it was closed) while keeping the file invisible from the file system point of view. It was still possible to grab the file by using the <code>/proc</code> file system to examine file descriptors used by the browser process, but with every one of those small steps youtube-dl turned to be more and more convenient.</p>
<p>As many free and open source enthusiasts back then, I used <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freecode">Freshmeat</a> to subscribe to new releases of projects I was interested in. When I created youtube-dl, I also created a project entry for it in that website so users could easily get notifications of new releases and a change log listing new features, fixes and improvements. Freshmeat could also be browsed to find new and interesting projects and its front page contained the latest updates, which usually amounted to only a few dozens a day. It’s only my guess that’s the way <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joe_Barr">Joe Barr</a> (rest in peace), an editor for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linux.com">linux.com</a>, found out about the program and decided to write <a href="https://www.linux.com/news/cli-magic-enhance-your-youtube-viewing-pleasure/">an article about it</a> back in 2006. Linux.com was a bit different then and I think it was one of the frequently-visited sites for Linux enthusiasts together with other classics like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slashdot">Slashdot</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LWN.net">Linux Weekly News</a>. At least, it was for me.</p>
<p>From that point on, youtube-dl’s popularity started to grow and I started getting some emails from time to time to thank me for creating and maintaining the program.</p>
</div>
<div>
<h4 id="_measuring_buckets_of_bits">Measuring buckets of bits</h4>
<p>Fast forward to the year 2008. youtube-dl’s popularity had kept growing slowly and users frequently asked me to create similar programs to download from more sites, a request I had conceded a few times. It was at that point that I decided to rewrite the program from scratch and make it support multiple video sites natively. I had some simple ideas that would separate the program internals into several pieces. To simplify the most important parts: one would be the file downloader, common for every website, and another one would be the information extractors: objects (classes) that would contain code specific to a video site. When given a URL or pseudo-URL, the information extractors would be queried to know which one could handle that type of URL and then requested to extract information about that video or list of videos, with the primary goal of obtaining the video URL or a list of video URLs with available formats, together with some other metadata like the video titles, for example.</p>
<p>I also took the chance to switch version control systems and change where the project would be hosted. …</p></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://rg3.name/202011071352.html">https://rg3.name/202011071352.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rg3.name/202011071352.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25047818</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 16:33:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Jack Ma's Bund Finance Summit Speech]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 87 | Comments 30 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25047544">thread link</a>) | @ceohockey60
<br/>
November 10, 2020 | https://interconnected.blog/jack-ma-bund-finance-summit-speech/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://interconnected.blog/jack-ma-bund-finance-summit-speech/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">
    <div>

        <article>

            


            <section>
                <div>
                    <!-- social share icon -->
                    

                    <p><em>I don’t normally do any translation, because Interconnected is focused on original work and thinking. But I felt compelled to provide an English version of Jack Ma’s speech on October 24 at the Bund Finance Summit in Shanghai, because mainstream media coverage of the speech and the subsequent cancellation of Ant Group’s IPO has been lacking and simplistic. The speech is worth reading in its entirety to have a deeper understanding the full picture. Below is my unofficial translation of the speech </em><a href="https://sfl.global/news_post/mayunshanghaiwaitanjinrongluntanyanjiangquanwenwushanjian/"><em>based on a Chinese transcript</em></a><em>, with minor edits for clarity and speechifying. To read my deep dive analysis on the speech and its broader context, please check out: "<a href="https://interconnected.blog/jack-ma-p2p-lending-responsibility-legacy/">Jack Ma, P2P Lending, Responsibility, Legacy</a>"</em></p><p><em>我通常不做任何翻译工作，因为《互联》专注于原创作品和思考。但我觉得有必要提供马云10月24日在上海外滩金融峰会上的演讲的一个英文版，尽管只是我个人非官方的翻译，因为主流媒体对演讲和随后蚂蚁集团取消上市的报道太欠缺，过于简单化。整套演讲值得一读来更深层的了解整个事情，可以在</em><a href="https://sfl.global/news_post/mayunshanghaiwaitanjinrongluntanyanjiangquanwenwushanjian/"><em>这里看全文</em></a><em>，在</em><a href="https://finance.sina.com.cn/chanjing/gsnews/2020-10-28/doc-iiznctkc8161643.shtml"><em>这里看视频</em></a><em>。想看我对这套演讲和有关大观景的深度分析，请读《<a href="https://interconnected.blog/jack-ma-p2p-lending-responsibility-legacy/">马云，P2P借贷，责任，留给社会的遗产</a>》</em></p><hr><p>Thank you for inviting me to this Summit. I am delighted to have this opportunity to learn, discuss, and exchange ideas together with you. In 2013, also in Shanghai, I came to the Lujiazui Finance Summit and shared some “pie in the sky” views about Internet-powered finance. Seven years later, today I'm back in Shanghai as an unofficial non-professional person here at the Bund Finance Summit, hoping to share more ideas for you to ponder.</p><p>Actually, I was quite torn about whether to speak here today. But I think there is one thing that is incumbent upon this group of people, and that is the responsibility to think about the future, because although the world has left us many opportunities for development, there are really only one or two critical opportunities. This is a most critical moment.</p><p>So I come here to share some of my own thoughts and views, which are the result of our own practical experience in the last 16 years, plus discussions and research I have had with scholars, experts, and practitioners from all over the world, during the period when I was honored to be the co-chair of the UN High-Level Panel on Digital Cooperation and an advocate for the UN Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).</p><p>I’m basically retired at this point, so I thought I'd speak freely at this unofficial forum and share the non-professional views of a non-professional person. Fortunately, I've discovered that many professionals no longer speak about their professions anymore.</p><p>I have three points of view for you to consider. They may be immature, incorrect, or laughable. Just give them a listen, if they make no sense, just forget about them.</p><p>The first point of view is we have some inertia in our thinking, like we always feel that in order to keep pace with international standards, we must do what developed countries like Europe and the United States have done. If we don’t have something they have, the so-called “blank spot”, we must fill those blank spots domestically. Filling these spots has become the goal to pursue.</p><p>I have always felt that, given this year's situation, the phrase to “fill the blank spot” is problematic. Just because Europe and the United States have something does not mean that thing is always advanced and worth having ourselves. In fact, today, we should not be concerned about what things to align with, which country's standard to adapt to, what blank spots to fill. Today, we have to think about how to align with the future, how to adapt to the future’s standard, how to fill the future’s blank spots. We have to figure out what the future will be, and what we really want to do, and then look at how others do it. If we always repeat the language of others, discuss topics defined by others, we will not only be lost in the present, but also miss the future.</p><p>After World War II, the world needed to restore economic prosperity. The establishment of the Bretton Woods system was an enormous catalyst to the global economy. Later, after the Asian financial crisis occurred, the Basel Accords talked about risk control, which has been gaining more and more attention, to the point that it became an operational standard for risk control. Now the trend is, the world is talking more and more just about risk control, not development. Very few people talk about where the opportunities are for young people, for developing countries.</p><p>This, in fact, is the root cause of many of the world's problems today. We also see today that the Basel Accords have put great limitations on Europe’s ability to innovate as a whole, for example, in digital finance.</p><p>Basel, more like a seniors club, is about solving the problem of an aging financial system that has been operating for decades, and Europe’s aging system is extremely complex. But the problem in China is the opposite: it is not a problem of systemic financial risk, because China's financial sector basically doesn’t have a system. Its risk is actually a "lack of financial system."</p><p>China's financial sector, like other developing countries that have just grown up, is a young industry that does not have a mature ecosystem and is not fully moving. China has many big banks. They are more like big rivers or arteries in our body’s circulatory system, but today we need more lakes, ponds, streams and tributaries, all kinds of swamps. Without these parts of the ecosystem, we will die when we are flooded, and die when we are in a drought. So, today we are a country that bears the risk of lacking a healthy financial system, and we need to build a healthy financial system, not worry about financial systemic risks.</p><p>They are like two completely different diseases, like Alzheimer's disease and polio. Both look similar at first glance but are two totally different illnesses. If a child takes Alzheimer's medication, he or she will not only get the old person’s disease, but a lot of other strange diseases as well.</p><p>The Basel Accords is designed to treat the diseases of the elderly with an aging system and over-complexity, and what we have to think about is what can we learn from the elderly? You must remember, older people and younger people care about different issues. Younger people care about whether there are schools, older people care about whether there are hospitals.</p><p>So, the way the world is changing this year is fascinating and very fast. Last night in Shanghai, we decided on the pricing of Ant’s IPO. This is the largest listing ever priced in the history of the entire human race, and the pricing happened in a place other than New York City. This was unthinkable five years ago, even three years ago, but miracles happen.</p><p>Second, innovation must come at a price, and our generation must take on that responsibility.</p><p>President Xi once said, "success does not have to come from me." I understand this phrase to be about a sense of responsibility. It’s about taking responsibility for the future, for tomorrow, for the next generation. Many of the world's problems today, including China's, can only be solved by innovation. However, for real innovation to happen, no one will show you the way, and someone must shoulder that responsibility, because innovation is bound to make mistakes. But the question is not how not to make mistakes, but whether we can perfect and correct them after making mistakes and persistently innovate. To make risk-free innovation is to stifle innovation, and there is no risk-free innovation in this world. There is no such thing as risk-free innovation. Oftentimes, managing risk down to zero is the biggest risk.</p><p>When the battle of Red Cliff was fought, I believe Cao Cao’s act of connecting all the ships together was the first instance of an aircraft carrier, in China and the world, but after a fire burned it all down, for a thousand years, the Chinese people didn't dare to think about it again. Once they thought about that fire, who still wanted to make a bigger ship, who could still have this kind of system-level thinking?</p><p>Seven or eight years ago, also in Shanghai, I mentioned this concept of Internet-powered finance. We have always emphasized that Internet-powered finance must have three core elements: first, it must have rich data; second, it must have risk control technology based on rich big data; and third, it must have a credit-based system built on big data.</p><p>Using these three criteria to evaluate, we can see that P2P is not Internet-powered finance at all, but today we cannot negate the innovation that the Internet has brought to finance just because of P2P. In fact, let's think about it, how can there be thousands of Internet-powered finance companies in China within a few years? Shouldn't we examine what gave birth to thousands of “Internet-powered finance”, the so-called P2P companies?</p><p>Today, it's really difficult to regulate ourselves; it's hard to conduct regulation everywhere around the globe. Innovation mainly comes from the marketplace, innovation comes from the grassroots, innovation comes from young people. Regulatory challenges are getting bigger and bigger. In fact, <em>jian </em>[editor's note: English word is “supervision”, the first character in the word for “regulation” in Chinese] and <em>guan </em>[editor's note: English word is “management”, the second character in the word for “regulation” in Chinese] are two different things. "Supervision" means watching you as you develop and paying attention to your development. “Management” means intervening when there is a problem or when there is a foreseeable problem.</p><p>We are very good at “management”, but our “supervision” ability is sorely lacking.</p><p>Good innovation is not afraid of regulation, but is afraid of being subjected to yesterday's way to regulate. We cannot use the way to manage a railway station to manage an airport. We cannot use yesterday's way to manage the future.</p><p>"Supervision" and "management" are not the same, “policies” and “documents” are also not the same. This isn’t allowed, that isn’t allowed, those are all called “documents”. Policy …</p></div></section></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://interconnected.blog/jack-ma-bund-finance-summit-speech/">https://interconnected.blog/jack-ma-bund-finance-summit-speech/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://interconnected.blog/jack-ma-bund-finance-summit-speech/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25047544</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 16:10:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[C source-to-source compiler enhancement from within]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 35 | Comments 9 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25047169">thread link</a>) | @ingve
<br/>
November 10, 2020 | https://hal.inria.fr/hal-02998412 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://hal.inria.fr/hal-02998412">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                                    <p><strong>Abstract</strong> : We show how locally replaceable code snippets can be used to easily
  specify and prototype compiler and language enhancements for the
  C language that work by local source-to-source
  transformation.
  A toolbox implements the feature and provides many directives that
  can be used for compile time configuration and tuning, code
  unrolling, compile time expression evaluation and program
  modularization.
  The tool is also easily extensible by simple filters that can be
  programmed with any suitable text processing framework.                    </p>
                                </div><p><small>
                https://hal.inria.fr/hal-02998412<br>
                Contributeur : <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hal.inria.fr/search/index/q/*/contributorId_i/105206" target="_blank">Jens Gustedt</a>                        &lt;<a href="" id="link5fae429544adc"></a>&gt;
                        <br>Soumis le : mardi 10 novembre 2020 - 15:02:12<br>DerniÃ¨re modification le : mercredi 11 novembre 2020 - 03:36:16</small>
        </p></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://hal.inria.fr/hal-02998412</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25047169</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 15:42:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Micro 3.0 is a platform for cloud native development]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 94 | Comments 58 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25044604">thread link</a>) | @asim
<br/>
November 10, 2020 | https://micro.mu/blog/2020/11/05/micro-v3-aka-m3o.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://micro.mu/blog/2020/11/05/micro-v3-aka-m3o.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      
      
      

      
      
      

      <p>This is the official announcement for the release of Micro 3.0 better known as M3O - a platform for cloud native development. 
Our 3.0 release is a major refactor and consolidation of the existing tooling into something that addresses the entire workflow 
of build, run, manage and consume all from the developers perspective.</p>

<p>Read on to learn more or go straight to the <a href="https://github.com/micro/micro/releases/latest">latest release</a>. 
Head to <a href="https://m3o.com/">m3o.com</a> for the hosted offering.</p>

<h2 id="overview">Overview</h2>

<p>Micro focuses on developer productivity for the backend. It’s clear that the Cloud has become infinitely more complex 
over the past few years. Micro attempts to create order out of that chaos by distilling it all down to a handful of 
primitives for distributed systems development.</p>

<p>Why should you care? If you’re reading this you’ve no doubt encountered the tedious nature of infrastructure management, 
wrangling a kubernetes cluster on AWS or the thousands of things you need to do to cobble together a platform before 
starting to build a product. We think we’ve nailed the solution for that just as Android did for Mobile. Keep reading 
if you want to find out more.</p>

<h2 id="quick-flashback">Quick Flashback</h2>

<p>Micro started out as a <a href="https://micro.mu/blog/2016/03/20/micro.html">toolkit for microservices</a> development, 
incorporating an api gateway, web dashboard and cli to interact with services built using a Go RPC framework. 
Back then it felt like getting anyone to buy into PaaS again was going to be a losing battle. So we chose 
to write single purpose tools around an RPC framework thinking it might allow people to adopt it piece by piece 
until they saw the need for a platform. It was really straight forward right until it wasn’t.</p>

<p>There was a simple Go framework plus some surrounding 
components to query and interact with them, but like any long lived project, the complexity grew as we 
tried to solve for that platform experience that just couldn’t be done with a swiss army knife. The repo 
exploded with a number of independent libraries. To the creator its obvious what these are all for but to 
the user there is nothing but cognitive overload.</p>

<p>In 2019 we went through a <a href="https://micro.mu/blog/2019/06/10/the-great-consolidation.html">consolidation</a> of all those libraries 
which helped tremendously but there was still always one outstanding question. What’s the difference between 
<a href="https://github.com/micro/micro">micro</a> and <a href="https://github.com/micro/go-micro">go-micro</a>? It’s a good 
question and one we’ve covered before. We saw go-micro as a framework and micro as a toolkit but these 
words were basically empty and meaningless because multiple projects working in coordination really need a 
crisp story that makes sense and we didn’t have one.</p>

<p>In 2020 we’re looking to rectify that but let’s first let’s talk about platforms.</p>

<h2 id="paas-in-2020">PaaS in 2020</h2>

<p>5 years ago the world exploded with a proliferation of “cloud native” tooling as containers and 
container orchestration took centre stage. More specifically, Docker and Kubernetes redefined the 
technology landscape along with a more conscious move towards building software in the cloud.</p>

<p>Micro took a forward looking view even as far back as 2015. It was clear distributed systems and cloud native 
was going to become the dominant model for backend services development over the coming years but, what wasn’t clear 
is just how long we’d spend wrangling all sorts tools like docker, kubernetes, grpc, istio and everything else. 
It felt like we were rebuilding the stack and weren’t really ready to talk about development aspects of it all.</p>

<p>In fact at that time, people mostly wanted to kick the tyres on all these tools and piece something together. 
Running kubernetes yourself became all the rage and even using service mesh as the holy grail for solving 
all your distributed systems problems. Many of us have come to realise while all of this tech is fun 
it’s not actually solving development problems.</p>

<p>We’ve gotten to the point of managed kubernetes and even things like Google Cloud Run or DigitalOcean App 
Platform, but none of these things are helping with a development model for a cloud native era. Our 
frustrations with the existing developer experience have grown and Micro felt like something that 
could solve for all that, but only if we took a drastic step to overhaul it.</p>

<p>We think PaaS 3.0 is not just about running your container or even your source code but something that 
encapsulates the entire developer experience including a model for writing code for the cloud. Based on that 
Micro 3.0 aka M3O is a platform for cloud native development.</p>

<h2 id="what-even-is-cloud-native">What even is Cloud Native?</h2>

<p>What is cloud native? What does it mean to build for the cloud? What is a cloud service?</p>

<p>Cloud native is basically a descriptive term for something that was built to run in the cloud. That’s it. It’s not 
magic, it might sound like a buzzword, but the reality is it simply means, that piece of software was built 
to run in the cloud. How does that differ from the way we used to build before? Well the idea behind the cloud 
is that its ephemeral, scalable and everything can be accessed via an API.</p>

<p>Our expectation for services running in the cloud is that they’re mostly stateless, leveraging external services 
for the persistence, that they are identified by name rather than IP address and they themselves provide an 
API that can be consumed by multiple clients such as web, mobile and cli or other services.</p>

<p>Cloud native applications are horizontally scalable and operate within domain boundaries that divide them as 
separate apps which communicate over the network via their APIs rather than as one monolithic entity. 
We think cloud services require a fundamentally different approach to software creation and why Micro 3.0 
was designed with this in mind.</p>

<h2 id="micro-30-aka-m3o">Micro 3.0 aka M3O</h2>

<p>Micro 3.0 (M3O) reimagines Micro as a platform for cloud native development. What does that mean? Well we think of 
it as PaaS 3.0, a complete solution for source to running and beyond. Micro has moved from just being a Go 
framework to incorporating a standalone server and hosted platform. Our hosted offering is called 
<a href="https://m3o.com/">M3O</a>, a hat tip to Micro 3.0 or M[icr]o, whichever way you want to see it.</p>

<p>Another way to think about it. What Git is to GitHub, Micro is to the M3O platform. Let’s dig into it.</p>

<p>Micro 3.0 includes the following.</p>

<h3 id="server">Server</h3>

<p>The server is our abstraction for cloud infrastructure and underlying systems you might need for writing 
distributed systems. The server encapsulates all of these concerns as gRPC services which you can 
query via any language. The goal here is to say developers don’t really need to be thinking about infrastructure 
but what they do need is design patterns and primitives for building distributed systems.</p>

<p><img src="https://micro.mu/images/micro-3.0.png"></p>

<p>The server includes the following:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Authentication</strong>: Auth whether its authentication or authorization is part of the system. Create JWT tokens, define access rules, use one system to govern everything in a simple and straight forward manner. Whether it’s for a user or a service.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Configuration</strong>: Dynamic config management allows you to store relevant config that needs to be updated without having to restart services. Throw API keys and business logic related configuration into the secure config service and let your services pick up the changes.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Key-Value Storage</strong>: We’re focused on best practices for microservices development which means keeping services mostly stateless. To do this we’re providing persistent storage on the platform. Key-Value allows you to rapidly write code and store data in the format you care about.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Event Streaming</strong>: Distributed systems are fundamentally in need of an event driven architecture to breakdown the tight dependencies between them. Using event streaming and pubsub allows you to publish and subscribe to relevant events async.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Service Registry</strong>: Micro and M3O bake in service discovery so you can browse a directory of services to explore your service APIs and enable you to query services by name. Micro is all about microservices and multi-service development.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Service Network</strong>: Because you don’t want to have to resolve those service names to addresses and deal with the load balancing aspect, the server bakes in a “service mesh” which will handle your inter-service requests (as gRPC) and route to the 
appropriate instance.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Identity Proxy</strong>: We include a separate identity proxy for external requests using gRPC via the CLI and other means. This enables you to query from your local machine or anywhere else using valid auth credentials and have it seamlessly work as if 
you were in the platform itself.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>API Gateway</strong>: Finally there’s an API gateway that automatically exposes your services to the outside world over HTTP. Internally writing service to service using gRPC makes sense, but at the end of the day we want to build APIs consumed from clients via HTTP.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h3 id="clients">Clients</h3>

<p>The server provides inter-service communication and two means of external communication with a HTTP API and gRPC proxy but that 
experience is made much better when there’s user experience on the client side that works. Right now we’ve got two ways of doing this.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Command Line</strong>: The CLI provides a convenient and simple way to talk to the server via gRPC requests through the proxy. 
The most convenient commands are builtin but every service you write also gets beautiful dynamic generated commands 
for each endpoint.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>gRPC SDKs</strong>: Every service in the server is accessible via gRPC. We’re code generating clients for the server itself 
so you can access them from any language. What this enables is a wide array of experiences on the client side without 
having to handcraft libraries for each language.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Web Interface</strong>: Coming soon is a dynamically generated web interface that creates a simple query mechanism through a 
browser for any of your services. We’ve got a http api, gRPC proxy and command line interface but feel like the browser 
could use some love too.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h3 id="framework">Framework</h3>

<p>One thing we really understood from our time working on go-micro was that the developer experience …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://micro.mu/blog/2020/11/05/micro-v3-aka-m3o.html">https://micro.mu/blog/2020/11/05/micro-v3-aka-m3o.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://micro.mu/blog/2020/11/05/micro-v3-aka-m3o.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25044604</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 11:00:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to revert HP printer’s ban on 3rd-party ink cartridges]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 407 | Comments 247 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25044597">thread link</a>) | @kdeldycke
<br/>
November 10, 2020 | https://kevin.deldycke.com/2020/11/revert-hp-printer-ban-on-third-party-ink-cartridges/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://kevin.deldycke.com/2020/11/revert-hp-printer-ban-on-third-party-ink-cartridges/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content" role="main">
     <p>
      Hewlett
      <span>
       &amp;
      </span>
      Packard, the founders, had great lessons to teach us (managers in high-tech) about culture. I even
      <a href="https://github.com/kdeldycke/awesome-engineering-team-management/commit/de3e64647c911f78a37b3e54c7e46197acb061e1">
       quoted them
      </a>
      in my
      <a href="https://github.com/kdeldycke/awesome-engineering-team-management#readme">
       awesome list on engineering team management
      </a>
      .&nbsp;👨‍💼
     </p>
     <p>
      <span>
       HP
      </span>
      Inc., the company, sucks. At least their
      <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25045024">
       printer division’s business model
      </a>
      . They recently pushed a
      <strong>
       firmware update to ban third-party compatible toner cartridges
      </strong>
      .&nbsp;💔
     </p>
     <p>
      The timeline is&nbsp;straightforward:
     </p>
     <ul>
      <li>
       <p>
        2020, March: general lockdown. 🦠 I need a home office.
        <span>
         SO
        </span>
        is a scientist and spend her time printing papers for review. Got her an
        <a href="https://amzn.com/B073R2WVKB/?tag=kevideld-20">
         <span>
          HP
         </span>
         Color LaserJet M254dw
        </a>
        to keep her productive workflow (
        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Publish_or_perish">
         publish or perish!
        </a>
        ).
       </p>
      </li>
      <li>
       <p>
        2020, October:
        <span>
         HP
        </span>
        release a new firmware (versioned
        <code>
         20201021
        </code>
        ).
       </p>
      </li>
     </ul>
     <p>
      <img alt="" src="https://kevin.deldycke.com/uploads/2020/hp-laserjet-printer-20201021-firmware.jpg">
     </p>
     <ul>
      <li>
       2020, November: my printer auto-upgrade. I’m welcomed with this
       <em>
        Supply Problem
        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Screen_of_death">
         Screen of Death
        </a>
       </em>
       :
      </li>
     </ul>
     <p>
      <img alt="" src="https://kevin.deldycke.com/uploads/2020/hp-laserjet-printer-supply-problem-screen-of-death.jpg">
     </p>
     <p>
      I can’t print anymore.&nbsp;🤯
     </p>
     <p>
      Eight months. My printer worked for only 8 months.&nbsp;😤
     </p>
     <p>
      <span>
       OK
      </span>
      . It’s my fault. I should have spent more money buying certified™ gear.&nbsp;😑
     </p>
     <p>
      <img alt="" src="https://comdoc.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/copier-printer-meme-03.jpg">
     </p>
     <p>
      The solution is to travel back in time when things were working just great, and downgrade to the previous&nbsp;firmware.
     </p>
     <h2 id="disable-auto-upgrade">
      Disable Auto-Upgrade
      <a href="#disable-auto-upgrade" title="Permanent link">
       ¶
      </a>
     </h2>
     <p>
      We will start by stopping this madness for good, and prevent the printer from downloading a firmware behind our&nbsp;back.
     </p>
     <p>
      In the control panel, go to
      <code>
       Setup
      </code>
      &gt;
      <code>
       Service
      </code>
      &gt;
      <code>
       LaserJet Update
      </code>
      &gt;
      <code>
       Manage Updates
      </code>
      :
     </p>
     <p>
      <img alt="" src="https://kevin.deldycke.com/uploads/2020/hp-laserjet-printer-manage-updates-menu.jpg">
     </p>
     <p>
      Then set these&nbsp;options:
     </p>
     <ul>
      <li>
       Allow Downgrade:
       <code>
        Yes
       </code>
      </li>
      <li>
       Check Automatically:
       <code>
        Off
       </code>
      </li>
      <li>
       Prompt Before Install:
       <code>
        Always Prompt
       </code>
      </li>
      <li>
       Allow Updates:
       <code>
        No
       </code>
      </li>
     </ul>
     <p>
      I’m quite surprised downgrades are allowed. 🤔 It seems out of character. Therefor, with my
      <em>
       Evil Product Manager
      </em>
      hat, I advise
      <span>
       HP
      </span>
      to monetize this feature under a monthly Enterprise Subscription of sort.&nbsp;😈
     </p>
     <h2 id="download-old-firmware">
      Download Old Firmware
      <a href="#download-old-firmware" title="Permanent link">
       ¶
      </a>
     </h2>
     <p>
      I got lucky and found the previous
      <code>
       20200612
      </code>
      firmware referenced in
      <a href="https://ftp.hp.com/pub/networking/software/pfirmware/pfirmware.glf">
       <code>
        https://ftp.hp.com/pub/networking/software/pfirmware/pfirmware.glf
       </code>
      </a>
      .
     </p>
     <p>
      There you’ll get a direct link to the
      <code>
       .rfu
      </code>
      file (Remote Firmware Update):
      <a href="http://ftp.hp.com/pub/networking/software/pfirmware/HP_Color_LaserJet_Pro_M254_dw_Printer_series_20200612.rfu">
       <code>
        http://ftp.hp.com/pub/networking/software/pfirmware/HP_Color_LaserJet_Pro_M254_dw_Printer_series_20200612.rfu
       </code>
      </a>
      .
     </p>
     <p>
      And just in case it disappear from its original location, here is a
      <a href="https://kevin.deldycke.com/uploads/2020/HP_Color_LaserJet_Pro_M254_dw_Printer_series_20200612.rfu">
       copy of
       <code>
        HP_Color_LaserJet_Pro_M254_dw_Printer_series_20200612.rfu
       </code>
      </a>
      .
     </p>
     <p>
      The checksum of that file&nbsp;is:
     </p>
     <div>
      <pre><span></span><code><span data-linenos="1 "></span><span>$</span> sha256sum ./HP_Color_LaserJet_Pro_M254_dw_Printer_series_20200612.rfu
<span data-linenos="2 "></span><span>91c7f51ceba2386f3b94dcb9da20c669ab10b1ee3a9b1e1f742c40091920188e</span>
</code></pre>
     </div>
     <h2 id="downgrade-firmware">
      Downgrade Firmware
      <a href="#downgrade-firmware" title="Permanent link">
       ¶
      </a>
     </h2>
     <p>
      Once you get the
      <code>
       .rfu
      </code>
      file, list all your printers from a macOS&nbsp;terminal:
     </p>
     <div>
      <pre><span></span><code><span data-linenos="1 "></span><span>$</span> lpstat -p -d
<span data-linenos="2 "></span><span>printer HP_Color_LaserJet_M254dw_0 is idle.  enabled since Fri Nov  6 17:47:06 2020</span>
<span data-linenos="3 "></span><span>system default destination: HP_Color_LaserJet_M254dw_0</span>
</code></pre>
     </div>
     <p>
      And run the firmware downgrade
      <span>
       CLI
      </span>
      :
     </p>
     <div>
      <pre><span></span><code><span data-linenos="1 "></span><span>$</span> lpr -P HP_Color_LaserJet_M254dw_0 /Users/kde/Downloads/HP_Color_LaserJet_Pro_M254_dw_Printer_series_20200612.rfu
</code></pre>
     </div>
     <p>
      Nothing gets printed to the&nbsp;console.
     </p>
     <p>
      I don’t know what happens here but it seems the
      <code>
       .rfu
      </code>
      file is pushed to the printer’s queue and then gets consumed as any other printable document. See,
      <a href="https://www.jsof-tech.com/unpacking-hp-firmware-updates-part-1/">
       the
       <span>
        RFU
       </span>
       file format is a matryoshka doll
      </a>
      embedding printing commands, encoded data and raw
      <span>
       NAND
      </span>
      code.
     </p>
     <p>
      After a minute  or two, the printers reboots and upgrades&nbsp;itself:
     </p>
     <p>
      <img alt="" src="https://kevin.deldycke.com/uploads/2020/hp-laserjet-printer-firmware-updating.jpg">
     </p>
     <p>
      And we’re back in business!&nbsp;🥳
     </p>
     <p>
      A detour via
      <code>
       Setup
      </code>
      &gt;
      <code>
       Service
      </code>
      &gt;
      <code>
       Firmware Datecode
      </code>
      menu confirm we’re running the the previous&nbsp;firmware:
     </p>
     <p>
      <img alt="" src="https://kevin.deldycke.com/uploads/2020/hp-laserjet-printer-20200612-firmware.jpg">
     </p>
     <h2 id="printer-security">
      Printer Security
      <a href="#printer-security" title="Permanent link">
       ¶
      </a>
     </h2>
     <p>
      In my research for this article, I found out about
      <a href="https://github.com/RUB-NDS/PRET">
       <span>
        PRET
       </span>
       , a printer exploitation toolkit
      </a>
      . It’s a brilliant tool, in a malignant way. It allows for pen-testing and hacking, using the same vectors as the firmware update.&nbsp;🤫
     </p>
     <p>
      I’ll probably play with it in the future. For fun, but also to try enhance the security of the printer. In the mean time, I guess a password is the bare minimum. And if my printer get kidnapped by a cyber gang, I now have a way to restore my printer’s firmware!&nbsp;😬
     </p>
     <h3>
      Related content
     </h3>
     
     
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://kevin.deldycke.com/2020/11/revert-hp-printer-ban-on-third-party-ink-cartridges/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25044597</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 10:59:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The myriad meanings of pwd in Unix systems]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 63 | Comments 59 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25044131">thread link</a>) | @quyleanh
<br/>
November 10, 2020 | https://qmacro.org/2020/11/08/the-meaning-of-pwd-in-unix-systems/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://qmacro.org/2020/11/08/the-meaning-of-pwd-in-unix-systems/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p><em>Last week I ran a poll on Twitter to see what people considered with respect to the meaning of ‘pwd’ in Unix and Linux systems. The results were varied, for perhaps good reason.</em></p>

<p>At the end of Oct 2020 I ran a <a href="https://twitter.com/qmacro/status/1322567992551624705">brief poll on Twitter</a>, on which 82 people voted. Here’s that poll, and the results. They’re quite mixed, which at first might seem surprising. But there are reasons for that, as we’ll find out.</p>

<p><img src="https://qmacro.org/content/images/2020/11/twitter-poll-pwd.png" alt="Poll on Twitter: &quot;Fun Saturday afternoon shell poll. In Unix (and Linux), what do you think the P in $PWD (or pwd) stand for?&quot;"></p>

<p><strong>Print working directory</strong></p>

<p>The most popular option was “print working directory”. At first sight it seems logical: “print out the current working directory, i.e. where I am right now”. Moreover, the description in various versions of the manual for <code>pwd</code> help to drive home that notion. Typically we see sentences like “<a href="https://linux.die.net/man/1/pwd">print name of current/working directory</a>” or “<a href="https://www.mankier.com/1/pwd">print the current directory</a>”.</p>

<p>But there are lots of commands that print stuff, and are described in that way too. Take the <code>id</code> command. Here’s what one man page says: “<a href="https://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man1/id.1.html">print real and effective user and group IDs</a>”. There’s “print” again. But the command isn’t <code>pid</code>, it’s <code>id</code>. When you think about it, many, many commands in Unix send information to STDOUT, i.e. to the terminal. That’s sort of the point of many of them.</p>

<p>This time arguably only superficially definitive, it would seem, the Wikipedia entry states, on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pwd">page for <code>pwd</code></a>: “the pwd command (print working directory) writes the full pathname of the current working directory to the standard output”. As if to underline the hopeful authority of this statement, there are five (!) footnotes that supposedly link to resources that back this up.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, the first footnote points to a Wayback Machine copy of the <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20050520231659/http://cm.bell-labs.com/7thEdMan/v7vol1.pdf">UNIX PROGRAMMERS MANUAL - Seventh Edition, Volume 1 - January, 1979</a>, wherein there are actually zero references to <code>pwd</code> being short for “print working directory”:</p>

<p><img src="https://qmacro.org/content/images/2020/11/programmers-manual-pwd.png" alt="excerpt from UNIX PROGRAMMERS MANUAL on pwd"></p>

<p>I don’t know about you, but this historic document carries more weight for me than other sources I’ve come across, and it only serves here to undermine the credibility of the Wikipedia entry.</p>

<p>The rest of the footnote links seem dubious at best, except for the one pointing to the <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/coreutils/manual/coreutils.html#pwd-invocation">GNU Coreutils manual on pwd</a> which has it as “print working directory”. But everything else I’ve seen so far makes me think that this is a misunderstanding that has spread for obvious and innocent reasons. In addition, the one footnote in the Wikipedia page that is not used to back this claim up is a pointer to <a href="https://pubs.opengroup.org/onlinepubs/9699919799/utilities/pwd.html">The Open Group Base Specifications Issue 7, 2018 edition’s information on pwd</a>, which almost seems like it’s actually avoiding using the word “print” at all: “return working directory name” … “The pwd utility shall write to standard output an absolute pathname of the current working directory, which does not contain the filenames dot or dot-dot.”. Very specific, very not-print.</p>

<p>So I’m thinking that “print working directory” isn’t what <code>pwd</code> stands for. In fact, “print working directory” may be common to some man pages, but on this macOS machine, with its <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Berkeley_Software_Distribution">BSD</a> heritage, we have, instead: “pwd – return working directory name”. Moreover, it goes on to say “The pwd utility writes the absolute pathname of the current working directory to the standard output”.</p>

<p><strong>Pathname of working directory</strong></p>

<p>So perhaps it really is “pathname of working directory”. That would, at least to me, make more sense. Not only does it eschew the redundancy of “print”, it also is more specific about the output - if I’m in <code>/home/dja/</code> for example, then invoking pwd will tell me that, i.e. where I am, including the whole path, and not just <code>dja</code>:</p>



<p><strong>Process working directory</strong></p>

<p>As for the other options, I do favour “process working directory”, mostly because it makes a lot of sense to me; every process in Unix has the concept of a current working directory, and that’s exactly what I’m asking for when I’m in my shell process and enter <code>pwd</code> - there’s a part in the video <a href="https://youtu.be/hgFBRZmwpSM?t=165">Unix terminals and shells</a> that explains this very well.</p>

<p>I’d love to be able to point to some old Unix sources that definitively explain the answer, but unfortunately that search has come up with very little - the <code>pwd</code> source in both the <a href="https://minnie.tuhs.org/cgi-bin/utree.pl?file=V5/usr/source/s2/pwd.c">5th</a> and <a href="https://github.com/yisooan/unix-v6/blob/master/source/s2/pwd.c">6th</a> Editions of Unix shed no light on this whatsoever.</p>

<p><strong>Present working directory</strong></p>

<p>What about “present working directory”? Well, that option seems to have legs, in the form of the Korn shell. While <a href="https://northstar-www.dartmouth.edu/doc/solaris-forte/ipe-help/dbx/dbx88cc.html">one source</a> implies that the answer might well be “pathname of current working directory”, in that <code>pwd</code> just emits the value of the <code>$PWD</code> environment variable (and a variable called “print working directory” makes no sense at all) … it would seem that in ksh-land, at least, “present working directory” is what <code>pwd</code> represents. Take, for example, the <a href="https://osr507doc.xinuos.com/en/man/html.C/ksh.C.html">ksh man page</a> which states “PWD - The present working directory set by the cd command”.</p>

<p>There’s a ton of discussion, both direct and indirect, on this very question. Take for example these two entries in the Unix &amp; Linux Stack Exchange forum: <a href="https://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/399026/etymology-of-pwd">Etymology of $PWD</a> and <a href="https://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/174990/what-is-pwd-vs-current-working-directory">What is $PWD? (vs current working directory)</a>. Of course, perhaps the definitive answer will never be found, as computing history is nothing if not varied and prone to forking.</p>

<p><strong>Multics and print_wdir</strong></p>

<p>Talking of history, we could go further back to pre-Unix roots, in the form of Multics, which indirectly gave rise to Unix (originally “Unics”). In the <a href="https://multicians.org/multics-commands.html">list of Multics Commands</a>, we see, nestled amongst other similarly named commands, something that jumps out at us:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>print_mail (pm)	display mail in a mailbox
print_messages (pm)	display interactive messages in a mailbox
print_motd (pmotd)	display message of the day (source)
print_proc_auth (ppa)	display process's sensitivity level and compartments
print_request_types (prt)	display list of I/O daemon request types
print_search_paths (psp)	display search paths
print_search_rules (psr)	display ready messages
print_wdir (pwd)	display working directory
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>There’s <code>pwd</code>, and in fact, just like its sibling <code>pmotd</code>, for example, which is short for <code>print_motd</code>, it’s short for <code>print_wdir</code>. Now, given the context of the original poll being set to Unix and Linux, perhaps we must discount this information. But as someone who is fascinated with Unix history in general - how can I?</p>

<p>I guess there are few things to conclude. The history is rich and diverse, and maybe we’ll never know for sure. Perhaps, in fact, the answer will depend on whom we ask. In the grand scheme of things, it doesn’t really matter … but to those who delight in minutiae, it’s a fun topic worth exploring.</p>

  </div>

</article>

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://qmacro.org/2020/11/08/the-meaning-of-pwd-in-unix-systems/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25044131</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 09:30:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[This is how I git]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 223 | Comments 133 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25043731">thread link</a>) | @ingve
<br/>
November 10, 2020 | https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/11/09/this-is-how-i-git/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/11/09/this-is-how-i-git/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Every now and then I get questions on how to work with git in a smooth way when developing, bug-fixing or extending curl – or how I do it. After all, I <a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/10/26/working-open-source/" data-type="post" data-id="14901">work on open source full time</a> which means I have very frequent interactions with git (and GitHub). Simply put, I work with git all day long. Ordinary days, I issue git commands several hundred times.</p>



<p>I have a very simple approach and way of working with git in curl. This is how it works.</p>



<h2>command line</h2>



<p>I use git almost exclusively from the command line in a terminal. To help me see which branch I’m working in, I have this little bash helper script.</p>



<pre>brname () {
  a=$(<code>git rev-parse --abbrev-ref HEAD 2&gt;/dev/null</code>)
  if [ -n "$a" ]; then
    echo " [$a]"
  else
    echo ""
  fi
}
PS1="\u@\h:\w\$(brname)$ "</pre>



<p>That gives me a prompt that shows username, host name, the current working directory and the current checked out git branch.</p>



<p>In addition: I use Debian’s <a href="https://salsa.debian.org/debian/bash-completion/-/blob/master/README.md">bash command line completion</a> for git which is also really handy. It allows me to use tab to complete things like git commands and branch names. </p>



<h2>git config</h2>



<p>I of course also have my customized <code>~/.gitconfig</code> file to provide me with some convenient aliases and settings. My most commonly used git aliases are:</p>


<pre title="">st = status --short -uno
ci = commit
ca = commit --amend
caa = commit -a --amend
br = branch
co = checkout
df = diff
lg = log -p --pretty=fuller --abbrev-commit
lgg = log --pretty=fuller --abbrev-commit --stat
up = pull --rebase
latest = log @^{/RELEASE-NOTES:.synced}..
</pre>


<p>The ‘latest’ one is for listing all changes done to curl since the most recent RELEASE-NOTES “sync”. The others should hopefully be rather self-explanatory.</p>



<p>The config also sets <code>gpgsign = true</code>, enables mailmap and a few other things.</p>



<h2>master is clean and working</h2>



<p>The main curl development is done in the single <a href="https://github.com/curl/curl">curl/curl</a> git repository (primarily hosted on GitHub). We keep the master branch the bleeding edge development tree and we work hard to always keep that working and functional. We do our releases off the master branch when that day comes (every eight weeks) and we provide “<a href="https://curl.haxx.se/snapshots/">daily snapshots</a>” from that branch, put together – yeah – daily.</p>



<p>When merging fixes and features into master, we avoid merge commits and use rebases and fast-forward as much as possible. This makes the branch very easy to browse, understand and work with – as it is 100% linear.</p>



<h2>Work on a fix or feature</h2>



<p>When I start something new, like work on a bug or trying out someone’s patch or similar, I first create a local branch off master and work in that. That is, I don’t work directly in the master branch. Branches are easy and quick to do and there’s no reason to shy away from having loads of them!</p>



<p>I typically name the branch prefixed with my GitHub user name, so that when I push them to the server it is noticeable who is the creator (and I can use the same branch name locally as I do remotely).</p>



<pre>$ git checkout -b bagder/my-new-stuff-or-bugfix</pre>



<p>Once I’ve reached somewhere, I commit to the branch. It can then end up one or more commits before I consider myself “done for now” with what I was set out to do.</p>



<p>I try not to leave the tree with any uncommitted changes – like if I take off for the day or even just leave for food or an extended break. This puts the repository in a state that allows me to easily switch over to another branch  when I get back – should I feel the need to. Plus, it’s better to commit and explain the change <em>before</em> the break rather than having to recall the details again when coming back.</p>



<h2>Never stash</h2>



<p>“git stash” is therefore not a command I ever use. I rather create a new branch and commit the (temporary?) work in there as a potential new line of work.</p>



<h2>Show it off and get reviews</h2>



<p>Yes I am the lead developer of the project but I still maintain the same work flow as everyone else. All changes, except the most minuscule ones, are done as pull requests on GitHub.</p>



<p>When I’m happy with the functionality in my local branch. When the bug seems to be fixed or the feature seems to be doing what it’s supposed to do and the test suite runs fine locally.</p>



<p>I then clean up the commit series with “<code>git rebase -i</code>” (or if it is a single commit I can instead use just “<code>git commit --amend</code>“).</p>



<p>The commit series should be a set of logical changes that are related to this change and not any more than necessary, but kept separate if they are separate. Each commit also gets its own proper commit message. Unrelated changes should be split out into its own separate branch and subsequent separate pull request.</p>



<pre>git push origin bagder/my-new-stuff-or-bugfix</pre>



<h2>Make the push a pull request</h2>



<p>On GitHub, I then make the newly pushed branch into a <a href="https://github.com/curl/curl/pulls">pull request</a> (aka “a PR”). It will then become visible in the list of pull requests on the site for the curl source repository, it will be announced in the #curl IRC channel and everyone who follows the repository on GitHub will be notified accordingly.</p>



<p>Perhaps most importantly, a pull request kicks of a flood of CI jobs that will build and test the code in numerous different combinations and on several platforms, and the results of those tests will trickle in over the coming hours. When I write this, we have around 90 different CI jobs – per pull request – and something like 8 different code analyzers will scrutinize the change to see if there’s any obvious flaws in there.</p>



<figure><a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot_2020-11-05-curl-Project-status-dashboard.png"><img loading="lazy" width="2686" height="1510" src="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot_2020-11-05-curl-Project-status-dashboard.png" alt=""></a><figcaption>CI jobs per platform over time. Graph snapped on November 5, 2020</figcaption></figure>



<h2>A branch in the actual curl/curl repo</h2>



<p>Most contributors who would work on curl would not do like me and make the branch in the curl repository itself, but would rather do them in their own forked version instead. The difference isn’t that big and I <em>could</em> of course also do it that way.</p>



<h2>After push, switch branch</h2>



<p>As it will take some time to get the full CI results from the PR to come in (generally a few hours), I switch over to the next branch with work on my agenda. On a normal work-day I can easily move over ten different branches, polish them and submit updates in their respective pull-requests.</p>



<p>I can go back to the&nbsp;master branch again with ‘<code>git checkout master</code>‘ and there I can “<code>git pull</code>” to get everything from upstream – like when my fellow developers have pushed stuff in the mean time.</p>



<h2>PR comments or CI alerts</h2>



<p>If a reviewer or a CI job find a mistake in one of my PRs, that becomes visible on GitHub and I get to work to handle it. To either fix the bug or discuss with the reviewer what the better approach might be.</p>



<p>Unfortunately, flaky CI jobs is a part of life so very often there ends up one or two red markers in the list of CI jobs that can be ignored as the test failures in them are there due to problems in the setup and not because of actual mistakes in the PR…</p>



<p>To get back to my branch for that PR again, I “<code>git checkout bagder/my-new-stuff-or-bugfix</code>“, and fix the issues.</p>



<p>I normally start out by doing follow-up commits that repair the immediate mistake and push them on the branch:</p>



<pre>git push origin <code>bagder/my-new-stuff-or-bugfix</code></pre>



<p>If the number of fixup commits gets large, or if the follow-up fixes aren’t small, I usually end up doing a squash to reduce the number of commits into a smaller, simpler set, and then force-push them to the branch.</p>



<p>The reason for that is to make the patch series easy to review, read and understand. When a commit series has too many commits that changes the previous commits, it becomes hard to review.</p>



<h2>Ripe to merge?</h2>



<p>When the pull request is ripe for merging (independently of who authored it), I switch over to the master branch again and I merge the pull request’s commits into it. In special cases I cherry-pick specific commits from the branch instead. When all the stuff has been yanked into master properly that should be there, I push the changes to the remote.</p>



<p>Usually, and especially if the pull request wasn’t done by me, I also go over the commit messages and polish them somewhat before I push everything. Commit messages should follow our style and mention not only which PR that it closes but also which issue it fixes and properly give credit to the bug reporter and all the helpers – using the right syntax so that our automatic tools can pick them up correctly!</p>



<p>As already mentioned above, I merge fast-forward or rebased into master. No merge commits.</p>



<h2>Never merge with GitHub!</h2>



<p>There’s a button GitHub that says “rebase and merge” that could theoretically be used for merging pull requests. I <em>never</em> use that (and if I could, I’d disable/hide it). The reasons are simply:</p>



<ol><li>I don’t feel that I have the proper control of the commit message(s)</li><li>I can’t select to squash a subset of the commits, only all or nothing</li><li>I often want to cleanup the author parts too before push, which the UI doesn’t allow</li></ol>



<p>The downside with not using the merge button is that the message in the  PR says “closed by [hash]” instead of “merged in…” which causes confusion to a fair amount of users who don’t realize it means that it actually means the same thing! I consider this is a (long-standing) GitHub UX flaw.</p>



<h2>Post merge</h2>



<p>If the branch has nothing to be kept around more, I delete the local branch again with “<code>git branch -d [name]</code>” and I remove it remotely too since it was completely merged there’s no reason to keep the work version left.</p>



<p>At any given point in time, I have some 20-30 different local branches alive using this approach so things I work on over time all live in their own branches and also submissions from various people that haven’t been merged into master yet exist in branches of various maturity levels. Out of those local branches, the number of concurrent pull requests I have in progress can be somewhere between just a few up to ten, twelve something.</p>



<h2>RELEASE-NOTES</h2>



<p>Not strictly related, but in order to keep interested people informed about what’s happening in the tree, we sync the <a href="https://github.com/curl/curl/blob/master/RELEASE-NOTES">RELEASE-NOTES</a> file every once in a while. Maybe every 5-7 days or so. It …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/11/09/this-is-how-i-git/">https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/11/09/this-is-how-i-git/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/11/09/this-is-how-i-git/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25043731</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 08:08:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[AppleCrate II: A New Apple II-Based Parallel Computer (2015)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 111 | Comments 33 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25042551">thread link</a>) | @aresant
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | http://michaeljmahon.com/AppleCrateII.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://michaeljmahon.com/AppleCrateII.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">

<b><span face="Arial, helvetica" size="4"><p>AppleCrate II:  A New Apple II-Based Parallel Computer</p>
</span><span face="Arial, helvetica" size="2"><p>
Michael J. Mahon – July 26, 2008<br>
Revised – September 23, 2015</p>

<p><img src="http://michaeljmahon.com/CrateII.jpg" width="500" height="612"></p>

</span><span face="Arial, helvetica"><p>Introduction</p>
</span></b><span face="Arial, helvetica" size="2"><p>
In 2004 I built the first <a href="http://michaeljmahon.com/Applecrate.html">AppleCrate</a>, an 8-board system, as an inexpensive, easy to program
vehicle for experiments in parallel programming—a kind of "blade server" for the Apple II, if
you will!  AppleCrate I (at the time I didn't realize that it was number "I" ;-) was great fun, and it
enabled some very interesting experiments, but over time I discovered some of its shortcomings.</p>

<p>First and foremost, since the boards were supported by only two edges and not clamped in place, it
was relatively fragile and hard to transport.  Second, I had come across situations in which more
than 8 slave processors would have been useful.  Third, my arrangement for collecting audio signals
synthesized by the slaves was quite makeshift and delivered sound with lots of digital "hash"
as background noise.  And finally, the original AppleCrate made no provision for plugging I/O cards
into any of its boards, so it had to be hosted by a separate Apple II, adding to the problem of
transporting it for demonstrations.</p>

<p>The AppleCrate II is designed to be significantly improved in all of the areas that were
problems for the AppleCrate I.</p>

<b></b></span><b><span face="Arial, helvetica"><p>Description</p>
</span></b><span face="Arial, helvetica" size="2">

<p>The AppleCrate II is made from 17 Enhanced Apple //e main boards.  (Fifteen of these boards were
obtained in the same eBay auction that netted the eight unenhanced boards for the original AppleCrate.)
Because they are enhanced ROMs, the original NadaNet boot ROM code would not fit and a new
boot protocol had to be developed, as described below.</p>

<p>Instead of mounting the cards vertically in a frame, as in the original, I decided to mount them
horizontally in a stack secured with standoffs—3/4" long hexagonal rods, each with a screw protruding from
one end and a tapped hole in the other.  The AppleCrate II has nine "columns" of these standoffs—six
metal columns at the back and corners of the boards and three nylon columns interior to the boards
to add stiffness, as shown in the photo below at the 2-board construction stage:</p>

<p><img src="http://michaeljmahon.com/TwoBoards.jpg" width="800" height="554"></p>

<p>This "hi-rise" construction makes the "stack" quite rigid and sturdy, while eliminating the need
for a space-consuming exoskeleton.  It also has the advantage of leaving the top board unobstructed
so that I/O cards can be plugged in, allowing it to serve as the host machine for the AppleCrate.  (In fact,
I used 17 boards so that the top board can serve as master and leave 16 slave machines for parallel
programs.)</p>

<p>The Pushbutton 1 input and Annunciator 1 output bus wires and the AN2-to-PB2 GETID daisy chain wires are connected to
machined-pin sockets inserted into the 16-pin game port connector.  These connections support <a href="http://michaeljmahon.com/NadaNet.html">NadaNet</a>,
which is the only signal connection between the boards.  The network adapter (described below) is shown
with its mounting bracket under what will be the third board.  The power bus card is supported by a
similar angle bracket, and the standoffs immediately beneath them are filed down to accomodate the
bracket thickness.</p>

<p>The boards are powered by a PC AT power supply.  The average power consumed by an Apple //e
board is about 4.2 watts, so the whole 17-board crate consumes only about 70 watts in total,
and both the AppleCrate and the power supply run only a few degrees above ambient temperature.</p>

<p>I decided to use #12 copper bus wires
to distribute power to all boards (visible on the right side of the first photo).  I would have preferred
a connectorized approach, but I could not come up with a connector scheme with a
reasonable mating/unmating force.  As a result, I decided to go with soldered power connections.
(It's a good thing that Apple //e's are so reliable, since replacing one in the middle of the
stack would be relatively difficult!)</p>

<p>The top board is used as the "master" machine with I/O cards and an external keyboard plugged into it.
The Master boots the 16 slave Apples in the AppleCrate II and uses them to run parallel programs.
Once they have been booted and started, they can run independently of the master—though they are clearly
I/O-constrained!</p>

<b></b></span><b><span face="Arial, helvetica"><p>Indicators</p>
</span></b><span face="Arial, helvetica" size="2">

<p>It has proven useful to have some real-time indication of each board's activity.  The stock board contains a
red "power" LED (at the right) and a red "speaker" LED at the left.  Both are easily visible from the back of the
boards (the "front" of the AppleCrate).  The function of the power LED is fixed, but the speaker LED is usable
as an indicator that software running on the board can operate, just by toggling the speaker.  For example,
printing a "beep"—CHR$(07)—causes the speaker LED to flash for 0.1 second, and can be used to indicate some
condition in the software.  (The speaker LED will not light when a speaker is installed, but AppleCrate
boards have no speakers attached.)</p>

<p>Although the Applecrate network interface described below incorporates an LED to show global network activity,
it is very useful to be able to see when any particular board is sending on the network.  This need is met by
using the PDL 3 timer to "stretch" each packet send operation into a visible flash of a green rectangular LED.</p>

<p><img src="http://michaeljmahon.com/SendLED.jpg" width="762" height="263"></p>

<p>These photos show the modification made to the 558 timer chip, in which a 267-ohm resistor (just what I
had handy—any value between 220 and 560 ohms is fine) is connected
between pins 5 and 8, and the "send" signalling LED is connected between pin 8 and ground, with pin 8 going to the
anode.  The rectangular LED is carefully pressed between the cassette input and output jacks.  On some boards,
the jacks were so close together that it was necessary to "shave" the upper plastic swage on the side of the input
jack with an Exacto knife to make room for the LED to press fit between them.  (Note that in these photos the red
wire connected to the anode of the LED has not yet been soldered.)</p>

</span><b><span face="Arial, helvetica"><p>Network Boot in NadaNet 3.x</p>
</span></b><span face="Arial, helvetica" size="2">

<p>Since AppleCrate machines have no I/O capabilities other than
the network, they must be booted from the network.  This requires that the ROMs on the boards be replaced with
EPROMs containing modified RESET code to perform the network boot.</p>

<p>As with the AppleCrate I, replacement of the self-test code was the easiest path, since it is self-contained,
contiguous, and is executed upon power-on reset if no keyboard is connected.  However, the Enhanced //e ROM contains
only $200 bytes of self-test code, just half the size of the unenhanced //e self-test, requiring a new
design for the network boot.</p>

<p>The AppleCrate I used an "active" boot protocol, in which each board enabled by the "GETID daisy chain" (connected from
AN2 of the previous machine to PB2 of the current machine) continuously sent GETID requests to ID 1, until it was assigned
a permanent ID and received a NadaNet boot image.  The complexity of this protocol, requiring both sending and receiving
packets over the network, resulted in a boot ROM requirement of almost $400 bytes—which fit in an <b>Unenhanced</b> //e ROM.</p>

<p>Since the <b>Enhanced</b> //e ROM has only $200 bytes available, a new "passive" boot protocol had to be devised.
The <a href="http://michaeljmahon.com/PASSIVEBOOT.ROM.pdf">new ROM code</a> continuously monitors the network for a broadcast BOOTREQ control packet
containing  the load address and length of the immediately following boot code data.  When the boot image has been correctly
read from the network, control is passed to its starting address.  This passive boot code only needs to <b>read</b> packets from the
net, and so occupies just $190 bytes, which comfortably fits in place of the Enhanced //e ROM self-test code at $C600.</p>

<p>The new boot protocol capitalizes on the fact that boot code is sent as a broadcast transaction, so the
machines being booted do not need IDs to receive boot code.  A page of "second-stage boot" code is added at the
front of the slave machine boot image.  This code is given control immediately after the boot image is received, and,
when enabled by the "GETID daisy chain", it sends a GETID request to the machine that &amp;BOOTed it, making use of the
code in the full NadaNet boot image to do so (see the BOOT2 code in the <a href="http://michaeljmahon.com/NADA.CRATE.pdf">NADA.CRATE</a>
listing for details).</p>

<p>The GETID daisy chain functions just as it did in the AppleCrate I.  The "first" machine is permanently enabled
by connecting its PB2 to ground.  AN2 of each machine is connected
to PB2 of the "next" machine.  The second-stage boot code running in each machine initially sets its AN2.
Then it waits until it sees its PB2 go low, enabling it to send its GETID request.  When its GETID is successful
it drops its AN2, enabling the next machine.  Then it clears its video display, writes a banner showing the
machine ID, and enters its server loop.</p>

<p>This results in permanent
IDs being assigned in the fixed order of the physical daisy chain, while allowing all ROMs to be identical.
An LED on the AppleCrate II NadaNet adapter board is wired to the last machine's AN2, so that when the last
machine drops its AN2, the red LED extinguishes, signalling that all machines have booted successfully.</p>

<p>When a network-booting machine is reset, it first checks the network state.  If the network is low (ZERO),
it performs a cold start.  If the network is being held high (ONE), it checks page 3 to see if it is being cold started or warm reset.  If it is
a warm reset, it re-enters its Server loop.  If it is a cold start, it initializes and enters the ROM boot code, again waiting
for a BOOTREQ packet.  (This approach has the advantage of reliably forcing a reboot on a power cycle, while
still permitting boards to be warm reset while holding the network high.)</p>

<p>As of NadaNet 3.1, all AppleCrate boot ROMs must be <a href="http://michaeljmahon.com/PASSIVEBOOT.ROM.pdf">NadaNet 3.x capable</a>.</p>

</span><b><span face="Arial, helvetica"><p>AppleCrate II NadaNet Interface</p>
</span></b><span face="Arial, helvetica" size="2">
<p><a href="http://michaeljmahon.com/NadaNet.html">NadaNet</a> is a TTL-level serial network in which logic high is represented by a voltage greater than +2 volts
and logic low is represented by a voltage less than +0.7 volts.  The fanout capability of a TTL annunciator output
is sufficient to  drive a dozen or so TTL pushbutton inputs if they are not otherwise …</p></span></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://michaeljmahon.com/AppleCrateII.html">http://michaeljmahon.com/AppleCrateII.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://michaeljmahon.com/AppleCrateII.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25042551</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 03:23:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Best Practices for Writing Clean Interfaces in Go]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 43 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25042085">thread link</a>) | @lanecwagner
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | https://qvault.io/2020/03/15/best-practices-for-writing-clean-interfaces-in-go/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://qvault.io/2020/03/15/best-practices-for-writing-clean-interfaces-in-go/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
<p>Interfaces in Go allow us to treat different types as the same data type temporarily. They are central to a Go programmers toolbelt and are often used improperly by new Go developers… leading to hard to read and buggy code. Let’s take a look at some of the best practices for Golang interfaces.</p>



<h2>Recap on Interfaces</h2>



<p>I often look to the standard library as an example of the way to write clean Go. The standard error interface is simple:</p>



<pre><code lang="go">type error interface {
    Error() string
}</code></pre>



<p>The error interface encapsulates any type that has an <code>Error()</code> method defined on it. That method accepts no parameters, and returns a <em>string</em>. For example, let’s define a struct that represents a network problem:</p>



<pre><code lang="go">type networkProblem struct {
	message string
	code    int
}</code></pre>



<p>Then we define an <code>Error()</code> method:</p>



<pre><code lang="go">func (np networkProblem) Error() string {
	return fmt.Sprintf("network error! message: %s, code: %v", np.message, np.code)
}</code></pre>



<p>Now, we can use an instance of the <code>networkProblem</code> struct wherever an error is accepted.</p>



<pre><code lang="go">func handleErr(err error) {
	fmt.Println(err.Error())
}

np := networkProblem{
	message: "we received a problem",
	code:    404,
}

handleErr(np)

// prints "network error! message: we received a problem, code: 404"</code></pre>



<h2>Keep Interfaces Small</h2>



<p>If there is only one piece of advice that you take away from this article, make it this: <strong>keep interfaces small!</strong> Interfaces are meant to define the <em>minimal</em> behavior necessary to accurately represent an idea or concept. </p>



<p>Here is an example from the standard <a aria-label="HTTP package (opens in a new tab)" href="https://golang.org/pkg/net/http/#pkg-overview" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">HTTP package</a> of a larger interface that’s a good example of defining minimal behavior:</p>



<pre><code lang="go">type File interface {
    io.Closer
    io.Reader
    io.Seeker
    Readdir(count int) ([]os.FileInfo, error)
    Stat() (os.FileInfo, error)
}</code></pre>



<p>Any type that satisfies the interface’s behaviors can be considered by the HTTP package as a <em>File</em>. This is convenient because the HTTP package doesn’t need to know if it’s dealing with a file on disk, a network buffer, or a simple <code>[]byte</code>. </p>



<h2>Interfaces Should Have No Knowledge of Satisfying Types </h2>



<p>An interface should define what is necessary for other types to classify as a member of that interface. They shouldn’t be aware of any types that happen to satisfy the interface at design time.</p>



<p>For example, let’s assume we are building an interface to describe the components necessary to define a car.</p>



<pre><code lang="go">type car interface {
	GetColor() string
	GetSpeed() int
	IsFiretruck() bool
}</code></pre>



<p><code>GetColor()</code> and <code>GetSpeed()</code> make perfect sense, they are methods confined to the scope of a car. <code>IsFiretruck()</code> is an anti-pattern. We are forcing all cars to declare whether or not they are firetrucks. In order for this pattern to make any amount of sense, we would need a whole list of possible subtypes. <code>IsPickup()</code>, <code>IsSedan()</code>, <code>IsTank()</code>… where does it end??</p>



<p>Instead, the developer should have relied on the native functionality of <a href="https://yourbasic.org/golang/type-assertion-switch/" target="_blank" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">type assertion</a> to derive the underlying type when given an instance of the <strong>car</strong> interface. Or, if a sub-interface is needed, it can be defined as:</p>



<pre><code lang="go">type firetruck interface {
	car
	HoseLength() int
}</code></pre>



<p>Which inherits the required methods from <code>car</code> and adds one additional required method to make the car a <code>firetruck</code>.</p>



<h2>Interfaces Are Not Classes</h2>



<ul><li>Interfaces are not classes, they are slimmer.</li><li>Interfaces don’t have constructors or deconstructors that require that data is created or destroyed.</li><li>Interfaces aren’t hierarchical by nature, though there is syntactic sugar to create interfaces that happen to be supersets of other interfaces.</li><li>Interfaces define function signatures, but not underlying behavior. Making an interface often won’t <a aria-label="DRY (opens in a new tab)" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_repeat_yourself" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">DRY</a> up your code in regards to struct methods. For example, if five types satisfy the error interface, they all need their own version of the <code>Error()</code> function.</li></ul>







<h2>Related Work</h2>



<ul><li><a href="https://qvault.io/2020/03/29/how-to-separate-library-packages-in-go/">How To Separate Library Packages in Go</a></li><li><a href="https://qvault.io/2020/03/19/golang-mutexes-what-is-rwmutex-for/">Golang Mutexes – What Is RWMutex For?</a></li><li><a href="https://qvault.io/2020/02/20/how-to-build-jwts-in-go-golang/">How To Build JWT’s in Go (Golang)</a></li></ul>
		</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://qvault.io/2020/03/15/best-practices-for-writing-clean-interfaces-in-go/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25042085</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 01:53:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Debunking an election fraud claim using open data and Dolt]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 33 | Comments 30 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25041998">thread link</a>) | @proverbialbunny
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2020-11-09-debunking-election-fraud/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2020-11-09-debunking-election-fraud/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2020-11-09-debunking-election-fraud/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25041998</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 01:34:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Try Design Thinking]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 47 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25041961">thread link</a>) | @gbasin
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | https://garybasin.com/try-design-thinking/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://garybasin.com/try-design-thinking/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-2081">
	<img width="362" height="410" src="https://i1.wp.com/garybasin.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/remote-1.png?resize=362%2C410&amp;ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" alt="" loading="lazy" data-lazy-src="https://i1.wp.com/garybasin.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/remote-1.png?resize=362%2C410&amp;ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7">	<div>
		<!-- .entry-header -->

		<div>
			
<p>It’s 9pm, you’re at your friend’s house, and the show you’re watching ends. You scramble to change the channel but you can’t figure out the remote. You stare at dozens of buttons with no clue where to start. <strong>Doesn’t it make you feel stupid?</strong> Some experimentation might get you somewhere, but it’s not easy. Why can’t you figure it out?</p>



<p>In these situations, we often blame ourselves. We’re not smart, patient, or capable enough. This conclusion is incorrect ⏤ <strong>product design is the direct cause of the stress</strong>.</p>



<p>This realization won’t help you with your frustrating remote experience. However, it does emphasize the importance of user experience design. <strong>We can redesign experiences to create new feelings</strong>.</p>



<p>Next time you’re confronted with a bad user experience, <a href="https://twitter.com/garybasin/status/1324908038524899329">spend some time brainstorming better designs</a>. You never know where your experiments will take you.</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" width="362" height="950" src="https://i1.wp.com/garybasin.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/remote-1.png?resize=362%2C950&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/garybasin.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/remote-1.png?w=362&amp;ssl=1 362w, https://i1.wp.com/garybasin.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/remote-1.png?resize=114%2C300&amp;ssl=1 114w" sizes="(max-width: 362px) 100vw, 362px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i1.wp.com/garybasin.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/remote-1.png?w=362&amp;ssl=1 362w, https://i1.wp.com/garybasin.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/remote-1.png?resize=114%2C300&amp;ssl=1 114w" data-lazy-src="https://i1.wp.com/garybasin.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/remote-1.png?resize=362%2C950&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure></div>




					</div><!-- .entry-content -->

		<!-- .entry-meta -->
	</div>

	
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://garybasin.com/try-design-thinking/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25041961</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 01:27:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
