<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 12:33:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 12:33:33 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Open-source self-hosted comments systems for static websites]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 146 | Comments 34 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24676152">thread link</a>) | @nuker
<br/>
October 3, 2020 | https://lisakov.com/projects/open-source-comments/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://lisakov.com/projects/open-source-comments/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>This comparison table is inspired by
<a href="http://staticsitegenerators.net/">staticsitegenerators.net</a>. Contribute at
<a href="https://github.com/pozitron57/open-source-comments">github</a> —
add the missing data. Github-related data (stars, open issues + PR, etc.)
are updated daily automatically. Want different columns? Noted a bug? Submit
an <a href="https://github.com/pozitron57/open-source-comments/issues/new">issue</a>.</p>
<h2>What’s wrong with Disqus</h2>
<p>Disqus loads absurd amount of tracking services, which exposes your visitors’
personal data and significantly increases loading time. See, e.g., 
<a href="http://donw.io/post/github-comments/#what-s-wrong-with-disqus">this post</a>.</p>
<h2>What’s not covered here</h2>
<p>For a static website, one usually wants a lightweight commenting server with
as little dependencies as possible. Few commenting engines listed on the page
are provided by heavy applications (e.g.,
<a href="https://github.com/discourse/discourse">discourse</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/debiki/talkyard">talkyard</a>), but the majority are
relatively lightweight applications designed specifically to provide 
comments for the static pages.</p>
<p>This page prioritizes information on self-hosted comments. However, there
are other open-source solutions, including implementations of third-party
services (e.g., Github issues, such as
<a href="https://github.com/imsun/gitment">[1]</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/gitalk/gitalk">[2]</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/Blankj/awesome-comment">[3]</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/utterance/utterances">[4]</a>).</p>
<h2>Stars vs. time</h2>
<p>The figure below shows some of the top competitors except for Discourse (as it's not
just a light commenting server like others). The figure is useful to
indirectly estimate how active the project is.</p>
<p><a href="https://lisakov.com/projects/open-source-comments/stars-v-date.png">
<img src="https://lisakov.com/projects/open-source-comments/stars-v-date.png" alt="Plot stars vs. time" width="800px">
</a></p>
<h2>Choose columns to show</h2>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://lisakov.com/projects/open-source-comments/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24676152</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 02:31:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A web of trust for NPM]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 136 | Comments 101 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24673917">thread link</a>) | @tao_oat
<br/>
October 3, 2020 | https://www.btao.org/2020/10/02/npm-trust.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.btao.org/2020/10/02/npm-trust.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>In 1984 the co-inventor of Unix, Ken Thompson, delivered a seminal speech in which he highlighted that <em>you can’t trust code that you did not totally create yourself</em> <sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup>. For a while, this lesson was largely ignored as open-source package registries like RubyGems, PyPI and npm grew rapidly. However, as we’re seeing <a href="https://blog.reversinglabs.com/blog/mining-for-malicious-ruby-gems" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">more</a> <a href="https://blog.npmjs.org/post/185397814280/plot-to-steal-cryptocurrency-foiled-by-the-npm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">and</a> <a href="https://snyk.io/blog/a-post-mortem-of-the-malicious-event-stream-backdoor/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">more</a> supply-chain attacks through software dependencies, the risks of using unvetted dependencies are becoming clearer.</p>

<p>The risks are particularly great for JavaScript applications. Veracode found that the average JavaScript project relies on 377 dependencies – compared with just 16 for Python projects, or 43 in the Java ecosystem<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2">2</a></sup>. Whenever a developer pulls in a new dependency, they are implicitly trusting the maintainers of that dependency. Often, this trust is awarded on the basis of popularity – we assume that a popular library will be more carefully vetted, or that since many others trust the maintainers, we can too. Other times, this trust relationship and the risks involved are not considered at all.</p>

<p><a href="https://sambleckley.com/writing/npm.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Some have argued</a> that the ill health of the npm registry is a social, rather than a technical problem, and suggest a human-compiled set of packages in order to separate the wheat of maintained, healthy packages from the chaff of abandoned toy projects with no documentation. <a href="https://medium.com/@dpc_96143/cargo-crev-and-rust-2019-fearless-code-reuse-b75d58398cb8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Another suggestion from the Rust world</a> involves creating a manual web of trust from maintainers cryptographically signing each other’s projects. Either way, there are challenges: webs of trust have rarely taken off (outside of Debian), and compiling a vetted set of packages from scratch is a massive undertaking. I propose something in the middle: bootstrapping a web of trust using existing npm dependency relationships, and building from that foundation.</p>

<h2 id="existing-trust-relationships-in-npm">Existing trust relationships in npm</h2>

<p>Creating a web of trust from existing npm dependencies is, admittedly, somewhat problematic. As stated earlier, choosing to use a particular dependency is not always a well-considered decision based on researching its code and maintainers, and the trust relationship is merely implied. Similarly, there is no cryptographic verification of this weak trust, nor does npm currently have the infrastructure for such tools<sup id="fnref:3" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:3">3</a></sup>. What I am suggesting is an imperfect starting point to demonstrate the need for, and potential of, stronger trust measures in open source.</p>

<p>To construct this initial web, we can model npm’s maintainerships as a graph. If we let each node be a maintainer, then the edges between them are the trust relationship arising from using a dependency. In other words, if Alice maintains a package A, and A depends on package B maintained by Bob, then there is a directed edge from Alice to Bob. We can even weigh these edges by the number of Alice’s packages in which she implies trust of Bob.</p>

<h2 id="exploring-the-graph">Exploring the graph</h2>

<p>This simple model exhibits a power-law-like pattern in terms of trust: the vast majority of users are trusted by few or no others, and a very small number of users are highly trusted. This type of pattern is common in social networks: you see a similar thing emerge when plotting follower counts on Twitter. Such power laws often lead to a rich-get-richer feedback process in which the inequality (in terms of trust, in this case) gets more pronounced over time<sup id="fnref:4" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:4">4</a></sup>.</p>

<p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/efe1a929e64ebeeb021e79f341b35faa4baf1397/c0643/static/img/maintainer-wot-in-degrees.png" alt="Scatter plot of in-degree vs. number of users. Shows a roughly power-law relationship."></p>

<p>Who are these highly-trusted users? They’re who you’d expect: bots for large projects (e.g. <code>types</code>), corporate accounts (e.g. <code>fb</code>), and the maintainers of extremely popular open-source libraries (e.g. <code>sindresorhus</code>, who maintains e.g. <code>string-length</code>).</p>

<p>Perhaps more interestingly, this web of trust exhibits some useful structures. A number of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strongly_connected_component" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">strongly connected components</a> emerge – groups of users that, roughly speaking, all trust each other according to the web of trust principles (i.e. if I trust Alice, and Alice trusts Bob, then I trust Bob, too). All of these connected components are small, with the exception of a single one that’s home to over 11,000 users<sup id="fnref:5" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:5">5</a></sup>. This core component – we’ll call it the <strong>strong set</strong> – could provide a starting point for a measure of trust in the npm ecosystem.</p>



<p>We can quantify trust in a slightly more nuanced way than simply looking at the in-degree of each npm user. The PageRank algorithm provides such a measure that takes into account the trustworthiness of the people who trust me. For example, I may only be trusted by one user, but if that user is <code>isaacs</code> (the creator of npm) then that trust relationship counts for a lot! After running PageRank, the 10 “most-trusted” users are:</p>

<ol>
  <li><code>types</code></li>
  <li><code>sindresorhus</code></li>
  <li><code>angular</code></li>
  <li><code>m1tk4</code></li>
  <li><code>tjholowaychuk</code></li>
  <li><code>google-wombot</code></li>
  <li><code>fb</code></li>
  <li><code>isaacs</code></li>
  <li><code>gaearon</code></li>
  <li><code>yyx990803</code></li>
</ol>

<p>Many of these are unsurprising. However, <code>m1tk4</code> stands out: they only maintain two rarely-downloaded libraries. Because one of these libraries is used by the BBC, <code>m1tk4</code> is implicitly trusted by a large number of relatively trustworthy BBC employees who maintain other, more popular projects. This demonstrates how PageRank diffuses trust across the social network of npm maintainers. In fact, <code>m1tk4</code> is not a member of the strong set mentioned earlier – but many of the users who trust them <em>are</em>. <code>m1tk4</code> just doesn’t trust those users back!</p>

<p>While PageRank gives a fun measure of trust, it’s a very rough model for the reasons mentioned earlier: it’s based on a pretty weak indication of real trust. However, it might be useful in detecting suspicious behaviours in npm, which is something we – or registry maintainers – need to do proactively if we want to stop supply-chain attacks. For example, it might be a red flag if a highly-trusted user suddenly starts using a library by someone with a PageRank-based-trust of close to 0. And regardless, the strong set comes merely from observing which dependencies people choose to use without applying any complex calculations.</p>

<p>How might we want to use the strong set to create a stricter trust (or reputation) system? I think that formalizing such a system is unlikely if it requires large-scale buy-in from npm users. Instead, we might create a simple wrapper for npm that checks if you’re about to install something from a developer outside of the strong set, similar to Liran Tal’s excellent <a href="https://github.com/lirantal/npq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">npq</a>. Or perhaps security researchers could use the npm web of trust as an additional data point when deciding whether a suspicious package warrants further investigation. Either way, the state of trust within the npm ecosystem is not great. This model gives us a starting point.</p>

<p><em>Do you think I’ve got it all wrong? Or do you have further suggestions on how we can improve the state of trust in open source? <a href="https://www.btao.org/contact">Get in touch</a>.</em></p>

<p><em>A final note: this analysis is based on data from June 2020, which I collected for my Master’s thesis. I believe you’d reach similar numbers if you ran the analysis on data from today.</em></p>

<h3 id="footnotes">Footnotes</h3>



</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.btao.org/2020/10/02/npm-trust.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24673917</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 18:51:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Rust Starter Kit 2020]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 320 | Comments 95 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24671403">thread link</a>) | @psxuaw
<br/>
October 3, 2020 | https://wiki.alopex.li/RustStarterKit2020 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://wiki.alopex.li/RustStarterKit2020">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="wikipage">

<p>People were arguing about Rust’s std lib recently, so I went through the <code>Cargo.toml</code> of all the Rust projects I’ve written since 2015 and picked out the choice tools that get used over and over again. Up to date as of October 2020.</p>
<p>Also see <a href="https://wiki.alopex.li/RustCrates" title="Go to wiki page">RustCrates</a>, though that’s old. There’s also <a href="https://christine.website/blog/rust-crates-go-stdlib-2020-09-27">this</a>, which is narrower but deeper, and <a href="https://github.com/rust-unofficial/awesome-rust">awesome-rust</a>, which is shallower and broader, and the various <a href="https://www.arewewebyet.org/">more</a> <a href="https://arewegameyet.rs/">specific</a> <a href="https://areweasyncyet.rs/">websites</a> <a href="https://www.areweguiyet.com/">for various</a> <a href="https://areweideyet.com/">topics</a>.</p>

<p>I need to set up a new Rust dev environment, what do I install?</p>
<h2 id="linting-clippy">Linting – <code>clippy</code></h2>
<p>The one, the only, the great Rust style and correctness linter. Want to learn how to write “idiomatic” Rust, or just learn more about handy little corners of the language and library? Run <code>clippy</code> regularly. It’s distributed with the compiler via <code>rustup</code> now, so you have no excuse not to.</p>
<h2 id="build-cache-sccache">Build cache – <code>sccache</code></h2>
<p>Or, “how to make a full rebuild 70% faster”. <code>sccache</code> is a build artifact cache similar to <code>icecream</code> or <code>ccache</code>, except it’s actually trivial to just use. <code>cargo install sccache</code>, add a single line in a home dir config file, and you’re ready to go. Pretty much handles most crate and compiler versioning issues for you, so it Just Works if you update crates or install a new version of <code>rustc</code> or something. I think I’ve had to force-clear the cache due to some build weirdness a grand total of once. Looks like it has enough features to use in a professional context as well, at least on a small-to-medium scale.</p>
<h2 id="dependency-viewer-cargo-tree">Dependency viewer – <code>cargo-tree</code></h2>
<p>The best way to view what dependencies you are using, and what dependencies they are using, and so on. Best way to start cracking down on flabby dependencies.</p>
<h2 id="benchmarking-criterion">Benchmarking – <code>criterion</code></h2>
<p>Basically the best benchmark system out there. Incredibly simple to use, informative, and statistically sound. Doesn’t really do profiling, but it’s a good start for understanding your program’s performance, and better for proving that your implementation of X is faster than someone else’s.</p>
<h2 id="other-things">Other things</h2>
<p>Stuff that is less general purpose but occasionally very useful for the meta-programming process of choosing libraries, evaluating them, etc.</p>
<ul>
<li><code>cargo-geiger</code> – Measures how much unsafe code is in a codebase, and its dependencies</li>
<li><code>cargo-crev</code> – A <a href="https://wiki.alopex.li/ActuallyUsingCrev">very neat tool</a> for authoring and verifying distributed code reviews.</li>
<li>Various tools maintained by <a href="https://github.com/EmbarkStudios/rust-ecosystem">Embark Studios</a>, useful for production/company purposes like checking licenses, pinning specific versions of crates, etc.</li>
</ul>

<p>The cool stuff Real Computer Scientists write about.</p>
<h2 id="hashing">Hashing</h2>
<p>No specific crates here. There’s no single crate that provides All The Hash Algorithms, just lots of little ones that generally provide a single algorithm each. Just type the name of the algorithm you want into <code>crates.io</code> and you’ll get at least a couple options, choose the one with 8 million downloads or whatever. <code>sha2</code>, <code>md5</code>, <code>crc</code>, etc. Lots of them are written by the Rust core team.</p>
<h2 id="compression">Compression</h2>
<p>Same as the hashing category. Type <code>zip</code> or <code>bzip2</code> or whatever into crates.io and you’ll get what you need. <code>flate2</code> might be the one crate that’s not quite trivial to find. Again, many of them are written by the Rust core team.</p>
<h2 id="encryption">Encryption</h2>
<p>I have little actual experience or authority on this topic, so I’m going to punt on this one.</p>
<h2 id="pseudorandom-number-generator">Pseudorandom number generator</h2>
<p>Use <code>oorandom</code>. (Disclaimer, I wrote <code>oorandom</code>, but people besides me seem to like it.) More usually you’ll see the <code>rand</code> crate in use. If you’re doing Real Science and need to generate <a href="https://docs.scipy.org/doc/numpy-1.15.0/reference/routines.random.html">fancy probabilities</a>, then <code>rand</code> is the right tool, but most people aren’t doing that. Otherwise <code>rand</code> is complicated and has lots of features, while <code>oorandom</code> is very simple and has about two features, and I expect 80% of code to use at least one of them. <code>rand</code> has had several major breaking changes in its history that the rest of the ecosystem still hasn’t caught up with, while I intend <code>oorandom</code>’s API to change maybe twice in my lifetime. (Its version number, while obeying semver, is mostly a joke.)</p>
<p>There’s other lightweight PRNG crates that are just fine; see <code>oorandom</code>’s readme for a list of some others and choose one you like. Whatever you choose, use the <code>getrandom</code> crate to produce Real Random Seeds for it.</p>

<p>“I just need to solve this ooooooone common problem, but it needs to be solved WELL…”</p>
<h2 id="logging-log">Logging – <code>log</code></h2>
<p>Need to output log messages in your code? Why, use the <code>log</code> crate. Where do the log messages go? <code>log</code> provides only an interface, and that interface compiles to nothing if it isn’t used. You can write your own system for it to actually output the logs to, which is pretty easy, or use one of the small plethora of crates for it. My preferred one is <code>pretty_env_logger</code>, but <code>fern</code>, <code>slog</code> and others are all good too.</p>
<h2 id="parallel-data-crunching-rayon">Parallel data crunching – <code>rayon</code></h2>
<p>Ever have some computation where you have a big list of STUFF and want to process it in parallel, farming out jobs to as many threads as you have CPU’s? That’s what <code>rayon</code> does, and it does it really, really well. You still <a href="https://aspenuwu.me/posts/rust-optimization.html">have to know what you’re doing</a>, but changing a single <code>.iter()</code> into <code>.par_iter()</code> and watching your CPU-bound data-crunching run 8x faster is pretty magical. Now your CPU can help keep you warm this winter!</p>
<p>Please never use it in a library. It’s rude to spawn threads in library code, unless that’s specifically what the library is for.</p>
<h2 id="regexes-regex">Regexes – <code>regex</code></h2>
<p>To quote the inestimable <a href="https://www.jwz.org/blog/">jwz</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Some people, when confronted with a problem, think “I know, I’ll use regular expressions.” Now they have two problems.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>On the other hand, <a href="https://xkcd.com/208/">somebody’s gotta save the day</a>. So, use the <code>regex</code> crate. Also use <a href="https://crates.io/crates/ripgrep">anything else</a> <a href="https://crates.io/crates/xsv">written by BurntSushi</a>. BurntSushi is a paragon of Rust program design, and also just a great <del>human being</del> charred cuisine in general.</p>
<h2 id="threadsafe-globals-lazy_static">Threadsafe globals – <code>lazy_static</code></h2>
<p>“I know globals are evil,” you say, “but I just need one. I’ll only use it for good, I promise.” <code>lazy_static</code> has your back.</p>
<p>May eventually be superseded by <code>once_cell</code>, which looks like its <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs/pull/2788">headed for inclusion into <code>std</code></a>.</p>
<h2 id="serializationdeserialization-serde">Serialization/deserialization – <code>serde</code></h2>
<p>Ever have a struct and just wanted to turn it into JSON, CBOR, XML, or some other engine of woe and devastation designed to be written to an I/O stream? Or had a blob of random JSON and wanted to just stuff it into a struct matching it? Sure you have. <code>serde</code> lets you do this with a single <code>#[derive]</code>. <code>serde</code> is without a doubt one of Rust’s killer libraries. It is better than any other serialization system I have ever used.</p>
<p>What data formats does it support? Anything; the actual reading and writing is done via plugin library. There’s a <a href="https://serde.rs/#data-formats">wide selection of them</a>, of varying quality, and writing your own is a little tedious but not terribly difficult.</p>
<h2 id="error-handling">Error handling</h2>
<p>This spot deliberately left blank.</p>
<p>Rust’s <code>Result&lt;T,E&gt;</code> type is one of the best setups for lightweight, transparent error handling I’ve seen, but it doesn’t do everything. How do you easily write your own error type without a bunch of boilerplate? What if you have multiple different error types from different libraries you want to coalesce together? How do you collect a backtrace of every function an <code>Err</code> is returned through, so you can find the root cause of where it came from? Can we do all this without allocating anything unnecessarily? And so on.</p>
<p>There have been various crates to try to solve these problems. First in 2015 there was <code>error_chain</code>, which was complicated and not very convenient. Then in 2017 there was <code>failure</code>, which was simpler but not very flexible, and which took an irritatingly long time to compile. Then in 2019 there was <code>anyhow</code>, which was about the time I stopped paying attention. Now apparently the new kid on the block is <code>eyre</code>, and I’m sure that in another year or two there will be something else.</p>
<p>So, I just write the boilerplate and make my errors descriptive enough I don’t need a backtrace. When I want to get fancy I implement the built-in <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/error/trait.Error.html"><code>Error</code></a> trait, which used to be kinda useless but is now more helpful. And in another five years it’ll still work just fine.</p>
<h2 id="byte-mucking-bytemuck">Byte mucking – <code>bytemuck</code></h2>
<p>For the rare occasions you need to turn a structure into arbitrary <code>&amp;[u8]</code> or back. Doing this using unsafe pointers is quite easy, and also makes it very easy to screw up horribly with Undefined Behavior galore. (Did you know that changing the value of padding bytes in a struct in UB? You do now.) <code>bytemuck</code> lets you muck around with bytes a little more responsibly.</p>
<h2 id="human-dates-and-times-chrono">Human dates and times – <code>chrono</code></h2>
<p>Rust’s <code>std::time</code> doesn’t really handle calendar or wall-clock times, just arbitrary, monotonic <code>Instant</code>’s and measurable <code>Duration</code>’s between them. Nice, pure, computationally-robust time measurement. For all the nasty human calendar and timezone stuff, you use <code>chrono</code>. (And maybe <code>humantime</code>, but I personally reach for <code>chrono</code> first, just out of habit.)</p>
<h2 id="bit-flags-bitflags">Bit flags – <code>bitflags</code></h2>
<p>Defining type-safe bit-masks in a reasonably convenient way. Not always worth the trouble, but sometimes pretty convenient.</p>

<p>“I have to create or read a…”</p>
<h2 id="pngjpeggifetc-image">PNG/JPEG/GIF/etc – <code>image</code></h2>
<p>General-purpose loading and saving and images, which can handle a lot of formats. Can do some amount of image manipulation as well, such as cropping, smoothing, etc. but that will hopefully be pulled out into its own library at some point soon.</p>
<h2 id="small-data-things-uuid-base64-csv-semver">Small data THINGS – <code>uuid</code>, <code>base64</code>, <code>csv</code>, <code>semver</code>…</h2>
<p>Exactly what it says on the tin.</p>

<p>Not aware of any great encoders, but there’s plenty of <em>decoders</em> for common audio formats. <code>lewton</code> for Ogg Vorbis, <code>hound</code> for .wav, <code>minimp3</code> for MP3, <code>claxon</code> for FLAC. Video, I haven’t used enough to have an opinion on.</p>
<h2 id="config-files-toml">Config files – <code>toml</code></h2>
<p>For all your config file format needs. Works with <code>serde</code>, naturally.</p>
<h2 id="markdown-pulldown-cmark">Markdown – <code>pulldown-cmark</code></h2>
<p>There’s several good Markdown readers and writers, <code>pulldown-cmark</code> is my favorite. It supports CommonMark, it’s simple to use, and it’s pure Rust.</p>
<h2 id="templating-askama">Templating – <code>askama</code></h2>
<p>There’s several quite good text templating engines, but <code>askama</code> IMO rises above them all by compiling your templates into Rust code and type-checking your templates at compile time. Sometimes this isn’t what you want, but it is a great feature surprisingly often. This also makes it super fast, for when you really need to …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://wiki.alopex.li/RustStarterKit2020">https://wiki.alopex.li/RustStarterKit2020</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://wiki.alopex.li/RustStarterKit2020</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24671403</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 12:04:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The case for building a SETI observatory on the moon]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 160 | Comments 70 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24670960">thread link</a>) | @pseudolus
<br/>
October 3, 2020 | https://www.supercluster.com/editorial/the-case-for-building-a-seti-observatory-on-the-moon | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.supercluster.com/editorial/the-case-for-building-a-seti-observatory-on-the-moon">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span>On Monday, a group of researchers sponsored by Breakthrough Listen, the world’s largest SETI program, </span><a href="http://seti.berkeley.edu/lunarseti/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">submitted a paper</a><span> to National Academy of Sciences’ Planetary Science and Astrobiology Decadal Survey that makes the case for establishing a SETI radio observatory on the farside of the moon. The decadal survey establishes scientific priorities for the next ten years and the new paper addresses one of the biggest problems facing the search for extraterrestrial intelligence today: The overwhelming amount of radio interference.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>Our planet has become so “loud” in the part of the radio spectrum observed by SETI that it threatens to drown out any signal sent from an intelligent civilization. Not only would a lunar radio telescope not have to deal with terrestrial radio interference, it could also significantly increase our chances of hearing from ET by opening up parts of the radio spectrum that are blocked by Earth's atmosphere. While the idea of using the moon for radio astronomy is decades old, the researchers make the case that technological advancements have finally made a lunar SETI observatory truly feasible.</span></p></div><div><div><p><span>
says Eric Michaud, an intern at the SETI Berkeley Research Center and the first author of the paper. “Maybe not today, but I think it’s going to get more and more feasible as time goes on.”&nbsp;</span></p></div></div><div><p><span>Radio interference has been a problem for SETI from the very beginning. In the spring of 1960, the planetary scientist Frank Drake trained the massive radio telescope at Green Bank Observatory in West Virginia on Tau Ceti and Epsilon Eridani, two stars a mere 12 light years from Earth. That summer, Drake spent his days studying the signals picked up by Green Bank’s giant mechanical ear in the hopes of receiving a message broadcast by an alien civilization orbiting those stars. Known as Project Ozma, Drake’s experiment marked the beginning of SETI, the scientific search for extraterrestrial intelligence.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>Shortly after Drake started his observations, he was surprised to find what appeared to be a signal of intelligent origin. After days of watching a needle drift lazily over a spool of paper recording the random undulations of cosmic static, Drake and his colleagues were jolted awake when the machine started recording the frantic pulses of a strong radio signal picked up by the telescope. The timing and magnitude of the pulses clearly marked them as artificial; there was nothing in the natural world that could produce such a frenetic radio profile. It would have been an astounding stroke of luck to pick up an alien message after only a few hours of observation, but it was hard to argue with the data.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>“None of us had ever seen anything like it,” Drake recalled in </span><em>Is Anyone Out There?</em><span>, his autobiographical book about the early days of SETI. “We looked at each other wide-eyed. Could discovery be this easy?”</span></p></div><div><div><p><span>

It was a letdown, but the false detection turned out to be a portent for the future of SETI. In the 60 years since Drake’s pioneering experiment, researchers have conducted dozens of SETI searches across thousands of stars and turned up empty-handed. At the same time, the sources of radio interference on Earth—military radars, TV towers, cell phones, and satellites—have exponentially increased, which greatly increases the chances that an extraterrestrial signal will be lost among the noise.&nbsp;</span></p></div></div><div><p><span>Earth was never a particularly great place to do any kind of radio astronomy due to our thick atmosphere blocking a large portion of the radio spectrum. The proliferation of radio communication technologies has only made things harder. The moon, by comparison, has no atmosphere and its nights last for weeks on end, which limits radio noise from the sun. And as&nbsp;NASA discovered through a spate of lunar orbiter missions in the late 1960s, the moon also acts as a natural shield that blocks radio signals emanating from Earth. As the planetary astronomer Phillipe Zarka has put it, “the farside of the moon during the lunar night is the most radio-quiet place in our local universe.” It’s exactly the sort of peace and quiet you want if you’re searching for faint radio signals from solar systems that might be hundreds of light years away.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>The new Breakthrough Listen paper proposed two main approaches to a lunar SETI observatory: an orbiter and a telescope on the surface. The basic idea behind a SETI lunar orbiter would be to scan for signals as it passed over the lunar farside and relay data back to Earth as it passed over the near side. One of the main advantages of an orbiter is cost. The proliferation of small satellites that are capable of accurate tracking combined with low-cost small launch providers like Rocket Lab means that a SETI orbiter could conceivably be sent to the moon </span><a href="https://www.nasa.gov/press-release/nasa-awards-contract-to-launch-cubesat-to-moon-from-virginia/#:~:text=The%20firm%2Dfixed%2Dprice%20launch,Tyvak%20Nano%2DSatellite%20Systems%20Inc." rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">for less than $20 million</a><span>. This would be a valuable pathfinder mission that could pave the way for a more ambitious observatory on the surface, but without the risk and cost.&nbsp; As the </span><a href="https://www.supercluster.com/editorial/the-supercluster-podcast-water-bears-might-now-occupy-the-moon" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">ill-fated Israeli Beresheet lander mission</a><span> reminded us, landing on the moon is extremely challenging even when the mission is backed by $100 million.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>But a SETI lunar orbiter would also come with a lot of compromises. It would only be able to conduct observations during the brief stretches when it was on the lunar farside, which would make a sustained observation campaign more challenging. The upshot is that an orbiter would have access to the full sky, whereas a telescope on the surface would be constrained by the moon’s rotation. The biggest downside of an orbiter is that it might lose a lot of the shielding benefits of the moon and be more vulnerable to radio interference from Earth since it would be orbiting high above the lunar surface.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>“The first SETI observations that are done from the lunar farside will be done from orbit, there’s no question about that,” says Andrew Siemion, the director of the Berkeley SETI Research Center and the second author on the paper. “I think eventually we absolutely want to do something on the surface because we want to build a very large aperture telescope, but even when we’re at that point I don’t think that would negate the utility of doing things from orbit as well.”&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>So what would a SETI observatory on the moon look like? One idea is to use the naturally parabolic lunar crater as a radio dish, much like the Arecibo telescope in Puerto Rico and </span><a href="https://www.supercluster.com/editorial/chinas-massive-telescope-is-the-next-great-seti-hope" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">the FAST telescope in China</a><span>, which are built into natural depressions in the land. This idea was </span><a href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1029/RS012i005p00845" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">first considered</a><span> back in the late 1970s by a group of scientists at the radio physics lab at the Stanford Research Institute. Their idea was to recreate Arecibo on the moon by suspending an antenna from the lip of a crater and using the basin as a reflector. The reduced gravity on the moon would allow for a radio telescope far larger than any on Earth, which could significantly enhance the sensitivity of SETI searches. Ultimately the researchers concluded that a lunar radio observatory was too expensive compared to SETI telescopes that could be built on Earth.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>But 40 years later, Michaud says that building a radio dish in a lunar crater may finally be cheap enough to pull off. One of the main drivers of this cost reduction is the advent of commercial launch providers like SpaceX and Rocket Lab, which have </span><a href="https://www.supercluster.com/editorial/cheaper-rockets-growing-the-human-family-in-space" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">dramatically lowered the cost of space access</a><span>. Another driver is NASA’s push to establish a permanent human presence on the moon, which has subsidized the development of a fleet of commercial lunar exploration vehicles. “There’s so much interest in going back to the moon,” says Michaud, who cited Blue Origin’s lunar lander and Rocket Lab’s Photon Lunar satellite as examples of technologies enabled by </span><a href="https://www.supercluster.com/editorial/nasas-first-puerto-rican-born-director-aims-for-a-moonshot" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">NASA’s Artemis program</a><span>.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>A crux of the original vision for lunar SETI observatories was that it would require a human settlement on the moon to build and operate the radio dish. But robotic systems have improved enough that it may be possible to take humans out of the equation. This was clearly demonstrated in 2019 when China’s Chang’e 4 rover landed autonomously on the farside of the moon. These advancements in autonomous navigation have laid the foundation for a lunar radio observatory that is built entirely by robots.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>It sounds like science fiction, but earlier this year NASA’s Advanced Innovative Concepts program </span><a href="https://www.nasa.gov/directorates/spacetech/niac/2020_Phase_I_Phase_II/lunar_crater_radio_telescope/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">awarded one of it’s prestigious grants to Saptarshi Bandyopadhyay, a researcher at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory, to figure out a way to make it happen</a><span>. His idea is to use rovers to deploy wire mesh in a crater on the lunar farside and suspend a receiver over the dish. NIAC is all about funding high risk, high reward missions, and there’s no guarantee that Bandyopadhyay’s proposal will ever come to fruition. Still, addressing the technical problems associated with building a radio receiver on the farside of the moon is an important first step.</span></p></div><div><p><span>And Bandyopadhyay isn’t the only NASA-backed researcher contemplating a lunar radio observatory. Jack Burns, a radio astronomer at the University of Colorado, has also received a grant to study a mission concept for a radio telescope array called </span><a href="https://www.colorado.edu/project/lunar-farside/dr-jack-burns" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">FARSIDE</a><span>. Instead of using a crater as a dish, FARSIDE would deploy several smaller antennas across the lunar surface that would collectively form a large radio telescope. Both NASA studies are focused on radio astronomy rather than SETI, but Siemion sees the two disciplines as natural allies in the quest to establish an observatory on the lunar farside. SETI has piggybacked on other radio astronomy projects in the past—SERENDIP, for instance, opportunistically searched for ET signals during radio observation campaigns at a variety of telescopes—and it seems plausible that a similar arrangement could be made with an observatory on the moon.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>Siemion acknowledged that there were certain technical challenges that would arise in a collaboration on a lunar radio observatory. The biggest issue, he says, is that a lot of radio astronomy is done at frequencies that don’t really require an observatory on the moon. “Radio …</span></p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.supercluster.com/editorial/the-case-for-building-a-seti-observatory-on-the-moon">https://www.supercluster.com/editorial/the-case-for-building-a-seti-observatory-on-the-moon</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.supercluster.com/editorial/the-case-for-building-a-seti-observatory-on-the-moon</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24670960</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 10:14:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[An Honest Review of Gatsby]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 171 | Comments 113 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24670252">thread link</a>) | @ehfeng
<br/>
October 3, 2020 | https://cra.mr/an-honest-review-of-gatsby/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://cra.mr/an-honest-review-of-gatsby/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>We decided to adopt Gatsby for <a href="https://docs.sentry.io/">Sentry’s customer-facing documentation</a> - well, I should say that <em>I</em> decided. We were already using it successfully for a variety of static marketing content, and I knew it had a lot of hype, so after a brief proof-of-concept it seemed like a safe choice.</p>
<p>To help contextualize everything I’m about to say, it’s important to understand the scope of our usage. Sentry’s documentation is not as straightforward as you might think - in fact, there are over 3,000 pages as of writing. We have a large amount of templated content designed to render language-specific examples, as well as a variety of different types of documentation (user guides, help desk-y articles, code-rich technical docs). Originally we had extended Jekyll to support a lot of this, but Ruby isn’t widely used at Sentry (approximately 0% of the engineering team knows Ruby), and it had become a big mess of spaghetti code with slow build times.</p>
<p>I also want to note that while this blog post is primarily focusing on the flaws of Gatsby as a framework, I’m not here to tell you that it’s not good for your use case. That said, I was not able to discover many of these short comings easily when evaluating Gatsby, and many things you read on the internet don’t stem out of real-world usage. My hope here is that Gatsby continues to improve over time, and that, as a user, you can be more informed about if it’s the right choice for you.</p>
<h2>Adopting Gatsby</h2>
<p>So, enter Gatsby. It seemed fast, was built on React (we’re experts on that here, with our gigabyte-sized Sentry frontend app), and had a huge adoption (assumed future existence and stability). While we didn’t have the desire to use MDX, it also seemed like a positive outcome given we could more easily deal with some of the rich aspects of our docs site, without having to resort to 2010-era JavaScript. We assumed a bunch of the other features of Gatsby had value-add, but we didn’t have an immediate need. These were things like dynamic source data - thus the need for a GraphQL engine at all - as well as the large plug-in ecosystem.</p>
<p>We started by iteratively converting sections of the Jekyll site into Gatsby - running them side by side for a time. At one point we eventually bulk converted pages, and ripped off the band aid. At this point though it was becoming clear build times were a problem. You’d spend at least 5 minutes on image optimization alone, with no way to even disable that. Slowly but surely we were depleting the ozone later on re-optimizing images which had already been pre-optimized. Oh yeah, and we were crippling our iteration speed as well, since the build cache would invalidate under a variety of situations in early development.</p>
<p>Making this worse was how we deployed Gatsby. We started off leveraging what we had already done: deploying Jekyll with Docker onto our own infrastructure - effectively just proxied via a CDN. We continued that for a period of time, but deploy times were far too long - upwards of 30-40 minutes for everything to build. Eventually we moved over to <a href="https://vercel.com/">Vercel</a> which dropped it down closer to 10 minutes, but ultimately it can’t fix what it doesn’t control.</p>
<p>The build and deploy times were the first of many woes, and they represent what would become a continued frustration: a problem without a clear solution.</p>
<h2>Enter MDX</h2>
<p>Rewind time a little bit - this actually wasn’t our first project converting documentation to Gatsby. The proof-of-concept I mentioned earlier was actually our <a href="https://develop.sentry.dev/">developer documentation</a>, which I had migrated out of Notion to make public. While doing that we had gotten our hands dirty with some initial MDX usability and extensions - like our code samples which support toggling between different languages. This was one of the many things we needed to solve for, but MDX made it look like it’d be seemingly easy. No more jQuery DOM manipulation, just clean, encapsulated React components. Or so we thought.</p>
<p>Almost immediately we hit rough spots with MDX. We were coming from Jekyll - which was Liquid-rendered (a template engine) markdown - to MDX - a strange offspring of Markdown and JSX, attempting all of the benefits of both, but missing by a fairly large margin. Let’s illustrate the crux of the issue with what has got to be one of the most common needs in a documentation system: an alert (or callout) component:</p>
<div data-language="markdown"><pre><code><span><span><span>&lt;</span>Alert</span> <span>level</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>info<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span>You should know something important about this!<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>Alert</span><span>&gt;</span></span></code></pre></div>
<p>At face value this looks great. <code>Alert</code> is just a React component, and JSX is close enough to HTML that non-technical folks are able to pick it up fairly easily. Now the problem comes into play when you actually want to do something in the real world. Here’s an example from our API docs:</p>
<div data-language="markdown"><pre><code><span><span><span>&lt;</span>Alert</span> <span>level</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>warning<span>"</span></span> <span>title</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>Note<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span>
    <span><span>**</span><span>PUT/DELETE</span><span>**</span></span> methods only apply to updating/deleting issues.
Events in sentry are immutable and can only be deleted by deleting the whole issue.
<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>Alert</span><span>&gt;</span></span></code></pre></div>
<p>How would you expect this to render? Both as an engineer and a non-engineer, I would expect - given this is markdown - that the “PUT/DELETE” text would be bold. It’s not. Because the MDX interpreter decides that once you enter a component block, it’s no longer markdown. So instead, we’re forced with this monstrosity <em>everywhere</em> in our documentation:</p>
<div data-language="markdown"><pre><code><span><span><span>&lt;</span>Alert</span> <span>level</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>warning<span>"</span></span> <span>title</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>Note<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span><span><span><span>&lt;</span>markdown</span><span>&gt;</span></span>

<span><span>**</span><span>PUT/DELETE</span><span>**</span></span> methods only apply to updating/deleting issues.
Events in sentry are immutable and can only be deleted by deleting the whole issue.

<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>markdown</span><span>&gt;</span></span><span><span><span>&lt;/</span>Alert</span><span>&gt;</span></span></code></pre></div>
<p>There’s two things you should note here: 1) we have to use this <code>&lt;markdown&gt;</code> tag, 2) we have to put empty new-lines to ensure paragraph tags render.</p>
<p>“But David”, you might say, “why don’t you just tell the <code>Alert</code> component to render the text as markdown?“. If only you could, or at least, if only I could have possibly found a way to achieve that as a user with minimal Gatsby or MDX internals knowledge.</p>
<p>To Gatsby, or at least to the MDX team’s credit, they recognize some of these problems and <a href="https://github.com/mdx-js/mdx/issues/1041">there is work underway</a> on a 2.0 of the MDX dialect. While I’m confident they will improve things, I’m not confident MDX can ultimately succeed. It’s likely going to tradeoff one problem for another due to what it’s trying to achieve in the first place. It may get to a good place, but frankly, we need to step back and look at what we’re trying to solve, instead of creating a solution to a problem we don’t have. I don’t need JSX syntax in my markdown, I need a way to include JSX components. That might sound similar, but its quite a different thing.</p>
<p>As an example, there’s no reason I couldn’t simply use markdown syntax, and provide a way to achieve something akin to:</p>
<div data-language="markdown"><pre><code><span><span><span>&lt;</span>a-valid-html-tag-because-markdown-allows-that</span> <span>a-valid-property</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>a-value<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span></code></pre></div>
<p>This wouldn’t force us to work around quirks in a new language (or interpreter even), and could be solved in a much more sustainable way. There are other alternatives as well. A generic way to render extensions in markdown could simply call into a React component, and avoid even trying to hijack HTML in the first place. While I don’t know what this might look like in Markdown, in <a href="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/en/master/usage/restructuredtext/index.html">Sphinx’s use of reStructuredText</a> this was solved early on with Directives:</p>
<div data-language="text"><pre><code>.. my-directive:: some data
   :property-name: property-value</code></pre></div>
<p>I will hold out for MDX 2.0 and hope that finds a nice minimal-compromise place, but if not, we’ll be looking for a way to extend native markdown.</p>
<h2>A Broken DOM</h2>
<p>While we were able to work around the kinks of MDX, there’s been some things not yet solved. One of those is the layer which Gatsby uses to apply diffs to the DOM. I’m going to caveat this section with <em>I don’t know what the technical implementation is</em>, but I can make some assumptions given what I know of the domain. The system itself is intended to apply deltas to the DOM. This is naively also how React works, and I imagine under the hood it’s relying on React at least for part of it. We’ve had issues with this identified in two places already:</p>
<ul>
<li>progressive image loading</li>
<li>dynamic JSX components</li>
</ul>
<p>While they might not be linked to the same issue, they smell like they are, so we’re going to roll with it. The problem exhibits itself when you have a bunch of DOM that to a naive robot might look the same:</p>
<div data-language="text"><pre><code>&lt;div&gt;foo&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;bar&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;baz&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;foobizbar&lt;/div&gt;</code></pre></div>
<p>In React it uses the graph to identify which node is which - effectively creating a unique entity ID based on its location. In cases where that’s difficult, React will warn you to explicitly bind a <code>key</code> attribute on each element to ensure it can more accurately deal with updates. While I would assume Gatsby is at least partially using React’s DOM engine, what we see in production effectively takes the above example, and replaces some of the content with other subsets of content - meaning it’s unable to accurately identify which nodes need updated.</p>
<p>We’ve seen this where a progressive image is replaced with an entirely different image that’s present near it on the page. We’ve also seen this happen for a dynamically loaded section of content (our language-selector include tags). While we’ve yet to identify a fix for the image tags, our other issue was resolved by literally changing a <code>div</code> tag to a different tag, one which is less commonly used (in our case, <code>section</code>).</p>
<p>All of the cases happen after Gatsby’s initial static render and exist only when applying some form of delta.</p>
<h2>Let’s Talk GraphQL</h2>
<p>It’s a static website generator. It literally does not need GraphQL all over the place. While there are few instances in the real world where that is valuable, it shouldn’t require a GraphQL API to read objects that are already in memory.</p>
<p>I don’t want to spend the energy to hammer this in, but take a look at Jared Palmer’s <a href="https://jaredpalmer.com/gatsby-vs-nextjs">Gatsby vs. Next.js</a> as it echoes my thoughts.</p>
<p>So, let’s actually not talk about GraphQL, but all its done is create complexity for us.</p>
<h2>Minor Gripes</h2>
<p>There’s a number of other things we’ve found fairly frustrating at this point, but this post is already getting long, so I’m choosing to summarize them.</p></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://cra.mr/an-honest-review-of-gatsby/">https://cra.mr/an-honest-review-of-gatsby/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://cra.mr/an-honest-review-of-gatsby/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24670252</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 07:18:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
