<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 10]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 10. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 08:35:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-10.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 08:35:13 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Rust, Zig, and the Futility of “Replacing” C]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 14 | Comments 27 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26291054">thread link</a>) | @ghoward
<br/>
February 27, 2021 | https://gavinhoward.com/2021/02/rust-zig-and-the-futility-of-replacing-c/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://gavinhoward.com/2021/02/rust-zig-and-the-futility-of-replacing-c/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p>This post has been discussed on <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26291054#26294846">Hacker News</a>, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/rust/comments/luawx6/rust_zig_and_the_futility_of_replacing_c/"><code>/r/rust</code></a>, and
<a href="https://lobste.rs/s/1iiifg"><code>lobste.rs</code></a>.</p><p>I should not have posted this to Hacker News on a Saturday night right before
going to bed, but in my defense, this post blew up in a way I didn’t expect.</p></div><h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2><p>There was a recent <a href="https://github.com/pyca/cryptography/issues/5771">dust-up on GitHub</a> surrounding the decision by the
<a href="https://github.com/pyca/cryptography">Cryptography library</a> (which I will call <code>cryptography</code> for convenience) to
switch to <a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/">Rust</a>.</p><p>One of the distro maintainers of my distro of choice, <a href="https://www.gentoo.org/">Gentoo</a>, filed a bug
report with the <code>crytography</code> saying that the switch broke builds on several
platforms that Gentoo still supports. The <code>cryptography</code> authors replied that
those platforms are not really used anymore, and that they were going to stick
with Rust because it has better memory safety than C. They also argued that it
is better to force better programming languages on people because of better
security.</p><p>At first glance, it appears that the better argument is on the side of the
<code>cryptography</code> maintainers, but after thinking about it carefully, I think they
are wrong.</p><h2 id="reasons">Reasons</h2><p>There are a few reasons why I believe the <code>cryptography</code> maintainers are at
fault.</p><h3 id="due-diligence">Due Diligence</h3><p>First, their argument for Rust (and against C) because of memory safety implies
that they have not done due diligence in finding and fixing such bugs.</p><p>I can almost hear the rage of my readers against that paragraph above and
against the fact that I don’t have a commenting system on my blog. So let me
answer the comments preemptively.</p><p>“They are volunteers, giving their time away for free!”</p><p>Yes, but they also <em>intend</em> for their code to be used widely. They managed to
succeed in that, so they now have some obligation to their users.</p><p>“They don’t have any obligation!”</p><p>If a software project actively goes out and gets users, which just about any
project with a serious number of users has done, then yes, they have an
obligation to those users. The reason is that they sold users on the idea of
using their software. In other words, they were marketing their software, which
means making promises.</p><p>In fact, when people release <em>libraries</em> and try to get users for them, it’s
<em>because</em> they want them to be used by downstream programmers. A programmer
might write a program to scratch an itch and release it, but that reasoning
applies much less to libraries, in my opinion.</p><p>“Okay, but they didn’t get anything in return, so there’s still no obligation.”</p><p>In return, the users gave them <strong>relevance</strong>.</p><p>One of the most vocal (in favor of Rust) developers of <code>cryptography</code> works for
Red Hat Security Engineering (if I read his GitHub profile right). I don’t know
if his work on <code>cryptography</code> helped him get that job, but it might have.</p><p>Another of the most vocal developers has a computer security company. I would
bet money that his work on <code>cryptography</code> gives his company relevance.</p><p>So they did <em>not</em> get “nothing” from users. Quite the opposite, in fact.</p><p>By the way, this position comes from my own experience pushing my <a href="https://git.yzena.com/gavin/bc"><code>bc</code></a>. I
managed to convince the FreeBSD project to <a href="https://github.com/freebsd/freebsd-src/tree/main/contrib/bc">make it the default</a> in FreeBSD
13.</p><p>Once I did that, I shouldered, willingly, the need to keep FreeBSD happy. And
while I have made mistakes, I have done well so far.</p><p>And with my <code>bc</code>, <strong>I did my due diligence with memory safety</strong>. I fuzzed my
<code>bc</code> and eliminated all of the bugs. I even run the generated fuzzer test cases
through AddressSanitizer, and my entire test suite is run through Valgrind
<em>and</em> AddressSanitizer. I also add failing fuzzer cases to my test suite, which
means I run more and more test cases through both of those frightfully
effective tools.</p><p>For the record, those tools are only effective with effective test suites, which
I spent a lot of time building. But <em>building</em> such a test suite is part of due
diligence itself.</p><p>So it follows that if the developers have <em>not</em> done their due diligence, their
users should <strong>leave</strong>, either by forking the project or creating a new one.
The relevance they gave to the <code>cryptography</code> authors should disappear.</p><h3 id="battle-tested-c-code">Battle-Tested C Code</h3><p>In fact, I have done enough due diligence with my <code>bc</code> that I would consider it
a dereliction of duty to Rewrite It in Rust (RIIR).</p><p>Why would it be a dereliction of duty? Because rewriting it in Rust would cause
<em>more</em> bugs, not less. This is because of several reasons:</p><ol><li>I would need to <em>redesign</em> it to fit the language.</li><li>I would need to <em>reimplement</em> it, and new implementations always have bugs.</li><li>The C code is battle-tested, both by me (using fuzzing and other techniques)
and by users.</li></ol><p>That last point is the most crucial, especially in the case of <code>cryptography</code>.</p><p>If the developers of <code>cryptography</code> claim that they have, in fact, done their
due diligence with regards to memory safety in their C code, then they are
claiming that it’s battle-tested.</p><p>The saying that “a bird in the hand is worth two in the bush,” and in this case,
<em><strong>if</strong></em> the <code>cryptography</code> developers are claiming that they have done their
due diligence, they are throwing away a bird in the hand for a single one in the
bush.</p><div><p><strong>Edit (28 Feb 2021)</strong>: This part of the post seems to be misunderstood widely,
so I am going to attempt to clarify.</p><p>People are arguing that having safe C code requires a frozen, small codebase
with a thorough test suite. And then they debate my position based on the belief
that the codebase needs to evolve.</p><p>For the record, I agree with them that in order to have safe C code, the
codebase must be small and frozen.</p><p>What I am arguing is that <strong>crypto</strong> code <em>should</em> be small and frozen, with a
thorough test suite. I wrote about that <a href="https://gavinhoward.com/2019/11/finishing-software/">here</a>.</p></div><p>And if that’s the case, their users should <strong>leave</strong> and take <code>cryptography</code>'s
relevance with them.</p><h3 id="desktops-and-smartphones-are-not-the-only-computers">Desktops and Smartphones Are Not the Only Computers</h3><p>The users of <code>cryptography</code> were claiming in the bug report discussion that Rust
is not portable to many platforms, and the authors said that they don’t have the
time or resources to target those platforms. Fair enough.</p><p>But then they claim that the <em>users</em> should put in the effort to port Rust to
their platforms. This is wrong.</p><p>The <code>cryptography</code> authors also claim that the platforms that Rust doesn’t
support do not matter. As we will see below, this is false.</p><p>While I agree that the <code>cryptography</code> authors are not responsible for porting
Rust to other platforms, the users of those platforms are not either.</p><p>That responsibility falls on the Rust developers.</p><p><em>They</em> were the ones who sold Rust to those who have used it, so as above,
<em>they</em> have the responsibility for supporting their users.</p><p>Granted, the Rust developers have made no claim about being portable to every
platform. But they <em>have</em> claimed that it is <a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/what/embedded">appropriate for embedded
software</a>.</p><p>If it were true, this would be great. After all, <a href="https://youtu.be/3HxPzutkNYw?t=257">IoT devices outnumber
desktops and smartphones by at least one order of magnitude</a>.</p><p>But there are a lot of them that LLVM, Rust’s backend, cannot generate code
for. In fact, there are a lot of them that <em>C++</em> cannot run on.</p><div><p><strong>Edit (28 Feb 2021)</strong>: Also, the Rust developers are the developers with the
most experience reading ISA manuals knowing how to make a compiler generate
code. So they are still the best placed to support those “esoteric”
architectures.</p><p>And if they do not know how to read ISA manuals and generate code, it’s because
they lean too heavily on LLVM.</p></div><p>Make no mistake; embedded software is still running the majority of devices in
the world. And C is the king of embedded software.</p><p>I don’t know exact numbers, but I wouldn’t be surprised if the majority of
programmable devices in the world cannot run Rust.</p><p>Thus, because Rust uses LLVM, it is not portable.</p><p>And in my opinion, Rust is not appropriate for the embedded space.</p><p>So in this case, I would consider that the <code>cryptography</code> developers were
victims of the Rust developers.</p><h3 id="gcc-is-not-the-only-compiler"><code>gcc</code> Is Not the Only Compiler</h3><p>That isn’t the only problem.</p><p>There is a <a href="https://github.com/Rust-GCC/gccrs">project to make <code>gcc</code> able to compile Rust</a>. That’s commendable.</p><p>However, many people seem to believe that once it’s done, Rust will be portable.
That is not the case.</p><p>Why? Simple: <strong><code>gcc</code> is not the only compiler</strong>.</p><p>There is plenty of code out there that uses dead simple C compilers, like
<a href="https://bellard.org/tcc/">tcc</a>, <a href="http://sdcc.sourceforge.net/">sdcc</a>, and others. And often, they have <a href="https://embeddedgurus.com/stack-overflow/2012/06/optimizing-for-the-cpu-compiler/">good reason to do
so</a>.</p><p>Adding a <code>gcc</code> frontend, while it will improve the situation, will not make Rust
as portable as C. Period.</p><h3 id="pushing-for-progress-hinders-it">Pushing for Progress Hinders It</h3><p>The other thing that the <code>cryptography</code> authors claim is that their users who
refuse to adopt Rust are hindering progress.</p><p>That may be true, but it is also true that forcing “progress” on others hinders
<em>true</em> progress.</p><p>By forcing users to either adopt Rust or pin their dependency on <code>cryptography</code>
to the most recent version without it, they are forcing those users to use
stagnant code.</p><p>Isn’t that the very opposite of progress?</p><h2 id="cryptography-at-fault"><code>cryptography</code> at Fault</h2><p>Those reasons lay out why I think the <code>cryptography</code> authors should shoulder the
blame for this situation, and I think I can explain where they went wrong.</p><ol><li>They let ideology come before pragmatic engineering.</li><li>They sold <code>cryptography</code> to users.</li><li>They knew that switching to Rust would break existing users and did it
anyway.</li><li>They either did not do their due diligence for memory safety, or they did
and threw that battle-tested code out.</li></ol><h2 id="portability">Portability</h2><p>To be honest, I used to think that it was better to switch to a better language
than C.</p><p>I had several talks with Linux distro maintainers, as well as a talk with my
father-in-law, that convinced me that C’s portability is still important enough
that it should be used.</p><p>Unless, of course, you <em>explicitly</em> target only certain platforms. But you had
better be prepared to never target others.</p><p>In fact, after talking with the distro maintainers, who have had to build Rust,
I am also convinced that it’s not just about being portable, it’s also about how
<em>easy</em> it is to <em>build</em> software.</p><p>Rust’s bootstrap is <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/nightly/rustc/platform-support.html">complicated</a>, and it is one of the worst things about
it.</p><p>If building software in Rust means building Rust for a <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/nightly/rustc/platform-support.html">Tier 3</a> platform,
you can bet that <a href="https://drewdevault.com/2021/02/09/Rust-move-fast-and-break-things.html">people will stick with C</a>.</p><h3 id="zig">Zig</h3><p>I want to take a moment to talk about Zig.</p><p>Zig might be one of the most promising up-and-coming languages of recent memory.</p><p>But it will ultimately fail to reach its goal.</p><p>You see, Zig is meant to replace C. But …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://gavinhoward.com/2021/02/rust-zig-and-the-futility-of-replacing-c/">https://gavinhoward.com/2021/02/rust-zig-and-the-futility-of-replacing-c/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://gavinhoward.com/2021/02/rust-zig-and-the-futility-of-replacing-c/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26291054</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 06:04:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How fighting games use delay-based and rollback netcode (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 192 | Comments 78 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26289933">thread link</a>) | @Kinrany
<br/>
February 27, 2021 | https://ki.infil.net/w02-netcode.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ki.infil.net/w02-netcode.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
				<div>
					<div id="content">

						<!-- Content -->
					
							<article>

								<div>
								
								<div>
								<p><a href="https://ki.infil.net/words.html">
								<img src="https://ki.infil.net/images/words/header.gif"></a>
								
								</p></div>
								
								
								
								
								<hr>
								
								<div>
								
								<div>
								<p>Netcode</p>
								<p>Explaining how fighting games use delay-based and rollback netcode</p>
								<p>October 16, 2019</p>
								
								
								
								
								</div>
								
								</div>
							
								
								<!-- blog navigation -->
								
								
								

								<div>
								<div><p>
								<em>I would like to thank <a href="https://twitter.com/Krazhier">krazhier</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/TheKeits">Keits</a> for taking hours out of their busy schedules to discuss technical aspects of netcode with me, and <a href="https://twitter.com/Sajam">Sajam</a> for taking time to answer interview questions and being supportive throughout the writing process. I would also like to especially thank <a href="https://twitter.com/MagicMoste">MagicMoste</a> for making all the wonderful videos you see in this article. All their help was offered for free and I am thankful for their friendship.
								</em></p><p><em>

								This article has been <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/10/explaining-how-fighting-games-use-delay-based-and-rollback-netcode/">cross-posted on Ars Technica</a>.
								</em></p><p><em>

								You may also enjoy <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1RI5scXYhK0">watching a video feature</a> on the topics in this article.
								</em>							
								</p></div>
								</div>

								
															
								<!-- Infil -->
								<div><p><img src="https://ki.infil.net/images/words/infil_smiling_2.jpg"></p>
								<p>
								Welcome back to Fightin’ Words! It’s been a while since we last discussed how the <a href="https://ki.infil.net/w01-bugs.html">most famous fighting game bugs</a> have impacted the community’s favorite games. Today’s topic is a bit more technical, but it’s an equally important factor in how our favorite modern games are played -- we’re going to be doing a <strong>deep dive into netcode</strong>.								
								</p>
								</div>

								<hr><!-- Infil -->
								<div><p><img src="https://ki.infil.net/images/words/infil_lecture.jpg"></p>
								<div><p>
								At its core, netcode is simply a method for two or more computers, each trying to play the same game, to talk to each other over the internet. While local play always ensures that all player inputs arrive and are processed at the same time, <strong>networks are constantly unstable</strong> in ways the game cannot control or predict. Information sent to your opponent may be delayed, arrive out of order, or become lost entirely depending on dozens of factors, including the physical distance to your opponent, if you’re on a WiFi connection, and whether your roommate is watching Netflix.
								</p><p>
								Online play in games is nothing new, but fighting games have their own set of unique challenges. They tend to involve direct connections to other players, unlike many other popular game genres, and <strong>low, consistent latency</strong> is extremely important because muscle memory and reactions are at the core of virtually every fighting game. As a result, two prominent strategies have emerged for playing fighting games online: <strong>delay-based netcode</strong> and <strong>rollback netcode</strong>. 
								</p></div>
								</div>

								<div><p><img src="https://ki.infil.net/images/words/infil_thoughtful.jpg"></p>
								<div><p>
								There’s been a renewed passion in the fighting game community that <strong>rollback is the best choice</strong>, and fighting game developers who <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qW61xJNJ9m8">choose to use delay-based netcode</a> are <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iTUtnclr2hs">preventing the growth of the genre</a>. While people have been passionate about this topic <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Tu2kAdmUCaI&amp;t=42m34s">for many years</a>, frustrations continue to rise as new, otherwise excellent games repeatedly have bad online experiences.
								</p><p>

								There are relatively few easy-to-follow explanations for what exactly rollback netcode is, how it works, and why it is so good at hiding the effects of bad connections (though <a href="http://mauve.mizuumi.net/2012/07/05/understanding-fighting-game-networking.html">there are some</a>). Because I feel this topic is extremely important for the future health of the fighting game community, I want to help squash some misconceptions about netcode and explain both netcode strategies thoroughly so everyone can be informed as they discuss. If you stick around to the end, I’ll even <strong>interview some industry experts and community leaders</strong> on the topic!
								</p><p>
								Before we dig into the details, though, let’s get one thing straight.
										
								</p></div>
								</div>

								<hr><!-- Infil -->
								<!-- header -->
								

								<div><p><img src="https://ki.infil.net/images/words/infil_smiling_3.jpg"></p>
								<div><p>
										Both companies and players should care about good netcode because <strong>playing online is no longer the future -- it's the present</strong>. 
								</p><p>
										While most other video game genres have been this way for a decade or longer, fighting game developers seem to be resistant to embracing online play, perhaps because of the genre’s roots in offline settings such as arcades and tournaments. Playing offline is great, and it will always have considerable value in fighting games, but it’s simply a reality that <strong>a large percentage of the player base will never play offline</strong>. For many fighting game fans, playing online <em>is</em> the game, and a bad online experience prevents them from getting better, playing or recommending the game to their friends, and ultimately causes them to <a href="https://youtu.be/iTUtnclr2hs?t=758">simply go do something else</a>.
								</p><p>
										Even if you think you have a good connection, or live in an area of the world with robust internet infrastructure, good netcode is still mandatory. Plus, lost or delayed information happens regularly even on the best networks, and poor netcode can <a href="https://twitter.com/john_takeuchi/status/1162562266027327488">actively hamper matches</a> no matter how smooth the conditions may be. Good netcode also has the benefit of connecting regions across greater distances, effectively uniting the global player base as much as possible.

										<!-- gif 1A -->
										</p><div><!-- image -->
											<figure>
												
											<figcaption>Bad netcode can ruin matches. This match, played online between two Japanese players, impacted who gets to attend the Capcom Pro Tour finals. <a href="https://twitter.com/john_takeuchi/status/1162562266027327488">(source)</a>
											</figcaption></figure></div>
										
								</div>
								</div>

								<div><p><img src="https://ki.infil.net/images/words/infil_content.jpg"></p>
								<div><p>
										What about those who never play online because they much prefer playing offline with their friends? The <strong>healthy ecosystem</strong> that good netcode creates around a game benefits everyone. There will be more active players, more chances to consume content for your favorite game -- from tech videos to spectating online tournaments to expanding the strategy of lesser-used characters -- and more excitement surrounding your game in the FGC. Despite <a href="http://ki.infil.net/">Killer Instinct</a>’s pedigree as an excellent game, there’s no doubt that its superb rollback netcode has played a huge part in the sustained growth of its community.
								</p><p>

										Good netcode matters, period. So let’s talk about it.
										
								</p></div>
								</div>
								
								
								<!-- blog navigation -->
								
								
								

								</div>
								
							</article>
				
					</div>
				</div>
			</section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ki.infil.net/w02-netcode.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26289933</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 01:47:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[First vaccine to immunize against malaria builds on pandemic-driven RNA tech]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 35 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26289245">thread link</a>) | @cpncrunch
<br/>
February 27, 2021 | https://academictimes.com/first-vaccine-to-fully-immunize-against-malaria-builds-on-pandemic-driven-rna-tech/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://academictimes.com/first-vaccine-to-fully-immunize-against-malaria-builds-on-pandemic-driven-rna-tech/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div id="articleBody"><p>Consistently ranked as one of the leading causes of death around the world, malaria doesnâ€™t have an effective vaccine yet. But researchers have invented a promising new blueprint for one â€” with properties akin to the novel RNA-based vaccine for COVID-19.</p><p>Making a vaccine for malaria is challenging because its associated parasite, <a href="https://www.britannica.com/science/Plasmodium-protozoan-genus"><em>Plasmodium</em></a><em>,</em> contains a protein that inhibits production of <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/biochemistry-genetics-and-molecular-biology/memory-t-cell">memory T-cells</a>, which protect against previously encountered pathogens. If the body canâ€™t generate these cells, a vaccine is ineffective. But scientists recently tried a new approach using an RNA-based platform.Â&nbsp;</p><p>Their design circumvented the sneaky protein, allowed the body to produce the needed T-cells and completely immunized against malaria. The patent application for their novel vaccine, which hasn't yet been tested on humans, was <a href="http://appft1.uspto.gov/netacgi/nph-Parser?Sect1=PTO1&amp;Sect2=HITOFF&amp;d=PG01&amp;p=1&amp;u=/netahtml/PTO/srchnum.html&amp;r=1&amp;f=G&amp;l=50&amp;s1=20210030859.PGNR.&amp;OS=DN/20210030859&amp;RS=DN/20210030859">published</a> by the U.S. Patent &amp; Trademark Office on Feb. 4.</p><p>â€œIt's probably the highest level of protection that has been seen in a mouse model,â€� said Richard Bucala, co-inventor of the new vaccine and a physician and professor at Yale School of Medicine.</p><p>The teamâ€™s breakthrough could save hundreds of thousands of lives, particularly in developing nations. <a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/malaria">In 2019 alone</a>, there were an estimated 229 million cases of malaria and 409,000 deaths worldwide. Of those deaths, 94% were in Africa, with children being the most vulnerable.</p><p>â€œIt affects societies and populations that have the least amount of resources and expertise to manage these infections well," Bucala told <em>The Academic Times</em>. "We need new vaccines, and we need more tools."</p><p>Novartis Pharmaceuticals and the National Institutes of Health funded the work. GlaxoSmithKline is an assignee on the patent, which if approved, will allow the company to produce the vaccine and make it available to the public.</p><p>At present, the only vaccine to prevent malaria is called <a href="https://www.malariavaccine.org/sites/www.malariavaccine.org/files/content/page/files/PATH_MVI_RTSS_Fact%20sheet_042019.pdf">RTS,S</a>. Approved two years ago, this vaccine is the result of nearly two decades of research, but is only about 30% effective. And after four years, that figure drops to 15%.</p><p>â€œIt doesn't work very well,â€� Bucala said. â€œAnd the research studies all have the conclusion that the people who fail to mount a vaccine response, or who get reinfected, have poor memory T-cell responses.â€�</p><p>Along with Andrew Geall, a pharmaceutical researcher who developed the RNA platform that the duo used, Bucala found a way to prevent the unwanted protein in <em>Plasmodium</em>, called <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17158894/">PMIF</a>, from inhibiting T-cell generation.Â&nbsp;</p><p>â€œOur research studies indicate that it was this particular gene product, PMIF, that was responsible for this,â€� Bucala said. â€œIt prevented memory T-cells from forming, and that's why one could not generate a memory response to <em>Plasmodium</em>.â€�</p><p>In a conventional vaccine, for instance the <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/flu/prevent/keyfacts.htm">standard flu vaccine</a>, an inactivated version of the virus is injected into a host. The body recognizes an intruder, fights against it, generates antibodies against the harmless virus, then returns back to normal.Â&nbsp;</p><p>However, once the virus has left the host, the body needs a way to remember how it fought back. Otherwise it will have to relearn the antibody generation â€” but perhaps next time with the actual, harmful virus infecting the host all the while. This is where memory T-cells come in: They remember how to generate the immune response and remind the body when the time comes. <em>PlasmodiumÂ&nbsp;</em>prevents the immune memory system from occurring by producing PMIF.</p><p>â€œSuppressing the T-cell response and immune memory is so important to the parasite that the parasite brings its own gene, PMIF, to do that,â€� Bucala said. â€œIf you eliminate that factor, the body naturally develops memory immunity.â€�</p><p>The concept of the novel malaria vaccine accounts for the PMIF problem. Instead of injecting the actual pathogen, the vaccine presents the body with instructions, via RNA, on how to create the protein unique to the pathogen by itself in order to fight it â€” which is precisely how Pfizerâ€™s COVID-19 vaccine works.</p><p>However, rather than an <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/vaccines/different-vaccines/mrna.html">mRNA platform</a>, Bucala and Geall use a self-amplifying <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7474593/">saRNA</a> platform. The key benefit of the latter is that it is effective at much lower doses because it can rapidly produce copies of itself inside the cell.Â&nbsp;</p><p>â€œFor saRNA, one can potentially make a million doses of vaccine with a couple liters of synthetic production,â€� Bucala said. â€œIt's much more efficient than the base-protected mRNA vaccines.â€�</p><p>The proposed saRNA vaccine tells the body to create the troublesome PMIF protein, generates antibodies against it and naturally produces the necessary memory T-cells, as Bucala had hoped.</p><p>â€œWe thought we could combine RTS,S with a PMIF vaccine, but the mouse studies seem to suggest that just immunizing with PMIF is sufficient,â€� Bucala highlighted.Â&nbsp;â€œThat's how striking the results were.â€�</p><p>Bucala and Geall have placed their vaccine in the hands of the Oxford University institution that facilitated the <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/health-55302595">AstraZeneca</a> COVID-19 vaccine. It is one of the only places in the world that is doing phase 1 studies in malaria, meaning researchers infect human volunteers with the disease after immunizing them.</p><p>â€œThis is not in humans yet," Bucala noted, â€œbut they are the group that can put it into humans, I think, best. We are doing those studies this year."</p><p>Beyond the saRNA technology's use for the malaria vaccine, Bucala believes it is an ideal method for immunization design in the future, including for COVID-19 prevention, because of its dual low cost and high yield. He says it could reach far and wide.Â&nbsp;</p><p>â€œThe current mRNA approach is an important step in that direction,â€� he said. â€œBut we are going to, I believe, need to do better. I hope that the saRNA opens that platform.â€�</p><p><em>The application for the patent, Uses Of Parasite Macrophage Migration Inhibitory Factors, was filed on Oct. 16, 2020 to the U.S. Patent Trademark Office with the application number 17/073006. The inventors of the pending patent are Richard Bucala, Yale School of Medicine and Andrew Geall, Novartis Pharmaceuticals. The assignees are Yale University and GlaxoSmithKline Biologicals SA.</em></p><p><em>Parola Analytics provided technical research for this story.</em></p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://academictimes.com/first-vaccine-to-fully-immunize-against-malaria-builds-on-pandemic-driven-rna-tech/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26289245</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 23:44:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Translating My Z3 Tutorial to Coq]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 85 | Comments 15 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26288749">thread link</a>) | @philzook
<br/>
February 27, 2021 | https://www.philipzucker.com/translating-z3-to-coq/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.philipzucker.com/translating-z3-to-coq/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    









<p>I had a fun time giving a Z3 tutorial at Formal Methods for the Informal Engineer (FMIE) <a href="https://fmie2021.github.io/">https://fmie2021.github.io/</a> (videos coming soon hopefully!). I got to be kind of the "fun dad" with the Z3 tutorial <a href="https://github.com/philzook58/z3_tutorial">https://github.com/philzook58/z3_tutorial</a> , while at times it felt a bit like Cody's Coq tutorial <a href="https://github.com/codyroux/broad-coq-tutorial">https://github.com/codyroux/broad-coq-tutorial</a> was trying to feed the kids their vegetables. It was a fantastic tutorial (maybe the best I've seen?), but it was tough love. He knew it was going to be like this from the outset and had a fun little analogy of me downhill skiing while he was about to go on an uphill mountaineering slog.</p>
<p>There are a number of factors to lead to this:</p>
<ul>
  <li>I could use Z3’s python bindings giving an air of familiarity, whereas everything was incredibly foreign in Coq.</li>
  <li>Z3 can actually be used to declaratively state problems and pushbutton calculate solutions to them with very little user help, which gives it a lot more "Wow" factor.</li>
  <li>Coq is a tool that requires significantly more background to even comprehend what the hell it is. I still think many aspects of it are totally bizarre. But Coq users, this is just the water they swim in. For example, defining an inductive predicate as a datatype is still a bizarre notion to me, but it is Coq 101. I say this to Coq users and they look at me like I’m nuts. “What could even be the problem?”</li>
</ul>
<p>Anyway, a fun exercise for me was to take the examples from my tutorial and try to translate them into Coq. For the most part I think it isn't that hard and rather educational.</p>
<p>It's interesting the things that show up. Because the Z3 tutorial was designed for automation, the more automated tactics in MicroOmega and Ring are super useful. </p>
<p><a href="https://coq.inria.fr/refman/addendum/micromega.html">https://coq.inria.fr/refman/addendum/micromega.html</a></p>
<p>
The thing is that the sort of proofs that show up here are fine and all, but they aren't going to teach you to fish for yourself. When you step out of this super automatable fragment you're sunk if you don't know other techniques, like the ones Cody was teaching. There may be a better balance of fun and education to be found.</p>
<p>I think there is a hole in the educational content out there on Coq. Software Foundations focuses on the rudiments, CPDT and FRAP kind of takes it a little hardcore, and the Mathematical Components stuff makes you buy in on ssreflect style and some hardcore math topics, both of which are nuts I have not cracked. Also, all of them are really long and initimidating. Seems like there should be something a little more breezy, a little more automatic. It is demoralizing as a beginner to either not know how to prove obvious trivial facts, or even to struggle to do so at great length.</p>
<p>This was also a nice opportunity to take Alectryon by Clément Pit-Claudel out for a spin <a href="https://github.com/cpitclaudel/alectryon">https://github.com/cpitclaudel/alectryon</a> Alectryon allows you to see the proof state on hover over in your browser. It's a super important part of the Coq. It was pretty easy to put in my blog. Just copy and paste the gnarly html output into a Jekyll post and make sure to link in the CSS files in an assets folder, because they are where the magic happens.</p>
<p>The gist for this post is here <a href="https://gist.github.com/philzook58/acd204b4895c41f9e85618f0f6b30a58">https://gist.github.com/philzook58/acd204b4895c41f9e85618f0f6b30a58</a></p>
<div id="intro-stuff">

<p>The very first problem in the tutorial was</p>
<pre><!-- Generator: Alectryon --><span><span><span>(** python</span>
<span>x = Int('x')</span>
<span>y = Int('y')</span>
<span>solve(x &gt; 2, y &lt; 10, x + 2*y == 7)</span>
<span>*)</span></span></span></pre><p>which Z3 returns the solution [y = 0, x = 7].</p>
<p>It isn't so obvious how to get coq to find this solution in a low effort way. However, it is easy to get Coq to confirm the validity of this solution given that you know about the [lia] tactic. Otherwise it may be kind of annoying. In general, it may be a good approach to use external tools to produce solutions and just manually place the solutions into Coq. Validating a solution is often easier than producing it.</p>
<pre><!-- Generator: Alectryon --><span><span><span><span>Require Import</span> Lia.</span></span><span>
</span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk0"><span><span>Goal</span> <span>exists</span> <span>x</span> <span>y</span>, x &gt; <span>2</span> /\ y &lt; <span>10</span> /\ x + <span>2</span> * y = <span>7</span>.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><span><hr></span><p><span><span>exists</span> <span>x</span> <span>y</span> : nat, x &gt; <span>2</span> /\ y &lt; <span>10</span> /\ x + <span>2</span> * y = <span>7</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span>
</span></span><span>     </span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk1"><span><span>exists</span> <span>7</span>, <span>0</span>.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><span><hr></span><p><span><span>7</span> &gt; <span>2</span> /\ <span>0</span> &lt; <span>10</span> /\ <span>7</span> + <span>2</span> * <span>0</span> = <span>7</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span> </span></span><span><span><span><span>lia</span>.</span></span><span> </span></span><span><span><span><span>Qed</span>.</span></span></span></pre><p>A different automated version. Giving the appropriate hint database can matter a lot.
<a href="https://coq.inria.fr/refman/proofs/automatic-tactics/auto.html#hint-databases-defined-in-the-coq-standard-library">https://coq.inria.fr/refman/proofs/automatic-tactics/auto.html#hint-databases-defined-in-the-coq-standard-library</a></p>
<pre><!-- Generator: Alectryon --><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk2"><span><span>Goal</span> <span>exists</span> <span>x</span> <span>y</span>, x &gt; <span>2</span> /\ y &lt; <span>10</span> /\ x + <span>2</span> * y = <span>7</span>.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><span><hr></span><p><span><span>exists</span> <span>x</span> <span>y</span> : nat, x &gt; <span>2</span> /\ y &lt; <span>10</span> /\ x + <span>2</span> * y = <span>7</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span>
</span></span><span>     </span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk3"><span><span>exists</span> <span>7</span>, <span>0</span>.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><span><hr></span><p><span><span>7</span> &gt; <span>2</span> /\ <span>0</span> &lt; <span>10</span> /\ <span>7</span> + <span>2</span> * <span>0</span> = <span>7</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span> </span></span><span><span><span><span>eauto with</span> arith.</span></span><span> </span></span><span><span><span><span>Qed</span>.</span></span></span></pre><p>It turns out, surprisingly to me, that stock eauto is sufficient to actually solve the problem without supplying the solutions. They are discovered via unification and a prolog like search. This found the different solution x = 3, y = 2</p>
<pre><!-- Generator: Alectryon --><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk4"><span><span>Definition</span> <span>solution</span> : <span>exists</span> <span>x</span> <span>y</span>, x &gt; <span>2</span> /\ y &lt; <span>10</span> /\ x + <span>2</span> * y = <span>7</span>.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><span><hr></span><p><span><span>exists</span> <span>x</span> <span>y</span> : nat, x &gt; <span>2</span> /\ y &lt; <span>10</span> /\ x + <span>2</span> * y = <span>7</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span>
</span></span><span>   </span><span><span><span><span>do</span> <span>2</span> <span>eexists</span>.</span></span><span> </span></span><span><span><span><span>eauto with</span> arith.</span></span><span> </span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk5"><span><span>Show Proof</span>.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><span>(ex_intro
   (<span>fun</span> <span>x</span> : nat =&gt;
    <span>exists</span> <span>y</span> : nat, x &gt; <span>2</span> /\ y &lt; <span>10</span> /\ x + <span>2</span> * y = <span>7</span>)
   <span>3</span>
   (ex_intro
      (<span>fun</span> <span>y</span> : nat =&gt; <span>3</span> &gt; <span>2</span> /\ y &lt; <span>10</span> /\ <span>3</span> + <span>2</span> * y = <span>7</span>)
      <span>2</span>
      (conj (Gt.gt_Sn_n <span>2</span>)
         (conj
            (Lt.lt_n_S <span>1</span> <span>9</span>
               (Lt.lt_n_S <span>0</span> <span>8</span>
                  (PeanoNat.Nat.lt_0_succ <span>7</span>))) eq_refl))))</span></blockquote></div></div></small><span> </span></span><span><span><span><span>Defined</span>.</span></span><span>
</span></span><span><span>

<span>(* A fairly manual version for comparison. Could be even worse. *)</span>
</span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk6"><span><span>Goal</span> <span>exists</span> <span>x</span> <span>y</span>, x &gt; <span>2</span> /\ y &lt; <span>10</span> /\ x + <span>2</span> * y = <span>7</span>.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><span><hr></span><p><span><span>exists</span> <span>x</span> <span>y</span> : nat, x &gt; <span>2</span> /\ y &lt; <span>10</span> /\ x + <span>2</span> * y = <span>7</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span>
</span></span><span>   </span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk7"><span><span>exists</span> <span>7</span>, <span>0</span>.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><span><hr></span><p><span><span>7</span> &gt; <span>2</span> /\ <span>0</span> &lt; <span>10</span> /\ <span>7</span> + <span>2</span> * <span>0</span> = <span>7</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span> </span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk8"><span><span>split</span>.</span></label><small></small><span> 
</span></span><span>     </span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chka"><span>-</span></label><small></small><span> </span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chkb"><span><span>unfold</span> <span>"&gt;"</span>.</span></label><small></small><span> </span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chkc"><span><span>Locate</span> <span>"&lt;"</span>.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><span><span>Notation</span>
<span>"x &lt;= y &lt; z"</span> := <span>and</span> (le x y) (lt y z) : nat_scope
(default interpretation)
<span>"x &lt; y &lt;= z"</span> := <span>and</span> (lt x y) (le y z) : nat_scope
(default interpretation)
<span>"x &lt; y &lt; z"</span> := <span>and</span> (lt x y) (lt y z) : nat_scope
(default interpretation)
<span>"x &lt; y"</span> := lt x y : nat_scope (default interpretation)</span></blockquote></div></div></small><span> </span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chkd"><span><span>unfold</span> <span>"&lt;"</span>.</span></label><small></small><span> </span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chke"><span><span>Print</span> le.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><span><span>Inductive</span> <span>le</span> (<span>n</span> : nat) : nat -&gt; <span>Prop</span> :=
    le_n : n &lt;= n
  | le_S : <span>forall</span> <span>m</span> : nat, n &lt;= m -&gt; n &lt;= S m

<span>Arguments</span> le (_ _)%nat_scope
<span>Arguments</span> le_n _%nat_scope
<span>Arguments</span> le_S (_ _)%nat_scope</span></blockquote></div></div></small><span> </span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chkf"><span><span>do</span> <span>4</span> <span>apply</span> 
              le_S.</span></label><small></small><span> </span></span><span><span><span><span>apply</span> le_n.</span></span><span>
</span></span><span>     </span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk10"><span>-</span></label><small></small><span> </span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk11"><span><span>split</span>.</span></label><small></small><span>
</span></span><span>       </span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk13"><span>+</span></label><small></small><span> </span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk14"><span><span>do</span> <span>9</span> <span>apply</span> le_S.</span></label><small></small><span> </span></span><span><span><span><span>apply</span> le_n.</span></span><span>
</span></span><span>       </span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk15"><span>+</span></label><small></small><span> </span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk16"><span><span>simpl</span>.</span></label><small></small><span> </span></span><span><span><span><span>reflexivity</span>.</span></span><span>
</span></span><span><span><span><span>Qed</span>.</span></span><span> </span></span></pre><p>The next thing is the simplest possible tautology</p>
<pre><!-- Generator: Alectryon --><span><span><span>(**python</span>
<span>p = Bool("p")</span>
<span>my_true_thm = Implies(p, p)</span>
<span>prove(my_true_thm)</span>
<span>*)</span></span></span></pre><p>This is not a challenge in Coq.</p>
<pre><!-- Generator: Alectryon --><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk17"><span><span>Goal</span> <span>forall</span> <span>P</span>, P -&gt; P.</span></label><small></small><span> </span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk18"><span><span>intros</span>.</span></label><small></small><span> </span></span><span><span><span><span>assumption</span>.</span></span><span> </span></span><span><span><span><span>Qed</span>.</span></span><span>
</span></span><span><span>
<span>(* Even shorter proof *)</span>
</span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk19"><span><span>Goal</span> <span>forall</span> <span>P</span>, P -&gt; P.</span></label><small></small><span> </span></span><span><span><span><span>auto</span>.</span></span><span> </span></span><span><span><span><span>Qed</span>.</span></span></span></pre><p>A valid counterexample found by Z3. Here we prove the counterexample.</p>
<pre><!-- Generator: Alectryon --><span><span><span>(**python</span>
<span>q = Bool("q")</span>
<span>my_false_thm = Implies(q, p)</span>
<span>prove(my_false_thm)</span>

<span># counterexample</span>
<span># [p = False, q = True]</span>

<span>*)</span>

</span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk1a"><span><span>Goal</span> not (<span>True</span> -&gt; <span>False</span>).</span></label><small></small><span> </span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk1b"><span><span>unfold</span> not.</span></label><small></small><span> </span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk1c"><span><span>intros</span>.</span></label><small></small><span> </span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk1d"><span><span>apply</span> H.</span></label><small></small><span> </span></span><span><span><span><span>exact</span> I.</span></span><span> </span></span><span><span><span><span>Qed</span>.</span></span></span></pre><p>The first exercise: 
Get a root of the polynomial x**3 + 3*x**2 + 4*x + 2 == 0 using z3. Can you use z3 to show this is the only solution?</p>
<p>Here we open up the reals.
It is easy enough to confirm that the solution of x=-1 is a zero using the [ring] tactic.</p>
<pre><!-- Generator: Alectryon --><span><span><span><span>Require Import</span> Reals.</span></span><span>
</span></span><span><span><span><span>Open Scope</span> R_scope.</span></span><span>
</span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk1e"><span><span>Print Scope</span> R_scope.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><span>Scope R_scope
Delimiting key <span>is</span> R
Bound to class R
<span>"r ²"</span> := Rsqr r
<span>"x ^ y"</span> := pow x y
<span>"x &gt;= y"</span> := Rge x y
<span>"x &gt; y"</span> := Rgt x y
<span>"x &lt;= y &lt;= z"</span> := <span>and</span> (Rle x y) (Rle y z)
<span>"x &lt;= y &lt; z"</span> := <span>and</span> (Rle x y) (Rlt y z)
<span>"x &lt;= y"</span> := Rle x y
<span>"x &lt; y &lt;= z"</span> := <span>and</span> (Rlt x y) (Rle y z)
<span>"x &lt; y &lt; z"</span> := <span>and</span> (Rlt x y) (Rlt y z)
<span>"x &lt; y"</span> := Rlt x y
<span>"x / y"</span> := Rdiv x y
<span>"x - y"</span> := Rminus x y
<span>"x + y"</span> := Rplus x y
<span>"x * y"</span> := Rmult x y
<span>"/ x"</span> := RinvImpl.Rinv x
<span>"- x"</span> := Ropp x
</span></blockquote></div></div></small><span>
</span></span><span><span>
</span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk1f"><span><span>Goal</span> <span>exists</span> <span>x</span> : R, x^<span>3</span> + <span>3</span> * x^<span>2</span> + <span>4</span> * x + <span>2</span> = <span>0</span>.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><span><hr></span><p><span><span>exists</span> <span>x</span> : R, x ^ <span>3</span> + <span>3</span> * x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>4</span> * x + <span>2</span> = <span>0</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span>
</span></span><span>  </span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk20"><span><span>exists</span> (- <span>1</span>).</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><span><hr></span><p><span>(-<span>1</span>) ^ <span>3</span> + <span>3</span> * (-<span>1</span>) ^ <span>2</span> + <span>4</span> * -<span>1</span> + <span>2</span> = <span>0</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span> </span></span><span><span><span><span>ring</span>.</span></span><span> </span></span><span><span><span><span>Qed</span>.</span></span></span></pre><p>Proving there is no other solution is a bit trickier. A important lemma about a polynomial factor of x^3 + 3 * x^2 + 4 * x + 2</p>
<pre><!-- Generator: Alectryon --><span><span><span><span>Require Import</span> Lra.</span></span><span>
</span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk21"><span><span>Lemma</span> <span>pos_poly</span> : <span>forall</span> <span>x</span>, x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span> &gt; <span>0</span>.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><span><hr></span><p><span><span>forall</span> <span>x</span> : R, x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span> &gt; <span>0</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span> </span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk22"><span><span>intros</span>.</span></label><small></small><span>
</span></span><span>   </span><span><span><span><span>nra</span>.</span></span><span> </span></span><span><span><span><span>Qed</span>.</span></span><span>
</span></span><span><span>
<span>(* A slightly more manual proof involving completing the square.*)</span>
</span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk23"><span><span>Goal</span> <span>forall</span> <span>x</span>, x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span> &gt; <span>0</span>.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><span><hr></span><p><span><span>forall</span> <span>x</span> : R, x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span> &gt; <span>0</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span> 
</span></span><span>   </span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk24"><span><span>intros</span>.</span></label><small></small><span>
</span></span><span>   </span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk25"><span><span>assert</span> (x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span> = (x + <span>1</span>) ^ <span>2</span> + <span>1</span>) <span>as</span> H <span>by</span> <span>ring</span>.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><div><p><span>x</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>R</span></span></span></span></p><p><span>H</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span> = (x + <span>1</span>) ^ <span>2</span> + <span>1</span></span></span></span></span></p></div><span><hr></span><p><span>x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span> &gt; <span>0</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span>
</span></span><span>   </span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk26"><span><span>rewrite</span> H.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><div><p><span>x</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>R</span></span></span></span></p><p><span>H</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span> = (x + <span>1</span>) ^ <span>2</span> + <span>1</span></span></span></span></span></p></div><span><hr></span><p><span>(x + <span>1</span>) ^ <span>2</span> + <span>1</span> &gt; <span>0</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span> </span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk27"><span><span>Search</span> (<span>0</span> &lt;= _ ^ <span>2</span>).</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><span>pow2_ge_0: <span>forall</span> <span>x</span> : R, <span>0</span> &lt;= x ^ <span>2</span></span></blockquote></div><div><blockquote><div><p><span>x</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>R</span></span></span></span></p><p><span>H</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span> = (x + <span>1</span>) ^ <span>2</span> + <span>1</span></span></span></span></span></p></div><span><hr></span><p><span>(x + <span>1</span>) ^ <span>2</span> + <span>1</span> &gt; <span>0</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span>
</span></span><span>   </span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk28"><span><span>pose</span> (pow2_ge_0 (x + <span>1</span>)).</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><div><p><span>x</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>R</span></span></span></span></p><p><span>H</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span> = (x + <span>1</span>) ^ <span>2</span> + <span>1</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span>r</span><span><span><span>:=</span><span><span>pow2_ge_0 (x + <span>1</span>)</span></span></span><span><span>:</span><span><span><span>0</span> &lt;= (x + <span>1</span>) ^ <span>2</span></span></span></span></span></p></div><span><hr></span><p><span>(x + <span>1</span>) ^ <span>2</span> + <span>1</span> &gt; <span>0</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span>
</span></span><span>   </span><span><span><span><span>lra</span>.</span></span><span> </span></span><span><span><span><span>Qed</span>.</span></span><span>
</span></span><span><span>


<span>(* I'm actually a little suprised [nra] sufficed here and not psatz. *)</span>

</span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk29"><span><span>Goal</span> <span>forall</span> <span>x</span>, x + <span>1</span> &lt;&gt; <span>0</span> -&gt; (x^<span>3</span> + <span>3</span> * x^<span>2</span> + <span>4</span> * x + <span>2</span>) &lt;&gt; <span>0</span>.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><span><hr></span><p><span><span>forall</span> <span>x</span> : R,
x + <span>1</span> &lt;&gt; <span>0</span> -&gt; x ^ <span>3</span> + <span>3</span> * x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>4</span> * x + <span>2</span> &lt;&gt; <span>0</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span>
</span></span><span>  </span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk2a"><span><span>intros</span>.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><span><hr></span><p><span>x ^ <span>3</span> + <span>3</span> * x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>4</span> * x + <span>2</span> &lt;&gt; <span>0</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span>
</span></span><span>  </span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk2b"><span><span>assert</span> ((x^<span>3</span> + <span>3</span> * x^<span>2</span> + <span>4</span> * x + <span>2</span>) = 
         ((x + <span>1</span>) * (x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span> ))) <span>as</span> H0 <span>by</span> <span>ring</span>.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><div><p><span>x</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>R</span></span></span></span></p><p><span>H</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>x + <span>1</span> &lt;&gt; <span>0</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span>H0</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>x ^ <span>3</span> + <span>3</span> * x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>4</span> * x + <span>2</span> =
(x + <span>1</span>) * (x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span>)</span></span></span></span></p></div><span><hr></span><p><span>x ^ <span>3</span> + <span>3</span> * x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>4</span> * x + <span>2</span> &lt;&gt; <span>0</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span>
</span></span><span>  </span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk2c"><span><span>rewrite</span> H0.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><div><p><span>x</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>R</span></span></span></span></p><p><span>H</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>x + <span>1</span> &lt;&gt; <span>0</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span>H0</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>x ^ <span>3</span> + <span>3</span> * x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>4</span> * x + <span>2</span> =
(x + <span>1</span>) * (x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span>)</span></span></span></span></p></div><span><hr></span><p><span>(x + <span>1</span>) * (x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span>) &lt;&gt; <span>0</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span> </span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk2d"><span><span>pose</span> (pos_poly x).</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><div><p><span>x</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>R</span></span></span></span></p><p><span>H</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>x + <span>1</span> &lt;&gt; <span>0</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span>H0</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>x ^ <span>3</span> + <span>3</span> * x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>4</span> * x + <span>2</span> =
(x + <span>1</span>) * (x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span>)</span></span></span></span></p><p><span>r</span><span><span><span>:=</span><span><span>pos_poly x</span></span></span><span><span>:</span><span><span>x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span> &gt; <span>0</span></span></span></span></span></p></div><span><hr></span><p><span>(x + <span>1</span>) * (x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span>) &lt;&gt; <span>0</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span> </span></span><span><span><span><span>nra</span>.</span></span><span> </span></span><span><span><span><span>Qed</span>.</span></span><span>
</span></span><span><span>
<span>(* A slightly more manual proof *)</span>
</span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk2e"><span><span>Goal</span> <span>forall</span> <span>x</span>, x + <span>1</span> &lt;&gt; <span>0</span> -&gt; (x^<span>3</span> + <span>3</span> * x^<span>2</span> + <span>4</span> * x + <span>2</span>) &lt;&gt; <span>0</span>.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><span><hr></span><p><span><span>forall</span> <span>x</span> : R,
x + <span>1</span> &lt;&gt; <span>0</span> -&gt; x ^ <span>3</span> + <span>3</span> * x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>4</span> * x + <span>2</span> &lt;&gt; <span>0</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span>
</span></span><span>  </span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk2f"><span><span>intros</span>.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><span><hr></span><p><span>x ^ <span>3</span> + <span>3</span> * x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>4</span> * x + <span>2</span> &lt;&gt; <span>0</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span>
</span></span><span>  </span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk30"><span><span>assert</span> ((x^<span>3</span> + <span>3</span> * x^<span>2</span> + <span>4</span> * x + <span>2</span>) = 
         ((x + <span>1</span>) * (x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span> ))) <span>by</span> <span>ring</span>.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><div><p><span>x</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>R</span></span></span></span></p><p><span>H</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>x + <span>1</span> &lt;&gt; <span>0</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span>H0</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>x ^ <span>3</span> + <span>3</span> * x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>4</span> * x + <span>2</span> =
(x + <span>1</span>) * (x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span>)</span></span></span></span></p></div><span><hr></span><p><span>x ^ <span>3</span> + <span>3</span> * x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>4</span> * x + <span>2</span> &lt;&gt; <span>0</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span>
</span></span><span>  </span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk31"><span><span>rewrite</span> H0.</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><div><p><span>x</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>R</span></span></span></span></p><p><span>H</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>x + <span>1</span> &lt;&gt; <span>0</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span>H0</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>x ^ <span>3</span> + <span>3</span> * x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>4</span> * x + <span>2</span> =
(x + <span>1</span>) * (x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span>)</span></span></span></span></p></div><span><hr></span><p><span>(x + <span>1</span>) * (x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span>) &lt;&gt; <span>0</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span> </span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk32"><span><span>pose</span> (pos_poly x).</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><div><p><span>x</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>R</span></span></span></span></p><p><span>H</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>x + <span>1</span> &lt;&gt; <span>0</span></span></span></span></span></p><p><span>H0</span><span><span><span>:</span><span><span>x ^ <span>3</span> + <span>3</span> * x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>4</span> * x + <span>2</span> =
(x + <span>1</span>) * (x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span>)</span></span></span></span></p><p><span>r</span><span><span><span>:=</span><span><span>pos_poly x</span></span></span><span><span>:</span><span><span>x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span> &gt; <span>0</span></span></span></span></span></p></div><span><hr></span><p><span>(x + <span>1</span>) * (x ^ <span>2</span> + <span>2</span> * x + <span>2</span>) &lt;&gt; <span>0</span></span></p></blockquote></div></div></small><span> </span></span><span><label for="z3-tut-v-chk33"><span><span>Search</span> (_ * _ = <span>0</span>).</span></label><small><div><div><blockquote><span>Rmult_0_l: <span>forall</span> <span>r</span> : R, <span>0</span> * r = <span>0</span></span></blockquote><blockquote><span>Rmult_0_r: <span>forall</span> <span>r</span> : R, r * <span>0</span> = <span>0</span></span></blockquote><blockquote><span>Rmult_eq_0_compat_l:
  <span>forall</span> <span>r1</span> <span>r2</span> : R, r2 = <span>0</span> -&gt; r1 * r2 = <span>0</span></span></blockquote><blockquote><span>Rmult_eq_0_compat_r:
  <span>forall</span> <span>r1</span> <span>r2</span> : R, r1 = <span>0</span> -&gt; r1 * …</span></blockquote></div></div></small></span></pre></div></div></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.philipzucker.com/translating-z3-to-coq/">https://www.philipzucker.com/translating-z3-to-coq/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.philipzucker.com/translating-z3-to-coq/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26288749</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 22:27:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Rich Text Math Editing on the Web with Markdown and AsciiMath]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 39 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26287948">thread link</a>) | @abhinav22
<br/>
February 27, 2021 | https://writer.math.dev/landing.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://writer.math.dev/landing.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

<p><a href="https://writer.math.dev/">https://writer.math.dev</a></p>
<p>Welcome to Math Writer and thank you for visiting this page. Math Writer is a rich text web editor for math, utilising the power of MathJax and the featureful TinyMCE text editor. It allows you to enter markdown and math together and aims to be a convenient way to write digital math, particularly for your own websites, with pdf and html export options. It will always be free to use and I welcome suggestions, pull requests and bug reports.</p>
<h2>The Power of MathJax</h2>
<p>All math is entered and rendered in accordance with <a href="https://www.mathjax.org/">MathJax</a>, the popular math rendering engine for the web. This means you can enter math either as AsciiMath or LaTex, however I prefer the former for most cases as it reads better in raw form (ultimately it is a personal preference). In addition, a set of handy keyboard shortcuts are included in this editor to aide with commonly used mathematical symbols.</p>
<h2>The Power of TinyMCE</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.tiny.cloud/">TinyMCE</a> is, by their own admission, the world's most customizable and flexible rich text editor. It provides powerful WYSIWYG functionality and ease of use. By combining TinyMCE with the power of MathJax, I was able to build (what I hope is) a high quality math editor.</p>
<h2>Markdown Works!</h2>
<p>Basic markdown commands like headers (#, ##, ...), italics (*), bold (**) and lists (*, -, 1., a., etc.) work in this editor. So you can think of it as a Markdown Editor with mathematical input.</p>
<h2>Who is the Audience?</h2>
<p>I built this editor for myself, but decided it might be worthwhile for others, hence hosting it online. It is most valuable to those who enter a lot of mathematical content for websites (using MathJax), as it exports nicely to HTML and provides a convenient workflow. It is also useful for those looking for a reasonable quality math editor, who are not yet tied in to LaTeX, MS Word or another option. I believe the editor hits the sweetpot of being able to write WYSIWYG formatted rich text, with the power of mathematical input from AsciiMath &amp; LaTeX, with one-click previews of rendered maths.</p>
<h2>Suggestions &amp; Pull Requests Welcome!</h2>
<p>I would be very happy for others to take this editor and customise it for themselves or morph it into something more. I would love to see AsciiMath become a standard for mathematical input (LaTeX is good too, but I am a big fan of AsciiMath being more readable in raw form), and perhaps this project will help push in that direction.</p>
<h2>Get started!</h2>
<p>To get started, simply navigate to <a href="https://writer.math.dev/">https://writer.math.dev</a>. There is a basic tutorial under the "Read Me" tab. If you like this editor, please do star it on <a href="https://github.com/ashok-khanna/math-writer">GitHub</a>.</p>
<h2>Contact Information</h2>
<p>You can e-mail me at <a href="https://writer.math.dev/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection" data-cfemail="fa9b89929591d491929b94949bba92958e979b9396d4999597">[email&nbsp;protected]</a> for any queries, suggestions or just a general chat. Thank you again for your time and I hope you enjoy this editor.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://writer.math.dev/landing.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26287948</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 20:41:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[SolarWind, enough with the password already]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 208 | Comments 119 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26286940">thread link</a>) | @troydavis
<br/>
February 27, 2021 | https://gru.gq/2021/02/28/solarwind-enough-with-the-password-already/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://gru.gq/2021/02/28/solarwind-enough-with-the-password-already/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div><main><article itemscope="" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork"><div itemprop="text"><p>This is a much delayed discussion on the complexity and nuance of the SolarWind hack. The simplistic and wrong messaging from some quarters of the infosec community has resulted in an atrocious misunderstanding of the hack in the public sphere. This has extended into the policy world as these bad takes are treated as cogent analysis.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/thegrugq/status/1341439709487087618?s=21">I wrote this back in December</a>, but months later this <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2021/02/26/politics/solarwinds123-password-intern/index.html">bad analysis is still brought up in the policy space.</a></p>
<h2>Espionage is the second oldest profession</h2>
<p>It is a truth universally acknowledged, that with spying, the ends justify the means. This is true for all espionage organisations, the opposition’s and your own. Why is that relevant? Because any standard which is used to hamper the opposition will also apply to, and hamper, yours.</p>
<p>Sometimes laying down blanket rules about acceptable espionage behaviour is not a problem. Almost always this is when a certain type of operation is out of character with the society that produces the espionage agency. China makes extensive use of their diaspora community for espionage. The US has thousands of trained professionals and doesn’t use their diaspora community for organic bottom up collection. The US sometimes coopts civilians (and China has professionals) but generally speaking the diaspora method is one that only China uses extensively.</p>
<p>Extending this a bit further: if an espionage rule was proposed that banned the use of professionals but allowed the use of amateur civilians, China would be able to easily adapt to the new espionage environment. The US would be severely constrained. For this reason, the US wouldn’t sign up to, or abide by, such a requirement. (This is complicated further by the nature of targets for espionage, and national policy, but we can explore that another day.)</p>
<p>This brings me to targeting civilian companies and supply chain attacks. The US uses these methods just as, if not more, frequently than the Russians. FLAME, a strain of malware that targeted entities in the Middle East, exploited a cryptologic bug in the way Microsoft signed their updates. The NSA was then able to inject malicious code into the updates of Microsoft software. And just like SolarWinds, it was specifically targeted to ensure only legitimate espionage targets were infected and collected.</p>
<p><strong>There is no rule that would prohibit the SolarWinds espionage campaign which the US would be willing to abide by itself.</strong></p>
<h2>Russian Intelligence aren’t script kiddies</h2>
<p>Here’s the thing: the attackers are Russian foreign intelligence, the cream of the old KGB, and they will find a way to gain access to their target. Do they need to recruit a developer at the company and trick them into installing malware? They will do that.</p>
<p>They do not need to access the target via a weak password on the build servers. If that is what they use, then that is what they use, but it is not the make or break factor for the operation.</p>
<p>Part of the problem here might be that a superficial understanding of the cyber kill chain gives the impression that if you just stop <strong>The One Critical TTP</strong> in the chain then you will defeat the opposition. This is only true for an opposition that is inflexible and using just one technique. That description does not apply to the Russian intelligence services.</p>
<p>Intelligence agencies have targets and they will find the techniques to access them. The don’t start with a technique and look for targets that they can access.</p>
<p>The SolarWind backdoor was deeply integrated into the code, it was injected during their build process, and there is no way that the server having a weak password was the pivotal factor. As if Russian Intelligence would just give up if there were a strong password instead!</p>
<p>There is practically no chance that the server’s password was in anyway relevant to the hack overall. I can forgive the ignorance from the news media, but some infosec people are repeating this garbage as if it is important part of the SolarWind compromise.</p>
<blockquote><p>“The offense is routinely underestimated. When companies are hacked, they react as if they had only done this one thing or avoided this one mistake everything would have been okay. The adversary is treated as if they just got lucky.” — Network Attacks and Exploitation <a href="https://twitter.com/networkattack">@networkattack</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>People suggesting that the weak password example is relevant because it illustrates the poor security practices overall. I would agree with you if that was the argument presented. It was not. You have to work with the words ppl said, not what you wish they’d said.</p>
<blockquote><p>‘’Security researcher Vinoth Kumar told Reuters that, last year, he alerted the company that anyone could access SolarWinds’ update server by using the password “solarwinds123”<br>
“This could have been done by any attacker, easily,” Kumar said.’’</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I absolutely agree with the “it is illustrative of poor security practice” but… that isn’t what was said. They literally said that the weak password means that the attacker could be anyone. Anyone could do it. That is the dumbest take.</p>
<h2>The KGB vs a software vendor? Bet KGB.</h2>
<p>Here’s the thing.</p>
<p>I’m perfectly willing to believe that their build servers were using “admin:admin” and that’s how the Russians gained access to inject their code… but, this was a clandestine intelligence operation. They did not succeed merely because SolarWind had poor password hygiene.</p>
<p>The SVR was formed from the cream of the KGB — the first chief directorate (FCD). The most prestigious directorate in the KGB. As the SVR they are still formidable.</p>
<h2>Was SolarWind picked due to its poor security?</h2>
<p>No.</p>
<p>I suspect the primary motivation was the access that would be enabled by the attack, not the vulnerable nature of the company. This is the SVR, the cream of the KGB (first chief directorate). They are not going to be bothered by password policy.</p>
<p>That’s what kinda annoys me… however easy SolarWind may have been to hack, they were hacked by the fucking First Chief Directorate of the KGB. Quite possibly the people that are frying diplomats brains with microwaves in Havana. They’re pretty fucking metal.</p>
<p>Could SolarWind have been too difficult for the KGB to use them in an enablement operation? Yes, it is possible to achieve that level of security. Creating a strong fast detection capability with rapid remediation and incident response will make it hard for attackers to dwell for any length of time, or persist on the system after they gain access. It requires vigilance and some effort, but it can be done. Of course, SolarWind wasn’t close to reaching that level.</p>
<div><p>Liked it? Take a second to support grugq on Patreon!</p><p><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://www.patreon.com/oauth2/become-patron?response_type=code&amp;min_cents=100&amp;client_id=XPz53m5BPTmu-cnihK1RXoEaRoNywCco8VIPCNbwnAexV5YWdi_YG5Asup2LeG9p&amp;scope=identity%20identity[email]&amp;redirect_uri=https://gru.gq/patreon-authorization/&amp;state=eyJmaW5hbF9yZWRpcmVjdF91cmkiOiJodHRwczpcL1wvZ3J1LmdxXC8yMDIxXC8wMlwvMjhcL3NvbGFyd2luZC1lbm91Z2gtd2l0aC10aGUtcGFzc3dvcmQtYWxyZWFkeVwvIn0%3D&amp;utm_source=https%3A%2F%2Fgru.gq%2F2021%2F02%2F28%2Fsolarwind-enough-with-the-password-already%2F&amp;utm_medium=patreon_wordpress_plugin&amp;utm_campaign=457796&amp;utm_term=&amp;utm_content=post_unlock_button"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/gru.gq/wp-content/plugins/patron-button-and-widgets-by-codebard/images/become_a_patron_button.png?ssl=1" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-src="https://i2.wp.com/gru.gq/wp-content/plugins/patron-button-and-widgets-by-codebard/images/become_a_patron_button.png?ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></a></p></div>
<!--<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
			xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
			xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/">
		<rdf:Description rdf:about="https://gru.gq/2021/02/28/solarwind-enough-with-the-password-already/"
    dc:identifier="https://gru.gq/2021/02/28/solarwind-enough-with-the-password-already/"
    dc:title="SolarWind, enough with the password already!"
    trackback:ping="https://gru.gq/2021/02/28/solarwind-enough-with-the-password-already/trackback/" />
</rdf:RDF>-->
</div></article>
		

		
		

		</main></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://gru.gq/2021/02/28/solarwind-enough-with-the-password-already/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26286940</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 18:31:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A single cell slime mold makes decisions without a central nervous system]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 159 | Comments 68 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26285926">thread link</a>) | @gmays
<br/>
February 27, 2021 | https://www.tum.de/nc/en/about-tum/news/press-releases/details/36462/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.tum.de/nc/en/about-tum/news/press-releases/details/36462/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
				
<div id="c49300"><figure><img title="Prof. Dr. Karen Alim in ihrem Labor" alt="Prof. Dr. Karen Alim in ihrem Labor" src="https://www.tum.de/fileadmin/_processed_/f/7/csm_2102xx_Karen_Alim_lab_2100_60155babf1.jpg" width="1280" height="540"><figcaption>
				
					Prof. Dr. Karen Alim in her laboratory.
				
				<p><span>
					
						Image: Bilderfest / TUM
					
				</span></p></figcaption></figure><div><div><article itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article"><header><p itemprop="description">
					Having a memory of past events enables us to take smarter decisions about the future. Researchers at the Max-Planck Institute for Dynamics and Self-Organization (MPI-DS) and the Technical University of Munich (TUM) have now identified how the slime mold Physarum polycephalum saves memories – although it has no nervous system.
				</p></header><section><p>The ability to store and recover information gives an organism a clear advantage when searching for food or avoiding harmful environments. Traditionally it has been attributed to organisms that have a nervous system.</p><p>A new study authored by Mirna Kramar (MPI-DS) and <a href="https://www.professoren.tum.de/en/alim-karen" title="Profile of Prof. Dr. Karen Alim" target="_blank">Prof. Karen Alim</a> (TUM and MPI-DS) challenges this view by uncovering the surprising abilities of a highly dynamic, single-celled organism to store and retrieve information about its environment.</p><div id="c62766"><div><div><p>The slime mold Physarum polycephalum has been puzzling researchers for many decades. Existing at the crossroads between the kingdoms of animals, plants and fungi, this unique organism provides insight into the early evolutionary history of eukaryotes – to which also humans belong.</p><p>Its body is a giant single cell made up of interconnected tubes that form intricate networks. This single amoeba-like cell may stretch several centimeters or even meters, featuring as the largest cell on earth in the Guinness Book of World Records.</p></div></div></div><div id="c62767"><div><div><p>“It is very exciting when a project develops from a simple experimental observation”, says Karen Alim, head of the Biological Physics and Morphogenesis group at the MPI-DS in Göttingen and professor for the <a href="http://www.bpm.ph.tum.de/" target="_blank">Theory of Biological Networks</a> at the Technical University of Munich.</p><p>When the researchers followed the migration and feeding process of the organism and observed a distinct imprint of a food source on the pattern of thicker and thinner tubes of the network long after feeding.</p><p>“Given P. polycephalum's highly dynamic network reorganization, the persistence of this imprint sparked the idea that the network architecture itself could serve as memory of the past“, says Karen Alim. However, they first needed to explain the mechanism behind the imprint formation.</p></div></div></div><div id="c62768"><div><div><p>For this purpose the researchers combined microscopic observations of the adaption of the tubular network with theoretical modeling. An encounter with food triggers the release of a chemical that travels from the location where food was found throughout the organism and softens the tubes in the network, making the whole organism reorient its migration towards the food.</p><p>“The gradual softening is where the existing imprints of previous food sources come into play and where information is stored and retrieved”, says first author Mirna Kramar. “Past feeding events are embedded in the hierarchy of tube diameters, specifically in the arrangement of thick and thin tubes in the network.”</p><p>“For the softening chemical that is now transported, the thick tubes in the network act as highways in traffic networks, enabling quick transport across the whole organism”, adds Mirna Kramar. “Previous encounters imprinted in the network architecture thus weigh into the decision about the future direction of migration.”</p></div></div></div><div id="c62769"><div><div><p>„Given the simplicity of this living network, the ability of Physarum to form memories is intriguing. It is remarkable that the organism relies on such a simple mechanism and yet controls it in such a fine-tuned manner,” says Karen Alim.</p><p>“These results present an important piece of the puzzle in understanding the behavior of this ancient organism and at the same time points to universal principles underlying behavior. We envision potential applications of our findings in designing smart materials and building soft robots that navigate through complex environments”, concludes Karen Alim.</p></div></div></div><div><div><div><h3>
		Corporate Communications Center
	</h3></div></div></div><section></section></section></article></div></div><section><h2>
			Article at tum.de
		</h2><div><div><article><a title="ERC supports pioneering research projects at TUM" href="https://www.tum.de/en/about-tum/news/press-releases/details/36230-1/"><figure><img alt="Schleimpilz Physarum polycephalum" src="https://www.tum.de/fileadmin/_processed_/f/b/csm_Physarum_polycephalum_2100_6fd9eb4a44.jpg" width="1280" height="720" title="Physarum polycephalum ERC Grants"><figcaption></figcaption></figure></a><header><h2><a title="ERC supports pioneering research projects at TUM" href="https://www.tum.de/en/about-tum/news/press-releases/details/36230-1/">
						ERC supports pioneering research projects at TUM
					</a></h2><p>
					
						From new methods for examining individual cells, physical basics of the reactions of vascular systems and the development of better prognostic methods for osteoporosis to intelligent tools for urban planning and the...
				</p></header></article></div></div></section><!-- news uid 36459 --></div>


				
			</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.tum.de/nc/en/about-tum/news/press-releases/details/36462/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26285926</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 16:37:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Taxing Families Like Companies]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 42 | Comments 91 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26285606">thread link</a>) | @mooreds
<br/>
February 27, 2021 | https://americancompass.org/the-commons/taxing-families-like-companies/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://americancompass.org/the-commons/taxing-families-like-companies/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      
<div>
  <p>Sign up to receive The Commons posts in your inbox.</p>
  
</div>
<div>
    
  <div>
    <p><img data-src="https://americancompass.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/stellrweb-djb1whucfBY-unsplash-scaled.jpg" src="https://americancompass.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/stellrweb-djb1whucfBY-unsplash-scaled.jpg"></p><p><em>[Note: This post is from the policy forum <a href="https://americancompass.org/essays/7-proposals-to-make-america-more-family-friendly/">7 Proposals to Make America More Family-Friendly</a>.]</em></p>
<p>If families are people, and corporations are people, it stands to reason that families should be allowed to incorporate and file their taxes accordingly.</p>
<p>The benefits to incorporating are fairly obvious: corporations are taxed on their net income, and they enjoy a lower tax rate. Families, on the other hand, pay taxes on their revenue. And while families enjoy a few miscellaneous deductions and credits, they largely miss out on the good stuff. Corporations get to deduct nearly all capital expenditures; families receive no direct tax benefit for feeding their kids, purchasing clothes, buying a minivan, filling that minivan with unleaded, homeschooling or other education expenses, fixing a furnace, upgrading technology, or even moving to a safer neighborhood. If a corporation can demonstrate a net loss on the year, even due to its own aggressive spending habits, it doesn’t pay taxes. If a family loses money, the tax code doesn’t care.<span id="more-3557"></span></p>
<p>As a result, families pay a disproportionate share of federal tax receipts. In <a href="https://www.irs.gov/pub/irs-pdf/p55b.pdf">2019</a>, individuals paid just under 70 percent of all federal taxes, while corporations paid just 25 percent. Take payroll taxes out of the equation, and those numbers become even more lopsided: individuals paid nearly $1.6 trillion to the federal government while corporations paid about $226 billion.</p>
<p>This is not to suggest that corporations should be taxed on their revenue, or that we should dramatically increase corporate taxes. Lower taxes and reduced regulatory burdens can, at least in theory, encourage capital formation. So if Republicans are so eager to pass a $1.7 trillion, unfunded corporate tax cut on the belief that it would spur business investment, as they did in 2017, shouldn’t they be willing to consider a similar approach to other forms of capital formation—namely, human capital formation?</p>
<p>We are in the midst of a fertility crisis, which only worsened during the COVID-19 pandemic. The U.S. has already reached an all-time-low fertility rate of 1.71 births per woman, and Brookings estimates that there will be a “<a href="https://www.brookings.edu/research/half-a-million-fewer-children-the-coming-covid-baby-bust/">baby bust</a>” in 2021 of at least 300,000 fewer American births. The long-term effects of such a decline in human capital would be far-reaching. Shrinking populations don’t often lend themselves to growing economies.</p>
<p>Financial pressures are one of the main, addressable sources of the crisis. As American Compass’s recent Home Building Survey <a href="https://americancompass.org/essays/home-building-survey-part-1/">showed</a>, half of parenting-age adults want more children than they currently have. And for all but the most well-off, these parents cite the inability to afford more children as the primary reason for this deficit.</p>
<p>If we were to find a similar impediment to the formation or growth of American businesses, wouldn’t we do something about it? Wouldn’t we have done something already?</p>
<p>We could create new deductions or expand existing credits to attempt to level the playing field between corporations and families. Options include: boosting the Child Tax Credit, reworking the Earned Income Tax Credit, extending the Child and Dependent Care Tax Credit beyond two dependents or above the current $6,000 cap, or even expanding the scope of 529 savings accounts to include all K-12 schooling options.</p>
<p>Or, we could go big and allow families access to the same tax treatment that Amazon and General Electric enjoy. Instead of a Child Tax Credit, let families write off their grocery bills. Instead of deductions for mortgage interest that only kick in if tax filers earn enough income to itemize, let families deduct all housing costs. Instead of an inadequate childcare deduction, let families deduct the entire expense. Why not? Families are corporations, my friend.</p>
<p>For decades, supply-side ideology has led Republicans to cut taxes and regulation on behalf of corporations. Now, as financial pressures constrain the supply of future Americans, we should embrace supply-side <em>oikonomics</em> and let families incorporate.</p>
    <p><a href="https://americancompass.org/the-commons/">Return to the Commons</a>
  </p></div>
  <div>
    <div>
      <p><img src="https://americancompass.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Schweppe_Headshot-150x150.jpg" width="96" height="96" alt="Jon Schweppe"></p><div>
        
        <p>Jon Schweppe is the director of policy and government affairs at American Principles Project.</p>
                
              </div>
    </div>
  </div>
    
</div>
<p>
  <h3>Related Posts</h3>
</p>
<section>
    <div>
    <h5><a href="https://americancompass.org/the-commons/let-them-eat-daycare/">Let Them Eat Daycare</a></h5>
    
    <p>Our policy debates center on helping working families, but they routinely fail to capture those families’ preferences for their own lives or for policies that would help them most. Proposals most useful to households with all adults in the workforce, like subsidized childcare or paid leave, often receive far more attention from policymakers and pundits […]</p>
  </div>
    <div>
    <h5><a href="https://americancompass.org/the-commons/dont-federalize-family-policy/">Don’t Federalize Family Policy</a></h5>
    
    <p>[Note: This comment is from a&nbsp;series of responses&nbsp;to the proposal for a&nbsp;Family Income Supplemental Credit.] Although this is a response to the interesting and compelling Family Income Supplemental Credit (Fisc) proposal by Oren Cass and Wells King, it is meant, more broadly, to engage with those on the political right who argue for more forcefully […]</p>
  </div>
  </section>
        
      </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://americancompass.org/the-commons/taxing-families-like-companies/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26285606</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 15:54:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Phantom Types in Gleam]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 30 | Comments 11 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26284976">thread link</a>) | @pd-andy
<br/>
February 27, 2021 | https://blog.pd-andy.dev/phantom-types-in-gleam | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.pd-andy.dev/phantom-types-in-gleam">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text"><p>In this post we're going to be looking at a more advanced use of <a target="_blank" href="https://gleam.run/">Gleam</a>'s type system, known as phantom types. Hopefully by the end of this you'll have another tool in your belt to help you better model data in your programs. And fear not, because many languages support phantom types (most common functional programming languages support them, but so do others like Rust, and TypeScript, and even <a target="_blank" href="https://marcosh.github.io/post/2020/05/26/phantom-types-in-php.html">PHP</a>) so you can apply this knowledge elsewhere! </p>
<p>Before we get stuck into some examples, let's tackle the obvious question.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="what-are-phantom-types">What are phantom types?</h2>
<p>A phantom type is a type parameter that appears on the left hand side of a type's definition but not on the right hand side. In other words, it's a type parameter that is never used by any of a type's constructors.</p>
<pre><code>pub type Example(phantom) {
    Example
}
</code></pre>
<p>In the <code>Example</code> type we have a type parameter, <code>phantom</code>, that isn't used in the type's constructor. Phantom types can be used to provide additional safety or context to values without paying the runtime cost of carrying additional data around. Everything is handled at compile time!</p>
<blockquote>
<p>💡 In some languages, the compiler may emit a warning (or refuse to compile at all) when a type has unused type parameters. Often there are language-specific solutions to this, like <a target="_blank" href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/marker/struct.PhantomData.html">PhantomData</a> in Rust or <a target="_blank" href="https://medium.com/@dhruvrajvanshi/advanced-typescript-patterns-6cf8826c7944">impossible fields</a> in TypeScript.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The rest of this article will see us going over <strong>four</strong> different scenarios where phantom types can come in to play. The whole article is a bit long so if any of the examples describes a scenario that fits you perfectly, feel free to jump straight to it!</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="example-one-dealing-with-ids">Example One: Dealing with Ids.</h2>
<p>To understand why phantom types might be useful, let's start with a common scenario. Imagine we're building a social blogging platform like <a target="_blank" href="http://dev.to/">dev.to</a> or <a target="_blank" href="http://medium.com/">medium.com</a>. We want to support different users and blog posts, so we assign a unique id to all of these things.</p>
<p>We're a scrappy, fast-moving startup so we implement the simplest possible system for managing IDs: just type aliasing <code>Int</code>s to get things going.</p>
<pre><code>pub type Id = Int

pub fn next (id: Id) -&gt; Id {
    id + 1
}
</code></pre>
<p>Our platform supports Reddit-style upvoting or liking of posts, and we have a function just for that. It takes in the <code>Id</code> of a post to upvote and the <code>Id</code> of the user that upvoted it, and does some magic to make the upvote happen.</p>
<pre><code>pub fn upvote_post (user_id: Id, post_id: Id) -&gt; Nil {
    // Get a post from the database and upvote it.
    ...
}
</code></pre>
<p>This lets us rush to production, but maybe you've already spotted a potential problem with what we have so far. It's only a matter of time until someone gets the parameters the wrong way round and now a totally unrelated user has upvoted a random post.</p>
<p>One solution would be to stop aliasing <code>Int</code> and define new types for <code>PostId</code> and <code>UserId</code> instead.</p>
<pre><code>pub type PostId { PostId(Int) }
pub type UserId { UserId(Int) }
</code></pre>
<p>Now the two id types are successfully disjoint, but as a consequence we'll end up with a lot more duplicated code. We'll have to have separate <code>next</code> methods to increment each id type, similarly if we want to unwrap the type we'll need separate <code>to_int</code> functions, and the story is the same for <code>to_string</code>, and so on...</p>
<p>Really, the underlying representation of an <code>Id</code> stays the same no matter how we use it. Instead, we'd like the context an <code>Id</code> is used in to determine whether it is valid or not.</p>
<pre><code>pub opaque type Id(a) {
    Id(Int)
}

pub fn new () -&gt; Id(a) {
    Id(0)
}
</code></pre>
<p>We've now redefined our <code>Id</code> type to include a type parameter, <code>a</code>, but notice how that parameter isn't used in the type's constructor: this is where the name <strong>phantom type</strong> comes from. The second  thing to notice is that our <code>new</code> function returns an id with that generic <code>a</code> parameter. This lets <em>callers of the function</em> determine what the type of <code>a</code> should be.</p>
<pre><code>let foo: Id(String)      = new()
let bar: Id(Float)       = new()
let baz: Id(Option(Int)) = new()
</code></pre>
<p>Now, <code>foo</code>, <code>bar</code>, and <code>baz</code> are all incompatible with each other. We couldn't check them for equality, for example, because the types don't match up. Fundamental to phantom types is the fact that there is no runtime component, <code>foo</code> may be annotated as <code>Id(String)</code> but no such string exists at runtime, the same for <code>Id(Float)</code> or any other parameter. </p>
<pre><code>foo == bar // Uh oh, compile error!
</code></pre>
<p>This is powerful because we gain the ability to tell the compiler a fact about a particular <code>Id</code>, and the compiler will do extra work to ensure we don't make any mistakes.</p>
<pre><code>pub type User {
    User(id: Id(User), name: String)
}

pub type Post {
    Post(id: Id(Post), content: String)
}

pub fn upvote_post (user_id: Id(User), post_id: Id(Post)) -&gt; Nil {
    // Get a post from the database and upvote it.
    ...
}
</code></pre>
<p>In the snippet above, we've defined <code>User</code> and <code>Post</code> types and parameterised the <code>Id</code> type accordingly. Knowing what we know so far about phantom types, we can see that the new type signature for <code>upvote_post</code> will prevent us from accidentally swapping the order of the ids.</p>
<pre><code>let user = User(id: new(), name: "pd-andy")
let post = Post(id: new(), content: "Phantom Types in Gleam...")

upvote_post(post.id, user.id) // Uh oh, compile error!
</code></pre>
<p>Even though our phantom type lets us specialise the <code>Id</code> type, we can still write functions that work on <em>all</em> ids by leaving the type parameter as a variable.</p>
<pre><code>pub fn show (id: Id(a)) -&gt; String {
    let Id(n) = id
    int.to_string(n)
}

show(user.id)
show(post.id)
</code></pre>
<p>The ability to restrict or open up functions to different <code>Id</code>s is where a lot of the power with phantom types comes from. </p>
<h2 id="example-two-handling-money">Example Two: Handling money.</h2>
<p>Let's consider another scenario. We want to build an application that can handle monetary transactions such that we can easily work with currencies of the same type, but different currencies must be explicitly converted via an exchange rate before they can be used together.</p>
<p>Similar to our id scenario, the underlying representation for a value of currency is always the same.</p>
<pre><code>pub opaque type Currency(a) {
  Currency(Float)
}

pub fn from_float (x: Float) -&gt; Currency(a) {
  Currency(x)
}
</code></pre>
<p>As before, our <code>Currency</code> type has a single type parameter that we'll use to <em>tag</em> values with a particular type of currency. We also need to define some types to act as our currency tags. Because these types are only used for annotations, we'll make them opaque. </p>
<pre><code>pub opaque type USD { USD }
pub opaque type GBP { GBP }
</code></pre>
<p>Now we can use everything we've defined so far to create some different currencies.</p>
<pre><code>let dollars: Currency(USD) = from_float(2.50)
let pennies: Currency(GBP) = from_float(0.55)
</code></pre>
<p>Right now we have some currency values, but we can't do a whole lot with them. While they're wrapped up in our <code>Currency</code> type, we can't use any arithmetic operators or pass these values to functions expecting <code>Float</code>s.</p>
<p>Let's remedy that by writing two functions, <code>update</code> and <code>combine</code>. We'll use <code>update</code> to apply a function to the value wrapped by a <code>Currency</code>, and we'll use <code>combine</code> to apply a function to two <code>Currency</code> values.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>💡 For other data structures these functions might be called <code>map</code> and <code>map2</code>. These imply the type can change, for example <code>list.map</code> can be used to turn a <code>List(a)</code> into a <code>List(b)</code>. </p>
<p>Because we want to preserve the type (so we can't convert <code>Currency(USD)</code> to <code>Currency(GBP)</code>) we give these functions different names so there aren't any mismatched expectations.</p>
</blockquote>
<pre><code>pub fn update (a: Currency(a), f: fn (Float) -&gt; Float) -&gt; Currency(a) {
  let Currency(x) = a
  x |&gt; f |&gt; from_float
}

pub fn combine (a: Currency(a), b: Currency(a), f: fn (Float, Float) -&gt; Float) -&gt; Currency(a) {
    let Currency(x) = a
    let Currency(y) = b
    f(x, y) |&gt; from_float
}
</code></pre>
<p>Because the type parameter for <code>Currency</code> doesn't change (these function take a <code>Currency(a)</code> and return a <code>Currency(a)</code>), they can't change the tag of any currency passed in.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>💡 Both <code>update</code> and <code>combine</code> are examples of <strong>higher-order functions</strong>.  That is, they are functions that take <em>other functions</em> as one of their arguments (or return a new function themselves).</p>
</blockquote>
<p>We can use these two functions to define some more functions so we can actually <em>do</em> things with currency values, like doubling something or adding two currencies together.</p>
<pre><code>pub fn double (a: Currency(a)) -&gt; Currency(a) {
    update(a, fn (x) { x * 2 })
}

pub fn add (a: Currency(a), b: Currency(a)) -&gt; Currency(a) {
    combine(a, b, fn (x, y) { x + y })
}
</code></pre>
<p>We can call these functions with any type of currency, but for something like <code>add</code> we get compile-time safety that ensures we only add two currencies of the same type.</p>
<pre><code>double(dollars)       //=&gt; from_float(5.00): Currency(USD)
add(pennies, pennies) //=&gt; from_float(1.10): Currency(GBP)

add(dollars, pennies) //=&gt; I won't compile!
</code></pre>
<p>But what if we <em>want</em> to add two currencies together? To do that we need a way of converting one currency to another with an exchange rate. We can use phantom types again here to define an</p>
<p><code>Exchange</code> type that describes the exchange rate from one currency to another.</p>
<pre><code>pub opaque type Exchange (from, to) {
    Exchange(Float)
}

pub fn exchange_rate (r: Float) -&gt; Exchange(from, to) {
    Exchange(r)
}
</code></pre>
<p>Now, just like we did for currencies, we can define an exchange rate to go from <code>GBP</code> to <code>USD</code> (and vice versa).</p>
<pre><code>let gbp_to_usd: Exchange(GBP, USD) = exchange_rate(1.41)
let usd_to_gbp: Exchange(USD, GBP) = exchange_rate(0.71)
</code></pre>
<p>Using everything we know about phantom types, we can define a <code>convert</code> function that is type safe; we'll never be able to pass in the wrong exchange rate because all the phantom types have to match up!</p>
<pre><code>pub fn convert (a: Currency(from), e: Exchange(from, to)) -&gt; Currency(to) {
    let Currency(x) = a
    let Exchange(r) = e
    x *. r |&gt; from_float
}
</code></pre>
<p>Although our module provided the <code>USD</code> and <code>GBP</code> types to act as currency tags, the functions we've written are general to all currencies but retain their type safety. If consumers of the module want to define another type of currency, they can do that and our functions will still work.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="example-three-validating-data">Example Three: Validating data.</h2>
<p>So far the two examples we have seen in <code>Id</code> and <code>Currency</code> have been used to provide a general API across types …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.pd-andy.dev/phantom-types-in-gleam">https://blog.pd-andy.dev/phantom-types-in-gleam</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.pd-andy.dev/phantom-types-in-gleam</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26284976</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 14:17:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A new chapter – full-time working from a van in a forest]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 159 | Comments 76 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26284635">thread link</a>) | @ghuntley
<br/>
February 27, 2021 | https://ghuntley.com/a-new-chapter | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ghuntley.com/a-new-chapter">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              <p>For many people, the year 2020 will go down as a moment in time of hardship in their lives but for me, the year 2019 was dramatically harder as it was the realization that a long-term relationship wasn't going to work out and that everyone, including my children, would be homeless within 14 days. <em>Oomph</em>.</p><figure><div><div><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/IMG_20191111_094714.jpg" width="2000" height="2667" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/IMG_20191111_094714.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/IMG_20191111_094714.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1600/2021/02/IMG_20191111_094714.jpg 1600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w2400/2021/02/IMG_20191111_094714.jpg 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/vlcsnap-2021-02-23-14h54m12s813.png" width="1920" height="1080" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/vlcsnap-2021-02-23-14h54m12s813.png 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/vlcsnap-2021-02-23-14h54m12s813.png 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1600/2021/02/vlcsnap-2021-02-23-14h54m12s813.png 1600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/vlcsnap-2021-02-23-14h54m12s813.png 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p></div><div><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/2021-02-23_14-48-25-1.jpg" width="2000" height="769" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/2021-02-23_14-48-25-1.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/2021-02-23_14-48-25-1.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1600/2021/02/2021-02-23_14-48-25-1.jpg 1600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w2400/2021/02/2021-02-23_14-48-25-1.jpg 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/_95SAnmj.jpg-large-1.jpg" width="1536" height="2048" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/_95SAnmj.jpg-large-1.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/_95SAnmj.jpg-large-1.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/_95SAnmj.jpg-large-1.jpg 1536w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p></div></div><figcaption>Over the course of five years more than $110,000 had been spent on rent at that dumpster of a house.&nbsp;</figcaption></figure><p>I packed all of my artefacts and office equipment into a u-haul and left everything else, including the family car to my now ex-wife. To cut a long story short the cost of housing in Sydney, Australia and sole-income was a leading factor in the dissolution of the relationship.</p><figure><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/image-1.png" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/image-1.png 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/image-1.png 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1600/2021/02/image-1.png 1600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/image-1.png 1896w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2018/mar/15/sydney-more-expensive-to-live-in-than-london-and-new-york-study-finds</figcaption></figure><p>I'm doing excellent, <em>now</em>, but back then the entire experience left me shattered, soul destroyed and burnt out beyond belief. Luckily an el-rando, now friend, saw that I was in need and reached out:</p><blockquote>"Heading camping to Stradbroke week after next if you want to totally unplug. <strong>If you need anything, let me know</strong>."</blockquote><p>I just want to say, thank-you. I needed that. </p><p>Dear reader, if you ever find yourself in crisis or a situation similar to mine please do not hesitate to <a href="https://ghuntley.com/contact">contact me</a> if you need a shoulder or advice. You deserve to live a life that makes you happy and not miserable.</p><p>People often ask me what got you interested in #vanlife, now you know. It wasn't an interest as-per-say but more of a necessity and a key ingredient to ensuring my children would grow up with a father in their lives. </p><p>I first heard about the concept of #vanlife back in 2015 after reading this article about a <a href="https://jalopnik.com/google-software-engineer-lives-in-a-van-to-avoid-san-fr-1737619550">Google employee who lived in a box-truck in the company's parking lot</a>:</p><blockquote>“I realized I was paying an exorbitant amount of money for the apartment I was staying in — and I was almost never home,” he says. “It’s really hard to justify throwing that kind of money away. You’re essentially burning it — you’re not putting equity in anything and you’re not building it up for a future — and that was really hard for me to reconcile"</blockquote><p>The events that followed the Stradbroke camping trip put me on a path towards thinking about okay, what-next and how will I get there? Fast-forward a couple of months later I found myself on my own month-long camping trip down in Tasmania where I learned some important life lessons, bushcraft skills and met some <a href="https://www.onemanonebikeoneworld.com/2015/10/australia-at-home-in-crunchy-town/">interesting characters</a>, some of whom were living #vanlife.</p><figure><div><div><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/93956755_10157390553498505_8259160674995798016_o.jpg" width="1438" height="772" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/93956755_10157390553498505_8259160674995798016_o.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/93956755_10157390553498505_8259160674995798016_o.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/93956755_10157390553498505_8259160674995798016_o.jpg 1438w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/1-dLCs9WWLvE1Goul018u-Jg-1.jpeg" width="2000" height="2872" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/1-dLCs9WWLvE1Goul018u-Jg-1.jpeg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/1-dLCs9WWLvE1Goul018u-Jg-1.jpeg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1600/2021/02/1-dLCs9WWLvE1Goul018u-Jg-1.jpeg 1600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/1-dLCs9WWLvE1Goul018u-Jg-1.jpeg 2162w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/IMG_20200222_091110.jpg" width="2000" height="1500" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/IMG_20200222_091110.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/IMG_20200222_091110.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1600/2021/02/IMG_20200222_091110.jpg 1600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w2400/2021/02/IMG_20200222_091110.jpg 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p></div><div><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/2021-02-23_14-15-36.jpg" width="2000" height="914" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/2021-02-23_14-15-36.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/2021-02-23_14-15-36.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1600/2021/02/2021-02-23_14-15-36.jpg 1600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w2400/2021/02/2021-02-23_14-15-36.jpg 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/2021-02-23_14-14-28.jpg" width="2000" height="872" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/2021-02-23_14-14-28.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/2021-02-23_14-14-28.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1600/2021/02/2021-02-23_14-14-28.jpg 1600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w2400/2021/02/2021-02-23_14-14-28.jpg 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/2021-02-23_14-18-14.jpg" width="2000" height="856" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/2021-02-23_14-18-14.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/2021-02-23_14-18-14.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1600/2021/02/2021-02-23_14-18-14.jpg 1600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w2400/2021/02/2021-02-23_14-18-14.jpg 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p></div><div><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/IMG_20200308_082035-1.jpg" width="2000" height="1500" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/IMG_20200308_082035-1.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/IMG_20200308_082035-1.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1600/2021/02/IMG_20200308_082035-1.jpg 1600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w2400/2021/02/IMG_20200308_082035-1.jpg 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/Alana-Una-Divine.jpg" width="960" height="720" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/Alana-Una-Divine.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/Alana-Una-Divine.jpg 960w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/26756404_10155262413212066_7256284448836424591_o.jpg" width="1440" height="1080" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/26756404_10155262413212066_7256284448836424591_o.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/26756404_10155262413212066_7256284448836424591_o.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/26756404_10155262413212066_7256284448836424591_o.jpg 1440w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p></div></div></figure><p>I was amazed at the quality of life these people had, how they were able to make ends meet and their resourcefulness. They also knew how to have a freaking good time...</p><figure><iframe width="200" height="113" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/umxjUjqRdOY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></figure><p>Over the course of a month, a small group of people <a href="https://www.google.com.au/maps/place/41%C2%B018'37.0%22S+147%C2%B047'54.2%22E/@-41.3102818,147.7966608,555m/data=!3m2!1e3!4b1!4m14!1m7!3m6!1s0xaa775776abb20549:0x403c94dd0ddf450!2sScottsdale+TAS+7260,+Australia!3b1!8m2!3d-41.166667!4d147.516667!3m5!1s0x0:0x0!7e2!8m2!3d-41.3102849!4d147.7983983">camping on crown land</a> grew to over 500 people. Love was free and it was custom to hug <em>everyone</em>. Meanwhile, in a parallel universe, this was happening...</p><figure><div><div><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/IMG_20200324_154236.jpg" width="1386" height="1848" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/IMG_20200324_154236.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/IMG_20200324_154236.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/IMG_20200324_154236.jpg 1386w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/IMG_20200324_153304_MP.jpg" width="1386" height="1848" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/IMG_20200324_153304_MP.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/IMG_20200324_153304_MP.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/IMG_20200324_153304_MP.jpg 1386w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p></div></div></figure><p>With the new-found knowledge and experiences, I flew back to sunny Queensland, Australia and started my research. After watching hundreds of hours of videos on YouTube I found this video, which to this day, represents my north star:</p><figure><iframe width="200" height="113" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/l-DgMYB6L0c?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></figure><p>Over the months that followed through 2020, my father and mother helped make the dream a reality. I never wanted to live in Sydney, Australia ever again, yet, much to my dismay, my children would remain living in a city that makes no sense. Putting together a van was a major step in getting my life back on track and ensuring that my children would know their father.</p><figure><div><div><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/IMG_20200402_162953.jpg" width="300" height="225" alt=""></p><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/IMG_20200419_112842.jpg" width="2000" height="1500" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/IMG_20200419_112842.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/IMG_20200419_112842.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1600/2021/02/IMG_20200419_112842.jpg 1600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w2400/2021/02/IMG_20200419_112842.jpg 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/IMG_20200701_112931.jpg" width="1386" height="1848" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/IMG_20200701_112931.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/IMG_20200701_112931.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/IMG_20200701_112931.jpg 1386w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p></div><div><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/PXL_20201128_062424513.jpg" width="2000" height="1500" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/PXL_20201128_062424513.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/PXL_20201128_062424513.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1600/2021/02/PXL_20201128_062424513.jpg 1600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w2400/2021/02/PXL_20201128_062424513.jpg 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/PXL_20201204_222041572.MP.jpg" width="1386" height="1848" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/PXL_20201204_222041572.MP.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/PXL_20201204_222041572.MP.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/PXL_20201204_222041572.MP.jpg 1386w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p></div><div><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/IMG_20200919_094643.jpg" width="1386" height="1848" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/IMG_20200919_094643.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/IMG_20200919_094643.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/IMG_20200919_094643.jpg 1386w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/PXL_20201204_011641497.jpg" width="1386" height="1848" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/PXL_20201204_011641497.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/PXL_20201204_011641497.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/PXL_20201204_011641497.jpg 1386w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p></div></div></figure><p>It's now 2021, I'm doing better than I was in the relationship and my children are having more <em>quality time</em> with their father than they have ever had. Over the last 12 months during various stages of the van kit-out, my kids and I have been going away on overnight, weekend and school holiday adventures where they get to experience the sights and sounds of Australia.</p><figure><div><div><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/PXL_20210103_102322442.PORTRAIT-2.jpg" width="2000" height="1500" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/PXL_20210103_102322442.PORTRAIT-2.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/PXL_20210103_102322442.PORTRAIT-2.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1600/2021/02/PXL_20210103_102322442.PORTRAIT-2.jpg 1600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w2400/2021/02/PXL_20210103_102322442.PORTRAIT-2.jpg 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/PXL_20210103_095904261.PORTRAIT.jpg" width="1386" height="1848" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/PXL_20210103_095904261.PORTRAIT.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/PXL_20210103_095904261.PORTRAIT.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/PXL_20210103_095904261.PORTRAIT.jpg 1386w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/PXL_20210103_100004979.PORTRAIT.jpg" width="1386" height="1848" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/PXL_20210103_100004979.PORTRAIT.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/PXL_20210103_100004979.PORTRAIT.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/PXL_20210103_100004979.PORTRAIT.jpg 1386w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p></div></div></figure><p>On the relationship front, I'm pleased to share that there has been minimal conflict and day-by-day we each learn to love and respect each other as the parents of our children. A large part of that is due to some early advice I received from a man who had also recently divorced:</p><blockquote>It will all work out. Just keep the focus on the kids and relationship will improve. We're at the stage where my ex will come around and have drinks with my girlfriend and I. You have drop everything (hurt, money, etc) from before on the floor and move past it. You'll be much happier.</blockquote><p>To that person, thank you for sharing your perspectives and advice on how to ensure that, unlike you see in the movies, co-parenting does not need to be adversarial.</p><figure><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/image-2.png" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/image-2.png 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/image-2.png 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1600/2021/02/image-2.png 1600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w2400/2021/02/image-2.png 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><div><p>So, in summary - everything has been going well but there was still one thing left to resolve:</p><p>✔️ housing.<br>✔️ conflict free co-parenting.<br>✔️ children having quality time with their father.<br>🚧 <em>meaningful </em>work</p></div><p>Approx 21% to 35% of our time awake is spent at work and every two years that goes by at a company you don't like (or unemployed) is wasting 2% of your working life. Time is valuable and there are no guarantees that tomorrow will come thus it is exceedinly important for happiness that you find work that is <em>meaningful and that treats you well</em>.</p><figure><iframe width="200" height="113" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mQkBnS4OOqU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe><figcaption>One of my first employers had meaningful work but didn't treat people well.&nbsp;</figcaption></figure><p>Work keeps us busy. &nbsp;It gives us structure, it defines us as functioning, contributing, worthwhile citizens. &nbsp;It makes us part of the team, a community of fellow workers — even if we do our work remotely in isolation. </p><h2 id="meaningful-work">meaningful work</h2><p>Pause for a moment and think about this...</p><blockquote>What brings meaning into your life? </blockquote><p>After what I had been through in 2019 I spent a considerable amount of time in 2020 thinking about the above question. </p><p>The clock rolled over to 2021 and fortunately I have answers to the above question, a kick-ass van but what good is a van if you can't go on adventures and work remotely from it indefinitely?</p><figure><div><div><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/PXL_20201217_041851644.jpg" width="2000" height="1500" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/PXL_20201217_041851644.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/PXL_20201217_041851644.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1600/2021/02/PXL_20201217_041851644.jpg 1600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w2400/2021/02/PXL_20201217_041851644.jpg 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/PXL_20201214_034618899.jpg" width="1386" height="1848" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/PXL_20201214_034618899.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/PXL_20201214_034618899.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/PXL_20201214_034618899.jpg 1386w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p></div><div><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/PXL_20201214_034540072.jpg" width="1386" height="1848" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/PXL_20201214_034540072.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/PXL_20201214_034540072.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/PXL_20201214_034540072.jpg 1386w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/PXL_20201214_034733334.MP.jpg" width="290" height="218" alt=""></p></div></div><figcaption>This is my office, as it is now. The interior design is temporary.</figcaption></figure><p>So anyway, I've got some news... </p><p>The founders of Gitpod recently approached me about joining them and it was a no-brainer. I have joined <a href="https://gitpod.io/?utm_medium=website&amp;utm_campaign=meaningful-work&amp;utm_source=ghuntley">Gitpod</a>. 🎉</p><p>The company is remote-first (✔️), embraces asyncrony (✔️), filled with brilliant people (✔️), the product is open-source (✔️) and built on GitHub (✔️) using the light weight Visual Studio code process (✔️). </p><figure><blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I was pitching the VSCode development process, with its 1-month release cycle to an open source project this morning.<br>All projects could benefit from embracing this model: <a href="https://t.co/ymkVy0OBoD">https://t.co/ymkVy0OBoD</a></p>— Miguel de Icaza (@migueldeicaza) <a href="https://twitter.com/migueldeicaza/status/1364582599000260615?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 24, 2021</a></blockquote>

</figure><p>Gitpod has been a meaningful and key piece of software in my toolkit over the last couple years because Gitpod enables me to develop on any device from anywhere. I can hop between pull-requests with a single click and there's no waiting because <a href="https://www.gitpod.io/docs/prebuilds/">the pull-request has already been pre-compiled</a>. </p><figure><iframe width="200" height="150" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KR8ESjGYsXI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></figure><p>Gitpod has enabled me to standardize development environments between people and, like docker, move to ephemeral instances so that I never experience "but it works on my machine" ever again.</p><p>I could talk for hours on end on how meaningful the work Gitpod is doing and how it makes it easier for open-source maintainers to onboard new contributors to their project but it's better that you just <em><a href="https://gitpod.io/#https://github.com/gitpod-io/website/">experience it for yourself</a></em>.</p><figure><a href="https://gitpod.io/#https://github.com/gitpod-io/website/"><div><p>Gitpod – Dev environments built for the cloud</p><p>Gitpod streamlines developer workflows by providing prebuilt, collaborative development environments in your browser – powered by VS Code.</p><p><img src="https://gitpod.io/images/gitpod-196x196.png"></p></div><p><img src="https://www.gitpod.io/media-image.jpg"></p></a><figcaption>Try Gitpod for yourself by mashing the above link!</figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/image-3.png" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/image-3.png 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/image-3.png 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1600/2021/02/image-3.png 1600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w2400/2021/02/image-3.png 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption>Visit https://gitpod.io/#https://github.com/gitpod-io/website/ in your browser</figcaption></figure><p>So, that's the news. Things are doing really well. I want to say thank-you for those whom <a href="https://ghuntley.com/support">have supported me</a> over the last couple years whilst I figured this all out.</p><p>This chapter is only just beginning. I'm blogging more and <a href="https://twitter.com/geoffreyhuntley">tweeting less</a> so if you want to learn about sweet places to visit in Australia, working remotely from a van or how I get internet whilst camping out in a remote forest, like, <a href="https://ghuntley.com/signup/">subscribe</a> (free) and enter your email address to be notified when future blog posts ship.</p><figure><blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Have some personal news and an exciting announcement to share with you...<a href="https://t.co/BbKl6cWKeO">https://t.co/BbKl6cWKeO</a></p>— *void malloc(geoff, 🐣) (@GeoffreyHuntley) <a href="https://twitter.com/GeoffreyHuntley/status/1365067454494351364?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 25, 2021</a></blockquote>

</figure><figure><div><div><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/2021-02-12_7-03-15-1.jpg" width="2000" height="863" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/2021-02-12_7-03-15-1.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/2021-02-12_7-03-15-1.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1600/2021/02/2021-02-12_7-03-15-1.jpg 1600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w2400/2021/02/2021-02-12_7-03-15-1.jpg 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/2021-02-12_6-51-28-1.jpg" width="2000" height="875" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/2021-02-12_6-51-28-1.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/2021-02-12_6-51-28-1.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1600/2021/02/2021-02-12_6-51-28-1.jpg 1600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w2400/2021/02/2021-02-12_6-51-28-1.jpg 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/Photo_6553666_DJI_66_jpg_21669666_0_2020122385728_photo_original-2.jpg" width="1980" height="1485" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/Photo_6553666_DJI_66_jpg_21669666_0_2020122385728_photo_original-2.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/Photo_6553666_DJI_66_jpg_21669666_0_2020122385728_photo_original-2.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1600/2021/02/Photo_6553666_DJI_66_jpg_21669666_0_2020122385728_photo_original-2.jpg 1600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/Photo_6553666_DJI_66_jpg_21669666_0_2020122385728_photo_original-2.jpg 1980w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p></div><div><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/2021-02-12_7-00-57-1.jpg" width="2000" height="877" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/2021-02-12_7-00-57-1.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/2021-02-12_7-00-57-1.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1600/2021/02/2021-02-12_7-00-57-1.jpg 1600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w2400/2021/02/2021-02-12_7-00-57-1.jpg 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p><p><img src="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/2021/02/Photo_6554005_DJI_405_jpg_6288768_0_202121019728_photo_original-PANO-2.jpg" width="2000" height="1007" alt="" srcset="https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/Photo_6554005_DJI_405_jpg_6288768_0_202121019728_photo_original-PANO-2.jpg 600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/Photo_6554005_DJI_405_jpg_6288768_0_202121019728_photo_original-PANO-2.jpg 1000w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w1600/2021/02/Photo_6554005_DJI_405_jpg_6288768_0_202121019728_photo_original-PANO-2.jpg 1600w, https://ghuntley.com/content/images/size/w2400/2021/02/Photo_6554005_DJI_405_jpg_6288768_0_202121019728_photo_original-PANO-2.jpg 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></p></div></div></figure>
            </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ghuntley.com/a-new-chapter</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26284635</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 13:11:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Vim Guide for Advanced Users]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 546 | Comments 160 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26284618">thread link</a>) | @asicsp
<br/>
February 27, 2021 | https://thevaluable.dev/vim-advanced/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thevaluable.dev/vim-advanced/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
    <article>
        

        <section>
            
                <picture>
                    
                        <source srcset="https://thevaluable.dev/images/2021/02_vim_advanced/vim-advanced.webp" type="image/webp">
                    
                    <img src="https://thevaluable.dev/images/2021/02_vim_advanced/vim-advanced.jpg" alt="Vim for advanced users">
                </picture>
            

            <p>Welcome to the third part of this series aimed to help you unleash a power never seen on Earth using the Almighty Vim. If you don’t understand what’s happening in this article, I recommend you to read the previous ones of the series first:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://thevaluable.dev/vim-beginner/">Vim for beginners</a></li>
<li><a href="https://thevaluable.dev/vim-intermediate/">Vim for intermediate users</a></li>
</ol>
<p>We’ll see together in this article:</p>
<ul>
<li>Some nice keystrokes beginning with <code>g</code>.</li>
<li>What ranges are and how to use them.</li>
<li>The quickfix list and the location lists.</li>
<li>The marvelous substitute command.</li>
<li>The crazy useful <code>:global</code> (or <code>:g</code>) command.</li>
<li>What marks are and what you can do with them.</li>
<li>How to increase and decrease numbers with a single keystroke.</li>
<li>How to sort text with a nice command.</li>
</ul>
<p>But before going into the juicy content of this article, I’ve some recommendations for you, dear reader:</p>
<ol>
<li>Fire up your Vim and play around with the commands and keystrokes while reading. It’s the best way for you to remember everything which blew you away. You’ll then be able to be blown away whenever you like for the rest of your life.</li>
<li>Don’t use a cheatsheet; write your own as you read. It will allow you to come back easily to the commands you find the most useful for <em>your own needs</em>.</li>
</ol>
<p>Enough rambling. Let’s begin!</p>
<h2 id="useful-g-keystrokes">Useful “g” Keystrokes</h2>
<p>Let’s begin gently with a mixed bag of keystrokes starting with <code>g</code>. There are many of these “g” commands in Vim, and we already saw some of them in the previous articles. Can you recall them?</p>
<p>You can use these keystrokes in NORMAL mode:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>gf</code> - Edit the file located at the filepath under your cursor.
<ul>
<li>You can use <code>CTRL+W CTRL+F</code> to open the file in a new window.</li>
<li>It can open the URL under your cursor if you have the plugin <code>netrw</code>.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><code>gx</code> - Open the file located at the filepath under your cursor.
<ul>
<li>It will use the default application used by your OS for this filetype.</li>
<li>It works with URLs too. It will open your favorite browser and load the website.</li>
<li>It only works if you have the plugin <code>netrw</code>.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><code>gi</code> - Move to the last insertion you did and switch to INSERT mode.
<ul>
<li>Pretty useful if you stopped your editing to look at some other file.</li>
<li>It uses marks under the hood: more on that later in this article.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><code>gv</code> - Start VISUAL mode and use the selection made during the last VISUAL mode.</li>
<li><code>gn</code> - Select the match of your last search:
<ol>
<li>Move to the last searched match.</li>
<li>Switch to VISUAL mode (if you weren’t in VISUAL mode already).</li>
<li>Select the match.</li>
<li>You can continue to hit <code>n</code> (or <code>gn</code>) to select the area between the current match and the next match.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><code>gI</code> - Insert text at the beginning of the line, no matter what the first characters are.
<ul>
<li>The keystroke <code>I</code> insert text <em>just before the first non-blank characters</em> of the line.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>To try out <code>gf</code> and <code>gx</code>, you can write for example <code>https://www.google.com/</code> in Vim, place your cursor on it, and hit the keystrokes. Don’t forget the trailing slash in your URL.</p>
<p>You’ll soon discover an inconvenience with <code>gx</code>: when you use it on a filepath, Vim will hang till you close the file. That’s why I’ve created the following mapping you can add to your <code>.vimrc</code>:</p>
<pre><code>nnoremap gX :silent :execute
            \ "!xdg-open" expand('%:p:h') . "/" . expand("&lt;cfile&gt;") " &amp;"&lt;cr&gt;
</code></pre><p>It maps the keystroke <code>gX</code> to use <code>xdg-open</code>  with the filepath under your cursor. It will open the file with your favorite application <em>in the background</em>. The program <code>xdg-open</code> will only work on Linux-based systems; for MacOS, try <code>open</code> instead.</p>


  




    





  





<h2 id="ranges">Ranges</h2>
<p>Now that we’re done with the appetizers, let’s discover the first real dish of our Vim feast: the ranges. You can apply them to many commands, making them terribly powerful.</p>
<h3 id="basics">Basics</h3>
<p>In Vim’s help, every command accepting a range will have the string of characters <code>[range]</code> in front of them. Multiple line specifiers are possible, separated by commas <code>,</code>.</p>
<p>Here are the most interesting ranges you can use:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>&lt;number&gt;</code> - Any number <code>&lt;number&gt;</code> in your range refers to a line number.</li>
<li><code>.</code> - Represent the current line (often the default range).</li>
<li><code>$</code> - Represent the last line of the current buffer.</li>
<li><code>%</code> - Represent the entire file (same as <code>1,$</code>).</li>
<li><code>*</code> - Use the last selection you’ve made during the last VISUAL mode.</li>
</ul>
<p>For example, using the command <code>:d</code>:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>:1,40d</code> - Delete line 1 to 40 included.</li>
<li><code>:2,$d</code> - Delete every line from the second one till the end of the file.</li>
<li><code>:.,$d</code> - Delete every line from the current one till the end of the file.</li>
<li><code>:%d</code> - Delete every line.</li>
</ul>
<p>You can also do some arithmetic with ranges if you want. For example, let’s imagine your cursor is on the line 60: the range <code>.,.+10</code> will be equivalent to the range <code>60,70</code>.</p>
<h3 id="visual-mode-and-range">Visual Mode and Range</h3>
<p>If you switch to COMMAND-LINE mode after doing some selection in VISUAL mode, you’ll see these two symbols appearing: <code>'&lt;</code> and <code>'&gt;</code> with a comma <code>,</code> in between. This is a range too!</p>
<p>The symbols <code>'&lt;</code> represents the first line you’ve selected and <code>'&gt;</code> the last line. Each of these are marks; again, we’ll see more about marks below.</p>
<p>In practice, the ranges <code>'&lt;,'&gt;</code> and <code>*</code> are synonym, but you’ll have more flexibility with the first. For example, you can execute a command from the first line you’ve selected till the end of the file with the range <code>'&lt;,$</code>.</p>


  




    





  

<div>
    
    <div>
         <ul>
<li><code>:help [range]</code></li>
<li><code>:help v_:</code></li>
<li><code>:help '&lt;</code></li>
<li><code>:help '&gt;</code></li>
</ul>
 
    </div>
</div>



<h2 id="vims-quickfix-and-location-list">Vim’s Quickfix And Location List</h2>
<p>Now, let’s talk about a very useful data structure available in Vim, the quickfix list.</p>
<p>Don’t confuse the quickfix list and the quickfix window: these are two different entities. The first is a data structure, the second can display this data structure.</p>
<h3 id="quickfix-lists">Quickfix Lists</h3>
<p>You can think of a quickfix list as a set of positions in one or multiple files.</p>
<h4 id="basics-1">Basics</h4>
<p>Let’s take an example: what happens if you run the command <code>:vimgrep hello *</code>?</p>
<ol>
<li>It will search the pattern “hello” in every file of your working directory.</li>
<li>It will populate a quickfix list with every position matching your pattern “hello”.</li>
<li>It will move your cursor to the first position of the quickfix list.</li>
</ol>
<p>If you want to know more about vimgrep and other tools you can search with, I <a href="https://thevaluable.dev/vim-search-find-replace/">wrote an article about that</a>. Other commands (like <code>:make</code> or <code>:grep</code>) also populate automatically a quickfix list.</p>
<p>Let’s expand the mystery around marks: these positions in the quickfix list are in fact hidden mark!</p>
<p>The quickfix list is often used to display specific errors in a codebase, often spit out from a compiler or a linter (via the command <code>:make</code> for example), but not only, as we just saw. I call the entries of a quickfix list “positions” to be more general, but sometimes Vim’s help will refer to them as “errors”. Don’t be confused: it’s the same idea.</p>
<p>Among other conditions, a quickfix list entry needs to have a filename for you to be able to jump to its position. Otherwise, the entry doesn’t point to anything. Difficult to move to anything.</p>
<h4 id="useful-commands">Useful Commands</h4>
<p>Here are the commands you can use to navigate through the current quickfix list:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>:cl</code> or <code>:clist</code> - Display all valid entries of the current quickfix list. You can add a range as argument (only numbers).</li>
<li><code>:cc &lt;number&gt;</code> - Move to the <code>&lt;number&gt;</code>th entry of the current quickfix list.</li>
<li><code>:cnext</code> or <code>:cn</code> - Move to the next entry of the current quickfix list.</li>
<li><code>:cprevious</code> or <code>:cp</code> - Move to the previous entry of the current quickfix list.</li>
<li><code>:cfirst</code> or <code>:cfir</code> - Move to the first entry of the current quickfix list.</li>
<li><code>:clast</code> or <code>:clas</code> - Move to the last entry of the current quickfix list.</li>
</ul>
<p>Here are additional commands which make quickfix lists really powerful:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>:cdo &lt;cmd&gt;</code> - Execute a command <code>&lt;cmd&gt;</code> on each valid entry of the current quickfix list.</li>
<li><code>:cexpr &lt;expr&gt;</code> or <code>:cex &lt;expr&gt;</code> - Create a quickfix list using the result of evaluating the Vimscript expression <code>&lt;expr&gt;</code>.</li>
<li><code>:caddexpr &lt;expr&gt;</code> or <code>:cadde &lt;expr&gt;</code> - Appends the result of evaluating the Vimscript expression <code>&lt;expr&gt;</code> to the current quickfix list.</li>
</ul>
<p>If you have no clue how to use the last two commands, you can do for example:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>:cex []</code> - Empty the current quickfix list.</li>
<li><code>:cex system("&lt;cmd&gt;")</code> - Populate your quickfix list with any shell command <code>&lt;cmd&gt;</code>. You can try it with <code>ls</code> for example.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="the-quickfix-window">The Quickfix Window</h3>
<p>What about displaying the current quickfix list in a new buffer? You can do that with the following command:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>:copen</code> or <code>:cope</code> - Open a window (with a special buffer) to show the current quickfix list.</li>
</ul>
<p>You can only have one quickfix window open. To move to the position of the selected entry of the quickfix list in the quickfix window, hit <code>ENTER</code> or <code>.cc</code>.</p>
<h3 id="location-lists">Location Lists</h3>
<p>A location list is similar to a quickfix list, except that the first is local to a window and the second is global to your Vim instance. In other words, you can have multiple location lists available at the same time (one per window open), but you can only have access to one quickfix list.</p>
<p>The commands for location lists are similar to the ones for the quickfix lists; often, you’ll only have to replace the first <code>c</code> (qui<code>c</code>fix) of the command with <code>l</code> (<code>l</code>ocation).</p>
<p>For example:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>:lli</code> or <code>:llist</code> - Display all valid entries of the current location list. You can add a range as argument (only numbers).</li>
<li><code>:ll &lt;number&gt;</code> - Move to the entry <code>&lt;number&gt;</code> of the current location list.</li>
<li><code>:lnext</code> or <code>:lne</code> - Move to the next entry of the current quickfix list.</li>
</ul>
<p>To populate your location list you can also use the commands <code>:lvimgrep</code> or <code>:lmake</code> for example.</p>
<p>Often, Vim users will use the quickfix list for anything related to errors in their codebase, and the location list for search results. But it’s up to you at the end of the day. With Vim, you’re the master of your destiny.</p>


  




    





  

<div>
    
    <div>
         <ul>
<li><code>:help quickfix</code></li>
<li><code>:help quickfix-window</code></li>
<li><code>:help location-list</code></li>
<li><code>:help location-list-window</code></li>
<li><code>:help expr</code></li>
<li><code>:help system()</code></li>
</ul>
 
    </div>
</div>



<h2 id="vims-registers">Vim’s Registers</h2>
<p>The registers are another big dish in our Vim feast. You can think of registers as places where you can read or write some text. I like to think about them as Vim’s clipboards.</p>
<h3 id="specifying-a-register">Specifying a Register</h3>
<p>Here’s a command and a NORMAL mode keystroke to display and <em>specify</em> registers:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>:registers</code> or <code>:reg</code> - Display the content of your registers.</li>
<li><code>"&lt;reg&gt;</code> - This keystroke <em>specif…</em></li></ul></section></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://thevaluable.dev/vim-advanced/">https://thevaluable.dev/vim-advanced/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thevaluable.dev/vim-advanced/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26284618</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 13:06:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[$38M USD moved for half a penny]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 29 | Comments 62 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26284143">thread link</a>) | @hggh
<br/>
February 27, 2021 | https://nitter.42l.fr/WhaleAlertBch/status/1365427359264956416 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nitter.42l.fr/WhaleAlertBch/status/1365427359264956416">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div>
                        <h2>Transaction c33e23505c95f1cf55e3133d423500686b1c809d3de963ddf4e1257f924b7be2 - Bitcoin Cash (BCH)...</h2>
                        <p>Providing block, transaction, and address data for the BCH and BTC chains.</p>
                        <p><span>explorer.bitcoin.com</span>
                      </p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nitter.42l.fr/WhaleAlertBch/status/1365427359264956416</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26284143</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 11:26:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Bupstash Garbage Collector]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 41 | Comments 10 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26282771">thread link</a>) | @andrewchambers
<br/>
February 26, 2021 | https://acha.ninja/blog/the_bupstash_garbage_collector/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://acha.ninja/blog/the_bupstash_garbage_collector/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
				<h2 id="overview">Overview</h2>
<p>My backup tool <a href="https://github.com/andrewchambers/bupstash">bupstash</a> stores backups in a repository as an evergrowing set of
encrypted data trees which use content addressing and structural sharing
to deduplicate data. In order to delete unused backups we need to do something very similar to how
many programming languages free unreferenced memory - garbage collection. This post will
explain the evolution and implementation of the garbage collector in bupstash for the curious.</p>
<h2 id="stop-mark-and-sweep">Stop, mark and sweep.</h2>
<p>The initial version of the bupstash garbage collector was a naive stop-the-world
garbage collector. It walks all backup data trees creating a set of reachable data chunks
by address and then deletes unreachable data.</p>
<p>The algorithm can be described as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Stop the world.</li>
<li>Mark.</li>
<li>Sweep.</li>
<li>Restart the world.</li>
</ul>
<p>Here is the pseudo code:</p>
<pre><code>lock_repository()
reachable_addresses = empty_set()

for data_tree in all_backups():
  
  work_list = new_work_list_from_backup(data_tree.root_address)
  
  until work_list.is_empty():
    
    node_height, node_address = work_list.pop()
    reachable_addresses.add(node_address)
    
    if node_height != 0:
      add_child_nodes_to_worklist(work_list, node_address)

for chunk_address in repository:
  if not reachable_addresses.has(chunk_address):
    delete_chunk(chunk_address)

unlock_repository()
</code></pre><p>This algorithm is short and sweet, but if the repository is very large our repository becomes unavailable
for a potentially long time. The next version shortens the downtime of the repository significantly.</p>
<h2 id="mark-stop-mark-and-sweep">Mark, stop, mark and sweep.</h2>
<p>The bupstash v0.6.4 garbage collector takes advantage of two facts:</p>
<ul>
<li>Because many backups share data with each other, we can memoize the walk phase to skip work.</li>
<li>Because backups are immutable while the repository is unlocked, we can walk most of them without
stopping the world.</li>
</ul>
<p>This time we walk the repository without the repository locked, then lock it and walk
the repository again using our memoization to quickly complete the job. If any new backups
appeared during our first walk, we are guaranteed to mark them now that the repository lock is held. Doing the majority of the slow mark phase without locking the repository greatly increases
the repository availability for other operations.</p>
<p>The algorithm can be described as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Memoized mark repository.</li>
<li>Stop the world.</li>
<li>Memoized mark repository.</li>
<li>Sweep.</li>
<li>Restart the world.</li>
</ul>
<p>Here is the pseudo code:</p>
<pre><code>walked_trees = empty_set()
reachable_addresses = empty_set()

func walk_repository():

  for data_tree in all_backups():

    if walked_trees.has(data_tree):
      continue

    walked_trees.add(data_tree)
    
    work_list = new_work_list_from_backup(data_tree.root_address)
    
    until work_list.is_empty():
      
      node_height, node_address = work_list.pop()
      already_walked = reachable_addresses.has(node_address)
      reachable_addresses.add(node_address)
      
      if node_height != 0 and not already_walked:
        add_child_nodes_to_worklist(work_list, node_address)

walk_repository()
lock_repository()
walk_repository()

for chunk_address in repository:
  if not reachable_addresses.has(chunk_address):
    delete_chunk(chunk_address)

unlock_repository()
</code></pre><h2 id="mark-stop-mark-bloom-adjust-and-sweep">Mark, stop, mark, bloom adjust, and sweep</h2>
<p>The next version of the garbage collector is a WIP unreleased version.</p>
<p>In bupstash each data chunk address is 32 bytes, which means we need at least 32 bytes of RAM per chunk in the repository to successfully perform a garbage collection. For a repository containing a 100 million chunks or
more this could easily exhaust memory on a busy or small system.</p>
<p>If we are willing to accept a very low probability of retaining some extra data, we can reduce this down
to a few <em>bits</em> per chunk reducing memory usage by 64x or more.
To do this we use a probabilistic data structure called a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bloom_filter">bloom filter</a> to track reachable addresses.</p>
<p>Bloom filters have two downsides:</p>
<ul>
<li>They can have false positives. For us this means we might keep a data chunk by accident we could have actually freed.</li>
<li>We must presize them. They cannot grow if we got the size wrong.</li>
</ul>
<p>Luckily for us these downsides are not bad:</p>
<ul>
<li>Because memory use is so low per address, we can generously size our bloom filter reducing false positives to less than one percent, even for large repositories.</li>
<li>We can easily detect when a bloom filter gets overly full and produces many false positives, and thus adjust it’s size for future garbage collections.</li>
</ul>
<p>As a bonus, the bupstash implementation of a bloom filter is actually simpler than a hash table, with the implemenation
weighing in at around 30 lines of code plus tests and helpers.</p>
<p>The algorithm can be described as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Memoized mark repository.</li>
<li>Stop the world.</li>
<li>Memoized mark the repository.</li>
<li>Adjust bloom filter size.</li>
<li>Sweep.</li>
<li>Restart the world.</li>
</ul>
<p>Here is the pseudo code:</p>
<pre><code>walked_trees = empty_set()
walked_addresses = empty_cache()
reachable_addresses = empty_bloom_filter(repository_bloom_size())

func walk_repository():

  for data_tree in all_backups():

    if walked_trees.has(data_tree):
      continue

    walked_trees.add(data_tree)
    work_list = new_work_list_from_backup(data_tree.root_address)
    
    until work_list.is_empty():
      
      node_height, node_address = work_list.pop()
      already_walked = walked_addresses.has(node_address)
      reachable_addresses.add(node_address)
      walked_addresses.add(node_address)
      
      if node_height != 0 and not already_walked:
        add_child_nodes_to_worklist(work_list, node_address)

walk_repository()
lock_repository()
walk_repository()

if bloom_filter_overutilized(reachable_addresses):
  increase_bloom_filter_size_for_next_gc()
else if bloom_filter_underutilized(reachable_addresses):
  decrease_bloom_filter_size_for_next_gc()

for chunk_address in repository:
  if not reachable_addresses.has(chunk_address):
    delete_chunk(chunk_address)

unlock_repository()
</code></pre><p>One thing to note about this implementation is that because the bloom filter has false positives we can not use it to skip processing addresses, instead
we must introduce a new cache for this purpose. A cache also lets us put a fixed upper bound on memory usage for large repositories.</p>
<p>Overall for large repositories, the addition of a bloom filter reduces ram requirements from the gigabyte range down to tens of megabytes while increasing the repository size by only a fraction of a percent.</p>

<p>The bupstash garbage collector tries hard to keep the repository avaliable as long
as possible while also providing excellent performance with a small memory profile. If you are implementing
a content addressed storage system, this post will hopefully provide you with some new ideas.</p>
<p>In the future bupstash could follow the same path as programming language garbage collectors to find more improvements:</p>
<ul>
<li>Parallelism in the mark phase.</li>
<li>Parallelism in the sweep phase.</li>
<li>Incremental collection.</li>
<li>Object generations.</li>
<li>Write barriers</li>
<li>Yet to be invented techniques…</li>
</ul>
<p>As always, thanks for reading and please feel free to give <a href="https://github.com/andrewchambers/bupstash">bupstash</a> a try.</p>

			</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://acha.ninja/blog/the_bupstash_garbage_collector/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26282771</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 04:59:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Do farmers have the right to repair their own equipment?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 52 | Comments 39 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26282642">thread link</a>) | @curmudgeon22
<br/>
February 26, 2021 | https://www.albertafarmexpress.ca/news/do-farmers-have-the-right-to-repair-their-own-equipment/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.albertafarmexpress.ca/news/do-farmers-have-the-right-to-repair-their-own-equipment/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<div>
<p><span><span>Reading Time: </span> <span>5</span> <span>minutes</span></span></p><p>It’s a story that’s becoming more and more common.</p>
<p>You’re smack dab in the middle of harvest and an error code appears on your combine’s monitor. A call to the dealership results in a long wait for a technician to come out, with anxiety rising with every passing hour because priceless harvesting time is being lost or, worse, nasty weather is moving in.</p>
<p>Then when the technician gets to your farm, he determines what is needed is to reset (or ‘flash’) the onboard computer.</p>
<p>That happened to Cole Siegle last fall when he was harvesting canola, leaving the Fairview-area producer to wonder why he can’t have access to the same diagnostic tools.</p>
<div id="attachment_133445"><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.albertafarmexpress.ca/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/22120509/repair-rights1-siegle-supplied-150x150.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="150" srcset="https://static.albertafarmexpress.ca/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/22120509/repair-rights1-siegle-supplied-150x150.jpg 150w, https://static.albertafarmexpress.ca/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/22120509/repair-rights1-siegle-supplied.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px"></p><p>Cole Siegle.<br><small><i>photo:</i><span> Supplied </span></small></p></div>
<p>“If I could have done that myself or been able to use a mechanic or a technician who’s closer to me, our downtime could have gone from six hours to two hours,” he said. “That four hours could have been the difference between getting&nbsp;a crop off before the snow or not.”</p>
<p>But these days it’s dealerships — via sales and service agreements with manufacturers — that have legal access to these diagnostic tools. So when an error message pops up, farmers and independent mechanics are out in the cold, sometimes literally.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Read more: <a href="https://www.albertafarmexpress.ca/news/connectivity-grey-under-new-trade-agreement/">Connectivity ‘grey’ under new trade agreement</a></strong></li>
<li><strong>Read more: <a href="https://www.albertafarmexpress.ca/news/remote-diagnostics-blocked-by-poor-internet-on-farms/">Remote diagnostics blocked by poor internet on farms</a></strong></li>

</ul>
<p>“As a producer I think we need access to these diagnostic tools,” said Siegle. “If (manufacturers) want to continue to build equipment like this that’s fine, but we need access to the laptops with the programs that we can plug into our equipment so we can buy whatever part we need.”</p>
<p>Equipment manufacturers make a lot of repair information public, including what codes mean, but giving access to proprietary tools raises several issues, said John Schmeiser, CEO of the Western Equipment Dealers Association.</p>
<p>The hardware and software Siegle and other farmers wish to acquire for repair purposes can also be used to modify equipment to the detriment of machinery, warranties, the lawfulness of their operations and even their own safety, he said.</p>
<p>“I applaud the manufacturers that put a lot of stuff online&nbsp;like parts, service manuals and operational guides. But it’s a slippery slope,” said Schmeiser.</p>
<p>“When you provide special tools to somebody outside a controlled environment like the manufacturer/dealer&nbsp;relationship, that opens the door for illegal modification. They lose that control when they provide&nbsp;diagnostic or special tools to a third-party retailer with whom they don’t have the same sales and services agreement.”</p>
<h2>Repair versus modify</h2>
<p>‘Right to repair’ is a term being thrown around a lot in ag circles today, but it means different things to different people.</p>
<p>For Siegle and other like-minded producers, it means the right to either repair equipment themselves or hire an unaffiliated local mechanic — just as farmers have done throughout the history of mechanized agriculture.</p>
<div id="attachment_133446"><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.albertafarmexpress.ca/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/22120516/SchmeiserJohn-150x150.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="150" srcset="https://static.albertafarmexpress.ca/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/22120516/SchmeiserJohn-150x150.jpg 150w, https://static.albertafarmexpress.ca/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/22120516/SchmeiserJohn.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px"></p><p>John Schmeiser.<br><small><i>photo:</i><span> Supplied </span></small></p></div>
<p>But Schmeiser argues that farmers’ right to repair is already entrenched in law in many jurisdictions (including Alberta) as long as the owner is using the equipment for its intended purpose and doesn’t violate manufacturer standards.</p>
<p>The right to repair (R2R) movement (which started in the tech sphere but expanded to other areas, such as ag equipment) is actually a front for promoting the ‘right to modify,’ he said.</p>
<p>Often that means making modifications to bypass environmental controls in order to boost vehicle horsepower.</p>

<p>“There are over 25 states that had R2R bills introduced — every one impacting farm equipment has been defeated,” said Schmeiser. “They haven’t passed&nbsp;because as the state representatives were hearing the rationale coming from R2R advocates, they were finding out that what they were really looking for is to modify the equipment in a manner where&nbsp;it can get around emission standards and violate U.S. Environmental Protection Agency laws and regulations.”</p>
<h2>DEF delete and chipping</h2>
<p>There are two specific actions that concern Schmeiser’s association (a Missouri-based advocacy group for equipment dealerships with a Canadian headquarters in Calgary).</p>
<p>One is circumventing Diesel Exhaust Fluid (or DEF) emissions systems using grey-market ‘DEF delete’ kits to boost horsepower on tractors and combines. Another is ‘chipping’ or ‘tuning,’ which usually refers to adding a specific chip to increase horsepower.</p>
<p>Bypassing emissions control systems contravenes the Canadian Environmental Protection Act, leaving producers open to fines, said Schmeiser, adding he was unsure of the Canadian penalties but breaches of similar U.S. laws have produced fines in excess of $300,000.</p>
<p>Part of the problem is that not everyone knows this practice is illegal. Another is it comes with a host of potential risks including damaged equipment, voided warranties, reduced trade-in value, insurance cancellation and even safety, he said.</p>
<p>“We have seen an unusual number of combine fires this (past) year,” said Schmeiser.</p>
<p>“Now, we have had some dry conditions but in some of those cases the combines were running hotter (due to alterations).</p>

<p>“The insurance company will look at it from the standpoint that you have altered your combine away from the manufacturer’s original standards and you are going to be denied insurance coverage in a situation like that.”</p>
<p>But Siegle isn’t convinced.</p>
<p>He said he has no interest in making such modifications to his equipment and suggested it’s a straw man argument from manufacturing and dealership interests seeking exclusive control over the diagnostic tools.</p>
<p>The kind of modification Siegle is concerned about losing is the legal ability to place, for example, a third-party manufacturer’s custom header on a John Deere combine. Specifically, he worries about big manufacturers denying third-party companies the codes required for an implement to interact with a tractor or combine.</p>
<p>Schmeiser said this isn’t considered modification but rather interoperability or connectivity: A third party designing an implement to attach to another manufacturer’s product. This is a long-standing tradition in the manufacturing and dealership industries that few if anyone has any interest in ceasing, he said (see accompanying story).</p>
<h2>The business aspect</h2>
<p>All of this still does not answer Siegle’s fundamental question: Why can’t I — or mechanics unaffiliated with specific manufacturers — have all the tools required to diagnose and fix a mechanical problem?</p>
<p>In the past it was relatively easy for mechanically minded producers and unaffiliated mechanics to repair machinery because it ran on tried-and-traditional engineering principles. This is still by and large the case, said Schmeiser, adding 95 per cent of equipment issues can still be fixed mechanically.</p>
<p>He said he understands the frustration farmers feel by not having diagnostic tools at their fingertips. But at the same time dealerships have rights as well, especially when one considers the considerable training and expense needed to obtain service contracts with manufacturers.</p>
<p>“What the farmer is speaking to is the frustration of being down. He wants to get up and running as quickly as possible. We get that,” said Schmeiser.</p>
<p>“But the moment the manufacturers start providing special tools or diagnostics&nbsp;equipment to businesses that are outside of their dealer contracts, doesn’t that diminish the value of the contract in the dealer’s eyes as well?… So what’s the incentive for the manufacturer&nbsp;to provide special tools or even service manuals to a third party that would be competing with somebody they have a contractual relationship with&nbsp;(and) who is also making a substantial financial investment to be the representative for the manufacturer?”</p> </div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.albertafarmexpress.ca/news/do-farmers-have-the-right-to-repair-their-own-equipment/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26282642</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 04:40:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Mining Ethereum on M1 Mac GPU]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 150 | Comments 123 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26281864">thread link</a>) | @gyf304
<br/>
February 26, 2021 | https://blog.yifangu.com/2021/02/26/mining-ethereum-on-a-m1-mac-gpu/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.yifangu.com/2021/02/26/mining-ethereum-on-a-m1-mac-gpu/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">

	<section id="primary">
		<main id="main">

			
<article id="post-444">

	

	
	<div>
		
<p>TL;DR: It’s possible to mine Ethereum on a M1 Mac GPU. Hashrate is about 2Mh/s.</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="452" data-permalink="https://blog.yifangu.com/image-1-5/" data-orig-file="https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2021/02/image-1.png" data-orig-size="1338,754" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="image-1" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2021/02/image-1.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2021/02/image-1.png?w=750" src="https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2021/02/image-1.png?w=1024" alt="" srcset="https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2021/02/image-1.png?w=1024 1024w, https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2021/02/image-1.png?w=150 150w, https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2021/02/image-1.png?w=300 300w, https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2021/02/image-1.png?w=768 768w, https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2021/02/image-1.png 1338w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption>Mining on a M1 Mac</figcaption></figure>



<p>I’ve had my M1 MacBook Air for a bit of time now, and I also recently started mining Ethereum. I can’t help asking myself: What’s Ethereum mining performance like on a M1 Mac?</p>



<p>The obvious thing to do first is to run the off-the-shelf <code>ethminer</code>, which gives the following error:</p>



<pre><code>ethminer 0.19.0-alpha.0
Build: darwin/release/appleclang

Unrecognized platform Apple
Error: No usable mining devices found</code></pre>



<p>Not good. Apparently Apple GPUs are not whitelisted in ethminer. That should be easy to fix. Relevant lines are in <code>libethash-cl/CLMiner.cpp</code>, and I added Apple GPUs to the whitelist, pretending it’s an Intel GPU.</p>



<p>Then <code>boost</code> won’t compile since it’s trying to compile with a <code>-fcoalesce-templates</code> argument, which doesn’t exist in recent clang versions. So I have to update <code>boost</code> to the latest version, and fix relevant <code>asio</code> code since <code>ethminer</code> was using deprecated <code>asio</code> APIs.</p>



<p>I also need to upgrade OpenSSL to the latest version to have it support darwin + arm64.</p>



<p>After getting everything to compile. Here’s the result:</p>



<pre><code>ethminer 0.19.0-17+commit.ce52c740.dirty
Build: darwin/release/appleclang

 i 19:51:36          Configured pool eth-us-east1.nanopool.org:9999
 i 19:51:36          Selected pool eth-us-east1.nanopool.org:9999
 i 19:51:36          Connection remotely closed by eth-us-east1.nanopool.org
 i 19:51:36          Stratum mode : EthereumStratum/1.0.0 (NiceHash)
 i 19:51:36          Established connection to eth-us-east1.nanopool.org [144.217.14.139:9999]
 i 19:51:36          Spinning up miners...
cl 19:51:36 cl-0     Using Device : Intel GPU 0.0 Apple M1 OpenCL 1.2  Memory : 10.67 GB (11453251584 B)
 i 19:51:36          Extranonce set to 778d
 i 19:51:36          Extranonce set to 778d
 i 19:51:36          Authorized worker [REDACTED]
 i 19:51:36          Epoch : 397 Difficulty : 10.00 Gh
 i 19:51:36          Job: c7fc5311… eth-us-east1.nanopool.org [144.217.14.139:9999]
cl 19:51:38 cl-0     Generating split DAG + Light (total): 4.10 GB
 i 19:51:38          Job: 40a57756… eth-us-east1.nanopool.org [144.217.14.139:9999]
cl 19:51:38 cl-0     OpenCL kernel
cl 19:51:38 cl-0     Creating DAG buffer, size: 4.10 GB, free: 6.57 GB
cl 19:51:38 cl-0     Creating light cache buffer, size: 65.62 MB
cl 19:51:38 cl-0     Loading kernels
cl 19:51:38 cl-0     Creating buffer for header.
cl 19:51:38 cl-0     Creating mining buffer
 m 19:51:41          0:00 A0 0.00 h - cl0 0.00
 i 19:51:42          Job: 077b62f6… eth-us-east1.nanopool.org [144.217.14.139:9999]
 m 19:51:46          0:00 A0 0.00 h - cl0 0.00
 i 19:51:46          Job: 2835839e… eth-us-east1.nanopool.org [144.217.14.139:9999]
 m 19:51:51          0:00 A0 0.00 h - cl0 0.00
 m 19:51:56          0:00 A0 0.00 h - cl0 0.00
 i 19:51:57          Job: 97f724e7… eth-us-east1.nanopool.org [144.217.14.139:9999]
 m 19:52:01          0:00 A0 0.00 h - cl0 0.00
 m 19:52:06          0:00 A0 0.00 h - cl0 0.00
 m 19:52:11          0:00 A0 0.00 h - cl0 0.00
 m 19:52:16          0:00 A0 0.00 h - cl0 0.00
 i 19:52:16          Job: 54df0504… eth-us-east1.nanopool.org [144.217.14.139:9999]
 m 19:52:21          0:00 A0 0.00 h - cl0 0.00
cl 19:52:22 cl-0     4.10 GB of DAG data generated in 44,060 ms.
 m 19:52:26          0:00 A0 184.16 Kh - cl0 184.16
 m 19:52:31          0:00 A0 1.96 Mh - cl0 1.96
 m 19:52:36          0:01 A0 1.98 Mh - cl0 1.98
 i 19:52:39          Job: d3b1da5e… eth-us-east1.nanopool.org [144.217.14.139:9999]
 m 19:52:41          0:01 A0 1.99 Mh - cl0 1.99
cl 19:52:43 cl-0     Job: 54df0504… Sol: 0x778d000001d14c71
 i 19:52:43          **Accepted 150 ms. eth-us-east1.nanopool.org [144.217.14.139:9999]
 m 19:52:46          0:01 A1 1.95 Mh - cl0 1.95
 m 19:52:51          0:01 A1 2.07 Mh - cl0 2.07
 m 19:52:56          0:01 A1 2.00 Mh - cl0 2.00
 m 19:53:01          0:01 A1 1.98 Mh - cl0 1.98
 i 19:53:01          Job: ccc2b97f… eth-us-east1.nanopool.org [144.217.14.139:9999]
 m 19:53:06          0:01 A1 1.97 Mh - cl0 1.97
 i 19:53:07          Job: 23919d82… eth-us-east1.nanopool.org [144.217.14.139:9999]
^C i 19:53:10 main     Got interrupt ...
 i 19:53:10 main     Disconnected from eth-us-east1.nanopool.org [144.217.14.139:9999]
 i 19:53:10 main     Shutting down miners...
 i 19:53:16 main     Terminated!</code></pre>



<p>Code is available at <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://github.com/gyf304/ethminer-m1" target="_blank">https://github.com/gyf304/ethminer-m1</a></p>



<h2>Is it worth it?</h2>



<p>Um. Not really. At current Ethereum prices (2021-02-26), it generates $0.14 of profit per day. It’s still a profit, but very miniscule.</p>
	</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->

			<!-- .author-bio -->
	
</article><!-- #post-${ID} -->

	<nav role="navigation" aria-label="Posts">
		<h2>Post navigation</h2>
		
	</nav>
<!-- #comments -->

		</main><!-- #main -->
	</section><!-- #primary -->


	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.yifangu.com/2021/02/26/mining-ethereum-on-a-m1-mac-gpu/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26281864</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 01:32:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
