<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 02:00:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 02:00:50 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Beating Up on Qsort (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 72 | Comments 10 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25783617">thread link</a>) | @tjalfi
<br/>
January 14, 2021 | https://travisdowns.github.io/blog/2019/05/22/sorting.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://travisdowns.github.io/blog/2019/05/22/sorting.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>Recently, Daniel Lemire <a href="https://lemire.me/blog/2019/05/07/almost-picking-n-distinct-numbers-at-random/">tackled the topic</a> of selecting N <em>distinct</em> numbers at random. In the case we want sorted output, an obvious solution presents itself: sorting randomly chosen values and de-duplicating the list, which is easy since identical values are now adjacent.<sup id="fnref:distinct" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:distinct">1</a></sup></p>

<p>While Daniel suggests a clever method of avoiding a sort entirely<sup id="fnref:danmethod" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:danmethod">2</a></sup>, I’m also interested in they <em>why</em> for the underlying performace of the sort method: it takes more than 100 ns per element, which means 100s of CPU clock cycles and usually even more instructions than that (on a superscalar processor)! As a sanity check, a quick benchmark (<code>perf record ./bench &amp;&amp; perf report</code>) shows that more than 90% of the time spent in this approach is in the sorting routine, <a href="https://devdocs.io/c/algorithm/qsort">qsort</a> - so we are right to focus on this step, rather than say the de-duplication step or the initial random number generation. This naturally, this raises the question: how fast is qsort when it comes to sorting integers and can we do better?</p>

<p>All of the code for this post <a href="https://github.com/travisdowns/sort-bench">is available on GitHub</a>, so if you’d like to follow along with the code open in an editor, go right ahead (warning: there are obviously some spoilers if you dig through the code first).</p>

<h2 id="benchmarking-qsort">Benchmarking Qsort</h2>

<p>First, let’s take a look at what <code>qsort</code> is doing, to see if there is any delicous low-hanging performance fruit. We use <code>perf record ./bench qsort</code> to capture profiling data, and <code>perf report --stdio</code> to print a summary<sup id="fnref:long-tail" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:long-tail">3</a></sup>:</p>

<div><div><pre><code># Samples: 101K of event 'cycles:ppp'
# Event count (approx.): 65312285835
#
# Overhead  Command  Shared Object      Symbol
# ........  .......  .................  ..............................................
#
    64.90%  bench    libc-2.23.so       [.] msort_with_tmp.part.0
    21.45%  bench    bench              [.] compare_uint64_t
     8.65%  bench    libc-2.23.so       [.] __memcpy_sse2
     0.87%  bench    libc-2.23.so       [.] __memcpy_avx_unaligned
     0.83%  bench    bench              [.] main
     0.41%  bench    [kernel.kallsyms]  [k] clear_page_erms
     0.34%  bench    [kernel.kallsyms]  [k] native_irq_return_iret
     0.31%  bench    bench              [.] bench_one
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The assembly for the biggest offender, <code>msort_with_tmp</code> looks like this<sup id="fnref:annotate-command" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:annotate-command">4</a></sup> :</p>

<div><div><pre><code> Percent | Address      | Disassembly
--------------------------------------------------
   30.55 :   39200:       mov    rax,QWORD PTR [r15]
    0.61 :   39203:       sub    rbp,0x1
    0.52 :   39207:       add    r15,0x8
    7.30 :   3920b:       mov    QWORD PTR [rbx],rax
    0.39 :   3920e:       add    rbx,0x8
    0.07 :   39212:       test   r12,r12
    0.09 :   39215:       je     390e0   ; merge finished
    1.11 :   3921b:       test   rbp,rbp
    0.01 :   3921e:       je     390e0   ; merge finished
    5.24 :   39224:       mov    rdx,QWORD PTR [rsp+0x8]
    0.42 :   39229:       mov    rsi,r15
    0.19 :   3922c:       mov    rdi,r13
    6.08 :   3922f:       call   r14
    0.59 :   39232:       test   eax,eax
    3.52 :   39234:       jg     39200
   32.69 :   39236:       mov    rax,QWORD PTR [r13+0x0]
    1.31 :   3923a:       sub    r12,0x1
    1.01 :   3923e:       add    r13,0x8
    1.09 :   39242:       jmp    3920b &lt;bsearch@@GLIBC_2.2.5+0x205b&gt;
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Depending on your level of assembly reading skill, it may not be obvious, but this is basically a classic merge routine: it is merging two lists by comparing the top elements of each list (pointed to by <code>r13</code> and <code>r15</code>), and then storing the smaller element (the line <code>QWORD PTR [rbx],rax</code>) and loading the next element from that list. There are also two checks for termination (<code>test   r12,r12</code> and <code>test   rbp,rbp</code>). This hot loop corresponds directly to this code from <code>glibc</code> (from the file<code>msort.c</code><sup id="fnref:msort-note" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:msort-note">5</a></sup>) :</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>while</span> <span>(</span><span>n1</span> <span>&gt;</span> <span>0</span> <span>&amp;&amp;</span> <span>n2</span> <span>&gt;</span> <span>0</span><span>)</span>
<span>{</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>((</span><span>*</span><span>cmp</span><span>)</span> <span>(</span><span>b1</span><span>,</span> <span>b2</span><span>,</span> <span>arg</span><span>)</span> <span>&lt;=</span> <span>0</span><span>)</span>
    <span>{</span>
        <span>*</span><span>(</span><span>uint64_t</span> <span>*</span><span>)</span> <span>tmp</span> <span>=</span> <span>*</span><span>(</span><span>uint64_t</span> <span>*</span><span>)</span> <span>b1</span><span>;</span>
        <span>b1</span> <span>+=</span> <span>sizeof</span> <span>(</span><span>uint64_t</span><span>);</span>
        <span>--</span><span>n1</span><span>;</span>
    <span>}</span>
    <span>else</span>
    <span>{</span>
        <span>*</span><span>(</span><span>uint64_t</span> <span>*</span><span>)</span> <span>tmp</span> <span>=</span> <span>*</span><span>(</span><span>uint64_t</span> <span>*</span><span>)</span> <span>b2</span><span>;</span>
        <span>b2</span> <span>+=</span> <span>sizeof</span> <span>(</span><span>uint64_t</span><span>);</span>
        <span>--</span><span>n2</span><span>;</span>
    <span>}</span>
    <span>tmp</span> <span>+=</span> <span>sizeof</span> <span>(</span><span>uint64_t</span><span>);</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This loop suffers heavily from branch mispredictions, since the “which element is larger” branch is highly unpredictable (at least for random-looking input data). Indeed, we see roughly 128 million mispredicts while sorting ~11 million elements: close to 12 mispredicts per element.</p>

<p>We also note the presence of the indirect call at the <code>call r14</code> line. This corresponds to the <code>(*cmp) (b1, b2, arg)</code> expression in the source: it is calling the user provided comparator function through a function pointer. Since the <code>qsort()</code> code is compiled ahead of time and is found inside the shared libc binary, there is no chance that the comparator, passed as a function pointer, can be inlined.</p>

<p>The comparator function I provide looks like:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>int</span> <span>compare_uint64_t</span><span>(</span><span>const</span> <span>void</span> <span>*</span><span>l_</span><span>,</span> <span>const</span> <span>void</span> <span>*</span><span>r_</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>uint64_t</span> <span>l</span> <span>=</span> <span>*</span><span>(</span><span>const</span> <span>uint64_t</span> <span>*</span><span>)</span><span>l_</span><span>;</span>
    <span>uint64_t</span> <span>r</span> <span>=</span> <span>*</span><span>(</span><span>const</span> <span>uint64_t</span> <span>*</span><span>)</span><span>r_</span><span>;</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>l</span> <span>&lt;</span> <span>r</span><span>)</span> <span>return</span> <span>-</span><span>1</span><span>;</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>l</span> <span>&gt;</span> <span>r</span><span>)</span> <span>return</span>  <span>1</span><span>;</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>which on gcc compiles to branch-free code:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>mov    rax,QWORD PTR [rsi]
mov    edx,0xffffffff
cmp    QWORD PTR [rdi],rax
seta   al
movzx  eax,al
cmovb  eax,edx
ret
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Note that the comparator has to redundantly load from memory the two locations to compare, something the merge loop already did (the merge loop reads them because it is responsible for moving the elements).</p>

<p>How much better could things get if we inline the comparator into the merge loop? That’s what we do in <code>qsort-inlined</code><sup id="fnref:inline-hard" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:inline-hard">6</a></sup>, and here’s the main loop which now includes the comparator function<sup id="fnref:cmdline1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:cmdline1">7</a></sup> :</p>

<pre><code> 0.07 :   401dc8:       test   rbp,rbp
 0.66 :   401dcb:       je     401e0c &lt;void msort_with_tmp&lt;CompareU64&gt;(msort_param const*, void*, unsigned long, CompareU64)+0xbc&gt;
 3.51 :   401dcd:       mov    rax,QWORD PTR [r9]
 5.00 :   401dd0:       lea    rdx,[rbx+0x8]
 1.62 :   401dd4:       mov    rcx,QWORD PTR [rbx]
 0.24 :   401dd7:       lea    r8,[r9+0x8]
 6.96 :   401ddb:       cmp    rax,rcx
20.83 :   401dde:       cmovbe r9,r8
 8.88 :   401de2:       cmova  rbx,rdx
 0.27 :   401de6:       cmp    rcx,rax
 6.23 :   401de9:       sbb    r8,r8
 0.74 :   401dec:       cmp    rcx,rax
 4.93 :   401def:       sbb    rdx,rdx
 0.24 :   401df2:       not    r8
 6.69 :   401df5:       add    rbp,rdx
 0.44 :   401df8:       cmp    rax,rcx
 5.34 :   401dfb:       cmova  rax,rcx
 5.96 :   401dff:       add    rdi,0x8
 7.48 :   401e03:       mov    QWORD PTR [rdi-0x8],rax
 0.00 :   401e07:       add    r15,r8
 0.71 :   401e0a:       jne    401dc8 &lt;void msort_with_tmp&lt;CompareU64&gt;(msort_param const*, void*, unsigned long, CompareU64)+0x78&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>A key difference is that the core of the loop is now branch free. Yes, there are still two conditional jumps, but they are both just checking for the termination condition (that one of the lists to merge is exhausted), so we expect this loop to be free of branch mispredictions other than the final iteration. Indeed, we measure with <code>perf stat</code> that the misprediction rate has dropped from to close to 12 mispredicts per element to around 0.75 per element. The loop has only two loads and one store, so the memory access redundancy between the merge code and the comparator has been eliminated<sup id="fnref:load-redundancy" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:load-redundancy">8</a></sup>. Finally, the comparator does a three-way compare (returning distrinct results for <code>&lt;</code>, <code>&gt;</code> and <code>==</code>), but the merge code only needs a two-way compare (<code>&lt;=</code> or <code>&gt;</code>) - inlining the comparator manages to remove extra code associated with distinguishing the <code>&lt;</code> and <code>==</code> cases.</p>

<p>What’s the payoff? It’s pretty big:</p>

<p><img src="https://travisdowns.github.io/assets/2019-05-22/fig2.svg" alt="Effect of comparator inlining"></p>

<p>The speedup hovers right around 1.77x. Note that this is much larger than simply eliminating all the time spent in the separate comparator function in the original version (about 17% of the time implying a speedup of 1.2x if all the function time disapeared). This is a good example of how inlining isn’t just about removing function call overhead but enabling further <em>knock on</em> optimizations which can have a much larger effect than just removing the overhead associated with function calls.</p>

<h2 id="what-about-c">What about C++?</h2>

<p>Short of copying the existing glibc (note: LGPL licenced) sorting code to allow inlining, what else can we do to speed things up? I’m writing in C++, so how about the C++ sort functions available in the <code>&lt;algorithm&gt;</code> header? Unlike C’s <code>qsort</code> which is generic by virtue of taking a function pointer and information about the object size, the C++ sort functions use templates to achieve genericity and so are implemented directly in header files. Since the sort code and the comparator are being compiler together, we expect the comparator to be easily inlined, and perhaps other optimizations may occur.</p>

<p>Without further ado, let’s just throw <code>std::sort</code>, <code>std::stable_sort</code> and <code>std::partial_sort</code> into the mix:</p>

<p><img src="https://travisdowns.github.io/assets/2019-05-22/fig3.svg" alt="C vs C++ sort functions"></p>

<p>The C++ sort functions, other than perhaps <code>std::partial_sort</code><sup id="fnref:partial-sort" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:partial-sort">9</a></sup>, put in a good showing. It is interesting that <code>std::stable_sort</code> which has <em>stricly more requirements</em> on its implementation than <code>std::sort</code> (i.e., any stable sort is also suitable for <code>std::sort</code>) ends up faster. I re-wrote this paragaph several times, since sometimes after a reboot <code>stable_sort</code> was slower and sometimes it was faster (as shown above). When it was “fast” it had less than 2% branch mispredictions, and when it was slow it was at 15%. So perhaps there was some type of aliasing issue in the branch predictor which depends on the physical addresses assigned, which can vary from run to run, I’m not sure. See <sup id="fnref:stablesort" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:stablesort">10</a></sup> for an old note from when <code>std::stable_sort</code> was slower.</p>

<h2 id="can-we-do-better">Can we do better?</h2>

<p>So that’s as fast as it gets, right? We aren’t going to beat <code>std::sort</code> or <code>std::stable_sort</code> without a huge amount of effort, I think? After all, these are presumably highly optimized sorting routines written by the standard library implementors. Sure, we might expect to be able to beat <code>qsort()</code>, but that’s mostly because of built-in disadvantages that <code>qsort</code> has, lacking the ability to inline the comparator, etc.</p>

<h3 id="radix-sort-attempt-1">Radix Sort Attempt 1</h3>

<p>Well, one thing we can try is a non-comparison sort. We know we have integer keys, so why stick to comparing …</p></div></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://travisdowns.github.io/blog/2019/05/22/sorting.html">https://travisdowns.github.io/blog/2019/05/22/sorting.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://travisdowns.github.io/blog/2019/05/22/sorting.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25783617</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 22:25:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Elasticsearch and Kibana are now business risks]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 81 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25781695">thread link</a>) | @vmbrasseur
<br/>
January 14, 2021 | https://anonymoushash.vmbrasseur.com/2021/01/14/elasticsearch-and-kibana-are-now-business-risks | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://anonymoushash.vmbrasseur.com/2021/01/14/elasticsearch-and-kibana-are-now-business-risks">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      
        <header>
          
          
          <p><strong> </strong> <time datetime="2021-01-14T00:00:00-08:00">January 14, 2021</time></p>
          
          
            <p> 




  4 minute read

</p>
          
        </header>
      

      <section itemprop="text">
        
        <p>In a play to convert users of their open source projects into paying customers, today Elastic announced that they are <a href="https://www.elastic.co/blog/licensing-change">changing the license</a> of both Elasticsearch and Kibana from the open source Apache v2 license to <a href="https://www.mongodb.com/licensing/server-side-public-license">Server Side Public License</a> (SSPL). If your organisation uses the open source versions of either Elasticsearch or Kibana in its products or projects, it is now at risk of being forced to release its intellectual property under terms dictated by another.</p>

<p>If you’re not yet aware of the SSPL, you can catch up <a href="https://mjg59.dreamwidth.org/51230.html">here</a>. As licenses go, it’s pretty problematic from a business perspective. Every <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intellectual_property">IP lawyer</a> to whom I’ve showed the text of the SSPL has been rather alarmed before they even reach the end of it. Basically, it’s a hostile proprietary license masquerading in open source clothing. By using an SSPL project in your code, you are agreeing that if you provide an online service using that code then you will release not only that code but also the code for every supporting piece of software, all under the SSPL. It’s not a stretch to interpret the wording of the license as requiring users of the SSPL’d software therefore to release the code for everything straight down to the bare metal. There are those who will point to <a href="https://www.mongodb.com/licensing/server-side-public-license/faq">the FAQ</a> for the SSPL and claim that the license isn’t interpreted in that way because the FAQ says so. Unfortunately, when you agree to a license you are agreeing to the <em>text of that license document</em> and not to a FAQ. If the text of that license document is ambiguous, then so are your rights and responsibilities under that license. Should your compliance to that license come before a judge, it’s <em>their</em> interpretation of those rights and responsibilities that will hold sway. This ambiguity puts your organisation at risk.</p>

<p>In <a href="https://www.elastic.co/blog/licensing-change">its announcement</a>, Elastic claims that this is simply a change of open source license. In one way they’re correct: they’re changing the license away from the open source Apache v2 license. However they are changing to what can best be described as a proprietary source available license, <em>not</em> to an open source one. MongoDB, the originators of SSPL, requested that <a href="https://opensource.org/">Open Source Initiative</a> (OSI) (the standards body that maintains the <a href="https://opensource.org/osd-annotated">Open Source Definition</a> and certifies licenses as open source) certify the SSPL as such. After a great deal of discussion among the panel of legal, licensing, and open source experts, MongoDB withdrew the SSPL from consideration as an open source license, as it appeared highly unlikely it would be certified as open source. That SSPL is not an open source license is no longer in dispute. That ship has sailed. If you have a problem with this, I suggest you <a href="https://lists.opensource.org/pipermail/license-discuss_lists.opensource.org/2019-May/020483.html">take it up</a> with OSI. As for Elastic’s public and verifiably false claim that SSPL is an open source license, it’s my hope that OSI will have a conversation with them and make a public statement of their own shortly.</p>

<p>No, this is a business decision, not an ideological one. Elastic made a business decision to change to this hostile proprietary license to give them a way to <del>extort</del>influence users to become customers. Without a great deal more strategic information about Elastic’s business and operations none of us are qualified to judge whether it’s the correct decision, but the decision itself is valid. They are allowed to make this sort of strategic move for their company.</p>

<p>However, you and your organisation have now also been forced into a business decision. If your organisation uses the Apache v2 licensed Elasticsearch or Kibana in its projects or products, it must now assume that it is at risk one way or another. It can upgrade to version 7.11 of these projects, thereby accepting the terms of SSPL and potentially also being required to release the code for its entire stack (a great deal of which it will not have the copyright over and will be unable to release, thereby potentially being in violation of SSPL). It can remain on version 7.10, but then it will no longer receive future updates, including important security fixes, thereby taking on another sort of risk. It could choose to pay for a Gold+ license for the software, but it’s unlikely that the budget is prepared for this sort of unexpected expense. And finally it can rearchitect its project or product, replacing Elasticsearch and/or Kibana with alternatives. Frankly, considering today’s unfriendly move by Elastic, putting some space between it and your organisation may be the safest alternative in the long run, but it will come with its own considerable price tag in time and other potential opportunity and switching costs.</p>

<p>The one thing your organisation cannot afford to do is ignore this. It’s time to call a meeting with your legal, software development, product, finance, and strategy teams to start to figure out the best option for you.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>For more information on relicensing moves like this, please see <a href="https://anonymoushash.vmbrasseur.com/2019/06/07/the-problem-with-amazon-and-open-source-isnt-amazon/">The problem with Amazon and Open Source isn’t Amazon</a>.</p>
</blockquote>

<hr>

<blockquote>
  <p>Judging from the bandwidth usage stats on my hosting service, people seem to appreciate this post. Thank you for that. If you’d like me to provide corporate open source strategy for your company, please <a href="https://www.vmbrasseur.com/about/#contact">drop me an email</a>. I’ll soon be kicking my job search into high gear after <a href="https://anonymoushash.vmbrasseur.com/2020/06/01/farewell-juniper">Juniper laid off its open source team</a> last year. Contacting me now makes it more likely your company will be in consideration for my next role.</p>
</blockquote>

        
      </section>

      

      


      
  

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://anonymoushash.vmbrasseur.com/2021/01/14/elasticsearch-and-kibana-are-now-business-risks</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25781695</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 20:02:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[U.S. jobless numbers surge as worsening Covid-19 pandemic hurts businesses]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 62 | Comments 85 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25778289">thread link</a>) | @heyheyheysome
<br/>
January 14, 2021 | https://www.cbc.ca/news/business/us-jobless-numbers-1.5872817 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/news/business/us-jobless-numbers-1.5872817">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>The number of Americans filing first-time applications for unemployment benefits surged last week, confirming a weakening in labour market conditions as a worsening COVID-19 pandemic disrupts operations at restaurants and other businesses.</p><div><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5872837.1610635730!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/usa-smallbusiness-ppp.JPG"></p></div><figcaption>A woman walks past a business that is closing in New York City in August. Initial claims for state unemployment benefits totalled a seasonally adjusted 965,000 for the week ended Jan. 9, compared to 784,000 in the prior week, the U.S. Labour Department said on Thursday.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Carlo Allegri/Reuters)</figcaption></figure><p><span><p>The number of Americans filing first-time applications for unemployment benefits surged last week, confirming a weakening in labour market conditions as a worsening COVID-19 pandemic disrupts operations at restaurants and other businesses.</p>  <p>Initial claims for state unemployment benefits totalled a seasonally adjusted 965,000 for the week ended Jan. 9, compared to 784,000 in the prior week, the U.S. Labour Department said on Thursday. Economists polled by Reuters had forecast 795,000 applications in the latest week.</p>  <p>It's the highest number since late August.&nbsp;Applications declined over the summer but have been stuck above 700,000 since September.</p>  <p>Claims were also likely lifted by re-applications for benefits following the government's renewal of a $300 US unemployment supplement until March 14 as part of nearly $900 billion in additional relief approved at the end of December.</p>    <p>Government-funded programs for the self-employed, gig workers and others who do not qualify for the state unemployment programs as well as those who have exhausted their benefits were also extended.</p>  <p>Authorities in many states have banned indoor dining to slow the spread of the coronavirus. The economy shed jobs in December for the first time in eight months.</p>  <p>The Federal Reserve's Beige Book report of anecdotal information on business activity collected from contacts nationwide in early January showed on Wednesday that "contacts in the leisure and hospitality sectors reported renewed employment cuts due to stricter containment measures."</p>  <p>The central bank also noted that the resurgence in the coronavirus was causing staff shortages in the manufacturing, construction and transportation&nbsp;sectors.</p>  <h2>Most infections of any country</h2>  <p>The virus has infected more than 22.5 million people in the United States and killed over 376,188, the most of any country.&nbsp;More than 4,300 deaths were reported Tuesday, a&nbsp;record high.</p>  <p>Though jobless claims have dropped from a record 6.867 million in March, they remain above their 665,000 peak during the 2007-09 Great Recession. Economists say it could take several years for the labour market to recover from the pandemic.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5859227.1609502755!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_300/health-coronavirus-usa-florida.JPG 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5859227.1609502755!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_460/health-coronavirus-usa-florida.JPG 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5859227.1609502755!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_620/health-coronavirus-usa-florida.JPG 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5859227.1609502755!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_780/health-coronavirus-usa-florida.JPG 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5859227.1609502755!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_1180/health-coronavirus-usa-florida.JPG 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5859227.1609502755!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_780/health-coronavirus-usa-florida.JPG"></p></div><figcaption>Hundreds wait in line to receive the COVID-19 vaccine in Fort Myers, Fla., in late December. Economists are hopeful the economy will turn around in late 2021.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Andrew West/The News-Press/USA Today Network/Reuters)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>"While prospects for the economy later in 2021 are upbeat, the labour market recovery has taken a step backward," said Nancy Vanden Houten, an economist at Oxford Economics, "and we expect claims to remain elevated, with the risk that they rise from last week's levels."</p>  <p>Last week's applications for aid might have been elevated in part because state employment offices had been closed over the holidays, requiring some jobless people to wait until last week to apply.&nbsp;</p>  <h2>5.3 million Americans receiving jobless benefits</h2>  <p>In addition to last week's first-time applications for unemployment aid, the government said Thursday that 5.3 million Americans are continuing to receive state jobless benefits, up from 5.1 million in the previous week. It suggests that fewer people who are out of work are finding jobs.</p>  <p>About 11.6 million people received jobless aid from two federal programs in the week that ended Dec. 26, the latest period for which data is available. One of those programs provides extended benefits to people who have exhausted their state aid. The other supplies benefits to self-employed and contract workers.</p>  <p>Those two programs had expired near the end of December. They were belatedly renewed, through mid-March, in the $900-billion rescue aid package that Congress approved and President Donald Trump signed into law. That legislation also included $600 relief cheques&nbsp;for most adults and a supplemental unemployment benefit payment of $300 a week. Congressional Democrats favour boosting the cheques&nbsp;to $2,000 and extending federal aid beyond March, as does president-elect Joe Biden.</p>    <p>The U.S. job market's weakness was made painfully clear in the December employment report that the government issued last week. Employers shed jobs for the first time since April as the pandemic tightened its grip on consumers and businesses.</p>  <p>The figures also depicted a sharply uneven job market: The losses last month were concentrated among restaurants, bars, hotels and entertainment venues. Educational services, mostly colleges and universities, also cut workers in December. So did film and music studios.</p>  <p>Most other large industries, though, reported job gains. Many economists had expected last spring that job losses would spread to more industries. Though all sectors of the economy initially laid off workers, most of them have avoided deep job cuts. Manufacturing, construction, and professional services like engineering and architecture, for example, all added jobs in December.</p>  <p>At the same time, many companies seem reluctant to sharply ramp up hiring. A government report Tuesday showed that employers advertised fewer open jobs in November than in October. The decline, while small, was widespread across most industries.</p></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/business/us-jobless-numbers-1.5872817</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25778289</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 16:28:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Licensing changes to Elasticsearch and Kibana]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 266 | Comments 317 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25776657">thread link</a>) | @sl_
<br/>
January 14, 2021 | https://www.elastic.co/blog/licensing-change | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.elastic.co/blog/licensing-change">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div><div><h2>Upcoming licensing changes to Elasticsearch and Kibana</h2><p>We are moving our Apache 2.0-licensed source code in Elasticsearch and Kibana to be dual licensed under Server Side Public License (SSPL) and the Elastic License, giving users the choice of which license to apply. This license change ensures our community and customers have free and open access to use, modify, redistribute, and collaborate on the code. It also protects our continued investment in developing products that we distribute for free and in the open by restricting cloud service providers from offering Elasticsearch and Kibana as a service without contributing back. This will apply to all maintained branches of these two products and will take place before our upcoming 7.11 release. Our releases will continue to be under the Elastic License as they have been for the last three years.
</p><p>This change in source code licensing has <b>no impact on the overwhelming majority of our user community</b> who use our default distribution for free. It also has <b>no impact on our cloud customers or self-managed software customers</b>.</p><p>In recent years, the market has evolved, and the community has come to appreciate that open source companies need to better protect their software to continue to innovate and make the investments required. As companies continue the shift to SaaS offerings, some cloud service providers have taken open source products and provided them as a service without investing back into the community. Moving to the dual license strategy with <a href="https://www.mongodb.com/licensing/server-side-public-license">SSPL</a> or the Elastic License is a natural next step for us after opening our commercial code and creating a free tier, all under the Elastic License, nearly 3 years ago. It is similar to those made by many other open source companies over these years, including <a href="https://www.mongodb.com/licensing/server-side-public-license/faq">MongoDB</a>, which developed the SSPL. The SSPL allows free and unrestricted use, as well as modification, with the simple requirement that if you provide the product as a service, you must also publicly release any modifications as well as the source code of your management layers  under SSPL.
</p><h2>Our open origins</h2><p>My personal journey with open source goes a long way back. In 2005, I open sourced my first project, Compass, to provide a Java framework on top of Apache Lucene while I was building a recipe app for my wife. In the following five years, I invested many weekends and nights working on it, from writing code to helping users with bugs, features, and questions.
</p><p>I had no idea what I was signing up for, especially with a day job “on the side,” but I fell in love with the opportunity to make such a positive impact — trying to build a great product, but more importantly, a great community around it, through the power of open source.
</p><p>In 2009, I decided to do it again, and started to write a brand new project called Elasticsearch. I spent many nights and weekends building it, and in 2010 open sourced it. I even quit my job and decided to dedicate my full attention to it. To be there for the users, through writing code, and engaging on GitHub, mailing lists, and IRC.
</p><p>And when we founded Elastic as a company in 2012, we brought the same spirit to our company. We invested heavily in our free and open products, and supported the rapid growth of our community of users. We expanded from just Elasticsearch to Kibana, Logstash, Beats, and now a complete set of solutions built into the Elastic Stack: Elastic Enterprise Search, Observability, and Security.
</p><p>We have matured the products, fostered vibrant communities around them, and focused on providing the greatest amount of value to our users. Today, we have hundreds of engineers who wake up every day and work to make our products even better. And we have hundreds of thousands of community members who engage with us and contribute to our shared success.
</p><p>I am proud of the company we built, and humbled by the level of trust that we have earned with our user base. This starts by being open and transparent, and continues with being true to our community and user base in our choices.
</p><h2>Free and open FTW</h2><p>Back in 2018, we <a href="https://www.elastic.co/blog/doubling-down-on-open">opened the code of our free and paid proprietary features</a> under the Elastic License, a source-available license, and we changed our default distribution to include all of our features, with all free features enabled by default.
</p><p>We did this for a few reasons. It allowed us to engage with our paying customers in the same way we engage with our community: in the open. It also allowed us to build free features that empower our users without providing those capabilities to companies that take our products and provide them as a service, like Amazon Elasticsearch Service, and profit from our open source software without contributing back.
</p><p>This approach was well received — today, over 90% of new downloads choose this distribution — and has allowed us to make so much of our work available for free while also building a successful company.
</p><p>The list of improvements under this new free and open, yet proprietary, license, is overwhelming. I am humbled by the amazing progress our team and community has made across all our products, so much so that I would love to share some of them:
</p><p>We've dramatically improved the speed, scalability, and reliability of Elasticsearch, with a new distributed consensus algorithm and significantly reduced memory usage, in addition to new data storage and compression approaches that have reduced the typical index size by nearly 40% while improving indexing and query throughput. We added new field types for geospatial analysis, and more efficient ways to store and search logs and perform fast, case-insensitive search on security data. In Kibana, we cut load time by 80% and eliminated whole-page refreshes thanks to a multiyear replatforming project, while at the same time introducing an intuitive drag-and-drop data visualization experience with Kibana Lens, key capabilities like dashboard drill-downs, and so much more.
</p><p>Over the last three years, we also built first-class experiences around our most common use cases. In the security area, we created a free and open SIEM right inside Kibana, with a powerful detection engine that supports simple rules as well as complex correlations via a new query language called EQL in Elasticsearch. We include hundreds of detection rules, which we develop publicly, in collaboration with our community. And we joined forces with Endgame, a leading endpoint security company, and have released powerful malware protection for free as part of the Elastic Agent, our unified, centrally managed observability and security agent for servers and endpoints, with more to come.
</p><p>In observability, the story is similar. We've built an entire observability suite right inside Kibana — from a live-tail logging UI to an intuitive infrastructure-level view of the key metrics and alerts across your hosts, pods, and containers. And we now have a fully featured APM product with open source data collectors and agents, supporting OpenTelemetry, real user monitoring (RUM), synthetic monitoring, and the recent addition of user experience monitoring.
</p><p>With Elastic Enterprise Search, we introduced App Search, a layer on top of Elasticsearch that simplifies building rich applications and provides powerful management interfaces for relevance tuning, as well as analytics on how it's being used. We also provide a free Workplace Search product that makes it easy to integrate and search the content sources that you use to run your life or company, like Google Workplace, Microsoft 365, Atlassian Jira and Confluence, and Salesforce.
</p><p>It is simply amazing that we've been able to build all of these capabilities and provide them for free to our community. It has been humbling to see the level of engagement and adoption around our products and how these new features have helped so many people and businesses succeed. And this was possible because the overwhelming majority of our community chose our default distribution under the Elastic License, where all these features are free and open.
</p><h2>Why change?</h2><p>As previously mentioned, over the last three years, the market has evolved and the community has come to appreciate that open source companies need to better protect their software in order to maintain a high level of investment and innovation. With the shift to SaaS as a delivery model, some cloud service providers have taken advantage of open source products by providing them as a service, without contributing back. This diverts funds that would have been reinvested into the product and hurts users and the community.
</p><p>Similar to our open source peers, we have lived this experience firsthand, from our trademarks being misused to outright attempts to splinter our community with “open” repackaging of our OSS products or even taking “inspiration” from our proprietary code. While each open source company has taken a slightly different approach to address this issue, they have generally modified their open source license in order to protect their investment in free software, while trying to preserve the principles of openness, transparency, and collaboration. Similarly, we are taking the natural next step of making a targeted change to how we license our source code. This change won't affect the vast majority of our users, but it will restrict cloud service providers from offering our software as a service.
</p><p>We expect that a few of our competitors will attempt to spread all kinds of FUD around this change. Let me be clear to any naysayers. We believe deeply in the principles of free and open products, and of transparency with the community. Our track record speaks to this commitment, and we will continue to build upon it.
</p><h2>The change</h2><p>Starting with the upcoming Elastic 7.11 release, we will be moving the Apache 2.0-licensed code of Elasticsearch and Kibana to be dual licensed under SSPL and the Elastic License, giving users the choice of which license to apply. SSPL is a source-available license created by MongoDB to embody the principles …</p></div></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.elastic.co/blog/licensing-change">https://www.elastic.co/blog/licensing-change</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.elastic.co/blog/licensing-change</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25776657</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 14:29:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[10 years-ish of Elixir]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 395 | Comments 113 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25776525">thread link</a>) | @1_player
<br/>
January 14, 2021 | https://dashbit.co/blog/ten-years-ish-of-elixir | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dashbit.co/blog/ten-years-ish-of-elixir">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <article>
    
<ul>
  <li>
    <i></i> José Valim
  </li>
  <li>
    <i></i> January 11th, 2021
  </li>
  <li>
    <i></i><a href="https://dashbit.co/blog/tags/elixir">elixir</a>, <a href="https://dashbit.co/blog/tags/phoenix">phoenix</a>, <a href="https://dashbit.co/blog/tags/broadway">broadway</a>, <a href="https://dashbit.co/blog/tags/nerves">nerves</a>, <a href="https://dashbit.co/blog/tags/liveview">liveview</a>, <a href="https://dashbit.co/blog/tags/membrane">membrane</a>
  </li>
</ul>
<p>
This past weekend, on January 9th, we celebrated 10 years since <a href="https://github.com/elixir-lang/elixir/commit/337c3f2d569a42ebd5fcab6fef18c5e012f9be5b">the first commit to the Elixir repository</a>. While I personally don’t consider <a href="https://elixir-lang.org/">Elixir</a> to be 10 years old yet - the language that became what Elixir is today <a href="https://github.com/elixir-lang/elixir/commit/6052352b6281752b905b30eb5b08fac0f51f68cd">surfaced only 14 months later</a> - a decade is a mark to celebrate!</p>
<p>
The goal of this post is to focus on the current state of some projects in the ecosystem and then briefly highlight a few of the exciting efforts coming over the next months.</p>
<h2>
Recap: The language goals</h2>
<p>
When I started working on Elixir, I personally had the ambition of using it for building scalable and robust web applications. However, I didn’t want Elixir to be tied to the web. My goal was to design an <em>extensible</em> language with a diverse ecosystem. Elixir aims to be a general purpose language and allows developers to extend it to new domains.</p>
<p>
Given Elixir is built on top of Erlang and Erlang is used for networking and distributed systems, Elixir would naturally be a good fit in those domains too, as long as I didn’t screw things up. The Erlang VM is essential to everything we do in Elixir, which is why <em>compatibility</em> has become a language goal too.</p>
<p>
I also wanted the language to be <em>productive</em>, especially by focusing on the tooling. Learning a functional programming language is a new endeavor for most developers. Consequently their first experiences getting started with the language, setting up a new project, searching for documentation, and debugging should go as smoothly as possible.</p>
<p>
Extensibility, compatibility, and productivity are the goals we built the language upon.</p>
<h2>
Recap: Elixir in production</h2>
<p>
Last year we started <a href="https://elixir-lang.org/cases.html">a series of articles on companies using Elixir in production on the official website</a>. As of today, we have 7 production cases listed with more coming this year! Overall it is very exciting to see many different companies using a variety of business models and industries running Elixir in production.</p>
<p>
Companies like <a href="https://www.brex.com/">Brex</a> (<a href="https://elixir-lang.org/blog/2020/06/23/growing-with-elixir-at-brex/">case</a>), <a href="https://discord.com/">Discord</a> (<a href="https://elixir-lang.org/blog/2020/10/08/real-time-communication-at-scale-with-elixir-at-discord/">case</a>), <a href="https://getdivvy.com/">Divvy</a>, <a href="https://www.podium.com/">Podium</a>, and <a href="https://salesloft.com/">SalesLoft</a> have reached <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unicorn_(finance)">“unicorn status”</a> and rely heavily on Elixir. Startups like <a href="https://www.joinblvd.com/">Boulevard</a> (<a href="https://soundcloud.com/elixirtalk/episode-166-feat-sean-stavropoulos">podcast</a>), <a href="https://community.com/">Community</a>, <a href="https://duffel.com/">Duffel</a> (<a href="https://elixir-lang.org/blog/2020/12/10/integrating-travel-with-elixir-at-duffel/">case</a>), <a href="https://www.ockam.io/">Ockam</a>, <a href="https://www.mux.com/">Mux</a>, <a href="https://ramp.com/">Ramp</a>, <a href="https://remote.com/">Remote</a>, and <a href="https://www.v7labs.com/">V7</a> (<a href="https://elixir-lang.org/blog/2021/01/13/orchestrating-computer-vision-with-elixir/">case</a>) also use Elixir and have received funding in the last year or two. Elixir is also used within known brands and enterprises such as <a href="https://bleacherreport.com/">Bleacher Report</a>, <a href="https://www.change.org/">Change.org</a> (<a href="https://elixir-lang.org/blog/2020/10/27/delivering-social-change-with-elixir-at-change.org/">case</a>), <a href="https://heroku.com/">Heroku</a> (<a href="https://elixir-lang.org/blog/2020/09/24/paas-with-elixir-at-Heroku/">case</a>), <a href="https://www.pagerduty.com/">PagerDuty</a>, <a href="https://www.pepsico.com/">PepsiCo</a>, and <a href="https://www.therealreal.com/">TheRealReal</a>.</p>
<p>
There is also a special category of startups that run Elixir alonside an open source model, such as <a href="https://plausible.io/">Plausible Analytics</a>, <a href="https://app.supabase.io/">Supabase</a>, <a href="https://logflare.app/">Logflare</a> (<a href="https://runninginproduction.com/podcast/11-logflare-is-a-log-management-and-event-analytics-platform">podcast</a>), and <a href="https://hex.pm/">Hex.pm</a> (<a href="https://runninginproduction.com/podcast/19-hexpm-is-elixirs-official-package-manager">podcast</a>) itself. Still on the open source front, you will find projects like <a href="https://pleroma.social/">Pleroma</a> and <a href="https://changelog.com/">Changelog</a>. There also many small scale and hobby projects that use Elixir for a productive and joyful development experience.</p>
<h2>
Recap: Diverse ecosystem</h2>
<p>
Today, Elixir has a diverse ecosystem that works on a wide range of domains and industries. Let’s take a look at some examples.</p>
<h3>
Web</h3>
<p>
Most developers are familiar with using Elixir for web development thanks to <a href="https://phoenixframework.org/">the Phoenix web framework</a>. Phoenix gained traction in the ecosystem because it was the first to fully leverage the language and the platform for building real-time applications besides the usual MVC (Model-View-Controller) offering.</p>
<p>
It all started with Phoenix Channels, as a bi-directional communication between clients and servers, and Phoenix PubSub, which uses Erlang’s distributed compatibilities to broadcast messages across nodes. As far as I know, Phoenix was the first major web framework to provide a multi-node web real-time solution completely out-of-the-box. Regardless if you are using one node or ten nodes, everything just works, with minimal configuration and dependencies.</p>
<p>
Phoenix has matured a lot since its first stable release. Phoenix v1.2 included <a href="https://hexdocs.pm/phoenix/Phoenix.Presence.html">Phoenix Presence</a>, that allows developers to track which users, IoT devices, etc are connected to your cluster right now. No databases or external dependencies required! This is one of the problems that look deceptively simple at first, but once you outline all scalability, performance, and fault-tolerance requirements, it <a href="https://elixir-lang.org/blog/2020/11/17/real-time-collaboration-with-elixir-at-slab/">becomes quite complex</a>. Luckily, Phoenix is running on a platform that excels at these problems, and I am not aware of any other framework that provides such a lean and elegant solution as part of its default stack.</p>
<p>
Most recently, <a href="https://github.com/phoenixframework/phoenix_live_view">Phoenix LiveView</a> was released and brought new ways to build rich, real-time user experiences with server-rendered HTML, inspiring developers to attempt similar solutions for other languages and frameworks. You can read the <a href="https://dockyard.com/blog/2018/12/12/phoenix-liveview-interactive-real-time-apps-no-need-to-write-javascript">original announcement</a> or <a href="https://www.phoenixframework.org/blog/build-a-real-time-twitter-clone-in-15-minutes-with-live-view-and-phoenix-1-5">learn how to build a real-time Twitter clone in 15 minutes</a>. As part of the <em>Live</em> family, we have also announced <a href="https://twitter.com/josevalim/status/1250846714665357315">Phoenix LiveDashboard</a>, making monitoring and instrumentation a first-class citizen for Phoenix applications.</p>
<h3>
Embedded and IoT</h3>
<p>
While I always expected Elixir to shine for building web applications, I was taken by surprise when I heard about the <a href="https://www.nerves-project.org/">Nerves platform</a> for creating high-end embedded applications. However, once I learned their premise, it all made sense: writing embedded systems <em>is</em> complicated. Reasoning about failures is hard. So what if we could leverage the decades of lessons learnt by Erlang/OTP to design embedded applications? What if a fault on the Wi-Fi driver could be fixed by having a supervisor simply restart it? After all, the first major use of Erlang/OTP was in an embedded system, the Ericsson AXD301 ATM switch.</p>
<p>
Nerves brings the Elixir ecosystem and the battle-tested Erlang VM to edge computing, providing a rich developer experience using proven technology. Nerves started as a one step process for turning an Elixir project into a complete software image for common hardware devices. Today, Nerves is being used in production in industrial automation, machine learning, consumer electronics and more, with <a href="https://farm.bot/">Farmbot</a> (<a href="https://elixir-lang.org/blog/2020/08/20/embedded-elixir-at-farmbot/">case</a>) and <a href="https://www.rosepoint.com/">Rose Point Navigation</a> being two of the most notable examples.</p>
<p>
The Nerves team also created <a href="https://www.nerves-hub.org/">NervesHub</a>, a fully open-source device management system. Combining all these technologies makes Elixir a comprehensive language for building end-to-end IoT platforms.</p>
<h3>
Data ingestion and pipelines</h3>
<p>
Shortly after Elixir v1.0 was released, the Elixir Core Team and I started looking into abstractions for tackling data ingestions and data pipelines in Elixir. We ran through a couple designs until we eventually <a href="https://elixir-lang.org/blog/2016/07/14/announcing-genstage/">landed on GenStage</a>: a behaviour for exchanging data with back-pressure between Elixir processes and external systems. For an introduction, make sure to check out <a href="https://youtu.be/srtMWzyqdp8?t=242">my keynote introducing both GenStage and Flow</a>.</p>
<p>
Today, almost 5 years later, GenStage has been used by many industries and has become one of the factors driving Elixir adoption. For example, you can read how both <a href="https://elixir-lang.org/blog/2020/10/08/real-time-communication-at-scale-with-elixir-at-discord/">Discord</a> and <a href="https://elixir-lang.org/blog/2020/10/27/delivering-social-change-with-elixir-at-change.org/">Change.org</a> have built systems on Elixir and GenStage that handle spikes and run at massive scale.</p>
<p>
However, GenStage was just the beginning. In 2019, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZOExnT1PYjs">we announced Broadway</a>, which is a higher-level abstraction on top of GenStage that makes building data ingestion pipelines a breeze. We originally released with Amazon SQS support. Nowadays, RabbitMQ, Google Cloud PubSub, Apache Kafka, and other sources (known as producers in Broadway terms) are also available.</p>
<h3>
Audio/Video streaming</h3>
<p>
Since the Erlang VM was designed for scalable network processing, one can expect to also be an excellent platform for audio and video streaming. However, if you also wanted to process and transform those streams on the fly, the situation becomes much more complicated as you likely have to integrate with native code.</p>
<p>
Luckily, the tables have turned when Erlang/OTP 20 was released a couple years ago with the so-called Dirty NIFs. The Erlang VM always had the ability to invoke native code, but this native code could not run for long, as to not interfere with the preemptive features of the Erlang runtime. Dirty NIFs allow developers to tag native code either as IO or CPU bound, which runs on specific threads. Between ports (I/O based), NIFs, Dirty NIFs, and remote nodes, developers now have many options to interface with native code with different performance and reliability guarantees. That’s exactly the foundation the <a href="http://www.membraneframework.org/">Membrane Framework</a> builds on top of.</p>
<p>
Membrane was extracted from RadioKit, a startup aiming at disrupting the radio broadcasting industry. Originally it focused on processing and mixing audio. Later, <a href="https://www.swmansion.com/">Software Mansion</a> acquired the framework and provided stable funding and a solid team to help it grow into a full-scale framework. Currently, it allows developers to process, transmit, broadcast, and transform audio and videos streams on the fly. Whether you are building a Twitch clone, a VOD application or a video conferencing system, Membrane provides a growing set of high-level abstractions and pre-made modules so you don’t have to dive into idiosyncrasies of particular codecs, protocols, and formats. </p>
<h2>
Looking ahead: what is coming in 2021</h2>
<p>
The year of 2021 looks very exciting for the Erlang Ecosystem and the Elixir community. In this section, we are going to mention some of the things we expect to see in 2021.</p>
<h3>
Erlang/OTP 24 with JIT</h3>
<p>
In September 2020, <a href="https://github.com/erlang/otp/pull/2745">Lukas Larsson and the Erlang/OTP team</a> announced a JIT compiler for the Erlang VM called BeamAsm. How faster the JIT will be in practice depends on your application but the results posted in the announcement are promising. To quote Lukas:</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>
If we run the JSON benchmarks found in the <a href="https://github.com/devinus/poison/tree/master/bench">Poison</a> or <a href="https://github.com/michalmuskala/jason/tree/master/bench">Jason</a>, BeamAsm achieves anything from 30% to 130% increase (average at about 70%) in the number of iterations per second for all Erlang/Elixir implementations. For some benchmarks, BeamAsm is even faster than the pure C implementation <a href="https://github.com/davisp/jiffy">jiffy</a>.  </p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
  <p>
More complex applications tend to see a more moderate performance increase, for instance, RabbitMQ is able to handle 30% to 50% more messages per second depending on the scenario.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>
I have been running …</p></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://dashbit.co/blog/ten-years-ish-of-elixir">https://dashbit.co/blog/ten-years-ish-of-elixir</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dashbit.co/blog/ten-years-ish-of-elixir</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25776525</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 14:21:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[We don't need data scientists, we need data engineers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 640 | Comments 319 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25775872">thread link</a>) | @winkywooster
<br/>
January 14, 2021 | https://www.mihaileric.com/posts/we-need-data-engineers-not-data-scientists/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.mihaileric.com/posts/we-need-data-engineers-not-data-scientists/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-reactid="11"><figure>
    
  <a href="https://www.mihaileric.com/static/nasa-Q1p7bh3SHj8-unsplash-1d801dd5a6a5e44b7503e433b3a540b5-85f3f.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
  
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="world in data" title="" src="https://www.mihaileric.com/static/nasa-Q1p7bh3SHj8-unsplash-1d801dd5a6a5e44b7503e433b3a540b5-c6823.jpg" srcset="https://www.mihaileric.com/static/nasa-Q1p7bh3SHj8-unsplash-1d801dd5a6a5e44b7503e433b3a540b5-dad4f.jpg 240w,
https://www.mihaileric.com/static/nasa-Q1p7bh3SHj8-unsplash-1d801dd5a6a5e44b7503e433b3a540b5-1808a.jpg 480w,
https://www.mihaileric.com/static/nasa-Q1p7bh3SHj8-unsplash-1d801dd5a6a5e44b7503e433b3a540b5-c6823.jpg 960w,
https://www.mihaileric.com/static/nasa-Q1p7bh3SHj8-unsplash-1d801dd5a6a5e44b7503e433b3a540b5-e8e5f.jpg 1440w,
https://www.mihaileric.com/static/nasa-Q1p7bh3SHj8-unsplash-1d801dd5a6a5e44b7503e433b3a540b5-54793.jpg 1920w,
https://www.mihaileric.com/static/nasa-Q1p7bh3SHj8-unsplash-1d801dd5a6a5e44b7503e433b3a540b5-c4df6.jpg 2880w,
https://www.mihaileric.com/static/nasa-Q1p7bh3SHj8-unsplash-1d801dd5a6a5e44b7503e433b3a540b5-85f3f.jpg 4256w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px">
    </span>
  </span>
  
  </a>
    
</figure>
<p>Data. It’s everywhere and we’re <a href="https://techjury.net/blog/how-much-data-is-created-every-day/#gref">only getting more of it</a>. For the last 5-10 years, <em>data science</em> has attracted newcomers near and far trying to get a taste of that forbidden fruit. </p>
<p>But what does the state of <em>data science</em> hiring look like today?</p>
<p>Here’s the gist of the article in two-sentences for the busy reader.</p>
<p><strong>TLDR</strong>: There are <strong>70% more open roles</strong> at companies in <em>data engineering</em> as compared to <em>data science</em>. As we train the next generation of data and machine learning practitioners, let’s place more emphasis on engineering skills.</p>
<hr>
<p>As part of my work developing an <a href="https://www.confetti.ai/">educational platform</a> for data professionals, I think a lot about how the market for data-driven (machine learning and data science) roles is evolving. </p>
<p>In talking to dozens of prospective entrants to data fields including students at top institutions around the world, I’ve seen a tremendous amount of confusion around what skills are most important to help candidates stand out in the crowd and prepare for their careers. </p>
<p>When you think about it, a <em>data scientist</em> can be responsible for any subset of the following: machine learning modelling, visualization, data cleaning and processing (i.e. SQL wrangling), engineering, and production deployment. </p>
<p>How do you even begin to recommend a study curriculum for newcomers?</p>
<p>Data speaks louder than words. So I decided to do an analysis of the data roles being hired for at every company coming out of <a href="https://www.ycombinator.com/">Y-Combinator</a> since 2012. The questions that guided my research:</p>
<ul>
<li>What data roles are companies most frequently hiring for?</li>
<li>How in-demand is the conventional <em>data scientist</em> that we talk about so much?</li>
<li>Are the same skills that started the data revolution relevant today?</li>
</ul>
<p>If you want the full details and analysis, read on. </p>
<h2>Methodology</h2>
<p>I chose to do an analysis of YC portfolio companies that claim to make some sort of data work part of their value proposition. </p>
<p>Why focus on YC? Well, for starters, they do a good job of providing an easily searchable (and scrapable) <a href="https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/">directory of their companies</a>. </p>
<p>In addition, as a particularly forward-thinking incubator that has funded companies from around the world across domains for over a decade, I felt they provided a representative sample of the market with which to conduct my analyses. That being said, take what I say wit a grain of salt, as I didn’t analyze super-large tech companies.</p>
<p>I scraped the homepage URLs of every YC company since 2012, producing an initial pool of ~1400 companies. </p>
<p>Why stop at 2012? Well, 2012 was the year that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AlexNet">AlexNet</a> won the ImageNet competition, effectively kickstarting the machine learning and data-modelling wave we are now living through. It’s fair to say that this birthed some of the earliest generations of data-first companies.</p>
<p>From this initial pool, I performed keyword filtering to reduce the number of relevant companies I would have to look through. In particular, I only considered companies whose websites included at least one of the following terms: AI, CV, NLP, natural language processing, computer vision, artificial intelligence, machine, ML, data. I also disregarded companies whose website links were broken. </p>
<p>Did this generate a ton of false positives? Absolutely! But here I was trying to prioritize high recall as much as possible, recognizing that I would do a more fine-grained manual inspection of the individual websites for relevant roles.</p>
<p>With this reduced pool, I went through every site, found where they were advertising jobs (typically a <em>Careers</em>, <em>Jobs</em>, or <em>We’re Hiring</em> page), and took note of every role that included data, machine learning, NLP, or CV in the title. This gave me a pool of about 70 distinct companies hiring for data roles. </p>
<p>One note here: it’s conceivable that I missed some companies as there were certain websites with very little information (typically those in stealth) that might actually be hiring. In addition, there were companies that didn’t have a formal <em>Careers</em> page but asked that prospective candidates reach out directly via email. </p>
<p>I disregarded both of these types of companies rather than reach out to them, so they are not part of this analysis.</p>
<p>Another thing: the bulk of this research was done towards the final weeks of 2020. Open roles may have changed as companies update their pages periodically. However, I don’t believe this will drastically impact the conclusions drawn. </p>
<h2>What Are Data Practitioners Responsible For?</h2>
<p>Before diving into the results, it’s worth spending some time clarifying what responsibilities each data role is typically responsible for. Here are the four roles we will spend our time looking at with a short description of what they do:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Data scientist</em>: Use various techniques in statistics and machine learning to process and analyse data. Often responsible for building models to probe what can be learned from some data source, though often at a prototype rather than production level. </li>
<li><em>Data engineer</em>: Develops a robust and scalable set of data processing tools/platforms. Must be comfortable with SQL/NoSQL database wrangling and building/maintaining ETL pipelines.</li>
<li><em>Machine Learning (ML) Engineer</em>: Often responsible for both training models and productionizing them. Requires familiarity with some high-level ML framework and also must be comfortable building scalable training, inference, and deployment pipelines for models.</li>
<li><em>Machine Learning (ML) Scientist</em>: Works on cutting-edge research. Typically responsible for exploring new ideas that can be published at academic conferences. Often only needs to prototype new state-of-the-art models before handing off to ML engineers for productionization.</li>
</ul>
<h2>How Many Data Roles Are There?</h2>
<p>So what happens when we plot the frequency of each data role that companies are hiring for? The plot looks  like this:</p>
<figure>
    
  <a href="https://www.mihaileric.com/static/all_roles-76753bdb67cdaac40a0ea69ffbe76267-7931f.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
  
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="all machine learning, data science, data engineering roles at Y-Combinator companies" title="" src="https://www.mihaileric.com/static/all_roles-76753bdb67cdaac40a0ea69ffbe76267-3d61e.png" srcset="https://www.mihaileric.com/static/all_roles-76753bdb67cdaac40a0ea69ffbe76267-d182c.png 240w,
https://www.mihaileric.com/static/all_roles-76753bdb67cdaac40a0ea69ffbe76267-5220f.png 480w,
https://www.mihaileric.com/static/all_roles-76753bdb67cdaac40a0ea69ffbe76267-3d61e.png 960w,
https://www.mihaileric.com/static/all_roles-76753bdb67cdaac40a0ea69ffbe76267-7931f.png 985w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px">
    </span>
  </span>
  
  </a>
    
</figure>
<p>What immediately stands out is how many more open <em>data engineer</em> roles there are compared to traditional <em>data scientists</em>. In this case, the raw counts correspond to companies hiring <strong>roughly 55% more</strong> for data engineers than data scientists, and roughly the same number of machine learning engineers as data scientists.</p>
<p>But we can do more. If you look at the titles of the various roles, there seems to be some repetition. </p>
<p>Let’s only provide coarse-grained categorization through role consolidation. In other words, I took roles whose descriptions were roughly equivalent and consolidated them under a single title. </p>
<p>That included the following set of equivalence relations: </p>
<ul>
<li><em>NLP engineer</em> <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mo>≈</mo></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">\approx</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> <em>CV engineer</em> <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mo>≈</mo></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">\approx</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> <em>ML engineer</em> <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mo>≈</mo></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">\approx</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> <em>Deep Learning engineer</em> (while the domains might be different, the responsiblities are roughly the same)</li>
<li><em>ML scientist</em> <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mo>≈</mo></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">\approx</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> <em>Deep Learning researcher</em> <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mo>≈</mo></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">\approx</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> <em>ML intern</em> (the internship description very much seemed research-focused)</li>
<li><em>Data engineer</em> <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mo>≈</mo></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">\approx</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> <em>Data architect</em> <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mo>≈</mo></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">\approx</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> <em>Head of data</em> <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mo>≈</mo></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">\approx</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> <em>Data platform engineer</em></li>
</ul>
<figure>
    
  <a href="https://www.mihaileric.com/static/consolidated_roles-d0609bd70c768ce428b0873ea5ff1bd3-7931f.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
  
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="all machine learning, data science, data engineering roles at Y-Combinator companies consolidated into coarse categories" title="" src="https://www.mihaileric.com/static/consolidated_roles-d0609bd70c768ce428b0873ea5ff1bd3-3d61e.png" srcset="https://www.mihaileric.com/static/consolidated_roles-d0609bd70c768ce428b0873ea5ff1bd3-d182c.png 240w,
https://www.mihaileric.com/static/consolidated_roles-d0609bd70c768ce428b0873ea5ff1bd3-5220f.png 480w,
https://www.mihaileric.com/static/consolidated_roles-d0609bd70c768ce428b0873ea5ff1bd3-3d61e.png 960w,
https://www.mihaileric.com/static/consolidated_roles-d0609bd70c768ce428b0873ea5ff1bd3-7931f.png 985w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px">
    </span>
  </span>
  
  </a>
    
</figure>
<p>If we don’t like dealing with raw counts, here are some percentages to put us at ease:</p>
<figure>
    
  <a href="https://www.mihaileric.com/static/normalized_consolidated_roles-48138e6d849e501e2823381e49ba06e1-7931f.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
  
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="all machine learning, data science, data engineering roles at Y-Combinator companies normalized frequencies" title="" src="https://www.mihaileric.com/static/normalized_consolidated_roles-48138e6d849e501e2823381e49ba06e1-3d61e.png" srcset="https://www.mihaileric.com/static/normalized_consolidated_roles-48138e6d849e501e2823381e49ba06e1-d182c.png 240w,
https://www.mihaileric.com/static/normalized_consolidated_roles-48138e6d849e501e2823381e49ba06e1-5220f.png 480w,
https://www.mihaileric.com/static/normalized_consolidated_roles-48138e6d849e501e2823381e49ba06e1-3d61e.png 960w,
https://www.mihaileric.com/static/normalized_consolidated_roles-48138e6d849e501e2823381e49ba06e1-7931f.png 985w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px">
    </span>
  </span>
  
  </a>
    
</figure>
<p>I probably could have lumped <em>ML research engineer</em> into one of the <em>ML scientist</em> or <em>ML engineer</em> bins, but given that it was a bit of a hybrid role, I left it as is. </p>
<p>Overall the consolidation made the differences even more pronounced! There are <strong>~70%</strong> more open <em>data engineer</em> than <em>data scientist</em> positions. In addition, there are <strong>~40%</strong> more open <em>ML engineer</em> than <em>data scientist</em> positions. There are also only <strong>~30%</strong> as many <em>ML scientist</em> as <em>data scientist</em> positions. </p>
<h2>Takeaways</h2>
<p><em>Data engineers</em> are in increasingly high demand compared to other data-driven professions. In a sense, this represents an evolution for the broader field. </p>
<p>When machine learning become hot 🔥 5-8 years ago, companies decided they need people that can make classifiers on data. But then frameworks like <a href="https://www.tensorflow.org/">Tensorflow</a> and <a href="https://pytorch.org/">PyTorch</a> became really good, democratizing the ability to get started with deep learning and machine learning. </p>
<p>This commoditized the data modelling skillset. </p>
<p>Today, the bottleneck in helping companies get machine learning and modelling insights to production center on data problems. </p>
<p>How do you annotate data? How do you process and clean data? How do you move it from A to B? How do you do this every day as quickly as possible?</p>
<figure>
    
  <a href="https://www.mihaileric.com/static/patrick-951fdc9920aa2a6cc7b75e0959379665-321c9.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
  
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="patrick star moving data" title="" src="https://www.mihaileric.com/static/patrick-951fdc9920aa2a6cc7b75e0959379665-321c9.png" srcset="https://www.mihaileric.com/static/patrick-951fdc9920aa2a6cc7b75e0959379665-8c52f.png 240w,
https://www.mihaileric.com/static/patrick-951fdc9920aa2a6cc7b75e0959379665-0f208.png 480w,
https://www.mihaileric.com/static/patrick-951fdc9920aa2a6cc7b75e0959379665-321c9.png 720w" sizes="(max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px">
    </span>
  </span>
  
  </a>
    
</figure>
<p>All that amounts to having good engineering skills. </p>
<p>This may sound boring and unsexy, but old-school software engineering with a bend toward data may be what we really need right now. </p>
<p>For years, we’ve become enamored with the idea of data professionals that breathe life into raw data thanks to cool demos and media hype. After all, when was the last time you saw a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/">TechCrunch</a> article about an ETL pipeline? </p>
<p>If nothing else, I believe solid engineering is something we don’t emphasize enough in data science job training or educational programs. In addition to learning how to use <em>linear_regression.fit()</em>, learn how to write a unit test too!</p>
<p>So does that mean you shouldn’t study data science? No. </p>
<p>What it means is that competition is going to be tougher. There are going to be fewer positions available for what is looking to be an abundance of newcomers to the market trained to do data science. </p>
<p>There will always be a need for people that can effectively analyze and extract actionable insights from data. But they have to be good. </p>
<p>Downloading a pretrained model off the Tensorflow website on the <a href="https://scikit-learn.org/stable/auto_examples/datasets/plot_iris_dataset.html">Iris dataset</a> probably is no longer enough to get that data science job. </p>
<p>It’s clear, however, with the large number of <em>ML engineer</em> openings that companies often want a hybrid data practitioner: someone that can build and deploy models. Or said more succinctly, someone that can use Tensorflow but can also build it from source.</p>
<p>Another takeaway here is that there just aren’t that many ML research positions. </p>
<p>Machine learning research tends to get its fair share of hype because that’s where all the cutting-edge stuff happens, all the <a href="https://deepmind.com/research/case-studies/alphago-the-story-so-far">AlphaGo</a> and <a href="https://openai.com/blog/openai-api/">GPT-3</a> and what-not. </p>
<p>But for …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.mihaileric.com/posts/we-need-data-engineers-not-data-scientists/">https://www.mihaileric.com/posts/we-need-data-engineers-not-data-scientists/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.mihaileric.com/posts/we-need-data-engineers-not-data-scientists/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25775872</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 13:09:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Parisian Accent in 1912]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 297 | Comments 154 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25775091">thread link</a>) | @paganel
<br/>
January 14, 2021 | https://www.franceculture.fr/sciences-du-langage/archive-exceptionnelle-ecoutez-laccent-parisien-en-1912 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.franceculture.fr/sciences-du-langage/archive-exceptionnelle-ecoutez-laccent-parisien-en-1912">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>"C’est extraordinaire que j’aie une voix aussi traînarde, jamais je l’aurais cru ! On ne s’entend pas, absolument !" Dans ce document unique en son genre, un Parisien réagit à l'écoute de son propre accent, celui du 14e arrondissement, en 1912. Il est interviewé par le linguiste Ferdinand Brunot. </p><div>
            <p>Cette archive exceptionnelle est l’une des premières interviews sonores, le premier enregistrement d'un échange spontané, non lu. C’est aussi l’une des rares traces de l’accent parisien d’avant-guerre. En 1912, le linguiste Ferdinand Brunot veut enregistrer les dialectes des artisans. Ici, c’est le parler parisien qui l’intéresse, l’accent populaire des différents quartiers de la capitale. Louis Ligabue, tapissier dans le 14e arrondissement, a alors 37 ans, et note déjà l'embourgeoisement de son quartier.</p>

<h2>Le parler d'un pur "Parisien de Paris"</h2>
<p>Le linguiste Ferdinand Brunot, fondateur des "Archives de la parole"&nbsp;en 1911, est l'un des rares universitaires de son temps à s'intéresser à l'enregistrement du français parlé&nbsp;"commun". Pour lui, le "parler parisien" est une forme de dialecte dont il faut garder la trace. Chaque quartier de la capitale est censé présenter ses spécificités linguistiques&nbsp;: on ne parle pas à Montrouge comme à Montmartre. Or pour <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://gallica.bnf.fr/blog/11052020/quand-un-parisien-entend-pour-la-premiere-fois-le-son-de-sa-voix?mode=desktop">Pascal Cordereix</a>, responsable du service des documents sonores à la BnF, "<em>ce 'dialecte' parisien renvoie lui-même à l’un des plus grands mythes de la linguistique romane parisienne de la fin du XIXe siècle, à savoir le "françien", un supposé dialecte d’Île-de-France dans lequel le français trouverait sa seule origine. On est là au cœur de la construction jacobine de la langue française mise en œuvre après 1870, opposant définitivement français et autres idiomes parlés sur le territoire.</em>"</p>
<p><em>Ferdinand Brunot interviewe Louis Ligabue en 1912&nbsp;:&nbsp;</em></p>


<p>- Vous êtes vraiment, vous monsieur, un Parisien de Paris&nbsp;?&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>-</em> Je suis né à Paris même, boulevard Sébastopol et j’ai monté du côté de Montrouge, rue Daguerre. Ensuite, j’ai été avenue d’Orléans. J’ai travaillé dans le quartier constamment. Je ne l’ai jamais quitté du reste.&nbsp;</p>
<p>- Et vous êtes exclusivement tapissier, alors&nbsp;?&nbsp;</p>
<p>- Absolument. (...) et je travaille pour le client personnel (...)</p>
<p>- Vous êtes exclusivement dans la clientèle bourgeoise&nbsp;?&nbsp;</p>
<p>- Oui, monsieur.</p>
<p>- Il y a eu beaucoup d’installations de ce côté-là, ce doit être un bon métier&nbsp;?</p>
<p><em>-</em> Ah le quartier a beaucoup gagné. Nous avons depuis quelques années travaillé admirablement.</p>
<p>- J’ai entendu dire que vous n’étiez pas payé très régulièrement...</p>
<p>- Oh vous savez, le 14e est tout à fait spécial. Nous avons de bons clients, de bons bourgeois, et puis régulièrement, on hésite à donner une affaire... Mais quant au règlement, jamais nous ne perdons quoi que ce soit.&nbsp;</p>
<p>- On m’avait dit au contraire que rue Alphonse Daudet, il y avait une clientèle peu recommandable...</p>
<p>- Ah dame ! Ça, je m’en réjouis bien !</p>
<h2>Entendre sa propre voix</h2>
<p>Ce document est unique à plus d'un titre&nbsp;: c’est aussi la première fois qu’on entend quelqu’un réagir à ses propos, à sa voix. &nbsp;Dans la foulée de l’interview, Louis Ligabue s’écoute, et s’étonne, toujours en dialoguant avec le linguiste Ferdinand Brunot. <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://gallica.bnf.fr/blog/11052020/quand-un-parisien-entend-pour-la-premiere-fois-le-son-de-sa-voix?mode=desktop">Pascal Cordereix</a>, spécialiste du fonds sonore ancien à la Bibliothèque nationale de France (BnF)&nbsp;: "<em>On connaît beaucoup de récits écrits d’un enregistrement et de la surprise du locuteur s’écoutant parler. Mais à notre connaissance, Ferdinand Brunot est le seul, avant longtemps, à avoir l’idée de graver ainsi sur disque les réactions du témoin à l’écoute de sa propre voix.</em>"</p>
<p><strong>Ferdinand Brunot interviewe Louis Ligabue en 1912&nbsp;:&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p>- Eh bien, vous avez entendu ce que vous avez dit. Vous êtes-vous reconnu&nbsp;?&nbsp;</p>
<p>- Oui, parfaitement monsieur !</p>
<p>- N’est-ce pas que c’est bien votre voix&nbsp;?&nbsp;</p>
<p>- C’est parfait, parfait, c’est même très très curieux ! C’est très drôle, il me semble même que c’est extraordinaire que j’aie une voix si traînarde, jamais je ne l’aurais cru ! On ne s’entend pas, absolument !&nbsp;</p>
<p>- Vous n’avez pas la voix traînarde, vous avez tout simplement l’accent de Paris, c’est justement ça que je veux enregistrer.&nbsp;</p>
<p>- Ah ça aujourd'hui j’en suis convaincu, bien des gens m’ont dit des fois&nbsp;: “Comme il traîne ce garçon dans sa conversation”. Ben, je disais non, pourtant, il me semble que c’est tout naturel&nbsp;; mais alors là, vous savez, j’ai un accent presque d’La Villette on dirait…</p>
<p>- La Villette&nbsp;? Ne croyez-vous pas qu’il y a une grande différence justement entre l’accent de La Villette et le vôtre&nbsp;?</p>
<p>- Ah peut-être, je ne sais pas…</p>
<p>- Vous qui êtes de Paris, est-ce que vous ne reconnaissez pas justement quelqu’un qui est de nos arrondissements&nbsp;?</p>
<p>- Ah absolument, si, il y a réellement des différences.</p>
<p>- Quelqu’un qui s’est beaucoup occupé de ça me disait par exemple qu’il reconnaissait du premier coup un habitant du 14e et un habitant de Montmartre.</p>
<p>- Ah peut-être, mais enfin, il me semble que c’est une étude assez sérieuse.</p>
<p>- Oui, il y a des gars qui imitent ça étonnamment et à volonté vous savez, ils se transforment en gens de Montparnasse, ou en gens de Montmartre comme ils veulent.</p>
<p>- Ah oui, on voit ça dans les revues, là, dans les concerts, là&nbsp;; on a des types spéciaux là-dessus.</p>
<p>- Oui. Est-ce que dans la rue de la Gaîté, là, il y a des gens qui imitent justement l’accent du quartier&nbsp;?</p>
<p>- Ah y en a, y en a. Mais alors, ça devient peut-être un peu en exagération. Tandis que là, moi, je cause naturellement, et quand j’écoute, il me semble que j’exagère… Je suis bien content, vous savez, d’avoir jugé et ça m’a bien intéressé !</p>
<p>- Et bien je vous remercie de vous être prêté à l’expérience.</p>
<p>- De rien.</p>
<h2>Les Archives de la parole à découvrir sur Gallica</h2>
<p>Archive conservée à la Bibliothèque nationale de France. Merci au service Son du département de l’Audiovisuel, BnF et au Service de la coopération numérique et de Gallica, BnF. Archives de la Parole, conservation&nbsp;: BnF, Département de l’Audiovisuel, service Son.</p>
<ul>
<li><a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://gallica.bnf.fr/html/und/enregistrements-sonores/archives-de-la-parole-ferdinand-brunot-1911-1914">Les Archives de la parole, 1911-1914</a></li>
<li><a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://gallica.bnf.fr/html/und/enregistrements-sonores/archives-de-la-parole-jean-poirot-enregistrements-la-sorbonne">Les Archives de la parole, 1920-1924</a></li>
<li><a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://gallica.bnf.fr/html/und/enregistrements-sonores/archives-de-la-parole-musee-de-la-parole-et-du-geste-hubert-pernot-1924-1930">Les Archives de la parole, 1924-1930</a></li>
</ul>



    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.franceculture.fr/sciences-du-langage/archive-exceptionnelle-ecoutez-laccent-parisien-en-1912</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25775091</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 11:26:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Tracing and visualizing the Python GIL with perf and VizTracer]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 54 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25774945">thread link</a>) | @maartenbreddels
<br/>
January 14, 2021 | https://www.maartenbreddels.com/perf/jupyter/python/tracing/gil/2021/01/14/Tracing-the-Python-GIL.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.maartenbreddels.com/perf/jupyter/python/tracing/gil/2021/01/14/Tracing-the-Python-GIL.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<div>
<div>

<p>There are plenty of articles explaining why the Python GIL (The Global Interpreter Lock) exists<sup id="fnref-1"><a href="#fn-1">1</a></sup>, and why it is there. The TLDR version is: the GIL prevents multithreaded pure Python code from using multiple CPU cores.</p>
<p>However, in <a href="https://vaex.io/">Vaex</a> we execute most of the CPU intensive parts in C (C++) code, where we release the GIL. This is a common practice in high-performance Python libraries, where Python acts merely as a high-level glue.</p>
<p>However, the GIL needs to be released explicitly, and this is the responsibility of the programmer and might be forgotten, leading to suboptimal use of your machine.</p>
<p>I recently had this issue in <a href="https://github.com/vaexio/vaex/pull/1114">Vaex</a> where I simply forgot to release the GIL and found a similar issue in <a href="https://github.com/apache/arrow/pull/7756">Apache Arrow</a><sup id="fnref-2"><a href="#fn-2">2</a></sup>.</p>
<p>Also, when running on 64 cores, I sometimes see a performance in Vaex that I am not happy with. It might be using 4000% CPU, instead of 6400% CPU, which is something I am not happy with. Instead of blindly pulling some levers to inspect the effect, I want to understand what is happening, and if the GIL is the problem, why, and where is it holding Vaex down.</p>


</div>
</div>
</div><div>
<div>
<div>

<p>I'm planning to write a series of articles explaining some tools and techniques available for profiling/tracing Python together with native extensions, and how these tools can be glued together, to analyze and visualize what Python is doing, and when the GIL it taken or dropped.</p>
<p>I hope this leads to improvement of tracing, profiling, and other performance tooling in the Python ecosystem, and the performance of the whole Python ecosystem.</p>

<h2 id="Linux">
Linux<a href="#Linux"> </a>
</h2>
<p>Get access to a Linux machine, and make sure you have root privileges (sudo is fine), or ask your sysadmin to execute some of these commands for you. For the rest of the document, we only run as user.</p>
<h2 id="Perf">
Perf<a href="#Perf"> </a>
</h2>
<p>Make sure you have perf installed, e.g. on Ubuntu:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo yum install perf</code></pre>
<h2 id="Kernel-configuration">
Kernel configuration<a href="#Kernel-configuration"> </a>
</h2>
<p>To enable running it as a user:</p>

<pre><code># Enable users to run perf (use at own risk)
$ sudo sysctl kernel.perf_event_paranoid=-1

# Enable users to see schedule trace events:
$ sudo mount -o remount,mode=755 /sys/kernel/debug
$ sudo mount -o remount,mode=755 /sys/kernel/debug/tracing</code></pre>
<h2 id="Python-packages">
Python packages<a href="#Python-packages"> </a>
</h2>
<p>We will make use of <a href="https://github.com/gaogaotiantian/viztracer/">VizTracer</a> and <a href="https://github.com/maartenbreddels/per4m">per4m</a></p>

<pre><code>$ pip install "viztracer&gt;=0.11.2" "per4m&gt;=0.1,&lt;0.2"</code></pre>

</div>
</div>
</div><div>
<div>
<div>

<p>There is no way to get the GIL state in Python <sup id="fnref-3"><a href="#fn-3">1</a></sup> since there is no API for this. We can track it from the kernel, and the right tool for this under Linux is <strong>perf</strong>.</p>
<p>Using the linux perf tool (aka perf_events), we can listen to the state changes for processes/threads (we only care about sleeping and running), and log them. Although perf may look scary, it is a powerful tool. If you want to know a bit more about perf, I recommend reading <a href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2018/04/16/new-perf-zine/">Julia Evans' zine on perf</a> or <a href="http://www.brendangregg.com/perf.html">go through Brendan Gregg's website</a>.</p>
<p>To build our intuition, we will first run perf on a <a href="https://github.com/maartenbreddels/per4m/blob/master/per4m/example0.py">very trivial program</a>:</p>


</div>
</div>
</div><div>
<div>
<div>
<p>We listen to just a few events to keep the noise down (note the use of wildcards):</p>

<pre><code>$ perf record -e sched:sched_switch  -e sched:sched_process_fork \
        -e 'sched:sched_wak*' -- python -m per4m.example0
[ perf record: Woken up 2 times to write data ]
[ perf record: Captured and wrote 0,032 MB perf.data (33 samples) ]</code></pre>
<p>And use the <code>perf script</code> command to write human/parsable output.</p>

<pre><code>$ perf script
        :3040108 3040108 [032] 5563910.979408:                sched:sched_waking: comm=perf pid=3040114 prio=120 target_cpu=031
        :3040108 3040108 [032] 5563910.979431:                sched:sched_wakeup: comm=perf pid=3040114 prio=120 target_cpu=031
          python 3040114 [031] 5563910.995616:                sched:sched_waking: comm=kworker/31:1 pid=2502104 prio=120 target_cpu=031
          python 3040114 [031] 5563910.995618:                sched:sched_wakeup: comm=kworker/31:1 pid=2502104 prio=120 target_cpu=031
          python 3040114 [031] 5563910.995621:                sched:sched_waking: comm=ksoftirqd/31 pid=198 prio=120 target_cpu=031
          python 3040114 [031] 5563910.995622:                sched:sched_wakeup: comm=ksoftirqd/31 pid=198 prio=120 target_cpu=031
          python 3040114 [031] 5563910.995624:                sched:sched_switch: prev_comm=python prev_pid=3040114 prev_prio=120 prev_state=R+ ==&gt; next_comm=kworker/31:1 next_pid=2502104 next_prio=120
          python 3040114 [031] 5563911.003612:                sched:sched_waking: comm=kworker/32:1 pid=2467833 prio=120 target_cpu=032
          python 3040114 [031] 5563911.003614:                sched:sched_wakeup: comm=kworker/32:1 pid=2467833 prio=120 target_cpu=032
          python 3040114 [031] 5563911.083609:                sched:sched_waking: comm=ksoftirqd/31 pid=198 prio=120 target_cpu=031
          python 3040114 [031] 5563911.083612:                sched:sched_wakeup: comm=ksoftirqd/31 pid=198 prio=120 target_cpu=031
          python 3040114 [031] 5563911.083613:                sched:sched_switch: prev_comm=python prev_pid=3040114 prev_prio=120 prev_state=R ==&gt; next_comm=ksoftirqd/31 next_pid=198 next_prio=120
          python 3040114 [031] 5563911.108984:                sched:sched_waking: comm=node pid=2446812 prio=120 target_cpu=045
          python 3040114 [031] 5563911.109059:                sched:sched_waking: comm=node pid=2446812 prio=120 target_cpu=045
          python 3040114 [031] 5563911.112250:          sched:sched_process_fork: comm=python pid=3040114 child_comm=python child_pid=3040116
          python 3040114 [031] 5563911.112260:            sched:sched_wakeup_new: comm=python pid=3040116 prio=120 target_cpu=037
          python 3040114 [031] 5563911.112262:            sched:sched_wakeup_new: comm=python pid=3040116 prio=120 target_cpu=037
          python 3040114 [031] 5563911.112273:                sched:sched_switch: prev_comm=python prev_pid=3040114 prev_prio=120 prev_state=S ==&gt; next_comm=swapper/31 next_pid=0 next_prio=120
          python 3040116 [037] 5563911.112418:                sched:sched_waking: comm=python pid=3040114 prio=120 target_cpu=031
          python 3040116 [037] 5563911.112450:                sched:sched_waking: comm=python pid=3040114 prio=120 target_cpu=031
          python 3040116 [037] 5563911.112473: sched:sched_wake_idle_without_ipi: cpu=31
         swapper     0 [031] 5563911.112476:                sched:sched_wakeup: comm=python pid=3040114 prio=120 target_cpu=031
          python 3040114 [031] 5563911.112485:                sched:sched_switch: prev_comm=python prev_pid=3040114 prev_prio=120 prev_state=S ==&gt; next_comm=swapper/31 next_pid=0 next_prio=120
          python 3040116 [037] 5563911.112485:                sched:sched_waking: comm=python pid=3040114 prio=120 target_cpu=031
          python 3040116 [037] 5563911.112489:                sched:sched_waking: comm=python pid=3040114 prio=120 target_cpu=031
          python 3040116 [037] 5563911.112496:                sched:sched_switch: prev_comm=python prev_pid=3040116 prev_prio=120 prev_state=S ==&gt; next_comm=swapper/37 next_pid=0 next_prio=120
         swapper     0 [031] 5563911.112497:                sched:sched_wakeup: comm=python pid=3040114 prio=120 target_cpu=031
          python 3040114 [031] 5563911.112513:                sched:sched_switch: prev_comm=python prev_pid=3040114 prev_prio=120 prev_state=S ==&gt; next_comm=swapper/31 next_pid=0 next_prio=120
         swapper     0 [037] 5563912.113490:                sched:sched_waking: comm=python pid=3040116 prio=120 target_cpu=037
         swapper     0 [037] 5563912.113529:                sched:sched_wakeup: comm=python pid=3040116 prio=120 target_cpu=037
          python 3040116 [037] 5563912.113595:                sched:sched_waking: comm=python pid=3040114 prio=120 target_cpu=031
          python 3040116 [037] 5563912.113620:                sched:sched_waking: comm=python pid=3040114 prio=120 target_cpu=031
         swapper     0 [031] 5563912.113697:                sched:sched_wakeup: comm=python pid=3040114 prio=120 target_cpu=031</code></pre>

</div>
</div>
</div><div>
<div>
<div>
<p>Take a moment to digest the output. I can see a few things. Looking at the 4th column (time in seconds), we can see where the program slept (it skips 1 second). Here we see that we enter the sleeping state with a line like:</p>
<p><code>python 3040114 [031] 5563911.112513:                sched:sched_switch: prev_comm=python prev_pid=3040114 prev_prio=120 prev_state=S ==&gt; next_comm=swapper/31 next_pid=0 next_prio=120</code></p>
<p>This means the kernel changed the state of the Python thread to <code>S</code> (=sleeping) state.</p>
<p>A full second later, we see it being woken up:</p>
<p><code>swapper     0 [031] 5563912.113697:                sched:sched_wakeup: comm=python pid=3040114 prio=120 target_cpu=031</code></p>
<p>Of course, you need to build some tooling around this, to really see what is happening. But one can imagine this output can be easily parsed and this is what <a href="https://github.com/maartenbreddels/per4m/">per4m</a> does. However, before we go there, I'd first like to visualize the flow of a slightly more advanced program using <a href="https://github.com/gaogaotiantian/viztracer/">VizTracer</a>.</p>

</div>
</div>
</div><div>
<div>
<div>

<p><a href="https://github.com/gaogaotiantian/viztracer/">VizTracer</a> is a Python tracer that can visualize what your program does in the browser. Let us run it on a slightly <a href="https://github.com/maartenbreddels/per4m/blob/master/per4m/example1.py">more advanced example</a> to see what it looks like.</p>

</div>
</div>
</div><div>
<div>
<div>
<p>Running viztracer gives output like:</p>

<pre><code>$ viztracer -o example1.html --ignore_frozen -m per4m.example1
Loading finish                                        
Saving report to /home/maartenbreddels/github/maartenbreddels/per4m/example1.html ...
Dumping trace data to json, total entries: 94, estimated json file size: 11.0KiB
Generating HTML report
Report saved.</code></pre>
<p>And the HTML should render as:
<img src="https://www.maartenbreddels.com/images/copied_from_nb/per4m/example1.png" alt="image.png"></p>
<p>From this, it seems that <code>some_computation</code> seem to be executed in parallel (twice), while in fact, we know the GIL is preventing that. So what is really going on?</p>

</div>
</div>
</div><div>
<div>
<div>

<p>Let us run <code>perf</code> on this, similarly to what we did to example0.py. However, we add the argument <code>-k CLOCK_MONOTONIC</code> so that we use <a href="https://github.com/gaogaotiantian/viztracer/blob/3321ba4024afe5623f938a601d7f7db3b08f534d/src/viztracer/modules/snaptrace.c#L91">the same clock as VizTracer</a> and ask VizTracer to generate a JSON, instead of an HTML file:</p>

<pre><code>$ perf record -e sched:sched_switch  -e sched:sched_process_fork -e 'sched:sched_wak*' \
   -k CLOCK_MONOTONIC  -- viztracer -o viztracer1.json --ignore_frozen -m per4m.example1</code></pre>
<p>Then …</p></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.maartenbreddels.com/perf/jupyter/python/tracing/gil/2021/01/14/Tracing-the-Python-GIL.html">https://www.maartenbreddels.com/perf/jupyter/python/tracing/gil/2021/01/14/Tracing-the-Python-GIL.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.maartenbreddels.com/perf/jupyter/python/tracing/gil/2021/01/14/Tracing-the-Python-GIL.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25774945</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 11:06:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Analyzing the performance of Tensorflow training on M1 Mac Mini and Nvidia V100]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 222 | Comments 81 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25773109">thread link</a>) | @briggers
<br/>
January 13, 2021 | https://wandb.ai/vanpelt/m1-benchmark/reports/Can-Apple-s-M1-help-you-train-models-faster-cheaper-than-NVIDIA-s-V100---VmlldzozNTkyMzg | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://wandb.ai/vanpelt/m1-benchmark/reports/Can-Apple-s-M1-help-you-train-models-faster-cheaper-than-NVIDIA-s-V100---VmlldzozNTkyMzg">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://wandb.ai/vanpelt/m1-benchmark/reports/Can-Apple-s-M1-help-you-train-models-faster-cheaper-than-NVIDIA-s-V100---VmlldzozNTkyMzg</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25773109</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 07:04:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[If you want peace, study war]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 196 | Comments 192 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25772365">thread link</a>) | @ascertain
<br/>
January 13, 2021 | https://www.persuasion.community/p/if-you-want-peace-study-war-533 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.persuasion.community/p/if-you-want-peace-study-war-533">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure><a target="_blank" href="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fee9f8cb1-eee9-4e69-bce8-d7b52537900a_3896x2568.jpeg"><img src="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fee9f8cb1-eee9-4e69-bce8-d7b52537900a_3896x2568.jpeg" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/ee9f8cb1-eee9-4e69-bce8-d7b52537900a_3896x2568.jpeg&quot;,&quot;height&quot;:960,&quot;width&quot;:1456,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:null,&quot;bytes&quot;:1194587,&quot;alt&quot;:null,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;image/jpeg&quot;,&quot;href&quot;:null}" alt=""></a></figure></div><p><strong>“War…What is it good for?” </strong>the classic song asks. Many universities agree on the answer: “Absolutely nothing.”</p><p>Although anthropologists and archeologists still wonder why human beings have for so long organized themselves to fight, the study of war in history and political science departments is fading. Senior scholars are retiring and not being replaced, or their posts are allocated to other fields of history. Each year, fewer courses are offered on great conflicts such as the Napoleonic wars, the total wars of the 20th century, and the Cold War. The Second World War, you may hear on campus, “has been done.”</p><p>Yet war remains one of the events—along with revolution, famine, financial collapse and, as we are learning again, pandemics—that change the course of history. In privileged countries, we forget the importance of military conflicts because we have enjoyed the “Long Peace” that followed the Second World War. Other places have not been so fortunate, with wars around the world almost every year since 1945, bringing millions of deaths and creating millions more refugees. Meanwhile, the world’s great powers maintain large military establishments, and still prepare for battle. </p><p>It is as important as ever to understand war—its causes, nature and consequences—and the many ways that conflicts have shaped our societies. The conquering armies that came from the Arabian Peninsula in the 7th century after the Prophet Mohammad’s death created new empires and spread the new religion of Islam across the Middle East, North Africa and the Iberian Peninsula. The Seven Years’ War (1756-1763), a global conflict, laid the foundations for the dominance of the British Empire and the bankruptcy of France, which helped to fuel the French Revolution.&nbsp; </p><p>War can also speed up advances in science and technology that have benefits in peacetime. Think of the development of penicillin, blood transfusions, radar, or the transistor. And war can bring about significant social change, often for the better. The need for mass armies in the 19th and 20th centuries meant that governments had to treat the lower classes better, whether by educating them or by improving public health. In many countries that fought in the two world wars, ruling classes recognized the contributions of women and the working classes, granting them the franchise and introducing social benefits. </p><p>So why do history faculties, which accept the need to study other great forces in history, such as changes in the means of production or systems of belief, shy from war? I suspect that horror at the phenomenon itself has affected universities’ willingness to treat it as a subject for scholarship. Years ago, when I proposed a new course on war and society, an education consultant asked me, “Why don’t you call it peace studies?” </p><p>I have since met with incomprehension, even hostility, when I have pointed out that wars can bring unintended benefits. However much I say that we would not <em>choose</em> to make war in order to improve our societies, I am charged with loving war. Yet nobody would say that the study of imperialism, racism or famine means that we think those are good things.</p><p><strong>The history of war is neglected for other reasons, too. </strong>First, separate histories—of women, emotions, food and the environment, for example—have come along. Quite rightly, room has been made for them in the big and eclectic house that is the study of the past. However, part of the shift away from war studies owes to the quest for “social justice”—intended as a drive for radical change in society at large—that has taken root in many history faculties. </p><p>Here, for example, is how the chair of Historical and Cultural Studies at the Scarborough campus of the University of Toronto, Natalie Rothman, <a href="https://www.utsc.utoronto.ca/hcs/">welcomed students</a> this autumn: “As a department, we have strengthened our resolve to confront racism, colonialism and Islamophobia throughout our curriculum and in our co-curricular initiatives.” The University of Berkeley in California <a href="https://history.berkeley.edu/graduate/prospective-students/admissions">asks prospective graduate students</a> to provide “evidence of how you have come to understand the barriers faced by others, evidence of your academic service to advance equitable access to higher education for women, racial minorities, and individuals from other groups that have been historically underrepresented in higher education, evidence of your research focusing on underserved populations or related issues of inequality, or evidence of your leadership among such groups.” It is hard to quarrel with such goals, but their impact on curriculum has been to <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2016/08/29/opinion/why-did-we-stop-teaching-political-history.html?smid=em-share">downgrade subjects such as political and military history,</a> which are seen as too focused on elites and complicit with hierarchy and oppression. </p><p>Another factor is that history overall is worryingly in decline as an academic subject. While it remains popular among publishers and readers, enrollments in history majors are significantly down. They have <a href="https://www.historians.org/publications-and-directories/perspectives-on-history/december-2018/the-history-ba-since-the-great-recession-the-2018-aha-majors-report">dropped more than any other major</a> in the humanities—perhaps by as much as <a href="http://www.chronicle.com/article/why-are-students-ditching-the-history-major">one-third</a> in <a href="https://www.insidehighered.com/news/2018/11/27/new-analysis-history-major-data-says-field-new-low-can-it-be-saved">American universities</a> in the past decade. At the University of Toronto, where I am a professor, colleagues fear that history enrollment may be down as much as 50% over the same period. Even in the United Kingdom, where history remains popular among undergraduates, the number of those majoring in history has dropped by about <a href="https://www.economist.com/britain/2019/07/18/the-study-of-history-is-in-decline-in-britain">one-tenth</a> in the past decade. </p><p>Part of the reason is that, given the lingering effects of the 2008 financial crisis and uncertainty over the economy, students and their parents want university courses to lead to jobs. The decline in history students in turn affects university hiring, and the fewer the tenured faculty, the fewer places for the doctoral students who are the future of the profession.&nbsp; </p><p>Faculties and administrators are not necessarily helping matters, reluctant to include popular courses on war in the curriculum, or to support well-established centers for the study of conflict, some of which are being remodeled, such as the Laurier Centre for Military, Strategic and Disarmament Studies, in Waterloo, Ontario, which will focus more on Canadian history; another at the University of Calgary is fading as those who retire are not replaced. This seems to be particularly true of elite universities. War studies remains in better health at military colleges or some second-tier public universities, while schools of public policy are also still teaching military history, strategic studies and diplomatic history. </p><p>But those in other fields stereotype war studies, characterizing it as too narrowly focused on tactics, battles, or “toys for boys,” meaning armaments. If that caricature were ever true, it has not been for decades. The great historian Sir Michael Howard, who pioneered the modern study of war and trained generations of historians, always insisted that what he was doing was to consider wars within their social and political contexts as a part of the great sweep of history, not somehow separate from it. &nbsp;</p><p><strong>My own evidence of the distaste for military and diplomatic history </strong>at North American universities comes from tales exchanged privately among fellow academics. One retired Canadian military historian recounted that his old faculty had asked him how to reverse the collapse in enrollment. He suggested a course in military history, but the response was a flat no. When a university in the Maritime provinces of eastern Canada was offered a fully funded post in naval history a few years ago—a good fit in a port town that had been deeply affected by conflict on the Atlantic—members of the department rejected it. </p><p>Yet, despite the overall downturn in university history programs, we know from course enrollments that students are interested in war, as indeed they are in international relations, when they get the chance to study them: At Yale, Paul Kennedy’s “Military History of the West” attracted large crowds; at Toronto’s Ryerson University, international relations courses are the most popular choices among students.</p><p>I would not suggest that student preference should determine what departments offer. But they should at least be listened to. Much more important is what we, as societies, want our future leaders to know. Political history, diplomatic history and the study of war—they all offer critical warnings and instructive analogies to our times. Social and cultural histories, and history from the bottom up, add to our understanding too. But we need balance, and a sense of how the micro- and macro-histories mesh with each other. </p><p>Do we really want citizens who have so little knowledge of how war helped to shape our values and societies and our world? Do we ever want another president asking, as Donald Trump <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/trump-pearl-harbor-memorial-tour-john-kelly-stable-genius-2020-1?r=US&amp;IR=T">did</a> during a visit to the Pearl Harbor memorial: “What’s this all about? What’s this a tour of?” </p><p>If we aren’t aware of how wars happen, we may fail to recognize warning signs when the next conflict brews, as it will. </p><p><strong>Margaret MacMillan is a professor of history at the University of Toronto and emeritus professor at the University of Oxford. Her latest book, </strong><em><strong><a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/609692/war-how-conflict-shaped-us-by-margaret-macmillan/">War: How Conflict Shaped Us</a></strong></em><strong>, was among the </strong><em><strong>New York Times</strong></em><strong> 10 Best Books of 2020. </strong></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.persuasion.community/p/if-you-want-peace-study-war-533</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25772365</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 05:10:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Only M1 Benchmark That Matters]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 95 | Comments 52 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25769469">thread link</a>) | @nemoniac
<br/>
January 13, 2021 | https://lars.ingebrigtsen.no/2021/01/13/the-only-m1-benchmark-that-matters/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://lars.ingebrigtsen.no/2021/01/13/the-only-m1-benchmark-that-matters/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-79875">
	
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>
		<p><a href="https://lars.ingebrigtsen.no/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/DSC02169.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="https://lars.ingebrigtsen.no/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/DSC02169-scaled.jpg" alt="" width="840" height="558" srcset="https://lars.ingebrigtsen.no/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/DSC02169-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://lars.ingebrigtsen.no/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/DSC02169-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lars.ingebrigtsen.no/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/DSC02169-1024x681.jpg 1024w, https://lars.ingebrigtsen.no/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/DSC02169-768x511.jpg 768w, https://lars.ingebrigtsen.no/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/DSC02169-1536x1021.jpg 1536w, https://lars.ingebrigtsen.no/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/DSC02169-2048x1362.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 840px) 100vw, 840px"></a></p>
<p>I’ve got a new Apple laptop, so I thought I’d do an Emacs build benchmark.  Building Emacs is what people do on computers, right?  At least if I extrapolate from myself, which is the only natural thing to do.</p>
<p>It’s called proof by induction.  Look it up, nerds.</p>
<p>So here’s the benchmarks:</p>
<table>
<tbody><tr>
<td>My Main Build Machine</td>
<td>AMD Ryzen 7 3700X (8 Core/16 Threads)</td>
<td>2m14s</td>
<td>7m31</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>My Lenovo Carbon X1 Laptop</td>
<td>Intel(R) Core(TM) i7-10610U CPU (4 Core/4 Threads)</td>
<td>6m22s</td>
<td>15m22</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>My Old Apple Laptop</td>
<td>Intel(R) Core(TM) i5-7360U CPU (2 Core/4 Threads)</td>
<td>7m13s</td>
<td>12m33</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>My New M1 Apple Laptop</td>
<td>Apple M1 (4-to-8-ish Cores)</td>
<td>2m44s</td>
<td>6m37s</td>
</tr>
</tbody></table>
<p>The next-to-last column is with -jTO-THE-MAX, and the last column is with -j1.</p>
<p>I’m impressed!  The M1 is able to build Emacs almost as fast as my AMD machine…  which is a lot bigger.</p>
<p>Of course, on Debian I’m using gcc and on Macos I’m using clang, so it’s an apples-to-some-different-brand-of-apples comparison.</p>
<p>It’s even more impressive how much faster this laptop is compared to the Apple laptop from…  2019?  Yeah.  It’s more than twice as fast!  And doesn’t have a fan!  The old Apple laptop would sound like a VAX in a hurricane while building Emacs!</p>
<p>And it’s also twice as fast as the laptop I use daily here on the couch; last year’s Lenovo Carbon X1, which is just embarrassing.  Lenovo!  Get on it!  Make an ARM laptop that’s fast!</p>
<p>For the first time in my life, I have Apple envy.  That is, for the first time ever, they’ve made a laptop that’s clearly superior to what’s available for us Linux peeps.  My only comfort is that the Apple keyboard still sucks.  Yeah!  And it doesn’t have a TrackPoint!  Yeah!  My laptop is still the best!  Yeah!  Take that!</p>
<p><a href="https://lars.ingebrigtsen.no/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/DSC02170.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="https://lars.ingebrigtsen.no/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/DSC02170-scaled.jpg" alt="" width="840" height="558" srcset="https://lars.ingebrigtsen.no/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/DSC02170-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://lars.ingebrigtsen.no/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/DSC02170-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lars.ingebrigtsen.no/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/DSC02170-1024x681.jpg 1024w, https://lars.ingebrigtsen.no/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/DSC02170-768x511.jpg 768w, https://lars.ingebrigtsen.no/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/DSC02170-1536x1021.jpg 1536w, https://lars.ingebrigtsen.no/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/DSC02170-2048x1362.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 840px) 100vw, 840px"></a></p>
<p>Yeah!  I’m not the least envious!</p>
<p>*sniff*</p>
<p>Edit some hours later:</p>
<p>But one thing that would be interesting to look at is Emacs performance on M1 vs the other machines.  And a way to broadly look at that is to see how long it takes to byte-compile a bunch of Emacs Lisp files: This exercises much of Emacs, except display-related stuff.</p>
<p>So:  Benchmarking with</p>
<pre>rm `find lisp -name '*.elc'`; time make -jMAX</pre>
<p>I get:</p>
<table>
<tbody><tr>
<td>My Main Build Machine</td>
<td>AMD Ryzen 7 3700X (8 Core/16 Threads)</td>
<td>0m57s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>My Lenovo Carbon X1 Laptop</td>
<td>Intel(R) Core(TM) i7-10610U CPU (4 Core/4 Threads)</td>
<td>4m13s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>My Old Apple Laptop</td>
<td>Intel(R) Core(TM) i5-7360U CPU (2 Core/4 Threads)</td>
<td>5m33s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>My New M1 Apple Laptop</td>
<td>Apple M1 (4-to-8-ish Cores)</td>
<td>1m33s</td>
</tr>
</tbody></table>
<p>Here the AMD clearly wins over the ARM, but per-core performance is in advantage of the ARM.  And, of course, the ARM soundly wins over both of the other two laptops.</p>

	</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	
	<!-- .entry-footer -->

</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://lars.ingebrigtsen.no/2021/01/13/the-only-m1-benchmark-that-matters/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25769469</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 23:27:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[An Unlikely Database Migration]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 354 | Comments 173 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25767128">thread link</a>) | @ifcologne
<br/>
January 13, 2021 | https://tailscale.com/blog/an-unlikely-database-migration/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://tailscale.com/blog/an-unlikely-database-migration/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <h4 id="brad-joins-a-startup">Brad joins a startup</h4>
<p>When I first joined <a href="https://tailscale.com/">Tailscale</a> almost a year
ago, one of the first things I asked
<a href="https://github.com/crawshaw">Crawshaw</a> was, “So, what database do you
use? MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite maybe?”, knowing that he loved SQLite.</p>
<p>“A text file," he replied.</p>
<p>“Huh?”</p>
<p>“Yeah, we write out one big JSON object to a text file.”</p>
<p>“How? When? <em>What?</em>”</p>
<p>“Yeah, whenever something changes, we grab a lock in our single
process and rewrite out the file!” he chuckled with glee.</p>
<p>It sounded insane. It <em>was</em> insane. Sure, it was easily testable, but
it didn’t scale. We both knew that. But it worked.</p>
<p>Until it didn’t.</p>
<p>Even with fast NVMe drives and splitting the database into two halves
(important data vs. ephemeral data that we could lose on a tmpfs),
things got slower and slower. We knew the day would come. The file
reached a peak size of 150MB and we were writing it as quickly as the
disk I/O would let us. Ain’t that just peachy?</p>
<p>So, migrate to MySQL or PostgreSQL, right? Maybe SQLite?</p>
<p>Nope, Crawshaw had other ideas.</p>
<h4 id="a-bit-of-backstory-from-david">A bit of backstory from David</h4>
<p>Tailscale’s coordination server, our “control plane”, has become known
as <a href="https://getsmart.fandom.com/wiki/CONTROL">CONTROL</a>. It’s currently
a single Go process on a single VM. The very earliest prototypes for
CONTROL used SQLite. Our original designs were very different from
what we ended up with, involving configuration databases synchronized
onto client machines and all sorts of other concepts we ended up not
needing. Through this process we would do major reorganizations of our
SQL data model every week, which required an astonishing amount of
typing. SQL is widely used, durable, effective, and requires an
annoying amount of glue to bring into just about any programming
language. (Attempts to avoid this with ORMs usually replace an
annoying amount of typing with an annoying amount of magic and loss of
efficiency.)</p>
<p>One day, fed up with the refactorings, I threw it all out and built an
in-memory data model for experimentation. That made iterating
much faster. A couple of weeks later, a customer wanted to try it
out. I wasn’t ready to commit to the data model yet and do it properly
in SQL, so I took a shortcut: the object holding all the data was
wrapped in a <code>sync.Mutex</code>, all accesses went through it, and on edit the
whole structure was passed to <code>json.Marshal</code> and written to disk. This
gave us data model persistence in ~20 lines of Go.</p>
<p>The plan was always to migrate to something else but, uh, we got busy
with other stuff and kinda forgot.</p>
<h4 id="what-comes-after-jsonmutexdb">What comes after JSONMutexDB?</h4>
<p>The obvious next step to take was to move to SQL. My favorite is still
SQLite, but I couldn’t bring myself to make an argument for migrating
a rapidly growing service to it. It certainly could work, especially
as the design of our control plane doesn’t require the high
availability of typical web services: the result of a short outage is
that new nodes can’t log in; working networks continue to work.</p>
<p>MySQL (or PostgreSQL) would come next. I’m not particularly familiar
with anything MySQL post 1998, but I’m sure it would work. The HA
story for open source databases is somewhat surprising, though: you
can either have traditional lagging replicas, or commit to
no-primary-replica clusters that have very surprising transaction
semantics. I wasn’t excited about trying to design a stable API or
good network graph calculations on top of those semantics.
<a href="https://github.com/cockroachdb/cockroach#what-is-cockroachdb">CockroachDB</a>
looked very promising, and indeed still does! But it’s relatively new
for a database and I was a little concerned about getting attached to
features in a fresh DBMS that would be hard to migrate away from if we
needed to.</p>
<p>Making our control server depend on MySQL or PostgreSQL also means our
control server’s testing story gets slow &amp; ugly. Brad had fought that
battle with <a href="https://perkeep.org/">Perkeep</a> and previously written
<a href="https://godoc.org/perkeep.org/pkg/test/dockertest">perkeep.org/pkg/test/dockertest</a>
which works but isn’t something we wanted to subject future employees
to. It requires Docker on your machine and it’s not particularly fast.</p>
<p>Then one day we saw a <a href="https://jepsen.io/analyses/etcd-3.4.3">Jepsen report on
etcd</a>. Unlike the usual
less-than-satisfying Jepsen reports to which we’d become accustomed,
this one said <em>good things</em> about <a href="https://etcd.io/">etcd</a>.
Combined with some positive experiences <a href="https://github.com/danderson">Dave Anderson</a>
had with it, we started thinking about whether we could just use etcd directly.
Being written in Go, we could just link it into our tests and use it
directly. No Docker, no mocks, testing what we’d actually use in
production.</p>
<p>It turned out that the core data model we were writing to disk closely
followed the pattern:</p>
<pre><code>type AllTheData struct {
	BigLock    sync.Mutex
	Somethings map[string]Something
	Widgets    map[string]Widget
	Gadgets    map[string]Gadget
}
</code></pre><p>This maps surprisingly well onto a KV-store. So this led us to etcd as
a “minimally-viable database”. It does the critical things we needed
now, which was 1) breaking the BigLock into something more akin to a
<code>sync.RWMutex</code>, and 2) reducing our I/O to only write the changed data,
not the whole world on any write.</p>
<p>(We are careful not to use any etcd features that would be hard to map onto CockroachDB.)</p>
<p>The downside of this is that etcd, while popular in Kubernetes, has
relatively few users for a database system. As a company, Tailscale is
spending an <a href="https://mcfunley.com/choose-boring-technology">innovation
token</a> on it. But the
database is conceptually small enough that we don’t have to treat it
as a black box. When we ran into a surprisingly slow key pagination
edge case in etcd 3.4, I was able to read my way through its sources
and write a fix for it in an hour. (I then discovered an <a href="https://github.com/etcd-io/etcd/commit/26c930f27d46776da5fedae69267ba0b69c31185">equivalent
fix</a>
had already been applied to the next version of etcd, so we backported
that instead.)</p>
<h4 id="tailetc-our-etcd-client-wrapper">tailetc: our etcd client wrapper</h4>
<p>The client we use for etcd is open source at
<a href="https://github.com/tailscale/tailetc">github.com/tailscale/tailetc</a>. It
is built around two concepts: 1) the total data in the DB is small
enough to fit into the server’s memory and 2) reads are far more
common than writes. Given that, we want to make reads cheap.</p>
<p>The way we do that is by registering a watch against etcd. Every
change is sent to the client, which maintains an enormous cache
<code>map[string]interface{}</code> behind a <code>sync.RWMutex</code>. When you create a Tx
and do a Get, the value is read out of this cache (which may be behind
etcd, but is kept transactionally consistent by tracking the modrev: a
global incrementing ID that etcd uses to define revisions of key-value
pairs.). To avoid aliasing bugs with the cache, we copy the object
out, but avoid JSON decoding on each Get by implementing a more
efficient Clone call on objects in the cache.</p>
<p>The result is that fetching a value from etcd does not require any
network traffic.</p>
<p>This is one of those few times writing Go that I felt the limitations
of its type system as I was designing a package. If I were working in
a language with all the bells and whistles, there would be some kind
of const qualifier I could place on objects leaving the cache and
avoid cloning the memory. That said, running profiles on our server
show the copying is not a performance issue, so perhaps this is an
example of where I feel the pull towards a more complex type system
without actually having a real need for them. As is so often the case,
assumptions are dangerous, profiling is enlightening.</p>
<h4 id="one-snag-indexes">One snag: indexes</h4>
<p>The biggest problem with choosing a minimal viable “nosql” is the lack
of the wonderful index system every standard SQL DBMS supplies. We are
stuck with either storing indexes inside etcd, or managing them in
memory in our client.</p>
<p>With JSONMutexDB we generated them in memory, because it’s much easier
to make data model changes. The easy option with etcd would have been
writing them to the database, but that would have really complicated
data models. Unfortunately, if we want to move to running more than
one CONTROL process simultaneously for high-availability and better
release management, that means we no longer have exactly one process
managing the data, so our indexes need to be transaction (and
rollback) aware. So we invested what probably amounts to two or three
weeks of engineering time into designing in-memory indexes that are
transactionally consistent. This gets a bit tricky to describe, so
we’ll save that for a future blog post (and hopefully we can clean up
the code enough to open source it some day).</p>
<h4 id="the-migration">The migration</h4>
<p>The migration wasn’t very notable, which is always a good thing. We
ran both systems in parallel for a while and at some point stopped
using the old one. The most exciting thing was that our commit latency
dropped a bunch when we turned off the JSON writes. This was most
noticeable when editing networks in the admin panel. We’d include
pretty Grafana graphs here but the cut-over predates us changing our
Prometheus config to keep more history. In any case, writes went from
nearly a second (sometimes worse!) to milliseconds. When we’d started,
writes weren’t a second of course. Never underestimate how long your
“temporary” hack will stay in production!</p>
<h4 id="future">Future</h4>
<p>The most exciting thing about this work, besides ensuring the
Tailscale control plane can scale out for the foreseeable future, is
improving our release process. A consistent database we can easily
attach multiple control plane instances to means we can move to
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blue-green_deployment">blue-green deployment</a>.
This will let Tailscale engineers experiment with deploying features
with the confidence that the worst-case outcome of a change is
limited. The goal is to keep development speed as close to the early
days of JSONMutexDB, when you could recompile and run locally in a
fraction of a second and deploy ten times a day.</p>

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://tailscale.com/blog/an-unlikely-database-migration/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25767128</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 19:52:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Ten years without Elixir]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 117 | Comments 135 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25767030">thread link</a>) | @_nato_
<br/>
January 13, 2021 | http://blog.cretaria.com/posts/ten-years-without-elixir.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://blog.cretaria.com/posts/ten-years-without-elixir.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <header>
                
                <p>Sync’ up! … without getting drained</p>
            </header>
	    <section>
<article>
<p><abbr>jan 13</abbr></p>
<h2>Ten years without Elixir</h2>
<p>José Valim committed the first bit of Elixir code January
9th, 2011, which marks a ten-year anniversary for the kid
brother of Erlang. It’s incredible how time flies on 
certain paradigms, while crawls on others.</p>

<p>I never got into Elixir, largely because it looked like
Ruby. I was a Rubyist for a good while, spent time
and effort to learn where to park my commas, semicolons,
and periods in Erlang, so I never felt that Elixir was
something I wanted.</p>

<p>Nor have I since. There was a good web framework that
came along, and since I’m of that age, you’d thing that
Phoenix would have pulled me in: it never did. I kept
hacking Erlang and just used lighter web <abbr>API</abbr>s like
Cowboy &amp; Elli, instead of going all in on a full
fledged web framework.</p>

<p>From my Erlang-colored glasses, Elixir seems to have
a lot of wins. Their packaging efforts looks like a
mature tool (Hex), and nobody seems to be complaining
about the documentation, an issue Erlang always had (though
to be honest, I never quite grasped what aspect of the
Erlang documentation to be problematic).</p>

<p>On the other hand, some of the syntax Elixir offers
is retrograde, in my humble opinion. Erlang seems to
have prettier syntax now that I have spent so much
time with it. A moot point, perhaps, considering how
subjective beauty is.</p>

<p>My strongest anti-Elixir sentiment (from armchair
reach) is their use of pipes. I know mixologists love
the Elixir pipe operator, but for someone who has
learned to necessarily un-nest code as severely as I have, I
feel as though this operator could be a detriment, or
at least come with some prickily moral hazards. More on that
can be read 
<a href="http://blog.cretaria.com/posts/erlang-beauty.html">here</a>.</p>

<p>Elixir is a cool project, and managed to out-pace Erlang
in a lot of areas it struggled (community,
tooling, etc.).</p>

<p>Hats off to the Elixir team on ten enormous years of
success!</p><p><svg xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="200 0 400 800" width="400" height="800"><rect width="400" height="800" fill="#b33a3a"></rect><polygon points="299.5 150 254.5 247 351.5 247 "></polygon><path d="m321.9 548.9l-243.8 0"></path><path d="m303 247.1l0 243.8"></path><polygon points="94.5 150 49.5 247 146.5 247 "></polygon><path d="m98 247.1l0 243.8"></path><text font-family="Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif" font-size="60" y="112" x="10" style="fill-opacity:null">THIS END UP</text><a xlink:href="//cretaria.com"><text id="link-cretaria" font-family="Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif" font-size="50" y="680" x="10" fill-opacity="null">What’s Cretaria?</text></a><path d="m175 700l200 0" style="fill-opacity:null;fill:none;stroke-linejoin:null;stroke-opacity:null;stroke-width:4;stroke:#000"></path></svg></p></article>
            </section>
            
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://blog.cretaria.com/posts/ten-years-without-elixir.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25767030</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 19:44:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Workaholism leads to health problems, work addiction risk depends on occupation]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 438 | Comments 229 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25763863">thread link</a>) | @rustoo
<br/>
January 13, 2021 | https://www.hse.ru/en/news/research/433782660.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.hse.ru/en/news/research/433782660.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><img alt="Workaholism Leads to Mental and Physical Health Problems: Work Addiction Risk Depends on Occupation" src="https://www.hse.ru/data/2021/01/13/1347222870/iStock-1180554582.jpg" title="Workaholism Leads to Mental and Physical Health Problems: Work Addiction Risk Depends on Occupation"></p></div><div><p>Workaholism or work addiction risk is a growing public health concern that can lead to many negative mental and physical health outcomes such as depression, anxiety or sleep disorder. Perception of work (job demands and job control) may become a major cause of employees’ work addiction. The international group of researchers including the HSE University scientist explored the link between work addiction risk and health-related outcomes using the framework of Job Demand Control Model. The results were published in the <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7593928/" rel="nofollow"><em>International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health</em></a>.</p>  <p>Workaholics are people who usually work seven and more hours more than others per week. There are potential reasons for that: financial problems, poor marriage or pressure by their organization or supervisor. What can differentiate a workaholic behaviour from similar behaviour like work engagement? Workaholism is also known as a behavioural disorder, which means the excessive involvement of the individual in work when an employer doesn’t require or expect it.</p> </div>








    
    
        <p>The scientists aimed to demonstrate the extent to which the work addiction risk is associated with the perception of work (job demands and job control), and mental health in four job categories suggested by Karasek’s model or Job Demand-Control-Support model (JDCS). The JDCS model assumes four various work environments (four quadrants) in which workers may experience a different level of job demands and job control: passive, low-strain, active, and tense/job-strain. Job control is the extent to which an employee feels control over doing work.</p>


<div><ul>  <li>Passive” jobs (low job control, low job demands) might be satisfying to a worker as long as the workers reach the set goal.</li>  <li>Low strain” jobs have high job control and low job demands. Individuals in this category are not particularly at risk of mental health problems, and it corresponds typically to creative jobs such as architects.</li>  <li>Active” workers have high job demands and high job control. They are highly skilled professionals with responsibilities, such as heads or directors of companies. Those highly skilled workers have very demanding tasks but they have high levels of decision latitude to solve problems.</li>  <li>Finally, workers at risk of stress-related disorders are those within the “job strain” group (high demand and low control). For example, healthcare workers from emergency departments are typically in job strain because they cannot control the huge workload.</li> </ul>  <p>The study was conducted in France because it is one of the industrial countries with growing numbers of occupations. The authors of the research collected data from 187 out of 1580 (11.8%) French workers who agreed to participate in a cross-sectional study using the WittyFit software online platform. The self-administered questionnaires were the Job Content Questionnaire by Karasek, the Work Addiction Risk Test, the Hospital Anxiety and Depression scale and socio-demographics. The authors of this study divided all the participants based on their occupational groups and investigated the link between work addiction risk and mental and physical health outcomes.</p> </div>








    
    
        <div>
            

            
                <p>
                     <img alt="" height="200" src="https://www.hse.ru/pubs/share/thumb/433782649:c456x456+5+6:r190x190!.jpg" width="200">
                </p>
             
            <h4><a href="https://www.hse.ru/en/org/persons/211299142">Morteza Charkhabi</a>,<br>
Assistant&nbsp;Professor at the HSE&nbsp;<a href="https://ioe.hse.ru/en/">Institute of Education</a></h4>

<p>‘One of the novelties of this research was to introduce vulnerable occupational groups to organizations or job holders. For example, if we find that work addiction risk can be found more in some occupations and may result in negative outcomes for the health situation then we can give this information to decision makers in this organization or, for example, to the ministry of health. And they could intervene to prevent this problem.’</p>

            
        </div>


<div><p>The results show that high job demands at work are strongly associated with work addiction risk but the job control level does not play the same role. The prevalence of work addiction risk is higher for active and high-strain workers than for passive and low-strain workers. These two groups of workers appeared to be more vulnerable and therefore can suffer more from the negative outcomes of work addiction risk, in terms of depression, sleep disorder, stress and other health issues.</p>  <p>‘We found that job demands could be the most important factor that can develop work addiction risk. So this factor should be controlled or should be investigated by the organization's manager, for example, HR staff, psychologists. Also another conclusion could be the job climate like job demands of each job category can influence the rate of work addiction risk. Thus in this study we actually focused on external factors like job demands not internal factors like the personal characteristics,’ adds Morteza Charkhabi.</p>  <p>The researchers found that people with higher work addiction risk compared to people with low work addiction risk have twice the risk of developing depression. Sleep quality was lower to workers with high risk of work addiction compared to workers with low risk of work addiction. Also women had almost twice the work addiction risk than men.</p> </div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.hse.ru/en/news/research/433782660.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25763863</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 16:08:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Hiding execution of unsigned code in Windows system threads]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 87 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25762322">thread link</a>) | @jm1337
<br/>
January 13, 2021 | https://secret.club/2021/01/12/callout.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://secret.club/2021/01/12/callout.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>Anti-cheat development is, by nature, reactive; anti-cheats exist to respond to and thwart a videogame’s population of cheaters. For instance, a videogame with an exceedingly low amount of cheaters would have little need for an anti-cheat, while a videogame rife with cheaters would have a clear need for an anti-cheat. In order to catch cheaters, anti-cheats will employ as many methods as possible. Unfortunately, anti-cheats are not omniscient; they can not know of every single method or detection vector to catch cheaters. Likewise, the game hacks themselves must continue to discover new or unique methods in order to evade anti-cheats.</p><h2 id="the-reactive-development-cycle-of-game-hacking"> <a href="#the-reactive-development-cycle-of-game-hacking">The Reactive Development Cycle of Game Hacking</a></h2><p>This brings forth a reactive and continuous development cycle, for both the cheats and anti-cheats: the opposite party (cheat or anti-cheat) will employ a unique method to circumvent the adjacent party (anti-cheat or cheat) which, in response, will then do the same.</p><p>One such method employed by an increasing number of anti-cheats is to execute core anti-cheat functions from within the operating system’s kernel. A clear advantage over the alternative (i.e. usermode execution) is in the fact that, on Windows NT systems, the anti-cheat can selectively filter which processes are able to interact with the memory of the game process in which they are protecting, thus nullifying a plethora of methods used by game hacks.</p><p>In response to this, many (but not all) hack developers made (or are making) the decision to do the same; they too would, or will, execute their hack, either wholly or in part, from within the operating system’s kernel, thus nullifying what the anti-cheats had done.</p><p>Unlike with anti-cheats, however, this decision carries with it numerous concessions: namely, the fact that, for various reasons, it is most convenient (or it is only practical) to execute the hack as an unsigned kernel driver running without the kernel’s knowledge; the “driver” is typically a region of executable memory in the kernel’s address space and is never loaded or allocated by the kernel. In other words, it is a “manually-mapped” driver, loaded by a tool used by a game hack.</p><p>This ultimately provides anti-cheats with many opportunities to detect so-called “kernel-mode” or “ring 0” game hacks (noting that those terms are typically said with a marketable significance; they are literally used to market such game hacks, as if to imply robustness or security); if the anti-cheat can prove that the system is executing, or had executed, unsigned code, it can then potentially flag a user as being a cheater.</p><h3 id="analyzing-a-threads-kernel-stack"> <a href="#analyzing-a-threads-kernel-stack">Analyzing a Thread’s Kernel Stack</a></h3><p>One such method - the focus of this article, in fact - of detecting unsigned code execution in the kernel is to iterate each thread that is running in the system (optionally deciding to only iterate threads associated with the system process, i.e. system threads) and to initiate some kind of stack trace.</p><p>Bluntly, this allows the anti-cheat to quite effectively determine if a cheat were executing unsigned code. For example, some anti-cheats (e.g. BattlEye) will queue to each system thread an APC which will then initiate a stack trace. If the stack trace returns an instruction pointer that is not within the confines of any loaded kernel driver, the anti-cheat can then know that it may have encountered a system thread that is executing unsigned code. Furthermore, because it is a stack trace and not a direct sampling of the return instruction pointer, it would work quite reliably, even if a game hack were, for example, executing a spin-loop or continuous wait; the stack trace would always lead back to the unsigned code.</p><p>It is quite clear to any cheat developer that they can respond to this behavior by simply running their thread(s) with kernel APCs disabled, preventing delivery of such APCs and avoiding the detection vector. As is will be seen, however, this method does not entirely prevent detection of unsigned code execution.</p><h3 id="copying-out-then-analyzing-a-threads-kernel-stack"> <a href="#copying-out-then-analyzing-a-threads-kernel-stack">(Copying Out, Then) Analyzing a Thread’s Kernel Stack</a></h3><p>Certain anti-cheats - EasyAntiCheat, in particular - had a much more apt method of generating a pseudo-stacktrace: instead of generating a stack trace with a blockable APC, why not copy the contents of the thread’s kernel stack asynchronously? Continuing the reactive cheat-anti-cheat development cycle, EasyAntiCheat had opted to manually search for instances of nonpaged code pointers that may have been left behind as a result of system thread execution.</p><p>While the downsides of this method are debatable, the upside is quite clear: as long as the thread is making procedure calls (e.g. x86 call instruction) from within its own code, either to kernel routines or to its own, and regardless of its IRQL or if the thread is even running, its execution will leave behind detectable traces on its stack in the form of pointers to its own code which can be extracted and analyzed.</p><h2 id="callouts-continuing-the-reactive-development-cycle"> <a href="#callouts-continuing-the-reactive-development-cycle">Callouts: Continuing The Reactive Development Cycle</a></h2><p>Proposed is the “callout” method of system thread execution, born from the recognition that:</p><ol><li>A thread’s kernel stack, as identified by the kernel stack pointer in a thread’s ETHREAD object, can be analyzed asynchronously by a potential anti-cheat to detect traces of unsigned code execution; and that</li><li>To be useful in most cases, a system thread must be able to make calls to most external NT kernel or executive procedures with little compromise.</li></ol><h3 id="the-life-cycle-of-the-callout-thread"> <a href="#the-life-cycle-of-the-callout-thread">The Life-cycle of the Callout Thread</a></h3><p>The life-cycle of a callout thread is quite simple and can be used to demonstrate its implementation:</p><ul><li>Before thread creation:<ul><li>Allocate a non-paged stack to be loaded by the thread; the callout thread’s “real stack”</li><li>Allocate shellcode (ideally in executable memory not associated with the main driver module) which disables interrupts, preserves the old/kernel stack pointer (as it was on function entry), loads the real stack, and jumps to an initialization routine (the callout thread’s “bootstrap routine”)</li><li>Create a system thread (i.e. PsCreateSystemThread) whose start address points to the initialization shellcode</li></ul></li><li>At thread entry (i.e. the bootstrap routine):<ul><li>Preserve the stack pointer that had been given to the thread at thread entry (this must be given by the shellcode)</li><li>(Optionally) Iterate the thread’s old/kernel stack pointer, ceasing iteration at the stack base, eliminating any references/pointers to the initialization shellcode</li><li>(Optionally) Eliminate references to the initialization shellcode within the thread’s ETHREAD; for example, it may be worth changing the thread’s start address</li><li>(Optionally, but recommended) Free the memory containing the initialization shellcode, if it was allocated separately from the driver module</li><li>Proceed to thread execution</li></ul></li></ul><p>In clearer terms, the callout thread spends most of its time executing the driver’s unsigned code with interrupts disabled and with its own kernel stack - the real stack. It can also attempt to wipe any other traces of its execution which may have been present upon its creation.</p><h3 id="the-usefulness-of-the-callout-thread"> <a href="#the-usefulness-of-the-callout-thread">The Usefulness of the Callout Thread</a></h3><p>The callout thread must also be capable of executing most, if not all, NT kernel and executive procedures. As proposed, this is effectively impossible; the thread must run with interrupts disabled and with its own stack, thus creating an obvious problem as most procedures of interest would run at an IRQL &lt;= DISPATCH_LEVEL. Furthermore, the NT IRQL model may be liable to ignore our setting of the interrupt flag, causing most routines to unpredictibly enter a deadlock or enable interrupts without our consent.</p><p>A mechanism to allow for a callout thread to invoke these routines of interest, the callout mechanism, is therefore used to:</p><ol><li>Provide a routine which can be used to conveniently invoke (“call out”) an external function; and in this routine,</li><li>Load the thread’s original/kernel stack pointer;</li><li>Copy function arguments on to the kernel thread’s stack from the real stack;</li><li>Enable interrupts;</li><li>Invoke the requested routine (within the same instruction boundary as when interrupts are enabled);</li><li>Cleanly return from the routine without generating obvious stack traces (e.g. function pointers);</li><li>Load the real stack pointer and disable the interrupt flag, and do so before returning to unsigned code; and</li><li>Continue execution, preserving the function’s return value</li></ol><p>While somewhat complicated, the callout mechanism can be achieved easily and, to a reasonable degree, portably, using two widely-available ROP gadgets from within the NT kernel.</p><h3 id="the-usefulness-of-iretq"> <a href="#the-usefulness-of-iretq">The Usefulness of IRET(Q)</a></h3><p>The constraint of needing to load a new stack pointer, interrupt flag, and interrupt pointer within an instruction boundary was immediately satisfied by the IRET instruction.</p><p>For those unfamiliar, the IRET (lit. “interrupt return”) instruction is intended to be used by an operating system or executive (here, the NT kernel) to return from an interrupt routine. To support the recognition of an interrupt from any mode of execution, and to generically resume to any mode of execution, the processor will need to (effectively) preserve the instruction pointer, stack pointer, CPL or privilege level (through the CS and SS selectors; and while they have a more general use-case, this is effectively what is preserved on most operating systems with a flat memory model), and RFLAGS register (as interrupts may be liable to modify certain flags).</p><p>To report this information to the OS interrupt handler, the CPU will, in a specific order:</p><ol><li>Push the SS (stack segment selector) register;</li><li>Push the RSP (stack pointer) register;</li><li>Push the RFLAGS (arithmetic/system flags) register;</li><li>Push the CS (code segment selector) register;</li><li>Push the RIP (instruction pointer) register; and, for some exception-class interrupts,</li><li>Push an error code which may describe certain interrupt conditions (e.g. a page fault will know if the fault was caused by a non-present page, or if it were caused by a protection violation)</li></ol><p>Note that the error code is not important to the CPU and must be accounted for by the interrupt handler. Each operation is an 8-byte push, …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://secret.club/2021/01/12/callout.html">https://secret.club/2021/01/12/callout.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://secret.club/2021/01/12/callout.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25762322</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 14:28:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Thou shalt not run a database inside a container]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 59 | Comments 41 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25761568">thread link</a>) | @swyx
<br/>
January 13, 2021 | https://patrobinson.github.io/2016/11/07/thou-shalt-not-run-a-database-inside-a-container/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://patrobinson.github.io/2016/11/07/thou-shalt-not-run-a-database-inside-a-container/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
    <div>
        <div>
            <div>

				<p>So my last blog post, <a href="https://patrobinson.github.io/2016/11/05/docker-in-production/">Docker in Production: A retort</a>, generated a lot of comments. One of them was “Why shouldn’t you run a Database in Docker?” I’ve seen this questions a few times, but rarely reply because it’s such a long answer. But here goes.</p>

<p>EDIT: I’ve been made aware I’m not being clear that I am referring to running a database in a container management solution, like Kubernetes. The issues laid out below don’t relate to just running your database in docker with no shared storage or ability to start it automatically on a different node.</p>

<h2 id="kelsey-hightower-told-you-not-to">Kelsey Hightower told you not to</h2>

<p>He’s a smart guy, he’s worked at CoreOS and now works at Google. He has done some fantastic talks on Docker, Kubernetes and System Administration in general. <a href="https://youtu.be/Nosa5-xcATw?t=1080">Here’s him talking about it</a></p>

<h2 id="distributed-systems-are-hard">Distributed systems are hard</h2>

<p>Like really hard. But that’s ok when your application is stateless, because when it all goes to shit you just reboot things and they magically get better. But when your database gets fubar you can end up with permanent corruption. The most complex part of a distributed system is the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Byzantine_fault_tolerance#The_Byzantine_Generals.27_Problem">Byzantine Generals problem</a>, which describes the problem of how we determine what is the source of truth and how do we know for certain it is the only source of truth. There are various solutions to this problem, usually implemented in the storage engine of databases. Some databases do this well, mostly NoSQL databases where it’s possible to shard data across multiple nodes by not supporting a JOIN operation. Traditional relational databases do not do this well, they generally only work  in a master-slave configuration. There are ways to run them in master-master configuration but you need a very specific skill type to execute this. If you’re doing this, well why are you reading my blog post? You know better than I do.</p>

<p>If you cannot determine what is the master node, which involves some kind of conensus algorithm and an odd number of nodes to vote on it, then you will end up with data loss and/or corruption.</p>

<h2 id="volume-management-for-docker-is-still-in-its-infancy">Volume management for Docker is still in it’s infancy</h2>

<p>There isn’t a well respected solution for how to do volume management for Docker clusters right now. Some people use NFS, but it lacks any kind of locking support on files (see <a href="http://0pointer.de/blog/projects/locking.html">this blog</a> for more details on linux file lock support). So you cannot guarentee that another system is not writing to your files.</p>

<p>GlusterFS is a recent successor to NFS, that offers much better performance, clustering and scalability. However it has several known issues that render locking unreliable.<a href="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1194546">1</a> <a href="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1287099">2</a></p>

<h2 id="you-lied-to-us-i-can-total-run-my-nosql-database-in-docker">You lied to us! I can total run my NoSQL database in Docker</h2>

<p>The answer here is it really depends on the underlying technology. As stated, there is no solution for filesystem level replication of data (except in a few proprietary solutions like AWS’s flagship database Aurora, VMware File System and Google File System, none of which tackle this specific use case). So instead we must rely on the storage engine of the database to do clustering and replication for us. Some are well known for their support of this (etcd, ElasticSearch and Riak KV to name a few), but it needs to be considered on a case by case basis to evaluate how well the particular database deals with this problem, because it’s so easy to get wrong.</p>

<h2 id="with-great-knowledge-comes-great-responsibility">With great knowledge comes great responsibility</h2>

<p>Now you know why there is significant anxiety to running databases in Docker, you have the power to make the decision for yourself.</p>

<p>If you find yourself wanting to learn more I highly recommend Pintrest’s blog on <a href="https://engineering.pinterest.com/blog/sharding-pinterest-how-we-scaled-our-mysql-fleet">how they sharded their MySQL Cluster</a>. They use Zookeeper, similar to etcd, to keep the configuration of which data lives in which MySQL database. This provides a highly available, consistent store. But they still recommend you “only read/write to the master… It simplifies everything and avoids lagged replication bugs.”</p>

<p>I’ve yet to see a blog post about somebody containerising their MySQL server and how it went really well.</p>

<h2 id="edit-some-solutions-to-the-problems-i-have-presented-here">EDIT: Some solutions to the problems I have presented here</h2>

<p>Some people have pointed out a couple of solutions to the problem presented here. One is the Kubernetes <a href="http://kubernetes.io/docs/user-guide/petset/">PetSet</a> concept. While still in Alpha (so obviuosly not fit for Production), this looks to be solving the exact problem of ensuring one and only one master exists at any one time.</p>

<p>Uber also <a href="https://eng.uber.com/dockerizing-mysql/">blogged about their dockerizing of MySQL</a> which is a very similar solution to the Kubernetes approach. They are defining the cluster topology up front, which guarentees a single master. They don’t talk about how they generate the master, but since that obviously comes from another source it’s likely highly consistent.</p>

<p>So today we still can’t run Docker inside a container cluster, but there are some good solutions on the roadmap.</p>

<p>Check out my <a href="http://patrobinson.github.io/2017/12/16/should-i-run-a-database-in-kubernetes/">follow up post</a> on this ∂subject.</p>


                <hr>

                

            </div>
        </div>
    </div>
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://patrobinson.github.io/2016/11/07/thou-shalt-not-run-a-database-inside-a-container/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25761568</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 13:16:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A rabbit hole full of Lisp]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 213 | Comments 36 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25760381">thread link</a>) | @mpereira
<br/>
January 13, 2021 | https://www.murilopereira.com/a-rabbit-hole-full-of-lisp/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.murilopereira.com/a-rabbit-hole-full-of-lisp/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>At work I contribute to a moderately-sized monorepo at 70 thousand files,
8-digit lines of code and hundreds of PRs merged every day. One day I
opened a remote buffer at that repository and ran <code>M-x find-file</code>.</p><p><code>find-file</code> is an interactive function that shows a narrowed list
of files in the current directory, prompts the user to filter and scroll
through candidates, and for a file to open.</p><p>Emacs froze for <em>5 seconds</em> before showing me the <code>find-file</code> prompt. Which
isn’t great, because when writing software, opening files is actually
something one needs to do all the time.</p><figure><img src="https://www.murilopereira.com/find_file_linux.png"></figure><p>Luckily, Emacs is “the extensible, customizable, self-documenting real-time
display editor”, and comes with profiling capabilities: <code>M-x profiler-start</code>
starts a profile and <code>M-x profiler-report</code> displays a call tree showing how
much CPU cycles are spent in each function call after starting the profile.
Starting a profile and running <code>M-x find-file</code> showed that all time was being
spent in a function called <code>ffap-guess-file-name-at-point</code>, which was being
called by <code>file-name-at-point-functions</code>, an <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/html%5Fnode/emacs/Hooks.html#:~:text=A%20few%20hooks%20are%20abnormal,are%20used%20in%20some%20way.">abnormal hook</a> run when <code>find-file</code>
is called.</p><p>If you're familiar with Vim you can think of Emacs <i>hooks</i> as
Vim <i>autocommands</i>, only with much better ergonomics.</p><p>I checked the documentation for <code>ffap-guess-file-name-at-point</code> with <code>M-x describe-function ffap-guess-file-name-at-point</code> and it didn’t seem
to be something essential, so I removed the hook by running <code>M-x eval-expression</code>, writing the form below, and pressing <code>RET</code>.</p><div><div><table><tbody><tr><td><pre><code><span>1
</span></code></pre></td><td><pre><code data-lang="emacs-lisp">(<span>remove-hook</span> <span>'file-name-at-point-functions</span> <span>'ffap-guess-file-name-at-point</span>)
</code></pre></td></tr></tbody></table></div></div><p>This solved the immediate problem of Emacs blocking for 5 seconds every
time I ran <code>find-file</code>, with no noticeable drawbacks.</p><div><p>As I write this I attempt to reproduce the issue by re-adding
<code>ffap-guess-file-name-at-point</code>
to
<code>file-name-at-point-functions</code>.
I can't reproduce it anymore. The initial issue might have been</p><ul><li>caused by having manually mutated the Emacs environment via ad-hoc code
evaluation (drifting from the state defined in configuration)</li><li>caused by settings or packages that aren't in my configuration anymore</li><li>fixed by settings or packages that were recently added to my
configuration</li><li>fixed by some recent package upgrade</li></ul><p>Or some combination of the above. I have no idea exactly what.
Which is to say: maintaining Emacs configurations is complicated.</p></div><p>I could now navigate around and open files. The next thing I tried in this
remote git repository was searching through project files. The great
<em>projectile</em> package provides the <code>projectile-find-file</code> function for that,
but I had previously given up making projectile perform well with remote
buffers; given how things are currently implemented it seems to be
<a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=projectile+tramp">impractical</a>. So I installed the <em>find-file-in-project</em> package for use on
remote projects exclusively: <code>M-x package-install find-file-in-project</code>.</p><p>Most Emacs commands are accessible via key combinations, with defaults
that can be customized to be anything you want. I'll stick to referencing
command names themselves instead of their default keybindings.</p><p>Both <code>projectile-find-file</code> and <code>find-file-in-project</code> (aliased as <code>ffip</code>):</p><ul><li>show a narrowed list of all project files in the minibuffer</li><li>prompt the user to filter and scroll through candidates</li><li>open a file when <code>RET</code> is pressed on a candidate.</li></ul><figure><img src="https://www.murilopereira.com/projectile_find_file_linux.png"></figure><p>To disable projectile on remote buffers I had the following form in my
configuration.</p><div><div><table><tbody><tr><td><pre><code><span>1
</span><span>2
</span></code></pre></td><td><pre><code data-lang="emacs-lisp">(<span>defadvice</span> <span>projectile-project-root</span> (<span>around</span> <span>ignore-remote</span> <span>first</span> <span>activate</span>)
  (<span>unless</span> (<span>file-remote-p</span> <span>default-directory</span> <span>'no-identification</span>) <span>ad-do-it</span>))
</code></pre></td></tr></tbody></table></div></div><p>Which causes the <code>projectile-project-root</code> function to not run its usual
implementation on remote buffers, but instead return <code>nil</code> unconditionally.
<code>projectile-project-root</code> is used as a way to either get the project root for
a given buffer (remote or not), or as a boolean predicate to test if the
buffer is in a project (e.g., a git repository directory). Having it return
<code>nil</code> on remote buffers effectively disables projectile on remote buffers.</p><p>Emacs
<i><a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/html_node/elisp/Advising-Functions.html">advices</a></i> are a way of modifying the behavior of existing functions without
having to redefine them. They serve a similar purpose as hooks, but are
more flexible.</p><p>I then wrote a function that falls back to <code>ffip</code> when projectile is
disabled and bound it to the keybinding I had for <code>projectile-find-file</code>,
so that I could press the same keybinding whenever I wanted to search for
projects files, and not have to think about whether I’m on a remote buffer
or not:</p><div><div><table><tbody><tr><td><pre><code><span>1
</span><span>2
</span><span>3
</span><span>4
</span><span>5
</span><span>6
</span></code></pre></td><td><pre><code data-lang="emacs-lisp">(<span>defun</span> <span>maybe-projectile-find-file</span> ()
  <span>"Run </span><span>`projectile-find-file'</span><span> if in a project buffer, </span><span>`ffip'</span><span> otherwise."</span>
  (<span>interactive</span>)
  (<span>if</span> (<span>projectile-project-p</span>)
      (<span>projectile-find-file</span>)
    (<span>ffip</span>)))
</code></pre></td></tr></tbody></table></div></div><p><code>projectile-project-p</code> uses <code>projectile-project-root</code> internally.</p><p>And called it:</p><p><code>M-x maybe-projectile-find-file</code></p><p>Emacs froze for <strong>30 seconds</strong>. After that, it showed the prompt with the
narrowed list of files in the project. 30 seconds! What was it doing during
the whole time? Let’s try out the profiler again.</p><ol><li><p>Start a new profile:</p><p><code>M-x profiler-start</code></p></li><li><p>Call the function to be profiled:</p><p><code>M-x maybe-projectile-find-file</code> (it freezes Emacs again for 30 seconds)</p></li><li><p>And display the report:</p><p><code>M-x profiler-report</code></p></li></ol><p>Which showed:</p><div><div><table><tbody><tr><td><pre><code><span>1
</span><span>2
</span><span>3
</span></code></pre></td><td><pre><code data-lang="text">Function                                                  CPU samples    %
+ ...                                                           21027  98%
+ command-execute                                                 361   1%
</code></pre></td></tr></tbody></table></div></div><p>This tells us that 98% of the CPU time was spent in whatever <code>...</code> is.
Pressing <code>TAB</code> on a line will expand it by showing its child function
calls.</p><div><div><table><tbody><tr><td><pre><code><span>1
</span><span>2
</span><span>3
</span><span>4
</span><span>5
</span><span>6
</span><span>7
</span><span>8
</span><span>9
</span></code></pre></td><td><pre><code data-lang="text">Function                                                  CPU samples    %
- ...                                                           21027  98%
 + ivy--insert-minibuffer                                       13689  64%
 + #&lt;compiled 0x131f715d2b6fa0a8&gt;                                3819  17%
   Automatic GC                                                  2017   9%
 + shell-command                                                 1424   6%
 + ffip-get-project-root-directory                                 77   0%
 + run-mode-hooks                                                   1   0%
+ command-execute                                                 361   1%
</code></pre></td></tr></tbody></table></div></div><p>Expanding <code>...</code> shows that Emacs spent 64% of CPU time in
<code>ivy--insert-minibuffer</code> and 9% of the time—roughly 3 whole seconds!—
garbage collecting. I had <code>garbage-collection-messages</code> set to <code>t</code> so I could
already tell that Emacs was GCing a lot; enabling this setting makes a
message be displayed in the echo area whenever Emacs garbage collects. I
could also see the Emacs process consuming 100% of one CPU core while it was
frozen and unresponsive to input.</p><p>The <code>profiler</code> package implements a
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Profiling_(computer_programming)#Statistical_profilers">sampling profiler</a>. The <code>elp</code>
package can be used for getting actual wall clock times.</p><p>Drilling down on <code>#&lt;compiled 0x131f715d2b6fa0a8&gt;</code> shows that cycles there
(17% of CPU time) were spent on Emacs waiting for user input, so we can
ignore it for now.</p><p>As I get deep in drilling down on <code>ivy--insert-minibuffer</code>, names in the
“Function” column start getting truncated because the column is too narrow.
A quick Google search (via <code>M-x google-this emacs profiler report width</code>)
shows me how to make it wider:</p><div><div><table><tbody><tr><td><pre><code><span>1
</span><span>2
</span></code></pre></td><td><pre><code data-lang="emacs-lisp">(<span>setf</span> (<span>caar</span> <span>profiler-report-cpu-line-format</span>) <span>80</span>
      (<span>caar</span> <span>profiler-report-memory-line-format</span>) <span>80</span>)
</code></pre></td></tr></tbody></table></div></div><p>Describing those variables with <code>M-x describe-variable</code> shows that the
default values are <code>50</code>.</p><p>From the profiler report buffer I run <code>M-x eval-expression</code>, paste the form
above with <code>C-y</code> and press <code>RET</code>. I also persist this form to my
configuration. Pressing <code>c</code> in the profiler report buffer (bound to
<code>profiler-report-render-calltree</code>) redraws it, now with a wider column,
allowing me to see the function names.</p><p>Here is the abbreviated expanded relevant portion of the call stack.</p><div><div><table><tbody><tr><td><pre><code><span> 1
</span><span> 2
</span><span> 3
</span><span> 4
</span><span> 5
</span><span> 6
</span><span> 7
</span><span> 8
</span><span> 9
</span><span>10
</span><span>11
</span><span>12
</span><span>13
</span><span>14
</span><span>15
</span><span>16
</span><span>17
</span><span>18
</span><span>19
</span><span>20
</span><span>21
</span><span>22
</span><span>23
</span><span>24
</span><span>25
</span><span>26
</span><span>27
</span><span>28
</span><span>29
</span><span>30
</span><span>31
</span><span>32
</span><span>33
</span><span>34
</span><span>35
</span><span>36
</span><span>37
</span><span>38
</span><span>39
</span><span>40
</span><span>41
</span><span>42
</span></code></pre></td><td><pre><code data-lang="text">Function                                                  CPU samples    %
- ffip                                                          13586  63%
 - ffip-find-files                                              13586  63%
  - let*                                                        13586  63%
   - setq                                                       13585  63%
    - ffip-project-search                                       13585  63%
     - let*                                                     13585  63%
      - mapcar                                                  13531  63%
       - #&lt;lambda 0xb210342292&gt;                                 13528  63%
        - cons                                                  13521  63%
         - expand-file-name                                     12936  60%
          - tramp-file-name-handler                             12918  60%
           - apply                                               9217  43%
            - tramp-sh-file-name-handler                         9158  42%
             - apply                                             9124  42%
              - tramp-sh-handle-expand-file-name                 8952  41%
               - file-name-as-directory                          5812  27%
                - tramp-file-name-handler                        5793  27%
                 + tramp-find-foreign-file-name-handler          3166  14%
                 + apply                                         1237   5%
                 + tramp-dissect-file-name                        527   2%
                 + #&lt;compiled -0x1589d0aab96d9542&gt;                337   1%
                   tramp-file-name-equal-p                        312   1%
                   tramp-tramp-file-p                              33   0%
                 + tramp-replace-environment-variables              6   0%
                   #&lt;compiled 0x1e202496df87&gt;                       1   0%
               + tramp-connectable-p                             1006   4%
               + tramp-dissect-file-name                          628   2%
               + eval                                            …</code></pre></td></tr></tbody></table></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.murilopereira.com/a-rabbit-hole-full-of-lisp/">https://www.murilopereira.com/a-rabbit-hole-full-of-lisp/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.murilopereira.com/a-rabbit-hole-full-of-lisp/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25760381</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 10:43:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Milestone: Half a million downloads for VideoLAN packages in the .NET ecosystem]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 115 | Comments 67 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25760180">thread link</a>) | @martz
<br/>
January 13, 2021 | https://mfkl.github.io/2021/01/13/half-a-million-downloads.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://mfkl.github.io/2021/01/13/half-a-million-downloads.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      
        <header>
          
          
            <p> 




  1 minute read

</p>
          
        </header>
      

      <section itemprop="text">
        
        <p><a href="https://www.nuget.org/profiles/videolan">The NuGet VideoLAN account</a> just reached half a million downloads in the .NET ecosystem.</p>

<p>
    <a href="https://nugettrends.com/packages?months=24&amp;ids=VideoLAN.LibVLC.Windows&amp;ids=LibVLCSharp&amp;ids=LibVLCSharp.Forms&amp;ids=VideoLAN.LibVLC.iOS&amp;ids=VideoLAN.LibVLC.Android"><img src="https://mfkl.github.io/assets/nugettrends.png"></a>
</p>

<p>The first publication of the first VideoLAN NuGet package dates back to April 1st, 2018 (no joke!). We have been steadily adding new packages since then to cover all platforms supported by both LibVLC and .NET.</p>

<p>Today, we actively publish and maintain <strong>15 NuGet packages</strong>, 6 of which  actually containing native platform-specific code. The remaining 9 packages are managed C# DLLs composed of the main binding (<a href="https://www.nuget.org/packages/LibVLCSharp/">LibVLCSharp</a>) and various GUI toolkit integrations for getting users up and running quickly.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Xamarin.Android</li>
  <li>Xamarin.iOS</li>
  <li>Xamarin.tvOS</li>
  <li>Xamarin.Mac (Cocoa)</li>
  <li>Windows Classic (WPF, WinForms, GTK)</li>
  <li>Windows Universal (UWP for Desktop, mobile and Xbox)</li>
  <li>Linux including desktop, server and Raspberry Pi (GTK)</li>
  <li>Xamarin.Forms</li>
  <li>Uno Platform (UWP, Android, iOS)</li>
  <li>Avalonia (Windows, macOS, Linux)</li>
</ul>

<p>LibVLCSharp counts about <strong>19 contributors</strong>, with most people doing one-off contributions and mainly 2 active maintainers (<a href="https://github.com/jeremyVignelles">Jérémy</a> and myself). I’d like to thank each of them for their valuable OSS contributions!</p>



<p>Many exciting things! More game engine integrations, ongoing LibVLC 4 support, interop performance improvements and plenty of new integrations, samples and features are yet to be implemented.</p>

<p>We have a diverse and (mostly) well-defined <a href="https://code.videolan.org/videolan/LibVLCSharp/-/issues">backlog</a> of both features to implement and bugs to fix, with a varying degree of difficulty, and always welcome new contributors. We are available on the <a href="https://discord.gg/3h3K3JF">LibVLC community Discord server</a> (320+ members).</p>

<p>Feel free to let me know what you think on <a href="https://twitter.com/martz2804">Twitter</a>.</p>

        
      </section>

      

      


      
  

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://mfkl.github.io/2021/01/13/half-a-million-downloads.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25760180</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 10:07:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Foam: A personal knowledge management and sharing system for VSCode]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 388 | Comments 103 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25760066">thread link</a>) | @lelf
<br/>
January 13, 2021 | https://foambubble.github.io/foam/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://foambubble.github.io/foam/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      

      






<p><strong>Foam</strong> is a personal knowledge management and sharing system inspired by <a href="https://roamresearch.com/">Roam Research</a>, built on <a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/">Visual Studio Code</a> and <a href="https://github.com/">GitHub</a>.</p>

<p>You can use <strong>Foam</strong> for organising your research, keeping re-discoverable notes, writing long-form content and, optionally, publishing it to the web.</p>

<p><strong>Foam</strong> is free, open source, and extremely extensible to suit your personal workflow. You own the information you create with Foam, and you’re free to share it, and collaborate on it with anyone you want.</p>

<p>
  <b>New!</b> Join <a href="https://discord.gg/rtdZKgj" target="_blank">Foam community Discord</a> for users and contributors!
</p>



<h2 id="table-of-contents">Table of Contents</h2>

<ul>
  <li><a href="#foam">Foam</a>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="#table-of-contents">Table of Contents</a></li>
      <li><a href="#how-do-i-use-foam">How do I use Foam?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#whats-in-a-foam">What’s in a Foam?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#getting-started">Getting started</a></li>
      <li><a href="#features">Features</a></li>
      <li><a href="#call-to-adventure">Call To Adventure</a></li>
      <li><a href="#thanks-and-attribution">Thanks and attribution</a></li>
      <li><a href="#license">License</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="how-do-i-use-foam">How do I use Foam?</h2>

<p><strong>Foam</strong> is a tool that supports creating relationships between thoughts and information to help you think better.</p>

<p><img src="https://foambubble.github.io/foam/assets/images/foam-features-dark-mode-demo.png" alt="Foam kitchen sink, showing a few of the key features"></p>

<p>Whether you want to build a <a href="https://www.buildingasecondbrain.com/">Second Brain</a> or a <a href="https://zettelkasten.de/posts/overview/">Zettelkasten</a>, write a book, or just get better at long-term learning, <strong>Foam</strong> can help you organise your thoughts if you follow these simple rules:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Create a single <strong>Foam</strong> workspace for all your knowledge and research following the <a href="#getting-started">Getting started</a> guide.</li>
  <li>Write your thoughts in markdown documents (I like to call them <strong>Bubbles</strong>, but that might be more than a little twee). These documents should be atomic: Put things that belong together into a single document, and limit its content to that single topic. (<a href="https://zettelkasten.de/posts/overview/#principles">source</a>)</li>
  <li>Use Foam’s shortcuts and autocompletions to link your thoughts together with <code>[[wiki-links]]</code>, and navigate between them to explore your knowledge graph.</li>
  <li>Get an overview of your <strong>Foam</strong> workspace using a [<a href="https://foambubble.github.io/foam/features/graph-visualisation.md" title="Graph Visualisation">graph-visualisation</a>] (⚠️ WIP), and discover relationships between your thoughts with the use of [<a href="https://foambubble.github.io/foam/features/backlinking.md" title="Backlinking">backlinking</a>].</li>
</ol>

<p>Foam is a like a bathtub: <em>What you get out of it depends on what you put into it.</em></p>

<h2 id="whats-in-a-foam">What’s in a Foam?</h2>

<p>Like the soapy suds it’s named after, <strong>Foam</strong> is mostly air.</p>

<ol>
  <li>The editing experience of <strong>Foam</strong> is powered by VS Code, enhanced by workspace settings that glue together [<a href="https://foambubble.github.io/foam/recommended-extensions.md" title="Recommended Extensions">recommended-extensions</a>] and preferences optimised for writing and navigating information.</li>
  <li>To back up, collaborate on and share your content between devices, Foam pairs well with <a href="http://github.com/">GitHub</a>.</li>
  <li>To publish your content, you can set it up to publish to <a href="https://pages.github.com/">GitHub Pages</a> with zero code and zero config, or to any website hosting platform like <a href="http://netlify.com/">Netlify</a> or <a href="https://vercel.com/">Vercel</a>.</li>
</ol>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Fun fact</strong>: This documentation was researched, written and published using <strong>Foam</strong>.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="getting-started">Getting started</h2>

<blockquote>
  <p>⚠️ Foam is still in preview. Expect the experience to be a little rough.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>These instructions assume you have a GitHub account, and you have Visual Studio Code installed.</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Use the <a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam-template">foam-template project</a> to generate a new repository. If you’re logged into GitHub, you can just hit this button:</p>

    <p><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam-template/generate" data-icon="octicon-repo-template" data-size="large" aria-label="Use this template foambubble/foam-template on GitHub">Use this template</a></p>

    <p><em>If you want to keep your thoughts to yourself, remember to set the repository private, or if you don’t want to use GitHub to host your workspace at all, choose <a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam-template/archive/master.zip"><strong>Download as ZIP</strong></a> instead of <strong>Use this template</strong>.</em></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://help.github.com/en/github/creating-cloning-and-archiving-repositories/cloning-a-repository">Clone the repository locally</a> and open it in VS Code.</p>

    <p><em>Open the repository as a folder using the <code>File &gt; Open...</code> menu item. In VS Code, “open workspace” refers to <a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/editor/multi-root-workspaces">multi-root workspaces</a>.</em></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>When prompted to install recommended extensions, click <strong>Install all</strong> (or <strong>Show Recommendations</strong> if you want to review and install them one by one)</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>After setting up the repository, open <code>.vscode/settings.json</code> and edit, add or remove any settings you’d like for your Foam workspace.</p>

<p>To learn more about how to use <strong>Foam</strong>, read the [<a href="https://foambubble.github.io/foam/recipes/recipes.md" title="Recipes">recipes</a>].</p>

<p>Getting stuck in the setup? Read the [<a href="https://foambubble.github.io/foam/frequently-asked-questions.md" title="Frequently Asked Questions">frequently-asked-questions</a>].</p>

<p>Check our <a href="http://github.com/foambubble/foam/issues">issues on GitHub</a> if you get stuck on something, and create a new one if something doesn’t seem right!</p>

<h2 id="features">Features</h2>

<p><strong>Foam</strong> doesn’t have features in the traditional sense. Out of the box, you have access to all features of VS Code and all the [<a href="https://foambubble.github.io/foam/recommended-extensions.md" title="Recommended Extensions">recommended-extensions</a>] you choose to install, but it’s up to you to discover what you can do with it!</p>

<p><img src="https://foambubble.github.io/foam/assets/images/foam-navigation-demo.gif" alt="Short video of Foam in use"></p>

<p>Head over to [<a href="https://foambubble.github.io/foam/recipes/recipes.md" title="Recipes">recipes</a>] for some useful patterns and ideas!</p>

<h2 id="call-to-adventure">Call To Adventure</h2>

<p>The goal of <strong>Foam</strong> is to be your personal companion on your quest for knowledge.</p>

<p>It’s currently about “10% ready” relative to all the features I’ve thought of, but I’ve only thought of ~1% of the features it could have, and I’m excited to learn from others.</p>

<p>I am using it as my personal thinking tool. By making it public, I hope to learn from others not only how to improve Foam, but also to improve how I learn and manage information.</p>

<p>If that sounds like something you’re interested in, I’d love to have you along on the journey.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Read about our [<a href="https://foambubble.github.io/foam/principles.md" title="Principles">principles</a>] to understand Foam’s philosophy and direction</li>
  <li>Read the [<a href="https://foambubble.github.io/foam/contribution-guide.md" title="Contribution Guide">contribution-guide</a>] guide to learn how to participate.</li>
  <li>Feel free to open <a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/issues">GitHub issues</a> to give me feedback and ideas for new features.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="thanks-and-attribution">Thanks and attribution</h2>

<!-- ALL-CONTRIBUTORS-LIST:START - Do not remove or modify this section -->
<!-- prettier-ignore-start -->
<!-- markdownlint-disable -->
<table>
  <tbody><tr>
    <td><a href="https://jevakallio.dev/"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/1203949?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Jani Eväkallio</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=jevakallio" title="Code">💻</a> <a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=jevakallio" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://joeprevite.com/"><img src="https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/3806031?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Joe Previte</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=jsjoeio" title="Code">💻</a> <a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=jsjoeio" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://github.com/riccardoferretti"><img src="https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/457005?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Riccardo</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=riccardoferretti" title="Code">💻</a> <a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=riccardoferretti" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="http://ojanaho.com/"><img src="https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/2180090?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Janne Ojanaho</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=jojanaho" title="Code">💻</a> <a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=jojanaho" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="http://bypaulshen.com/"><img src="https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/2266187?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Paul Shen</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=paulshen" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://github.com/coffenbacher"><img src="https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/245867?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>coffenbacher</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=coffenbacher" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://mathieu.dutour.me/"><img src="https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/3254314?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Mathieu Dutour</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=mathieudutour" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td><a href="https://github.com/presidentelect"><img src="https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/1242300?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Michael Hansen</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=presidentelect" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="http://klickverbot.at/"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/19335?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>David Nadlinger</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=dnadlinger" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://pluckd.co/"><img src="https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/20598571?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Fernando</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=MrCordeiro" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://github.com/jfgonzalez7"><img src="https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/58857736?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Juan Gonzalez</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=jfgonzalez7" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="http://www.louiechristie.com/"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/6807448?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Louie Christie</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=louiechristie" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://supersandro.de/"><img src="https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/7258858?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Sandro</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=SuperSandro2000" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://github.com/Skn0tt"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/14912729?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Simon Knott</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=Skn0tt" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td><a href="https://styfle.dev/"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/229881?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Steven</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=styfle" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://github.com/Georift"><img src="https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/859430?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Tim</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=Georift" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://github.com/sauravkhdoolia"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/34188267?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Saurav Khdoolia</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=sauravkhdoolia" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://anku.netlify.com/"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/22813027?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Ankit Tiwari</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=anku255" title="Documentation">📖</a> <a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=anku255" title="Tests">⚠️</a> <a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=anku255" title="Code">💻</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://github.com/ayushbaweja"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/44344063?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Ayush Baweja</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=ayushbaweja" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://github.com/TaiChi-IO"><img src="https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/65092992?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>TaiChi-IO</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=TaiChi-IO" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://github.com/juanfrank77"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/12146882?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Juan F Gonzalez </b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=juanfrank77" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td><a href="https://sanketdg.github.io/"><img src="https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/8980971?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Sanket Dasgupta</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=SanketDG" title="Documentation">📖</a> <a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=SanketDG" title="Code">💻</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://github.com/nstafie"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/10801854?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Nicholas Stafie</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=nstafie" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://github.com/francishamel"><img src="https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/36383308?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Francis Hamel</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=francishamel" title="Code">💻</a></td>
    <td><a href="http://digiguru.co.uk/"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/619436?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>digiguru</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=digiguru" title="Code">💻</a> <a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=digiguru" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://github.com/chirag-singhal"><img src="https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/42653703?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>CHIRAG SINGHAL</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=chirag-singhal" title="Code">💻</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://github.com/lostintangent"><img src="https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/116461?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Jonathan Carter</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=lostintangent" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://www.synesthesia.co.uk/"><img src="https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/181399?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Julian Elve</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=synesthesia" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td><a href="https://github.com/thomaskoppelaar"><img src="https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/36331365?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Thomas Koppelaar</b></sub></a><br><a href="#question-thomaskoppelaar" title="Answering Questions">💬</a> <a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=thomaskoppelaar" title="Code">💻</a> <a href="#userTesting-thomaskoppelaar" title="User Testing">📓</a></td>
    <td><a href="http://www.akshaymehra.com/"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/8671497?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Akshay</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=MehraAkshay" title="Code">💻</a></td>
    <td><a href="http://johnlindquist.com/"><img src="https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/36073?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>John Lindquist</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=johnlindquist" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://ashwin.run/"><img src="https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/1689183?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Ashwin Ramaswami</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=epicfaace" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://github.com/Klaudioz"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/632625?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Claudio Canales</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=Klaudioz" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://github.com/vitaly-pevgonen"><img src="https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/6272738?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>vitaly-pevgonen</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=vitaly-pevgonen" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://dshemetov.github.io/"><img src="https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/1810426?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Dmitry Shemetov</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=dshemetov" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td><a href="https://github.com/hooncp"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/48883554?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>hooncp</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=hooncp" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="http://rt-canada.ca/"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/13721239?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Martin Laws</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=martinlaws" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="http://seanksmith.me/"><img src="https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/2085441?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Sean K Smith</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=sksmith" title="Code">💻</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-neely/"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/37545028?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Kevin Neely</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=kneely" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://ariefrahmansyah.dev/"><img src="https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/8122852?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Arief Rahmansyah</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=ariefrahmansyah" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="http://vhanda.in/"><img src="https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/426467?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Vishesh Handa</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=vHanda" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/heroichitesh"><img src="https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/37622734?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Hitesh Kumar</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=HeroicHitesh" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td><a href="https://spencerwoo.com/"><img src="https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/32114380?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Spencer Woo</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=spencerwooo" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://ingalless.com/"><img src="https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/22981941?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>ingalless</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=ingalless" title="Code">💻</a> <a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=ingalless" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="http://jmg-duarte.github.io/"><img src="https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/15343819?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>José Duarte</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=jmg-duarte" title="Code">💻</a> <a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=jmg-duarte" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://www.yenly.wtf/"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/6759658?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Yenly</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=yenly" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://www.hikerpig.cn/"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/2259688?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>hikerpig</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=hikerpig" title="Code">💻</a></td>
    <td><a href="http://sigfried.org/"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/1586931?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Sigfried Gold</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=Sigfried" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="http://www.tristansokol.com/"><img src="https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/867661?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Tristan Sokol</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=tristansokol" title="Code">💻</a></td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td><a href="https://umbrellait.com/"><img src="https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/49779373?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Danil Rodin</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=umbrellait-danil-rodin" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/scottjoewilliams/"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/2026866?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Scott Williams</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=scott-joe" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://jackiexiao.github.io/blog"><img src="https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/18050469?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>jackiexiao</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=Jackiexiao" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://generativist.substack.com/"><img src="https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/78835?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>John B Nelson</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=jbn" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://github.com/asifm"><img src="https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/3958387?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Asif Mehedi</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=asifm" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://github.com/litanlitudan"><img src="https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/4970420?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Tan Li</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=litanlitudan" title="Code">💻</a></td>
    <td><a href="http://shaunagordon.com/"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/579361?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Shauna Gordon</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=ShaunaGordon" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td><a href="https://mcluck.tech/"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/1753801?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Mike Cluck</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=MCluck90" title="Code">💻</a></td>
    <td><a href="http://brandonpugh.com/"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/684781?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Brandon Pugh</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=bpugh" title="Code">💻</a></td>
    <td><a href="https://max.davitt.me/"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/27709025?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Max Davitt</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=themaxdavitt" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="http://briananglin.me/"><img src="https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/2637602?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>Brian Anglin</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=anglinb" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
    <td><a href="http://deft.work/"><img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/1455507?v=4?s=60" width="60px;" alt=""><br><sub><b>elswork</b></sub></a><br><a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/commits?author=elswork" title="Documentation">📖</a></td>
  </tr>
</tbody></table>

<!-- markdownlint-restore -->
<!-- prettier-ignore-end -->

<!-- ALL-CONTRIBUTORS-LIST:END -->

<p><strong>Foam</strong> was inspired by <a href="https://roamresearch.com/">Roam Research</a> and the <a href="https://zettelkasten.de/posts/overview">Zettelkasten methodology</a></p>

<p><strong>Foam</strong> wouldn’t be possible without <a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/">Visual Studio Code</a> and <a href="https://github.com/">GitHub</a>, and relies heavily on our fantastic open source [<a href="https://foambubble.github.io/foam/recommended-extensions.md" title="Recommended Extensions">recommended-extensions</a>] and all their contributors!</p>

<h2 id="license">License</h2>

<p>Foam is licensed under the <a href="https://foambubble.github.io/foam/license">MIT license</a>.</p>







      
      
      
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://foambubble.github.io/foam/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25760066</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 09:51:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The neural network of the Stockfish chess engine]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 354 | Comments 94 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25759430">thread link</a>) | @c1ccccc1
<br/>
January 13, 2021 | https://cp4space.hatsya.com/2021/01/08/the-neural-network-of-the-stockfish-chess-engine/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://cp4space.hatsya.com/2021/01/08/the-neural-network-of-the-stockfish-chess-engine/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
						<p>Last time, we <a href="https://cp4space.hatsya.com/2020/12/13/shallow-trees-with-heavy-leaves/">briefly mentioned</a> the high-level differences between Stockfish and Leela Chess.</p>
<p>To recap, Stockfish evaluates about 100 million positions per second using rudimentary heuristics, whereas Leela Chess evaluates 40 000 positions per second using a deep neural network trained from millions of games of self-play. They also use different tree search approaches: Stockfish uses a variant of alpha-beta pruning, whereas Leela Chess uses Monte Carlo tree search.</p>
<p>An important recent change to Stockfish was to introduce a neural network to evaluate the positions in the search tree, instead of just relying on hardcoded heuristics. It’s still much simpler than Leela Chess’s neural network, and only slows down Stockfish to exploring 50 million positions per second.</p>
<p>The real cleverness of Stockfish’s neural network is that it’s an <strong>efficiently-updatable neural network (NNUE)</strong>. Specifically, it’s a simple feedforward network with:</p>
<ul>
<li>a large (10.5M parameters!) input layer, illustrated below, that can utilise two different levels of sparsity for computational efficiency;</li>
<li>three much smaller layers (with 17.5k parameters in total) which are evaluated densely using vector instructions;</li>
<li>a single scalar output to give a numerical score for the position, indicating how favourable it is for the player about to move.</li>
</ul>
<p>Everything is done using integer arithmetic, with 16-bit weights in the first layer and 8-bit weights in the remaining layers.</p>
<h3>The input layer</h3>
<p>Let’s begin by studying the first — and most interesting — layer. Here’s an illustration I made using Wolfram Mathematica:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cp4space.hatsya.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/nnue-initial.png" alt="" width="640" height="760" srcset="https://cp4space.hatsya.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/nnue-initial.png 640w, https://cp4space.hatsya.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/nnue-initial-253x300.png 253w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px"></p>
<p>The inputs to the layer are two sparse binary arrays, each consisting of 41024 elements. It may seem highly redundant to encode a chess position using 82048 binary features, but this is similar to <a href="https://ai.googleblog.com/2016/06/wide-deep-learning-better-together-with.html">an approach</a> (called ‘feature crosses’) used in recommender systems.</p>
<p>What are the two sparse binary arrays, and why do they have 41024 features? My preferred way of interpreting these two arrays are as the ‘worldviews’ of the white king and the black king. In particular, the differences are:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Coordinate systems:</strong> because black and white pawns move in opposite directions, the two players need to ‘see the board from opposite angles’. This already happens in regular (human) chess because the two players are seated opposite each other at the chessboard, so one player’s ‘top’ is the other player’s ‘bottom’. If you imagine each player numbering the squares from top to bottom, left to right, then any physical square would be called <em>n</em> by one player and 63 − <em>n</em> by the other player.</li>
<li><strong>Piece types:</strong> instead of viewing the pieces as black or white, a player sees it as either ‘mine’ or ‘theirs’. The 10 non-king piece types are thus {my pawn, their pawn, my knight, their knight, my bishop, their bishop, my rook, their rook, my queen, their queen}.</li>
</ul>
<p>The reason for these ‘player-relative coordinate systems’ is that it means that Stockfish can use the same neural network irrespective of whether it’s playing as white or black. The network uses <em>both</em> your king’s worldview and your enemy king’s worldview for evaluating a position, because they’re both highly relevant (you want to protect your own king and capture your enemy’s king).</p>
<p>So, why does each worldview have 41024 features? It can be seen as an outer product (or tensor product) of:</p>
<ul>
<li>a 64-element feature encoding the position of the king whose worldview this is, in their own coordinate system. This is ‘one-hot encoding’, where exactly one of the 64 entries is ‘1’ and the other 63 entries are ‘0’.</li>
<li>a 641-element feature encoding, for each of the 64 × 10 ordered pairs (square, piece-type), whether or not that square is occupied by that piece. The 641st element is unused, and is (according to the <a href="https://www.chessprogramming.org/Stockfish_NNUE">Chess Programming Wiki</a>) apparently a result of the network being ported from Shogi to chess.</li>
</ul>
<p>Each of the two 64-by-641 outer product matrices* is then flattened (the matrix is ‘reshaped’ into a vector with the same entries) to yield the corresponding 41024-element ‘sparse worldview’. In the input layer, each of the two 41024-element sparse worldviews are then affinely transformed to form a 256-element ‘dense worldview’.</p>
<p><strong>*Important note:</strong> the 41024-element sparse binary arrays are never explicitly materialised, either as a 64-by-641 matrix or as a 41024-element vector. The Stockfish NNUE effectively ‘fuses’ the construction of these sparse vectors with the subsequent affine transformation (described below), updating the 256-element dense worldviews directly when the configuration of pieces on the chessboard is modified.</p>
<p>There are <strong>two levels of sparsity</strong> which are utilised when computing this affine transformation from <img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%5Cmathbb%7BR%7D%5E%7B41024%7D&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=000&amp;s=0&amp;c=20201002" alt="\mathbb{R}^{41024}" title="\mathbb{R}^{41024}"> to <img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%5Cmathbb%7BR%7D%5E%7B256%7D&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=000&amp;s=0&amp;c=20201002" alt="\mathbb{R}^{256}" title="\mathbb{R}^{256}">, allowing the network to be efficiently evaluated many times in a tree search:</p>
<ul>
<li>the 41024-element implicit vectors are themselves sparse: the number of nonzero elements is equal to the number of non-king pieces on the board.</li>
<li>moving a piece typically changes very few of the entries of the vector: if it’s a regular non-king move, only 2 entries change; if it’s a non-king move with capture, then 3 entries change.</li>
</ul>
<p>It’s this second aspect which warrants the name ‘efficiently updatable’: when a move is made (or unmade, since we’re doing a tree search), we only need to add/subtract a few 256-element matrix columns from the resulting ‘dense worldview’ to update it.</p>
<p>Unless a king is moved, this (2 or 3 vector additions/subtractions) beats summing all of the matrix columns corresponding to nonzero entries (up to 30 vector additions), which in turn unconditionally beats doing a regular dense matrix-vector multiplication (41024 vector additions). That is to say, the second-level sparsity is about 10 times more efficient than the first-level sparsity, which is in turn about 1000 times more efficient than naively doing a dense matrix-vector multiplication.</p>
<p>The two dense worldviews are concatenated according to which player is about to move, producing a 512-element vector, which is elementwise clamped to [0, 127]. This elementwise clamping is the nonlinear activation function of the input layer, and (as we’ll describe) the hidden layers use a similar activation function. We can think of this as a ‘clipped ReLU’, which is <a href="https://github.com/official-stockfish/Stockfish/blob/master/src/nnue/layers/clipped_relu.h">exactly what the Stockfish source code calls it</a>.</p>
<h3>The remaining layers</h3>
<p>The two hidden layers each use 8-bit weights and 32-bit biases. The activation function first divides the resulting 32-bit integer by 64 before again clamping to [0, 127], ready to be fed into the next layer. The output layer also uses 8-bit weights and 32-bit biases, but with no nonlinear activation function.</p>
<p>The first hidden layer takes 512 inputs (the clamped concatenated worldviews) and produces 32 outputs. The second hidden layer takes those 32 values as inputs, and again produces 32 outputs. The output layer takes those 32 values as inputs, and produces a single scalar output.</p>
<p>Since these subsequent layers are applied to dense vectors, they can’t use the same ‘efficiently updatable’ approach as the input layer; that’s why they’re necessarily substantially smaller. They can, however, use hardware vectorisation instructions (SSE/AVX) to apply the linear transformation and activation function.</p>
<p>This scalar output is then <a href="http://www.talkchess.com/forum3/viewtopic.php?f=7&amp;t=75506&amp;start=9">further postprocessed</a> using other Stockfish heuristics, including taking into account the 50-move rule which isn’t otherwise incorporated into the evaluation function.</p>
<p>Observe that the neural network doesn’t actually have complete information, such as whether a pawn has just moved two squares (relevant to <em>en passant</em>), whether a king is able to castle, and various other information pertaining to the rather complicated rules for determining a draw. This is okay: the network is only being used as a cheap approximate evaluation for a position; when deciding what move to make, Stockfish performs a very deep tree search and only uses this approximate evaluation in the leaves.</p>
<p>Equivalently, you can think of this as being a massive refinement of the approach of ‘look a few moves ahead and see whether either player gains a material or positional advantage’, using a neural network as a much more sophisticated position-aware alternative of crudely ‘counting material’.</p>
<p>This is a neural network, so the weight matrices and bias vectors of the layers were learned by training the network on millions of positions and using backpropagation and a gradient-based optimiser. Of course, for supervised learning, you need a ‘ground truth’ for the network to attempt to learn, which seems somewhat circular: how do you even gather training data? The answer is that you use the classical version of Stockfish to evaluate positions <strong>using the deep tree search</strong>, and use that as your training data.</p>
<p>In theory, you could then train another copy of the NNUE using the NNUE-enhanced Stockfish as the evaluation function, and then iterate this process. Leela Chess does the same thing: its current network is trained on positions evaluated by using deep lookahead with the previous network as the leaf evaluation function. Note that the construction of the training data is orders of magnitude more expensive than training the network with this data, as you’re doing thousands of evaluations of the previous network (owing to the deep tree search) to construct each item of training data for the new network.</p>
<h3>Further reading</h3>
<p>The network is <a href="https://www.chessprogramming.org/Stockfish_NNUE">described and illustrated</a> on the Chess Programming Wiki, which also has tonnes of references to forum discussions and other references. The first description of an NNUE was a Japanese paper by Yu Nasu (who suggested it for the board game Shogi instead of chess); the paper has <a href="https://github.com/asdfjkl/nnue">since been translated</a> into English and German. There’s also the Stockfish source code, which is very well organised (there’s <a href="https://github.com/official-stockfish/Stockfish/tree/master/src/nnue">a directory</a> for the NNUE) and clearly written.</p>
											</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://cp4space.hatsya.com/2021/01/08/the-neural-network-of-the-stockfish-chess-engine/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25759430</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 08:01:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Drawbridge: What SQL Server on Linux is built on]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 59 | Comments 15 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25758012">thread link</a>) | @tech234a
<br/>
January 12, 2021 | https://threedots.ovh/blog/2021/01/drawbridge-what-sql-server-on-linux-is-built-on/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://threedots.ovh/blog/2021/01/drawbridge-what-sql-server-on-linux-is-built-on/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-146">

	

	<div>
		
<p>Interestingly, public materials about the <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/project/drawbridge/">Drawbridge</a> variant used on SQL Server are few and far between.</p>



<p>So <a href="https://threedots.ovh/slides/Drawbridge.pdf">here</a> is a slide deck about me working with Drawbridge from several years back. I’ve updated parts of it later on, keeping up partially with more recent SQLPAL versions.</p>



<p>Since I made that slide deck, lots of things happened… which will maybe be a subject for a story or two some day.</p>
	</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->

				
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://threedots.ovh/blog/2021/01/drawbridge-what-sql-server-on-linux-is-built-on/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25758012</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 04:12:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Signal community: Reminder: Please be nice]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 1143 | Comments 428 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25757398">thread link</a>) | @decrypt
<br/>
January 12, 2021 | https://community.signalusers.org/t/reminder-please-be-nice/21217 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://community.signalusers.org/t/reminder-please-be-nice/21217">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main-outlet">
        

  


      <div itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting">
        <div>
          
          


          <p><span>
              <meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2021-01-12T10:20:07Z">
              <time itemprop="dateModified" datetime="2021-01-14T09:19:59Z">
                January 14, 2021,  9:19am
              </time>
          <span itemprop="position">#1</span>
          </span>
        </p></div>
        <div itemprop="articleBody">
          <p>I have seen a significant uptick of people posting or joining the forums and using belligerent language, making unilateral demands and insulting the process that is open source software. “The fact you haven’t done x is stupid”. “How can you write a piece of software that doesn’t do y?”. “It’s 2021 and you still can’t make a program do z, how pathetic”. Not exact words, but accurate sentiments.</p>
<p>Please don’t do this. Please be nice.</p>
<p>The Signal team, as with any open-source team, are not infinite resources to pour down the drain. Every hour they spend on their job working for Signal, every hour they spend after work helping out, every hour a volunteer puts into forum support and bug investigation, is an hour consumed. To receive insults and vitriol in return is corrosive. It is unfair and it is not in the spirit of giving, of making something and offering it for free.</p>
<p>You’re receiving this for free, this great software which is made by people who <em>literally care</em> about your privacy. They don’t know you, and they sure don’t know what you talk about on Signal, and yet they put in a lot of effort for this. Not to make wads of cash. Not to sell you to advertisers for your social life to be analysed and abused.</p>
<p>The developer for the Mastodon software Fedilab recently <a href="https://framagit.org/tom79/fedilab/-/issues/498" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">revealed he has been burnt out</a> and I’ve read elsewhere it was because people were screaming hate at him for a principle he upheld - which was that his software would not censor people screaming hate at each other. I’m sure you can appreciate the painful irony here. (Please note that his stepping down seems to be for real, the specific reasons I’ve gave are speculation). I, for one, chose his software specifically because it did not censor, because whilst I believe a service can censor if it chooses, software must remain neutral. (If you wish to discuss this, perhaps let’s do that on another thread).</p>
<p>Don’t be that person. Don’t jump on issues making demands. Don’t pile on forum threads that make some users’ opinions very clear as it is, and throw your bellicose howling in there too. Don’t insult the developers or their priorities, their choices. They are real people who have a finite capacity for work and for abuse. Add a thumbs up to an issue, add a heart to a forum request. Post only if you can materially add to the discussion, else use a reaction. Post in the spirit and the letter of the <a href="https://community.signalusers.org/guidelines">community guidelines</a>.</p>
<p>Please be nice.</p>
        </div>

        <meta itemprop="headline" content="Reminder: Please be nice">
          <meta itemprop="keywords" content="">

        

         

      </div>
      <div itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting">
        
        <div itemprop="articleBody">
          <p>We as old community members should also be reminded to be nice even when other people are not nice.<br>
I can talk of myself (and think many other here feel the same) that sometimes when a wave of people hits and behave bad I am angry and I should be nicer to other people.</p>
<p>So to us, even when we have people misbehave and maybe even spaming or other stuff we should still try to be serious and nice to each other :)</p>
<p>Have a nice day all!</p>
        </div>

        <meta itemprop="headline" content="Reminder: Please be nice">

        

         

      </div>
      <div itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting">
        
        <p><a href="https://community.signalusers.org/u/herohtar">@Herohtar</a> I’d suggest to pin this topic at the top wherever that’s possible (at least for now)</p>

        <meta itemprop="headline" content="Reminder: Please be nice">

        

         

      </div>
      <div itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting">
        <div>
          
          <p><span itemprop="author" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Person">
            <a itemprop="url" href="https://community.signalusers.org/u/Herohtar"><span itemprop="name">Herohtar</span></a>
            
              pinned globally 
          </span></p>


          <p><span>
              <time itemprop="datePublished" datetime="2021-01-12T22:38:12Z">
                January 12, 2021, 10:38pm
              </time>
              <meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2021-01-12T22:38:12Z">
          <span itemprop="position">#6</span>
          </span>
        </p></div>
        

        <meta itemprop="headline" content="Reminder: Please be nice">

        

         

      </div>
      <div itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting">
        
        <p>I’ve tried pinning it globally for a month, we’ll see how that goes.</p>

        <meta itemprop="headline" content="Reminder: Please be nice">

        

         

      </div>
      <div itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting">
        <div>
          
          <p><span itemprop="author" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Person">
            <a itemprop="url" href="https://community.signalusers.org/u/Junkii"><span itemprop="name">Junkii</span></a>
            
          </span></p>


          <p><span>
              <time itemprop="datePublished" datetime="2021-01-13T00:51:24Z">
                January 13, 2021, 12:51am
              </time>
              <meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2021-01-13T00:51:24Z">
          <span itemprop="position">#8</span>
          </span>
        </p></div>
        <p>Thank- you. Great reminder. Community is important.</p>

        <meta itemprop="headline" content="Reminder: Please be nice">

        

         

      </div>
      <div itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting">
        
        <p>This post was flagged by the community and is temporarily hidden.</p>

        <meta itemprop="headline" content="Reminder: Please be nice">

        

         

      </div>
      <div itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting">
        <div>
          
          <p><span itemprop="author" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Person">
            <a itemprop="url" href="https://community.signalusers.org/u/Meteor0id"><span itemprop="name">Meteor0id</span></a>
            (Meteor0id)
          </span></p>


          <p><span>
              <time itemprop="datePublished" datetime="2021-01-13T02:06:08Z">
                January 13, 2021,  2:06am
              </time>
              <meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2021-01-13T02:06:08Z">
          <span itemprop="position">#11</span>
          </span>
        </p></div>
        <p>Taking a risk of offending people is not a means to push your opinion. There is no law against it, but there are community guidelines against it.<br>
Pushing the buttons of other people, you full well know that sooner or later you will push a button that triggers something. That’s why we don’t push each others buttons in the first place. you can always make your point without being rude.</p>

        <meta itemprop="headline" content="Reminder: Please be nice">

        

         

      </div>
      <div itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting">
        <div>
          
          <p><span itemprop="author" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Person">
            <a itemprop="url" href="https://community.signalusers.org/u/m-graf"><span itemprop="name">m-graf</span></a>
            (Graf)
          </span></p>


          <p><span>
              <time itemprop="datePublished" datetime="2021-01-13T04:15:26Z">
                January 13, 2021,  4:15am
              </time>
              <meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2021-01-13T04:15:26Z">
          <span itemprop="position">#12</span>
          </span>
        </p></div>
        <p>Thank you for encouraging this. If y’all need an engineer who’s dabbling in product, message me. I’d love to help however I can.</p>

        <meta itemprop="headline" content="Reminder: Please be nice">

        

         

      </div>
      <div itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting">
        
        <p>You being offended by my offensive behaviour is offensive.</p>

        <meta itemprop="headline" content="Reminder: Please be nice">

        

         

      </div>
      <div itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting">
        <div>
          
          <p><span itemprop="author" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Person">
            <a itemprop="url" href="https://community.signalusers.org/u/CatEars"><span itemprop="name">CatEars</span></a>
            
          </span></p>


          <p><span>
              <time itemprop="datePublished" datetime="2021-01-13T06:11:57Z">
                January 13, 2021,  6:11am
              </time>
              <meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2021-01-13T06:11:57Z">
          <span itemprop="position">#14</span>
          </span>
        </p></div>
        <div itemprop="articleBody">
          <p>This is a great example of what not to say.</p>
<p>When a community leader says “Please be nice to each other”, the appropriate response is not “cyber bullying is not against the law, so it is okay”.</p>
        </div>

        <meta itemprop="headline" content="Reminder: Please be nice">

        

         

      </div>
      <div itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting">
        
        <div itemprop="articleBody">
          
<p>This is not cool, and you have kind of missed the point entirely.</p>
<p>As the post says, the people behind the non-profit app are spending time out of their days to help everyone get the best out of the app. Of late, with the influx of users requesting (and demanding!) features akin to WhatsApp and the other monstrosities, it’s likely to take its toll.</p>
<p>I appreciate what you are saying, to a degree. I also don’t think your post should be ‘hidden’ as it’s been reported by the Cancel-Culture-Community. I firmly believe that if you say something, you own that! As you will expect, people are entitled to reply to that to support or rebut. That’s called a conversation. So you shouldn’t be denied that. That said, the Community Guidelines are what they are. And if we disagree, we can chose not to participate.</p>
<p>In summary, the bottom line is being aware of the unkindness towards those trying to help. Berating developers for not having something featured isn’t likely to inspire ‘will’. Neither is your post. But then you have every right to say what you have said and others have the right to reply to it accordingly. In my opinion, anyway.</p>
        </div>

        <meta itemprop="headline" content="Reminder: Please be nice">

        

         

      </div>
      <div itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting">
        <div>
          
          <p><span itemprop="author" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Person">
            <a itemprop="url" href="https://community.signalusers.org/u/Rafi993"><span itemprop="name">Rafi993</span></a>
            (Rafi)
          </span></p>


          <p><span>
              <meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2021-01-13T09:17:16Z">
              <time itemprop="dateModified" datetime="2021-01-13T09:25:39Z">
                January 13, 2021,  9:25am
              </time>
          <span itemprop="position">#16</span>
          </span>
        </p></div>
        <p>Thanks for signal developers for this awesome product that is given for free and other people in the community for being awesome. Being nice to other people in the community might make some ones day little better.</p>

        <meta itemprop="headline" content="Reminder: Please be nice">

        

         

      </div>
      <div itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting">
        
        <div itemprop="articleBody">
          <p>Firstly. Thank you to Signal Devs. I think you’re all doing an amazing job and I will be signing up to donate, even if it is a small amount.</p>
<p>One thing I want to say to the Signal Dev Team. I bet that 99% of your user base appreciate all the hard work you are doing and want to support you in any way they can, myself included, even if just morally. Please don’t let that 1% of intolerant users discourage you from all the great input you have.</p>
<p>I am a great supporter of free speech even if something is “offensive” but posters must also realize the difference between <strong>“saying something offensive”</strong> and <strong>"hate speech"</strong></p>
<p>Keep up the good work Signal <img src="https://community.signalusers.org/images/emoji/apple/+1.png?v=9" title=":+1:" alt=":+1:"></p>
        </div>

        <meta itemprop="headline" content="Reminder: Please be nice">

        

         

      </div>
      <div itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting">
        <div>
          
          <p><span itemprop="author" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Person">
            <a itemprop="url" href="https://community.signalusers.org/u/Froiz"><span itemprop="name">Froiz</span></a>
            (Froiz)
          </span></p>


          <p><span>
              <time itemprop="datePublished" datetime="2021-01-13T09:56:56Z">
                January 13, 2021,  9:56am
              </time>
              <meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2021-01-13T09:56:56Z">
          <span itemprop="position">#18</span>
          </span>
        </p></div>
        <div itemprop="articleBody">
          
<p>You might have the right to say what you want, but free speech isn’t about interrupting a conversation about football yelling about zebras. Free speech is about tolerance, about a productive and focused conversation –that’s why there’re guidelines, and why guidelines are there to be tolerated.</p>
        </div>

        <meta itemprop="headline" content="Reminder: Please be nice">

        

         

      </div>
      <div itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting">
        
        <div itemprop="articleBody">
          
<p>I was one of the flaggers. I am fine with someone disagreeing with me and refuting or rebutting what I’ve said. I even tolerate them doing so rudely if their points are salient. (A few hours later I usually come back and +1 their post with begrudging flouncing) If their first post on a forum is flaming someone without addressing a single one of their points in a coherent or sensible way, misrepresenting the letter and spirit of the conversation and acting generally in bad-faith, then I will flag that as it’s not a conversation, it’s just pointless screaming. If they also break the rules then they’re definitely getting a flag.</p>
<p>Flagging/reporting a post is not cancel culture at all. Flagging a rude, abusive or entirely unconstructive post is doing your bit as a member of the community to weed out bad behaviour and bad actors. I urge everyone to flag anyone posting in bad faith, or breaking the rules. Flag it all and let the pages written by people who detract from the conversation burn.</p>
<p>I did not hunt down the user to find all of their …</p></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://community.signalusers.org/t/reminder-please-be-nice/21217">https://community.signalusers.org/t/reminder-please-be-nice/21217</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://community.signalusers.org/t/reminder-please-be-nice/21217</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25757398</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 02:50:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Distributing Mac apps outside the App Store, a quick start guide]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 306 | Comments 158 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25757228">thread link</a>) | @tosh
<br/>
January 12, 2021 | https://rambo.codes/posts/2021-01-08-distributing-mac-apps-outside-the-app-store | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rambo.codes/posts/2021-01-08-distributing-mac-apps-outside-the-app-store">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article><div><p>The Mac has always been very different from its close relative, iOS, especially when it comes to what a user is or is not allowed to run on their system. Even with the introduction of Apple Silicon, Apple <a href="https://developer.apple.com/videos/play/wwdc2020/10686/?t=1161">has made it very clear</a> that the Mac is still the Mac, and is still <em>hackable</em>, even when running on the new architecture.</p><p>What this means for us developers is that, when targeting the Mac platform, we have choices: we can distribute our apps independently, outside the Mac App Store, through the Mac App Store exclusively, or through both at the same time.</p><p>This article is my brain dump on the subject. It is meant to be a guide on the things that you’ll need to know about when distributing a Mac app outside the App Store, rather than a how-to tutorial. My hope is that having everything listed here will help demystify the process for beginners, and the descriptions of my own process will be useful as starting points.</p><h2>App Store x Direct: pros and cons</h2><p>All of these choices come with their pros and cons, and depending on which type of Mac app you’re making, you might not be able to have it in the Mac App Store to begin with. An example of that is my app <a href="https://v2.airbuddy.app/">AirBuddy</a> which, in order to provide deep integration with Apple’s wireless devices, needs to run a system agent and use some private APIs, which would never be allowed in the App Store. The same goes for many other types of apps which simply wouldn’t work with the restrictions of the Mac’s sandbox.</p><p>For those who do have that choice, I’ve compiled a list of what I believe to be the pros and cons between shipping through the Mac App Store or shipping directly.</p><h3>Mac App Store pros</h3><ul><li>Apple handles the distribution, billing and licensing for you</li><li>The app is easier to find and install for most users</li><li>Potential to get featured by Apple and reach more customers</li><li>Can use features such as Sign in With Apple which are not available for apps distributed outside the Mac App Store</li></ul><h3>Mac App Store cons</h3><ul><li>Have to pay a 15% or 30% cut of all sales to Apple, <a href="https://developer.apple.com/app-store/small-business-program/">depending on how much you make in a year across all apps</a></li><li>Every single update, no matter how minor, has to go through App Review and has the potential of being rejected for arbitrary and random reasons</li><li>Can’t unlock the full potential of macOS because of the strict sandboxing requirements</li><li>Can’t do paid upgrades</li></ul><h3>Direct distribution pros</h3><ul><li>Ship updates whenever you want, no need to wait for them to be reviewed and no fear of random rejections</li><li>Unlock the full potential of macOS with system extensions, daemons, no sandboxing, private API, and more</li><li>Keep a higher percentage of your sales</li><li>Do paid upgrades or other business models which are not allowed in the App Store</li><li>Live without the constant fear that your app will suddenly become a problem for Apple and be threatened with removal from the App Store</li></ul><h3>Direct distribution cons</h3><ul><li>Have to handle licensing, distribution, and updates (it’s not that hard, you’ll see)</li><li>Not as easy to do consumable or non-consumable in-app purchases (no StoreKit)</li><li>Can’t use some Apple services such as Sign in With Apple (others such as CloudKit still work just fine)</li></ul><h2>A note on Catalyst and SwiftUI</h2><p>With the introduction of Catalyst, we’re now seeing many new Mac apps being released, since it’s a lot easier to take an existing iPad app and turn it into a Mac app. Apps ported to macOS through Catalyst are not required to be released in the App Store, even if their counterpart on iOS is.</p><p>Additionally, there is currently no TestFlight for macOS (one of my wishes for 2021), so if you’d like to distribute beta builds of a Catalyst app, you’ll have to do that outside the Mac App Store, and it is not that different from distributing a production app.</p><p>A lot of what I’m presenting here will also apply for Catalyst apps — they’re Mac apps, after all — but some might require additional hacking in order to work around the fact that Apple doesn’t want you to use the entirety of AppKit directly from within a Catalyst app. With a bit of work though, you can make a Catalyst app very Mac-capable, including <a href="https://www.highcaffeinecontent.com/blog/20190607-Beyond-the-Checkbox-with-Catalyst-and-AppKit">support for AppleScript</a> and other features.</p><p>For SwiftUI apps targeting the Mac, there should be no major differences with the distribution process, since you can use all features of the macOS API in a SwiftUI app without requiring a lot of hacking like it does for Catalyst apps.</p><h2>Distribution</h2><p>Distribution of an app involves two parts: actually uploading, storing and serving the app binary and its updates somewhere, and also producing the right package that will work for your users.</p><h3>Hosting</h3><p>The first major step with getting your Mac app in the hands of users without the App Store is to figure out how to distribute its binary. No App Store means that you’ll have to host your app’s binaries and updates somewhere on the internet and provide a link for your users to download it.</p><p>There are several ways you can go about this. For an open-source app, you can use Github releases and even host your app’s update feed in the Github repo. That’s how I distribute the <a href="https://github.com/insidegui/WWDC/releases">WWDC app for macOS</a>.</p><p>For my commercial apps, I’ve been using <a href="https://www.backblaze.com/b2/cloud-storage.html">Backblaze B2</a> for storage of both the app binaries, delta updates and update feed, and proxying all requests through <a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/">Cloudflare</a> so that I can have a custom domain for the downloads/updates and also add filtering, caching and logic on the server if needed.</p><p>B2 is an extremely affordable provider (I rarely pay over US$1 in a month). Most Mac apps are not that large in size, so even if your app is downloaded a lot, it’s unlikely that you’ll end up having to pay a lot of money for storage/bandwidth. Another popular option is using <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/s3/">Amazon S3</a> buckets, but their control panel gives me nightmares so I prefer to use B2 which is a lot simpler (and less expensive).</p><p>I haven’t automated the publishing step for my app releases as of yet, so to upload a new release I just use <a href="https://panic.com/transmit/">Transmit</a> as a client for my B2 buckets. Speaking of that, before we even get to upload a release to whatever provider we’ve chosen, there’s a very important step: getting the right file to put out there.</p><h3>Notarization and packaging</h3><p>When exporting an archived app from within Xcode, we get two main options for distribution: App Store Connect and Developer ID. To distribute apps without the App Store, you’re going to be using Developer ID.</p><p>The same developer account you use for distributing apps to the Mac App Store can be used to sign your apps for Developer ID distribution. The certificate itself is different, but Xcode will auto-generate and install one for you during the process of exporting the archive if you haven’t done so yet.</p><p>Since macOS Catalina, all apps distributed directly to users must be notarized by Apple, otherwise they won’t launch by default. This process uploads your app to Apple, which will then run automated malware checks and “staple” your binary with a special signature that will allow it to run. This is not App Review, it’s an automated check to prevent malware from being distributed through this method, and it is also a way for Apple to flag a single binary for malware, instead of a developer’s entire account, should it become compromised at some point.</p><p>Whether or not you notarize the binary directly from within the Xcode organizer will depend on which packaging method you’ll be using to distribute your app. We can’t just upload a <code>.app</code> directory to a server and let users download that, we have to turn it into a flat file. The simple way to do that is to just zip the app and distribute it as a zip file, but I’ve found through experience that distributing the app as a DMG file reduces support requests by quite a bit.</p><p>You’ve probably seen DMGs before when downloading Mac apps. They’re disk images that are mounted by macOS when double-clicked in Finder, and they can also provide some artwork instructing the user to drag the app into their Applications folder. This makes it easy for a user to figure out what to do, and it also reduces the chances that a given user will be running your app from their Downloads folder or some other random place like that.</p><p>If you’re going to be distributing your app as a DMG, you should just export it using the Developer ID option in Xcode, without notarization, then notarize the DMG itself. There’s no option in Xcode to export a DMG, so you’ll have to use a third-party tool. The one I like to use is <a href="https://github.com/sindresorhus/create-dmg">create-dmg</a>. I’ve also created and open-sourced <a href="https://github.com/insidegui/dmgdist">dmgdist</a>, a tool that automates the process of creating, uploading and stapling the DMG so that you can get the image ready to be distributed by running a single command.</p><p>To distribute the app as a zip file, the process is simpler: pick the upload option from Xcode after selecting “Developer ID” and it’ll produce a notarized version of your app, which you can then zip up and distribute directly.</p><h2>App updates</h2><p>Another aspect of the App Store is that it also handles app updates. Whenever we upload a new version to App Store Connect and it gets approved, users receive the update in the App Store. For apps distributed directly, we need to replicate that somehow.</p><p>The best way to do that — and the most common — is to use <a href="https://sparkle-project.org/">Sparkle</a>. It’s been around for many many years and is pretty much the official way to distribute updates for Mac apps distributed outside the Mac App Store.</p><p>Sparkle is currently living a double life of sorts. You can either use the “legacy” version of Sparkle or use a more modern “v2” branch which includes many improvements such as the ability to update sandboxed apps. I still use the “legacy” version because it’s the one that I’m familiar with and I find that integrating the more modern version is still a bit more complicated. If it ain’t broke, don’t fix it.</p><p>The process of generating an app update usually goes as follows: ensure that with every update you increase the app’s version (of course), produce the package as described before (Sparkle can handle zips, DMGs and installer packages), then use the <code>generate_appcast</code> tool to update the feed. After doing that, upload the deltas, the package for the new version, and the updated AppCast …</p></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://rambo.codes/posts/2021-01-08-distributing-mac-apps-outside-the-app-store">https://rambo.codes/posts/2021-01-08-distributing-mac-apps-outside-the-app-store</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rambo.codes/posts/2021-01-08-distributing-mac-apps-outside-the-app-store</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25757228</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 02:28:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
