<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 5]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 5. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 08:23:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-5.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 08:23:37 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Annoying website features I face as a blind person]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 220 | Comments 123 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24429012">thread link</a>) | @Garbage
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://bighack.org/5-most-annoying-website-features-i-face-as-a-blind-screen-reader-user-accessibility/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bighack.org/5-most-annoying-website-features-i-face-as-a-blind-screen-reader-user-accessibility/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p><span>These are the five most annoying inaccessible web elements I face as a blind screen reader user every day, and how to fix them.
</span>
					</p><div>
						<p><span>For blind and visually impaired people like me, accessibility is the difference between us being able to use a website and clicking off it.&nbsp;</span></p>
<h2>How screen readers work</h2>
<p><span>Screen readers allow blind and visually impaired people to use computers, phones and tablets independently. Most screen readers use software, and a Text To Speech (TTS) engine, which is what converts the text from the screen reader into speech. Screen readers convert the text displayed on screen into a format that blind users can process.</span></p>
<p><span>Screen readers read out loud everything that’s on the screen and allow people to navigate using touch gestures and shortcut keys. They also work with other output devices such as a braille display.</span></p>
<p><span>As a screen reader user, here are the most common issues I encounter on a daily basis.&nbsp;</span></p>
<h2>Unlabelled links and buttons</h2>
<p><span>Screen reader users rely on links and buttons to navigate around a website and to find the information we need. If links and buttons are not labelled correctly or if at all, then it makes it difficult for screen reader users to find the information they need. Ultimately, unlabelled links make it much harder to navigate the website easily, quickly and independently.</span></p>
<p><span>For example, when linking to an about page, ‘click here’ doesn’t give any clue as to where it leads to, but ‘find out more about who we are’ is clear.</span></p>
<p><span>If links and buttons are labelled correctly, screen readers can read the label out loud. It means that blind and visually impaired people don’t have to press the link or button without knowing where it will take them.</span></p>
<p><span>As well as unlabelled elements, links and buttons that do not have a clear description are also really frustrating. They must have a clear description of where they will lead to when pressed, rather than ‘click here’. Never make your users guess where a link will take them or force them into a trial-and-error situation. This makes for tedious user experience.</span></p>
<h2>No image descriptions</h2>
<p><span>This is probably the most common issue I encounter when browsing the web.&nbsp;</span><span>Using image descriptions is essential for accessibility. Image descriptions are also known as alt text (alternative text) which is a written description of an image.</span></p>
<p><span>Screen readers read image descriptions out loud. This means that blind and visually impaired people can understand the content of the image in an accessible way.&nbsp;</span><span>If images do not have alt text, then screen readers will simply say “image” or “graphic” which gives no context or meaning.</span></p>
<p><span>Images often convey valuable information. It’s therefore important that people with a visual impairment can access this information as well.&nbsp;</span><span>Alt text should be clearly written and give an accurate description of the image.</span></p>
<p><strong>Check out <a href="https://bighack.org/how-to-write-better-alt-text-descriptions-for-accessibility/">our tips for writing better alt text</a> to ensure your images are fully accessible.</strong></p>
<h2>Poor use of headings</h2>
<p><span>For quick and easy navigation, many screen reader users navigate using various elements on the page such as headings. They are a great way to find the information we need quickly and effectively. Especially when they follow a logical heading structure with H1s, H2s and H3s helping to prioritise the content.</span></p>
<p><img src="https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x.jpg" alt="Logical heading structure begins with Heading 1, with Heading 2 sitting beneath heading 1. Heading 3 sits within heading 2 and so on." width="1958" height="1236" srcset="https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x.jpg 1958w, https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x-300x189.jpg 300w, https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x-768x485.jpg 768w, https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x-1536x970.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1958px) 100vw, 1958px" data-srcset="https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x.jpg 1958w, https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x-300x189.jpg 300w, https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x-768x485.jpg 768w, https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x-1536x970.jpg 1536w" data-src="https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x.jpg" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></p>
<p><span>If websites don’t use headings, it means screen reader users are unable to use the keyboard shortcuts to navigate through the webpage this way. If that’s the case, we have to resort to tabbing or arrowing through a long web page to find the information we need.</span></p>
<p>Headings also help to break up the web content visually and improve readability. Other elements that screen reader users use to navigate webpages include links, lists or landmarks.</p>
<h2>Inaccessible web forms</h2>
<p><span>Most websites use forms in one way or another. Whether it’s to help you search for a product or to get in touch through a contact form. However, when these forms are not labelled, or not labelled correctly, it means we cannot use them.</span></p>
<p><span>For example, if a search box is not labelled, it means screen reader users have no idea of the purpose of that box. It means people who use screen readers cannot access the same functionality.</span></p>
<p><span>Contact forms are an effective way for customers to get in touch with your brand or business. And as a screen reader user, there’s nothing more frustrating than these forms being labelled incorrectly.</span></p>
<p><span>Especially CAPTCHA checkout requirements. Without an option to hear the audio, it’s not accessible. It means we are unable to fill in the form independently. I often have to enlist help from a sighted person, but this isn’t possible for everyone.</span><b>&nbsp;</b></p>
<h2>Auto-playing audio and video</h2>
<p><span>Most people will know how annoying it is to load a web page with noisy adverts that start playing suddenly. But for screen reader users, it can be even more alarming. When video or audio starts playing automatically, it can drown out the voice of the screen reader. This makes it harder to find the pause or stop buttons.</span></p>
<p><span>(And if these buttons are unlabelled, then it’s practically impossible for me to stop the video quickly which causes extra frustration.) If I’m unable to stop the sound or video, I normally click off.</span></p>
<p><span>The solution? Make sure there’s no auto-playing video or audio when your website loads. If you really want to use video, make sure the audio is muted and the user can pause, stop or hide the media player.</span></p>
<p><span>These issues may seem small to sighted users. But they’re the difference between me being able to use a website independently or not. And they make a huge difference when implemented correctly.</span></p>
					</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bighack.org/5-most-annoying-website-features-i-face-as-a-blind-screen-reader-user-accessibility/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24429012</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 04:55:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The rate of obsolescence of knowledge in software engineering]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 10 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24428810">thread link</a>) | @dgs_sgd
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://daltyboy11.github.io/obsolescence-of-knowledge-in-software-engineering/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://daltyboy11.github.io/obsolescence-of-knowledge-in-software-engineering/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p>A physicist loses half the value of their physics knowledge in just four years whereas
an English professor would take over 25 years to lose half the value of the
knowledge they had at the beginning of their career [1]. These estimates are
taken form a paper written in 1982 so software engineers obviously weren’t
included. But it begs the question… What would the half-life of the value of a
software engineer’s knowledge be? I suspect it’s somewhere between the physicist’s
and the English professor’s because a software engineer’s knowledge is a combination
of eternal computer science/engineering principles and ephemeral technologies that
drift in and out of popularity over time.</p>

<h2 id="knowledge-that-doesnt-expire">Knowledge that doesn’t expire</h2>
<p>Software engineers with a traditional computer science background learn things
that never expire with age: data structures, algorithms, compilers,
distributed systems, etc. But most of us don’t work with these concepts
directly. Abstractions and frameworks are built on top of these well studied
ideas so we don’t have to get into the nitty-gritty details on the job
(at least most of the time). Examples are the C++ standard library which
implements optimized sorting for arrays, and Apache Spark which provides fault
tolerant cluster computing out of the box.</p>

<h2 id="knowledge-that-does-expire">Knowledge that does expire</h2>
<p>The unavoidable ephemeral knowledge one accumulates during their career comes in
many forms and this isn’t an exhaustive list:</p>

<ol>
  <li>A vogue framework or programming paradigm that falls out of favor in a couple of years.</li>
  <li>Domain knowledge in a rapidly evolving industry/field.</li>
  <li>Knowledge of proprietry technology: e.g. internal tools at your company.</li>
</ol>

<p>Knowledge of this kind can quickly transition from zealous adoption to every company who
uses said knowledge trying to sunset everything they’ve built with it.</p>

<h2 id="my-experience">My Experience</h2>
<p>I’m inclined to say I use ephemeral knowledge more than eternal knowledge to perform
my job. And then there’s the added pressure in our industry of always having to learn
new and useful things.</p>

<p>A theoretical physicist who spends a great deal of time mastering a theory and
the mathematical techniques behind it, only to see that theory rendered obsolete
by a new and improved theory several years later, is analogous to a software
engineer who spends a great deal of time mastering a web development framework,
learning its intricacies and gotcha’s, only to see that framework rendered
obsolete by a new framework several years later, leaving no more demand for
that knowledge in the labor market.</p>

<p>I relate to the physicist more than the English professor. What do you think?</p>



<p>[1] McDowell, John M. “Obsolescence of Knowledge and Career Publication Profiles: Some Evidence of Differences among Fields in Costs of Interrupted Careers.” The American Economic Review, vol. 72, no. 4, 1982, pp. 752–768. JSTOR, www.jstor.org/stable/1810015. Accessed 9 Sept. 2020.</p>

  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://daltyboy11.github.io/obsolescence-of-knowledge-in-software-engineering/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24428810</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 04:10:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Interfacing Microcontrollers with SD Card]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24428745">thread link</a>) | @peter_d_sherman
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://openlabpro.com/guide/interfacing-microcontrollers-with-sd-card/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://openlabpro.com/guide/interfacing-microcontrollers-with-sd-card/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><img height="1" width="1" src="https://www.facebook.com/tr?id=720372835040462&amp;ev=PageView&amp;noscript=1">    <meta name="generator" content="WordPress Download Manager 3.0.4">
<a href="#content">Skip to content</a><div id="boxed-wrapper"><div id="wrapper"><header></header><main id="main"><div><section id="content"><article id="post-2339"><div><p>The secure digital card (SD) is a low cost, non-volatile memory card format developed by the SD Card Association. Since its inception back at the start of the century, the demand for this medium-sized, energy and space-efficient, the memory storage device has been growing at a fast rate. Therefore, to meet the market requirements, the SDA was set up as a non-profit organization to promote and create SD Card standards. There are various topics related to the SD card such as the different device families, speed classes, smart cards, card security and so on and it is used in various markets like digital cameras, personal computers, and embedded systems. Some of the standard variations include SD, SDHC, SDXC, SD-ultra high speed etc. The microSD is the miniaturized SD memory card format with a small form factor and is widely used in various electronic devices.<br>
What we are going to learn is the use of SD cards in an embedded system. To be specific, we will be dealing with the use of SD cards in small embedded systems.</p><h2>Circuit&nbsp;and Interfacing</h2><p>SD card has a native host interface apart from the SPI mode for communicating with master devices. The native interface uses four lines for data transfer where the microcontroller has SD card controller module and it needs separate license to use it. Since the SPI is a widely used protocol and it is available in most low-cost microcontrollers, the SPI mode is the widely used interface in low cost embedded systems. The working voltage range of SD family is 2.7V to 3.6V and this is indicated in the operation condition register (OCR).</p><p><img src="https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/2000px-SD_Pins.svg_-1.png" alt="2000px-sd_pins-svg" width="214" height="292"></p><div id="attachment_2345"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2345" src="https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card.png" alt="sd-card" width="371" height="229" srcset="https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-200x124.png 200w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-300x185.png 300w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-400x247.png 400w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-600x371.png 600w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-768x475.png 768w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-800x495.png 800w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 371px) 100vw, 371px"><p id="caption-attachment-2345">SD Card pinout</p></div><div id="attachment_2347"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2347" src="https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-2.png" alt="sd-card-2" width="381" height="213" srcset="https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-2-200x112.png 200w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-2-300x168.png 300w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-2-400x223.png 400w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-2-600x335.png 600w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-2-768x429.png 768w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-2-800x447.png 800w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-2.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 381px) 100vw, 381px"><p id="caption-attachment-2347">MicroSD Card pinout</p></div><p>Most micro-controllers use the SPI communication protocol to interface with the SD cards. The SD cards have a microcontroller that shows their availability to the master controller(microcontroller). The micro-controller sees the SD card as an addressable sector on which read/write functions are possible. Once the microcontroller is in the SPI mode, communication between the master and the slave is done via 4 pins viz. clock, chip select, data in and data out. It should be kept in mind that throughout the communication between the two devices, the micro-controller will be sending out the clock.<br>
Most development boards have a dedicated SD card slot. But to understand the connections, let us analyze this fairly simple circuit.</p><div id="openl-1450463586"><div data-animationoffset="100%"><div><div data-link="https://openlabpro.com/online-courses/pic-microcontroller/" data-link-target="_self" data-animationoffset="100%"><div>From the very basic I/O control to the advaced SD Card interfacing, this course covers what you need to get started in Embedded Systems.<div><div><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/362065141?autoplay=0&amp;autopause=0" width="600" height="360" allowfullscreen="" title="vimeo362065141" allow="autoplay; fullscreen"></iframe></div></div></div><a href="https://openlabpro.com/online-courses/pic-microcontroller/" target="_self">Learn more about the course</a></div></div></div></div><h3>Circuit</h3><p><img src="https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-circuit.png" alt="sd-card-circuit" width="506" height="284" srcset="https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-circuit-200x113.png 200w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-circuit-300x169.png 300w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-circuit-400x225.png 400w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-circuit-600x338.png 600w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-circuit-768x432.png 768w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-circuit-800x450.png 800w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-circuit-1024x576.png 1024w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-circuit-1200x675.png 1200w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-circuit.png 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 506px) 100vw, 506px"></p><p>If the logic level of the microcontroller is different than the SD card, level shifter needs to be used for converting the line voltages.<br>
The MISO (master in serial out) pin should be connected to the SDI (serial data in) pin on the microcontroller.<br>
The MOSI (master out serial in) pin should be connected to the SDO (serial data out) pin on the microcontroller.<br>
The SCK (serial clock) pin should be connected to the SCK (serial clock) pin on the microcontroller.<br>
The CS (chip select) pin should be connected to the corresponding CS pin on the microcontroller or on any digital I/O pin on the microcontroller. A common ground is provided.</p><p><b>IMPORTANT NOTE</b>: While connecting the power supply, make sure that the supply is drawn from a 3.3V supply as a 5V supply would see your card go up in smoke.</p><h3>Interfacing</h3><p>Once the connections are set up, we are ready to interface our hardware with the software.<br>
Set the directions of each of the four pins correctly. While activating the SPI mode, an ideal configuration should be, mode(0,0) and the phase with input sampled at the middle of data out. Also, the clock frequency should be set in the range of 100 kHz and 400 kHz prior to initializing the card. Once the initialization is done, the clock can be set to a more desired frequency.</p><h2>SD Commands</h2><p>Next comes the tricky part, initializing the SD card and performing the raw data communication. A systematic approach to programming the software would make the task pretty easy.<br>
But first, it is important to learn how the micro-controller activates the SD card. There are a fixed set of commands and responses, which must be followed to create a command to response structure in our program. The data is transmitted in a byte-oriented format with a definite length.<br>
The following table shows the necessary<b> commands</b> to the card and the corresponding response from the card.</p><p><img src="https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-3.png" alt="sd-card-3" width="507" height="1118" srcset="https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-3-136x300.png 136w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-3-200x441.png 200w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-3-400x882.png 400w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-3-464x1024.png 464w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-3-600x1323.png 600w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-3-768x1694.png 768w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-3-800x1765.png 800w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-3-1200x2647.png 1200w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/SD-card-3.png 1274w" sizes="(max-width: 507px) 100vw, 507px"></p><p>Every command has a constant length of 6 bytes.<br>
The first byte is the addition of the command number and the number 64.<br>
<b>Example</b>:<br>
For CMD0: command number 0 + 64 = 64 = 0x40 in hexadecimal.<br>
For CMD1: command number 1 + 64 = 65 = 0x41 in hexadecimal.<br>
And so on.<br>
This is followed by a set of four bytes which are known as the arguments. These arguments usually contain the address of a data or the length of a block.<br>
The last byte is the CRC (Cyclic Redundancy Check) Byte. Most commands in the SPI mode does not require a check byte if the CRC feature isn’t enabled. For some commands like CMD0, the CRC is 0x95 and in most cases, a 0xFF is sent. Enabling the CRC requires you to send the correct check byte from the micro-controller. So, ensure whether the CRC feature is enabled or disabled.<br>
A <b>command frame</b> looks like this-</p><p><img src="https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/Clr_frame1-800x267.png" alt="Interfacing Microcontrollers with SD Card - Command frame" width="800" height="267" srcset="https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/Clr_frame1-200x67.png 200w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/Clr_frame1-300x100.png 300w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/Clr_frame1-400x133.png 400w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/Clr_frame1-600x200.png 600w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/Clr_frame1-768x256.png 768w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/Clr_frame1-800x267.png 800w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/Clr_frame1-1024x342.png 1024w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/Clr_frame1-1200x400.png 1200w, https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/Clr_frame1.png 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px"></p><p>The card will receive a command when the DO pin (Data Out) is driven high as shown above. The CS pin (Chip Select) must be driven high to low before sending the command and must be kept low during the process. The time between a command and its response is known as the command response time (NCR). As mentioned earlier, regarding the clock pulses from the micro-controller, the corresponding response byte sent back from the card to the microcontroller should be driven by the serial clock pulses of the micro-controller. There is a chance that the response byte from the card might get skipped by the microcontroller due to the absence of a driving clock pulse. Hence it is necessary to make sure that an 8-Bit clock pulse is sent to the Card soon after the Command Frame is sent (Refer the <b>TECHNICAL NOTE </b>below). Also while receiving a Byte from the card, the DI pin (Data In) must be driven high.</p><p>Furthermore, let us analyze the different<b> types of responses</b> that we get from the card and what they mean.</p><p><img src="https://openlabpro.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/Response_Color-1.jpg" alt="response_color" width="568" height="289"></p><p>An R1 response, 0x01 means that the command sent prior to the response has resulted in the card going into an idle state.<br>
A response byte 0x00 means that the command has been accepted and the card will be waiting for the proposed event to take place. If any other bits in an R1 response is set, it is the result of an error and it’ll be down to the factor mentioned in each R1 response bit in the figure.</p><h2>Initializing&nbsp;the SD Card</h2><p>Now, as far as sending the commands are concerned, there is an order in which they must be sent. Only the commands, CMD0, CMD1, ACMD41, CMD58 and CMD59 will be accepted when the card is in its idle state. Sending any other command will likely to yield an illegal response.</p><p><b>TECHNICAL NOTE</b>: After interfacing the card, the micro-controller must always send a set of bytes, which we will refer to as dummy bytes. One dummy byte is 0xFF. These dummy bytes have a simple yet significant purpose. Prior to the initialization, the card must know the frequency at which the data is being sent. By sending around 75 dummy bits approximately (dummy byte * 10 times = 80 bits), the card will be ready for communication. Also even after every command is sent, it is a good practice to send at least one dummy byte. A logical explanation for this is that communication is driven by the clock pulse of the micro-controller. The clock pulse is sent only when the data buffer is filled. After every response is sent and prior to the next command or between command and response, the SCK will stop generating pulses due to an empty data buffer. To ensure the continual transmission of clock pulses between every command, fill the data buffer with a junk value such as a dummy byte. To create a dummy byte function with the number of loops as the argument.</p><p>The<b> first command</b> to be sent to the card is the <b>CMD0</b> command. The structure of every other command-response should be based on this model.</p><ul><li>Drive the DO pin high.</li><li>Drive the CS pin from high to low.</li><li>Send a dummy byte.</li><li>Then send the following 6-byte command continuously<br>
First byte: 0x40<br>
Next four bytes: 0x00000000<br>
CRC byte: 0x95</li></ul><ul><li>Send another dummy byte or as many as required, to generate the SCK giving time for the SD card to respond to the command request.</li><li>Wait for the receive flag bit to set and then read the response from the SD card or create a loop to read the response a few number of times. The response should reach back within the command to response (Ncr) time. Or else, something must be wrong.</li></ul><ul><li>The desired response is 0x01, meaning the card is in the idle state and we are good to go.</li></ul><p>Send the <b>CMD8</b> command next to check the version of your SD card.<br>
The difference in the 6-byte commands are<br>
First byte: 0x48<br>
Next four bytes: 0x000001AA<br>
CRC byte: 0x87</p><p>We are looking for two possibilities in our response byte. Either 0x01 or 0x05.</p><p>A 0x01 response means that you have a version 2 SD card. The 0x01 response is followed by the 4 bytes 0x00, 0x00, 0x01, 0xAA in the order of their transmission from the SD card which is, in fact, the argument you send in your command.</p><p>If the response is 0x05, it means the card is a version 1 or an MMC card. If the card is actually a version 2 SD card, then this response is the result of an illegal command. Also, the card is now in the idle state.</p><p>Once the above two commands (CMD0 and CMD8) are done, it is safe to say that our SD Card is working in good condition and ready for data Read/Write.<br>
Additionally, just to ensure whether the SD Card is functioning in the correct working voltage, send the <b>CMD58</b> Command.</p><p>Next, we must initiate the i<b>nitialization</b> process. For this send a <b>CMD1</b> command and wait for response 0x00, meaning the idle state bit is cleared.<br>
If you are using an SDC or for the purpose of creating a general code, it is …</p></div></article></section></div></main></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://openlabpro.com/guide/interfacing-microcontrollers-with-sd-card/">https://openlabpro.com/guide/interfacing-microcontrollers-with-sd-card/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://openlabpro.com/guide/interfacing-microcontrollers-with-sd-card/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24428745</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 03:55:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[On moving away from a six figure consultancy to becoming an indie hacker]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 14 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24428473">thread link</a>) | @jv22222
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://matteomosca.io/how-covid-and-a-kick-scooter-turned-me-into-an-indie-hacker | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://matteomosca.io/how-covid-and-a-kick-scooter-turned-me-into-an-indie-hacker">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://matteomosca.io/how-covid-and-a-kick-scooter-turned-me-into-an-indie-hacker</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24428473</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 02:52:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The amazing $1 microcontroller (2017)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 265 | Comments 123 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24426882">thread link</a>) | @appwiz
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://jaycarlson.net/microcontrollers/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jaycarlson.net/microcontrollers/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h4>Silcon Labs EFM8: Fantastic value and ease-of-use from the only 8-bit part with a totally-free cross-platform vendor ecosystem</h4><p>The <a href="https://jaycarlson.net/pf/silicon-labs-efm8/">EFM8</a> was the fastest 8-bit part in my round-up, and admittedly, my favorite 8-bit architecture to develop with overall. What these parts lack in brains they make up for in brawns — 14-bit ADCs, 12-bit DACs, lots of timers, and a 72 MHz core clock speed that gives you timing options not found in any other part in the round-up.</p><p>Plus, this is the only 8-bit part with a totally-free, cross-platform, vendor-provided ecosystem. Let that sink in.</p><p>Keil C51 is a silly compiler, but Silicon Labs does an excellent job hiding it under the hood — even when running its Eclipse-based Simplicity Studio on Linux or macOS.</p><p>Simplicity Configurator is the lightest-weight code generator in our round-up, using only 534 bytes of flash to house the entire DMX-512 receiver project. It was one of the easiest to use, and seemed to strike a good balance between abstraction, performance, and ease of use.</p><p>Debugging speeds are snappy with a J-Link debugger, but at $35, the official Silicon Labs USB Debug Adapter is one of the cheapest first-party debugger in the round-up, and clones of the hardware are even cheaper.</p><p>And call me old-fashioned, but I think the 8051 definitely has a place in 2017 — especially among hobbyists and students, where its bit-addressable memory, easy-to-use peripherals, and fuse-free configuration help get students comfortable with microcontrollers quickly.</p><h4>Microchip megaAVR &amp; tinyAVR 1-Series: Different strokes for different folks — still with the best 8-bit toolchain available</h4><p>The <a href="https://jaycarlson.net/pf/atmel-microchip-megaavr/">megaAVR</a> came in surprisingly flat for me: especially when compared with its lower-cost, new sibling, the <a href="https://jaycarlson.net/pf/atmel-microchip-tinyavr-1-series/">tinyAVR 1-Series</a>.</p><p>There’s no comparison when it comes to price: tinyAVR has incredible value — packing in a nice assortment of timers, analog peripherals (including a DAC), and a new 20 MHz internal oscillator — while costing 20-40% less than the megaAVR.</p><p>While the megaAVR has a perplexing debugging experience that requires two completely different interfaces and protocols to work with the part, the new one-wire UPDI interface the tinyAVR sports worked flawlessly in my testing.</p><p>But that’s the crux of the problem for the tinyAVR — by shedding many of its megaAVR roots, Microchip ended up with a wonderful microcontroller that will be challenging to use for a large base of Atmel fans: indie developers and hobbyists who use low-cost, open-source programmers (which don’t support the UPDI interface).</p><p>While the tinyAVR wasn’t the fastest part in the round-up (even among 8-bitters), it was the most efficient – both in terms of active-mode power and clock efficiency. Amazingly, the AVR only uses about twice as many instructions as 16- and 32-bit parts when performing 16-bit math.</p><p>Unfortunately, the AVR system as a whole is not without its issues. The Windows-only Atmel Studio is still buggy (especially with older megaAVR devices and AVR Dragon stuff in my tests), and there isn’t an under-$50 low-cost debugger available (other than hacking apart Xplained Mini dev boards).</p><p>In many ways, there seems to be a tacit demarcation Atmel creates between its hobbyist/indie developers, and the professional shops that use Atmel parts.</p><p>As a professional embedded developer, I most definitely have access to Windows computers, and I have no problem blowing a few billable hours’ worth of pay on a $140 debugger.</p><p>But even as popular as Atmel is among hobbyists, Atmel has largely stayed out of this space directly. Instead, they’ve secured small-volume AVR sales by relying on the open-source community to build their own tools for themselves: turning out a slew of hardware and software used to program the megaAVR devices.</p><p>While I applaud the efforts of these developers, these tools are inferior to Atmel’s. Their programming speeds are terrible, they don’t support the new tinyAVR 1-Series devices, and they have absolutely no debug capability.</p><p>Having said that, both the megaAVR and tinyAVR have the best toolchain available for 8-bit MCU development. The part supports a full, end-to-end Makefile-based GCC toolchain.</p><p>If you love printf() debugging, would never touch a proprietary toolchain, and hate IDEs, megaAVR and old tinyAVR parts are definitely for you. The older ones are still available in DIP packages, and as you probably know, there are a ton of low-cost programmers available across the world. The online community is massive, and as clunky as I find Atmel START to be, I have to applaud its support for Makefile-based project generation.</p><p>Consequently, the megaAVR remains the most open-source 8-bit microcontroller on the market — by a long shot.</p><p>But I’d really like to see Microchip provide a PicKit-priced debugger with UPDI support — and allow off-board debugging the way their PIC Curiosity Boards do.</p><p>I also hope these open-source projects can add UPDI support to their tools, so that hobbyists and indie developers can start integrating the tinyAVR into their projects — it’s a much better part, and if you’re an AVR user with access to Atmel Studio, you really ought to buy an Xplained Mini board and take it for a spin.</p><h4>STM32F0: A low-cost, no-nonsense part with arguably the best Arm development ecosystem tested</h4><p><a href="https://jaycarlson.net/pf/st-stm32f0/">The STM32F0</a> was the lowest-power Arm microcontroller in the round-up, and also one of the easiest to use. STM32CubeMX doesn’t generate the most compact code on Arm (that honor belongs to Cypress PSoC Creator and Infineon DAVE), but it has a snappy interface, and the generated code is easy enough to manipulate for your own goals.</p><p>I love the nearly-stock Eclipse-based environment that System Workbench for STM32 provides, and the ST-Link and excellent Discovery/Nucleo boards seals the deal for me.</p><p>Most pros have used ST parts in their work, but for all these reasons, any hobbyist looking at moving to Arm should probably pick up a dev board from this ecosystem, too. ST has a huge market footprint, so there’s tons of resources online — aimed at both hobbyists and professionals.</p><h4>SAM D10: Killer performance &amp; peripherals, but with runtime library hiccups</h4><p>The Microchip/Atmel <a href="https://jaycarlson.net/pf/atmel-microchip-sam-d10/">SAM D10</a> (and the broader D11/D20/D21 ecosystem) has good value (considering their analog portfolio includes a DAC, and they have good timing options), and the SAM D10 was the most efficient part tested when running at full speed.</p><p>Professionals will like the easy-to-use, well-documented header files, and hobbyists will appreciate the 1.27mm-pitch SOIC package options and GCC compilers that come with the Arm ecosystem. But before I grab this part for a project, Microchip really needs to fix the extremely slow, bloated peripheral library, and update their code-gen tool to do proper error-checking of clock and peripheral configurations.</p><p>As it is, whenever I use Atmel START on the D10, I want to STOP almost immediately. And there are no current, stand-alone peripheral drivers that Microchip has released for this part, so unless you want to do register programming from scratch, you’ll be relying on third-party, open-source projects — like Alex Taradov’s <a href="https://github.com/ataradov/mcu-starter-projects">code examples</a>.</p><h4>Infineon XMC1100: Interesting peripheral perks make this Cortex-M0 stand out</h4><p>The most interesting Arm chip was, without a doubt, the <a href="https://jaycarlson.net/pf/infineon-xmc1100/">Infineon XMC1100</a> — and I think professionals who may be wary of getting out of the ST/NXP/Atmel Arm ecosystem need to take a second look at these XMC1000 (and XMC4000) parts.</p><p>The timer options are amazingly flexible, and you can squeeze fantastic performance out of the USIC module.</p><p>I’m going to go out on a limb and recommend that serious hobbyists who are building motor / lighting control projects look into these parts, too. DAVE makes setting up these complex peripherals painless, and the 38-pin TSSOP chips will be substantially easier to solder than the 0.5mm QFNs and QFPs you usually end up with in these pin counts.</p><p>Like many of the parts reviewed here, the biggest problem for hobbyists and indie developers is the tiny online communities and lack of GitHub repos with open-source projects that use these chips. My advice — be bold, and post in the forums. Infineon employees monitor and usually respond within a day or so.</p><h4>PIC16: Tons of peripherals with a slower, power-efficient core</h4><p>When you compare the <a href="https://jaycarlson.net/pf/microchip-pic16-five-digit-enhanced/">PIC16</a> with other 8-bit parts out there, it’s obviously a part built for low-power applications, and not processing power. And while the development ecosystem is workable, there are other parts more friendlier pathways — especially for smaller shops, hobbyists, and students who need extremely low-cost tools (and free software).</p><p>To add fuel to the PIC-vs-AVR debate, my testing found that a 32 MHz PIC16 is roughly equivalent to an AVR part running at 1.4 MHz (in terms of math performance), and 9 MHz (in terms of bit-shuffling performance).</p><p>Having said that, the DMX-512 receiver seems a perfect match for the PIC16, and that’s where it looks best in my testing: the PIC16 was the lowest-power 8-bit part in my testing.</p><p>It’s also full of timers and digital logic-oriented peripherals that make it suitable for funky special-purpose projects that require some crafty use of configurable logic and and the numerically-controlled oscillator — these peripherals help offload the (relatively slow) CPU, at the expense of requiring more developer familiarity with the device and these peripherals.</p><p>The usual Microchip gotchas apply: clunky IDE, expensive compilers, and expensive debuggers.</p><p>The usual Microchip advantages apply: huge online community, seemingly infinite product lifetime guarantees, and DIP, SOIC, QFP, and QFN package availability.</p><h4>PIC24: An expensive MSP430 wannabe that doesn’t hit the mark</h4><p>The <a href="https://jaycarlson.net/pf/microchip-pic24/">PIC24</a> is nearly forgettable. In the biquad test, it’s marginally faster than the <a href="https://jaycarlson.net/pf/renesas-rl-78/">Renesas RL-78</a> but uses almost three times as much power. In the DMX-512 test, both the RL-78 and MSP430 beat it, too. It was also one of the least-endowed parts in the round-up (which really just means it’s expensive — higher-end PIC24 parts have no shortage …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://jaycarlson.net/microcontrollers/">https://jaycarlson.net/microcontrollers/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jaycarlson.net/microcontrollers/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24426882</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 22:56:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How Much Time Is Spent at Traffic Signals?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 7 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24426023">thread link</a>) | @sharkweek
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://transportist.org/2018/03/06/how-much-time-is-spent-at-traffic-signals/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://transportist.org/2018/03/06/how-much-time-is-spent-at-traffic-signals/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-24122">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>
		<figure data-shortcode="caption" id="attachment_26070" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-26070"><img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="26070" data-permalink="https://transportist.org/books-2/books/the-30-minute-city-designing-for-access/the30-minutecity-cover-print/" data-orig-file="https://transportationist.files.wordpress.com/2019/12/the30-minutecity-cover-print.jpg" data-orig-size="2694,3434" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone XS Max&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1577200438&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;4.25&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;250&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.016666666666667&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="The30-MinuteCity-Cover-Print" data-image-description="<p>The 30-Minute City by David M. Levinson</p>
" data-medium-file="https://transportationist.files.wordpress.com/2019/12/the30-minutecity-cover-print.jpg?w=471" data-large-file="https://transportationist.files.wordpress.com/2019/12/the30-minutecity-cover-print.jpg?w=764" src="https://transportationist.files.wordpress.com/2019/12/the30-minutecity-cover-print.jpg?w=300&amp;h=383" alt="The 30-Minute City by David M. Levinson" width="300" height="383" srcset="https://transportationist.files.wordpress.com/2019/12/the30-minutecity-cover-print.jpg?w=300&amp;h=383 300w, https://transportationist.files.wordpress.com/2019/12/the30-minutecity-cover-print.jpg?w=600&amp;h=766 600w, https://transportationist.files.wordpress.com/2019/12/the30-minutecity-cover-print.jpg?w=118&amp;h=150 118w, https://transportationist.files.wordpress.com/2019/12/the30-minutecity-cover-print.jpg?w=471&amp;h=600 471w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-26070"><a href="https://transportist.org/books/the-30-minute-city-designing-for-access/">The 30-Minute City</a> by David M. Levinson&nbsp;</figcaption></figure>
<p>While working on another piece, I came upon the question of how much time is spent at traffic lights, for which there is not a well-sourced answer. I posted to Twitter and got some useful replies.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Transport Twitter: What percent of total travel time is spent stopped at traffic lights? Empirical results please.</p>
<p>— David M. Levinson (@trnsprtst) <a href="https://twitter.com/trnsprtst/status/967547973788827648?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 24, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p>With that and some additional digging, I attempt to answer the question.</p>
<p>As the saying goes: Your Mileage May Vary. This depends on your origin and destination and path and mode and time of day and local traffic signal policies and street design. <a href="https://twitter.com/tvanvuren">Tom VanVuren</a> notes: “Much of the impact is in slow moving queues, rather than waiting for the signal cycle to complete. I expect you can make this number smaller than 10% (time at the stop line) or larger than 50% (time affected by traffic lights).” For simplicity, I am considering vehicles that would be stopped if they could either move at the desired speed or must stop (i.e. they are subject to “vertical” or “stacking” queues), but clearly measurement will depend on assumption. Still, there must be a system average. I had heard the number 20% bandied about, which feels right, but let’s first begin with some thought experiment, then look for some empirical results. We take different modes in turn.</p>
<figure data-shortcode="caption" id="attachment_24089" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-24089"><a href="https://transportationist.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/img_0230.jpg"><img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="24089" data-permalink="https://transportist.org/2018/02/14/the-ambiguous-hump/img_0230/" data-orig-file="https://transportationist.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/img_0230.jpg" data-orig-size="4032,3024" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;2.2&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone 6s&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1518165138&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;4.15&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;25&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.00090991810737034&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="Free left" data-image-description="<p>A signalized but porkchop-islanded crosswalk at a Free Left (Free Right for those in the right-side drive countries). Notice the pedestrian light is red (don’t walk) but the pedestrians cross anyway. If the free left is not eliminated in a more comprehensive redesign, it could easily be de-signaled and the crosswalk raised, so pedestrians dominate, and cars travel when they can.</p>
" data-medium-file="https://transportationist.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/img_0230.jpg?w=600" data-large-file="https://transportationist.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/img_0230.jpg?w=764" src="https://transportationist.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/img_0230.jpg?w=300&amp;h=225&amp;crop=1" alt="A signalized but porkchop-islanded crosswalk at a Free Left (Free Right for those in the right-side drive countries). Notice the pedestrian light is red (don't walk) but the pedestrians cross anyway. If the free left is not eliminated in a more comprehensive redesign, it could easily be de-signaled and the crosswalk raised, so pedestrians dominate, and cars travel when they can." width="300" height="225" srcset="https://transportationist.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/img_0230.jpg?w=300&amp;h=225&amp;crop=1 300w, https://transportationist.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/img_0230.jpg?w=600&amp;h=450&amp;crop=1 600w, https://transportationist.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/img_0230.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113&amp;crop=1 150w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-24089">Pedestrian Crossing at Broadway and City Road, Sydney. Pedestrians crossing against the light.</figcaption></figure>

<h2><strong>Thought Experiments</strong></h2>
<h3><strong>Thought Experiment&nbsp;</strong><strong>1 A</strong></h3>
<p>Imagine an urban grid.</p>
<ul>
<li>Assume 10 signalized intersections per km.</li>
<li>Assume a travel speed of 60 km/h when in motion. (This is probably too high with so many intersections and no platooning, but we are imagining here that you would not be stopping.)</li>
<li>Time to traverse 1 km=1 minute + signal delay. &nbsp;(Some of the distance traversal time overlaps some of the signal delay time, but we will imagine a stacking queue, rather than one that has physical distance for simplicity, we can correct this later if it matters.)</li>
<li>Assume each intersection has only 2 phases.</li>
<li>Assume fixed time signals at each intersection evenly distributing green time between N/S and E/W directions. &nbsp;So&nbsp;red time = 1/2 cycle length.</li>
<li>Assume 1 minute cycle length</li>
<li>If a vehicle stops, it waits 1/2 red time.</li>
<li>Vehicles obey traffic signals.</li>
<li>Assume no platooning.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>This means that the average vehicle will&nbsp;stop at 5 intersections for 15 seconds each = 75 seconds (or 1.25 &nbsp;minutes) (vs. 1 &nbsp;minute in motion time). In this case, 1.25/2.25 minutes (55.5%) is spent waiting at signals.</em></p>
<h3><strong>Thought Experiment 1 B</strong></h3>
<p>In contrast.</p>
<ul>
<li>Assume near perfect platooning.</li>
</ul>
<p>In this case, the vehicle will stop at 1 intersection per km, for 15 seconds = 15 seconds. In this case 0.25/1.25 = 20% of the time is spent waiting at signals.</p>
<h3><strong>Discussion</strong></h3>
<p>Now, not all travel takes place on an urban grid.</p>
<ul>
<li>Assume 25% of travel is on limited access roads (this is approximately true in the US), &nbsp;75% on non-limited access roads.</li>
</ul>
<p>With perfect platooning on the grid, and 25% off-grid, then 15% of travel time is intersection delay with near perfect platooning.</p>
<p>Clearly in practice platooning is far from perfect. My guess is the green wave breaks down after one or two intersections during peak times, but can survive well in the off-peak. As a rule of thumb, about ~10% of travel is in the peak hour, ~30% peak period. ~60% AM + PM Peak.</p>
<h2>Data</h2>
<h3>GPS Studies</h3>
<p>Eric Fischer of MapBox was kind enough to offer to run this question on their open traffic data. The results are not yet in. I will update when they are.</p>
<h3>Arterial Travel Time Studies</h3>
<p>There are a variety of Arterial Travel Time studies for specific corridors, but nothing that is universally generalizable. &nbsp;(And logically where people do arterial travel time studies, there is a congestion problem, otherwise why study it.)</p>
<p>I recall that in my childhood,<a href="https://conservancy.umn.edu/handle/11299/179862"> I did a study in Montgomery County, Maryland</a>&nbsp;using such data (from 1987 traffic counts and a floating car study published by Douglas and Douglas), I did not actually compute the percentage, but fortunately I reported enough data that allows me to compute the percentage now. (The sample is of course biased to what is measured). For the average arterial link, the speed was</p>
<div class="page" title="Page 24">
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>&nbsp;<strong>Variable</strong></td>
<td><strong>Inside the Beltway</strong></td>
<td><strong>&nbsp;Outside the Beltway</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>&nbsp;Speed (km/h)</td>
<td>34.88</td>
<td>&nbsp;41.60</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>&nbsp;Length (km)</td>
<td>&nbsp;0.46</td>
<td>&nbsp;0.72</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>&nbsp;Time (min)</td>
<td>&nbsp;0.792</td>
<td>&nbsp;1.04</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>&nbsp;Downstream Delay (min)</td>
<td>&nbsp;0.27</td>
<td>&nbsp;0.24</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>&nbsp;Percentage of Signal Delay</td>
<td>&nbsp;25%</td>
<td>&nbsp;18.75%</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Which is consistent with expectations that signals are more significant in more urbanized areas (inside the beltway is basically Bethesda and Silver Spring, MD), and with our general estimates. Now of course the speed here is impacted by downstream signals, and so is lower than the speed limit and certainly lower than the free-flow speed sans-signals. More details are in the paper.</p>
<ul>
<li>Levinson, David (1998)&nbsp;<a href="http://hdl.handle.net/11299/179862">Speed and Delay on Signalized Arterials</a>.&nbsp;<em>ASCE Journal of Transportation Engineering</em>&nbsp;124(3) 258-264. [<a href="http://dx.doi.org/doi:10.1061/(ASCE)0733-947X(1998)124:3(258)">doi</a>]</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Engine Idling Studies</h3>
<p>Moaz Ahmed pointed me to a<a href="https://tc.gc.ca/eng/policy/annual-2014-3141.html"> Vehicle Idling Study</a> by <a href="http://www.nrcan.gc.ca/energy/efficiency/communities-infrastructure/transportation/cars-light-trucks/idling/4415">Natural Resources Canada</a>.</p>
<p>The percent of time of vehicle idling ranged from 20-25%. (Not all vehicle idling is at signalized intersections).</p>
<p>(Engine idling of course burns fuel without doing work, so if the engine is going to be idling for an extended period, it would save fuel (and reduce air pollution) to turn it off. Turning the engine on and off also has costs, so the estimate was if idling was going to be longer than 10 seconds, it uses more fuel, but considering other wear and tear costs, the recommended threshold is if idling is longer than 60 seconds, then turn off the engine. &nbsp;But at a signalized intersection, how will vehicles know how long they will wait? Smart traffic signals with connected vehicles could provide this, but now they don’t. Eventually this will be moot with a full electric vehicle fleet. Until that time, it matters. I suspect given the longevity and sluggishness of the traffic control sector, smart signals informing trucks will not be widely or systematically deployed before trucks are electrified.)</p>

<p>Now as noted above, Your Mileage May Vary. If you are a pedestrian, you are unlikely to hit a greenwave designed for cars, though of course your travel speed is slower is well. So redoing the Thought Experiment</p>
<h2><strong>Thought Experiment 2</strong></h2>
<p>Imagine an urban grid.</p>
<ul>
<li>Assume 10 signalized intersections per km.</li>
<li>Assume a travel speed of 6 km/h when in motion. (this is a bit on the high side, average pedestrian speed is closer to <a href="https://westernite.org/datacollectionfund/2005/psu_ped_summary.pdf">5 km/h</a>)</li>
<li>Time to traverse 1 km=10 minutes + signal delay. &nbsp;(Some of the distance traversal time overlaps some of the signal delay time, but we will imagine a vertical stacking queue, rather than one that has physical distance for simplicity, this is a much better assumption for pedestrians than vehicles.)</li>
<li>Assume each intersection has only 2 phases.</li>
<li>Assume fixed time signals at each intersection evenly distributing green time between N/S and E/W directions. &nbsp;So&nbsp;red time = 1/2 cycle length.</li>
<li>Assume 1 minute cycle length</li>
<li>If a pedestrian stops, she waits 1/2 red time. (That is the “walk” phase for pedestrians is as long as the green phase for cars. Strictly speaking this is not true, it is more true in cities with narrow streets than it is in suburban environments with wide streets, as narrow streets can be crossed more quickly, so the amount of “walk” time allocated can be most of the phase. This is certainly not true in Sydney, where the “walk” phase is cut short so turning cars have fewer conflicts with late pedestrians.)</li>
<li>Pedestrians obey traffic lights. &nbsp;(This is not as good an assumption as vehicles obey signals, pedestrian signal violation is probably higher. This is not a moral judgment one way or the other, people tend to obey authority, even when <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Milgram_experiment">authority abuses power</a>.)</li>
<li>Assume no platooning. (This is probably too severe, a quick pedestrian with some signal coordination can probably make a couple of lights in a row).</li>
</ul>
<p>Here the average pedestrian will&nbsp;stop at 5 intersections for 15 seconds each = 2.5 minutes (vs. 10 &nbsp;minute in-motion time). In this case, 2.5/(2.5+10) minutes (or 20%) is spent waiting at signals. Now, this number is probably true for more pedestrians than the vehicle delay estimate is for vehicles, since pedestrians are more likely to be found on an urban grid and less in a suburban or limited access environment. (Self-selection at work).</p>

<p>If you are a bicyclist, you are unlikely to hit a greenwave designed for cars unless you travel at exactly an integer fraction (1/1, 1/2, 1/3) of the green wave, as your travel speed is slower is well. So redoing the Thought Experiment</p>
<h2><strong>Thought Experiment 3</strong></h2>
<p>Imagine an urban grid.</p>
<ul>
<li>Assume 10 signalized intersections per km.</li>
<li>Assume a travel speed of &nbsp;20 km/h when in motion. (This is a typical for <a href="http://www.road-bike.co.uk/articles/average-speed.php">experienced riders</a>).&nbsp;Time to traverse 1 km=3 minutes + signal delay. (Assume a stacking queue)</li>
<li>Assume each intersection has only 2 phases.</li>
<li>Assume fixed time signals at each intersection evenly distributing green time between N/S and E/W directions. &nbsp;So&nbsp;red time = 1/2 cycle length.</li>
<li>Assume 1 minute cycle length</li>
<li>If a bicyclist stops, she waits 1/2 red time. (That is the ‘bike’ phase for bicyclists is as long as the green phase for cars.)</li>
<li>Bicyclists obey traffic lights. &nbsp;(This is not as good an assumption as ‘motor vehicles obey signals’, bicyclists signal violation is probably higher.)</li>
<li>Assume no platooning. (This is probably too severe, a quick bicyclists with some signal coordination can probably make a couple of lights in a row).</li>
</ul>
<p>In this case the average bicyclists will&nbsp;stop at 5 intersections for 15 seconds each = 2.5 minutes (vs. 3 &nbsp;minute in-motion time). In this case, 2.5/(3+2.5) minutes (or 45%) is spent waiting at signals in an urban environment.</p>
<h2>Strava Data</h2>
<p>Strava, an app for tracking bicyclists and runners can produce some useful data. <a href="https://twitter.com/dr_hsu">Andrew Hsu</a>, e.g., <a href="https://www.strava.com/athletes/16556#interval_type?chart_type=hours&amp;interval_type=week&amp;interval=201807&amp;year_offset=0">reports</a>&nbsp;“28 mile bike commute. 1:30-ish moving time. 10-15 minutes waiting at lights.” From this, for him, we estimate 15 / (15+90) = 14%. To be clear, 1:30 is an extreme commute. I don’t have access to …</p></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://transportist.org/2018/03/06/how-much-time-is-spent-at-traffic-signals/">https://transportist.org/2018/03/06/how-much-time-is-spent-at-traffic-signals/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://transportist.org/2018/03/06/how-much-time-is-spent-at-traffic-signals/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24426023</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 21:19:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Git/serve: A Git server for Plan 9]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 7 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24425114">thread link</a>) | @ori_b
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://orib.dev/gitserve.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://orib.dev/gitserve.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">


<p>A while ago, I released <a href="https://orib.dev/git9.html">git9</a>, a git client for
Plan 9. However, it always felt like it was missing something: A git server.
over a few weekends of work, I sat down and put one together. This Labor
Day weekend, I took the opportunity to labor on it, and got something working.</p>

<h3>usage</h3>

<p><code>Git/serve</code> is a git server designed to fit into the Plan
9 ecosystem, allowing hosting of, and interacting with, code on a Plan 9
server, while still allowing legacy clients running on Unix to get a copy
of the code.</p>

<p><code>Git/serve</code> only speaks the <code>git://</code> protocol.
But because it runs behind
<a href="http://man.9front.org/8/listen">aux/listen</a>
and 
<a href="http://man.9front.org/8/tlssrv"><code>tlssrv</code></a>, we
effectively get two additional protocols for free: <code>gits://</code>, or
TLS-encrypted <code>git://</code>, and <code>hjgit://</code>, which is
<code>git://</code> but with Plan 9 authentication to support user login
over TLS. Unfortunately, only the unencrypted <code>git://</code> protocol
is supported out of the box by upstream git. There may be ways to solve
this, using <a href="https://rovaughn.github.io/2015-2-9.html">custom
transports</a>, and a unix port of tlsclient</p>

<p>To start a <code>git://</code> server, just run it under aux/listen1.
To enable encryption and user authentication, run it under
<code>tlssrv -a</code>. This doesn't need a certificate, because
the Plan 9 authentication generates the secret used for TLS. And,
finally, if you just want encryption, you can use <code>tlsclient</code>
with a certificate.</p>

<pre># git:// server, serving every repository under the current directory
% aux/listen1 'tcp!*!9418' git/serve -r `{pwd}

# gits:// server, doing the same: But with encryption.
% aux/listen1 'tcp!*!9418' tlsclient -c /path/to/cert.pem git/serve -r `{pwd}

# hjgit:// server doing the same: Requires account on server to connect
% aux/listen1 'tcp!*!9418' tlsclient -a git/serve -r `{pwd}
</pre>

<p>If you want to allow people to write, you can just add the
<code>-w</code> flag to git/serve. While you can do this on
any of the protocols, keep in mind that only <code>hjgit://</code>
authenticates the users. Push to the world, but don't let the
world push to you!</p>



<p>All the protocols git uses are closely related. The <code>ssh://</code>
protocol is just the <code>git://</code> protocol, with the command selected
sightly differently. The smart <code>http://</code> protocols are the same
as the <code>git://</code> protocol, with a different handshake, and split
over multiple post requests.</p>

<p>Git9 implements the git protocol in under 500 lines of C. The
full code is available on github, in
<a href="https://github.com/oridb/git9/blob/24abe6c00b6f65e7241763399fc72c043b7d9bbf/serve.c">serve.c</a>.
</p>

<p>The protocol look something like this for pushing:</p>

<pre>&lt;=w= 0030:	"git-fetch-pack /oridb/git9\0host=github.com\n"
=r=&gt; 0086:	"747e9e80f710c0b8bbd928080745915ad2493322 HEAD\n"
=r=&gt; 009d:	"747e9e80f710c0b8bbd928080745915ad2493322 refs/heads/master\n"
&lt;=w= 0076:	"747e9e80f710c0b8bbd928080745915ad2493322 dc802c499dc7164aa208b919a07c5bd18701b0e1 refs/heads/master\0report-status\n"
&lt;=w= 0000
&lt;=w= <pack-data>
=r=&gt; 000e:	unpack ok
=r=&gt; 0019:	ok refs/heads/master
</pack-data></pre>

<p>And this for pulling:</p>

<pre>&lt;=w= 0030:	"git-upload-pack /oridb/git9\0host=github.com\n"
=r=&gt; 013b:	"dc802c499dc7164aa208b919a07c5bd18701b0e1 HEAD\n"
=r=&gt; 003f:	"dc802c499dc7164aa208b919a07c5bd18701b0e1 refs/heads/master\n"
=r=&gt; 0000
&lt;=w= 0032:	"want 5d761590cfdce23e4b17e94050b0776c8804d4a1\n"
&lt;=w= 0032:	"want 8f0eb1386a2c748cb7bf26917684479ff8c6d5b5\n"
&lt;=w= 0032:	"want dc4a9d467c6a28dab3927c8611a1bfbc571f1568\n"
&lt;=w= 0000
&lt;=w= 0033:	"have dc802c499dc7164aa208b919a07c5bd18701b0e1\n"
&lt;=w= 0009:	"done\n"
=r=&gt; 0031:	"ACK dc802c499dc7164aa208b919a07c5bd18701b0e1\n"
<pack-data>
</pack-data></pre>

<p>The git protocol consists of pkt-lines, which are strings with a
hex-formatted length prefix.  The length prefix includes itself.  So,
the string <code>"hi"</code> would be formatted as
<code>0006hi</code>. A zero lenth packet where the length prefix
is not included is special. This is called a 'flush packet', and
is used to terminate a phase of negotiation.</p>

<p> All negotiation is with these packet lines, at
which git flips over to pure binary mode to transfer a pack file
over.</p>

<p>In the <code>git://</code> protocol, the client always starts off
by saying which action it wants to do: Either it wants the server to
fetch a pack from the client, or it wants the server to upload a pack
to the client.  That's this line:</p><pre>&lt;=w= 0030:	"git-fetch-pack /oridb/git9\0host=github.com\n"
</pre>

<p>The upload side of this protocol is simpler on the server side so
we'll go through it first.</p>

<h3>pushing</h3>

<p>In the upload protocol, the server begins by sending a list of
references that the client may update. In <code>git/serve</code>
we grab all the refs in the repository, and filter down to just
the ones beginning with <code>heads/</code>.</p>

<pre>	if((nrefs = listrefs(&amp;refs, &amp;names)) == -1)
		sysfatal("listrefs: %r");
	for(i = 0; i &lt; nrefs; i++){
		if(strncmp(names[i], "heads/", strlen("heads/")) != 0)
			continue;
		if(fmtpkt(c, "%H refs/%s\n", refs[i], names[i]) == -1)
			goto error;
	}
	if(flushpkt(c) == -1)
		goto error;
</pre>

<p>With the first phase of the protocol, the client then
sends the list of references it wants to update. This
takes the form of:</p>

<pre>	OLDHASH NEWHASH heads/refs/updateme\n"
</pre>

<p>Because the client knows what the reference versions are on
the server, it can compute what commits are between the version
on the server and the version that it has. If the new hash
is the zero hash, this signals to the server that the reference
should be deleted. This list of updates is terminated with a
flush packet. The code in git9 that handles this is below:

</p><pre>	while(1){
		/* Did we get a packet? */
		if((n = readpkt(c, pkt, sizeof(pkt))) == -1)
			goto error;
		/* Was it a flush packet? */
		if(n == 0)
			break;
		/* Split it up into the 3 parts: old, new, reference */
		if(getfields(pkt, sp, nelem(sp), 1, " \t\n\r") != 3){
			fmtpkt(c, "ERR  protocol garble %s\n", pkt);
			goto error;
		}
		/* verify that these are valid hashes */
		if(hparse(&amp;old, sp[0]) == -1){
			fmtpkt(c, "ERR bad old hash %s\n", sp[0]);
			goto error;
		}
		if(hparse(&amp;new, sp[1]) == -1){
			fmtpkt(c, "ERR bad new hash %s\n", sp[1]);
			goto error;
		}
		/* and valid refs */
		if(!validref(sp[2])){
			fmtpkt(c, "ERR invalid ref %s\n", sp[2]);
			goto error;
		}
		/* and then remember them for when we do the update */
		*cur = erealloc(*cur, (*nupd + 1)*sizeof(Hash));
		*upd = erealloc(*upd, (*nupd + 1)*sizeof(Hash));
		*ref = erealloc(*ref, (*nupd + 1)*sizeof(Hash));
		(*cur)[*nupd] = old;
		(*upd)[*nupd] = new;
		(*ref)[*nupd] = estrdup(sp[2]);
		*nupd += 1;
	}
</pre>

<p>Next, the client uploads the pack. This is a blob containing
the commit data. It goes into <code>.git/objects/packs/recv-$pid.pack</code>,
at least until we can index it and rename it.</p>

<pre>	while(1){
		n = read(c-&gt;rfd, buf, sizeof(buf));
		if(n == 0)
			break;
		if(n == -1 || write(pfd, buf, n) != n)
			return -1;
		packsz += n;
	}
	if(checkhash(pfd, packsz, &amp;h) == -1){
		dprint(1, "hash mismatch\n");
		goto error1;
	}
	if(indexpack(packtmp, idxtmp, h) == -1){
		dprint(1, "indexing failed\n");
		goto error1;
	}
	if(rename(packtmp, idxtmp, h) == -1){
		dprint(1, "rename failed: %r\n");
		goto error2;
	}
</pre>

<p>Finally, we update the references. Note that we haven't
locked the repository yet. This is because none of the data
we have here can conflict: All objects are addressed by hash,
so a race would simply leave us with a duplicate hash in the
packfile. Eventually, a <code>git/repack</code> will clean
that up.</p>

<p>However, updating the references can conflict. So,
for updating the references, we acquire a lock file.
We then read all the references, make sure that they
match the old reference, and then write in the new
reference.</p>

<pre>	for(i = 0; i &lt; nupd; i++){
		if(resolveref(&amp;h, ref[i]) == 0 &amp;&amp; !hasheq(&amp;h, &amp;cur[i])){
			fmtpkt(c, "ERR old ref changed: %s", ref[i]);
			goto error;
		}
		if((o = readobject(upd[i])) == nil){
			fmtpkt(c, "ERR update to nonexistent hash %H", upd[i]);
			goto error;
		}
		if(o-&gt;type != GCommit){
			fmtpkt(c, "ERR not commit: %H", upd[i]);
			goto error;
		}
		unref(o);
		if(snprint(refpath, sizeof(refpath), ".git/%s", ref[i]) == sizeof(refpath)){
			fmtpkt(c, "ERR ref path too long: %s", ref[i]);
			goto error;
		}
		if((fd = create(refpath, OWRITE, 0644)) == -1){
			fmtpkt(c, "ERR open ref: %r");
			goto error;
		}
		if(fprint(fd, "%H", upd[i]) == -1){
			close(fd);
			fmtpkt(c, "ERR upate ref: %r");
			goto error;
		}
		close(fd);
	}
</pre>

<p>And that's pushing.

</p><h3>pulling</h3>

<p>Pulling takes more work on the server side, because the
server needs to compute a reasonable packfile to send to
the client. The protocol itself is still fairly simple.</p>

<p>It begins the same way as pushing, by sending all the
branches that a client may want to obtain from the git
repository.</p>

<pre>=r=&gt; 013b:	"dc802c499dc7164aa208b919a07c5bd18701b0e1 HEAD\n"
=r=&gt; 003f:	"dc802c499dc7164aa208b919a07c5bd18701b0e1 refs/heads/master\n"
=r=&gt; 0000
</pre>

<p>The client then starts telling us what commits they want,
and what commits they have. This lets us find a graph difference
between the server and client graph, and generate a pack file
that contains few, if any, extraneous commits. </p>

<pre>&lt;=w= 0032:	"want 5d761590cfdce23e4b17e94050b0776c8804d4a1\n"
&lt;=w= 0032:	"want 8f0eb1386a2c748cb7bf26917684479ff8c6d5b5\n"
&lt;=w= 0032:	"want dc4a9d467c6a28dab3927c8611a1bfbc571f1568\n"
&lt;=w= 0000
&lt;=w= 0033:	"have dc802c499dc7164aa208b919a07c5bd18701b0e1\n"
&lt;=w= 0009:	"done\n"
=r=&gt; 0031:	"ACK dc802c499dc7164aa208b919a07c5bd18701b0e1\n"
</pre>

<p>Computing the commits that go into a pack is not always trivial.
The comits that the client may be on may have "bubbles" in the graph,
so simply walking back from the start of the graph to the commits
that the client has may end up walking around the commit, leading
to nearly the whole history of the repository being sent, instead
of just one or two commits.</p>

<p>Consider a repo where the server is ahead of the client, and
now the client is trying to pull the changes. The client has commits
<code>c</code>, and we're trying to compute a pack with only the
commits <code>o</code>.</p>


<pre>                o---o
               /     \
    --c---c---c---c---o---o &lt;-- server
                  ^
                client
</pre>

<p>The client does a git/pull, and sends that it has the
commit marked <code>[c]</code>. Since the server has
every commit the client does, and more, it can look at
all ancestors of the client commit. If we're smart, we
would, but a naive …</p></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://orib.dev/gitserve.html">https://orib.dev/gitserve.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://orib.dev/gitserve.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24425114</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 19:47:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Dolt, a SQL database with Git-like functionality, implements push and pull]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24424593">thread link</a>) | @reltuk
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2020-09-09-push-pull-on-a-merkle-dag/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2020-09-09-push-pull-on-a-merkle-dag/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="blog-post-text"><p><a href="https://www.github.com/liquidata-inc/dolt">Dolt</a> is a SQL database
with Git-like functionality, including branch, merge and diff and push
and pull to remotes. This is a post in a series of posts about the
internal workings of some of the core algorithms that underly Dolt's
implementation. The previous posts in this series were about:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2020-04-01-how-dolt-stores-table-data/">The Prolly-tree</a>,
a unique content-address indexed data structure that underlies Dolt's table storage.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2020-05-13-dolt-commit-graph-and-structural-sharing/">The Commit Graph</a>
and structural sharing in Dolt's table storage.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2020-06-16-efficient-diff-on-prolly-trees/">Dolt's Diff Implementation</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2020-07-15-three-way-merge/">Dolt's Merge Implementation</a></li>
</ol>
<p>In this post, we explore the Merkle DAG structure underlying Dolt's
commit graph and table storage a little more, and investigate how push
and pull to remote repositories is implemented in Dolt.</p>
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>A Dolt repository contains any number of branches and tags, where each
branch or tag is a top-level reference to a particular commit. A
commit, in turn, points to a value of the database at that commit, and
0 or more parent commits. All data in the repository, the commits and
the table data, is stored in content-addressed <code>Chunk</code>s which in turn
can contain references to other <code>Chunk</code>s, forming a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Merkle_tree">Merkle
DAG</a>. This was the example
of a three commit branch from our previous blog post on the commit
graph:</p>
<p><span>
      <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/cbb97ed1114403fc268e56a4a12c67c1/4597d/dolt-commit-graph.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="Dolt Commit Graph" title="Dolt Commit Graph" src="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/cbb97ed1114403fc268e56a4a12c67c1/4597d/dolt-commit-graph.png" srcset="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/cbb97ed1114403fc268e56a4a12c67c1/a48b3/dolt-commit-graph.png 214w,
https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/cbb97ed1114403fc268e56a4a12c67c1/47730/dolt-commit-graph.png 428w,
https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/cbb97ed1114403fc268e56a4a12c67c1/4597d/dolt-commit-graph.png 631w" sizes="(max-width: 631px) 100vw, 631px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></p>
<p>And this was the example of how the data in a single table might be
broken down:</p>
<p><span>
      <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/8b22553d249aa55cec98241019cf0d15/4ee7f/dolt-table-value.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="Dolt Table Value" title="Dolt Table Value" src="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/8b22553d249aa55cec98241019cf0d15/4ee7f/dolt-table-value.png" srcset="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/8b22553d249aa55cec98241019cf0d15/a48b3/dolt-table-value.png 214w,
https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/8b22553d249aa55cec98241019cf0d15/47730/dolt-table-value.png 428w,
https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/8b22553d249aa55cec98241019cf0d15/4ee7f/dolt-table-value.png 486w" sizes="(max-width: 486px) 100vw, 486px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></p>
<p>Dolt supports remotes, which means it can clone, push and pull branch
and tag references from a Dolt repository stored in
<a href="https://www.dolthub.com/">Dolthub</a> or in cloud storage like <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/s3/">AWS
S3</a> or <a href="https://cloud.google.com/storage">Google Cloud
Storage</a>. This blog post briefly
explores what Dolt remotes are and how they operate under the hood.</p>
<h2>A Dolt Remote</h2>
<p>A Dolt repository can have multiple remote repositories configured,
and each of these repositories can be fetched from and pushed to
separately. Each configured Dolt remote consists of three pieces of
configuration within a Dolt repository:</p>
<ol>
<li>The name of the remote. After a clone, this will be <code>origin</code>.</li>
<li>Configuration for a networked endpoint that implements a network
protocol that Dolt can use as a remote. Most commonly, this is the
GRPC API exported by <a href="https://doltremoteapi.dolthub.com/">https://doltremoteapi.dolthub.com</a> and a
Dolthub repository path like <code>Liquidata/image-net</code>.</li>
<li>Default fetch specs for the remote. After a clone, this will be
<code>refs/heads/*:refs/remotes/origin/*</code>, and most users never need to
interact directly with fetch specs.</li>
</ol>
<p>The fetch spec is the subtlest piece of the configuration, but it's
also fundamental to the way that remotes actually work. The above
fetch spec says: When we <code>fetch</code> from <code>origin</code>, create a new <code>ref</code> in
<code>refs/remotes/origin/...</code> for each ref we find in the remote at
<code>refs/heads/...</code>. <code>refs/heads/...</code> will be all the branches in the
remote, and so fetching from the remote will create corresponding refs
in our local repository for each branch in the remote repository. If
the remote had the branches <code>main</code>, <code>bh/agi</code> and <code>aaron/by-zip</code>, and
we fetched from it, Dolt would create the refs
<code>refs/remotes/origin/main</code>, <code>refs/remotes/origin/bh/agi</code> and
<code>refs/remotes/origin/aaron/by-zip</code>, each pointing at the corresponding
commits that the remote branches were pointing at when we ran the
<code>fetch</code>.</p>
<p>So the remotes <code>ref</code>s namespace is seperate from our local branches
namespace, and Dolt is keeping a copy of the branches that we fetch
from the remote locally. The only time that copy is updated, and the
only time we reference the remote generally, is when we run <code>dolt
fetch</code> (or <code>dolt pull</code>, which does a <code>fetch</code> and then <code>merge</code>). And
the fundamental operation involved in a <code>fetch</code> is:</p>
<ol>
<li>Contact the remote to list all the branches we will clone.</li>
<li>For each branch we will clone, update our local repository to
contain the referenced Commit <code>Chunk</code> and all <code>Chunk</code>s reachable from
it.</li>
<li>Set a corresponding <code>ref</code> in our local repository to point to the
newly fetched Commit <code>Chunk</code>.</li>
</ol>
<p>Step #2 is where all the missing data actually gets copied into our
local repository. Let's take a look at exactly how that happens.</p>
<h2>Chunk Stores and DAG Traversals</h2>
<p>As mentioned above, all the data in the repository, both Commits and
the table data, is stored in these content-addressed variable sized
blocks called <code>Chunk</code>s. A storage abstraction exists in the Dolt
storage layer called a <code>ChunkStore</code>, which is a place where we can
read, and potentially write, chunks.</p>
<div data-language="go"><pre><code><span>package</span> chunk

<span>type</span> Address <span>[</span><span>20</span><span>]</span><span>byte</span>

<span>type</span> Chunk <span>interface</span> <span>{</span>
    
    <span>Refs</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>[</span><span>]</span>Address
    
    <span>Bytes</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>[</span><span>]</span><span>byte</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>type</span> Store <span>interface</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>Has</span><span>(</span>addr Address<span>)</span> <span>bool</span>
    <span>Get</span><span>(</span>addr Address<span>)</span> Chunk
    <span>Put</span><span>(</span>contents Chunk<span>)</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre></div>
<p>We can create a <code>Store</code> implementation for a remote repository which
is hosted in DoltHub, and we have a <code>Store</code> implementation for our
local repository as well. A simple recursive DAG walk to copy a given
commit (or any <code>Chunk</code> with all of its children) into our local
repository looks like:</p>
<div data-language="go"><pre><code><span>func</span> <span>CopyChunks</span><span>(</span>to<span>,</span> from Store<span>,</span> a Address<span>)</span> <span>{</span>
	<span>if</span> <span>!</span>to<span>.</span><span>Has</span><span>(</span>a<span>)</span> <span>{</span>
		c <span>:=</span> from<span>.</span><span>Get</span><span>(</span>a<span>)</span>
		<span>for</span> <span>_</span><span>,</span> r <span>:=</span> <span>range</span> c<span>.</span><span>Refs</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
			<span>Fetch</span><span>(</span>to<span>,</span> from<span>,</span> r<span>)</span>
		<span>}</span>
		to<span>.</span><span>Put</span><span>(</span>c<span>)</span>
	<span>}</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre></div>
<p>This approach already has some nice properties. Ideally, if a <code>Chunk</code>
is in a <code>Store</code>, all the <code>Chunk</code>s it references would also be in the
<code>Store</code>. We don't want our algorithm to persist any <code>Chunk</code>s to the
<code>Store</code> whose children we haven't already fetched and persisted,
because if the algorithm gets aborted halfway through the <code>Store</code>
could then be in an inconsistent state. So we're careful not to <code>Put</code>
the fetched <code>Chunk</code> until its children are persisted.</p>
<h2>Better Performance With Batching</h2>
<p>In Go, the recursion is not much of a concern because goroutines have
on-heap growable stacks. But if it is a concern, it's easy to
translate the call stack state into an explicit stack with on-heap
state as well.</p>
<p>The above algorithm has one glaring issue: it's very slow. If <code>from</code>
is a remote <code>Store</code>, then every <code>Get</code> is a round-trip RPC, and as
written there's no capacity for pipelining or batching. The simplest
solution is to make the batching explicit. We can give <code>Store</code> batch
methods, and make <code>CopyChunks</code> take a slice of <code>Address</code>es instead:</p>
<div data-language="go"><pre><code><span>type</span> Store <span>interface</span> <span>{</span>
    
    
    <span>HasMany</span><span>(</span><span>[</span><span>]</span>Address<span>)</span> <span>(</span>present<span>,</span> missing <span>[</span><span>]</span>Address<span>)</span>
    
    
    <span>GetMany</span><span>(</span><span>[</span><span>]</span>Address<span>)</span> <span>[</span><span>]</span>Chunk
    
    <span>PutMany</span><span>(</span><span>[</span><span>]</span>Chunk<span>)</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>func</span> <span>CopyChunks</span><span>(</span>to<span>,</span> from Store<span>,</span> as <span>[</span><span>]</span>Address<span>)</span> <span>{</span>
	<span>_</span><span>,</span> missing <span>:=</span> to<span>.</span><span>HasMany</span><span>(</span>as<span>)</span>
	chunks <span>:=</span> from<span>.</span><span>GetMany</span><span>(</span>missing<span>)</span>
	nextlevel <span>:=</span> <span>[</span><span>]</span>Address<span>{</span><span>}</span>
	<span>for</span> <span>_</span><span>,</span> c <span>:=</span> <span>range</span> chunks <span>{</span>
		nextlevel <span>=</span> <span>append</span><span>(</span>nextlevel<span>,</span> c<span>.</span><span>Refs</span><span>(</span><span>)</span><span>...</span><span>)</span>
	<span>}</span>
	<span>CopyChunks</span><span>(</span>to<span>,</span> from<span>,</span> nextlevel<span>)</span>
	to<span>.</span><span>PutMany</span><span>(</span>chunks<span>)</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre></div>
<p>That improves the round-trips for remote clones substantially and
allows for better bandwidth utilization. But it introduces two new
flaws.</p>
<ol>
<li>Memory usage is potentially unwieldy. In the batched version, we're
holding a potentially large number of <code>Chunk</code>s in memory at every call
to <code>CopyChunks</code>, and we're making a call to <code>GetMany</code> with an
unbounded number of <code>Address</code>es. Previously we were only holding one
<code>Chunk</code> in memory at each level of the call.</li>
<li>It potentially fetches the same <code>Chunk</code>s from <code>from</code> multiple
times. Two different length paths through the DAG to the same <code>Chunk</code>
will have <code>to.HasMany()</code> returning <code>missing</code> for the same <code>Chunk</code>
multiple times, with consequent calls to <code>GetMany()</code> with the same
addresses.</li>
</ol>
<p>Addressing those actually gets somewhat complicated. In Dolt, for #1
we form explicit RPC batches and write the fetched <code>Chunk</code>s to
temporary chunk files so that they don't have to stay in memory. The
temporary files are constructed so that they can be cheaply integrated
into the <code>to</code> <code>Store</code> when all their dependencies are
persisted. Addressing #2 involves adding a little bit of book keeping
across recursive calls.  But perfect behavior with regards to case #2
is actually a tradeoff between the batch sizes and memory usage. Once
the chunk from a higher level leaves memory and goes into the
temporary chunk file, it needs to be refetched from the remote or from
the disk in order to be incorporated in the <code>to</code> <code>Store</code> earlier than
its peers.</p>
<h2>Fetch and Push</h2>
<p>It's neat that the above algorithm works great whether operation is a
<code>push</code> or a <code>fetch</code>. If the remote <code>Store</code> is <code>from</code>, we're doing a
<code>fetch</code> and we will get new chunks from the remote into our local
<code>Store</code>. But we can also make the remote <code>Store</code> <code>to</code>, in which case
its a <code>push</code>—the remote <code>Store</code> gets the new <code>Chunk</code>s that were
unique to our local <code>Store</code>. In either case, once all the <code>Chunk</code>s are
persisted in the <code>to</code> <code>Store</code>, we can update any <code>refs</code> appropriately,
setting them to point to the newly persisted commit <code>Chunk</code>s based on
the operation we're performing and the fetch/push specs as
appropriate.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Dolt remotes are a powerful feature that allows for data
synchronization, collaboration and easily maintaining local changes
while tracking upstreams. Underlying the feature is a simple model for
how to build up the commit graph and the table data as a merkle DAG of
content addressed chunks. Building on top of that model allows for
<code>push</code> and <code>fetch</code> to be both be implemented by the same elegant DAG
walk. At the same time, practical engineering and performance concerns
introduce an opportunity for tradeoffs and optimization. Hopefully
we've given you some insight into the ways that Dolt approaches and
solves the issues underlying its implementation.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2020-09-09-push-pull-on-a-merkle-dag/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24424593</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 19:06:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Zink (OpenGL on Vulkan) performance better than expected]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 161 | Comments 86 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24424462">thread link</a>) | @mfilion
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | http://www.supergoodcode.com/funday/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.supergoodcode.com/funday/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <h2 id="just-for-fun">Just For Fun</h2>

<p>I finally managed to get a complete piglit run over the weekend, and, for my own amusement, I decided to check the timediffs against a reference run from the IRIS driver. Given that the Intel drivers are of extremely high quality (and are direct interfaces to the underlying hardware that I happen to be using), I tend to use ANV and IRIS as my references whenever I’m trying to debug things.</p>

<p>Both runs used the same base checkout from mesa, so all the core/gallium/nir parts were identical.</p>

<p>The results weren’t what I expected.</p>

<p>My expectation when I clicked into the timediffs page was that zink would be massively slower in a huge number of tests, likely to a staggering degree in some cases.</p>

<p>We were, but then also on occasion we weren’t.</p>

<p>As a final disclaimer before I dive into this, I feel like given the current state of people potentially rushing to conclusions I need to say that <strong>I’m not claiming zink is faster than a native GL driver</strong>, only that <strong>for some cases, our performance is oddly better than I expected</strong>.</p>

<h2 id="the-good">The Good</h2>
<p><img src="https://zmike.github.io/assets/piglit-misc-bench.png" alt="piglit-misc-bench.png"></p>

<p>The first thing to take note of here is that IRIS is massively better than zink in successful test completion, with a near-perfect 99.4% pass rate compared to zink’s measly 91%, and that’s across 2500 more tests too. This is important also since timediff only compares between passing tests.</p>

<p>With that said, somehow zink’s codepath is significantly faster when it comes to dealing with high numbers of varying outputs, and also, weirdly, a bunch of <code>dmat4</code> tests, even though they’re both using the same softfp64 path since my icelake hardware doesn’t support native 64bit operations.</p>

<p>I was skeptical about some of the numbers here, particularly the <code>ext_transform_feedback</code> <code>max-varying-arrays-of-arrays</code> cases, but manual tests were even weirder:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>time MESA_GLSL_CACHE_DISABLE=true MESA_LOADER_DRIVER_OVERRIDE=zink bin/ext_transform_feedback-max-varyings -auto -fbo

MESA_GLSL_CACHE_DISABLE=true MESA_LOADER_DRIVER_OVERRIDE=zink  -auto -fbo  2.13s user 0.03s system 98% cpu 2.197 total
</code></pre></div></div>

<div><div><pre><code>time MESA_GLSL_CACHE_DISABLE=true MESA_LOADER_DRIVER_OVERRIDE=iris bin/ext_transform_feedback-max-varyings -auto -fbo

MESA_GLSL_CACHE_DISABLE=true MESA_LOADER_DRIVER_OVERRIDE=iris  -auto -fbo  301.64s user 0.52s system 99% cpu 5:02.45 total
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>wat.</p>

<p>I don’t have a good explanation for this since I haven’t dug into it other than to speculate that ANV is just massively better at handling large numbers of varying outputs.</p>

<h2 id="the-bad">The Bad</h2>

<p>By contrast, zink gets thrashed pretty decisively in <code>arb_map_buffer_alignment-map-invalidate-range</code>, and we’re about <strong>150x slower</strong>.</p>

<p>Yikes. Looks like that’s going to be a target for some work since potentially an application might hit that codepath.</p>

<h2 id="the-weird">The Weird</h2>
<p><img src="https://zmike.github.io/assets/piglit-fp64-bench.png" alt="piglit-fp64-bench.png"></p>

<p>Somehow, zink is noticeably slower in a bunch of other fp64 tests (and this isn’t the full list, only a little over half). It’s strange to me that zink can perform better in certain fp64 cases but then also worse in others, but I’m assuming this is just the result of different shader optimizations happening between the drivers, shifting them onto slightly less slow parts of the softfp64 codepath in certain cases.</p>

<p>Possibly something to look into.</p>

<p>Probably not in too much depth since softfp64 is some pretty crazy stuff.</p>

<h2 id="in-closing">In Closing</h2>
<p>Tests (and especially piglit ones) are not indicative of real world performance.</p>

  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.supergoodcode.com/funday/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24424462</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 18:56:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What are the legal issues around web scraping?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 32 | Comments 18 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24424277">thread link</a>) | @neoflexycurrent
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | http://evan.law/2020/09/09/what-are-the-legal-issues-around-web-scraping/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://evan.law/2020/09/09/what-are-the-legal-issues-around-web-scraping/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="page">
				<div id="content">
			
	<div id="primary">
		<main id="main">
			
<article id="post-5792" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork" itemscope="">
	<div>
		
		<!-- .entry-header -->

		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
<figure><p>
<iframe title="Web scraping - what are the legal issues? | Evan Brown" width="900" height="506" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YA4eDamJz24?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Web scraping is that activity where a party uses automated software to crawl the internet and copy data and other content, usually so that it can compile that together and make its own product offering.  This may be of concern to you because you are a company that does web scraping. Or you may be a web publisher and there are other parties that are scraping your content. Let’s examine some of the legal issues around web scraping.</p>



<h3>Breach of contract</h3>



<p>One of the questions that commonly arises around web scraping is whether the activity is a breach of contract. More specifically, the question is whether the use of automated software violates the terms of service of the website that is being scraped. You often see website terms of service prohibit the use of spider and other automated crawling software to access and use the site. Parties who own websites that are being scraped will often look to see whether the scraping of their site is a breach of contract. </p>



<h3>Copyright infringement</h3>



<p>Another common question arising when analyzing web scraping is lawful whether scraping constitutes copyright infringement. This is a difficult argument to make if all that is being scraped is data, because mere facts usually are not subject to copyright protection. But if there is other content being scraped, such as images or specific compilations of data, the question of copyright infringement becomes a bit easier to answer in that unauthorized copying is an likely an infringement.</p>



<h3>Computer Fraud and Abuse Act</h3>



<p>The <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/18/1030" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Computer Fraud and Abuse Act</a> is another topic that often comes up in discussions about web scraping. This is a federal law that makes it unlawful for a person to access a protected computer without authorization, or in excess of a specific authorization. So the question becomes whether that access by the automated web scraper violates the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act. There are some important things that have to be proven for a plaintiff to succeed under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act, and one of those is loss or damage that results from the unauthorized access. It is a very fact intensive inquiry that has to be made,  but the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act is one thing that parties should think about in the context of web scraping. </p>



<h3>Trade secrets</h3>



<p>The question of trade secrets is another good one to raise in the context of web scraping. A trade secret is any information that a company has that gives that company a commercial advantage in the marketplace because it is secret. The information also has to be the subject of protective efforts — the company has to try to keep the information secret. For example, if information on a website is put there in a way that is behind certain protective barrier,s and the party doing the scraping circumvents those barriers, it could be that there is a misappropriation of trade secrets, particularly if that information is used for some competitive purpose. </p>



<h3>Let’s talk</h3>



<p>Web scraping legal issues can be complex. Scraping presents certain legal risks to the ones doing it, and the law provides certain powerful remedies when web scraping runs afoul of the rules. If you have questions about web scraping, give me a call at (630) 362-7237, or send me an email at <a href="mailto:ebrown@internetcases.com" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ebrown@internetcases.com</a>. </p>



<h3>About the author</h3>



<p>Evan Brown is a technology and intellectual property attorney in Chicago. This content originally appeared on <a href="http://evan.law/">evan.law</a>. </p>



<h3>See also:</h3>



<ul><li><a href="http://evan.law/2018/11/19/web-scraping-case-fails-under-dastar/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Web scraping case fails under Dastar</a></li><li><a href="http://evan.law/2012/11/01/terms-of-service-data-scraping/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Online terms of service were not effective to prohibit data scraping</a></li><li><a href="http://evan.law/2005/04/06/forum-selection-clause-upheld-in-content-scraping-case/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Forum selection clause upheld in content scraping case</a></li></ul>
		</div><!-- .entry-content -->

					<!-- .entry-meta -->
			</div><!-- .inside-article -->
</article><!-- #post-## -->

					

							</main><!-- #main -->
	</div><!-- #primary -->

	<!-- #secondary -->

	</div><!-- #content -->
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://evan.law/2020/09/09/what-are-the-legal-issues-around-web-scraping/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24424277</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 18:43:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Hoarding critical knowledge is a way to stay employed]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 13 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24423857">thread link</a>) | @qrt
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://qatalog.com/blog/post/got-knowledge | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://qatalog.com/blog/post/got-knowledge">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://qatalog.com/blog/post/got-knowledge</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24423857</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 18:02:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Leading a dev team with data and not being a tyrant]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24423702">thread link</a>) | @necco908
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://linearb.io/blog/data-driven-dev-team/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://linearb.io/blog/data-driven-dev-team/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-id="670d84f7" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="theme-post-content.default">
				<div>
			
<figure><img src="https://linearb.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/1a-Blog-Data-Driven-Dev-team-1024x488.png" alt="" srcset="https://linearb.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/1a-Blog-Data-Driven-Dev-team-1024x488.png 1024w, https://linearb.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/1a-Blog-Data-Driven-Dev-team-300x143.png 300w, https://linearb.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/1a-Blog-Data-Driven-Dev-team-768x366.png 768w, https://linearb.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/1a-Blog-Data-Driven-Dev-team.png 1386w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"></figure>



<h3><strong>Stack ranking is natural human behavior&nbsp;</strong></h3>



<p>I have a buddy from high school named Murph. His real name is <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bfelt/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ben Felt</a> but every legit teenage crew in Pitsford, New York in the 90s needed a Murph so Ben took one for the team.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He’s a quant. Like Taylor Mason from the show Billions.&nbsp;</p>







<figure><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/aLSHkNWCVa3tsooRGsEIn_ePCfPbm8q76JG1IFkqXgNr5XQ9UDaadhEWwDWx6PmnYKQbYUg3RejrISynwYZy21haJKT_N8O12TRFNBojxdP37hpOO80kmOoRc-ViIo2AWv2cJboF" alt=""></figure>







<p>It would have been easy to predict Murph would end up as a big shot on Wall Street. For starters, he got a perfect 1600 score on his SATs and was accepted early admission to Yale.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There was also his unique approach to fantasy football. I’ve been playing with the same group of guys since 1999. We started in my Mom’s basement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When it came time for draft day, the regular nerds in our group like me would bring fantasy football magazines with last year’s stats and analyst opinions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Murph brought his computer. He wrote a program that organized his draft board based on each player’s predicted performance correlated to his personal skill preferences. This is years before Daryl Morey founded <a href="http://www.sloansportsconference.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sloan Conference</a>. Murph was ahead of his time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>People naturally want to quantify objects by ranking them in lists of best to worst, most expensive to least expensive, most important to least important. We do this throughout our personal and professional lives. Often subconsciously before we even realize we’re doing it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sometimes it makes sense to rank objects by performance. Like ranking athletes in your fantasy league. Murph won our league multiple times using his ranking algo.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sometimes it even makes sense to rank real people by performance. Like on a sales team where there is a relatively direct link between the contribution of a sales rep and the outcomes (e.g. new customer, revenue) they deliver.</p>



<p><strong>When it comes to members of your dev team, it does not make sense to rank them using personal performance statistics.&nbsp;</strong></p>







<hr>



<div><figure><a href="https://linearb.io/trial/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><picture>
<source type="image/webp" srcset="https://linearb.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/CTACharacter.png.webp 502w" sizes="(max-width: 502px) 100vw, 502px">
<img src="https://linearb.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/CTACharacter.png" alt="" srcset="https://linearb.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/CTACharacter.png 502w, https://linearb.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/CTACharacter-202x300.png 202w" sizes="(max-width: 502px) 100vw, 502px">
</picture>
</a></figure></div>



<hr>







<h3><strong>Running a data-driven team does not mean stack ranking developers&nbsp;</strong></h3>



<p>A software development team is less like a sales team and more like a band. Everyone is highly dependent on one another to deliver a great result. If one person is off, it throws everyone off. And, like in a band, there are often unsung heroes (like the bass player or drummer) who make it possible for other stars (like the lead singer) to shine.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>







<figure><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-cqrL_fBle6dxY8DlVUhtTWbh54DZMympB2IVKA4EfMFLQ5y712qgwgXxHwVAsZH_8cxd3MCAmoRRGoIkbrpFVtpDrjTIWQqXjFijyhLLF2eRgjvCJmP7--6FkGXpmFnheNvtZyJ" alt=""></figure>







<p>The contributions of your most selfless team members may not show up if you just look at lines of code, number of commits or personal story point velocity.</p>



<p>The other big reason not to stack rank your devs is that they just don’t like it. Unlike sales people, your engineers did not sign up to work in a hyper competitive environment.</p>



<p>So why does stack ranking still happen? Some would say bad managers are the culprit. That’s probably true sometimes. Many bad managers want control and pitting teammates against each other in competition is certainly one way to get it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Most of the time the reason is more nuanced. I believe most managers have good intentions and want their people to succeed. But they get caught in the “data-driven trap.”</p>



<p>I hear it from engineering leaders every day… “My CEO wants me to be more data-driven” or “Our company is rolling out a metrics initiative.” Pressure to become data-driven can lead to arbitrary use of data to show the boss metrics are being used. “Let’s use data to make better decisions” gets confused as “let’s use data for performance management.”</p>



<p>When this misconception occurs, one of two things happens. Performance stack ranking metrics are implemented and it damages the team culture. Or the manager knows performance management is bad and avoids using metrics all together. Both are bad outcomes for the team.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>You can run a highly data and metrics-driven dev organization with absolutely zero performance management statistics.&nbsp;</strong></p>







<h3><strong>Data-driven engineering leadership anti-patterns</strong></h3>



<p>To avoid the “data-driven trap”, watch out for these 5 anti-patterns:&nbsp;</p>







<p><strong>Not knowing your “why”</strong></p>



<p>Without the “why”, the metrics themselves can become the outcome everyone cares about instead of being an indicator of the actual outcome you are trying to achieve like faster innovation, more predictable delivery dates, happier customers, etc.&nbsp;</p>







<p><strong>Only measuring individual stats</strong></p>



<p>As leaders we preach that we’re all working together as a band (team) to make beautiful music. What we measure shows what matters to us. If we track tons of individual metrics, we’re showing our people that individual stats matter more than team accomplishments. To get around this, I’ve actually seen some engineering leaders maintain secret dashboards with individual performance data. Their rationale is that it’s helpful for management as long as its existence does not get out. Everything always comes out eventually so I don’t recommend this. Plus, if you’re measuring something you don’t want your team to know about, that’s a good indicator you’re measuring the wrong thing.&nbsp;</p>







<p><strong>Focusing on just 1 or 2 metrics&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>I can’t tell you how many dev leads I meet that look only at velocity to determine the success of an iteration. <a href="https://linearb.io/blog/why-agile-velocity-is-the-most-dangerous-metric-for-software-development-teams/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Even if you think velocity is a useful indicator (I don’t)</a>, there is no silver bullet. Without a balanced approach to measuring each area of your team and process, it’s easy to lose sight of the big picture. For example, if you just focus on data that measures your delivery speed, you could encourage behavior that has a negative effect on quality.&nbsp;</p>







<p><strong>Thinking your new hammer (data) works for every nail (problem)&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>When we first start experiencing how powerful data can be as a tool to quantify trends and diagnose problems, it’s really exciting. And this is precisely when we need to be careful. We can’t forget to seek out input from our people too. Reports and dashboards are at their best when they prompt penetrating questions and point us in the right direction. We can’t get lazy and base decisions exclusively on the numbers.&nbsp;</p>







<p><strong>Just using metrics that are easily available&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>“Let’s use velocity to measure team performance. We get it from our project management system automatically.” Pulling the data you really need can be an initial large lift but the benefit overtime will pay back 100x. And it’s actually worse to force the wrong metrics than to use none at all.</p>







<h3><strong>14 ways to use data in your daily dev team practices without being a performance tyrant</strong></h3>



<p>Forget about individual performance management stats. There are many other ways to incorporate data into your team’s day to day routine that will have a positive impact on delivery efficiency, quality and predictability and actually improve your culture, not hurt it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So what should we measure?&nbsp;</p>



<p>When I was a team lead, I answered that question for myself by taking a step back and looking at my personal leadership responsibility areas. After analyzing all of my important jobs, I found that they fit into three pillars.&nbsp;</p>







<figure><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/13hUMY4HlnRRfrtmq4bMgYWOYBAHk95xsSDCvXbi7FRgNp7vUckkpkgFONefECxyU7deWyn46tOXd6QKnSNvrbKGwuiRzlS8hOFbKe1mhwgHXrXW6GxPUTRFTQzgWSXS-BkB67e0" alt=""></figure>







<p>These pillars became my “why”. So instead of starting with metrics and looking for a place to apply them, I looked for data that would help me understand and improve these areas.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Here’s 14 ways we use data to run our team on a day-to-day basis at <a href="https://linearb.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">LinearB</a>.&nbsp;</p>







<h4><strong>How we use data to accelerate project delivery</strong></h4>



<p>Project delivery is highly complicated because of the number of things happening in parallel. Even if your team is only 6-8 people. Technology, time constraints, priority shifts, developers, business stakeholders, customers… The only way to see across all of these dimensions is with data. Better yet, visual representations of data help distill complex things into manageable views and show you where to look and how to invest your time.&nbsp;</p>







<p><strong>1. Pull request throughput</strong></p>



<p>My friend <a href="https://linearb.io/coffee-talk/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Chris Downard</a>, the VP of Engineering at GigSmart, put it well.&nbsp;</p>



<p><em>“Knowing what to measure starts with aligning your team around what’s important to the business. In most companies, they want the dev team to deliver new value. So I care about metrics that are proxies for value delivery. I lean on merge requests because it helps me see throughput for work related to new features and bug fixes.”&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>We use our PR throughput dashboard the exact same way on our team. We like to see that the ratio of PRs opened to PRs merged stays in the 90-95% range otherwise we know we have a bottleneck in review.&nbsp;</p>







<figure><a href="https://linearb.io/get-started-linearb/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/dHWqhiCedjAb52oN1VY0S8uFUZ1cR7gJcHRrcRWQbb84XouHrTD21sRih0oQz9SwhywEdmp6ZHTaJ6niGMnWxReoMigGIieLXM2glZ5CUkCqc1HBGIrKM1vc7FKWCZCsBaTBqkwC" alt=""></a></figure>







<p><strong>2. Stuck pull requests&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>We look for A) PRs that have not been picked up for review, B) PRs that have abnormally high back and forth interaction and C) PRs with long review time.&nbsp; Then we alert the team to these in Slack so we can start a conversation about how to help and click through to the PR directly in Git.&nbsp;</p>







<figure><a href="https://linearb.io/get-started-linearb/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/1JL97AoLYrbimIpkxfT405N-FxrCieSqchuaEn2Dh6dwlRe5OYYBCX6TlpsUDIQiSHiEtQPsa9Sl_iJRDS2845EB4DyMUm03OvDba3_ASMiKaBe7ToucIUMAgyhFZYPjD6ICAywB" alt=""></a></figure>







<p>We implemented this in <a href="https://linearb.io/blog/dev-productivity-is-way-down-at-linearb/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">March when work-from-home started</a> and it’s become a critical part of our delivery process. Our devs love it because it’s one less thing they need to remember and they can jump in and help teammates more easily.&nbsp;</p>







<p><strong>3. PRs merged without review</strong></p>



<p>Our team is great about reviews but occasionally things slip. Flagging large PRs that have been merged without review has helped us catch a lot of mistakes before customers found them.&nbsp;</p>







<figure><a href="https://linearb.io/get-started-linearb/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/PsPxncxslm2V2acQox3pnFiR_nULYXN8FCXnvxjD-JLlVSiihieUMDayOELHpubE5aZ45QonVchJt9WhrDdD_M2TMyBlGCAp96lhU0BGVI2pzkRM6CB_j_pP4YivthPHVqgXs26N" alt=""></a></figure>







<p><strong>4. High risk branches</strong></p>



<p>About 15 months ago we analyzed all of our bugs and found a connection between bugs and large branches with a high rate of immediate rework (more than 30%). So now we look for those branches proactively and use our Slack alerts to get another set of eyes on them for review.&nbsp;</p>







<figure><a href="https://linearb.io/get-started-linearb/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/XuW12YJqhGmUTkMDRueIlTudnmil0P7uElElddlcDcc17COKUaporHhX7XhljQrRTWnjc2F1eHK1enijyKwIcppaIDnVnFpngbWYBYvslH0QI8U7W3uAK0-883deZ28d9cCN58Qq" alt=""></a></figure>







<hr>











<hr>







<p><strong>5. Days remaining to open work ratio&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>We work in two week iterations. Once we’re about a week in, there’s a general equation our leads use to figure out if we’re on track to deliver the iteration: WIP + to-do ÷ days remaining = almost everything you need to know about whether or not you are going to finish on time.&nbsp;</p>







<figure><a href="https://linearb.io/get-started-linearb/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://linearb.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/8-Data-Driven-Dev-team-v3-1024x488.png" alt="" srcset="https://linearb.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/8-Data-Driven-Dev-team-v3-1024x488.png 1024w, https://linearb.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/8-Data-Driven-Dev-team-v3-300x143.png 300w, https://linearb.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/8-Data-Driven-Dev-team-v3-768x366.png 768w, https://linearb.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/8-Data-Driven-Dev-team-v3.png 1386w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"></a><figcaption>Devboard Envy? <a href="https://linearb.io/get-started-linearb/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Get this one for free</a></figcaption></figure>







<p>Our dev team uses a board that shows our Github activity on a timeline with the Jira …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://linearb.io/blog/data-driven-dev-team/">https://linearb.io/blog/data-driven-dev-team/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://linearb.io/blog/data-driven-dev-team/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24423702</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 17:50:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Panther Labs Raises $15M to Reinvent SIEM for Cloud-First Teams]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 9 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24423524">thread link</a>) | @jacknagz
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://blog.runpanther.io/series-a-funding/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.runpanther.io/series-a-funding/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">
    <div>

        <article>

            

            <figure>
                <img srcset="https://blog.runpanther.io/content/images/size/w300/2020/09/patrick-tomasso-tN7fJdTaU40-unsplash.jpg 300w,
                            https://blog.runpanther.io/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/patrick-tomasso-tN7fJdTaU40-unsplash.jpg 600w,
                            https://blog.runpanther.io/content/images/size/w1000/2020/09/patrick-tomasso-tN7fJdTaU40-unsplash.jpg 1000w,
                            https://blog.runpanther.io/content/images/size/w2000/2020/09/patrick-tomasso-tN7fJdTaU40-unsplash.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 400px,
                            (max-width: 1170px) 700px,
                            1400px" src="https://blog.runpanther.io/content/images/size/w2000/2020/09/patrick-tomasso-tN7fJdTaU40-unsplash.jpg" alt="Panther Labs Series A Funding">
            </figure>

            <section>
                <div>
                    <p>Today, we're pleased to announce our <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/panther-labs-raises-15m-series-a-to-reinvent-siem-for-cloud-first-security-teams-301126303.html">$15M Series A financing led by Lightspeed Venture Partners</a>! </p><p>With this latest round of funding, we can double-down on our mission to re-invent the SIEM for modern and cloud-focused security teams. We're also excited to welcome <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ggupta/">Gaurav Gupta</a> to our board of directors. Gaurav brings 10+ years of experience as a product leader at Splunk and Elastic to our leadership team.</p><p>Security teams are struggling to manage the unprecedented scale and growth of data in the cloud. Panther operationalizes massive volumes of scattered and unstructured security logs into real-time Python detections and helpful analytics with SQL over structured data. This new data-driven, developer-centric paradigm will power security teams for the next 10 years.</p><p>Panther’s guiding product principles are:</p><ul><li><strong><strong><strong>Open</strong> </strong></strong>and transparent data processing and storage.</li><li><strong><strong><strong>Scalable </strong></strong></strong>serverless infrastructure designed for Petabyte-scale.</li><li><strong>Powerful</strong> Python detections to identify complex behaviors in real-time.</li></ul><p>Panther Community Edition is a fully functional and open source project for teams to get started with analyzing their log data and cloud security posture. For production-level deployments, Panther Enterprise offers advanced features around querying and data storage, the ability to pull SaaS log data, customizable RBAC and SSO integrations, and options for SaaS and self-hosted deployments.</p><p>One new feature we’re excited to announce in Panther Enterprise is an Indicator Search. This feature enables lightning-fast searches across all collected logs for IPs, domains, hashes, cloud-specific values like ARNs, and <a href="https://docs.runpanther.io/log-analysis/panther-fields">more</a>. This is made possible by the <a href="https://blog.runpanther.io/panther-database-as-service-modern-serverless-architecture/">Panther’s Data Lake</a>, which enables scalable storage for huge amounts of security data.</p><p>Try <a href="https://github.com/panther-labs/panther">Panther Community Edition</a> today and join the discussion on <a href="http://slack.runpanther.io/">Slack</a> to learn how teams are using Panther to prevent breaches at cloud-scale. Also check out our public roadmap that includes planned, in-progress, and recently launched features. </p><p><strong>We’re also hiring!</strong> If you’re interested in contributing to our mission, check out our <a href="https://boards.greenhouse.io/pantherlabs">open roles on Greenhouse</a>. Panther is a remote-friendly workforce and aims to foster a culture of diversity.</p><figure><img src="https://blog.runpanther.io/content/images/2020/09/Zoom-Sept-2020.png" alt="" srcset="https://blog.runpanther.io/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/Zoom-Sept-2020.png 600w, https://blog.runpanther.io/content/images/size/w1000/2020/09/Zoom-Sept-2020.png 1000w, https://blog.runpanther.io/content/images/size/w1600/2020/09/Zoom-Sept-2020.png 1600w, https://blog.runpanther.io/content/images/size/w2400/2020/09/Zoom-Sept-2020.png 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption>Our Team at Panther Labs</figcaption></figure>
                </div>
            </section>


            


        </article>

    </div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.runpanther.io/series-a-funding/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24423524</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 17:36:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Backup PostgreSQL to Cloud]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 17 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24423208">thread link</a>) | @Abishek_Muthian
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://abishekmuthian.com/backup-postgresql-to-cloud/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://abishekmuthian.com/backup-postgresql-to-cloud/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>This post will help you with easy, cost-effective and secure way to backup your PostgreSQL database to cloud.</p><h3 id="create-local-scheduled-backup-of-postgresql-database">Create local scheduled backup of PostgreSQL database</h3><ol><li><p>Login as <em>postgres</em> user on the console (<a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/671422/how-to-use-tmux-on-linux-and-why-its-better-than-screen/" target="_blank">tmux</a> is recommended).</p></li><li><p>Create .pgpass file to access database without entering credentials manually.</p><pre><code>$ nano .pgpass
</code></pre></li><li><p>Enter the credentials in the following format. Making changes according to the host if necessary.</p><pre><code>localhost:5432:dbname:dbusername:dbpassword
</code></pre></li><li><p>Set permissions to the file. login_username will be <em>postgres</em>, if you are logged in as that user.</p><pre><code>$ chmod 600 .pgpass
$ chown login_username:login_username .pgpass
</code></pre></li><li><p>Set the environment variable in the <em>.profile</em> file. Where /var/lib/pgsql is the home directory for the user <em>postgres</em> in my setup.</p><pre><code>$ nano .profile

export PGPASSFILE='/var/lib/pgsql/.pgpass'
</code></pre></li><li><p>Test the login. Making changes according to host if necessary.</p><pre><code>$ psql -h localhost -U dbusername dbname
</code></pre></li></ol><h3 id="setup-restic">Setup Restic</h3><p>Restic is a free open-source backup program available for multiple distributions. <a href="https://github.com/restic/restic/releases/" target="_blank">Download</a> the one appropriate to your operating system, extract it, move it to <em>/var/lib/pgsql/bin/</em> (home directory of user <em>postgres</em>) as <em>restic</em>, make it executable and set the PATH to that folder.</p><pre><code>$ bzip2 -d restic_*_linux_amd64.bz2
$ mv restic_*_linux_amd64 /usr/bin/restic
$ chmod u+x /var/lib/pgsql/bin/restic

$ nano .profile

export PATH=$PATH:/var/lib/pgsql/bin
</code></pre><p>Creat <em>restic-pw.txt</em> file with password for encrypting the Postgres database dump.</p><pre><code>$ nano restic-pw.txt
[Enter the password for encryption]

$ chmod 600 restic-pw.txt
$ chown postgres:postgres restic-pw.txt
</code></pre><h3 id="setup-backblaze">Setup Backblaze</h3><p>Backblaze is a cloud storage service, offering easy encrypted end-to-end cloud backup solutions for home and business users.</p><p>For backing up our PostgreSQL database to their cloud, we will use their <a href="https://www.backblaze.com/b2/sign-up.html?referrer=abishekmuthian" target="_blank">B2 service</a> for backing up our
data via their API. <strong>First 10GB of storage on B2 is free as of this writing</strong>, but charges may apply when we download those data and so read the pricing details carefully.</p><p>Create a B2 account to get the following credentials and export them in <em>.bashrc</em>.</p><pre><code>$ nano .bashrc

export B2_ACCOUNT_ID="XXXXX"
export B2_ACCOUNT_KEY="XXXXX"
export RESTIC_REPOSITORY="b2:bucket-name"
export RESTIC_PASSWORD_FILE="restic-pw.txt"
</code></pre><h3 id="setup-a-cron-job-to-schedule-the-backup-and-upload">Setup a cron job to schedule the backup and upload</h3><p>Setup a cronjob to create a PostgresSQL database dump using <em>pg_dump</em> tool, here it is done every day at 23:00 hours and is upload to B2 at 00:00 hours.</p><pre><code>$ crontab -e

0 23 * * * pg_dump -U dbusername -w -F t dbname &gt; /var/lib/pgsql/db.tar
0 0 * * * . /var/lib/pgsql/.bashrc; /usr/bin/restic backup -q /var/lib/pgsql/db.tar
</code></pre><p>Note: Depending upon the size of your database, how often it changes, you might need to change the schedule for the cron job accordingly.</p><h3 id="verify">Verify</h3><p>Check the Backblaze portal to verify that the snapshot was created in our b2 bucket.</p><h3 id="downloading-the-backup">Downloading the backup</h3><p>We can download the backup using restic again, when we need it.</p><p>Get the snapshot-ID.</p><pre><code>$ restic -r b2:bucket-name snapshots
</code></pre><p>Restore the snapshot to a folder using the snapshot_ID.</p><pre><code>$ restic -r b2:bucket-name restore snapshot_ID -t /tmp/restic-restore
</code></pre><p>Note: When downloading the snapshot in another machine, requisite credentials for restic and b2 should be provided as discussed earlier.</p><h3 id="retrieving-the-postgres-dump">Retrieving the Postgres dump</h3><p>Postgres dump would be available in the folder where the snapshot was restored.</p><pre><code>$ cd /tmp/restic-restore
</code></pre><h3 id="restoring-the-postgres-dump">Restoring the Postgres dump</h3><p>Create a database of the same name after logging in as the database user.</p><pre><code>$ CREATE DATABASE dbname;
</code></pre><p>Use the <em>pg_restore</em> tool to restore the database from the dump.</p><pre><code>$ pg_restore --dbname=dbname --verbose db.tar
</code></pre><p>That’s all, now we can have a safe and reliable backup postgres database in the cloud. You can <a href="https://twitter.com/heavyinfo" target="_blank">tweet</a> to me for queries and share this if you found it useful.</p><h3 id="backblaze-entire-storage-backup-solutions-for-home-and-business">Backblaze entire storage backup solutions for Home and Business</h3><p>If you would like unlimited automated backup your entire computer storage instead, then Backblaze has solutions for home and businesses users. Check them out using my affiliate links.</p><p><a href="https://www.backblaze.com/cloud-backup.html#af9vgw" target="_blank">Backblaze unlimited cloud backup for home users</a>.</p><p><a href="https://www.backblaze.com/business-backup.html#af9vgw" target="_blank">Backblaze business backup</a>.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://abishekmuthian.com/backup-postgresql-to-cloud/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24423208</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 17:12:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Classes are a way of writing higher order functions]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 114 | Comments 130 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24422547">thread link</a>) | @stopachka
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://stopa.io/post/250 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://stopa.io/post/250">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span><p>Joe and I recently <a href="https://twitter.com/stopachka/status/1295411936625074178" target="_blank">kicked off a re-read of SICP</a>. I can say that it is <em>the</em> most interesting textbook I have gone through. Imagine, you begin with just 4 or 5 constructs, and you end up building algebraic equation solvers, circuit simulators, and even logic programming languages. Because you start off with such few constructs, the added benefit is that you begin to see the fundamentally simple, shared essence in programming. </p><p>I wanted to give you one example that surprised me in the book. We tend to think that <strong>classes belong in a</strong> <strong>fundamentally different category</strong> <strong>from functions.</strong> </p><p>But are they so different? </p><p>For example, let’s say we have a class like this:</p><pre><code>class Person { 
  constructor(firstName, lastName) {
    this.fName = firstName; 
    this.lName = lastName;
  }
  getFullName() { 
    return this.fName + ' ' + this.lName;
  }
  setFirstName(firstName) {
    this.fName = firstName;
  }
}</code></pre><p>Well, if we think about it, this is really just a higher order function. a <code>Person</code> higher order function accepts arguments (constructor), and returns a list of functions that can manipulate those arguments (methods). We could write <code>Person</code> like this: </p><pre><code> function Person(firstName, lastName) {
  let fName = firstName; 
  let lName = lastName;

  function getFullName() { 
    return fName + ' ' + lName;
  }
  
  function setFirstName(firstName) { 
    fName = firstName
  }

  return function(method) { 
    switch (method) { 
      case 'getFullName': 
        return getFullName;
      case 'setFirstName': 
        return setFirstName;  
    }
  }
}</code></pre><p>Now, </p><pre><code>const person = new Person("Ben", "Bitdiddle")
person.getFullName()</code></pre><p>becomes</p><pre><code>const person = Person("Ben", "Bitdiddle")
person('getFullName')()</code></pre><p>Here, instead of invoking a method, we are “passing” a message. This is why by the way, many classic OO folks talk about object orientation really being about message passing.  </p><p>Yup, really. Classes are just higher order functions, which accept arguments (constructor) and return a list of functions that can manipulate those arguments (methods). </p><p>When you previously thought two concepts were different, but they turn out to be the same, you’re ripe to discover new ideas: you can find the deeper abstractions between them, apply ideas from across those seemingly different categories, and move between concepts more fluidly. So, not only are epiphanies like this fun, but they’re much more useful than you’d think. </p><p>If you liked this, there are a <em>ton</em> of similar epiphanies in the textbook. To experience it best, I suggest picking a partner and working through the book together.</p><p><em>Thanks to Daniel Woelfel, Alex Reichert, Jacky Wang for reviewing drafts of this essay</em></p></span></p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://stopa.io/post/250</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24422547</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 16:16:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[No-Code vs. Pro-Code: A New Hope]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 91 | Comments 18 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24421767">thread link</a>) | @ochiba
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://journeyapps.com/engineering-blog/no-code-vs-pro-code-a-new-hope/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://journeyapps.com/engineering-blog/no-code-vs-pro-code-a-new-hope/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              <p>When it comes to building apps, no-code is having its moment. Typeform is a shining example of how no-code is well suited for simple use cases, and here at JourneyApps we use it extensively. However, therein lies the problem: No-code’s sweet spot is simple use cases. This limitation of no-code tools has been well analyzed. [<a href="https://journeyapps.com/blog/low-code-road-to-software-enlightenment-part-1/">1</a>][<a href="https://www.alexhudson.com/2020/01/13/the-no-code-delusion/">2</a>]</p>

<p>If you want to build more sophisticated custom software, you essentially have two options:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Use a no-code/low-code tool and jump through nasty hoops to implement the sophisticated parts of your app — which most often means writing actual code that needs to conform to the constraints of the tool.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Use pro-code tools such as Swift/Objective-C, or frameworks like Xamarin/MAUI, etc.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p><img src="https://journeyapps.com/assets/images/blog/2020-09-08-no-code-vs-pro-code-a-new-hope/1.png" alt="image"></p>

<p><em>Image: building anything beyond basic logic with a visual programming language ends up looking like this</em></p>

<h3 id="a-big-problem-that-needs-solving">A Big Problem That Needs Solving</h3>

<p>Both of the above approaches (using pro-code, or using a low-code platform’s pro-code extensibility) are time-consuming, although for different reasons. Both also require senior developer talent, while senior developers are as scarce as hen’s teeth.</p>

<p>The result is that many companies are highly constrained while executing on ambitious software and digital initiatives.</p>

<p>These are the companies that we serve. Enterprise developers have been building custom apps using code on JourneyApps since 2009.</p>

<p>Towards the end of 2019 we wanted to up the ante. We wanted to offer a new app development paradigm for companies with a large app backlog, especially where a big chunk of that backlog consisted of ambitious B2E and B2B apps.</p>

<p>We set two high level goals for ourselves: help companies write great software much more productively (especially those whose core focus is not software), and let them do this using modern software technologies and best practices, without the typical barriers.</p>

<h3 id="key-tenets-of-what-we-set-out-to-build">Key Tenets of What We Set Out to Build</h3>

<p>We decided that the best thing we could do was to build a next-generation IDE (as a complement to our full-stack app platform) that has the <strong>power and flexibility of pro-code</strong> at its core, but also has the high <strong>development velocity and easy adoption of no-code/low-code platforms</strong>.</p>

<p>From the start, we decided that some things are non-negotiable:</p>

<h4 id="1-coding-should-be-easy">1. Coding should be easy</h4>

<ul>
  <li>Creating a new app shouldn’t require any configuration or setup.</li>
  <li>Developers should be able to start coding immediately.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="2-coding-should-have-a-fast-feedback-loop">2. Coding should have a fast feedback loop</h4>

<ul>
  <li>We will have a first-class IDE with real-time error checking, keyboard shortcuts, IntelliSense, etc.</li>
  <li>Developers should have access to a real debugger.</li>
  <li>We will have live, stateful hot reload on an actual device in development mode — not a time-consuming compile &amp; deploy process.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="3-coding-in-the-ide-should-be-fun-and-relevant">3. Coding in the IDE should be fun and relevant</h4>

<ul>
  <li>We will not use a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain-specific_language">DSL</a>: We will support open-source programming languages – preferably those with gradual typing.</li>
  <li>We will not use convoluted proprietary visual interfaces.</li>
  <li>We will not use a proprietary “app store”. Developers must be able to import open source packages.</li>
  <li>The IDE should be easily accessible to junior developers.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="4-coding-should-be-as-efficient-as-possible">4. Coding should be as efficient as possible</h4>

<ul>
  <li>We will provide developers with powerful functionality that can be used with minimal lines of code, and customized as required. This will include things like bi-directional relational offline data sync, dozens of UI components including Excel-like data grids, full audit trails, a cross-platform BLE engine, to name just a few.</li>
  <li>We will offer full git support with either hosted git, or external git providers (e.g. GitHub)</li>
  <li>We will support unit testing.</li>
  <li>We will support multiple environments, with easy portability of changes as new versions of software are moved from one environment to the next.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="5-there-should-always-be-an-escape-hatch">5. There should always be an escape hatch</h4>

<ul>
  <li>There will be APIs for everything.</li>
  <li>We will allow developers to easily mix in fully custom HTML in their UIs, and allow those custom HTML components to communicate bidirectionally with the rest of the frontend stack, when required.</li>
  <li>There will be a Node.js environment in our cloud backend where developers can build any custom backend functionality, without any configuration or setup.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="6-the-platform-should-be-secure-by-design">6. The platform should be secure by design</h4>

<h3 id="a-foundational-decision-building-a-web-ide">A Foundational Decision: Building a Web IDE</h3>

<p>We were taking the time to figure out a new approach to app development from first principles, so we had to make big design decisions with significant trade-offs. One major early decision was whether to build a web-based IDE or an installable desktop IDE.</p>

<p>The obvious question is: “Why an IDE on the web?”. We strongly believe that the recent developments across browser technology, transpiled languages and new approaches to software development (such as declarative UI) have made it possible to not only reach a desktop-grade level of quality in a web IDE, but also capitalize on the inherent benefits of the web paradigm.</p>

<p>Using this approach, we would have an IDE that is evergreen, cross-platform, cross-device, backed by modern UI and most importantly, ready for the future. Oh, and there would be nothing to install. Perhaps the biggest win, however, would be our ability to innovate quickly due to the open nature of web technologies and how quickly they evolve.</p>

<p>We’ll discuss other key design decisions in separate posts.</p>

<h3 id="unveiling-the-solution">Unveiling the Solution</h3>

<p>Today, we’re incredibly proud to announce <a href="https://journeyapps.com/platform/oxide/">OXIDE</a>. It’s the fruit of a lot of hard work by the JourneyApps team over the past year.</p>

<p>OXIDE helps both junior and senior developers build sophisticated cross-platform apps using JavaScript or TypeScript, complemented by visual tools. Apps can run natively on mobile and desktop operating systems, or in the browser as PWAs. Under the hood, OXIDE uses CRDTs [<a href="https://blog.kevinjahns.de/are-crdts-suitable-for-shared-editing/">3</a>] to enable live co-editing in teams, and it is deeply integrated with both GitHub and npm. In OXIDE, developers can switch between visual editing and coding for UI layout and schema design. Developers also have access to a first-class code debugging tool.</p>

<p>OXIDE is a fundamental pillar of the broader JourneyApps platform. Therefore, all apps inherit other flagship JourneyApps technologies out of the box — technologies that have seen around 10 years of R&amp;D and battle-hardening:</p>

<ul>
  <li>All apps ship with an enterprise-grade BaaS, and it’s easy to integrate with other data sources (in part because the platform is not based on a DSL).</li>
  <li>All apps are offline-first: Data is automatically synced to user devices, and loaded from the local database on each view. Querying data is fast. This avoids complicated state management and/or query cache systems. (What happens when data volumes scale? The platform provides highly configurable <a href="https://docs.journeyapps.com/reference/container/introduction-to-sync-rules">selective syncing.</a>)</li>
  <li>Each app is automatically provisioned with a Node.js serverless compute environment so that developers of all skill levels can add server-side logic and functionality.</li>
  <li>Developers have access to a rich built-in UI component set that is designed to work with data, with very little development overhead. No tweaking of styles or adding event listeners and state management to each component — this is handled for you.</li>
</ul>

<p>In general, JourneyApps takes the complexity out of the development cycle. We take care of the hard problems of enterprise software development (hosting, offline data sync, mobile app builds, backend APIs, deployment tooling, audit trails, and more) so that developers can focus on core app requirements and maximize the rate of innovation at their companies.</p>

<p>Working in OXIDE looks like this:</p>

<p><img src="https://journeyapps.com/assets/images/blog/2020-09-08-no-code-vs-pro-code-a-new-hope/2.png" alt="image"></p>

<p>And here’s a view of a debugging session. The app can be seen on the bottom right (running on macOS), the Chrome developer tools on the top right, and OXIDE on the left:</p>

<p><img src="https://journeyapps.com/assets/images/blog/2020-09-08-no-code-vs-pro-code-a-new-hope/3.png" alt="image"></p>

<p>Try it out and let us know what you think — <a href="https://accounts.journeyapps.com/portal/free-trial?utm_source=engineering-blog&amp;utm_medium=internal&amp;utm_campaign=engineering-blog">start building</a>.</p>


            </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://journeyapps.com/engineering-blog/no-code-vs-pro-code-a-new-hope/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24421767</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 15:01:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Designing New Cryptography for Non-Standard Threat Models]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 30 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24421073">thread link</a>) | @some_furry
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://soatok.blog/2020/09/09/designing-new-cryptography-for-non-standard-threat-models/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://soatok.blog/2020/09/09/designing-new-cryptography-for-non-standard-threat-models/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

		<div>

			
<p>Since the IETF’s CFRG decided to recommend OPAQUE as a next-generation <a href="https://soatok.blog/2020/04/21/authenticated-key-exchanges/">Password Authenticated Key Exchange</a>, there has been a lot of buzz in the cryptography community about committing authenticated encryption (known to the more academically inclined as Random Key Robustness), because OPAQUE requires <a href="https://mailarchive.ietf.org/arch/msg/cfrg/2W9LoeeiRzAiTWVnDsyxvjYPPmo/">an RKR-secure AE scheme</a>.</p>



<p>Random Key Robustness is a property that some symmetric encryption modes have, where it’s not feasible to decrypt a valid (ciphertext, tag) pair into two different plaintexts if both recipients are using different keys.</p>



<p>To illustrate this visually:</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="1348" data-permalink="https://soatok.blog/robustness/" data-orig-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/robustness.png" data-orig-size="750,550" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="robustness" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/robustness.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/robustness.png?w=580" src="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/robustness.png" alt="An example of random key robustness: encrypting two different images, with two different keys, can produce an identical stream of bits (ciphertext + tag)."><figcaption>RKR-secure ciphers don’t let people produce the same ciphertext+tag from two different plaintexts, with two different keys. You might be able to create an identical ciphertext, but the authentication tag will differ. (Art by <a href="https://twitter.com/SwizzlestixUK">Swizz</a>.)</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>In the wake of the CFRG discussion, it became immediately clear that <a href="https://soatok.blog/2020/05/13/why-aes-gcm-sucks/">AES-GCM doesn’t meet this requirement</a>.</p>



<p>What wasn’t immediately clear is <a href="https://keymaterial.net/2020/09/07/invisible-salamanders-in-aes-gcm-siv/">that AES-GCM-SIV also falls short</a>. But don’t take my word for it, Sophie Schmieg worked out the math in the linked post, which I highly recommend reading.</p>



<p>This isn’t to say that AES-GCM or AES-GCM-SIV are doomed, or should be deprecated. You probably don’t even care about Random Key Robustness in most of the places you’d use either algorithm! But if you are doing something where RKR actually matters, you probably care a lot. And it certainly violates the principle of least astonishment.</p>



<p>ChaCha20-Poly1305 won’t save you here either, since this is a property that message authentication codes based on cryptographic hash functions (e.g. HMAC) provide, but polynomial MACs (GMAC, Poly1305, etc.) do not.</p>



<p>So, if every standardized and widely-supported AEAD construction fails to provide RKR security, what’s a software engineer to do?<em> <a href="https://vnhacker.blogspot.com/2020/08/so-you-want-to-roll-your-own-crypto.html">Roll their own crypto</a>?!</em></p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="61" data-permalink="https://soatok.blog/glitch-ecb/" data-orig-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/glitch-ecb.png" data-orig-size="224,224" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="glitch-ecb" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/glitch-ecb.png?w=224" data-large-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/glitch-ecb.png?w=224" src="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/glitch-ecb.png" alt=""><figcaption>Don’t actually do that. (Art by <a href="https://twitter.com/SwizzlestixUK">Swizz</a>.)</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>If you’re always on a well-tread path with a well-defined, standard threat model (i.e. client-server application accessible via TLS 1.3, possibly storing hashed passwords server-side), then rolling your own crypto isn’t just dangerous; it’s wholly unnecessary.</p>



<h2 id="coping-with-nonstandard-threat-models">Coping with Non-Standard Threat Models</h2>



<p>Systems that require Random Key Robustness do not fall within the standard threat model of AEAD cipher constructions.</p>



<p>However, RKR is far from the only scenario in which application developers might find themselves without a clear solution. Another example that comes up a lot:</p>



<blockquote><p>“I need to encrypt data in a relational database, but still somehow use it in SELECT queries.”</p><cite>— Far too many damn developers who haven’t heard of <a href="https://ciphersweet.paragonie.com/">CipherSweet</a>.</cite></blockquote>



<p>The first thing that you should do is clearly document your requirements and what attacks your system must protect against. Any undefined attack vector in your model should be assumed to be a vulnerability in your design. (This gets into <a href="https://www.cryptofails.com/post/75204435608/write-crypto-code-dont-publish-it">Unknown Unknowns</a> territory quickly.)</p>



<p>And then you should have a cryptographer review your design, and then have a cryptography engineer build it for you.</p>



<p><strong><em>But where’s the fun in that?</em></strong></p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="1332" data-permalink="https://soatok.blog/soatoktelegrams2020-07/" data-orig-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-07.png" data-orig-size="512,512" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="SoatokTelegrams2020-07" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-07.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-07.png?w=512" src="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-07.png?w=512" alt="" srcset="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-07.png 512w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-07.png?w=150 150w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-07.png?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px"><figcaption>This would be a very boring blog post if I left it at that! (Art by <a href="https://twitter.com/lynxvsjackalope">Khia</a>.)</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Instead of copping out with sane and reasonable advice, let’s actually walk through the process. At the end of this post, I’ll share a toy example I cooked up for this blog post.</p>



<h2 id="designing-new-cryptography">Designing New Cryptography</h2>



<h3 id="understand-the-problem">First, Understand the Problem</h3>



<p>Why don’t AES-GCM, etc. provide Random Key Robustness? Because they’re built with universal hash functions rather than cryptographic hash functions.</p>



<p>Cryptographic hash functions have different properties (i.e. preimage resistance and collision resistance) that make it significantly difficult to calculate two different authentication tags under two different keys. Attacking HMAC-SHA-256 in this way is about <a href="https://pthree.org/2016/06/19/the-physics-of-brute-force/">as expensive as brute forcing a 128-bit AES key</a>. (Good luck with that!)</p>



<p>However, cryptographic hash functions are much slower than polynomial MACs, and using them in a construction like HMAC approximately doubles the slowness.</p>



<p>You might be tempted to just hash they key and the message together to save on CPU cycles, but that’s actually <a href="https://blog.skullsecurity.org/2012/everything-you-need-to-know-about-hash-length-extension-attacks">not safe for the hash functions nearly everybody uses</a> (due to length extension attacks).</p>



<p>It logically follows that, <strong>if we had an AEAD cipher construction based on a hash function, we could have RKR security</strong>.</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="1331" data-permalink="https://soatok.blog/soatoktelegrams2020-06/" data-orig-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-06.png" data-orig-size="512,512" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="SoatokTelegrams2020-06" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-06.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-06.png?w=512" src="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-06.png?w=512" alt="OwO *notices your cryptogrpahic robustness*" srcset="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-06.png 512w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-06.png?w=150 150w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-06.png?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px"><figcaption>Now we’re getting somewhere! (Art by <a href="https://twitter.com/lynxvsjackalope">Khia</a>.)</figcaption></figure></div>



<h3 id="prior-art">Look At Prior Art</h3>



<p>Before the days of AES-GCM and ChaCha20-Poly1305, there were a lot of ad hoc constructions used everywhere based on <a href="https://soatok.blog/2020/07/12/comparison-of-symmetric-encryption-methods/#aes-gcm-vs-aes-cbc">AES-CBC and HMAC</a>. (In that era, everyone used HMAC-SHA1, but don’t do that.)</p>



<p>However, there are a number of problems with ad hoc CBC+HMAC that we don’t want to reintroduce in modern systems:</p>



<ol><li>If you forget to include the initialization vector in the HMAC tag, you give attackers free reign over the first 16 bytes of the decrypted plaintext without having to break the MAC.</li><li>The order of operations (Encrypt-then-MAC, MAC-then-Encrypt, Encrypt and MAC) matters tremendously.</li><li>CBC+HMAC is usually implemented in application-layer code, but the security of such a construction depends heavily on the availability and utilization of <a href="https://soatok.blog/2020/08/27/soatoks-guide-to-side-channel-attacks/#string-comparison">constant-time functions</a>.</li><li>There is no standard format for CBC+HMAC, nor the order of operations for what gets fed into the MAC.<ul><li>IV + ciphertext? Ciphertext + IV?</li></ul><ul><li>Append the MAC, or prepend it?</li></ul></li><li>CBC+HMAC is only an AE mode, there is no room for additional authenticated data. If you try to naively shove extra data into the HMAC, <em>now you have to worry about canonicalization attacks</em>!</li><li>CBC mode requires padding (usually PKCS #7 padding), whereas cipher modes based on CTR do not.</li></ol>



<p>This is among the long list of reasons why cryptographers have spent the past decade (or longer) pushing developers towards AEAD modes.</p>



<p>Boring cryptography is good cryptography!</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="1210" data-permalink="https://soatok.blog/soatok_stickerpack_ind_cca2/" data-orig-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatok_stickerpack_ind_cca2.png" data-orig-size="512,512" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Soatok_STICKERPACK_IND_CCA2" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatok_stickerpack_ind_cca2.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatok_stickerpack_ind_cca2.png?w=512" src="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatok_stickerpack_ind_cca2.png?w=512" alt="This isn't IND-CCA2 Secure!" srcset="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatok_stickerpack_ind_cca2.png 512w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatok_stickerpack_ind_cca2.png?w=150 150w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatok_stickerpack_ind_cca2.png?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px"><figcaption>You never want to hear this about your design. (Art by <a href="https://twitter.com/lynxvsjackalope">Khia</a>.)</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Make sure you clearly understand the risks of the components other constructions have used.</p>



<h3 id="sketch-first-draft">Sketch Out A First Draft</h3>



<p>By now, it should be clear that if we have an Encrypt-then-MAC construction, where the MAC is based on a cryptographic hash function (e.g. SHA-256), we may be able to attain RKR security.</p>



<p>With that in mind, our sketch will probably look something like this:</p>



<ul><li>Encrypt(K1, M, N) -&gt; C<ul><li>Where Encrypt() is AES-CTR or equivalent</li></ul></li><li>Auth(K2, C, A) -&gt; T<ul><li>Where Auth() wraps HMAC-SHA2 or equivalent</li><li>How we feed C and A into the underlying MAC is important</li></ul></li><li>???? -&gt; K1, K2</li></ul>



<p>We still have to define some way of splitting a key (K) into two distinct keys (K1, K2). You never want to use a cryptographic key for more than one purpose, after all.</p>



<h3>Key-Splitting and Robustness</h3>



<p>Your encryption key and authentication key should be different, but they should also derived from the same input key! This is mainly to protect implementors from having independent keys and accidentally creating a forgery vulnerability.</p>



<p>There are several different ways you can split keys:</p>



<ol><li>Just use SHA-512(k), then cut it in half. Use one half for encryption, the other for authentication.</li><li>Use HMAC-SHA256(k, c1) and HMAC-SHA256(k, c2), where c1 and c2 are distinct (yet arbitrary) constants.</li><li>Use HKDF. This works with any secure cryptographic hash function, and was specifically designed for situations like this. HKDF also supports salting, which can be used to randomize our derived keys.</li></ol>



<p>We can really pick any of these three and be safe, but I’d advise against the first option. HKDF uses HMAC under-the-hood, so either of the latter options is fine.</p>



<h3 id="speed">Can We Make it Faster?</h3>



<p>What if, instead of HMAC-SHA256, we used <a href="https://github.com/BLAKE3-team/BLAKE3">BLAKE3</a>?</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="1362" data-permalink="https://soatok.blog/blake3/" data-orig-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/blake3.png" data-orig-size="1251,913" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="blake3" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/blake3.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/blake3.png?w=580" src="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/blake3.png" alt=""><figcaption>BLAKE3’s performance compared with other hash functions.</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>BLAKE3’s advertised 6.8 GiB/s can be even faster than <a href="https://crypto.stackexchange.com/a/60269">Poly1305 or GHASH</a> (and BLAKE3’s speed really shines through with long messages, due to its extreme parallelism through Merkle trees).</p>



<h3 id="chacha-vs-aes">In Favor of ChaCha over AES</h3>



<p>It’s no secret that <a href="https://soatok.blog/2020/05/13/why-aes-gcm-sucks/">I’m not a fan of AES</a>. It’s not the mathematical properties of AES that bother me, it’s the 128-bit block size and the fact that software implementations have to decide between being fast or being secure.</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="116" data-permalink="https://soatok.blog/soatok_stickerpack-facepaw/" data-orig-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-facepaw.png" data-orig-size="512,512" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Facepaw!" data-image-description="<p>Facepaw!</p>
" data-medium-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-facepaw.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-facepaw.png?w=512" src="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-facepaw.png?w=512" alt="Facepaw" srcset="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-facepaw.png 512w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-facepaw.png?w=150 150w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-facepaw.png?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px"><figcaption>Me, whenever I find an insecure software AES implementation. (Art by <a href="https://twitter.com/lynxvsjackalope">Khia</a>.)</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>ChaCha’s 256-bit security level is easier to justify: The underlying PRF state is 512 bits (which implies an approximately 256-bit security level) and the keys are always 256 bits.</p>



<p><s>Furthermore, if you’re building ChaCha and BLAKE3 in the same codebase, you could reuse some components (i.e. the compression function, G). This is very desirable if you’re trying to ship a small amount of code (e.g. embedded systems).</s> EDIT: <a href="https://twitter.com/veorq">One of the BLAKE3 authors</a> informed me that I’m mistaken about this: “[N]ope, not exactly the same logic (rotations in different direction)”.</p>



<h3 id="other-desirable-properties">Other Desirable Security Properties</h3>



<h4 id="nonces">Nonce Nonsense</h4>



<p>One of the biggest problems with standard AEAD modes is that they explode gloriously when you reuse a nonce. There are two ways out of this peril:</p>



<ol><li>Use a nonce misuse resistant AEAD construction (AES-GCM-SIV, etc.).<ul><li>For prior art on nonce-misuse resistant cipher modes based on ChaCha, check out <a href="https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/067">DAENCE</a>.</li></ul></li><li>Use large nonces (e.g. XChaCha20 uses 192-bit nonces) and generate them randomly, so the probability of nonce reuse becomes negligible.</li></ol>



<p>Since we’re already planning on using a hash function to derive subkeys (one for encryption, one for authentication), it makes sense to also accept a longer nonce than our stream cipher demands. The excess bytes can be passed to our KDF without significant risk or additional overhead.</p>



<p>Since the IETF’s ChaCha20 variant expects a 96-bit nonce, designing our construction to support 256-bit nonces means we can pass the first 160 bits of the nonce to the KDF and the latter 96 bits to the stream cipher. You can expect a single KDF collision after 2^80 encryptions, but it will almost certainly occur with a different nonce.</p>



<h4 id="safe-mac-canonicalization">Safe MAC Canonicalization</h4>



<p>We want to ensure it’s …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://soatok.blog/2020/09/09/designing-new-cryptography-for-non-standard-threat-models/">https://soatok.blog/2020/09/09/designing-new-cryptography-for-non-standard-threat-models/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://soatok.blog/2020/09/09/designing-new-cryptography-for-non-standard-threat-models/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24421073</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 14:03:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: XML Fiddler – tool for quick XML exploration]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 59 | Comments 17 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24419947">thread link</a>) | @masa331
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://masa331.github.io/xml_fiddler/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://masa331.github.io/xml_fiddler/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://masa331.github.io/xml_fiddler/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24419947</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 11:45:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Most annoying website features I face as a blind person]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 9 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24419169">thread link</a>) | @gostsamo
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://bighack.org/5-most-annoying-website-features-i-face-as-a-blind-screen-reader-user-accessibility/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bighack.org/5-most-annoying-website-features-i-face-as-a-blind-screen-reader-user-accessibility/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p><span>These are the five most annoying inaccessible web elements I face as a blind screen reader user every day, and how to fix them.
</span>
					</p><div>
						<p><span>For blind and visually impaired people like me, accessibility is the difference between us being able to use a website and clicking off it.&nbsp;</span></p>
<h2>How screen readers work</h2>
<p><span>Screen readers allow blind and visually impaired people to use computers, phones and tablets independently. Most screen readers use software, and a Text To Speech (TTS) engine, which is what converts the text from the screen reader into speech. Screen readers convert the text displayed on screen into a format that blind users can process.</span></p>
<p><span>Screen readers read out loud everything that’s on the screen and allow people to navigate using touch gestures and shortcut keys. They also work with other output devices such as a braille display.</span></p>
<p><span>As a screen reader user, here are the most common issues I encounter on a daily basis.&nbsp;</span></p>
<h2>Unlabelled links and buttons</h2>
<p><span>Screen reader users rely on links and buttons to navigate around a website and to find the information we need. If links and buttons are not labelled correctly or if at all, then it makes it difficult for screen reader users to find the information they need. Ultimately, unlabelled links make it much harder to navigate the website easily, quickly and independently.</span></p>
<p><span>For example, when linking to an about page, ‘click here’ doesn’t give any clue as to where it leads to, but ‘find out more about who we are’ is clear.</span></p>
<p><span>If links and buttons are labelled correctly, screen readers can read the label out loud. It means that blind and visually impaired people don’t have to press the link or button without knowing where it will take them.</span></p>
<p><span>As well as unlabelled elements, links and buttons that do not have a clear description are also really frustrating. They must have a clear description of where they will lead to when pressed, rather than ‘click here’. Never make your users guess where a link will take them or force them into a trial-and-error situation. This makes for tedious user experience.</span></p>
<h2>No image descriptions</h2>
<p><span>This is probably the most common issue I encounter when browsing the web.&nbsp;</span><span>Using image descriptions is essential for accessibility. Image descriptions are also known as alt text (alternative text) which is a written description of an image.</span></p>
<p><span>Screen readers read image descriptions out loud. This means that blind and visually impaired people can understand the content of the image in an accessible way.&nbsp;</span><span>If images do not have alt text, then screen readers will simply say “image” or “graphic” which gives no context or meaning.</span></p>
<p><span>Images often convey valuable information. It’s therefore important that people with a visual impairment can access this information as well.&nbsp;</span><span>Alt text should be clearly written and give an accurate description of the image.</span></p>
<p><strong>Check out <a href="https://bighack.org/how-to-write-better-alt-text-descriptions-for-accessibility/">our tips for writing better alt text</a> to ensure your images are fully accessible.</strong></p>
<h2>Poor use of headings</h2>
<p><span>For quick and easy navigation, many screen reader users navigate using various elements on the page such as headings. They are a great way to find the information we need quickly and effectively. Especially when they follow a logical heading structure with H1s, H2s and H3s helping to prioritise the content.</span></p>
<p><img src="https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x.jpg" alt="Logical heading structure begins with Heading 1, with Heading 2 sitting beneath heading 1. Heading 3 sits within heading 2 and so on." width="1958" height="1236" srcset="https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x.jpg 1958w, https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x-300x189.jpg 300w, https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x-768x485.jpg 768w, https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x-1536x970.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1958px) 100vw, 1958px" data-srcset="https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x.jpg 1958w, https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x-300x189.jpg 300w, https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x-768x485.jpg 768w, https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x-1536x970.jpg 1536w" data-src="https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x.jpg" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></p>
<p><span>If websites don’t use headings, it means screen reader users are unable to use the keyboard shortcuts to navigate through the webpage this way. If that’s the case, we have to resort to tabbing or arrowing through a long web page to find the information we need.</span></p>
<p>Headings also help to break up the web content visually and improve readability. Other elements that screen reader users use to navigate webpages include links, lists or landmarks.</p>
<h2>Inaccessible web forms</h2>
<p><span>Most websites use forms in one way or another. Whether it’s to help you search for a product or to get in touch through a contact form. However, when these forms are not labelled, or not labelled correctly, it means we cannot use them.</span></p>
<p><span>For example, if a search box is not labelled, it means screen reader users have no idea of the purpose of that box. It means people who use screen readers cannot access the same functionality.</span></p>
<p><span>Contact forms are an effective way for customers to get in touch with your brand or business. And as a screen reader user, there’s nothing more frustrating than these forms being labelled incorrectly.</span></p>
<p><span>Especially CAPTCHA checkout requirements. Without an option to hear the audio, it’s not accessible. It means we are unable to fill in the form independently. I often have to enlist help from a sighted person, but this isn’t possible for everyone.</span><b>&nbsp;</b></p>
<h2>Auto-playing audio and video</h2>
<p><span>Most people will know how annoying it is to load a web page with noisy adverts that start playing suddenly. But for screen reader users, it can be even more alarming. When video or audio starts playing automatically, it can drown out the voice of the screen reader. This makes it harder to find the pause or stop buttons.</span></p>
<p><span>(And if these buttons are unlabelled, then it’s practically impossible for me to stop the video quickly which causes extra frustration.) If I’m unable to stop the sound or video, I normally click off.</span></p>
<p><span>The solution? Make sure there’s no auto-playing video or audio when your website loads. If you really want to use video, make sure the audio is muted and the user can pause, stop or hide the media player.</span></p>
<p><span>These issues may seem small to sighted users. But they’re the difference between me being able to use a website independently or not. And they make a huge difference when implemented correctly.</span></p>
					</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bighack.org/5-most-annoying-website-features-i-face-as-a-blind-screen-reader-user-accessibility/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24419169</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 09:39:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How WebAssembly Changes Software Distribution]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 82 | Comments 66 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24419081">thread link</a>) | @ingve
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://desiatov.com/why-webassembly/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://desiatov.com/why-webassembly/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-reactid="51"><p>If you had any experience with Windows and Internet Explorer in the 90s,
quite probably you remember <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ActiveX">ActiveX</a> controls. Most
frequently this involved bulky popups on pages with these controls having to display something
more complex than a few blocks of text.</p>
<p><img src="https://desiatov.com/activex-0f260342e5426a0cc883966575235fe3.gif" alt="Internet Explorer displaying an alert that requires ActiveX controls to be installed"></p>
<p>Or, remember <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Java_applet">Java applets</a>? They became
available in 1995, and later they weren’t limited to just Windows and Internet Explorer. I remember
I had to use Java applets on macOS as recently as 2013, which chronologically is closer to the
present time than the 90s are. (Feeling so old anyway! 👴)</p>
<p>
  <a href="https://desiatov.com/static/java-d07ca75d3ee42f845ec400952480dcd3-86a48.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
  
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="Microsoft's Application and Network Access Portal that displays a warning about user's browser not
allowing Java applets to run" title="" src="https://desiatov.com/static/java-d07ca75d3ee42f845ec400952480dcd3-f8fb9.jpg" srcset="https://desiatov.com/static/java-d07ca75d3ee42f845ec400952480dcd3-e8976.jpg 148w,
https://desiatov.com/static/java-d07ca75d3ee42f845ec400952480dcd3-63df2.jpg 295w,
https://desiatov.com/static/java-d07ca75d3ee42f845ec400952480dcd3-f8fb9.jpg 590w,
https://desiatov.com/static/java-d07ca75d3ee42f845ec400952480dcd3-86a48.jpg 624w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px">
    </span>
  </span>
  
  </a>
    </p>
<p>Seems like ActiveX and Java applets were necessities mostly in the enterprise world, but
Macromedia Flash (later known as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adobe_Flash">Adobe Flash</a>)
was certainly much more widely known to consumers. It was a requirement in the early days of streaming
video (even <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/1/27/7926001/youtube-drops-flash-for-html5-video-default">YouTube required
Flash</a>
to work back then!), but also a major driver in browser gaming in late 2000s and early 2010s.
We certainly could blame Flash for making our browser windows look like this:</p>
<p>
  <a href="https://desiatov.com/static/flash-38961528058b4baa72341cf48381d93c-02110.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
  
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="Browser page warning about Adobe Flash Player not being installed" title="" src="https://desiatov.com/static/flash-38961528058b4baa72341cf48381d93c-f8fb9.jpg" srcset="https://desiatov.com/static/flash-38961528058b4baa72341cf48381d93c-e8976.jpg 148w,
https://desiatov.com/static/flash-38961528058b4baa72341cf48381d93c-63df2.jpg 295w,
https://desiatov.com/static/flash-38961528058b4baa72341cf48381d93c-f8fb9.jpg 590w,
https://desiatov.com/static/flash-38961528058b4baa72341cf48381d93c-02110.jpg 606w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px">
    </span>
  </span>
  
  </a>
    </p>
<p>While ActiveX has seemingly failed to reach a significant adoption, Microsoft made yet another
attempt with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_Silverlight">Silverlight</a>:</p>
<p>
  <a href="https://desiatov.com/static/silverlight-b8600e7fe201dbc24998a9aacecd3684-da6d6.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
  
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="Microsoft Silverlight page with an installation button" title="" src="https://desiatov.com/static/silverlight-b8600e7fe201dbc24998a9aacecd3684-f8fb9.jpg" srcset="https://desiatov.com/static/silverlight-b8600e7fe201dbc24998a9aacecd3684-e8976.jpg 148w,
https://desiatov.com/static/silverlight-b8600e7fe201dbc24998a9aacecd3684-63df2.jpg 295w,
https://desiatov.com/static/silverlight-b8600e7fe201dbc24998a9aacecd3684-f8fb9.jpg 590w,
https://desiatov.com/static/silverlight-b8600e7fe201dbc24998a9aacecd3684-da6d6.jpg 831w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px">
    </span>
  </span>
  
  </a>
    </p>
<p>In the meantime, Google was working on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Native_Client">its own thing for
Chrome</a>:</p>
<p>
  <a href="https://desiatov.com/static/chrome_nacl-14dd7527a35d3d99235e94e99ca4ae06-5d9c9.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
  
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="Google Native Client plug-in settings in the Chrome browser" title="" src="https://desiatov.com/static/chrome_nacl-14dd7527a35d3d99235e94e99ca4ae06-fb8a0.png" srcset="https://desiatov.com/static/chrome_nacl-14dd7527a35d3d99235e94e99ca4ae06-1a291.png 148w,
https://desiatov.com/static/chrome_nacl-14dd7527a35d3d99235e94e99ca4ae06-2bc4a.png 295w,
https://desiatov.com/static/chrome_nacl-14dd7527a35d3d99235e94e99ca4ae06-fb8a0.png 590w,
https://desiatov.com/static/chrome_nacl-14dd7527a35d3d99235e94e99ca4ae06-5d9c9.png 650w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px">
    </span>
  </span>
  
  </a>
    </p>
<p>It would be fair to say that these attempts failed to establish wide adoption, especially
after both consumers and businesses started shifting to mobile. Here’s how all these forays ended
according to Wikipedia:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Microsoft dropped ActiveX support from the Windows Store edition of Internet Explorer 10 in
Windows 8. In 2015 Microsoft released Microsoft Edge, the replacement for Internet Explorer with
no support for ActiveX, this marked the end of the technology in Microsoft’s web browser
development.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><small><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=ActiveX&amp;oldid=969259090#Platform_support">“ActiveX”</a>
article on Wikipedia.</small></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Beginning in 2013, major web browsers began to phase out support for the underlying technology
applets used to run, with applets becoming completely unable to be run by 2015–2017. Java applets
were deprecated since Java 9 in 2017 and removed from Java SE 11 (18.9), released in September
2018.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><small><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Java_applet&amp;oldid=972322018">“Java applet”</a>
article on Wikipedia.</small></p>
<blockquote>
<p>In July 2017, Adobe announced that it would declare Flash to be end-of-life at the end of 2020,
and will cease support, distribution, and security updates for Flash Player.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><small><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adobe_Flash#End_of_life">“Adobe Flash”</a> article on
Wikipedia.</small></p>
<blockquote>
<p>There is no Silverlight plugin available for Microsoft Edge. It has not been supported by Google
Chrome since September 2015 or by Firefox since March 2017.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><small><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_Silverlight#Demise">“Microsoft Silverlight”</a>
article on Wikipedia.</small></p>
<blockquote>
<p>On October 12, 2016, a comment on the Chromium issue tracker indicated that Google’s Pepper and
Native Client teams had been destaffed.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><small><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Google_Native_Client&amp;oldid=973604804">“Google Native
Client”</a> article on
Wikipedia.</small></p>
<h2>But JavaScript solved all these problems, didn’t it?</h2>
<p>Most of these browser add-ons were introduced before modern JavaScript and HTML5 became available,
so one could argue you no longer need browser add-ons at all. Well, <a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2017/06/27/web-without-javascript">some
purists</a> even say browsers
should have never supported JavaScript or any scripting whatsoever in the first place. Nevertheless,
there are enough use cases for browser scripting and browser apps in general that are hard to avoid.
When looking at the history of browser plugins in general, it’s hard not to notice a few themes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Distributing productivity apps via browsers is convenient in a lot of cases.</li>
<li>Browser gaming made a lot of sense, especially for casual games.</li>
<li>In both of these scenarios browsers had to display something more complex than text and a few
static images.</li>
</ul>
<p>
  <a href="https://desiatov.com/static/flashelementtd-d00aec3e17cce46cb27a2b1662672bcf-d5c50.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
  
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="Flash Element TD game screenshot with a classic tower defense battle field" title="" src="https://desiatov.com/static/flashelementtd-d00aec3e17cce46cb27a2b1662672bcf-d5c50.jpg" srcset="https://desiatov.com/static/flashelementtd-d00aec3e17cce46cb27a2b1662672bcf-399a3.jpg 148w,
https://desiatov.com/static/flashelementtd-d00aec3e17cce46cb27a2b1662672bcf-d5c50.jpg 288w" sizes="(max-width: 288px) 100vw, 288px">
    </span>
  </span>
  
  </a>
    </p>
<p><small>The modern casual <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tower_defense">tower defense game genre</a>
arguably was reborn due to the popularity of Adobe Flash and browser gaming, with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flash_Element_TD">Flash Element
TD</a> being a classic example.</small></p>
<p>Even though native apps were (and in many situations still are) objectively better for users, early
browser apps were attempting to build their own ad-hoc app stores before the App Store existed.
You didn’t have to buy a CD with an application and install it and manage it on your disk. You
didn’t have to install updates manually and migrate your data. There was no need to uninstall apps,
you just close a corresponding browser tab and forget about it.</p>
<p>And when browser scripting capabilities became advanced enough, some people started seeing the
allure of making a browser version of their app the only version they provided. Browsers are
cross-platform, aren’t they? Just wrap your JavaScript app code in a browser-like container (say
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electron_(software_framework)">Electron</a>) and distribute that instead
of your native app. </p>
<p>But eventually not only the JavaScript APIs became more complex, the language itself could no longer
accommodate what developers wanted. Not everyone liked JavaScript syntax (remember
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CoffeeScript">CoffeeScript</a>?) or semantics (I couldn’t help but
notice that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TypeScript">TypeScript</a> has grown in popularity in recent
years). But it’s hard to transpile an arbitrary programming language to JavaScript, the latter was
not built with that goal in mind.</p>
<p>Corollary, the JavaScript interpreter itself has both memory and performance overhead. Having a
garbage collector built in makes it even harder to transpile languages with different memory models
to JavaScript. The allure of having only one language to write all your apps for all platforms is
still there, but why do you have to be confined to JavaScript itself, even as a target language?</p>
<h2>How WebAssembly actually started</h2>
<p>With the death of browser plugins, at least we can praise the interoperability efforts of browser
vendors. Some lowest common denominator of JavaScript is supported in all browsers, and there is a
clear incentive for the vendors to keep up. With the demand to go beyond JavaScript, there were
initial attempts to support low level programming with asm.js in 2013:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Much of this performance gain over normal JavaScript [with asm.js was] due to 100% type consistency
and virtually no garbage collection (memory is manually managed in a large typed array).</p>
</blockquote>
<p><small><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Asm.js">“asm.js”</a> article on Wikipedia.</small></p>
<p>Syntactically this still looked pretty much like JavaScript, but when you have a lot of low level code,
the resulting file can get big pretty quickly, and the size of your code is pretty important when your
users download it frequently. As you weren’t supposed to write asm.js code manually most of the time,
and it was designed primarily as compilation target, it made sense to invent a binary format for it.
That’s basically how WebAssembly started:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>WebAssembly was first announced in 2015, and the first demonstration was executing Unity’s Angry
Bots in Firefox, Google Chrome, and Microsoft Edge. The precursor technologies were asm.js from
Mozilla and Google Native Client, and the initial implementation was based on the feature set of
asm.js.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><small><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WebAssembly#History">“WebAssembly”</a> article on
Wikipedia.</small></p>
<p>
  <a href="https://desiatov.com/static/angrybots-af143aa014afd3462b9ef4d25875af9f-5b672.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
  
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="Angry Bots is a 3rd-person shooter demo that features a marine-like character that walks
through some futuristic research base and defends from suicidal four-legged robots" title="" src="https://desiatov.com/static/angrybots-af143aa014afd3462b9ef4d25875af9f-fb8a0.png" srcset="https://desiatov.com/static/angrybots-af143aa014afd3462b9ef4d25875af9f-1a291.png 148w,
https://desiatov.com/static/angrybots-af143aa014afd3462b9ef4d25875af9f-2bc4a.png 295w,
https://desiatov.com/static/angrybots-af143aa014afd3462b9ef4d25875af9f-fb8a0.png 590w,
https://desiatov.com/static/angrybots-af143aa014afd3462b9ef4d25875af9f-526de.png 885w,
https://desiatov.com/static/angrybots-af143aa014afd3462b9ef4d25875af9f-fa2eb.png 1180w,
https://desiatov.com/static/angrybots-af143aa014afd3462b9ef4d25875af9f-08f6a.png 1770w,
https://desiatov.com/static/angrybots-af143aa014afd3462b9ef4d25875af9f-5b672.png 2567w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px">
    </span>
  </span>
  
  </a>
    </p>
<p><small>Angry Bots is still available to play on the <a href="https://beta.unity3d.com/jonas/AngryBots/">Unity
website</a>.</small></p>
<h2>What WebAssembly got right</h2>
<p>Now you’re no longer restricted to JavaScript as a target language for browser apps. As soon as
<a href="https://llvm.org/">LLVM</a> got WebAssembly backend more or less ready, it allowed compilers built
on top of LLVM (for C, C++, Rust, Swift and many more) to adopt it without rewriting everything from
scratch. This unlocked the browser environment to a huge amount of pre-existing software that can
also run close to native speed if optimized well.</p>
<p>Not only can you run fun little projects such as <a href="https://sandspiel.club/">Sandspiel</a> and
<a href="https://orb.farm/">orb.farm</a> in your browser tab, but complex games such as <a href="https://www.continuation-labs.com/projects/d3wasm/">Doom
3</a> (at least its demo version) are available too.
Both <a href="https://blogs.unity3d.com/2018/08/15/webassembly-is-here/">Unity</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/unrealengine/status/932624595722559490">Unreal
Engine</a> announced their support for
WebAssembly, and while we may not see AAA games running in browsers on their initial release date,
this still gives enough confidence in the maturity of the platform.</p>
<p>
  <a href="https://desiatov.com/static/orbfarm-d5127e6241542d4c77ee0faf5d5e8d41-9c30a.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
  
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="A pixel-art spherical fish tank filled with water, sand, algae, daphnia and fish." title="" src="https://desiatov.com/static/orbfarm-d5127e6241542d4c77ee0faf5d5e8d41-fb8a0.png" srcset="https://desiatov.com/static/orbfarm-d5127e6241542d4c77ee0faf5d5e8d41-1a291.png 148w,
https://desiatov.com/static/orbfarm-d5127e6241542d4c77ee0faf5d5e8d41-2bc4a.png 295w,
https://desiatov.com/static/orbfarm-d5127e6241542d4c77ee0faf5d5e8d41-fb8a0.png 590w,
https://desiatov.com/static/orbfarm-d5127e6241542d4c77ee0faf5d5e8d41-526de.png 885w,
https://desiatov.com/static/orbfarm-d5127e6241542d4c77ee0faf5d5e8d41-fa2eb.png 1180w,
https://desiatov.com/static/orbfarm-d5127e6241542d4c77ee0faf5d5e8d41-08f6a.png 1770w,
https://desiatov.com/static/orbfarm-d5127e6241542d4c77ee0faf5d5e8d41-9c30a.png 3730w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px">
    </span>
  </span>
  
  </a>
    </p>
<p><small>According to its creator, <a href="https://orb.farm/">orb.farm</a> is “a virtual ecosystem where different
species of creature can live, grow and die as part of a self-contained food chain”.</small></p>
<p>It’s obviously not limited to games, as we can see Apple folks compiling their <a href="https://twitter.com/lrz/status/1250453967957561344">C++ and Objective-C
code from iWork</a> to Wasm<sup id="fnref-1"><a href="#fn-1">1</a></sup>, or
<a href="https://1password.com/">1Password</a> using it in their browser extension getting substantial
performance improvements as a result:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>With our move to WebAssembly, page filling and analysis now runs at least twice as fast as before,
and those websites with a large number of fields are up to 13x faster in Chrome and up to 39x
faster in Firefox! It’s blazing fast. 🔥</p>
</blockquote>
<p><small><a href="https://blog.1password.com/1password-x-may-2019-update/">“1Password X: May 2019 update”</a>
article on <a href="https://blog.1password.com/">the 1Password blog</a>.</small></p>
<h2>Wasm is a general purpose virtual machine</h2>
<p>Not only you get performance improvements with WebAssembly compared to JavaScript, as it was
designed to run arbitrary code in your browser, it’s one of the most widely available secure sandbox
environments. And as a general purpose virtual machine, Wasm is not limited only to browsers.
<a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/">Cloudflare</a> uses it for edge computing on their CDN:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We’re excited by the possibilities that WebAssembly opens up. Perhaps, by integrating with
Cloudflare Spectrum, we could allow existing C/C++ server code to handle arbitrary TCP and UDP
protocols on the edge, like a sort of massively-distributed inetd. Perhaps game servers could
reduce latency by running on Cloudflare, as close to the player as possible. Maybe, with the help
of some GPUs and OpenGL bindings, you could do 3D rendering and real-time streaming directly from
the edge.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><small><a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/webassembly-on-cloudflare-workers/">“WebAssembly on Cloudflare
Workers”</a> on <a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/">the Cloudflare
blog</a>.</small></p>
<p>With people realizing the wide applicability of the Wasm tech stack, it was no surprise when
<a href="https://wasi.dev/">WASI</a> (stands for WebAssembly System Interface) appeared. Where WebAssembly
itself is a “bare metal” platform, it does not supply any primitives such as memory allocation or
filesystem access, which WASI does provide. As Solomon Hykes, creator of Docker, <a href="https://twitter.com/solomonstre/status/1111004913222324225">puts
it</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If WASM+WASI existed in 2008, we wouldn’t have needed to created Docker. That’s how important it
is. Webassembly on the server is the future of computing. A standardized system …</p></blockquote></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://desiatov.com/why-webassembly/">https://desiatov.com/why-webassembly/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://desiatov.com/why-webassembly/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24419081</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 09:26:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why Bayesian Stats Needs Monte-Carlo Methods]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 177 | Comments 96 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24416908">thread link</a>) | @laplacesdemon48
<br/>
September 8, 2020 | https://www.countbayesie.com/blog/2020/8/16/why-bayesian-stats-need-monte-carlo-methods | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.countbayesie.com/blog/2020/8/16/why-bayesian-stats-need-monte-carlo-methods">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site">
		<div id="canvas">

			<!-- / headerWrapper -->

			<div id="pageWrapper" role="main">
				<section id="page" data-content-field="main-content">
					<article id="article-5f3999dd551f15457784cec9" data-item-id="5f3999dd551f15457784cec9">

	<div>
  <!--SPECIAL CONTENT-->

    

    <div>

    <!--POST HEADER-->

			<header>
				
				
			</header>

    <!--POST BODY-->

      <div><div data-layout-label="Post Body" data-type="item" data-updated-on="1597610547002" id="item-5f3999dd551f15457784cec9"><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-ce72701dbc5d55959e37"><div><div><p>This post emerged from a series of question surrounding a Twitter comment that brought up some very interesting points about how Bayesian Hypothesis testing works and the inability of analytic solutions to solve even some seemingly trivial problems in Bayesian statistics. </p><p>Comparing Beta distributed random variables is something that comes up pretty frequently on this blog (and in my book as well). The set up is fairly straight forward: model an A/B test as sampling from two beta distributions, sample from each distribution a lot, then compare the results.</p><p>This simulation approach often first appears as a clever little trick to solve a more complex math problem, but in fact is a primative form of Monte-Carlo Integration and turns out to one of the only ways to really solve this problem. By exploring this topic deeper in this post we'll see some of the myths that many people have about analytic solutions as well as demonstrating why Monte-carlo methods are so essential to Bayesian statistics.</p></div><h2>Background: A conversation about election results</h2><div><p>An interesting conversation happened on Twitter recently. It started with a retweet of mine regarding Nate Silver (well know author and election forecaster) posting his latest predictions for the 2020 presidential election showing that Biden has a 71% probability of winning versus Trump's 29%</p></div></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_4659"><div><div><p>After the last election there was quite a lot of criticism about Nate Silver's forecasting since his company (538) predicted that <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/2016-election-forecast/">Hilary Clinton would win with a probability of 71%</a> in the 2016 presidential election.</p><p>This criticism has always annoyed me personally since, in statistical terms, 71% is generally not considered a strong belief in anything. So it is not inconsistent, nor suprising for someone to believe a candidate has 71% chance of success and they still lose. Even when looking at typical p-values, we wait for 95% percent certainty before making claims (and many feel this is a pretty weak belief). But for some reason whenever election polls come up, it seems even very statistically minded people suddenly think that 51% chance is a high probability.</p><p>I retweeted Nate Silver's forecast, mentioned my annoyance and provided an example of another case with a similar probability of winning:</p></div></div></div><div data-block-json="{&quot;cache_age&quot;:&quot;3153600000&quot;,&quot;authorUrl&quot;:&quot;https://twitter.com/willkurt&quot;,&quot;width&quot;:550,&quot;height&quot;:null,&quot;hSize&quot;:null,&quot;resolveObject&quot;:&quot;Tweet&quot;,&quot;html&quot;:&quot;<blockquote class=\&quot;twitter-tweet\&quot;><p dir=\&quot;ltr\&quot; lang=\&quot;en\&quot;>This time can we all remember that rarely in statistics would we judge P(H|D) = 0.71 as a strong belief in anything. <br><br>For comparison if in an A/B test we had these results:<br><br>A has 2 successes in 15 trials<br>B has 3 successes in 14 trials<br><br>This roughly how strong our belief in B is <a href=\&quot;https://t.co/bB4PiB5Tao\&quot;>https://t.co/bB4PiB5Tao</a></p>\u2014 Will Kurt (@willkurt) <a href=\&quot;https://twitter.com/willkurt/status/1293575032975884288?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw\&quot;>August 12, 2020</a></blockquote>\n<script async=\&quot;\&quot; src=\&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js\&quot; charset=\&quot;utf-8\&quot;></script>&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;https://twitter.com/willkurt/status/1293575032975884288&quot;,&quot;resolvedBy&quot;:&quot;twitter&quot;,&quot;floatDir&quot;:null,&quot;authorName&quot;:&quot;Will Kurt&quot;,&quot;version&quot;:&quot;1.0&quot;,&quot;resolved&quot;:true,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;rich&quot;,&quot;providerName&quot;:&quot;Twitter&quot;,&quot;providerUrl&quot;:&quot;https://twitter.com&quot;}" data-block-type="22" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_6372"><div><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>This time can we all remember that rarely in statistics would we judge P(H|D) = 0.71 as a strong belief in anything. </p><p>For comparison if in an A/B test we had these results:</p><p>A has 2 successes in 15 trials<br>B has 3 successes in 14 trials</p><p>This roughly how strong our belief in B is <a href="https://t.co/bB4PiB5Tao">https://t.co/bB4PiB5Tao</a></p></div>— Will Kurt (@willkurt) <a href="https://twitter.com/willkurt/status/1293575032975884288?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 12, 2020</a></blockquote>
</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_6436"><div><div><p>If you were running an A/B test and your A variant had 2 success in 15 trials and your B variant had 3 successes in 14 trails, you would be roughly 71% confident that B was the superior variant.</p><p>Even someone without much statistical training would likely be very skeptical of such a claim, but somehow during election forecasts even experience statisticians can look at Silver's post and think that Biden winning is a sure thing.</p></div><h2> How do we arrive at P(B &gt; A)?</h2><p><br>Twitter user <a href="https://twitter.com/mbarras_ing">@mbarras_ing</a> ask a really important follow up question, asking to explain this result:</p></div></div><div data-block-json="{&quot;cache_age&quot;:&quot;3153600000&quot;,&quot;authorUrl&quot;:&quot;https://twitter.com/mbarras_ing&quot;,&quot;width&quot;:550,&quot;height&quot;:null,&quot;hSize&quot;:null,&quot;resolveObject&quot;:&quot;Tweet&quot;,&quot;html&quot;:&quot;<blockquote class=\&quot;twitter-tweet\&quot;><p dir=\&quot;ltr\&quot; lang=\&quot;en\&quot;>I may be a bit slow but could you elaborate on how that is? How would one compute 0.71, from the info \&quot;A has 2 successes in 15 trials, B has 3 successes in 14 trials\&quot;?</p>\u2014 Matthew Rhys Barras (@mbarras_ing) <a href=\&quot;https://twitter.com/mbarras_ing/status/1293928326579589121?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw\&quot;>August 13, 2020</a></blockquote>\n<script async=\&quot;\&quot; src=\&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js\&quot; charset=\&quot;utf-8\&quot;></script>&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;https://twitter.com/mbarras_ing/status/1293928326579589121&quot;,&quot;resolvedBy&quot;:&quot;twitter&quot;,&quot;floatDir&quot;:null,&quot;authorName&quot;:&quot;Matthew Rhys Barras&quot;,&quot;version&quot;:&quot;1.0&quot;,&quot;resolved&quot;:true,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;rich&quot;,&quot;providerName&quot;:&quot;Twitter&quot;,&quot;providerUrl&quot;:&quot;https://twitter.com&quot;}" data-block-type="22" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_7791"><div><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">I may be a bit slow but could you elaborate on how that is? How would one compute 0.71, from the info "A has 2 successes in 15 trials, B has 3 successes in 14 trials"?</p>— Matthew Rhys Barras (@mbarras_ing) <a href="https://twitter.com/mbarras_ing/status/1293928326579589121?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 13, 2020</a></blockquote>
</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_7855"><div><div><p>I very strongly believe that all statistics, even quick off the cuff estimates, should be reproducible and explainable.</p><p>I've written a fair bit about approaching similar problems both <a href="https://www.countbayesie.com/blog/2015/4/25/bayesian-ab-testing">on this blog</a> and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bayesian-Statistics-Fun-Will-Kurt/dp/1593279566">in my book</a>. The big picture is that we're going to come up with parameter estimates for the rate that A and B convert users and then compute the probability that B is greater than A. </p><p>Since we're estimating conversion rates we're going to use <a href="https://www.countbayesie.com/blog/2015/3/17/interrogating-probability-distributions">the Beta distribution</a> as the distribution of our parameter estimate. In this example I'm also assume a \(\text{Beta}(1,1)\) prior for our A and B variants.</p><p>The likelihood for A is \(\text{Beta}(2,13)\) and for B is \(\text{Beta}(3,11)\) so we can represent A and B as two random variables samples form these posteriors:</p><p>$$A \sim \text{Beta}(2+1, 13+1)$$<br>$$B \sim \text{Beta}(3+1,11+1)$$</p></div><p>We can now represent this in R, and sample from these distributions:</p></div></div><div data-block-type="23" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_9136"><div><pre><span>N</span> <span>&lt;</span><span>-</span> <span>10000</span>
<span>a_samples</span> <span>&lt;</span><span>-</span> <span>rbeta</span>(<span>N</span>,<span>2</span><span>+</span><span>1</span>,<span>13</span><span>+</span><span>1</span>)
<span>b_samples</span> <span>&lt;</span><span>-</span> <span>rbeta</span>(<span>N</span>,<span>3</span><span>+</span><span>1</span>,<span>11</span><span>+</span><span>1</span>)</pre></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_9202"><p>And finally we can look at the results of this to compute the probability that B is greater than A:</p></div><div data-block-type="23" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_10612"><div><pre><span>sum</span>(<span>b_samples</span> <span>&gt;</span> <span>a_samples</span>)<span>/</span><span>N</span></pre></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_10678"><div><p>In this case we get 0.7028 pretty close to 71% for Nate Silver’s problem.</p><h2><p>Can we solve this without R?</p></h2><p><br>This explains where we get our probabilities from, but there is an obvious question that comes up when you see this result, one raised by <a href="https://twitter.com/little_rocko">@little_rocko</a></p></div></div><div data-block-json="{&quot;cache_age&quot;:&quot;3153600000&quot;,&quot;authorUrl&quot;:&quot;https://twitter.com/little_rocko&quot;,&quot;width&quot;:550,&quot;height&quot;:null,&quot;hSize&quot;:null,&quot;resolveObject&quot;:&quot;Tweet&quot;,&quot;html&quot;:&quot;<blockquote class=\&quot;twitter-tweet\&quot;><p dir=\&quot;ltr\&quot; lang=\&quot;en\&quot;>this is an awesome example. is there an easy way (as in non-brute force) to finding the beta parameters that'll match a probability?</p>\u2014 Rocko (@little_rocko) <a href=\&quot;https://twitter.com/little_rocko/status/1294938572299018242?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw\&quot;>August 16, 2020</a></blockquote>\n<script async=\&quot;\&quot; src=\&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js\&quot; charset=\&quot;utf-8\&quot;></script>&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;https://twitter.com/little_rocko/status/1294938572299018242&quot;,&quot;resolvedBy&quot;:&quot;twitter&quot;,&quot;floatDir&quot;:null,&quot;authorName&quot;:&quot;Rocko&quot;,&quot;version&quot;:&quot;1.0&quot;,&quot;resolved&quot;:true,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;rich&quot;,&quot;providerName&quot;:&quot;Twitter&quot;,&quot;providerUrl&quot;:&quot;https://twitter.com&quot;}" data-block-type="22" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_12117"><div><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">this is an awesome example. is there an easy way (as in non-brute force) to finding the beta parameters that'll match a probability?</p>— Rocko (@little_rocko) <a href="https://twitter.com/little_rocko/status/1294938572299018242?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 16, 2020</a></blockquote>
</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_12181"><div><div><p>This question is interesting because it asks two questions that don't necessarily have to be related:</p><p>- is there an easy way to solve this<br>- is there a non-"brute force" way solve this</p><p>Before moving on I want to mention that this little snippet of R involves a lot more abstraction then it seems at first glance. What we are really doing here is equalivant to using a Monte-Carlo simulation to integrate over the distribution of the difference between two Beta distributed random variables. After the next two sections it will be more clear that what's happening here is a surprisingly sophisticated operation that is, in my opinion, the easiest method of solving this problem as well as not truly a brute force solution.</p></div><h2><br>Analytic versus Easy</h2><div><p>When we see computational solutions to mathematical problems our first instinct is typically to feel that we are avoiding solving the problem <em>analytically.</em> An analytical solution is one that uses mathematical analysis to find a closed form solution.</p><p>A strivial example, suppose I wanted to find the value that minimized \(f(x) = (x+3)^2\)</p><p>In R I could brute force this by looking over a range of answers like this:</p></div></div></div><div data-block-type="23" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_13626"><div><pre><span>f</span> <span>&lt;</span><span>-</span> <span>function</span>(<span>x</span>){  
  (<span>x</span><span>+</span><span>3</span>)<span>^</span><span>2</span>
}
<span>xs</span> <span>&lt;</span><span>-</span> <span>seq</span>(<span>-</span><span>6</span>,<span>6</span>,<span>by</span><span>=</span><span>0.031</span>)
<span>xs</span>[<span>which</span>.<span>min</span>(<span>f</span>(<span>xs</span>))]</pre></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_13692"><div><div><p>As expected we get our answer of -3, but this solution takes a bit of work: we need to know how to code and we need a computer. It's also a bit messy because if we had iterated by an incredment that didn't include -3 exactly (say by 0.031) we would not get the exact answer.</p><p>If we know some basic calculus we know that our minimum has to be where the derivative is at 0. We can very easily work out that</p><p>$$f'(x) = 2(x+3)$$<br>And that</p><p>$$2(x + 3) = 0 $$</p><p>When</p><p>$$ x = -3 $$</p><p>Knowning basic calculus this later solution becomes much easier. </p><p>But even with the calculus is part is hard, often solving it once makes future solutions much easier. Take for example if you wanted to find the maximum likelihood for a normal distribution with a mean of \(\mu\) and standard deviation of \(\sigma\)</p><p>To solve this we start with our PDF for the normal distribution \(\varphi\):</p><p>$$\varphi(x) = \frac{1}{\sigma \sqrt{2\pi}}e^{-\frac{1}{2}(\frac{x-\mu}{\sigma})^2}$$</p><p>Now computing the derivative of this is not necessarily "easy" but it's certainly something we can do. All we really care about is when</p><p>$$\varphi'(x) = 0$$</p><p>Which we can find out happens when (computing the deriviative of course is left as an exercise for the reader):</p><p>$$\frac{\mu-x}{\sigma}$$</p></div><div><p>This allows us to reallize the amazing fact that for any normal distribution we come across, we know that the maximum likelihood estimate is the sample is when \(x = \mu\)!</p><p>Even though our calculus might take us a bit of work, once this is done the problem of doing maximum likelihood estimation for any Normal distribution truly does become easy!</p></div><h3><br>Proposing an Analytic solution to our problem</h3><div><p>Let's revisit our original problem this time attempting to find an analytic solution. This is a very interesting case because arguably this is the simplest Bayesian hypothesis test you can imagine.</p><p>Recall that we have two random variable representing our beliefs in each test. These are distributed according the the posterior which we described earlier.</p><p>$$A \sim \text{Beta}(2+1, 13+1)$$<br>$$B \sim \text{Beta}(3+1,11+1)$$</p><p>Here is where I skipped some steps in reasoning. What we want to know is:</p><p>$$P(B &gt;A)$$</p></div><div><p>Which is not expressed in a particularly useful mathematical way. A better way to solve this is to consider this as the sum (or difference in this case) of two random variables. What we really want to know is:</p><p>$$P(B - A &gt; 0)$$</p><p>In order to solve this problem we can think of a new random variable \(X\) which is going to be the difference between B and A:</p><p>$$X = B - A$$</p><p>Finally we'll suppose we have a probability density function for \(X\) we'll call \(\text{pdf}_X\). If we know \(\text{pdf}_X\) our solution is pretty close, we just need to integrate between 0 and the max domain of this distribution:</p><p>$$P(B &gt; A) = P(B - A &gt; 0) = \int_{x=0}^{\text{max}}\text{pdf}_{X}(x)$$</p><p>Already this is starting to look a bit complicated, but there's one big problem ahead. Unlike Normally distributed random variables, we have no equivalent of the Normal sum theorem (we'll cover this in a bit) for Beta distributed random variables. </p><p>What does \(\text{pdf}_X\) look like? For starters we know it's not a Beta distribution itself. We can see this because we know the domain (or support) of this distribution is not \([0,1]\). Because they are Beta distributed, A and B can both take on values from 0 to 1, which means the maximum result of this difference is 1 but the minimum is -1. So whatever this distribution is, its domain is \([-1,1]\) meaning it cannot be a Beta distribution.</p><p>We can use various rules about sum of random variables to determine the mean and variance of this distribution, but without knowing the exact form of this distribution we are unable to solve the integral analytically. </p><p>Here we can see that even in this profoundly simple problem the analytical solution is frustratingly …</p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></article></section></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.countbayesie.com/blog/2020/8/16/why-bayesian-stats-need-monte-carlo-methods">https://www.countbayesie.com/blog/2020/8/16/why-bayesian-stats-need-monte-carlo-methods</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.countbayesie.com/blog/2020/8/16/why-bayesian-stats-need-monte-carlo-methods</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24416908</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 03:54:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[AMD PSB Vendor Locks EPYC CPUs for Enhanced Security at a Cost]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 337 | Comments 252 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24416005">thread link</a>) | @virgulino
<br/>
September 8, 2020 | https://www.servethehome.com/amd-psb-vendor-locks-epyc-cpus-for-enhanced-security-at-a-cost/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.servethehome.com/amd-psb-vendor-locks-epyc-cpus-for-enhanced-security-at-a-cost/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <!-- image --><div><figure><a href="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/AMD-Platform-Secure-Boot-Feature-Cover.jpg" data-caption="AMD Platform Secure Boot Feature Cover"><img width="696" height="465" src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/AMD-Platform-Secure-Boot-Feature-Cover-696x465.jpg" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/AMD-Platform-Secure-Boot-Feature-Cover-696x465.jpg 696w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/AMD-Platform-Secure-Boot-Feature-Cover-400x268.jpg 400w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/AMD-Platform-Secure-Boot-Feature-Cover-628x420.jpg 628w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/AMD-Platform-Secure-Boot-Feature-Cover.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px" alt="AMD Platform Secure Boot Feature Cover" title="AMD Platform Secure Boot Feature Cover"></a><figcaption>AMD Platform Secure Boot Feature Cover</figcaption></figure></div>
            <!-- content --><p>Today we are going to discuss a change to server security that is going to make waves in the home lab and secondary markets for servers and components in the future. During our recent <a href="https://www.servethehome.com/dell-emc-poweredge-c6525-review-2u4n-amd-epyc-kilo-thread-server/">Dell EMC PowerEdge C6525 review</a> we briefly mentioned that AMD EPYC CPUs in the system are vendor locked to Dell EMC systems. This is not a Dell-specific concern. We have confirmed that other vendors are supporting the feature behind this. For the large vendors, their platform security teams are pushing to build more secure platforms for their customers, and that is going to have future impacts on the secondary server market and home labs.</p>
<p>In this article, we are going to cover the basics of what is happening. We are going to discuss the motivations, and why this is going to be more common in the future. Finally, we are going to discuss what those in the industry can do to keep the secondary server market operating well. If you work with partners or resellers who dip into used parts bins or even have the potential to purchase grey market CPUs, send them this article or accompanying video. The current market has a large disconnect between what some large customers are asking for, and large vendors are delivering on and what others in the market know is happening.<span id="more-46716"></span></p>
<h2>Accompanying Video</h2>
<p>This is an important topic. To ensure that we can cover those who like to read/ skim and those who like to get information via audio, we have an accompanying video:</p>
<p><iframe title="Vendor Locking AMD EPYC CPUs Great for Security at a Cost" width="696" height="392" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kNVuTAVYxpM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Feel free to pop open that video on YouTube and check it out or to send to those who prefer not to read.</p>
<h2>Background: How we learned this was a “thing”</h2>
<p>In 2018 we did a <a href="https://www.servethehome.com/dell-emc-poweredge-r7415-review/">Dell EMC PowerEdge R7415 review</a> and as part of that review, we started our normal process of trying different CPUs in the system. Early in that process, we used an AMD EPYC 7251 CPU, the low-end 8-core model, and noticed something curious. It would not work in our other test systems after.</p>
<p>After a bit of research, we found it was because Dell EMC was vendor locking the chips to Dell systems. We did not know exactly why, but we were told was a security feature. At this point, and even to this day two years later, not every vendor takes advantage of all of the AMD EPYC security features. What that practically means is that what we saw with the Dell EMC system is not what we saw with other systems. For example, we were able to interchangeably use CPUs in Supermicro and Tyan systems, but we could not use those systems once they went into a Dell EMC server.</p>
<figure id="attachment_24514" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-24514"><a href="https://www.servethehome.com/dual-amd-epyc-7251-linux-benchmarks-least-expensive-2p-epyc/amd-epyc-7251-in-socket-and-carrier/" rel="attachment wp-att-24514"><img src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/AMD-EPYC-7251-in-Socket-and-Carrier.jpg" alt="AMD EPYC In Socket And Carrier" width="800" height="533" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/AMD-EPYC-7251-in-Socket-and-Carrier.jpg 800w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/AMD-EPYC-7251-in-Socket-and-Carrier-400x267.jpg 400w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/AMD-EPYC-7251-in-Socket-and-Carrier-696x464.jpg 696w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/AMD-EPYC-7251-in-Socket-and-Carrier-630x420.jpg 630w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-24514">AMD EPYC In Socket And Carrier</figcaption></figure>
<p>We found we were not alone. Laboratories, VARs, and other organizations were finding that transferring AMD EPYC CPUs from one vendor’s system to another, was not the simple process it was on the Intel Xeon side. It did not always work.</p>
<p>We knew it was a security feature and thought that most who are buying servers would be informed of this by their sales reps or channel partners. After I personally got a lot of texts, e-mails, instant messaging, and comments on our C6525 video and article, I realized that this actually may be a situation where many people do not know what is going on.</p>
<figure id="attachment_46531" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-46531"><a href="https://www.servethehome.com/dell-emc-poweredge-c6525-review-2u4n-amd-epyc-kilo-thread-server/dell-emc-poweredge-c6525-internal-view-nodes-partially-out/" rel="attachment wp-att-46531"><img src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Dell-EMC-PowerEdge-C6525-Internal-View-Nodes-Partially-Out.jpg" alt="Dell EMC PowerEdge C6525 Internal View Nodes Partially Out" width="800" height="519" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Dell-EMC-PowerEdge-C6525-Internal-View-Nodes-Partially-Out.jpg 800w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Dell-EMC-PowerEdge-C6525-Internal-View-Nodes-Partially-Out-400x260.jpg 400w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Dell-EMC-PowerEdge-C6525-Internal-View-Nodes-Partially-Out-696x452.jpg 696w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Dell-EMC-PowerEdge-C6525-Internal-View-Nodes-Partially-Out-647x420.jpg 647w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-46531">Dell EMC PowerEdge C6525 Internal View Nodes Partially Out</figcaption></figure>
<p>This experience that we had, apparently is one that is not overly common yet. That makes sense because the systems that utilize the enhanced security levels are still largely new, and being used by their first buyers. Also, AMD still has a smaller market share than Intel. A big reason, by the way, that Intel Xeon does not have this issue is that they do not have the security feature that AMD has. Vendors have come out and stated that their AMD EPYC systems are more secure than their Intel Xeon systems, and this behavior is a byproduct of that enhanced security.</p>
<p>Next, we are going to dive into the feature of AMD processors (and what will be more common in future CPUs from other vendors.)</p>
<h2>AMD EPYC Secure Processor Platform Secure Boot (PSB)</h2>
<p>Let us start with the high-level slide. This is effectively the same slide on the AMD Secure Processor that we saw with the AMD EPYC 7001 series launch, but this is from the EPYC 7002 series. AMD EPYC CPUs may be x86, but they have an embedded Arm Cortex-A5 microcontroller that runs its own OS that is independent of the main system. This AMD Secure Processor is the backbone of AMD’s security push as it provides features such as key management and hardware root of trust for the platform.</p>
<figure id="attachment_36705" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-36705"><a href="https://www.servethehome.com/amd-epyc-7002-series-rome-delivers-a-knockout/amd-epyc-7002-platform-secure-processor/" rel="attachment wp-att-36705"><img src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Processor.jpg" alt="AMD EPYC 7002 Platform Secure Processor" width="1792" height="918" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Processor.jpg 1792w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Processor-400x205.jpg 400w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Processor-800x410.jpg 800w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Processor-696x357.jpg 696w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Processor-1068x547.jpg 1068w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Processor-820x420.jpg 820w" sizes="(max-width: 1792px) 100vw, 1792px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-36705">AMD EPYC 7002 Platform Secure Processor</figcaption></figure>
<p>AMD spends time <a href="https://www.servethehome.com/amd-confirms-cts-labs-exploits-requiring-admin-access/">patching this solution</a>&nbsp;to make it more secure, but it is generally fairly hard to reach without some extremely low-level access in a system. We are going to come back to the “Enables hardware validated boot” line shortly, but it is important to understand that this secure processor underpins many of AMD’s best security features.</p>
<p>For example, at STH we use EPYC’s Secure Memory Encryption and Secure Encrypted Virtualization heavily. With AMD EPYC, we do not have to manually manage keys. Instead, the ephemeral keys are managed for us by the AMD Secure Processor. This is the basis for what is really the building wave of confidential computing offerings such as&nbsp;<a href="https://www.servethehome.com/google-cloud-confidential-computing-enabled-by-amd-epyc-sev/">Google Cloud Confidential Computing Enabled by AMD EPYC SEV</a>. Intel has its secure boot features and SGX that will be enhanced greatly with <a href="https://www.servethehome.com/the-2021-intel-ice-pickle-how-2021-will-be-crunch-time/">Ice Lake Xeons</a>, but for now, AMD has this capability while Intel does not. When big vendors say AMD is more secure, the AMD Secure Processor is a cornerstone of those offerings.</p>
<figure id="attachment_36704" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-36704"><a href="https://www.servethehome.com/amd-epyc-7002-series-rome-delivers-a-knockout/amd-epyc-7002-platform-secure-memory-encryption/" rel="attachment wp-att-36704"><img src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Memory-Encryption.jpg" alt="AMD EPYC 7002 Platform Secure Memory Encryption" width="1769" height="890" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Memory-Encryption.jpg 1769w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Memory-Encryption-400x201.jpg 400w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Memory-Encryption-800x402.jpg 800w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Memory-Encryption-696x350.jpg 696w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Memory-Encryption-1068x537.jpg 1068w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Memory-Encryption-835x420.jpg 835w" sizes="(max-width: 1769px) 100vw, 1769px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-36704">AMD EPYC 7002 Platform Secure Memory Encryption</figcaption></figure>
<p>Let us discuss that “Enables hardware validated boot” line. While traditionally CPUs just fire up in whatever platform they are in, AMD has intelligence in their CPU due to the Arm-based AMD Secure Processor. EPYC CPUs are designed to be a bit more intelligent about the platforms they are in, and interact with server platform security to act as this root of trust that would not be possible if they effectively just booted up in any system.</p>
<p>Here is a statement from AMD describing the AMD Platform Secure Boot.</p>
<p><em>The AMD Platform Secure Boot Feature (PSB) is a mitigation for firmware Advanced Persistent Threats. It is a defense-in-depth feature. PSB extends AMD’s silicon root of trust to protect the OEM’s BIOS.&nbsp; This allows the OEM to establish an unbroken chain of trust from AMD’s silicon root of trust to the OEM’s BIOS using PSB, and then from the OEM’s BIOS to the OS Bootloader using UEFI secure boot. This provides a very powerful defense against remote attackers seeking to embed malware into a platform’s firmware.</em></p>
<p><em>An OEM who trusts only their own cryptographically signed BIOS code to run on their platforms will use a PSB enabled motherboard and set one-time-programmable fuses in the processor to bind the processor to the OEM’s firmware code signing key. AMD processors are shipped unlocked from the factory, and can initially be used with any OEM’s motherboard. But once they are used with a motherboard with PSB enabled, the security fuses will be set, and from that point on, that processor can only be used with motherboards that use the same code signing key. (<strong>Source</strong>: AMD statement to STH)</em></p>
<p>That is a lot to take in. We asked HPE about this. Their response mirrored what the above was describing. HPE firmware, when a system is first turned on, performs this binding process where the AMD EPYC CPU expects to see HPE signed firmware. If you alter the HPE firmware on the system, the check fails and the system will not work. That means if your HPE motherboard fails, you can replace it and put your CPU in another HPE motherboard with signed HPE firmware. It also means if the server platform’s firmware is not signed by HPE, the processor will see it as evidence of tampering and not work.</p>
<p><strong>Edit: 2020-09-09</strong> – HPE clarified that they are doing this in a different manner than Dell after initially confirming that they were using the AMD PSB feature. After this went live, HPE sent us the following:</p>
<p><em>HPE does not use the same security technique that Dell is using for a BIOS hardware root of trust. HPE does not burn, fuse, or permanently store our public key into AMD processors which ship with our products. HPE uses a unique approach to authenticate our BIOS and BMC firmware: HPE fuses our hardware – or silicon – root of trust into our own BMC silicon to ensure only authenticated firmware is executed.&nbsp; Thus, while we implement a hardware root of trust for our BIOS and BMC firmware, the processors that ship with our servers are not locked to our platforms. (<strong>Source</strong>: HPE)</em></p>
<p>What is at least interesting there is that HPE was initially claiming feature parity with Dell to us, and from the comments on this article were saying they used this feature in sales pitches, but now are saying they are not blowing the eFuses.</p>
<figure id="attachment_39258" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-39258"><a href="https://www.servethehome.com/pcie-gen4-hpe-proliant-dl325-gen10-plus-and-dl385-gen10-plus-amd-epyc-7002/hpe-proliant-dl325-gen10-plus-at-sc19-cpu-cover/" rel="attachment wp-att-39258"><img src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/HPE-ProLiant-DL325-Gen10-Plus-at-SC19-CPU-Cover.jpg" alt="HPE ProLiant DL325 Gen10 Plus At SC19 CPU Cover" width="800" height="600" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/HPE-ProLiant-DL325-Gen10-Plus-at-SC19-CPU-Cover.jpg 800w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/HPE-ProLiant-DL325-Gen10-Plus-at-SC19-CPU-Cover-400x300.jpg 400w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/HPE-ProLiant-DL325-Gen10-Plus-at-SC19-CPU-Cover-80x60.jpg 80w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/HPE-ProLiant-DL325-Gen10-Plus-at-SC19-CPU-Cover-265x198.jpg 265w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/HPE-ProLiant-DL325-Gen10-Plus-at-SC19-CPU-Cover-696x522.jpg 696w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/HPE-ProLiant-DL325-Gen10-Plus-at-SC19-CPU-Cover-560x420.jpg 560w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-39258">HPE ProLiant DL325 Gen10 Plus At SC19 CPU Cover</figcaption></figure>
<p>Here is where the concern develops, and not necessarily for AMD, the OEM, or most of the initial customer base. Customers want more security. The OEMs want to create a secure hardware environment because that is what their customers want. AMD is implementing an advanced security solution beyond what Intel Xeons have giving the OEMs and end-customers what they want. Effectively, when these are sold as new systems, this is exactly what everyone involved wants.</p>
<p>If everyone is getting what they want, then where is the concern, that is what we are going to cover next.</p>
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.servethehome.com/amd-psb-vendor-locks-epyc-cpus-for-enhanced-security-at-a-cost/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24416005</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 02:02:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Disney hit by backlash after thanking Xinjiang authorities in 'Mulan' credits]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 7 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24415532">thread link</a>) | @woranl
<br/>
September 8, 2020 | https://www.ctvnews.ca/mobile/entertainment/disney-hit-by-backlash-after-thanking-xinjiang-authorities-in-mulan-credits-1.5096476 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.ctvnews.ca/mobile/entertainment/disney-hit-by-backlash-after-thanking-xinjiang-authorities-in-mulan-credits-1.5096476">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <p>
	Disney has publicly thanked a Chinese government agency accused of human rights abuses in Xinjiang for its help in making "Mulan" — a revelation that has provoked a storm of criticism online.</p>
<p>
	Disney acknowledges several Chinese government bodies in the credits for the live-action remake of the 1998 animated picture of the same name, but a few in particular have raised red flags: The Xinjiang government's publicity department and the Public Security and Tourism bureaus for Turpan, a city of about <a href="http://www.tlf.gov.cn/zjtluf/rkyy/rkgk.htm" target="_blank">633,400 people</a> just outside Xinjiang's capital Urumqi.</p>
<p>
	Disney did not respond to a request for comment from CNN Business to its media inquiry line, and to U.S. press officers about the film and the credits. It's not clear how much of "Mulan" may have been shot in Xinjiang, though people who worked on the movie have said on social media and in interviews that they scouted and filmed locations there.</p>
<p>
	The U.S. State Department estimates that since 2015 as many as <a href="https://www.foreign.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/120418_Busby_Testimony.pdf" target="_blank">two million of the Muslim-majority Uyghurs and other Turkic minorities</a> have been imprisoned in enormous re-education camps in Xinjiang.</p>
<p>
	The Turpan Public Security Bureau has been listed by the U.S. government as an organization involved in <a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2019/10/09/2019-22210/addition-of-certain-entities-to-the-entity-list" target="_blank">"human rights violations and abuses"</a> in the region.</p>
<p>
	Beijing has long defended the crackdown in Xinjiang as necessary to tackle extremism and terrorism, and said it is in line with Chinese law and international practice, calling accusations of mass detentions a "groundless lie" and "sensational rumor." A spokesperson for the country's foreign ministry on Tuesday reiterated its defense of what it calls its Xinjiang "vocational skills education and training centers." CNN Business has reached out to the Xinjiang government and Turpan's tourism bureau, but Turpan's Public Security bureau could not be reached for comment.</p>
<p>
	"There are no so-called concentration camps in Xinjiang," said China's Foreign Ministry spokesperson Zhao Lijian. "The establishment of vocational skills education and training centers in Xinjiang in accordance with the law is a useful attempt and active exploration for preventive counter-terrorism and de-radicalization."</p>
<p>
	But the connections between Xinjiang and "Mulan" have ignited widespread criticism on social media since its release Friday on Disney+, the company's streaming service. Human rights advocates are now calling on Disney to make public any agreements with the Chinese government over filming in the region.</p>
<p>
	"[It's] deeply disturbing that Disney thought it was okay to partner with, and also thank, government departments, specifically propaganda departments, and a public security bureau from a region in China that is<a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/07/30/asia/xinjiang-sterilization-women-human-rights-intl-hnk/index.html" target="_blank"> complicit with genocide," </a>said Isaac Stone Fish, senior fellow at the Asia Society, a New York based non-profit organization focused on raising awareness of Asia.</p>
<h3>
	A FILM PLAGUED BY SETBACKS</h3>
<p>
	Disney hoped that "Mulan" would be a major success at the lucrative Chinese box office, now the second-largest in the world. The company spoke last year about its dedication to making the film culturally accurate — remarks that were reported in Chinese state media.</p>
<p>
	"We spent a lot of time in the beginning with scholars, experts and people from the region. And we spent a great deal of time in China," said Sean Bailey, president of Walt Disney Studios Motion Picture Production, at a Disney expo event last year, reported the state-run news agency Xinhua. Bailey added that the studio "not only has a Chinese cast but also brought in a Chinese producer to make the movie with them," the outlet noted.</p>
<p>
	Eschewing the musicality of Disney's earlier animated feature of the same name, one box office analyst told CNN Business earlier this year that the live-action epic was <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/02/13/media/disney-mulan-coronavirus/index.html" target="_blank">"tailor-made for success."</a></p>
<p>
	But the film — which is based on a traditional Chinese legend about <a href="http://www.womenofchina.cn/womenofchina/html1/history/1706/4656-1.htm" target="_blank">a female warrior</a> who disguised herself as a man and took her father's place in the army — has already faced controversy and setbacks.</p>
<p>
	In August 2019, pro-democracy activists in Hong Kong called for a boycott of "Mulan" after the lead actor expressed support for Hong Kong police on her social media account.</p>
<p>
	"I support the Hong Kong police. You can all attack me now. What a shame for Hong Kong," Liu Yifei, a Chinese-born U.S. citizen who plays the titular Hua Mulan, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2019/08/16/asia/china-mulan-actor-protests-intl-hnk-trnd/index.html" target="_blank">posted to her official Weibo account.</a> At the time, Hong Kong police faced allegations of excessive violence against protesters. (Hong Kong police <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2019/09/20/asia/hong-kong-protests-intl-hnk/index.html" target="_blank">defended their actions</a> in September 2019, saying they had been "so restrained.")</p>
<p>
	Then in March, Disney was forced to <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/03/12/media/mulan-delay-coronavirus/index.html" target="_blank">delay the film's release</a> as the coronavirus pandemic shuttered movie theaters.</p>
<p>
	Even now, its rollout has been stilted. The film was released as a US$30 <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/09/04/media/mulan-disney-china-international-release/index.html" target="_blank">video-on-demand </a>last Friday on Disney+, which is only available in certain markets, including the United States. It makes its debut in Chinese theaters this weekend. (Disney+ is not available in China.)</p>
<p>
	The release of the film has renewed the controversy surrounding it, however. Pro-democracy activists in Hong Kong, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/09/04/entertainment/mulan-boycott-hong-kong-trnd/index.html" target="_blank">Thailand and Taiwan</a> have once again called on people to boycott the film because of Yifei's remarks last year.</p>
<p>
	And it's not even clear that the film will win over Chinese audiences, who were already chilly toward the original animated version because of its westernized flair and unfaithful retelling of the original legend.</p>
<p>
	After the release of the trailer in 2019, Chinese state-run media Global Times criticized the film for using<a href="http://www.globaltimes.cn/content/1157286.shtml" target="_blank"> Japanese "ninja gestures"</a> and Chinese stereotypes.</p>
<h3>
	CALLS FOR TRANSPARENCY</h3>
<p>
	Allegations of human rights abuses in Xinjiang stretch back years.</p>
<p>
	In recent years, the Xinjiang government has allegedly undertaken a large campaign to imprison and re-educate Muslim minorities in the region, especially the large Uyghur population.</p>
<p>
	Evidence of widespread human rights abuse has trickled out from inside the region, including <a href="https://www.cnn.com/interactive/2020/02/asia/xinjiang-china-karakax-document-intl-hnk/" target="_blank">lengthy detentions,</a> abuse, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2019/11/26/asia/china-xinjiang-leaks-analysis-intl-hnk/index.html" target="_blank">indoctrination</a> and <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/07/30/asia/xinjiang-sterilization-women-human-rights-intl-hnk/index.html" target="_blank">mass birth control</a> — which experts have described as evidence of "genocide."</p>
<p>
	In 2017, Mulan director Niki Caro posted a photo from Urumqi, the capital of Xinjiang<strong> </strong>and said she was <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BZle-neFOc-/?utm_source=ig_embed" target="_blank">scouting out locations</a> for the film. And in an interview in September<strong> </strong>with Conde Nast traveler, Mulan production designer Grant Major discussed filming in Xinjiang's <a href="https://www.cntraveler.com/story/on-location-mulan" target="_blank">Taklamakan Desert</a>, in the region's far southwest.</p>
<p>
	Adrian Zenz, a leading academic<strong> </strong>at the Victims of Communism Foundation who has helped break major stories from Xinjiang, said that the earliest documented case of a re-education center in the region was in Turpan in 2013.</p>
<p>
	Zenz said that while it was possible Disney didn't know about the growing number of detention centers set up across Xinjiang, the widespread oppression in the region was impossible to miss.</p>
<p>
	"There were police stations and checkpoints all over Xinjiang by late 2016, not to be missed," he said.</p>
<p>
	Foreign ministry spokesperson Zhao dismissed Zenz's claims and accused him of making a living "through making Xinjiang-related rumors and slandering China." He also claimed there had been no cases of violence or terrorism in Xinjiang for "more than three consecutive years."</p>
<p>
	Turpan was also the setting for one of the worst outbreaks of ethnic violence in Xinjiang in recent years, when 35 people died during an attack on a police station in Lukqun township, in 2013, <a href="http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/kindle/2013-07/05/content_16731473.htm" target="_blank">according to state media.</a></p>
<p>
	Yaqiu Wang, a China researcher for Human Rights Watch, called for Disney to <a href="https://twitter.com/Yaqiu/status/1303002585155149825" target="_blank">disclose what assistance</a> it had received from Xinjiang authorities and what agreements it had made with the regional government.</p>
<p>
	And<strong> </strong>Asia Society fellow Stone Fish said that many companies were accustomed to making small concessions to the ruling Communist Party to access the Chinese market.</p>
<p>
	"Studios feel like they need to make these compromises to be in Beijing, but you can slightly censor your movies to get into the Chinese market, you can bring Chinese movies that shouldn't be in the States because of poor quality or because of propaganda elements into the States. And you can do that and maintain your integrity, mostly intact," he said.</p>
<p>
	"You don't need to take these extra steps that Disney is taking, and they're rightly getting excoriated for it."</p>

                                              </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.ctvnews.ca/mobile/entertainment/disney-hit-by-backlash-after-thanking-xinjiang-authorities-in-mulan-credits-1.5096476</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24415532</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 01:01:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
