<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 12:20:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 12:20:47 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Strange public IPv4 address assigned behind NAT (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 56 | Comments 57 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23827521">thread link</a>) | @rohan1024
<br/>
July 13, 2020 | https://broadbandforum.co/t/190267/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://broadbandforum.co/t/190267/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://broadbandforum.co/t/190267/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23827521</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 01:12:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Hacking with environment variables]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 174 | Comments 52 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23827486">thread link</a>) | @pentestercrab
<br/>
July 13, 2020 | https://www.elttam.com/blog/env/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.elttam.com/blog/env/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                        

<p>On a recent project we gained the ability to specify environment variables but not the process that was executed.
We were also unable to control the contents of a file on disk, and bruteforcing process identifiers (PIDs) and file descriptors found no interesting results, eliminating <a href="https://www.elttam.com/blog/goahead/">remote LD_PRELOAD exploitation</a>.
Fortunately, a scripting language interpreter was executed which enabled us to execute arbitrary commands by specifying particular environment variables.
This blog post discusses how arbitrary commands can be executed by a range of scripting language interpreters when supplied with malicious environment variables.</p>



<p>A quick read of the <code>ENVIRONMENT</code> section of the <code>perlrun(1)</code> man page reveals plenty of environment variables worth investigating.
The <code>PERL5OPT</code> environment variable allows specifying command-line options, but is restricted to only accepting the options <code>CDIMTUWdmtw</code>.
This unfortunately means that <code>-e</code>, which allows supplying perl code to run, is out.</p>

<p>All is not lost though, as demonstrated in the <a href="https://github.com/HackerFantastic/exploits/blob/master/cve-2016-1531.sh">exploit</a> for CVE-2016-1531 by <a href="https://twitter.com/hackerfantastic">Hacker Fantastic</a>.
The exploit writes a malicious perl module to <code>/tmp/root.pm</code> and supplies the environment variables <code>PERL5OPT=-Mroot</code> and <code>PERL5LIB=/tmp</code> to achieve arbitrary code execution.
However this was an exploit for a local privilege escalation vulnerability and a generic technique should ideally not require access to the file system. Looking at <a href="https://twitter.com/bl4sty">blasty</a>’s <a href="https://haxx.in/blasty-vs-exim.sh">exploit</a> for the same CVE, the exploit did not require creating a file and used the environment variables <code>PERL5OPT=-d</code> and <code>PERL5DB=system("sh");exit;</code>.
The same environment variables were also used to <a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/netsec/comments/1dm8fv/hack_this_website_and_win_bitcoins_the_first/c9tm6j4/">solve a CTF challenge</a> in 2013.</p>

<p>One final nicety of a generic technique would be to use a single environment variable instead of two.
<a href="https://twitter.com/justinsteven">@justinsteven</a> found this was possible by leveraging <code>PERL5OPT=-M</code>.
While either <code>-m</code> or <code>-M</code> can be used to load a perl module, the <code>-M</code> option allows adding extra code after the module name.</p>

<h2 id="proof-of-concept">Proof of Concept</h2>

<figure>
  <figcaption>Figure-0: arbitrary code execution achieved using an environment variable against perl running an empty script (/dev/null)</figcaption>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="console"><span>$</span><span> </span>docker run <span>--env</span> <span>'PERL5OPT=-Mbase;print(`id`)'</span> perl:5.30.2 perl /dev/null
<span>uid=0(root) gid=0(root) groups=0(root)</span></code></pre></figure>

</figure>



<p>Reading the <code>ENVIRONMENT VARIABLES</code> section of the <code>python(1)</code> man page, <code>PYTHONSTARTUP</code> initially appears like it may be a piece of a straightforward solution.
It allows specifying a path to a Python script that will be executed prior to displaying the prompt in interactive mode.
The interactive mode requirement didn’t seem like it would be an issue as the <code>PYTHONINSPECT</code> environment variable can be used to enter interactive mode, the same as specifying <code>-i</code> on the command line.
However, the documentation for the <code>-i</code> option explains that <code>PYTHONSTARTUP</code> will not be used when python is started with a script to execute.
This means that <code>PYTHONSTARTUP</code> and <code>PYTHONINSPECT</code> cannot be combined and <code>PYTHONSTARTUP</code> only has an effect when the python REPL is immediately launched.
This ultimately means that <code>PYTHONSTARTUP</code> is not viable as it has no effect when executing a regular Python script.</p>

<p>Other environment variables which looked promising were <code>PYTHONHOME</code> and <code>PYTHONPATH</code>. Both of these will let you gain arbitrary code execution but require you to also be able to create directories and files on the filesystem. It may be possible to loosen those requirements through the use of the proc filesystem and/or ZIP files.</p>

<p>The majority of the remaining environment variables are simply checked if they contain a non-empty string, and if so, toggle a generally benign setting. One of the rare exceptions to this is <code>PYTHONWARNINGS</code>.</p>

<h2 id="making-progress-with-pythonwarnings">Making progress with PYTHONWARNINGS</h2>
<p>The documentation for <code>PYTHONWARNINGS</code> states <code>it is equivalent to specifying the -W option</code>. The <code>-W</code> option is used for warning control to specify which warnings and how often they are printed. The full form of argument is <code>action:message:category:module:line</code>. While warning control didn’t seem like a promising lead, that quickly changed after checking the implementation.</p>

<figure>
  <figcaption>Figure-1: Python-3.8.2/Lib/warnings.py</figcaption>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="python"><span>[...]</span>
<span>def</span> <span>_getcategory</span><span>(</span><span>category</span><span>):</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>not</span> <span>category</span><span>:</span>
        <span>return</span> <span>Warning</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>'.'</span> <span>not</span> <span>in</span> <span>category</span><span>:</span>
        <span>import</span> <span>builtins</span> <span>as</span> <span>m</span>
        <span>klass</span> <span>=</span> <span>category</span>
    <span>else</span><span>:</span>
        <span>module</span><span>,</span> <span>_</span><span>,</span> <span>klass</span> <span>=</span> <span>category</span><span>.</span><span>rpartition</span><span>(</span><span>'.'</span><span>)</span>
        <span>try</span><span>:</span>
            <span>m</span> <span>=</span> <span>__import__</span><span>(</span><span>module</span><span>,</span> <span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>[</span><span>klass</span><span>])</span>
        <span>except</span> <span>ImportError</span><span>:</span>
            <span>raise</span> <span>_OptionError</span><span>(</span><span>"invalid module name: %r"</span> <span>%</span> <span>(</span><span>module</span><span>,))</span> <span>from</span> <span>None</span>
<span>[...]</span></code></pre></figure>

</figure>

<p>The above code shows that as long as our specified category contains a dot, we can trigger the import an arbitrary Python module.</p>

<p>The next problem is that the vast majority of modules from Python’s standard library run very little code when imported. They tend to just define classes to be used later, and even when they provide code to run, the code is typically <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/__main__.html">guarded with a check of the <code>__main__</code> variable</a> (to detect if the file has been imported or run directly).</p>

<p>An unexpected exception to this is the <a href="https://xkcd.com/353/">antigravity module</a>. The Python developers included an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Easter_egg_(media)">easter egg</a> in <a href="https://github.com/python/cpython/commit/206e3074d34aeb5a4d0c1e24d970b6569f7ad702">2008</a> which can be triggered by running <code>import antigravity</code>. This import will immediately open your browser to the xkcd comic that joked that <code>import antigravity</code> in Python would grant you the ability to fly.</p>

<p>As for how the <code>antigravity</code> module opens your browser, it uses another module from the standard library called <code>webbrowser</code>. This module checks your PATH for a large variety of browsers, including mosaic, opera, skipstone, konqueror, chrome, chromium, firefox, links, elinks and lynx. It also accepts an environment variable <code>BROWSER</code> that lets you specify which process should be executed. It is not possible to supply arguments to the process in the environment variable and the xkcd comic URL is the one hard-coded argument for the command.</p>

<p>The ability to turn this into arbitrary code execution depends on what other executables are available on the system.</p>

<h2 id="leveraging-perl-for-arbitrary-code-execution">Leveraging Perl for Arbitrary Code Execution</h2>

<p>One approach is to leverage Perl which is commonly installed on systems and is even available in the standard Python docker image. However, the <code>perl</code> binary cannot itself be used. This is because the first and only argument is the xkcd comic URL. The comic URL argument will cause an error and the process to exit without the <code>PERL5OPT</code> environment variable being used.</p>

<figure>
  <figcaption>Figure-2: PERL5OPT having no effect when a URL is passed to perl</figcaption>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="console"><span>$</span><span> </span>docker run <span>-e</span> <span>'PERL5OPT=-Mbase;print(`id`);exit'</span> perl:5.30.2 perl https://xkcd.com/353/
<span>Can't open perl script "https://xkcd.com/353/": No such file or directory</span></code></pre></figure>

</figure>

<p>Fortunately, when Perl is available it also common to have the default Perl scripts available, such as perldoc and perlthanks. These scripts will also error and exit with an invalid argument, but the error in this case happens later than the processing of the <code>PERL5OPT</code> environment variable. This means you can leverage the Perl environment variable payload detailed earlier in this blog post.</p>

<figure>
  <figcaption>Figure-3: PERL5OPT working as intended with perldoc and perlthanks</figcaption>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="console"><span>$</span><span> </span>docker run <span>-e</span> <span>'PERL5OPT=-Mbase;print(`id`);exit'</span> perl:5.30.2 perldoc https://xkcd.com/353/
<span>uid=0(root) gid=0(root) groups=0(root)
</span><span>$</span><span> </span>run <span>-e</span> <span>'PERL5OPT=-Mbase;print(`id`);exit'</span> perl:5.30.2 perlthanks https://xkcd.com/353/
<span>uid=0(root) gid=0(root) groups=0(root)</span></code></pre></figure>

</figure>

<h2 id="proof-of-concept-1">Proof of Concept</h2>

<figure>
  <figcaption>Figure-4: arbitrary code execution achieved using multiple environment variables against Python 2 and Python 3</figcaption>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="console"><span>$</span><span> </span>docker run <span>-e</span> <span>'PYTHONWARNINGS=all:0:antigravity.x:0:0'</span> <span>-e</span> <span>'BROWSER=perlthanks'</span> <span>-e</span> <span>'PERL5OPT=-Mbase;print(`id`);exit;'</span> python:2.7.18 python /dev/null
<span>uid=0(root) gid=0(root) groups=0(root)
Invalid -W option ignored: unknown warning category: 'antigravity.x'

</span><span>$</span><span> </span>docker run <span>-e</span> <span>'PYTHONWARNINGS=all:0:antigravity.x:0:0'</span> <span>-e</span> <span>'BROWSER=perlthanks'</span> <span>-e</span> <span>'PERL5OPT=-Mbase;print(`id`);exit;'</span> python:3.8.2 python /dev/null
<span>uid=0(root) gid=0(root) groups=0(root)
Invalid -W option ignored: unknown warning category: 'antigravity.x'</span></code></pre></figure>

</figure>



<p>A <a href="https://research.securitum.com/prototype-pollution-rce-kibana-cve-2019-7609/">blog post</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/securitymb">Michał Bentkowski</a> provided a payload for exploiting Kibana (CVE-2019-7609). A prototype pollution vulnerability was used to set arbitrary environment variables which resulted in arbitrary command execution. Michał’s payload used the <code>NODE_OPTIONS</code> environment variable and the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Procfs">proc filesystem</a>, specifically <code>/proc/self/environ</code>.</p>

<p>Although Michał’s technique was creative and worked perfectly for their vulnerability, the technique is not always guaranteed to work and has some constraints that would be nice to remove.</p>

<p>The first constraint is that it using <code>/proc/self/environ</code> is only viable if the contents can be made to be syntactically valid JavaScript. This requires being able to create an environment variable and have it appear first in the contents of <code>/proc/self/environ</code>, or knowing/bruteforcing the environment variable’s name that will appear first and overwriting it’s value.</p>

<p>Another constraint, as the first environment variable’s value finishes with a single line comment (<code>//</code>). Therefore, any newline character in other environment variables will likely cause a syntax error and prevent the payload from executing. The use of multi-line comments (<code>/*</code>) will not fix this issue as they must be closed to be syntactically valid. Therefore, in the rare case that an environment variable contains a newline character, it is required to know/bruteforce the environment variable’s name and overwrite it’s value to a new value that does not contain a newline.</p>

<p>Removing these contraints is an exercise left for the reader.</p>

<h2 id="proof-of-concept-2">Proof of Concept</h2>

<figure>
  <figcaption>Figure-5: achieving arbitrary code execution with environment variables against NodeJS by Michał Bentkowski</figcaption>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="console"><span>$</span><span> </span>docker run <span>-e</span> <span>'NODE_VERSION=console.log(require("child_process").execSync("id").toString());//'</span> <span>-e</span> <span>'NODE_OPTIONS=--require /proc/self/environ'</span> node:14.2.0 node /dev/null
<span>uid=0(root) gid=0(root) groups=0(root)</span></code></pre></figure>

</figure>



<p>If you run <code>ltrace -e getenv php /dev/null</code> you will find PHP uses the <code>PHPRC</code> environment variable.
The environment variable is used …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.elttam.com/blog/env/">https://www.elttam.com/blog/env/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.elttam.com/blog/env/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23827486</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 01:07:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The AirPods Pro “Rattlegate”]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 371 | Comments 314 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23826070">thread link</a>) | @dewey
<br/>
July 13, 2020 | https://annoying.technology/posts/abea6876cf4f2e13/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://annoying.technology/posts/abea6876cf4f2e13/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/a57da8f4dbb8954a0649e58235d5555af26d4c2f/d294d/media/rattlegate.jpg"></p><p>The AirPods Pro “Rattlegate”</p><p>The first generation of the AirPods was generally regarded as a perfect product. “Apple at its best!” was the universally accepted opinion.</p><p>I used them for a long time. No speaker issues, no battery issues.</p><p>Excited for the noise cancelling feature I ordered the AirPods Pro and for the first few months everything was fine. One day the left AirPod started buzzing every time I was moving my head. Slightly tilting my head would result in a buzzing noise with changing intensity depending on how my head moved.</p><p>Support agreed that this is a problem and sent a new AirPod.</p><p>A few weeks later the right AirPod started to produce weird rattling noises. It sounded like some tiny part fell off and was now bouncing around in the AirPod. It also started to behave weird as soon as there was a bit of wind.</p><p>Support agreed that this is a problem and sent a new AirPod.</p><p>Days later it was the left AirPod’s turn and it’s now rattling again.</p><p>There’s something very wrong with this product line and just getting a new one every few months is — financially and ecologically — not sustainable as they end up in a landfill. I’m also <a href="https://forums.macrumors.com/threads/airpods-pro-rattlegate.2233658/">far from being the only one</a> having this issue.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://annoying.technology/posts/abea6876cf4f2e13/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23826070</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 22:02:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Python malware on the rise]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 256 | Comments 58 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23824689">thread link</a>) | @vesche
<br/>
July 13, 2020 | https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/python-malware-on-the-rise/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/python-malware-on-the-rise/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <div>
                        <p>
                July 13, 2020            </p>
            
			
            <hr>
                        <p><img width="2560" height="1646" src="https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/david-clode-d0CasEMHDQs-unsplash-scaled.jpg" alt="" srcset="https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/david-clode-d0CasEMHDQs-unsplash-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/david-clode-d0CasEMHDQs-unsplash-300x193.jpg 300w, https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/david-clode-d0CasEMHDQs-unsplash-1024x658.jpg 1024w, https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/david-clode-d0CasEMHDQs-unsplash-768x494.jpg 768w, https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/david-clode-d0CasEMHDQs-unsplash-1536x988.jpg 1536w, https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/david-clode-d0CasEMHDQs-unsplash-2048x1317.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px">            </p>
                        <p>The vast majority of serious malware&nbsp;<a href="https://software.imdea.org/~juanca/papers/malsource_raid16.pdf">over the past 30 years</a>&nbsp;has been written in Assembly or compiled languages such as C, C++, and Delphi. However, ever-increasing over the past decade, a large amount of malware has been written in interpreted languages, such as Python. The low barrier to entry, ease of use, rapid development process, and massive library collection has made Python attractive for millions of developers- including malware authors. Python has quickly become a standard language in which threat actors create Remote Access Trojans (RATs), information stealers, and vulnerability exploit tools. As&nbsp;<a href="https://www.techrepublic.com/article/python-is-eating-the-world-how-one-developers-side-project-became-the-hottest-programming-language-on-the-planet/">Python continues to grow radically in popularity</a>&nbsp;and the&nbsp;<a href="https://research.checkpoint.com/2019/malware-against-the-c-monoculture/">C malware monoculture</a>&nbsp;continues to be challenged, it would seem only certain that Python will be increasingly utilized as malware in cyber attacks.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/python_growth.jpg" alt="" width="770" height="660" srcset="https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/python_growth.jpg 770w, https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/python_growth-300x257.jpg 300w, https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/python_growth-768x658.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 770px) 100vw, 770px"></p>
<p><span>Image Source: Stack Overflow</span></p>

<p>In comparison to a standard compiled language like C, writing malware in Python comes with a whole host of difficulties. The first being that Python is required to be installed on the operating system in order to interpret and execute Python code. However, as we’ll see in the next section, a Python program can easily be converted into a native executable using a variety of different methods.</p>
<p>Malware written in Python will also have adverse effects on file size, memory footprint, and processing power. Serious malware is often designed to be small, stealthy, have low memory footprint, and use limited processing power. A compiled malware sample written in C might be 200 KB, while a comparable malware sample written in Python might be 20 MB after converted into an executable. Both the CPU &amp; RAM usage will also be significantly higher when using an interpreted language.</p>
<p>However, it’s 2020 and the digital landscape isn’t what it once was. The internet is faster than it’s ever been, our computers have more memory &amp; storage capacity than ever, and CPUs get faster every year. Python is also more ubiquitous than ever, coming pre-installed on macOS and most all Linux distributions by default.</p>

<p>Microsoft Windows is still the primary target for most malicious campaigns, and it does not come with Python installed by default. Therefore, for threat actors to distribute their malware effectively they must convert their Python code into an executable format. There are many methods to “compile Python” into a native executable. Let’s take a look at the few most popular methods…</p>
<h3>PyInstaller</h3>
<p><img src="https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/pyinstaller.png" alt="" width="500" height="100" srcset="https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/pyinstaller.png 500w, https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/pyinstaller-300x60.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px"></p>

<p><a href="https://www.pyinstaller.org/">PyInstaller</a>&nbsp;is capable of building Python applications into stand-alone executables for Windows, Linux, macOS and more by “freezing” Python code. It is one of the most popular methods to convert Python code into executable format and has been used widely for both legitimate and malicious purposes.</p>
<p>Let’s create a simple “Hello, world!” program in Python and freeze it into a stand-alone executable using PyInstaller:</p>
<pre><code>$ cat hello.py
print('Hello, world!')

$ pyinstaller --onefile hello.py
...

$ ./dist/hello 
Hello, world!

$ file dist/hello 
dist/hello: ELF 64-bit LSB executable, x86-64, version 1 (SYSV), dynamically linked, interpreter /lib64/ld-linux-x86-64.so.2, for GNU/Linux 2.6.32, BuildID[sha1]=294d1f19a085a730da19a6c55788ec08c2187039, stripped

$ du -sh dist/hello 
7.0M    dist/hello
</code></pre>
<p>This process created a portable, stand-alone Linux ELF (Executable and Linkable Format) which is the equivalent to an EXE on Windows. Now let’s create and compile a “Hello, world!” program in C on Linux for comparison:</p>
<pre><code>$ cat hello.c
#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;
int main() {
    printf("Hello, world!");
}

$ gcc hello.c -o hello

$ ./hello 
Hello, world!

$ file hello
hello: ELF 64-bit LSB pie executable, x86-64, version 1 (SYSV), dynamically linked, interpreter /lib64/ld-linux-x86-64.so.2, BuildID[sha1]=480c7c75e09c169ab25d1b81bd28f66fde08da7c, for GNU/Linux 3.2.0, not stripped

$ du -sh hello
20K hello
</code></pre>
<p>Notice how much larger the file size is: 7 MB (Python) vs 20 KB (C)! This demonstrates the major drawback we discussed previously about file size and memory usage. The Python executable is so much larger due to the fact it must bundle the Python interpreter (as a shared object file on Linux) inside the executable itself in order to run.</p>
<h3>py2exe</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.py2exe.org/">Py2exe</a>&nbsp;is another popular method to convert Python code into Windows EXE (executable) format that can be run natively. Similar to PyInstaller, it bundles the Python interpreter with your Python code to make a portable executable. Py2exe is likely to fall out of style with time as it has not been supported past Python 3.4, this is due to&nbsp;<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/whatsnew/3.6.html#cpython-bytecode-changes">the bytecode in CPython being heavily changed in Python 3.6 and beyond</a>.</p>
<p>Py2exe utilizes distutils and requires a small&nbsp;<code>setup.py</code>&nbsp;script to be created to produce an executable. Let’s create an example “Hello, world!” executable using py2exe:</p>
<pre><code>&gt; type hello.py
print('Hello, world!')

&gt; type setup.py
import py2exe
from distutils.core import setup
setup(
    console=['hello.py'],
    options={'py2exe': {'bundle_files': 1, 'compressed': True}},
    zipfile=None
)

&gt; python setup.py py2exe
...

&gt; dist\hello.exe
Hello, world!
</code></pre>
<p>The&nbsp;<code>hello.exe</code>&nbsp;created by py2exe is similar in size to PyInstaller coming in at 6.83 MB.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/hello_exe.png" alt="" width="369" height="508" srcset="https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/hello_exe.png 369w, https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/hello_exe-218x300.png 218w" sizes="(max-width: 369px) 100vw, 369px"></p>
<h3>Nuitka</h3>
<p><img src="https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/nuitka.png" alt="" width="120" height="24"></p>
<p><a href="https://nuitka.net/">Nuitka</a>&nbsp;is perhaps the most underutilized, and yet more advanced method of compiling Python code to an executable. It translates Python code into a C program that then is linked against libpython to execute code the same as CPython. Nuitka can use a variety of C compilers including gcc, clang, MinGW64, Visual Studio 2019+, and clang-cl to convert your Python code to C.</p>
<p>Let’s create a “Hello, world!” Python program on Linux and compile it using Nuitka:</p>
<pre><code>$ cat hello.py
print('Hello, world!')

$ nuitka3 hello.py
...

$ ./hello.bin
Hello, world!

$ file hello.bin 
hello.bin: ELF 64-bit LSB pie executable, x86-64, version 1 (SYSV), dynamically linked, interpreter /lib64/ld-linux-x86-64.so.2, BuildID[sha1]=eb6a504e8922f8983b23ce6e82c45a907c6ebadf, for GNU/Linux 3.2.0, stripped

$ du -sh hello.bin
432K    hello.bin
</code></pre>
<p>Nuitka produced a portable binary very simply, and at 432 KB is a fraction of the size of what PyInstaller or py2exe can produce! How is Nuitka able to do this? Let’s take a look at the build folder:</p>
<pre><code>$ cloc hello.build/
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Language                     files          blank        comment           code
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------
C                               11           2263            709           8109
C/C++ Header                     1              1              0              7
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------
SUM:                            12           2264            709           8116
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------
</code></pre>
<p>Nuitka produced over 8,000 lines of C code from our 1 line Python program. The way Nuitka works is it actually translates the Python modules into C code and then uses libpython and static C files of its own to execute in the same way as CPython does.</p>
<p>This is very impressive, and it seems highly likely the Nuitka “Python compiler” will see further adoption as time goes on. As we’ll see later, Nuitka might have a further, built-in advantage in protection against Reverse Engineering (RE). There already exist several tools to easily analyze binaries produced by PyInstaller and py2exe to recover Python source code. However, by Nuitka translating the Python code to C it is much more difficult to reverse engineer.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/tools.png" alt="" width="557" height="383" srcset="https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/tools.png 557w, https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/tools-300x206.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 557px) 100vw, 557px"></p>
<p>Python malware can take advantage of a massive ecosystem of open-source Python packages and repositories. Almost anything you could think of, someone has already built it using Python. This is a huge advantage to malware authors as simplistic capabilities can be cherry-picked from the open web and more complex capabilities likely don’t need to be written from scratch.</p>
<p>Let’s take a look at three simple, yet powerful tool examples:</p>
<ol>
<li>Code Obfuscation</li>
<li>Taking Screenshots</li>
<li>Performing Web Requests</li>
</ol>
<h3>Tool Example 1 – Obfuscation</h3>
<p>Malware authors using Python have many libraries they could use to obfuscate their Python code to make code readability much more difficult, such as:&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/liftoff/pyminifier">pyminifier</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/dashingsoft/pyarmor">pyarmor</a>.</p>
<p>Here’s a small example of how&nbsp;<code>pyarmor</code>&nbsp;can obfuscate Python code:</p>
<pre><code>$ cat hello.py 
print('Hello, world!')

$ pyarmor obfuscate hello.py
...

$ cat dist/hello.py
from pytransform import pyarmor_runtime
pyarmor_runtime()
__pyarmor__(__name__, __file__, b'\x50\x59\x41\x52\x4d\x4f\x52\x00\x00\x03\x08\x00\x55\x0d\x0d\x0a\x04\x00\x00\x00\x00\x00\x00\x00\x01\x00\x00\x00\x40\x00\x00\x00\xd5\x00\x00\x00\x00\x00\x00\x18\xf4\x63\x79\xf6\xaa\xd7\xbd\xc8\x85\x25\x4e\x4f\xa6\x80\x72\x9f\x00\x00\x00\x00\x00\x00\x00\x00\xec\x50\x8c\x64\x26\x42\xd6\x01\x10\x54\xca\x9c\xb6\x30\x82\x05\xb8\x63\x3f\xb0\x96\xb1\x97\x0b\xc1\x49\xc9\x47\x86\x55\x61\x93\x75\xa2\xc2\x8c\xb7\x13\x87\xff\x31\x46\xa5\x29\x41\x9d\xdf\x32\xed\x7a\xb9\xa0\xe1\x9a\x50\x4a\x65\x25\xdb\xbe\x1b\xb6\xcd\xd4\xe7\xc2\x97\x35\xd3\x3e\xd3\xd0\x74\xb8\xd5\xab\x48\xd3\x05\x29\x5e\x31\xcf\x3f\xd3\x51\x78\x13\xbc\xb3\x3e\x63\x62\xca\x05\xfb\xac\xed\xfa\xc1\xe3\xb8\xa2\xaa\xfb\xaa\xbb\xb5\x92\x19\x73\xf0\x78\xe4\x9f\xb0\x1c\x7a\x1c\x0c\x6a\xa7\x8b\x19\x38\x37\x7f\x16\xe8\x61\x41\x68\xef\x6a\x96\x3f\x68\x2b\xb7\xec\x60\x39\x51\xa3\xfc\xbd\x65\xdb\xb8\xff\x39\xfe\xc0\x3d\x16\x51\x7f\xc9\x7f\x8b\xbd\x88\x80\x92\xfe\xe1\x23\x61\xd0\xf1\xd3\xf8\xfa\xce\x86\x92\x6d\x4d\xd7\x69\x50\x8b\xf1\x09\x31\xcc\x19\x15\xef\x37\x12\xd4\xbd\x3d\x0d\x6e\xbb\x28\x3e\xac\xbb\xc4\xdb\x98\xb5\x85\xa6\x19\x11\x74\xe9\xab\xdf', 1)

$ python dist/hello.py
Hello, world!
</code></pre>

<h3>Tool Example 2 – Screenshots</h3>
<p>Information stealing malware will often come with the capability to take screenshots of the users desktop in order to steal sensitive …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/python-malware-on-the-rise/">https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/python-malware-on-the-rise/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cyborgsecurity.com/python-malware-on-the-rise/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23824689</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 19:34:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Deschooling Society (1970)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 188 | Comments 179 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23821855">thread link</a>) | @minerjoe
<br/>
July 13, 2020 | https://davidtinapple.com/illich/1970_deschooling.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://davidtinapple.com/illich/1970_deschooling.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div width="700">
				<tbody><tr>
					<td><span size="+2">DESCHOOLING SOCIETY</span><p>
						
						&nbsp;
						IVAN ILLICH</p><p>
						
						&nbsp;
						
						&nbsp;
						Contents</p><p>
						
						&nbsp;
						
						Introduction xix </p><p>
						
						<a href="#1">1. Why We Must Disestablish School</a></p><p>
						
						<a href="#2">2. Phenomenology of School<br>
						</a><br>
						<a href="#3">3. Ritualization of Progress<br>
						</a><br>
						<a href="#4">4. Institutional Spectrum</a></p><p>
						
						<a href="#5">5. Irrational Consistencies</a></p><p>
						
						<a href="#6">6. Learning Webs</a></p><p>
						
						<a href="#7">7. Rebirth of Epimethean Man</a></p><p>
						
						&nbsp;
						
						
						
						
						&nbsp;
						
						Introduction</p><p>
						
						
						&nbsp;
						
						I owe my interest in public education to Everett Reimer. Until we first met in Puerto Rico in 1958, I had never questioned the value of extending obligatory schooling to all people. Together we have come to realize that for most men the right to learn is curtailed by the obligation to attend school. The essays given at CIDOC and gathered in this book grew out of memoranda which I submitted to him, and which we discussed during 1970, the thirteenth year of our dialogue. The last chapter contains my afterthoughts on a conversation with Erich Fromm on Bachofen's Mutterrecht.</p><p>
						
						
						Since 1967 Reimer and I have met regularly at the Center for Intercultural Documentation (CIDOC) in Cuernavaca, Mexico. Valentine Borremans, the director of the Center, also joined our dialogue, and constantly urged me to test our thinking against the realities of Latin America and Africa. This book reflects her conviction that the ethos, not just the institutions, of society ought to be "deschooled."</p><p>
						
						
						Universal education through schooling is not feasible. It would be no more feasible if it were attempted by means of alternative institutions built on the style of present schools. Neither new attitudes of teachers toward their pupils nor the proliferation of educational hardware or software (in classroom or bedroom), nor finally the attempt to expand the pedagogue's responsibility until it engulfs his pupils' lifetimes will deliver universal education. The current search for new educational funnels must be reversed into the search for their institutional inverse: educational webs which heighten the opportunity for each one to transform each moment of his living into one of learning, sharing, and caring. We hope to contribute concepts needed by those who conduct such counterfoil research on education--and also to those who seek alternatives to other established service industries.</p><p>
						
						
						On Wednesday mornings, during the spring and summer of 1970, I submitted the various parts of this book to the participants in our CIDOC programs in Cuernavaca. Dozens of them made suggestions or provided criticisms. Many will recognize their ideas in these pages, especially Paulo Freire, Peter Berger, and Jos? Maria Bulnes, as well as Joseph Fitzpatrick, John Holt, Angel Quintero, Layman Allen, Fred Goodman, Gerhard Ladner, Didier Piveteau, Joel Spring, Augusto Salazar Bondy, and Dennis Sullivan. Among my critics, Paul Goodman most radically obliged me to revise my thinking. Robert Silvers provided me with brilliant editorial assistance on Chapters 1, 3, and 6, which have appeared in The New York Review of Books.</p><p>
						
						
						Reimer and I have decided to publish separate views of our joint research. He is working on a comprehensive and documented exposition, which will be subjected to several months of further critical appraisal and be published late in 1971 by Doubleday &amp; Company. Dennis Sullivan, who acted as secretary at the meetings between Reimer and myself, is preparing a book for publication in the spring of 1972 which will place my argument in the context of current debate about public schooling in the United States. I offer this volume of essays now in the hope that it will provoke additional critical contributions to the sessions of a seminar on "Alternatives in Education" planned at CIDOC in Cuernavaca for 1972 and 1973.</p><p>
						
						
						I intend to discuss some perplexing issues which are raised once we embrace the hypothesis that society can be deschooled; to search for criteria which may help us distinguish institutions which merit development because they support learning in a deschooled milieu; and to clarify those personal goals which would foster the advent of an Age of Leisure (schole) as opposed to an economy dominated by service industries. </p><p>
						
						
						IVAN ILLICH</p><p>
						
						
						&nbsp;
						
						
						CIDOC</p><p>
						
						
						Cuernavaca, Mexico</p><p>
						
						
						November, 1970<br>
						<a name="1"></a>.</p><a href="#top"><span size="-1">index&nbsp;</span></a><span size="+1">1.  Why We Must Disestablish School</span><p>
						
						
						&nbsp;
						
						
						Many students, especially those who are poor, intuitively know what the schools do for them. They school them to confuse process and substance. Once these become blurred, a new logic is assumed: the more treatment there is, the better are the results; or, escalation leads to success. The pupil is thereby "schooled" to confuse teaching with learning, grade advancement with education, a diploma with competence, and fluency with the ability to say something new. His imagination is "schooled" to accept service in place of value. Medical treatment is mistaken for health care, social work for the improvement of community life, police protection for safety, military poise for national security, the rat race for productive work. Health, learning, dignity, independence, and creative endeavor are defined as little more than the performance of the institutions which claim to serve these ends, and their improvement is made to depend on allocating more resources to the management of hospitals, schools, and other agencies in question.</p><p>
						
						
						In these essays, I will show that the institutionalization of values leads inevitably to physical pollution, social polarization, and psychological impotence: three dimensions in a process of global degradation and modernized misery. I will explain how this process of degradation is accelerated when nonmaterial needs are transformed into demands for commodities; when health, education, personal mobility, welfare, or psychological healing are defined as the result of services or "treatments." I do this because I believe that most of the research now going on about the future tends to advocate further increases in the institutionalization of values and that we must define conditions which would permit precisely the contrary to happen. We need research on the possible use of technology to create institutions which serve personal, creative, and autonomous interaction and the emergence of values which cannot be substantially controlled by technocrats. We need counterfoil research to current futurology.</p><p>
						
						
						I want to raise the general question of the mutual definition of man's nature and the nature of modern institutions which characterizes our world view and language. To do so, I have chosen the school as my paradigm, and I therefore deal only indirectly with other bureaucratic agencies of the corporate state: the consumer-family, the party, the army, the church, the media. My analysis of the hidden curriculum of school should make it evident that public education would profit from the deschooling of society, just as family life, politics, security, faith, and communication would profit from an analogous process.</p><p>
						
						
						I begin my analysis, in this first essay, by trying to convey what the deschooling of a schooled society might mean. In this context, it should be easier to understand my choice of the five specific aspects relevant to this process with which I deal in the subsequent chapters.</p><p>
						
						
						Not only education but social reality itself has become schooled. It costs roughly the same to school both rich and poor in the same dependency. The yearly expenditure per pupil in the slums and in the rich suburbs of any one of twenty U.S. cities lies in the same range-and sometimes is favorable to the poor. Rich and poor alike depend on schools and hospitals which guide their lives, form their world view, and define for them what is legitimate and what is not. Both view doctoring oneself as irresponsible, learning on one's own as unreliable, and community organization, when not paid for by those in authority, as a form of aggression or subversion. For both groups the reliance on institutional treatment renders independent accomplishment suspect. The progressive underdevelopment of self- and community-reliance is even more typical in Westchester than it is in the northeast of Brazil. Everywhere not only education but society as a whole needs "deschooling."</p><p>
						
						
						Welfare bureaucracies claim a professional, political, and financial monopoly over the social imagination, setting standards of what is valuable and what is feasible. This monopoly is at the root of the modernization of poverty. Every simple need to which an institutional answer is found permits the invention of a new class of poor and a new definition of poverty. Ten years ago in Mexico it was the normal thing to be born and to die in one's own home and to be buried by one's friends. Only the soul's needs were taken care of by the institutional church. Now to begin andend life at home become signs either of poverty or of special privilege. Dying and death have come under the institutional management of doctors and undertakers.</p><p>
						
						
						Once basic needs have been translated by a society into demands for scientifically produced commodities, poverty is defined by standards which the technocrats can change at will. Poverty then refers to those who have fallen behind an advertised ideal of consumption in some important respect. In Mexico the poor are those who lack three years of schooling, and in New York they are those who lack twelve.</p><p>
						
						
						The poor have always been socially powerless. The increasing reliance on institutional care adds a new dimension to their helplessness: psychological …</p></td></tr></tbody></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://davidtinapple.com/illich/1970_deschooling.html">https://davidtinapple.com/illich/1970_deschooling.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://davidtinapple.com/illich/1970_deschooling.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23821855</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 15:34:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Meddling Middlemen of Academia]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 82 | Comments 50 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23819130">thread link</a>) | @Topolomancer
<br/>
July 13, 2020 | https://bastian.rieck.me/blog/posts/2020/middlemen/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bastian.rieck.me/blog/posts/2020/middlemen/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <p>One of the strangest phenomena in academia is the reliance on publishing
companies. In this article, I want to outline some of the issues that
arise when working with publishers. I shall also endeavour to provide
some solutions to improve this collaboration.</p>
<p>Before we start, a brief <strong>disclaimer</strong>: this article will use an
amalgamation of different incidents that involved either myself, my
colleagues, or my friends.  Names&nbsp;(of the publishing companies)
have been withheld because I do not think it fair to use my ‘soapbox’
without giving the <em>other</em> side a chance to respond. Moreover,
everything I write here pertains to publishing your research in
a journal. Conference publishing—at least in machine learning—is
a joy<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>. Plus, there <em>are</em> good examples of journals for machine
learning papers, foremost of them the <a href="http://www.jmlr.org/">Journal of Machine Learning
Research</a>. The ‘adversaries’ in this article are
rather the ‘big’ publishing companies and their practices. With that out
of the way, let us take a look at the state of the art!</p>

<p>If you are new to science, at some point, you will probably have to deal
with an established publishing company to get your article published.
The deal usually works like this:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>You look for a journal you want to publish in and submit your article
to the journal. This already often involves jumping through some
hoops. Without knowing the eventual fate of your article, you often
already have to abide by certain arbitrary formatting guidelines or
completely ‘butcher’ your article for the submission<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> by shifting
content around. However, this can be all accepted and endured because
of course, you want something from <em>them</em>, i.e. a published,
citable publication!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The journal then receives your submission—often through a web
interface that was developed with all the UX/UI knowledge of the
1980s<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup> and has <em>never</em> been updated since—and this is where it gets
slightly <em>murky</em>. Another person—typically the editor of the
journal—now decides whether to accept the paper for reviewing, or
whether to provide you with a desk reject. A desk reject usually cannot
be appealed. It just shows you the door and leaves you to try again
with another journal&nbsp;(more murkiness here). For early-career
researchers like Ph.D. students submitting their first paper,
this can be highly discouraging. I see the reason for reducing the
workload on reviewers, of course, but I also heard of academic feuds
that were carried out on the backs of Ph.D. students and their
publications.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Assuming your paper ‘survived’ the desk reject, it will now be sent
to reviewers or referees. Their job is to review your paper
thoroughly, provide feedback, and in general give this whole business
a formal veneer. Setting aside problems in the reviewing
process—which I discussed <a href="http://bastian.rieck.me/blog/posts/2019/reviewing/">in another blog post</a>—this again opens up a portal into
a strange dimension: working as a reviewer for a journal is usually
a job that is provided for free&nbsp;(same goes for editorial
duties). Notice that this is <em>despite</em> the fact that those journals
are charging money to readers and universities. ETH Zurich, my
current employer, describes their experiences of the <a href="https://www.library.ethz.ch/en/Services/Using-ordering-resources/National-negotiations-with-publishers-Read-publish-reorganised">negotiations
with
publishers</a>
and mentions an expenditure of 6.4 million EUR&nbsp;(roughly 7.25
million USD) per year for being allowed to access journal articles.
That is a lot of money.</p>
<p>Setting aside the actual numbers here, let me just point out how
strange it is that companies are relying on <em>unpaid labour</em>, and this
reliance is <em>crucial</em> to their business model. They often do not
employ people that are qualified to judge the content that they want
to publish! But of course, reviewers and editors get the benefit of
<em>exposure</em>—that wonderful currency that is supposed to help your
career along! Even stranger: journals often charge hefty sums for
accessing your own research articles. To me, it is super weird that
research that is often <em>funded</em> by the taxpayer cannot be <em>accessed</em>
by the taxpayer.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Supposing your article got sufficiently good reviews to be published,
the next stage of the process starts. This is where the <em>meddling</em>
begins in earnest. After a little back and forth, you article will be
changed according to some arbitrary rules: the last period of every
sentence in an image caption will be removed, footnotes will be put
into the text—because for some reason, footnotes are permitted in
virtually every template and publishing medium, but deemed somewhat
uncouth by certain publishers—and you might have to redo certain
parts of your paper because of subtle font changes or what have you.</p>
<p>Again, lest you think of me as a particularly cranky person prone to
grumbling and finding faults, you are getting the wrong idea here.
I do not object to these changes, but I <em>do</em> object to the fact that
these meddlesome changes often decrease the quality of your paper.
Here are some irksome changes:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Footnotes will be inserted willy-nilly into the text, regardless of
whether they make sense or not. That might break the flow of your
paper, but that is <em>your</em> problem.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Some ‘publisher house rules’ conflict with proper nomenclature in
a field. For example, the journal might have the ‘rule’ that all
fields in a table have to be capitalised. If this clashes with
nomenclature in your field, it is—you guessed it—<em>your</em> problem.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Your equations will typically be typeset yet
another time for you<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup>, which might introduce subtle changes: symbols
will change and you have to be go through your own paper once again
line-by-line to see whether anything untoward happened. Again, I am
primarily objecting to the substandard quality of this meddling:
the work that you put into writing your equations is completely
ignored, and now you have to chase—often very subtle—changes in
your own text. For mathematical typesetting, precision is crucial,
and it is unbecoming when people who do not <em>care</em> about this
precision create more work for you.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>As a last example, your figures might be meddled with: you might be
forced to convert them into obsolete file formats&nbsp;(because
apparently, EPS is still the best format available), or, more
appallingly, vector graphics might be converted to raster
images&nbsp;(judging from the experiences of my friends and myself,
this is unfortunately relatively common!). This might sound like a tiny
problem again, but it decreases readability and accessibility for
some readers, and, more to the point of this post, it is somewhat
unnecessary meddling.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Let me re-iterate my main point: I do not object to changing my
paper, I merely object to meddlesome changes that are just generating
useless work. For example, there is no need whatsoever to typeset
your equations again—this is quite literally the definition of
negative work.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If you survived this ordeal intact, you now must <em>pay</em>. To be fair,
not all journals charge you for normal articles, but <em>most</em> of them
charge you for open access publishing. In other words: if I want my
research, which is generously funded<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup> by the Swiss taxpayers, to
be available to those selfsame taxpayers, I have to pay. The amounts
vary a little bit, of course, but we are talking upwards of a few
hundred USD at least. Luckily, this is <em>not</em> a problem for my
research group; my postdoctoral adviser, <a href="https://bsse.ethz.ch/mlcb/karsten.html">Prof. Karsten
Borgwardt</a> ensures that
sufficient funds for open access publications are available.</p>
<p>Interestingly, sometimes the cost is fielded by a conference; this
happens when the conference has a contract that ensures that its
publications will be available as special issue of some journal.
This might seem nice because it <em>shifts</em> the costs away from authors,
but it is also somewhat non-transparent; conference costs being high
already, I find it strange that some of the money goes into the
pockets of another party.</p>
<p>After all this negativity, it is time for a <em>positive example</em>:
NeurIPS, one of the flagship machine learning conferences, is
partnered with a publisher and makes <em>all</em> papers available for free
online. I <em>gladly</em> pay the conference fee for this!</p>
</li>
</ol>

<p>How can this process be improved? I have a few suggestions:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Transparency</strong>: publishers should make it clear <em>where</em> the funds are
going. Are we increasing shareholder value by working for free? How
are profits split and used?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Giving back</strong>: it is generally understood that everyone needs to eat
and no one should have to work for free. Why is then that this
completely different in publishing? Almost all the profits are
essentially generated because editors and reviewers work for free.
I know that being remunerated for your reviewing work might raise
some questions about impartiality etc., so I think <em>paying</em> people to
write reviews might be somewhat problematic.</p>
<p>However, closely related to my point about transparency, publishers
could be more upfront about how they user their funds and <em>give back</em>
to the community. For example, publishers could sponsor students so
that they can visit a conference for free, or publishers could
sponsor the conferences themselves.</p>
<p>If you, as a publisher, engage the community and give back a little,
the community will be all the more happy to work with you. We need
you, but you also need us. Without the scientists, you cannot be
a scientific publisher.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Commitment to excellence</strong>: publishers should commit to the highest
quality and the highest standards. Employ people that are capable of
working <em>with</em> the scientists, not <em>for</em> the scientists. Train your
employees to be experts in typography, typesetting, and pair them
with domain experts so that they do not create more work for the
authors by inadvertently destroying equations, figures, and so on.</p>
<p>This goal is not necessarily orthogonal to maximising your profits,
by the way: if you lower your standards, your reputation as
a publisher will suffer, meaning that scientists in the long
run&nbsp;(!) might not be willing to publish with you any more. If
you commit to excellence, by contrast, we will flock to you.</p>
<p>I know that working with a publisher that <em>cares</em> about the end
product as much as I do is a heavenly match! So we should endeavour
to make such …</p></li></ol></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://bastian.rieck.me/blog/posts/2020/middlemen/">https://bastian.rieck.me/blog/posts/2020/middlemen/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bastian.rieck.me/blog/posts/2020/middlemen/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23819130</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 10:16:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Real World Programming in SWI-Prolog]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 104 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23818901">thread link</a>) | @luu
<br/>
July 13, 2020 | http://www.pathwayslms.com/swipltuts/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.pathwayslms.com/swipltuts/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">


<p>This is a hopefully ever expanding collection of tutorials on aspects of the SWI-Prolog environment.
Our emphasis is on learning to write <b>real world</b> applications in SWI-Prolog.</p>

<ol>
<li><a href="http://www.pathwayslms.com/swipltuts/dcg/index.html">Definite Clause Grammars</a> by <a href="mailto:annie@theelginworks.com">Anne Ogborn</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.pathwayslms.com/swipltuts/html/index.html">Web Applications</a> by <a href="mailto:annie@theelginworks.com">Anne Ogborn</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.pathwayslms.com/swipltuts/clpfd/clpfd.html">Constraint Logic Programming over Finite Domains</a> by <a href="mailto:annie@theelginworks.com">Anne Ogborn</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.pathwayslms.com/swipltuts/message/index.html">Printing Messages in SWI-Prolog</a>by <a href="mailto:annie@theelginworks.com">Anne Ogborn</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.pathwayslms.com/swipltuts/chr/index.html">Constraint Handling Rules</a>by <a href="mailto:annie@theelginworks.com">Anne Ogborn</a></li>
</ol>

<h2>Stuff that's in the general vein of the <i>Real World</i> tutorials, but are by others</h2>
<ul>
<li>There is a <a href="http://swish.swi-prolog.org/example/dict.swinb">SWISH tutorial on the dict structure</a> that was introduced with revision 7.0</li>
<li>There is a <a href="http://swish.swi-prolog.org/example/tabling.swinb">SWISH tutorial on tabling</a> that was introduced with 7.2.3</li>
<li>Michael Richter maintains a tutorial on using modules with SWI-Prolog <a href="http://chiselapp.com/user/ttmrichter/repository/gng/doc/trunk/output/tutorials/swiplmodtut.html">Using Modules with SWI-Prolog</a></li>
<li>Michael Hendricks has a tutorial for his vastly nifty pack "Julian" for reasoning about dates and times <a href="http://mndrix.github.io/julian/index.html">Julian tutorial</a></li>
<li>The Amzi Corporation maintains a useful introduction to expert systems <a href="http://www.amzi.com/ExpertSystemsInProlog/">Expert Systems in Prolog</a></li>
</ul>

<h2>Other stuff by me (Anne Ogborn) about Prolog</h2>
<li><a href="http://www.pathwayslms.com/swipltuts/student/index.html">FAQ For The ##Prolog Channel</a> by Anne Ogborn and Michael Richter</li>
<li>A little story about <a href="http://www.pathwayslms.com/swipltuts/teacher/index.html">teaching Programming Languages courses that include Prolog</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JmOHV5IlPyU">Youtube video (35 mins) of my tutorial on Pengines at Strange Loop 2014</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G_eYTctGZw8">Youtube video (40 mins)</a> of Michael Hendricks' talk on Production Prolog, with great hints on practical Prolog</li>
<li>I gave a workshop on SWI-Prolog web development at <a href="https://thestrangeloop.com/">Strangeloop 2013</a> The workshop materials were basically the set of html tutorials collected into a single program. <a href="https://github.com/Anniepoo/strangeloop">You can get them here</a>.</li>

<h2>Selected other folks' tutorials and info about prolog</h2>
<ul>
<li>Roman Bartok maintains a great <a href="http://kti.ms.mff.cuni.cz/~bartak/prolog/index.html">tutorial introduction to Prolog</a></li>
<li>The introductory book <a href="http://lpn.swi-prolog.org/lpnpage.php?pageid=online">Learn Prolog Now</a> is online, and has embedded SWISH so you can run the examples right in the text</li>
<li>Help, my brain is melting <a href="http://www.pathwayslms.com/swipltuts/())).pl">())).pl</a></li>
</ul>

<h2>Contribute!</h2>
<p>We'd love to have more contributors of tutorials. Areas we'd love to see covered: Pldoc, The IDE, CLP, Expert Systems, aggregator library, and whatever else excites you.</p>



</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.pathwayslms.com/swipltuts/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23818901</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 09:37:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Dark Web Price Index 2020]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 282 | Comments 197 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23818727">thread link</a>) | @known
<br/>
July 13, 2020 | https://www.privacyaffairs.com/dark-web-price-index-2020/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.privacyaffairs.com/dark-web-price-index-2020/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p><b>The dark web has a longstanding reputation as a haven for the worst kinds of criminal activity. This reputation is not wholly unjustified, as there are indeed terrible things happening around the world that can be bought and sold on the dark web. </b></p><p><span>The privacy offered by software such as TOR creates an environment where criminals can sell their wares on the dark web without the worry of law enforcement.</span></p><p><span>What’s more, many will have heard the horror stories of people’s bank accounts being cleaned out, or their identity stolen and turning up in custody in Mexico. Again, not unjustified horror.</span></p><p><span>You might be asking yourself, just how easy is it to obtain someone else’s personal information, documents, account details?&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>We certainly were.</span></p><p><span>To see just how prevalent such items of personal data are being listed, and at what price, we sent our researchers on a data-gathering mission into the dark web.</span></p><table><tbody><tr><td>Category</td><td>Product</td><td>Avg. dark web Price (USD)</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://www.privacyaffairs.com/dark-web-price-index-2020/#2">Credit Card Data</a></td><td>Cloned Mastercard with PIN</td><td>$15</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Cloned American Express with PIN</td><td>$35</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Cloned VISA with PIN</td><td>$25</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Credit card details, account balance up to $1000</td><td>$12</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Credit card details, account balance up to $5000</td><td>$20</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Stolen online banking logins, minimum $100 on account</td><td>$35</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Stolen online banking logins, minimum $2000 on account</td><td>$65</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Walmart account with credit card attached</td><td>$10</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://www.privacyaffairs.com/dark-web-price-index-2020/#3">Payment processing services</a></td><td>Stolen PayPal account details, minimum $100</td><td>$198.56</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>PayPal transfer from stolen account, $1000 – $3000</td><td>$320.39</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>PayPal transfers from stolen account, $3000+</td><td>$155.94</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Western Union transfer from stolen account, above $1000</td><td>$98.15</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://www.privacyaffairs.com/dark-web-price-index-2020/#4">Forged documents</a></td><td>US driving license, average quality</td><td>$70</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>US driving license, high quality</td><td>$550</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Auto insurance card</td><td>$70</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>AAA emergency road service membership card</td><td>$70</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Wells Fargo bank statement</td><td>$25</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Wells Fargo bank statement with transactions</td><td>$80</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Rutgers State University student ID</td><td>$70</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>US, Canada, or Europe passport</td><td>$1500</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Europe national ID card</td><td>$550</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://www.privacyaffairs.com/dark-web-price-index-2020/#5">Social Media</a></td><td>Hacked Facebook account</td><td>$74.5</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Hacked Instagram account</td><td>$55.45</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Hacked Twitter account<a id="mcegrid91" href="https://www.privacyaffairs.com/wp-admin/post.php?post=7083&amp;action=edit#" data-mce-x="1" data-mce-y="9"></a></td><td>$49</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Hacked Gmail account</td><td>$155.73</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Instagram followers x 1000</td><td>$7</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Spotify followers x 1000</td><td>$3</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Twitch followers x 1000</td><td>$6</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Tick Tok followers x 1000</td><td>$15</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>LinkedIn followers x 1000</td><td>$10</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>LinkedIn company page followers x 1000</td><td>$10</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Pinterest followers x 1000</td><td>$5</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Soundcloud plays x 1000</td><td>$1</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Daily Motion views x 1000</td><td>$2</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Twitter retweets x 1000</td><td>$25</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Instagram likes x 1000</td><td>$6</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://www.privacyaffairs.com/dark-web-price-index-2020/#6">Malware</a></td><td>Global low quality, slow speed, low success rate x 1000</td><td>$70</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Europe low quality, slow speed, low success rate x 1000</td><td>$300</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>USA, CA, UK, AU low quality, slow speed, low success rate x 1000<a id="mcegrid91" href="https://www.privacyaffairs.com/wp-admin/post.php?post=7083&amp;action=edit#" data-mce-x="1" data-mce-y="9"></a></td><td>$800</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Global med quality, 70% success rate x 1000</td><td>$80</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Europe med quality, 70% success rate x 1000</td><td>$700</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>USA only med quality, 70% success rate x 1000</td><td>$900+</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>USA, CA, UK, AU med quality, 70% success rate x 1000</td><td>$1300</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Europe fresh high quality x 1000</td><td>$2300</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Europe aged high quality x 1000</td><td>$1400</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>USA high quality x 1000</td><td>$1700</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>CA high quality x 1000</td><td>$1500</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>UK high quality x 1000</td><td>$2000</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Android x 1000</td><td>$600</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Premium x 1000</td><td>$6000</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://www.privacyaffairs.com/dark-web-price-index-2020/#7">DDoS Attack</a></td><td>Unprotected website, 10-50k requests per second, 1 hour</td><td>$10</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Unprotected website, 10-50k requests per second, 24 hours</td><td>$60</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Unprotected website, 10-50k requests per second, 1 week<br> <a id="mcegrid91" href="https://www.privacyaffairs.com/wp-admin/post.php?post=7083&amp;action=edit#" data-mce-x="1" data-mce-y="9"></a></td><td>$400+</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Unprotected website, 10-50k requests per second, 1 month</td><td>$800+</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Premium protected website, 20-50k requests per second, multiple elite proxies, 24 hours</td><td>$200</td></tr></tbody></table></section><div><section id="1"><h2>What We Found</h2><p>Whilst there are many marketplaces on the dark web, there are even more forum posts warning of scammers. This makes verified prices difficult to obtain without ordering the items to find out, which of course we didn’t.</p><p>Our methodology was to scan dark web marketplaces, forums, and websites, to create an index of the average prices for a range of specific products.</p><p>We were only interested in products and services relating to personal data, counterfeit documents, and social media.</p><p>This is what we found.</p></section><section id="2"><h2>Cloned credit cards and associated data</h2><table><tbody><tr><td>Product</td><td>Average dark web Price (USD)</td></tr><tr><td>Cloned Mastercard with PIN</td><td>$15</td></tr><tr><td>Cloned American Express with PIN</td><td>$35</td></tr><tr><td>Cloned VISA with PIN</td><td>$25</td></tr><tr><td>Credit card details, account balance up to $1000</td><td>$12</td></tr><tr><td>Credit card details, account balance up to $5000</td><td>$20</td></tr><tr><td>Stolen online banking logins, minimum $100 on account</td><td>$35</td></tr><tr><td>Stolen online banking logins, minimum $2000 on account</td><td>$65</td></tr><tr><td>Walmart account with credit card attached</td><td>$10</td></tr></tbody></table><p>Credit card details usually come in the format CC|MM|YY|CVV|HOLDER_NAME|ZIP|CITY|ADDRESS|EMAIL|PHONE with the first 4 sections being the details on the card and the rest the details of the account holder. This will definitely cause a major inconvenience, but the prospect of someone using your online banking logins to gain full access to your account is far more daunting.</p><p><a href="https://mk0privacyaffaidetc8.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Screenshot-1040-e1590230436263.png"><img src="https://mk0privacyaffaidetc8.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Screenshot-1040-e1590230436263.png" data-src="https://mk0privacyaffaidetc8.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Screenshot-1040-e1590230436263.png" alt="Dark web credit card price" width="840" height="447"></a></p><p>Vendors tend to offer a guarantee of 80%. Meaning that two of every ten cards either won’t work or will have less than the advertised balance. We didn’t order any so can’t verify whether this is true, but the prevalence of these claims alongside the well documented increase in identity fraud cases suggests that there is a high turnover of such data.</p></section><section id="3"><h2>Payment processing services</h2><table><tbody><tr><td>Product</td><td>&nbsp;Average dark web Price (USD)</td></tr><tr><td>Stolen PayPal account details, minimum $100</td><td>$198.56</td></tr><tr><td>PayPal transfer from stolen account, $1000 – $3000</td><td>$320.39</td></tr><tr><td>PayPal transfers from stolen account, $3000+</td><td>$155.94</td></tr><tr><td>Western Union transfer from stolen account, above $1000</td><td>$98.15</td></tr></tbody></table><p>PayPal account details were easily the most common items listed, and extremely cheap. More expensive was actual transfers from a hacked account.</p><p>Another very common item for sale was guides on how to “cash out” – actually get the money in a way that doesn’t alert the authorities. These guides go for a few cents, but whether or not they actually work is not what we were looking for.</p></section><section id="4"><h2>Forged documents</h2><table><tbody><tr><td>Product</td><td>&nbsp;Average dark web Price (USD)</td></tr><tr><td>US driving license, average quality</td><td>$70</td></tr><tr><td>US driving license, high quality</td><td>$550</td></tr><tr><td>Auto insurance card</td><td>$70</td></tr><tr><td>AAA emergency road service membership card</td><td>$70</td></tr><tr><td>Wells Fargo bank statement</td><td>$25</td></tr><tr><td>Wells Fargo bank statement with transactions</td><td>$80</td></tr><tr><td>Rutgers State University student ID</td><td>$70</td></tr><tr><td>US, Canada, or Europe passport</td><td>$1500</td></tr><tr><td>Europe national ID card</td><td>$550</td></tr></tbody></table><p>These documents came with a range of guarantees and are available with any details the buyer chooses. With just a few pieces of real information about someone, a criminal could create a whole file of official documents to be used for all sorts of fraudulent activities. This one way in which an identity is stolen.</p><h3>Counterfeit money</h3><p>Counterfeit banknotes are extremely common, mainly in 20 or 50 denominations.</p><p>We came across USD, EUR, GBP, CAD, AUD most often. Some come with a UV pen test guarantee. The “quality” ones tend to cost around 30% of the banknote value.</p></section><section id="5"><h2>Social media</h2><table><tbody><tr><td>Product</td><td>&nbsp;Average dark web Price (USD)</td></tr><tr><td>Hacked Facebook account</td><td>$74.5</td></tr><tr><td>Hacked Instagram account</td><td>$55.45</td></tr><tr><td>Hacked Twitter account<a id="mcegrid91" href="https://www.privacyaffairs.com/wp-admin/post.php?post=7083&amp;action=edit#" data-mce-x="1" data-mce-y="9"></a></td><td>$49</td></tr><tr><td>Hacked Gmail account</td><td>$155.73</td></tr><tr><td>Instagram followers x 1000</td><td>$7</td></tr><tr><td>Spotify followers x 1000</td><td>$3</td></tr><tr><td>Twitch followers x 1000</td><td>$6</td></tr><tr><td>Tick Tok followers x 1000</td><td>$15</td></tr><tr><td>LinkedIn followers x 1000</td><td>$10</td></tr><tr><td>LinkedIn company page followers x 1000</td><td>$10</td></tr><tr><td>Pinterest followers x 1000</td><td>$5</td></tr><tr><td>Soundcloud plays x 1000</td><td>$1</td></tr><tr><td>Daily Motion views x 1000</td><td>$2</td></tr><tr><td>Twitter retweets x 1000</td><td>$25</td></tr><tr><td>Instagram likes x 1000</td><td>$6</td></tr></tbody></table><p>Offers to hack accounts or sell them were relatively scarce, but not non-existent. Perhaps due to a lack of demand for the product coupled with increased security practices. Hackers trying to get the social media credentials from their victims mostly have to resort to using <a href="https://www.getsafeonline.org/blog/what-is-pii-and-how-do-you-keep-it-private/">social engineering techniques</a>, which have a very high effort input for relatively low success ratio.</p><p>The extremely low cost for social engagement should seriously make you question an account’s validity before blindly trusting their wealth of social currency.</p></section><section id="6"><h2>Malware</h2><table><tbody><tr><td>Product</td><td>&nbsp;Average dark web Price (USD)</td></tr><tr><td>Global low quality, slow speed, low success rate x 1000</td><td>$70</td></tr><tr><td>Europe low quality, slow speed, low success rate x 1000</td><td>$300</td></tr><tr><td>USA, CA, UK, AU low quality, slow speed, low success rate x 1000<a id="mcegrid91" href="https://www.privacyaffairs.com/wp-admin/post.php?post=7083&amp;action=edit#" data-mce-x="1" data-mce-y="9"></a></td><td>$800</td></tr><tr><td>Global med quality, 70% success rate x 1000</td><td>$80</td></tr><tr><td>Europe med quality, 70% success rate x 1000</td><td>$700</td></tr><tr><td>USA only med quality, 70% success rate x 1000</td><td>$900+</td></tr><tr><td>USA, CA, UK, AU med quality, 70% success rate x 1000</td><td>$1300</td></tr><tr><td>Europe fresh high quality x 1000</td><td>$2300</td></tr><tr><td>Europe aged high quality x 1000</td><td>$1400</td></tr><tr><td>USA high quality x 1000</td><td>$1700</td></tr><tr><td>CA high quality x 1000</td><td>$1500</td></tr><tr><td>UK high quality x 1000</td><td>$2000</td></tr><tr><td>Android x 1000</td><td>$600</td></tr><tr><td>Premium x 1000</td><td>$6000</td></tr></tbody></table><p>Malicious tools are installed on comprised systems (Windows, Android and others) which gives attackers access to the system. Initial installation is via fake online casino, FB/social networks, warez websites etc.</p><p>Some forms of malware may simply use your computer’s resources for activities such as cryptocurrency mining. Others may be used to steal credentials as you enter them on a website. For each 1000 installs, hackers can often steal tens of thousands of dollars.</p></section><section id="7"><h2>DDoS attack</h2><table><tbody><tr><td>Product</td><td>&nbsp;Average dark web Price (USD)</td></tr><tr><td>Unprotected website, 10-50k requests per second, 1 hour</td><td>$10</td></tr><tr><td>Unprotected website, 10-50k requests per second, 24 hours</td><td>$60</td></tr><tr><td>Unprotected website, 10-50k requests per second, 1 week<br> <a id="mcegrid91" href="https://www.privacyaffairs.com/wp-admin/post.php?post=7083&amp;action=edit#" data-mce-x="1" data-mce-y="9"></a></td><td>$400+</td></tr><tr><td>Unprotected website, 10-50k requests per second, 1 month</td><td>$800+</td></tr><tr><td>Premium protected website, 20-50k requests per second, multiple elite proxies, 24 hours</td><td>$200</td></tr></tbody></table><p>A distributed denial of service (DDoS) attack aims to take a website offline by sending thousands of requests per second in order to overload the website’s server, causing it to crash.</p></section><section id="8"><h2>Why This Data Is Important</h2><p>For the average person, underground market data isn’t necessarily going to provide much use as they most likely aren’t shopping around for stolen card data or PayPal accounts. Though this is true, the prices at which these items sell provide a powerful perspective.</p><p>If someone gets their hands on your financial details or social media credentials, the prices mentioned above is basically what it’s worth to them. There’s a good chance that you value these things much more than they do, as to them you’re just another mark for a quick buck.</p><p>For far less than the amount your data would sell for on the black market, you can protect it from ever having to reach their hands with a couple of simple rules and habits. With this knowledge, there’s no excuse not to do what you can to protect your data.</p><p>Nothing is foolproof however, and …</p></section></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.privacyaffairs.com/dark-web-price-index-2020/">https://www.privacyaffairs.com/dark-web-price-index-2020/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.privacyaffairs.com/dark-web-price-index-2020/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23818727</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 09:08:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Tutorial sites treating FreeBSD like a Linux distro]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 66 | Comments 77 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23818702">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
July 13, 2020 | https://rubenerd.com/tutorial-sites-treating-freebsd-like-a-linux-distro/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rubenerd.com/tutorial-sites-treating-freebsd-like-a-linux-distro/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="articleBody">
<p>On the Gold Coast in January, Deb Goodkin from the FreeBSD Foundation began her Linux.conf.au talk with an intentionally-provocative slide: <em>FreeBSD, that’s just another Linux distro, right?</em> It was said in jest to highlight what a common misconception it is.</p>
<p>One way this manifests is through introductory FreeBSD guides online, usually on blogs with the words sysadmin, cookbook, or tutorial in their names; you know the ones I’m talking about. Invariably they advise updating the base system and pkgng, then immediately installing bash, nano, htop, lsof, coreutils, proc, and more. Some go as far as aliasing these over the built-in tools, and even setting bash as the root shell. From then on, you barely have to touch the FreeBSD userland.</p>
<p>Like a poorly-maintained cheese utensil, this used to grate. If you’re installing an entire GNU toolchain, why not use a Linux distribution, or Debian/kFreeBSD, or a Nexenta-like OS that’s built specifically for those tools? You’re not learning about FreeBSD’s features, nor are you taking advantage of any of its benefits beyond the kernel and base. It’s wasted opportunity, and could render future project contributions more difficult because of misunderstood assumptions about how the system works.</p>
<p><img src="https://rubenerd.com/files/2020/usebsd-pillow@1x.jpg" srcset="https://rubenerd.com/files/2020/usebsd-pillow@1x.jpg 1x, https://rubenerd.com/files/2020/usebsd-pillow@2x.jpg 2x" alt="A photo of a pillow saying: Use BSD"></p>
<p>I’ve since changed my tune somewhat, with a caveat. I also want to take this opportunity— not a sponsor—to spruik Jay Patel’s <a href="https://www.redbubble.com/people/jaypatelani/shop">RedBubble store</a> for your BSD laptop and loungeroom. I’ve already added some to next sticker batch.</p>
<p>What was I talking about?</p>
<p>We should be encouraging Linux people to try FreeBSD, and if giving them their familiar tooling gets their foot in the door, it’s worth it. I personally learn things the quickest by jumping in the deep end, but I know others want to take things a step at a time.</p>
<p>What also gets lost in the fray is FreeBSD, even with all those Linux-focused tools, is still a compelling and useful operating system. It’s a feature not a bug to be able to have all these tools available, and at times run them faster than Linux could on the same hardware. It may even integrate better into shops that otherwise entirely run Linux, given the motivation to write portable, POSIX-compliant code and applications is no longer a priority for most people (sadface).</p>
<p>So rather than saying those guides aren’t useful or even misrepresent FreeBSD, we need to reframe them. Instead of <em>introductions to FreeBSD</em>, say they’re <em>FreeBSD for Linux people</em>. This shouldn’t be constued as criticism; the latter kinds of post would be <em>hugely</em> useful. It’s also then easier to introduce BSD-specific tools and ideas, either inline after each Linuxism you introduce, or in a follow-up post where you compare and contrast.</p>
<p>We need more bridge-building and outreach between the two communities, and anything to make FreeBSD relatable to people coming from Linux, or any other operating system, is useful.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rubenerd.com/tutorial-sites-treating-freebsd-like-a-linux-distro/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23818702</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 09:02:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Rust Is Surprisingly Good as a Server Language]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 306 | Comments 326 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23817464">thread link</a>) | @signa11
<br/>
July 12, 2020 | https://stu2b50.dev/posts/rust-is-surpris76171 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://stu2b50.dev/posts/rust-is-surpris76171">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="layout">
      <div id="main">
        

    

    <div>
        
<p>At some point, I got tired of my old static site generator setup for my blogs and other pages. It was annoying to ssh every time I wanted to make a modification, it was annoying to sftp or sshfs all my images, and so forth. And god forbid, if you ever wanted someone else to write something or make an edit, let me tell you, most people are not particularly happy when you tell him "hey, I'll make you a user on my server, give me your public key so you can ssh in".</p>
<p>I wanted something with a <em>little</em> more dynamism. </p>
<p>So that was the project: a small scope blog, where a few, already <em>trusted</em> users can make, edit, and post new pages in markdown (with a nice markdown editor courtesy of <a href="https://simplemde.com/">SimpleMDE</a>). Additionally, I want a built in jank verison of imgur so I can satisfy my need to be self sufficient without going crazy.</p>
<p>So while I could whip something up in an afternoon with Django, I could also experiment with other languages. The project is simple enough that I can't imagine being too limited by any language's ecosystem. And I've been itching to write something substansive in Rust...</p>
<h3>Which framework?</h3>
<p>The biggest framework is probably <code>actix-web</code>. But</p>
<ol>
<li>When I was scoping out my options months ago, actix-web's maintainer quit with a bunch of drama</li>
<li>At least from what I could tell reading the docs, it seems more suited to APIs rather than servers serving templated HTML</li>
<li>With the above, I wanted this to be a weekend project, not a weekly project, so the more batteries included the better</li>
<li>I really don't want to figure out which async library is considered better. And note that with each async library, comes its own ecosystem of libraries, which only work with that async library, so it's a pretty hard decision to reverse after you made it.</li>
</ol>
<p>So Rocket it is. </p>

<p>Something I didn't realize until I started scoping out this project is that on servers... the memory model is actually pretty simple! </p>
<p>Much of your state is just handled by your database. I <em>never</em> actually fought with the borrow checker. I never had to. For the most part, everything had exactly one owner, and exactly one lifetime: the function that's handling the request. </p>
<p>Rocket, too, has a surprising amount of "magic":</p>
<pre><code>#[get("/posts/&lt;slug&gt;/"]
pub fn post_view(slug: String) -&gt; Option&lt;Template&gt; {
    ...
		
    Some(Template::render("/posts/post", hashmap! { "post" =&gt; post}))
}
</code></pre>
<p>As opposed to Flask's</p>
<pre><code>@app.route("/posts/&lt;string:slug&gt;")
def post_view(slug):
    ...
		
    return render_template("posts/post.html", post=post)
</code></pre>
<p>Rust's macro system has really impressed me so far. Not only is there a shocking amount of "just works", but it's all statically typed and compiled.</p>
<p>The closest analogue to Rocket is flask + all the flask adjacent libraries (SQLAlchemy-flask, etc). Rocket, through the power of 3rd party integrations, comes with two template engines (handlebars, and Tera, which is basically Jinja2), database pooling support for quite a few ORMs/DB drivers, and more.</p>
<p>It's still at the point where you have to roll your own auth, though.</p>
<p>While I've heard comparisons to Django/Rails, it doesn't really seem like they're going that direction. Django/Rails purposefully put you, the developer, on the metaphorical rails, dictating best practices from everything from where the files go, to how you update your models and views. Rocket doesn't do that, and I'm not sure it should ever.</p>
<p>I also had, for the most part, the experience that "if it compiles, it works". Most of my runtime errors were in the templates, which incidentally is the only thing that's not statically typed. </p>
<p>I guess that's really what surprised me. For a lot of it, "it just works"! There's not a lot of boilerplate syntax, type inference keeps your functions clean, and I didn't write a <em>single</em> lifetime annotation at any point. My rust server really didn't look that different from my flask server, or my Django server, and honestly it looks cleaner than my Java server. All with no garbage collector or runtime.</p>

<p>Next, I'll talk about Diesel, which as far as I can see, is the most mature ORM available. While I do have my gripes, it's not really anything "objectively" bad. I suppose it's more on tradeoffs, and Diesel chooses to go light on the magic. </p>
<p>For one, it's annoying to make two structs for each table. You need one to represent the table, and one to insert with (with any autogenerated columns like the primary key removed). For instance, I have</p>
<pre><code>#[derive(Identifiable, Queryable, Associations, PartialEq, Debug, Serialize)]
#[belongs_to(BlogPosts, foreign_key="post_id")]
#[table_name = "tags"]
pub struct Tag {
    id: i32,
    tag_name: String,
    post_id: i32,
}

#[derive(Insertable)]
#[table_name = "tags"]
pub struct InsertTag {
    tag_name: String,
    post_id: i32
}
</code></pre>
<p>Additionally, while in some ORMs you write your table models, and the ORM generates your SQL migrations, in Diesel, you write your SQL migrations by hand, and the ORM generates a <code>schema.rs</code> file that contains the mappings. I actually don't mind that one too much.</p>
<p>Diesel also only supports parent-child relationships, and you have to be quite explicit. There's no magic field on your parent, that magically gives you a list of its children. No, you just have to write the query and call it. In some sense it's more like using a slightly fancier query builder.</p>
<p>Dipping down from that level of magic, it's not really a <em>bad</em> thing per se. By being explicit, you prevent users from believing too much in that magic, and shooting themselves in the foot, like N+1 selects. </p>
<p>But I'm not going to say it didn't slow me down quite a bit, either. And to be honest, writing joins was a humongous pain in the ass. Maybe that's how it should be, but maybe that also caused a generation of NoSQL databases. 🤷</p>

<p>Here's how you upload an image in flask</p>
<pre><code>@app.route('/images/upload')
def upload_file():
	files = request.files['file']
	if file and allowed_file(file.filename):
            filename = secure_filename(file.filename)
            file.save(os.path.join(app.config['UPLOAD_FOLDER'], filename))
</code></pre>
<p>Here's the "simpler" example, while using a <em>third party library in addition</em> from abonader</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/abonander/multipart/blob/master/examples/rocket.rs"><strong>See the whole thing here</strong></a></p>
<pre><code>#[post("/upload", data = "&lt;data&gt;")]
// signature requires the request to have a `Content-Type`
fn multipart_upload(cont_type: &amp;ContentType, data: Data) -&gt; Result&lt;Stream&lt;Cursor&lt;Vec&lt;u8&gt;&gt;&gt;, Custom&lt;String&gt;&gt; {
    // this and the next check can be implemented as a request guard but it seems like just
    // more boilerplate than necessary
    if !cont_type.is_form_data() {
        return Err(Custom(
            Status::BadRequest,
            "Content-Type not multipart/form-data".into()
        ));
    }

    let (_, boundary) = cont_type.params().find(|&amp;(k, _)| k == "boundary").ok_or_else(
            || Custom(
                Status::BadRequest,
                "`Content-Type: multipart/form-data` boundary param not provided".into()
            )
        )?;

    match process_upload(boundary, data) {
        Ok(resp) =&gt; Ok(Stream::from(Cursor::new(resp))),
        Err(err) =&gt; Err(Custom(Status::InternalServerError, err.to_string()))
    }
}

fn process_upload(boundary: &amp;str, data: Data) -&gt; io::Result&lt;Vec&lt;u8&gt;&gt; {
    let mut out = Vec::new();

    // saves all fields, any field longer than 10kB goes to a temporary directory
    // Entries could implement FromData though that would give zero control over
    // how the files are saved; Multipart would be a good impl candidate though
    match Multipart::with_body(data.open(), boundary).save().temp() {
        Full(entries) =&gt; process_entries(entries, &amp;mut out)?,
        Partial(partial, reason) =&gt; {
            writeln!(out, "Request partially processed: {:?}", reason)?;
            if let Some(field) = partial.partial {
                writeln!(out, "Stopped on field: {:?}", field.source.headers)?;
            }

            process_entries(partial.entries, &amp;mut out)?
        },
        Error(e) =&gt; return Err(e),
    }

    Ok(out)
}
</code></pre>
<p>Now, to be fair, Rocket is in version 0.4.5. From <a href="https://github.com/SergioBenitez/Rocket/issues/106"><strong>this github issue</strong></a>, multipart form support is coming in 0.5.0. But it doesn't change the fact that right now, the current libraries are somewhat immature still. They lack some of the edge features, especially for more traditional web servers that serve templated HTML, as opposed to pure API servers, or an SPA. </p>
<hr>
<p>Rust's errors are quite good, usually. But that's before you get into, well, libraries that try to do a bit more. I ran into some... interesting error messages, mostly from macros in Rocket and Diesel. Take a look at this one, for instance.</p>
<pre><code>the trait bound `(i32, std::string::String, std::string::String, std::string::String, i32, i32, std::string::String, i32, i32): diesel::Queryable&lt;diesel::sql_types::Nullable&lt;(diesel::sql_types::Integer, diesel::sql_types::Text, diesel::sql_types::Text, diesel::sql_types::Text, diesel::sql_types::Integer, diesel::sql_types::Integer, diesel::sql_types::Text, diesel::sql_types::Integer, diesel::sql_types::Integer)&gt;, diesel::sqlite::Sqlite&gt;` is not satisfied

the trait `diesel::Queryable&lt;diesel::sql_types::Nullable&lt;(diesel::sql_types::Integer, diesel::sql_types::Text, diesel::sql_types::Text, diesel::sql_types::Text, diesel::sql_types::Integer, diesel::sql_types::Integer, diesel::sql_types::Text, diesel::sql_types::Integer, diesel::sql_types::Integer)&gt;, diesel::sqlite::Sqlite&gt;` is not implemented for `(i32, std::string::String, std::string::String, std::string::String, i32, i32, std::string::String, i32, i32)`

help: the following implementations were found:
        &lt;(A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I) as diesel::Queryable&lt;(SA, SB, SC, SD, SE, SF, SG, SH, SI), __DB&gt;&gt;
note: required because of the requirements on the impl of `diesel::Queryable&lt;diesel::sql_types::Nullable&lt;(diesel::sql_types::Integer, diesel::sql_types::Text, diesel::sql_types::Text, diesel::sql_types::Text, diesel::sql_types::Integer, diesel::sql_types::Integer, diesel::sql_types::Text, diesel::sql_types::Integer, …</code></pre></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://stu2b50.dev/posts/rust-is-surpris76171">https://stu2b50.dev/posts/rust-is-surpris76171</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://stu2b50.dev/posts/rust-is-surpris76171</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23817464</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 05:31:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Website allows you to experience what it is like to live with dyslexia]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 420 | Comments 175 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23816678">thread link</a>) | @colinprince
<br/>
July 12, 2020 | http://geon.github.io/programming/2016/03/03/dsxyliea | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://geon.github.io/programming/2016/03/03/dsxyliea">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        


<div>
  <div>
    
<p>A friend who has dyslexia described to me how she experiences reading. She <em>can</em> read, but it takes a lot of concentration, and the letters seems to “jump around”.</p>

<p>I remembered reading about <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Typoglycemia">typoglycemia</a>. Wouldn’t it be possible to do it interactively on a website with Javascript? Sure it would.</p>

<p>Feel like making a bookmarklet of this or something? <a href="https://github.com/geon/geon.github.com/blob/master/_posts/2016-03-03-dsxyliea.md">Fork it</a> on github.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Dyslexia is characterized by difficulty with learning to read fluently and with accurate comprehension despite normal intelligence. This includes difficulty with phonological awareness, phonological decoding, processing speed, orthographic coding, auditory short-term memory, language skills/verbal comprehension, and/or rapid naming.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>Developmental reading disorder (DRD) is the most common learning disability. Dyslexia is the most recognized of reading disorders, however not all reading disorders are linked to dyslexia.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>Some see dyslexia as distinct from reading difficulties resulting from other causes, such as a non-neurological deficiency with vision or hearing, or poor or inadequate reading instruction. There are three proposed cognitive subtypes of dyslexia (auditory, visual and attentional), although individual cases of dyslexia are better explained by specific underlying neuropsychological deficits and co-occurring learning disabilities (e.g. attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder, math disability, etc.). Although it is considered to be a receptive language-based learning disability in the research literature, dyslexia also affects one’s expressive language skills. Researchers at MIT found that people with dyslexia exhibited impaired voice-recognition abilities.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><em>Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dyslexia">Wikipedia</a></em></p>






    <hr>
    
    <hr>
    


  


<p><a href="http://disqus.com/">blog comments powered by </a>




  </p></div>
  
  
</div>


      </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://geon.github.io/programming/2016/03/03/dsxyliea</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23816678</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 02:40:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Self Host a Wiki or Knowledge Base for Your Team]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 108 | Comments 69 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23816462">thread link</a>) | @chsasank
<br/>
July 12, 2020 | http://chsasank.github.io/outline-self-hosted-wiki.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://chsasank.github.io/outline-self-hosted-wiki.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
    <p>How is your startup sharing knowledge with the rest of your team?
We’ve been using slack’s <code>#general</code> or <code>#random</code> channels to make announcements.
We regularly post documents and PPTs slack channels so that they can be used by other people. We have a channel called <code>#setup</code> to post all IT related information like how to login to VPN etc.</p>

<p>But after a few weeks, these docs/notes become super hard to find. As good slack’s search is, you have to precisely know what you’re looking for. What we needed was a centralized knowledge base website - something like <a href="https://www.atlassian.com/software/confluence">Confluence</a></p>

<p>But Confluence is clunky and slow, and not cheap ($5/user). We experimented with <a href="https://tiddlywiki.com/">TiddlyWiki</a>. It calls itself ‘a non-linear personal web notebook’. It’s an opensource software which you can host on your servers or AWS. But its non linear organization makes it super unintuitive and confusing.</p>

<h2 id="why-outline">Why Outline?</h2>

<p>Then, I found <a href="https://www.getoutline.com/">outline</a>! Outline is similar to TiddlyWiki in that it’s opensource and free to self-host. Its UI is a great balance between simplicity of plain text notes and feature creep of Confluence. Login to outline is through your slack - so one less password to remember (or save). You can create private notebooks for a team or just for yourself. You can create a public link of a note so that you can share it with people outside your team - say via email.</p>

<p><span>
    Outline has great UI
</span>
<img src="https://www.getoutline.com/images/screenshot.png"></p>

<p>Best part of all of this is that <em>data doesn’t leave your servers</em> if you self-host it!
We already have a server lying around on AWS to host our own <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Python_Package_Index">python package server, pypi</a>. Since neither hosting pypi nor hosting outline are particularly intensive, we’ve hosted outline on this machine as <code>wiki.qure.ai</code>.</p>

<h2 id="install-outline">Install Outline</h2>

<p>Unfortunately, documentation for self-hosting outline is limited. There’s no robust docker-compose avaialable that you can use to directly create your server. In the rest of this post, I’ll show you how to host in your laptop or server. Before starting, make sure to install <a href="https://docs.docker.com/get-docker/">docker</a> and <a href="https://docs.docker.com/compose/install/">docker-compose</a>.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>git clone https://github.com/chsasank/outline-wiki-docker-compose.git
cd outline-wiki-docker-compose
make install
</code></pre></div></div>
<p><span>
    make install
</span>
<img src="http://chsasank.github.io/assets/images/outline/make_install.png"></p>

<p>Follow the instructions. You’ll have to create a slack app.
<span>
   Slack app
</span>
<img src="http://chsasank.github.io/assets/images/outline/slack_app.png"></p>

<p>If you want to install HTTPS:</p>



<p>Run the server:</p>



  </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://chsasank.github.io/outline-self-hosted-wiki.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23816462</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 02:00:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Build a Biotech]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 121 | Comments 22 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23816390">thread link</a>) | @apsec112
<br/>
July 12, 2020 | https://www.celinehh.com/how-to-build-a-biotech | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.celinehh.com/how-to-build-a-biotech">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main" role="main">

      

        

        <div data-content-field="main-content">
          <div data-type="page" data-updated-on="1594684464227" id="page-5e0541ebe2b52a3155df2dcb"><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-3ee5a93fdab84f05b621"><p><h3>The Summer of 2019, I gave a series of lectures to Longevity Fund’s Venture Fellows on the basics of building a biotechnology company. This is the write up of those lectures, with some additions by Laura Deming &amp; myself. </h3></p></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1577404962916_9483"><div><h2>First Steps</h2><p>You’re intrigued by biotech and want to explore ideas in the area. Where do you start? </p></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1577402821118_87823"><div><h2>Raising Money</h2><p>Science is expensive! One way to fund your work is to get venture capital (VC) investment. It’s a very different process from applying for an academic research grant. </p><p>There are a lot of excellent resources out there on raising capital.* Because of this I’ve focused here on “SF style” biotech investing, and the areas where the advice for a bio company differs from that of a tech company. </p><h3><a href="https://www.celinehh.com/vc101">VC for Bio 101</a> </h3><h3><a href="https://www.celinehh.com/investment-memo">Biotech investment memos</a></h3><p><a href="https://pmarchive.com/guide_to_startups_part1.html">*Marc Andreessen’s guide to startups</a>, the <a href="http://paulgraham.com/articles.html">PG essays</a>, and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Venture-Deals-Smarter-Lawyer-Capitalist/dp/1118443616">Venture Deals</a> are three classics</p></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1577402821118_96448"><div><h2>Building in Bio</h2><p>A bit of a deeper dive into the predominant types of drugs and the considerations around each of them. The type of drug you select impacts the safety, dosing strategy, potential efficacy, downstream price &amp; profit margin, and competitiveness of your drug. </p></div></div></div></div></div>
        </div>
      
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.celinehh.com/how-to-build-a-biotech</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23816390</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 01:46:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
