<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 10]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 10. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 08:22:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-10.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 08:22:23 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Using Obsidian to manage goals, tasks, notes, and software dev knowledge base]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 114 | Comments 68 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24206727">thread link</a>) | @sharjeelsayed
<br/>
August 18, 2020 | https://joshwin.imprint.to/post/how-i-use-obsidian-to-manage-my-goals-tasks-notes-and-software-development-knowledge-base | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://joshwin.imprint.to/post/how-i-use-obsidian-to-manage-my-goals-tasks-notes-and-software-development-knowledge-base">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>For someone who has as much experience as me in the task and note management app arenas, I believe I have finally found the tool that will serve me for many years to come. The tool is called <a href="https://obsidian.md/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Obsidian</a> and it touts itself as being "a powerful knowledge base that works on top of a local folder of plain text Markdown files." For reference, a Markdown file is a text file that is organized in a standardized way. More info can be found <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown#:~:text=Markdown%20is%20a%20lightweight%20markup,using%20a%20plain%20text%20editor." rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">here</a>. Obsidian allows you to create bidirectional links between your notes. So, instead of having your notes be siloed into different folders and subfolders, you can let your notes be automatically organized based on how they relate to similar topics and points. A lot of people like to use the brain metaphor in that the bidirectional nature resembles how our brains work and how it makes connections with everything that we are thinking and learning about. For reference, here is a screenshot of what my network of notes looked like a few days ago:</p><figure><img src="https://cosmonaut-storage.s3.amazonaws.com/241280059877739_current-note-network.png"></figure><h3>Roam Research and Why I Stopped Using It</h3><p>Before using Obsidian, I had been using <a href="https://roamresearch.com/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Roam Research</a> for about 2 months, starting in April. It calls itself the "notes tool for networked thoughts." Like many others, I was on the hype train and I had it open all day on my computer. It was that good and I understood and supported what Roam Research meant when they replied with the following regarding their planned $15 pricing policy:</p><blockquote>You're not our target user if Roam is worth less than netflix. - Roam Research (@RoamResearch) <a href="https://twitter.com/RoamResearch/status/1257863780186255364" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">May 5, 2020</a></blockquote><p>While using Roam Research, I had heard of Obsidian as being a comparable but limited alternative, but I didn't try it out until I encountered a hiccup with Roam Research's service towards the end of June. It kept deleting some text that I was trying to enter and it caused me to stop using the service that day. I had also been seeing people that were reporting data loss issues and that pushed me to give Obsidian a try. When you have someone that has made quite a bit of money <a href="https://learn.nateliason.com/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">from a course</a> on how to properly use Roam Research report data loss, it doesn't ring very well in the trust and reliability departments, especially if you are paying for the service.</p><blockquote>@RoamResearch Roam just froze and deleted everything on a super important page, is there anyway to rollback a page in a database? - Nat Eliason (@nateliason) <a href="https://twitter.com/nateliason/status/1289284989180403712" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">July 31, 2020</a></blockquote><p>I wouldn’t be surprised if the issues that I and other users encountered are because of the approach that Roam Research took when it came to developing their software. On Twitter, Sam Wight describes why he believes it wasn’t a very good one:</p><blockquote>Quick thread on @RoamResearch and *why* their software approach is not a very good one. - Sam Wight (@samwightt) <a href="https://twitter.com/samwightt/status/1271583334041255937" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">June 12, 2020</a></blockquote><p>I was actually debating whether I would mention these issues. However, as a fellow software craftsman, this is a call for <a href="https://twitter.com/Conaw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Conor</a> and his team at Roam Research to do a better job when it comes to offering a reliable service. I shouldn’t need to set up a <a href="https://medium.com/@quinten_62777/a-step-by-step-guide-to-backing-up-your-roam-research-database-356107fe82ee" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">backup system</a> myself if I’m paying for the service. With them hitting <a href="https://twitter.com/Conaw/status/1285337095167291392" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">$1 Million in Annual Recurring Revenue</a> within two months of starting to charge, I think they can take the criticism.</p><p>Now, I still wish them success with this endeavor. I'm also looking forward to seeing how much of an impact Roam Research will make in the collective knowledge management and academia <a href="https://twitter.com/RoamResearch/status/1254546642092474369" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">spaces</a>.</p><h3>My Past History with Task and Note Management Apps</h3><p>For those interested in the apps that I used for task and note management before Obsidian, here you go: (mostly chronological and from what I can remember/find the name of)</p><p><strong>Task management:</strong> Reminders (iPhone), Trello, Google Tasks, Wunderlist, Google Keep, Plan, Asana, Things, Notion, Taskful, Planny, Quire, Habitica, Focus Matrix, Coda, Sorted3, Complice, and Roam Research</p><p><strong>Note management:</strong> Notes (iPhone), Catch, Workflowy, Evernote, Google Keep, Notability, Outlinely, Milanote, Notion, Bear, Slite, and Roam Research</p><h3>My Experience with Obsidian so Far and a Rebuttal</h3><p>Regarding Obsidian, I have been enjoying the experience so far. Obviously, I have lost access to a number of features from Roam Research, i.e. filters, queries, block references (every bullet point you write is a block and you can reference all of them), and editable block embeds. However, I have been able to make do and haven't really missed them. Based on my experience and Obsidian's recent updates, don't let people like Robert Haisfield get you down with their comments:</p><blockquote>If you're using @obsdmd as though it's @RoamResearch, then you get what you pay for. I use both, and both have their strengths, but Obsidian has page level backlinks and no filtering. As soon as you get more than a few linked refs, their backlinks implementation is burdensome - Robert Haisfield (@RobertHaisfield) <a href="https://twitter.com/RobertHaisfield/status/1285383798088032257" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">July 20, 2020</a></blockquote><blockquote>Not trying to call out Justin, it's just that his tour is a visual example of this broader phenomena. Many Roam users will watch it and think to themselves "square peg, round hole" - Robert Haisfield (@RobertHaisfield) <a href="https://twitter.com/RobertHaisfield/status/1285385932112187392" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">July 20, 2020</a></blockquote><p>So, you might be wondering what he is talking about when it comes to linked references and Obsidian's backlinks implementation. In both of the following cases, for each listed reference/mention, you will see the name of the note where the note you are on is referenced and then the context in which it was used.</p><p><strong>Let's start with Roam Research:</strong></p><figure><img src="https://cosmonaut-storage.s3.amazonaws.com/360843078806628_roam%20research%20-%20linked%20refs%20-%20part%201.png"></figure><figure><img src="https://cosmonaut-storage.s3.amazonaws.com/103965367285517_roam%20research%20-%20linked%20refs%20-%20part%202.png"></figure><p>In the first picture, you will see the linked references that are at the bottom of my 🎌 Backlog Tasks note. In the second picture, you will see what happens when I click on the filter button that's to the upper right. This allows you to filter the listed blocks/references.</p><p><strong>Now, let's look at Obsidian:</strong></p><p><u>Note</u>: This is from the most recent Insider build (0.8.4).</p><figure><img src="https://cosmonaut-storage.s3.amazonaws.com/798287744589004_obsidian%20-%20linked%20refs.png"></figure><p>This is showing the linked mentions for a goal of mine that was related to setting up a tech-focused online social for my hometown. The great thing about this version is that Obsidian has added the ability to see more of the context around the linked mention. Additionally, they have added the ability to collapse linked/unlinked mention results. They don't offer the ability to filter mentions at the moment, but it would make sense for them to eventually add it.</p><p>The solution that's better, at the moment, depends on the type of user you are. If you are a full-time researcher or writer, I can see Roam's approach being more valuable, especially if you want to copy all your past work into it and see what type of connections you can discover. If you are someone that blogs on a casual basis, you probably won't see the lack of linked reference/mention filtering as a deal-breaker. With my workflow that does treat Obsidian like Roam (to a point), I actually haven't missed this feature.</p><p>However, I do see the benefits of it. So, if I don't create it, someone else in the community will make a more extensive backlinks plugin that supports filtering when Obsidian's <a href="https://trello.com/c/Z7qqKVXd/19-public-plugin-api-v10" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">plugin API</a> is released. And, even if the API doesn't include what's needed to do this, Obsidian will be incentivized to add this feature themselves if there's enough of a demand. There's already <a href="https://forum.obsidian.md/t/filtering-everywhere/163" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">a post that asks for this feature</a> on their forum.</p><h3>Why I Believe in Obsidian's Future</h3><p>Besides what I have stated above, these are the main reasons why I'm flying the Obsidian banner:</p><p><strong>Future-Proof:</strong> Your notes are future-proof since they use Markdown and not some type of proprietary format.</p><p><strong>Portability:</strong> You don't have to rely on Obsidian's servers in order to access your notes. You can use iCloud, Google Drive, other cloud storage providers, or even roll your own server.</p><p><strong>Safe and Private:</strong> If you use a cloud storage provide to store your notes, you won't have to worry about issues of data loss or your data getting into the wrong hands. I don't think I'm alone in saying that I trust players like Google and Apple more than smaller players (including the app developers themselves) when it comes to the security of my data.</p><p><strong>Extendability:</strong> Obsidian uses 19 core plugins to function and there's more to come. The great thing is that we will be able to install third party plugins and be able to build our own in the future as well. If you keep reading, you will see what type of plugin I have in mind.</p><p><strong>Good mobile experience:</strong> Obsidian doesn't have a mobile app yet. However, with me storing my notes in iCloud, I have easy access to my notes using <a href="https://ia.net/writer" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">iA Writer</a> on my iPhone. As a side note, if you also have an iPhone, I strongly recommend that you use iCloud to store your notes. I tried to use Google Drive, but I couldn't add new notes without manually moving them from the iCloud area in iA Writer to the Google Drive folder that I was using for my notes.</p><p>Now, let's get into the real meat of this article.</p><h2>Goal Management</h2><p>So, when it comes to managing my goals, I like to break things down. For each of my goals, I break them down into three parts: the overarching goal, the included milestones, and the intentions that are associated with each milestone. Here's a diagram (created using Obsidian via their support for <a href="https://mermaid-js.github.io/mermaid/#/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Mermaid diagrams</a>):</p><figure><img src="https://cosmonaut-storage.s3.amazonaws.com/600349239113337_goal%20management%20diagram.png"></figure><p>For reference, I got the the term intention from <a href="https://complice.co/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Complice</a> and intentions are the main way in which I chip away at a goal. A key part of my system is that I like to specify the item's type, title, and whether they have been completed in the item's name. This helps me focus on one item at a time. When it comes to the completion state, I use the "🗙" character for incomplete items, 🚧 for in progress items, ✅ for completed items, and 🚨 for items where my plans have changed and I need to edit them. I add emojis and a dash in the front of goals and milestones. As a way to make my life easier, I use <a href="https://www.alfredapp.com/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Alfred's</a> text expansion feature in order to speed up the creation of note titles and their associated contents. At the end of this article, you will find a link to a starter kit/vault that includes all of these, an Alfred workflow, and a vault that follows the Obsidian workflow that is described in this article.</p><p><u>Note</u>: If the above character for incomplete items looks off, this is what it looks …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://joshwin.imprint.to/post/how-i-use-obsidian-to-manage-my-goals-tasks-notes-and-software-development-knowledge-base">https://joshwin.imprint.to/post/how-i-use-obsidian-to-manage-my-goals-tasks-notes-and-software-development-knowledge-base</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://joshwin.imprint.to/post/how-i-use-obsidian-to-manage-my-goals-tasks-notes-and-software-development-knowledge-base</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24206727</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 02:59:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Cerebras Wafer Scale Engine Gen2 7nm 2.6T Transistors]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 51 | Comments 46 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24206308">thread link</a>) | @ramshanker
<br/>
August 18, 2020 | https://www.servethehome.com/cerebras-wafer-scale-engine-gen2-7nm-2-6t-transistors/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.servethehome.com/cerebras-wafer-scale-engine-gen2-7nm-2-6t-transistors/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <!-- image --><div><figure><a href="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Cerebras-WSE-Tesla-V100-Side-by-Side.jpg" data-caption="Cerebras WSE Tesla V100 Side By Side"><img width="696" height="396" src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Cerebras-WSE-Tesla-V100-Side-by-Side-696x396.jpg" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Cerebras-WSE-Tesla-V100-Side-by-Side-696x396.jpg 696w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Cerebras-WSE-Tesla-V100-Side-by-Side-400x228.jpg 400w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Cerebras-WSE-Tesla-V100-Side-by-Side-738x420.jpg 738w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Cerebras-WSE-Tesla-V100-Side-by-Side.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px" alt="Cerebras WSE Tesla V100 Side By Side" title="Cerebras WSE Tesla V100 Side By Side"></a><figcaption>Cerebras WSE Tesla V100 Side By Side</figcaption></figure></div>
            <!-- content --><p>Just before the global shutdown stopped international travel, I remember a Wednesday in January 2020 very well. I drove over to Cerebras Systems one town over in Los Altos, California to<a href="https://www.servethehome.com/our-interview-with-andrew-feldman-ceo-of-cerebras-systems/"> Interview Andrew Feldman</a> the company’s CEO. At Hot Chips 31 (2019) Cerebras was the standout as we covered in <a href="https://www.servethehome.com/cerebras-wafer-scale-engine-ai-chip-is-largest-ever/">Cerebras Wafer Scale Engine AI chip is Largest Ever</a>. I had the opportunity to first see the system built around the WSE, the <a href="https://www.servethehome.com/cerebras-cs-1-wafer-scale-ai-system-at-sc19/">Cerebras CS-1 Wafer-Scale AI System,</a> at SC19. At Hot Chips 32, Cerebras disclosed some details of its new chip the WSE Gen2.<span id="more-46406"></span></p>
<h2>Cerebras Wafer Scale Engine Gen2</h2>
<p>The Cerebras WSE Gen2 offers absolutely huge numbers. For some scale, the Xilinx Versal Premium’s top-end multi-chip package FPGA we covered today, that uses CoWoS to bind together multiple chips, tops out at 92 billion transistors. For GPUs the <a href="https://www.servethehome.com/nvidia-tesla-a100-ampere-resets-the-entire-ai-industry/">NVIDIA A100</a> has around 54 billion transistors. In contrast, the Cerebras WSE Gen2 encompasses 2.6 trillion transistors. That is on a single chip. These are all on 7nm TSMC processes.</p>
<figure id="attachment_46407" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-46407"><a href="https://www.servethehome.com/cerebras-wafer-scale-engine-gen2-7nm-2-6t-transistors/hot-chips-32-cerebras-wse-gen2/" rel="attachment wp-att-46407"><img src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Hot-Chips-32-Cerebras-WSE-Gen2.jpg" alt="Hot Chips 32 Cerebras WSE Gen2" width="1522" height="880" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Hot-Chips-32-Cerebras-WSE-Gen2.jpg 1522w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Hot-Chips-32-Cerebras-WSE-Gen2-400x231.jpg 400w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Hot-Chips-32-Cerebras-WSE-Gen2-800x463.jpg 800w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Hot-Chips-32-Cerebras-WSE-Gen2-696x402.jpg 696w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Hot-Chips-32-Cerebras-WSE-Gen2-1068x618.jpg 1068w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Hot-Chips-32-Cerebras-WSE-Gen2-726x420.jpg 726w" sizes="(max-width: 1522px) 100vw, 1522px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-46407">Hot Chips 32 Cerebras Wafer Scale Engine Gen2</figcaption></figure>
<p>This 850 AI optimized core chip is already back at Cerebras headquarters. Likely it is in the same lab we toured earlier this year in Los Altos. This is the only photo we could take from the lab:</p>
<figure id="attachment_40842" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-40842"><a href="https://www.servethehome.com/our-interview-with-andrew-feldman-ceo-of-cerebras-systems/cerebras-cs-1-3-stack-in-rack/" rel="attachment wp-att-40842"><img src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Cerebras-CS-1-3-Stack-in-Rack.jpg" alt="Cerebras CS 1 3 Stack In Rack" width="456" height="800" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Cerebras-CS-1-3-Stack-in-Rack.jpg 456w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Cerebras-CS-1-3-Stack-in-Rack-171x300.jpg 171w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Cerebras-CS-1-3-Stack-in-Rack-239x420.jpg 239w" sizes="(max-width: 456px) 100vw, 456px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-40842">Cerebras CS 1 3 Stack In Rack</figcaption></figure>
<p>If you are wondering what that is, it is a fully integrated rack of Cerebras CS-1 systems that are being designed for high-density with cooling and power integrated. Cooling was being provided, in this case, not by air, but by facility water, for the specific customer, it was being designed for. That gives one some sense of the demand that Cerebras is seeing. They are beyond the phase of customers looking for single systems and are moving to customers purchasing many systems and asking for higher integration.</p>
<figure id="attachment_40839" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-40839"><a href="https://www.servethehome.com/our-interview-with-andrew-feldman-ceo-of-cerebras-systems/cerebras-hq-q1-2020-lobby/" rel="attachment wp-att-40839"><img src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Cerebras-HQ-Q1-2020-Lobby.jpg" alt="Cerebras HQ Q1 2020 Lobby" width="1203" height="876" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Cerebras-HQ-Q1-2020-Lobby.jpg 1203w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Cerebras-HQ-Q1-2020-Lobby-400x291.jpg 400w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Cerebras-HQ-Q1-2020-Lobby-800x583.jpg 800w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Cerebras-HQ-Q1-2020-Lobby-324x235.jpg 324w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Cerebras-HQ-Q1-2020-Lobby-696x507.jpg 696w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Cerebras-HQ-Q1-2020-Lobby-1068x778.jpg 1068w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Cerebras-HQ-Q1-2020-Lobby-577x420.jpg 577w" sizes="(max-width: 1203px) 100vw, 1203px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-40839">Cerebras HQ Q1 2020 Lobby</figcaption></figure>
<p>One of the benefits of the giant WSE structure is that it eliminates an extraordinarily amount of chassis, PCB, cooling, networking, and other components from AI clusters.</p>
<h2>Final Words</h2>
<p>The Cerebras Wafer Scale Engine Gen2 is very exciting. Cerebras declined to comment on the amount of SRAM on-chip, but there is a good chance it has scaled with the number of cores. We expect more information is coming later this year. Hopefully, one of these days I will be able to head over to the Cerebras lab again and see the WSE Gen2 in-person to see if the Cerebras lobby skeleton has managed to thrive through the global pandemic.</p>
<p>The big question we have now is will the CS-1 get a WSE Gen2 upgrade, or will we get a CS-2?</p>
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.servethehome.com/cerebras-wafer-scale-engine-gen2-7nm-2-6t-transistors/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24206308</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 01:35:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Supply chain analysis of iPhone 5c cases and the pencil marks hidden inside them]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 14 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24206196">thread link</a>) | @pencerw
<br/>
August 18, 2020 | https://theprepared.org/features/production-marks | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://theprepared.org/features/production-marks">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="canvas">
		

		
		
		
			
				
			
		

		<main id="main" role="main">
			<div data-content-field="main-content">
				<section>

	
		<article id="article-5f32f7c917455f36a24d2d16" data-item-id="5f32f7c917455f36a24d2d16">

			
			

			

			<div>
				
					<div data-layout-label="Post Body" data-type="item" data-updated-on="1597177587323" id="item-5f32f7c917455f36a24d2d16"><div><div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597243589269_22379"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/594027566b8f5b6f0abad495/1597340137228-ZQSM75JH3UJOEJIRZO8H/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kCyMnPbmjX24sPS4sEPdsyJ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0r9YoV8ytu8SWDj21Bt3yU9MPGB0o2yMnHbCRIYfqkEhOh17coTfA3v9Ink498pYiQ/all+phones-Edit.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/594027566b8f5b6f0abad495/1597340137228-ZQSM75JH3UJOEJIRZO8H/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kCyMnPbmjX24sPS4sEPdsyJ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0r9YoV8ytu8SWDj21Bt3yU9MPGB0o2yMnHbCRIYfqkEhOh17coTfA3v9Ink498pYiQ/all+phones-Edit.jpg" data-image-dimensions="2500x1277" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Why are iPhone 5c cases, in all of their platonic perfection, covered with pencil marks?" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f3579d4c168d74a55a2f19c" data-type="image" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/594027566b8f5b6f0abad495/1597340137228-ZQSM75JH3UJOEJIRZO8H/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kCyMnPbmjX24sPS4sEPdsyJ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0r9YoV8ytu8SWDj21Bt3yU9MPGB0o2yMnHbCRIYfqkEhOh17coTfA3v9Ink498pYiQ/all+phones-Edit.jpg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
          
          <figcaption>
            <p>Why are iPhone 5c cases, in all of their platonic perfection, covered with pencil marks?</p>
          </figcaption>
        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-dafd753e6ba74b843441"><div><p>My class on media archaeology has a regular assignment where students conduct a “product autopsy,” tearing down old (and hopefully inoperable) gadgets to understand their origins and supply chains. Mobile phones are a favorite example, both because of their intricacy and because few students have seen inside them. The assignment requires learning to recognize not only individual components (camera sensors; capacitors; wire assemblies), but the language of contemporary manufacture, discerning the meaning of circuit boards, barcodes, and part numbers. It is, I think, a popular assignment—but it is rarely a surprising one. While the devices we have dissected over the years have spanned a range of models and manufacturers, they tend to be similar, and filled with similar sorts of symbols.&nbsp;</p><p>But when my students found what looked to be pencil markings on the interior of an iPhone 5c, we were surprised. Just what were these scribbles, and how did they get there? To answer these questions was not just to follow this broken object’s supply chain back to its moment of assembly, but also to understand what it meant for these marks to be made in the first place.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597243589269_303210"><p>The history of a product is told by the marks of its making. Early commodities were made things, and they brought with them the literal <a href="https://www.google.com/books/edition/Looking_at_Jewelry/SLWbDwAAQBAJ?hl=en&amp;gbpv=1&amp;dq=hallmark%20goldsmith&amp;pg=PA17&amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;bsq=hallmark%20goldsmith">hallmarks</a> of manufacture. Stamps and seals encoded an originary identity connected to an individual craft hall and craftsperson, promising that an object had been “made in” Sheffield, for example, <a href="https://supplystudies.com/2017/07/26/the-making-of-made-in/">or Solingen</a>. But beyond these obvious indications was the language of assembly itself: The unfinished sides, unraveled threads, and slips of hammer and chisel that until recently marked our manufacture. Heavily accented and regional, this was a kind of communication visible to all but comprehensible only to craftspeople. These were the human signs of production.</p></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597175695722_17903"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/594027566b8f5b6f0abad495/1597329301947-GMZGGXM295I1YP9TLHKJ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIQAUsdUBAN3RLmyo12mnkQUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKcG8RtdOIYmw75e04wuUS8EnVYAjW8LH3bL9OUUQfw5EoaQHxLJ6DXmVUDqtF_Yz4n/production_marks-8.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/594027566b8f5b6f0abad495/1597329301947-GMZGGXM295I1YP9TLHKJ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIQAUsdUBAN3RLmyo12mnkQUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKcG8RtdOIYmw75e04wuUS8EnVYAjW8LH3bL9OUUQfw5EoaQHxLJ6DXmVUDqtF_Yz4n/production_marks-8.jpg" data-image-dimensions="1380x614" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Inspection sticker from interior case of IBM &quot;Model M&quot; keyboard, 1987. Today, hand-inked initials are rarely seen on inspection tags." data-load="false" data-image-id="5f354f9528560b69e222e130" data-type="image" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/594027566b8f5b6f0abad495/1597329301947-GMZGGXM295I1YP9TLHKJ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIQAUsdUBAN3RLmyo12mnkQUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKcG8RtdOIYmw75e04wuUS8EnVYAjW8LH3bL9OUUQfw5EoaQHxLJ6DXmVUDqtF_Yz4n/production_marks-8.jpg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
          
          <figcaption>
            <p>Inspection sticker from interior case of IBM "Model M" keyboard, 1987. Today, hand-inked initials are rarely seen on inspection tags.</p>
          </figcaption>
        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597329263642_52497"><div><p>For casual consumers, an object’s story was confined to the inspection tickets and product tags attached at the end of its manufacture. Of these, only tags remain a familiar sight. But even when they are present—marking out something as “designed in California” or (perhaps grudgingly) “made in China”—they are often frustratingly general. There is nothing tying them to a particular object, after all, only to a particular product line. And while inspection tickets were once ubiquitous, they’re far less common now. Their initialed signatures may have identified their human inspectors only as no. 3 or 6, but they still assured us that each item on the assembly line had undergone some final, individual appraisal. Stuck to the backs of radios and slipped into the pockets of pants, these marks may have been of interest only to cranks and romantics. But the doctor and Poet John Stone’s <em>Poem in Praise of Perfect Pants</em> spoke of these inspection tickets as “a charm,” protecting its bearer:</p><blockquote><p>against all future irregulars</p><p>which may have been inspected</p><p>and sent away</p><p>without love…</p></blockquote><p>But what does it mean when even these messages are gone? If this fleeting charm has failed us, do we still retain the personal connection to production we might once have had?</p><p>Open up old electronics and you will find obvious evidence of the hands that made them: Blobs of unsightly solder, wires that jump in often unexpected directions. Their modern descendants reveal comparatively little of their inner life. Loosed from white cardboard packaging, their functional parts are covered with layers of protective presentation. Seeming no earthly thing (though surely it is the most rare of earth from which they are made), their polished appearance serves only to mask the signs and signals of production. They are perfect. Smooth and seamless, they have no chips, scuffs, or scratches. As <a href="https://www.ifixit.com/Right-to-Repair/Intro">inaccessible</a> as the brands that branded them, it is <a href="https://repair.org/electronics">impossible</a> to imagine the realities of production outside an abstract assemblage of assembly. There are no fingerprints on these reflective surfaces. Other than in <a href="http://www.followthethings.com/iphonegirl.shtml">the rarest of circumstances</a>, we see in them only the blank expressions of our own faces, amazed by the wonder of their construction.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597175695722_21658"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/594027566b8f5b6f0abad495/1597337531850-I3WOJW0J8HXW0609XUP1/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kM8JA-wejs7en-4jjr9BowJ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0tb-hnCqoepq4X8c1traqO-NH1tD-KJU5x2Mx0XM0NAUriZQhMBiLyc3-IdefaqU9A/exploded-5c-white-bg.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/594027566b8f5b6f0abad495/1597337531850-I3WOJW0J8HXW0609XUP1/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kM8JA-wejs7en-4jjr9BowJ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0tb-hnCqoepq4X8c1traqO-NH1tD-KJU5x2Mx0XM0NAUriZQhMBiLyc3-IdefaqU9A/exploded-5c-white-bg.jpg" data-image-dimensions="2500x1264" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="The exploded innards of an iPhone 5c, white." data-load="false" data-image-id="5f356fb4cfd3f27dc9051db2" data-type="image" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/594027566b8f5b6f0abad495/1597337531850-I3WOJW0J8HXW0609XUP1/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kM8JA-wejs7en-4jjr9BowJ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0tb-hnCqoepq4X8c1traqO-NH1tD-KJU5x2Mx0XM0NAUriZQhMBiLyc3-IdefaqU9A/exploded-5c-white-bg.jpg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
          
          <figcaption>
            <p>The exploded innards of an iPhone 5c, white.</p>
          </figcaption>
        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597175695722_21957"><div><p>Despite this veneer, modern electronics <em>are</em> inscribed with a myriad of marks—just not, strictly speaking, human ones. While manufacturing methods like the bill of materials (the BOM) are familiar to contemporary makers, their complexity is a relatively recent development—one amplified by an increasing drive toward the patterns of outsourcing and subcontracting that constitute supply chain capitalism. When computerized management first came to the shop a half century ago, the limitations of memory were so severe that early bills of material could not be recorded as single data entities. The solution was to break them into component parts, such that each part or subassembly became an individual bill with an individual shop order. As the scale of these subassemblies grew, the shop was now relegated, in the words of <a href="https://www.lillyworks.com/blog/from-ibm-to-lillyworks-an-evolution/" target="_blank">Richard Lilly</a>, to the “business of making parts instead of products.” The consequence was that these things were no longer purely human productions. Humans may (and do, more often than we think) produce modern parts, but they can no longer produce modern products.</p><p>The forms of communication that now mark these objects owes little to the history of tickets and tags. After all, reading them requires lasers rather than eyes, light sensors rather than optic nerves. A product like the iPhone, for example, is littered with nonhuman graffiti—components lined with electronic indications that attest to their assembly. Even the tiniest components now come printed with 2D barcodes. Most of these are used for process tracking and quality control purposes, though high-profile parts—like Apple’s A-series chips and the lithium-ion batteries that power them—often contain legal notices and logos. Intended either for corporations or computers, an iPhone’s internal inscriptions are an entirely nonhuman constitution—full of product codes, regulatory requirements, and business-to-business branding.</p><p>Imagine the surprise, then, when my students found pencil markings—with all of their humanity and romance and imperfection—on the interior of an otherwise unmarked iPhone 5c. Following a tedious application of heat gun and pliers to loosen the metal cage affixed to the iPhone’s back case, we found a strange and surprising sequence of numbers and letters. Some short (“B1”), some longer (“482”), and all at various angles and orientations. As marks, they were meaningless. But the marking, itself, surely had meaning.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597175695722_25231"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/594027566b8f5b6f0abad495/1597329437257-ICWNF30EVTUU79B9I0TA/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kJQZnyZNRAuEHm6sZzdAY4B7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0mwD1g8DYbkhCsgrhnj8CXblO7aoETSGZo1A1qEBtQCClU51NSN9VuKnf6KVznO_WQ/production_marks-2.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/594027566b8f5b6f0abad495/1597329437257-ICWNF30EVTUU79B9I0TA/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kJQZnyZNRAuEHm6sZzdAY4B7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0mwD1g8DYbkhCsgrhnj8CXblO7aoETSGZo1A1qEBtQCClU51NSN9VuKnf6KVznO_WQ/production_marks-2.jpg" data-image-dimensions="2500x1212" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="DRD3296N6Y0FFVGCY" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f355019d414204191c13923" data-type="image" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/594027566b8f5b6f0abad495/1597329437257-ICWNF30EVTUU79B9I0TA/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kJQZnyZNRAuEHm6sZzdAY4B7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0mwD1g8DYbkhCsgrhnj8CXblO7aoETSGZo1A1qEBtQCClU51NSN9VuKnf6KVznO_WQ/production_marks-2.jpg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
          
          <figcaption>
            <p>DRD3296N6Y0FFVGCY</p>
          </figcaption>
        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597175695722_25532"><div><h2>iPhone 5c, A1532</h2><p>The iPhone 5c was released in September of 2013 alongside its upmarket counterpart, the iPhone 5s. A great deal of speculation had surrounded the introduction of this new “low-cost” iPhone, and so had a great many questions. Chief among these was what, exactly, the “C” stood for. The “S” that had appeared alongside the name of every mid-cycle revision since the 3GS had, after all, a similarly murky meaning. The first release had stood for “speed.” For the next, commentators suggested that it might represent the introduction of the Siri voice assistant. With the seventh-generation iPhone, the only significance was that Apple wouldn’t confirm one. As a consequence, an entirely new letter lent itself to seemingly intentional ambiguity.</p><p>Perhaps, some suggested, it stood for “color.” Unlike prior models, the 5c came in colors beyond the familiar black, white, and metal. These new hues included blue, green, yellow, and white, along with a pink that the company called “coral.” But while color is itself a kind of marking, the only indication of this chromatic differentiation was an internal barcode (hidden inside the iPhone’s shell) and an electronic encoding in the device’s boot ROM. A colorblind consumer would not have been able to tell the phone’s color by looking at its model number, which <a href="https://everymac.com/systems/apple/iphone/iphone-faq/differences-between-iphone-5c-models.html"><span>differentiates only by compatible carrier</span></a>. If the “c” in “5c” was a meaningful mark, it must have meant something else. Some argued that it might fit the market rather than the markings—”consumer,” perhaps, or “cost.” Others suggested a less flattering appellation, but while this phone was less expensive than Apple’s other offerings, one would be hard-pressed to describe it as “cheap.”&nbsp;</p><p>Indeed, Apple’s chief designer, Jony Ive, <a href="https://youtu.be/puo-kbtVozM?t=94">called</a> the 5c a “distillation” of what people loved about the iPhone 5, just one that was “beautifully, unapologetically, plastic.” Hewn from “a single piece of polycarbonate” and fixed to a steel reinforced frame, the materials of the case constituted a kind of “bespoke assembly.” This …</p></div></div></div></div></div></div></article></section></div></main></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://theprepared.org/features/production-marks">https://theprepared.org/features/production-marks</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://theprepared.org/features/production-marks</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24206196</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 01:16:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Consortium for Python Data API Standards]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 78 | Comments 19 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24205363">thread link</a>) | @BerislavLopac
<br/>
August 18, 2020 | https://data-apis.org/blog/announcing_the_consortium/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://data-apis.org/blog/announcing_the_consortium/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="post" itemprop="articleBody">
    
    <p>Over the past few years, Python has exploded in popularity for data science,
machine learning, deep learning and numerical computing. New frameworks
pushing forward the state of the art in these fields are appearing every
year. One unintended consequence of all this activity and creativity has been
fragmentation in the fundamental building blocks - multidimensional array
(tensor) and dataframe libraries - that underpin the whole Python data
ecosystem. For example, arrays are fragmented between Tensorflow, PyTorch,
NumPy, CuPy, MXNet, Xarray, Dask, and others. Dataframes are fragmented
between Pandas, PySpark, cuDF, Vaex, Modin, Dask, Ibis, Apache Arrow, and
more. This fragmentation comes with significant costs, from whole libraries
being reimplemented for a different array or dataframe library to end users
having to re-learn APIs and best practices when they move from one framework
to another.</p>
<p><img src="https://data-apis.org/images/ecosystem_fragmentation.png" alt="Ecosystem growing up in silos"></p>
<p>Today, we are announcing the Consortium for Python Data API Standards, which
aims to tackle this fragmentation by developing API standards for arrays
(a.k.a. tensors) and dataframes. We aim to grow this Consortium into an
organization where cross-project and cross-ecosystem alignment on APIs, data
exchange mechanisms and other such topics happens. These topics require
coordination and communication to a much larger extent than they require
technical innovation. We aim to facilitate the former, while leaving the
innovating to current and future individual libraries.</p>
<p><em>Want to get started right away? Collect data on your own API usage with</em>
<em><a href="https://github.com/data-apis/python-record-api">python-record-api</a>.</em>
<em>And for array or dataframe maintainers: we want to</em>
<em>hear what you think – see the end of this post.</em></p>
<h2 id="bootstrapping-an-organization-and-involving-the-wider-community">Bootstrapping an organization and involving the wider community</h2>
<p>The goal is ambitious, and there are obvious hurdles, such as answering
questions like “what is the impact of a technical decision on each library?”.
There’s a significant amount of engineering and technical writing to do to
create overviews and data that can be used to answer such questions. This
requires dedicated time, and hence funding, in addition to bringing
maintainers of libraries together to provide input and assess those overviews
and data. These factors motivated the following approach to bootstrapping the
Consortium:</p>
<ol>
<li>Assemble a consortium of people from interested companies (who help fund
the required engineering and technical writing time) and key community
contributors.</li>
<li>Form a working group which meets weekly for an hour, sets the high-level
goals, requirements, and user stories, and makes initial decisions.</li>
<li>Several engineers with enough bandwidth will do the heavy lifting on
building the required tooling, and preparing the data and draft docs
needed by the working group. Iterate as needed based on feedback from the
working group.</li>
<li>Once drafts of an API standard have a concrete outline, request input from
a broader group of array and dataframe library maintainers.
<em><span>This is where we are today.</span></em></li>
<li>Once tooling or drafts of the API standards get mature enough for wider review,
release them as Request for Comments (RFC) and have a public review
process. Iterate again as needed.</li>
<li>Once there’s enough buy-in for the RFCs, and it’s clear projects are able
and willing to adopt the proposed APIs, publish a 1.0 version of the
standard.</li>
</ol>
<p>Such a gradual RFC process is a bit of an experiment. Community projects
like NumPy and Pandas aren’t used to this; however, it’s similar to successful
models in other communities (e.g. the Open Geospatial Consortium, or C++
standardization) and we think the breadth of projects involved and complexity
of the challenge makes this the most promising and likely to succeed approach.
The approach will certainly evolve over time though, based on experience and
feedback from the many stakeholders.</p>
<p><img src="https://data-apis.org/images/API_standard_RFC_review_diagram.png" alt="API standard RFC development and community review"></p>
<p>There are other, synergistic activities happening in the ecosystem that are
relevant for this Consortium, that individual members are contributing to,
such as the work on
<a href="https://github.com/numpy/archive/blob/master/other_meetings/2020-04-21-array-protocols_discussion_and_notes.md">developing NumPy array protocols</a>,
and the  <code>__dataframe__</code>
<a href="https://github.com/wesm/dataframe-protocol">data interchange protocol design</a>.
The section in the <code>__array_module__</code> NEP on <a href="https://numpy.org/neps/nep-0037-array-module.html#requesting-restricted-subsets-of-numpy-s-api">“restricted subsets of NumPy’s API”</a>
gives an outline for how the API standard we’re developing can be adopted.
The <code>__dataframe__</code> protocol attempts to solve a small, well-defined problem
that is a sub-problem of the one a full dataframe API standard would solve.</p>
<h2 id="an-api-standard---what-do-we-mean-by-that">An API standard - what do we mean by that?</h2>
<p>When we start talking about an “API standard” or a formal specification, it’s
important to start by explaining both why we need it and what “API standard”
means. “Standard” is a loaded word, and “standardization” is a process that,
when done right, can have a large impact but may also evoke past experiences
that weren’t always productive.</p>
<p>We can look at an API in multiple levels of detail:</p>
<ol>
<li>Which functions, classes, class methods and other objects are in it.</li>
<li>What is the signature of each object.</li>
<li>What are the semantics of each object.</li>
</ol>
<p>When talking about <em>compatibility</em> between libraries, e.g. “the Pandas, Dask
and Vaex <code>groupby</code> methods are compatible”, we imply that the respective
dataframe objects all have a <code>groupby</code> method with the same signature and the
same semantics, so they can be used interchangeably.</p>
<p>Currently, array and dataframe libraries all have similar APIs, but with
enough differences that using them interchangeably isn’t really possible.
Here is a concrete example for a relatively simple function, <code>mean</code>, for
arrays:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="python"><span>numpy</span><span>:</span>         <span>mean</span><span>(</span><span>a</span><span>,</span> <span>axis</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>dtype</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>out</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>keepdims</span><span>=&lt;</span><span>no</span> <span>value</span><span>&gt;</span><span>)</span>
<span>dask</span><span>.</span><span>array</span><span>:</span>    <span>mean</span><span>(</span><span>a</span><span>,</span> <span>axis</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>dtype</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>out</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>keepdims</span><span>=&lt;</span><span>no</span> <span>value</span><span>&gt;</span><span>)</span>
<span>cupy</span><span>:</span>          <span>mean</span><span>(</span><span>a</span><span>,</span> <span>axis</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>dtype</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>out</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>keepdims</span><span>=</span><span>False</span><span>)</span>
<span>jax</span><span>.</span><span>numpy</span><span>:</span>     <span>mean</span><span>(</span><span>a</span><span>,</span> <span>axis</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>dtype</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>out</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>keepdims</span><span>=</span><span>False</span><span>)</span>
<span>mxnet</span><span>.</span><span>np</span><span>:</span>      <span>mean</span><span>(</span><span>a</span><span>,</span> <span>axis</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>dtype</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>out</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>keepdims</span><span>=</span><span>False</span><span>)</span>
<span>sparse</span><span>:</span>        <span>s</span><span>.</span><span>mean</span><span>(</span><span>axis</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>keepdims</span><span>=</span><span>False</span><span>,</span> <span>dtype</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>out</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>)</span>
<span>torch</span><span>:</span>         <span>mean</span><span>(</span><span>input</span><span>,</span> <span>dim</span><span>,</span> <span>keepdim</span><span>=</span><span>False</span><span>,</span> <span>out</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>)</span>
<span>tensorflow</span><span>:</span>    <span>reduce_mean</span><span>(</span><span>input_tensor</span><span>,</span> <span>axis</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>keepdims</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>name</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>,</span>   
                           <span>reduction_indices</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>keep_dims</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>)</span>
</code></pre></div><p>We see that:</p>
<ul>
<li>All libraries provide this functionality in a function called <code>mean</code>,
except (1) Tensorflow calls it <code>reduce_mean</code> and (2) PyData Sparse has a
<code>mean</code> method instead of a function (it does work with <code>np.mean</code> though via
<a href="https://numpy.org/devdocs/reference/arrays.classes.html#special-attributes-and-methods">array protocols</a>).</li>
<li>NumPy, Dask, CuPy, JAX and MXNet have compatible signatures (except the
<code>&lt;no_value&gt;</code> default for <code>keepdims</code>, which really means <code>False</code> but with
different behavior for array subclasses).</li>
<li>The semantics are harder to inspect, but will also have differences. For
example, MXNet documents: <em>This function differs from the original <code>numpy.mean</code>
in the following way(s): - only ndarray is accepted as valid input, python
iterables or scalar is not supported - default data type for integer input is
<code>float32</code></em>.</li>
</ul>
<p>An API standard will specify function presence with signature, and semantics, e.g.:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>mean(a, axis=None, dtype=None, out=None, keepdims=False)</code></li>
<li>Computes the arithmetic mean along the specified axis.</li>
<li>Meaning and detailed behavior of each keyword is explained.</li>
<li>Semantics, including for corner cases (e.g. <code>nan</code>, <code>inf</code>, empty arrays, and
more) are given by a reference test suite.</li>
</ul>
<p>The semantics of a function is a large topic, so the <em>scope</em> of what is
specified must be very clear. For example (this may be specified separately,
as it will be common between many functions):</p>
<ul>
<li>Only array input is in scope, functions may or may not accept lists, tuples
or other object.</li>
<li>Dtypes covered are <code>int32</code>, <code>int64</code>, <code>float16</code>, <code>float32</code>, <code>float64</code>;
extended precision floating point and complex dtypes, datetime and custom
dtypes are out of scope.</li>
<li>Default dtype may be either <code>float32</code> or <code>float64</code>; this is a consistent
library-wide choice (rationale: for deep learning <code>float32</code> is the typical
default, for general numerical computing <code>float64</code> is the default).</li>
<li>Expected results when the input contains <code>nan</code> or <code>inf</code> is in scope,
behavior may vary slightly (e.g. warnings are produced) depending on
implementation details.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Please note: all the above is meant to sketch what an “API standard” means, the concrete signatures, semantics and scope may and likely will change</em>.</p>
<h2 id="approach-to-building-up-the-api-standards">Approach to building up the API standards</h2>
<p>The approach we’re taking includes a combination of design discussions,
requirements engineering and data-driven decision making.</p>
<h3 id="start-from-use-cases-and-requirements">Start from use cases and requirements</h3>
<p>Something that’s often missing when an API of a library grows organically
when many people add features and solve their own issues over a time span of
years is <em>requirements engineering</em>. Meaning: start with a well-defined scope
and use cases, derive requirements from those use cases, and then refer to
those use cases and requirements when making individual technical design
decisions. We aim to take such an approach, to end up with a consistent
design and with good, documented rationales for decisions.</p>
<p>We need to carefully define scope, including both goals and non-goals. For
example, while we aim to make array and dataframe libraries compatible so
consumers of those data structures will be able to support multiple of those
libraries, <em>runtime switching</em> without testing or any changes in the
consuming library is not a goal. A concrete example: we aim to make it
possible for scikit-learn to consume CuPy arrays and JAX and PyTorch tensors
from pure Python code (as a first goal; C/C++/Cython is a harder nut to crack),
but we expect that to require some amount of changes and possibly
special-casing in scikit-learn - because specifying every last implementation
detail scikit-learn may be relying on isn’t feasible.</p>
<h3 id="be-conservative-in-choices-made">Be conservative in choices made</h3>
<p>A standard only has value if it’s adhered to widely. So it has to be both
easy to adopt a standard and sensible/uncontroversial to do so.
This implies that we should only attempt to standardize functionality with which
there is already wide experience, and that all libraries either already have
in some form or can implement with a reasonable amount of effort. Therefore,
there …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://data-apis.org/blog/announcing_the_consortium/">https://data-apis.org/blog/announcing_the_consortium/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://data-apis.org/blog/announcing_the_consortium/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24205363</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 23:01:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A manager’s essential guide to holding regular check-ins]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 22 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24204478">thread link</a>) | @dootah
<br/>
August 18, 2020 | https://www.muchskills.com/playbooks/check-ins | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.muchskills.com/playbooks/check-ins">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>To get a deeper understanding of what employee engagement is really about, managers may also find it worthwhile to reflect on<a href="https://q12.gallup.com/public/en-us/Features"> Gallup’s Q12</a>. These are the 12 core questions Gallup developed to measure the most important elements of employee engagement in organizations. Gallup picked these specific questions after decades of writing, testing and refining hundreds of questions because they helped measure employee engagement most effectively.</p><p>One way managers can use these questions is to ask themselves: ‘If members of my team took this survey today how would they fare?’&nbsp;<br></p></div><p>The questions have been divided into four types — or levels — of employees’ performance development needs:<br></p><div><ul role="list"><li>Basic needs</li><li>Individual needs</li><li>Teamwork needs</li><li>Personal growth needs</li></ul><p>When managers hold regular weekly or biweekly one-on-one meetings along with in-depth quarterly meetings, they will gain insights about the whole gamut of needs in the engagement hierarchy illustrated above – from individual needs to teamwork needs – which will help them build stronger and more engaged teams.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.muchskills.com/playbooks/check-ins</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24204478</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 21:20:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Improve Your Negotiation Skills with the U-Shaped Story]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 18 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24203773">thread link</a>) | @cmitreanu
<br/>
August 18, 2020 | https://www.cristianmitreanu.com/blog/2017/2/25/improve-your-negotiation-skills-with-the-u-shaped-story | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cristianmitreanu.com/blog/2017/2/25/improve-your-negotiation-skills-with-the-u-shaped-story">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="canvasWrapper">

    <div id="canvas">
      

      <div>
        <section id="page">
          <div id="mainContent" role="main" data-content-field="main-content">

            

            <article id="article-58b13af16b8f5b2e7cb60c3d" data-item-id="58b13af16b8f5b2e7cb60c3d">

  <!--POST HEADER-->

  

  <!--POST BODY-->

  

  <div>
    <div data-layout-label="Post Body" data-type="item" data-updated-on="1488010431632" id="item-58b13af16b8f5b2e7cb60c3d"><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-6938e75fb93d56c65edc"><p>The legendary marketing professor Theodore Levitt <a href="http://hbswk.hbs.edu/item/what-customers-want-from-your-products" target="_blank">used to say</a>,</p></div><div data-block-type="31" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1487984371696_2394224"><div>

<figure>
  <blockquote data-animation-role="quote">
    <span>“</span>People don’t want to buy a quarter-inch drill. They want a quarter-inch hole!<span>”</span>
  </blockquote>
  <figcaption>— Theodore Levitt</figcaption>
</figure>
</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1487984371696_2395453"><p>And since this insight remains as relevant as ever, whether in the context of marketing or that of selling/pitching,&nbsp;I thought that you might find useful a new bargaining framework that brings to the table more structure and a research-based foundation. Called <strong>The U-Shaped Story</strong>, the concept is concisely presented in a poster/infographic (see below and/or download a <a href="https://www.cristianmitreanu.com/s/The-U-Shaped-Visual-Story-FINAL-20160420.pdf" target="_blank">high-resolution PDF version here</a>), which includes an illustrative visual example from the apartment rental industry, along with the brief description:</p></div><div data-block-type="31" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1487984371696_2395927"><div>

<figure>
  <blockquote data-animation-role="quote">
    <span>“</span>You have recently moved to a new city and are in the market for an apartment. Would it be easier to convince you to move to another city? Or to choose a different apartment?... That is the essence of the U-Shaped Story – a bargaining framework based on a novel theory, which posits that one’s needs are generated through a process of aggregation/disaggregation, where the broader needs are more valuable and the more specific ones matter less to the individual (Cristian Mitreanu, Spointra and the Secret of Business Success). Accordingly, when a need is placed in a bigger context, the preference for a solution that would address it tends to become less firm. The need and the associated product become less important to the customer, thus leading to circumstances that are more conducive to a win-win exchange. Easily applicable to most products and services, from apartments to cars to your morning coffee, the U-Shaped Story is closely aligned with the widely-known collaborative techniques of integrative negotiation (as opposed to distributive negotiation) and consultative selling (as opposed to transactional selling).<span>”</span>
  </blockquote>
  
</figure>
</div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1487984371696_2396812"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          <a href="https://www.cristianmitreanu.com/s/The-U-Shaped-Visual-Story-FINAL-20160420.pdf" target="_blank">
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/58b0d0ce4402430e14684ebf/1579194795288-J4XVDLCASK630V5WB58F/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kE1G8aDDySyXafgMqMi-3Wt7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fIBAe0aRMxRrpn6J5i2IfAjEZwkdJGvTULFlkLSJhK3Nw/The+U-Shaped+Visual+Story-FINAL-big-20160419.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/58b0d0ce4402430e14684ebf/1579194795288-J4XVDLCASK630V5WB58F/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kE1G8aDDySyXafgMqMi-3Wt7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fIBAe0aRMxRrpn6J5i2IfAjEZwkdJGvTULFlkLSJhK3Nw/The+U-Shaped+Visual+Story-FINAL-big-20160419.jpg" data-image-dimensions="2500x1618" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="The U-Shaped Visual Story-FINAL-big-20160419.jpg" data-load="false" data-image-id="5e2099a04eb64331e58375d1" data-type="image" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/58b0d0ce4402430e14684ebf/1579194795288-J4XVDLCASK630V5WB58F/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kE1G8aDDySyXafgMqMi-3Wt7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fIBAe0aRMxRrpn6J5i2IfAjEZwkdJGvTULFlkLSJhK3Nw/The+U-Shaped+Visual+Story-FINAL-big-20160419.jpg">
          </p>
        
          </a>
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1487984371696_2401568"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          <a href="https://www.ofmos.com/spointra-and-the-secret-of-business-success" target="_blank">
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/58b0d0ce4402430e14684ebf/1488010328986-3N9USU538O3G11B1SMQU/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPoswlzjSVMM-SxOp7CV59BZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PI7Hk5b7wKtplcrxPf3ag-g6VC0ObVEO8cEICumLtlwuA/cristian-mitreanu-spointra-1.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/58b0d0ce4402430e14684ebf/1488010328986-3N9USU538O3G11B1SMQU/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPoswlzjSVMM-SxOp7CV59BZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PI7Hk5b7wKtplcrxPf3ag-g6VC0ObVEO8cEICumLtlwuA/cristian-mitreanu-spointra-1.png" data-image-dimensions="800x600" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="cristian-mitreanu-spointra-1.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="58b13c58725e252ebd63f920" data-type="image" src="https://www.cristianmitreanu.com/blog/2017/2/25/cristian-mitreanu-spointra-1.png">
          </p>
        
          </a>
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1487984371696_2404052"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          <a href="https://www.ofmos.com/spointra-and-the-secret-of-business-success" target="_blank">
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/58b0d0ce4402430e14684ebf/1488010358195-T4AHHYRZUSO9MQGT8W3S/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPoswlzjSVMM-SxOp7CV59BZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PI7Hk5b7wKtplcrxPf3ag-g6VC0ObVEO8cEICumLtlwuA/cristian-mitreanu-spointra-2.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/58b0d0ce4402430e14684ebf/1488010358195-T4AHHYRZUSO9MQGT8W3S/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPoswlzjSVMM-SxOp7CV59BZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PI7Hk5b7wKtplcrxPf3ag-g6VC0ObVEO8cEICumLtlwuA/cristian-mitreanu-spointra-2.png" data-image-dimensions="800x600" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="cristian-mitreanu-spointra-2.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="58b13c761b631bccf548624b" data-type="image" src="https://www.cristianmitreanu.com/blog/2017/2/25/cristian-mitreanu-spointra-2.png">
          </p>
        
          </a>
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1487984371696_2406535"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          <a href="https://www.ofmos.com/spointra-and-the-secret-of-business-success" target="_blank">
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/58b0d0ce4402430e14684ebf/1488010380969-3LLB8DJTOOHY9CDH5HFN/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPoswlzjSVMM-SxOp7CV59BZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PI7Hk5b7wKtplcrxPf3ag-g6VC0ObVEO8cEICumLtlwuA/cristian-mitreanu-spointra-3.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/58b0d0ce4402430e14684ebf/1488010380969-3LLB8DJTOOHY9CDH5HFN/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPoswlzjSVMM-SxOp7CV59BZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PI7Hk5b7wKtplcrxPf3ag-g6VC0ObVEO8cEICumLtlwuA/cristian-mitreanu-spointra-3.png" data-image-dimensions="800x600" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="cristian-mitreanu-spointra-3.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="58b13c8c2994cab39588b9bb" data-type="image" src="https://www.cristianmitreanu.com/blog/2017/2/25/cristian-mitreanu-spointra-3.png">
          </p>
        
          </a>
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1487984371696_2409019"><div><p>...as well as a further-clarifying excerpt from the <a href="https://www.ofmos.com/s/CristianMitreanu-Spointra-BeyondTheFun-20130519-DRAFT.pdf" target="_blank">draft manuscript</a>&nbsp;(page 21) intended to become the Letter to the Reader in the book.</p><blockquote><p><em>The theory goes on, then, to show that humans respond to these pressures with need-addressing behaviors that combine disaggregation and matching of needs to potential solutions that we are aware of and exist in our environment. However, the weight of each component varies, depending on the need that is being addressed. At one end, we exclusively employ disaggregation to address the overarching need “successful existence.” Then, gradually, the process shifts to defining needs by exclusively matching existent solutions or offerings in the marketplace. And this all happens simultaneously top-down, where an ideal future state is broken down into clearer components, and bottom-up, where needs that match existent solutions are being adopted and inserted into the overarching need. As a result, we generate a hierarchical structure of needs called the tree of needs. Continuously changing, as we interact with the environment and process information, this structure includes all possible needs, regardless of the level of commitment we have to them. It is fluid and volatile, and some of its areas become clearer only when we focus on them.</em></p></blockquote><p>Of course, this is the framework. The actual execution will depend on the medium of communication and your corresponding skills.</p><p>What has been your win-win approach to negotiations?</p><p>----------------------------</p><p><em>This essay was first published on </em><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/improve-your-negotiation-skills-u-shaped-story-cristian-mitreanu" target="_blank"><em>LinkedIn</em></a><em>&nbsp;on April 26, 2016.</em></p></div></div></div></div></div>
    
  </div>

  <!--POST FOOTER-->

  

  <!-- COMMENTS -->

  


  </article>



<!--PAGINATION-->


  

          </div>

          
          
          
          
          
        </section>

        
        
        
        
        
        
      </div>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cristianmitreanu.com/blog/2017/2/25/improve-your-negotiation-skills-with-the-u-shaped-story</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24203773</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 20:13:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Product Activity Coefficient: A single metric to drive customer success teams]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 46 | Comments 11 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24203327">thread link</a>) | @borisjabes
<br/>
August 18, 2020 | https://blog.getcensus.com/a-single-metric-to-drive-customer-success-teams/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.getcensus.com/a-single-metric-to-drive-customer-success-teams/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">
    <div>

        <article>

            

            <section>
                <div>
                    <p><em>Over the past decade there's been plenty of advice for startups on picking a great metric to focus on growth. Since starting <a href="https://blog.getcensus.com/p/bbf6b3b0-b9bd-4931-a4ee-76b3f8c48b05/getcensus.com">Census</a>, I've been curious to see how the best CS teams apply this thinking to their work and help customers get the most from the software that they buy. In my experience, it's a lot easier to focus on fewer metrics: you can ensure they're computed correctly and that teams actually use them to prioritize their work. This post highlights a metric that we've helped <a href="https://twitter.com/Kazanjy">Pete Kazanjy</a> deploy at <a href="http://atriumhq.com/">Atrium</a> that should work as a starting point for most B2B SaaS companies.</em></p><figure><img src="https://blog.getcensus.com/content/images/2020/08/Heatmap-Product-Activity-GUI.png" alt="Product Activity Heatmap" srcset="https://blog.getcensus.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/08/Heatmap-Product-Activity-GUI.png 600w, https://blog.getcensus.com/content/images/2020/08/Heatmap-Product-Activity-GUI.png 838w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><h2 id="why-effective-customer-success-is-essential">Why effective Customer Success is essential</h2><p>While it may sound like old advice by now, it’s important for SaaS companies to invest in Customer Success today. This is especially true with the rise of product-led software adoption (aka “bottom-up growth”). A recent study showed that great companies have a net revenue retention of <a href="https://www.lennyrachitsky.com/p/what-is-good-retention-issue-29">110% to 130%</a>. While your core product plays the starring role in this task, a good Customer Success team can also have a huge impact. </p><ul><li>Ensuring customers are getting everything out of the services they’ve purchased leads to happier users, which in turn leads to more organic growth.</li><li>Building a “land &amp; expand” approach to growth can be accelerated by a CS team identifying internal opportunities.</li></ul><p>The hard problem is how to make your CS team effective. Ideally each member of the team is assigned 10+ customers. How do they know which users to prioritize? You need good metrics to indicate how they’re adopting your product without forcing them to explore each customer individually in your BI tools.</p><h2 id="focus-on-leading-indicators">Focus on leading indicators</h2><p>There’s no shortage of business metrics experts will recommend across categories like Churn Management, Expansion Prospecting, or Customer Satisfaction. Here’s some classic examples.</p><ul><li><strong>Churn</strong>: Customer Churn %, MRR Churn %, Net MRR Churn %</li><li><strong>Expansion Revenue</strong>: Expansion MRR %, Gross Renewal Rate, Net Revenue Retention</li><li><strong>Customer Satisfaction</strong>: Net Promotor Score (NPS), Customer Satisfaction Score (CSAT)</li></ul><p>While these are all metrics you should be tracking, they are ill-suited to prioritizing the work of your Customer Success team. The revenue metrics are great for the business, but it doesn’t help an individual CSM do their job or prioritize their time. Tracking customer satisfaction is a more visceral indicator that people are happy with your product but this is still reactive to their feedback rather than proactive based on their activity. Ultimately, these are all lagging indicators. By the time someone is about to downgrade, it’s too late to act.</p><p>The goal of your CS team is to prevent all of the metrics above from falling in the first place! What you need is a metric that can answer questions like these:</p><ul><li>Who are our power users?</li><li>Which account needs to be educated on new features?</li><li>Which account is at risk of churning?</li><li>Which account is not using all of the products/features they purchased?</li></ul><h2 id="why-a-product-activity-coefficient-is-a-great-metric-for-success">Why a Product Activity Coefficient is a great metric for Success</h2><p>What you need is a metric built on your product usage data that is easy to understand by anyone in the company and is <strong>a leading indicator so the CS team can be proactive and help customers before it is too late.</strong></p><figure><img src="https://blog.getcensus.com/content/images/2020/08/Product-Activity-Coefficient-Fomrula.png" alt="Product Activity Metrics for CSM" srcset="https://blog.getcensus.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/08/Product-Activity-Coefficient-Fomrula.png 600w, https://blog.getcensus.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/08/Product-Activity-Coefficient-Fomrula.png 1000w, https://blog.getcensus.com/content/images/size/w1600/2020/08/Product-Activity-Coefficient-Fomrula.png 1600w, https://blog.getcensus.com/content/images/2020/08/Product-Activity-Coefficient-Fomrula.png 2080w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>This is where the <strong>Product Activity Coefficient </strong>comes in. &nbsp;To measure it, you simply count the number of weeks a customer has been active out of the last 7 weeks. The lowest score is 0, the highest is 7. Simple.</p><p>The power in this kind of metric is that it’s normalized across any user and it represents their level of engagement with your product. It is similar in this respect to user metrics championed by big consumer product teams. Growth teams at companies like Facebook &amp; Netflix <a href="https://medium.com/sequoia-capital/selecting-the-right-user-metric-de95015aa38" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">use metrics like DAU/MAU</a> to track engagement because these quotients focus on turning their user base as a whole into more frequent users. We picked a weekly cadence as it’s a reasonable baseline for a B2B SaaS product (that users engage with it at least once a week). The key difference between general user engagement metrics and the coefficient we use here is that this one is focused on a single user (or account).</p><h2 id="putting-this-in-practice">Putting this in practice</h2><p>To measure <strong>product activity</strong>, you need to define what an active user looks like. This is unique to your business but it should be a score that your team can understand and decompose (ie. you don’t need to hire a data scientist for this). In many cases your product &amp; growth teams are already thinking about it. What is the key value of your product? Which part of your product provides that value? Here’s some examples.</p><figure><img src="https://blog.getcensus.com/content/images/2020/08/best_csm_teams.png" alt="Great CSM team uses that metric" srcset="https://blog.getcensus.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/08/best_csm_teams.png 600w, https://blog.getcensus.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/08/best_csm_teams.png 1000w, https://blog.getcensus.com/content/images/size/w1600/2020/08/best_csm_teams.png 1600w, https://blog.getcensus.com/content/images/2020/08/best_csm_teams.png 2080w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><ul><li><a rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">Atrium</a> helps sales leaders understand the performance of their team. The value is provided via the different pre-built dashboards (sales manager level, rep level, etc). So the more views these pages get, the better.</li><li><a rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">Loom</a> helps their users communicate more effectively by using video. The value they provide can be tracked by how many videos each user creates and how many views they get.</li><li>Here at <a href="http://getcensus.com/" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">Census</a>, we help customers sync their data from their data warehouse to business tools. The more data they sync, the more value they get. Therefore, we measure activity by the number of live syncs and the amount of data being synced.</li></ul><p>Once you’ve defined what an active user is, you can compute the coefficient wherever you do BI. For example, let’s say you have an event stream from Segment landing in your data warehouse and you’ve decided that page views of your dashboard constitute activity. Here’s a SQL query for generating the metric.</p><pre><code>SELECT
	user_id,
	COUNT(*) AS product_activity_coeff
FROM (
	SELECT DISTINCT
    	user_id,
    	DATEDIFF(week, timestamp, CURRENT_DATE) AS weeks_ago
  	FROM segment.tracks
  	WHERE event = 'viewed_dashboard'
)
WHERE weeks_ago &lt; 6
GROUP BY user_id</code></pre><p>The final step is deploying this metric into whatever tool your Customer Success uses to track its accounts. If you don’t have a dedicated CS tool, you can always use your CRM. This is where <a rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">Census</a> can help; we help you sync your data from your data warehouse to your business tools so metrics such as <strong>Product Activity</strong> are always up-to-date.</p><h2 id="what-s-next">What’s Next?</h2><p>Now that you have the Product Activity Coefficient in place, you can generate reports to classify users.</p><ul><li><strong>Low Product Activity Score</strong> → At Risk account that needs CSM attention</li><li><strong>High Product Activity Score</strong> → Power users with whom you should discuss product expansion, case studies, and get to act as evangelists for your business in their community</li></ul><p>Once you’ve mastered this metric, you’re ready to layer in more. I’ll mention two kinds of metrics that most CS teams should add as they grow. <strong>Feature usage metrics</strong> allow you to understand if various personas are using the right features and to identify expansion opportunities. The team at Atrium syncs these metrics into their CRM where they look for users who have a certain role (e.g. sales director vs. sales rep) that aren’t using a feature designed for them. <strong>Account level metrics </strong>help you understand whether a customer is using all the seats they’ve purchased or nearing their usage quotas.</p><p>As an extra bonus, you can visualize these metrics over time. For an example of how to do this, you can check out our previous <a href="https://blog.getcensus.com/how-to-add-sparklines-to-salesforce/" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">post about sparklines</a>.</p>
                </div>
            </section>



        </article>

    </div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.getcensus.com/a-single-metric-to-drive-customer-success-teams/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24203327</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 19:38:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Founder's Journey: SaaS vs. Marketplace Revenue Models]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 22 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24202773">thread link</a>) | @tlinnster
<br/>
August 18, 2020 | https://rapidly.co/blog/founders-journey-saas-vs-marketplace-revenue-models/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rapidly.co/blog/founders-journey-saas-vs-marketplace-revenue-models/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article><p>As a startup founder, I frequently receive questions from friends, family, acquaintances, about how this mysterious fundraising process works. In short, <a href="https://www.startups.com/library/playbooks/funding/structure-your-fundraise"><u>raising venture capital</u></a> funds is a business deal in which you exchange equity, or a percentage of company ownership, for the capital your business needs to grow, in the form of investment funds.</p><p>Rapidly just raised our Seed round in February and now I am currently in the process of raising our Series A in the midst of COVID-19. Rapidly has a distinct business model in which we have two streams of revenue: our SaaS subscription and our marketplace. The distinction between these is highly important when communicating with investors and customers.</p><h2>SaaS Business Models</h2><p>A <a href="https://www.techradar.com/news/what-is-saas"><u>SaaS</u></a> (software-as-a-service) business model is generally selling a software solution to businesses. Users pay on a monthly basis for the usage of the software, which has a predictable revenue month over month for the length of their contract. This type of business model has high margins of up to 70-90% because it costs very little to replicate the offering. The main overhead cost of the product is paying for the production of software and server time.</p><p>In a SaaS model, it is important to understand the relationship between your <a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/service/what-is-churn-rate"><u>churn rate</u></a> and your <a href="https://www.profitwell.com/blog/saas-guide-to-calculating-and-reducing-payback-period#:~:text=Payback%20period%20in%20capital%20budgeting,payback%20period%20of%2013.9%20months."><u>payback rate</u></a>.&nbsp;</p><p>Your <b>churn rate</b> helps you understand how many customers are no longer using your product month over month or year over year. If you have low churn numbers, your SaaS contract amounts should be quite steady or could increase over time as your clients grow. For a product with a higher churn rate, you might want to offer more upsells into higher tiers to compensate.</p><p>Your <b>payback period</b> helps you understand how quickly your SaaS contract fees pays back your customer acquisition cost (CAC). In an ideal SaaS model, you’re looking for both a low churn rate and a low payback rate, but that can be hard to achieve. A lower CAC and quick payback rate might have a higher churn rate. Some SaaS companies with higher CAC and a longer payback rate might have a very low churn rate.</p><h2>Marketplace Business Models</h2><p>In a Marketplace business model, you make money from the revenue take-rate through either buyers or sellers on the platform. This is a percent of the revenue generated in the marketplace, that will come back to your business and contribute to what is known as your gross services revenue.</p><p>It’s very important to optimize your take rate so that you always have both buyers and sellers in your marketplace. If your take rate is too high, sellers are gonna try to go around you to get those customers offline, because they don’t want to pay whatever you’re charging them for the acquisition of their customer. If your take rate is too low, you might easily acquire new customers but you’ll never be able to generate enough revenue to sustain the marketplace long-term.&nbsp;</p><p>As your company is spending money to acquire both buyers and sellers in the Marketplace, you must balance the budget to acquire both sides and make sure there are enough sellers for the buyers and vice versa. Which side do you see the most value? That’s where you will want to focus your marketing and advertising efforts. Or you may want to add additional products and services to continue to grow revenue without further customer acquisition costs.</p><p>Ideally, you want to know how high can you get your take rate and still continue to grow marketplace users? You have to have this magic number and be able to explain how those economics work to any investors.</p><h2>A Hybrid Business Model</h2><p>I myself use both SaaS tools and Marketplace offerings in my professional and personal life. As far as pure SaaS solutions go, Team Rapidly subscribes to Mailchimp and LogRocket. As a consumer, I use services with marketplace models every day, such as Doordash, Uber, Amazon, or the App Store.&nbsp;</p><p>Rapidly’s own business model comprises a hybrid model with SaaS solution that serves a point solution for tax and accounting firms to connect their other tools in one central dashboard. To get tax and accounting firms using our SaaS platform we have built a marketplace for tax and professionals to grow their practices and get verified and credentialed to best promote themselves online. A well-known example of a hybrid model is Salesforce, in which you sign up for their SaaS software for a flat monthly recurring fee, and they also have a take rate for any add-on purchases in their app integration marketplace.</p><p>If you have a SaaS component and marketplace component in your business model, this can be confusing to investors. I’m overcoming the confusion that comes with a hybrid business model by highlighting that we are building a <a href="https://www.koombea.com/blog/vertical-horizontal-saas/"><u>vertical SaaS</u></a> company, and looking for depth over breadth in the customers and industries we reach. We are looking to embed ourselves within the tax and accounting industry and to reach tax and accounting firms who need our solution. We are not trying to create a Salesforce-type product that has a use case for most industries that rely on their sales function.&nbsp;</p><p>Our marketplace function is just a single feature of our various offerings within our chosen vertical, and I make sure to communicate that to investors. Team Rapidly is building out these adjacent services that complement our SaaS functionality and allow us to better serve tax and accounting firms.</p></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rapidly.co/blog/founders-journey-saas-vs-marketplace-revenue-models/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24202773</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 18:59:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to give access to AWS resources without creating 100s of IAM Users?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 46 | Comments 37 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24202354">thread link</a>) | @rajanpanchal
<br/>
August 18, 2020 | https://blog.rajanpanchal.net/how-to-give-access-to-aws-resources-without-creating-100s-of-iam-users-ckds91qj100pf97s1gc3v8vwb | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.rajanpanchal.net/how-to-give-access-to-aws-resources-without-creating-100s-of-iam-users-ckds91qj100pf97s1gc3v8vwb">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text"><h3 id="scenario-">Scenario:</h3>
<p>Imagine you are a solution architect in a company with 100s of Sales employees and you are migrating from on premise to AWS Cloud. You want to use existing employee authentication system and you want to store files on S3 that employee uses in their day to day work. You don't want to keep S3 bucket public, that will expose all files to everybody. 
You have 2 options:</p>
<ol>
<li><p>Create single role with S3 bucket access and login credentials for all of the employees. With this user have to use 2 different logins. One to access their existing system and other to access S3 files.</p>
</li>
<li><p>Use AWS Security Token Service (STS) to assume role with S3 access and use that to give access to the files. User will still authenticate with their existing system. </p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>In this post, we will explore and implement option # 2. Please note that we are building this example on top of <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://blog.rajanpanchal.net/aws-kms-use-case-with-serverless-application-model-sam-an-end-to-end-solution-ckdfenqag00lsqqs1csp05vhj">previous</a> post.</p>
<h3 id="about-security-token-service-sts-">About Security Token Service (STS)</h3>
<p>AWS Security Token Service (AWS STS) is a web service that enables you to request temporary, limited-privilege credentials for AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) users or for users that you authenticate. You can use <strong>AssumeRole</strong> action on STS that returns a set of temporary security credentials that you can use to access AWS resources that you might not normally have access to. These temporary credentials consist of an access key ID, a secret access key, and a security token. Typically, you use AssumeRole within your account or for cross-account access. In our case, we are using AssumeRole within same account. </p>
<h3 id="how-to-setup-users-and-roles-">How to setup users and roles?</h3>
<p>In our case, we are going to create a role called <em>S3ReadOnlyAccessAssumeRole</em>. As name suggests it has only S3 read access policy. We will also create a Trust Policy and attached to this S3 role. Trust policy will allow this role to be assumed by our lambda execution role. Here is how our SAM will look like for this role.</p>
<pre><code>IamS3Role:
    Type: AWS::IAM::Role
    Properties: 
      AssumeRolePolicyDocument:
       Version: 2012-10-17
       Statement:
          - Effect: Allow
            Principal:
              AWS: !GetAtt ShowFilesFunctionRole.Arn
            Action:
              - 'sts:AssumeRole'
      Description: 'Readonly S3 role for lamdba to Assume at runtime'
      ManagedPolicyArns: 
      - arn:aws:iam::aws:policy/AmazonS3ReadOnlyAccess
      RoleName: S3ReadOnlyAccessAssumeRole
</code></pre>
<p>In above snippet, <em>AssumeRolePolicyDocument</em> attribute specifies trust policy that allow Lamdba execution role identified by principle <strong>AWS: !GetAtt ShowFilesFunctionRole.Arn</strong> to AssumeRole to which this policy is attached to i.e S3ReadOnlyAccessAssumeRole .  The <em>ManagedPolicyArns</em> attribute species the policy for <strong>S3ReadOnlyAccessAssumeRole</strong> that allows read only access to S3 buckets.</p>
<h3 id="lambda-handler">Lambda Handler</h3>
<p>Now, lets write our Lamdba handler that will use this role. Here is the SAM confgiuration</p>
<pre><code>Origin:
    Type: String
    Default: https://stsexamplebucket.s3.us-east-2.amazonaws.com
  FilesBucket:
    Type: String
    Default: s3-sales-rep
</code></pre>
<pre><code>ApiGatewayShowFilesApi:
    Type: AWS::Serverless::Api
    Properties:
      StageName: Prod
    Auth:
     UsagePlan:
      CreateUsagePlan: PER_API
      Description: Usage plan for this API
      Quota:
       Limit: 500
       Period: MONTH
      Throttle:
       BurstLimit: 100
       RateLimit: 50
  ShowFilesFunction:
    Type: AWS::Serverless::Function
    Properties:
      Environment:
        Variables:
          userTable: !Ref myDynamoDBTable
          s3role: !GetAtt IamS3Role.Arn
          origin: !Sub ${Origin}
          filesBucket: !Sub ${FilesBucket}
      CodeUri: Lambda/
      Handler: showfiles.lambda_handler
      Runtime: python3.8
      Policies:
        - DynamoDBCrudPolicy:
            TableName: !Ref myDynamoDBTable      
      Events:
        getCounter:
          Type: Api
          Properties:
            Path: /showFiles
            Method: GET
            RestApiId: !Ref ApiGatewayShowFilesApi
</code></pre>
<p>We are defining here couple of parameters that will be set as environment variables for Lambda. With <strong>Origin</strong> we specifying the origin domain for <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://www.w3.org/wiki/CORS_Enabled">CORS</a>. It is our S3 bucket's <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/VirtualHosting.html">Virtual hosted style URL</a>. <strong>FilesBucket</strong> is the bucket where files are stored. In Serverless Function definition, it uses <a href="http://showfiles.py/" target="_blank">showfiles.py</a> as lambda handler. Function has permissions to use DB. We also create API for this lamdba with path <em>/showFiles</em>.</p>
<p>Lets see what we do in the Lambda handlers. We modified <a href="http://login.py/" target="_blank">login.py</a> lambda handler from previous post. We are setting a cookie once the user is authenticated. This is completely optional and really not required for STS to work but you might need some kind of system to identify that user is already authenticated. </p>
<pre><code> <span>if</span> decryptedPass == pwd : 
      token = secrets.token_hex(<span>16</span>)  
      response = table.update_item(
        Key={
            <span>'userid'</span>: uname
        },
        AttributeUpdates={
            <span>'token'</span>: {
                <span>'Value'</span>: token,
            }
            }
        )

      <span>return</span> {
        <span>'statusCode'</span>: <span>200</span>,
        <span>'headers'</span>:{
             <span>'Set-Cookie'</span>:<span>'tkn='</span>+uname+<span>'&amp;'</span>+token+<span>';Secure;SameSite=None;HttpOnly;Domain=.amazonaws.com;Path=/'</span>,
             <span>'Content-Type'</span>: <span>'text/html'</span>
         },
        <span>'body'</span>: <span>'&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;script&gt;window.location.href = \''</span>+ os.environ[<span>'showFilesUrl'</span>]+<span>'\' &lt;/script&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;Hello&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;'</span>
      }
    <span>else</span>:
     response[<span>'status'</span>] = <span>'Login Failed'</span>
     <span>return</span> {
        <span>'statusCode'</span>: <span>200</span>,
        <span>'body'</span>: json.dumps(response) 
      }
</code></pre>
<p>When user submits the username and password, Login lambda handler will authenticate the user, store the unique id in DB, set the cookie in response with location to showFiles url html page from S3 bucket. On page load, browser will change the location to showfiles url that will trigger the showFiles Lambda handler defined in <a href="http://showfiles.py/" target="_blank">showFiles.py</a></p>
<p><strong>showFiles.html</strong></p>
<pre><code><span>&lt;<span>html</span>&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;<span>head</span>&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;<span>link</span> <span>rel</span>=<span>"stylesheet"</span> <span>href</span>=<span>"https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/semantic-ui/2.4.1/semantic.min.css"</span> <span>integrity</span>=<span>"sha512-8bHTC73gkZ7rZ7vpqUQThUDhqcNFyYi2xgDgPDHc+GXVGHXq+xPjynxIopALmOPqzo9JZj0k6OqqewdGO3EsrQ=="</span> <span>crossorigin</span>=<span>"anonymous"</span> /&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;<span>script</span>
  <span>src</span>=<span>"https://code.jquery.com/jquery-3.1.1.min.js"</span>
  <span>integrity</span>=<span>"sha256-hVVnYaiADRTO2PzUGmuLJr8BLUSjGIZsDYGmIJLv2b8="</span>
  <span>crossorigin</span>=<span>"anonymous"</span>&gt;</span><span></span><span>&lt;/<span>script</span>&gt;</span>

<span>&lt;<span>script</span> <span>src</span>=<span>"https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/semantic-ui/2.4.1/semantic.min.js"</span>&gt;</span><span></span><span>&lt;/<span>script</span>&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;/<span>head</span>&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;<span>body</span>&gt;</span>

<span>&lt;<span>div</span> <span>class</span>=<span>"ui raised very text container"</span>&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;<span>h1</span> <span>class</span>=<span>"ui header"</span>&gt;</span>File Access System<span>&lt;/<span>h1</span>&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;<span>i</span> <span>class</span>=<span>"folder open icon"</span>&gt;</span><span>&lt;/<span>i</span>&gt;</span><span>&lt;/<span>i</span>&gt;</span><span>&lt;<span>div</span> <span>class</span>=<span>"ui label"</span>&gt;</span>Files<span>&lt;/<span>div</span>&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;<span>div</span> <span>id</span>=<span>"files"</span> &gt;</span>Loading..<span>&lt;/<span>div</span>&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;/<span>div</span>&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;/<span>body</span>&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;<span>script</span>&gt;</span><span>

fetch(<span>"https://9nimlkmz74.execute-api.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/Prod/showFiles/"</span>, {
  credentials: <span>'include'</span>
})
  .then(response =&gt; response.text())
  .then((body) =&gt; {
    <span>var</span> files=<span>""</span>;
    <span>var</span> obj =  <span>JSON</span>.parse(body)
    <span>for</span> (i = <span>0</span>; i &lt; obj.length; i++) {
            files =  files+ <span>"&lt;i class='file alternate outline icon'&gt;&lt;a href='#'&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;"</span>+obj[i]+<span>"&lt;/a&gt;"</span>
    }
    <span>document</span>.getElementById(<span>"files"</span>).innerHTML= files
  })
  .catch(<span><span>function</span>(<span>error</span>) </span>{
    <span>console</span>.log(error); 
  });

</span><span>&lt;/<span>script</span>&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;/<span>html</span>&gt;</span>
</code></pre>
<p>We call the showFiles API, that gets the list of Files from S3 bucket and display on the page.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://showfiles.py/" target="_blank">showFiles.py</a></strong></p>
<pre><code><span>import</span> json
<span>import</span> logging
<span>import</span> boto3
<span>import</span> os

log = logging.getLogger()
log.setLevel(logging.INFO)


<span><span>def</span> <span>getLoginCookie</span><span>(cookies)</span>:</span>
    data ={}
    <span>for</span> x <span>in</span> cookies:
      keyValue = x.split(<span>'='</span>)

      <span>if</span> keyValue[<span>0</span>].strip() ==<span>'tkn'</span>:
        cookieValue = keyValue[<span>1</span>]
        tknvalues = cookieValue.split(<span>'&amp;'</span>)
        data[<span>'uid'</span>]=tknvalues[<span>0</span>]
        data[<span>'tkn'</span>]=tknvalues[<span>1</span>]
      <span>else</span>:
        cookieValue =<span>''</span>
      <span>return</span> data


<span><span>def</span> <span>verifyLogin</span><span>(data)</span>:</span>
    dynamodb = boto3.resource(<span>'dynamodb'</span>)
    table = dynamodb.Table(os.environ[<span>'userTable'</span>])
    response = table.get_item(Key={<span>'userid'</span>: data[<span>'uid'</span>]})
    json_str =  json.dumps( response[<span>'Item'</span>])

    resp_dict = json.loads(json_str)
    token = resp_dict.get(<span>"token"</span>)
    <span>return</span> bool(token == data[<span>'tkn'</span>])


<span><span>def</span> <span>getFilesList</span><span>()</span>:</span>
    sts_client = boto3.client(<span>'sts'</span>)

    
    
    assumed_role_object=sts_client.assume_role(
        RoleArn=os.environ[<span>'s3role'</span>],
        RoleSessionName=<span>"AssumeRoleSession1"</span>
    )

    
    
    credentials=assumed_role_object[<span>'Credentials'</span>]

    
    
    s3_resource=boto3.resource(
        <span>'s3'</span>,
        aws_access_key_id=credentials[<span>'AccessKeyId'</span>],
        aws_secret_access_key=credentials[<span>'SecretAccessKey'</span>],
        aws_session_token=credentials[<span>'SessionToken'</span>],
    )

    bucket = s3_resource.Bucket(os.environ[<span>'filesBucket'</span>])
    files=[]
    <span>for</span> obj <span>in</span> bucket.objects.all():
        files.append(obj.key)
    <span>return</span> files


<span><span>def</span> <span>lambda_handler</span><span>(event, context)</span>:</span>
    headers = event.get(<span>"headers"</span>)
    cookies = headers[<span>'Cookie'</span>].split(<span>";"</span>)
    data = getLoginCookie(cookies)
    isVerified = verifyLogin(data)

    <span>if</span>(isVerified):
        response = getFilesList()

    <span>return</span> {
        <span>'statusCode'</span>: <span>200</span>,
        <span>'headers'</span>: {
            <span>'Content-Type'</span>: <span>'application/json'</span>,
            <span>'Access-Control-Allow-Origin'</span>:os.environ[<span>'origin'</span>],
            <span>'Access-Control-Allow-Credentials'</span>: <span>'true'</span>
        },
        <span>'body'</span>: json.dumps(response)
    }
</code></pre>
<p>Focus on the lamdba_handler function here. We first get the cookie and verify the login.  If verified we call the <strong>getFilesList</strong> function where the magic of STS happens. We get the arn of role to be assumed from Lambda environment variables. The <em>assume_role</em> function returns the credentials that contains the access key id, secret access key and session token. You can use this credentials to get S3 resources and access the bucket. We create list of files as array and send it as response. </p>
<p>You can find full SAM template.yml and other code for this here
<a href="https://github.com/rajanpanchal/aws-kms-sts" target="_blank">github.com/rajanpanchal/aws-kms-sts</a></p>
<p>Before you run SAM deploy, create a S3 bucket that will store the html files. In our case, its <strong>stsexamplebucket</strong>. We use urls from this bucket in our SAM Template. On SAM Deploy, It will generate output with 3 URLS for the APIs. Modify the html files to point to those url and …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.rajanpanchal.net/how-to-give-access-to-aws-resources-without-creating-100s-of-iam-users-ckds91qj100pf97s1gc3v8vwb">https://blog.rajanpanchal.net/how-to-give-access-to-aws-resources-without-creating-100s-of-iam-users-ckds91qj100pf97s1gc3v8vwb</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.rajanpanchal.net/how-to-give-access-to-aws-resources-without-creating-100s-of-iam-users-ckds91qj100pf97s1gc3v8vwb</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24202354</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 18:31:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Would you use a Shared REPL for DevOps?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 12 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24201605">thread link</a>) | @jacksonpollock
<br/>
August 18, 2020 | https://cto.ai/blog/a-shared-repl-for-devops/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://cto.ai/blog/a-shared-repl-for-devops/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
			<!-- .cover -->
			<div>
				<p>One of the best things to come out of Functional Programming is the <strong>Read-Eval-Print-Loop (REPL)</strong>. The REPL, if you haven't heard, is basically a command line for your programming language.</p><p>Even if you haven't heard of a REPL, you've probably used one without knowing it. The most famous REPL is probably the Developer Console in your browser.</p><p>Open up the browser's Dev Console and you can evaluate any JavaScript expression in the programming environment of the live browser. Type in an expression and hit Enter: the value is printed to the Console. Any JavaScript that runs in your browser will run the same in the Console, making it an ideal way to try out code in a realistic context.</p><p>The Dev Console is a simple and popular REPL that millions of programmers use every day, but, what many don't know, is that this simple interface is the basis for one of the best ways to program that reaches far beyond the browser. REPL-driven programming, for those who know, is a subtle programming superpower.</p><p><em><strong>Our question to DevOps is... What if there were a REPL for DevOps?</strong></em></p><!--kg-card-begin: html--><!--kg-card-end: html--><h2 id="repl-driven-development">REPL-Driven Development</h2><p><strong><em>The most graceful way to code.</em></strong></p><!--kg-card-begin: html--><br><!--kg-card-end: html--><p>In REPL-Driven Development, you always put your code in the REPL before you put it in your source file. We, who love this style, like to point out that most of your time spent programming is not writing code, but understanding code. And not just understanding code, but understanding the situation, the environment, the context, and all the components that are used to piece together a system.</p><p>Even if you're very experienced, the bulk of your effort is grappling with the unknown—a new library, a colleague's abstractions, or the mysterious cause of a bug. The slowest part of programming is learning, so the best tools should help you explore and discover.</p><p>In REPL-Driven Development, when you encounter a new component, you type it into the REPL to see how it works. The REPL responds instantly, in microseconds. You never wait for a build to finish, let alone for processes to initialize or connections to ack.</p><p>The REPL maintains the live state of your program ready-to-go, so you can do a quick series of experiments in the real context of the system. Tinkering with the live system is a gentle and efficient way to discover. Never waiting on builds means your experiments are tactile and responsive. The particular behavior of some component may depend on any part of the system's context, so trying it in a realistic setting with a short feedback loop accelerates your learning.</p><p>Once you've found what you need—for example, composed a line you want to keep—you drop that into your source code. It joins the system's permanent context, and you already know exactly what it will do.</p><p>REPLs are so simple that many people don't notice their virtues. For example, all REPLs come with a built-in history that is tuned to the most natural way of remembering.</p><p>Every programmer knows what it’s like to say to yourself, "I wrote a line of code last month just like this... How did I do that again?" The history is natural to use because you can always sort-of remember the last time you did something. You always have a vague sense that it was "about a month ago, on this-or-that project."</p><p>With this mental breadcrumb, you grep backward in your REPL and find all your previous experiments. REPLs can be configured to store long-term history, creating a little coder's autobiography. I've found that these records can pay off years later.</p><p>Many of the advantages of the REPL are understated like this. Oftentimes, they are too subtle to notice.</p><p>Another touch of finesse is that the REPL encourages a coding style that leads to composable, well-structured programs that find the right balance between rigor and flexibility. This is because every time you switch to your REPL, you are only concerned with one expression and how that expression evaluates. You naturally start to build your program in terms of small components that handle the output of other components.</p><p>When your program is built up of small expressions that compose with each other, you have a functional-style program. Functional-style programs are easy to understand because each piece is easy to understand. Each piece can also be tested in isolation—it is trivial to write unit tests for code like this.</p><p>Starting your program at the REPL is a graceful path to code quality.</p><!--kg-card-begin: html--><!--kg-card-end: html--><h2 id="a-repl-for-devops">A REPL for DevOps</h2><p><em><strong>So what does this have to do with DevOps?</strong></em></p><!--kg-card-begin: html--><br><!--kg-card-end: html--><p>DevOps engineers are familiar with some of these REPL virtues because they make heavy use of command line interfaces (CLIs). The command line is not the same as a REPL, but it is pretty close.</p><p>The UNIX philosophy that inspired most CLIs emphasized stateless, composable utilities that communicate with each other by piping streams of characters from one utility to another. This UNIX style is in the same spirit as REPLs and pure functions.</p><p>Modern DevOps tools far surpass the design of classic UNIX utilities, but almost every DevOps tool still offers command line features. This is because CLIs are cheap to create and always powerful.</p><p>Adding a CLI to your DevOps tool turns it into a programming platform, in the same way that an HTTP API can create a web platform. REPLs are even cheaper to create than CLIs, and are even more flexible and extensible.</p><p>GUIs may offer a better beginner's experience, and formal plugin systems will be more rigorous, but a CLI will always be the most cost-effective way to expose an interface that is simultaneously human-usable and programmable. That is why DevOps tools still offer CLIs.</p><p>DevOps still has CLIs, but DevOps engineers don't gain all their benefits because the tools are fragmented across different environments. DevOps-relevant software runs in or on a huge variety of different data centers, devices, operating systems, programming contexts, and tool-specific contexts. This includes thousands of servers, but also every SaaS dashboard, container file system, source code repository, and every other place DevOps happens.</p><p>DevOps tools also have incompatible paradigms, so the muddiest part of the job is when you need to fit those mismatched pieces together.</p><!--kg-card-begin: html--><!--kg-card-end: html--><p><strong><em>The Ops Platform: where DevOps tools are pulled together into a Shared REPL.</em></strong></p><!--kg-card-begin: html--><br><!--kg-card-end: html--><p>By integrating with the Ops Platform, all the wildcats in your DevOps zoo are herded together into nice clean pens.</p><p>You build on the Ops Platform by creating one Op at a time. An Op is a logical unit of automation: one component in your system.</p><p>A SlackOp is an Op that can be run from Slack. Each SlackOp brings one automation into Slack.</p><p>As you create more SlackOps, Slack becomes a central, observable, Shared REPL. We wanted the central integration point to be a REPL so that it would be powerful and flexible. We put it in Slack so it could be shared and discovered.</p><p>In Slack, your infrastructure is laid bare for easy control and monitoring. You gain the benefits of the REPL, but not just a solo REPL—this is a Shared REPL.</p><p>Sharing the REPL introduces a new dimension of collaboration and auditability.</p><!--kg-card-begin: html--><!--kg-card-end: html--><p><strong><em>Solo REPLs are powerful. Shared REPLs are supercharged.</em></strong></p><!--kg-card-begin: html--><br><!--kg-card-end: html--><p>Slack is already where collaboration and communication happens. Slack is where discussions begin and people love to congregate.</p><p>CTO.ai's big idea is that Slack can be a Shared REPL for DevOps.</p><p>To achieve this, The Ops Platform needs to bend to accommodate the wildest tools, while being productive, enjoyable, discoverable, and extensible.</p><div><p>You may already separate your business functions into Slack channels. Now, you can split your DevOps into channels, each channel representing one stream of operations activity: talk shop in the place where it happens.</p><p>Onboard new hires just by inviting them to a channel. It is easy to learn by watching others run Ops.</p></div><p>No longer fragmented across the Internet, your DevOps tools and workflows are synthesized into one <a href="https://cto.ai/blog/slack-control-plane-for-devops-workflows/">Control Plane, in Slack</a>.</p><p>Imagine DevOps with the convenience and familiarity of Slack—that’s SlackOps, and that's our mission:</p><h3 id="the-shared-repl-for-devops-in-slack-">The Shared REPL for DevOps, in Slack.</h3><p>We hope you're as excited about this future as we are!</p><p>If you'd like to join our free Alpha test of the Shared REPL, enter your email below.</p><!--kg-card-begin: html--><!--[if lte IE 8]>
<script charset="utf-8" type="text/javascript" src="//js.hsforms.net/forms/v2-legacy.js"></script>
<![endif]-->

<!--kg-card-end: html--><p>We'd love to see what DevOps in Slack can do for your team!</p>
			</div><!-- .post-content -->
			<!-- .post-footer -->
		</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://cto.ai/blog/a-shared-repl-for-devops/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24201605</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 17:34:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Shadow traffic: site visits that are not captured by typical analytics providers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 55 | Comments 61 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24201369">thread link</a>) | @ahstilde
<br/>
August 18, 2020 | https://blog.parse.ly/post/9616/shadow-traffic-why-your-traffic-numbers-are-off-by-20/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.parse.ly/post/9616/shadow-traffic-why-your-traffic-numbers-are-off-by-20/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    						
    						
                            
                            
    					                            
                                                                                                            <p>Getting the complete picture of your traffic has always been challenging. <a href="https://blog.parse.ly/post/1848/did-facebook-fix-their-dark-social-problem/">Dark traffic</a> first popped up in 2012, when it became clear that traffic stripped of its referrer information was categorized as “direct.” Dark traffic has grown with <a href="https://https.cio.gov/everything/">the rise of HTTPS</a> and the<a href="https://blog.parse.ly/post/8921/outsized-influence-the-size-of-social-media-platforms-has-little-to-do-with-their-referral-traffic/"> increasing prevalence of private messaging systems</a> (Slack, WhatsApp, and the like).</p>
<p>While <a href="https://blog.parse.ly/post/5777/campaign-tracking/">campaign tracking</a> helps identify some dark traffic, there’s a new wrench in the gears of our analytics: <b>shadow traffic</b>.</p>
<p><b>Table of Contents</b></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="#what-is-shadow-traffic?">What is Shadow Traffic?</a></li>
<li><a href="#what-causes-shadow-traffic?">What Causes Shadow Traffic? </a></li>
<li><a href="#the-rise-of-shadow-traffic">The Rise of Shadow Traffic</a></li>
<li><a href="#how-to-measure-shadow-traffic">How to Measure Shadow Traffic</a></li>
<li><a href="#are-you-worried-about-shadow-traffic?">Are You Worried About Shadow Traffic?</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="what-is-shadow-traffic?"><b>What is Shadow Traffic?</b></h2>
<p>Shadow traffic is visits to your site that are not captured by your typical analytics software provider.</p>
<blockquote><p>Shadow traffic is real traffic from real people, but you won’t have any visibility into them or their behavior. <b>Shadow traffic</b>—real traffic that your analytics misses.</p></blockquote>
<p><i>Want Parse.ly to help you understand shadow traffic? </i><i><a href="#form">Sign up for our early-access program</a>.</i></p>
<p>Before you can understand <b>shadow traffic</b>, you need to understand how web, content, and product analytics tools work. Every major analytics tool, including Parse.ly, requires you to add code to your website or app. After this code is added, your analytics provider starts reporting on traffic and events.</p>
<p>When someone visits your website or app, this code sends “events” to your analytics provider. Events are little packets of information that summarize your activity on the site. You are probably most familiar with common web analytics events, such as pageview events, video start events, or email capture events. If events fail to arrive for any reason, such as being stopped by the browser or an adblocker, your analytics provider won’t record anything—not the user, not the session, not the pageview. These visits are still real traffic from real people, but you won’t have any visibility into them or their behavior. This is <b>shadow traffic</b>—real traffic that your analytics misses.</p>
<div><p><img data-attachment-id="9620" data-permalink="https://blog.parse.ly/post/9616/shadow-traffic-why-your-traffic-numbers-are-off-by-20/shadow-traffic-events-800w/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.parse.ly/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/shadow-traffic-events-800w.png?fit=800%2C400&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="800,400" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="shadow-traffic-events" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.parse.ly/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/shadow-traffic-events-800w.png?fit=300%2C150&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.parse.ly/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/shadow-traffic-events-800w.png?fit=800%2C400&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i1.wp.com/blog.parse.ly/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/shadow-traffic-events-800w.png?resize=800%2C400&amp;ssl=1" alt="Shadow Traffic Diagram" width="800" height="400" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/blog.parse.ly/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/shadow-traffic-events-800w.png?w=800&amp;ssl=1 800w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.parse.ly/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/shadow-traffic-events-800w.png?resize=300%2C150&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.parse.ly/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/shadow-traffic-events-800w.png?resize=768%2C384&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p><p>Shadow traffic happens when your analytics events fail to reach analytics servers.</p></div>
<h2 id="what-causes-shadow-traffic?"><b>What Causes Shadow Traffic? </b></h2>
<p>Shadow traffic is caused by adblockers, browser privacy features, and other tools which stop events from reading your analytics provider. The largest causes of shadow traffic on both web and mobile are adblockers and new privacy features built into browsers. Later on in this article, we’ll discuss the motivation behind adblockers and browser privacy features, which stems from a valid data privacy concern from internet users.</p>
<blockquote><p>The largest causes of shadow traffic on both web and mobile are adblockers and new privacy features built into browsers.</p></blockquote>
<p>Despite their name, <b>adblockers often block first-party analytics providers, too</b>. Firefox’s <a href="https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/09/03/todays-firefox-blocks-third-party-tracking-cookies-and-cryptomining-by-default/">Enhanced Tracking Protection</a>, Safari’s <a href="https://webkit.org/blog/9521/intelligent-tracking-prevention-2-3/">Intelligent Tracking Prevention (ITP)</a>, and <a href="https://blogs.windows.com/msedgedev/2019/12/03/improving-tracking-prevention-microsoft-edge-79/">Microsoft Edge’s Tracking Protection</a> act as built-in blockers of some first-party analytics services. Even Google, the juggernaut of advertising, is <a href="https://www.socialmediatoday.com/news/google-chromes-ad-blocker-will-come-into-full-effect-from-july-2019/545674/">building an adblocker into Chrome</a>. Shadow traffic is a growing concern you can’t ignore, since it affects pretty much every major browser and platform.</p>
<div id="attachment_9621"><p><img data-attachment-id="9621" data-permalink="https://blog.parse.ly/post/9616/shadow-traffic-why-your-traffic-numbers-are-off-by-20/blocking-tools-800w/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.parse.ly/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/blocking-tools-800w.png?fit=800%2C400&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="800,400" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Shadow Traffic Tools" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.parse.ly/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/blocking-tools-800w.png?fit=300%2C150&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.parse.ly/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/blocking-tools-800w.png?fit=800%2C400&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i1.wp.com/blog.parse.ly/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/blocking-tools-800w.png?resize=800%2C400&amp;ssl=1" alt="Shadow Traffic Causes" width="800" height="400" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/blog.parse.ly/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/blocking-tools-800w.png?w=800&amp;ssl=1 800w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.parse.ly/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/blocking-tools-800w.png?resize=300%2C150&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.parse.ly/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/blocking-tools-800w.png?resize=768%2C384&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p><p>The largest causes of shadow traffic: adblockers and new privacy features built into browsers. There are also less common tools which cause shadow traffic.</p></div>
<p>Some advanced internet users also use more advanced privacy tools that are less common causes of shadow traffic. These include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Network-level blocking — like <a href="https://pi-hole.net/">Pi-hole </a></li>
<li>VPN-level blocking — like <a href="https://nordvpn.com/features/cybersec/">NordVPN</a></li>
<li>Device DNS blocking — like <a href="https://adguard.com/en/adguard-dns/overview.html">AdGuard</a></li>
<li>Device App-based blocking — like <a href="https://giorgiocalderolla.com/wipr.html">Wipr</a></li>
</ul>

<h3 id="why-do-users-adopt-adblockers?"><b>Why do users adopt adblockers?</b></h3>
<p>Although every user is different, there are three major motivations driving the adoption of adblockers:</p>
<p><b>1. Preventing third-party personal information leakage: </b>Many advertising networks and vendors took advantage of their relationship with site operators to create “cross-site device graphs” out of users. These device graphs link personal information from one site with behavioral information from another site. Users rightly view this commercial practice as an invasion of privacy and installed adblockers in response. Regulations like GDPR and CCPA were created in part to address this issue on a widespread scale. Installing an adblocker reduces the impact of this commercial practice in your browser.</p>
<p><strong>2.</strong> <b>Avoiding creepy behavioral retargeting:</b><b>&nbsp;</b>Many advertising networks allow their customers to “retarget” users based on a multi-site visit history. For example, they might show you ads for a product you viewed (but did not buy) on Amazon.com in the ad slots for a news/information site you visited days later. Users feel these ads as “creepy” and installed adblockers to break the technology that let them work.</p>
<p><b>3. Improving web page performance: </b>This is probably the top pragmatic reason for the rise of adblockers — improving the end-user performance of most websites. Many sites have ten or twenty different ad networks installed on their sites, and sometimes ad networks deploy other ad networks through a “cascade” of adtech vendors. All of this dramatically slows down site performance and sometimes makes web browsing unbearable.</p>

<h3 id="why-did-browsers-create-built-in-blocking-technology?"><b>Why did browsers create built-in blocking technology?</b></h3>
<p>The reasons listed above might seem like nuisances, but preventing personal information leaks, avoiding poor user experiences, and improving page performance are all core responsibilities of the mainstream browsers and the companies or non-profits behind them (that is, Apple, Google, Microsoft, and Mozilla, among others). Plus, several new browser alternatives, like Brave and Vivaldi, started to grow popular by differentiating on these very features via built-in blocking technology. Thus, this technology — and the end-user benefits — are a permanent part of the “browser wars” we have witnessed over the last several decades, as browser developers build on each others’ work in an effort to win market share.</p>
<p>Unlike third-party adblockers, the blocking technology inside browsers tries very hard to not break web technologies in any dramatic way. They take a different implementation approach and tend to be more conservative in how they work. However, in the last couple of years, spurred on especially by <a href="https://webkit.org/blog/7675/intelligent-tracking-prevention/">Safari’s ITP</a> and <a href="https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enhanced-tracking-protection-firefox-desktop">Mozilla’s ETP</a>, several classes of technology have been blocked to increase user privacy and browser performance. Blocked technology includes social media trackers, cross-site tracking cookies, fingerprinters, and cryptominers. This has generally led to a better web browsing experience for the average user.</p>
<h2 id="the-rise-of-shadow-traffic"><b>The Rise of Shadow Traffic</b></h2>
<p>In 2019, a global <a href="https://www.globalwebindex.com/reports/global-ad-blocking-behavior">study</a> by GlobalWebIndex, <a href="https://www.impactbnd.com/blog/ad-blocker-trends-for-2019">cited</a> by IMPACT, concluded that 47% of today’s internet users use some type of blocker. In 2020, Parse.ly began our own research into what proportion of visitors go untracked. Participants in our <a href="#form">early-access program</a> found that at least 20% and up to 40% of traffic was shadow traffic, compared to traditional web analytics tracking.</p>
<p>Missing 20% to 40% of your visitor data leads to misguided decisions, revenue loss, and bad business outcomes. The first step to improving your data quality is addressing shadow traffic, while still fully respecting the valid privacy, user experience, and performance concerns of your audience.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-measure-shadow-traffic"><b>How to Measure Shadow Traffic</b></h2>
<p>Typical analytics tags deployed to your website or app won’t detect shadow traffic. There are workarounds to gain visibility into shadow traffic, but they are difficult to implement and have drawbacks, and all of them require heavy engineering or IT effort.</p>
<h3 id="option-1---consolidated-edge-server-logs"><b>Option 1 – Consolidated Edge Server Logs</b></h3>
<p>When users access your site or app, they interact with your servers. These servers can log user interactions, and then you can visualize this data to gain some insight onto your users. This approach falls apart because reconciling logs from different servers, a CDN, or even multiple sites is effectively impossible, even with server log management software. This tooling is made for developers and the information that matters to them. Content marketers and editors care about <a href="https://blog.parse.ly/post/7786/three-ways-value-engaged-time/">engagement</a> and <a href="https://blog.parse.ly/post/9156/introducing-conversions/">conversions</a>, not load balancers and server health checks.</p>
<h3 id="option-2---server-side-tracking"><b>Option 2 – Server-Side Tracking</b></h3>
<p>Blocking typically happens within the context of your user’s web browser, but ultimately, users still need to make requests against your servers in order to access your content. If you send first-party analytics events to your analytics provider from your own servers, then you can keep visibility into the user even as the browser might block a request to an analytics service. This option is technically complex, and replicating the intricacies of a robust client-side analytics instrumentation implementation is effectively impossible. You’ll likely miss out on data that should automatically be collected.</p>
<h3 id="option-3---leverage-existing-analytics-services-like-parse-ly"><b>Option 3 – Leverage Existing Analytics Services like Parse.ly</b></h3>
<p>The best option leverages your first-party analytics vendor’s managed service, but in a way where you could still securely access privacy-safe aggregated analytics events. This should span your visible and currently-invisible (shadow) traffic, and maintain respect for a user’s privacy, experience, and performance expectations.</p>
<h2 id="are-you-worried-about-shadow-traffic?"><b>Are You Worried About Shadow Traffic?</b></h2>
<p>At Parse.ly, we believe in <a href="https://blog.parse.ly/post/3394/analytics-privacy-without-compromise/">analytics without compromising privacy</a>. We support consumer privacy measures like <a href="https://www.parse.ly/help/integration/gdpr">GDPR</a> and <a href="https://www.parse.ly/help/integration/ccpa">CCPA</a>. We never sell, share, or correlate personal data among our measured sites.</p>
<p>At the same time, we’ve stayed ahead of technical and legal privacy changes and made sure that our customers can rely on their data. We provide site owners insights while protecting visitor privacy. As the analytics and privacy ecosystem evolves, our technology evolves, too. We’re developing a solution which will increase our customers’ insights into their audiences while …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.parse.ly/post/9616/shadow-traffic-why-your-traffic-numbers-are-off-by-20/">https://blog.parse.ly/post/9616/shadow-traffic-why-your-traffic-numbers-are-off-by-20/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.parse.ly/post/9616/shadow-traffic-why-your-traffic-numbers-are-off-by-20/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24201369</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 17:16:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Popular seafood species in sharp decline around the world]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 365 | Comments 365 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24199767">thread link</a>) | @InInteraction
<br/>
August 18, 2020 | https://news.ubc.ca/2020/07/21/popular-seafood-species-in-sharp-decline-around-the-world/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://news.ubc.ca/2020/07/21/popular-seafood-species-in-sharp-decline-around-the-world/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

            		

								 									<h5>Science, Health &amp; Technology</h5>
 								
								
																											  																			  

							</div><div>
                						<p>Fish market favourites such as orange roughy, common octopus and pink conch are among the species of fish and invertebrates in rapid decline around the world, according to new research.</p>
<p>In the first study of its kind, researchers at UBC, the GEOMAR Helmholtz Centre for Ocean Research Kiel and the University of Western Australia assessed the biomass—the weight of a given population in the water—of more than 1,300 fish and invertebrate populations. They discovered global declines, some severe, of many popularly consumed species.</p>
<p>Of the populations analyzed, 82 per cent were found to be below levels that can produce maximum sustainable yields, due to being caught at rates exceeding what can be regrown. Of these, 87 populations were found to be in the “very bad” category, with biomass levels at less than 20 per cent of what is needed to maximize sustainable fishery catches. This also means that fishers are catching less and less fish and invertebrates over time, even if they fish longer and harder.</p>
<p>“This is the first-ever global study of long-term trends in the population biomass of exploited marine fish and invertebrates for all coastal areas on the planet,” said Maria “Deng” Palomares, lead author of the study and manager of the <em>Sea Around Us</em> initiative in UBC’s Institute for the Oceans and Fisheries.“When we looked at how the populations of major species have been doing in the past 60 years, we discovered that, at present, most of their biomasses are well below the level that can produce optimal catches.”</p>
<p>To reach their findings, the researchers applied computer-intensive stock assessment methods known as CMSY and BSMY to the comprehensive catch data by marine ecosystem reconstructed by the Sea Around Us for the 1950-2014 period.</p>
<p>The greatest declines in stocks were found in the southern temperate and polar Indian Ocean and the southern polar Atlantic Ocean, where populations shrunk by well over 50 per cent since 1950.</p>
<p>While much of globe showed declining trends in fish and invertebrates, the analysis found a few exceptions. One of these was the Northern Pacific Ocean where population biomass increased by 800 per cent in its polar and subpolar zones, and by about 150 per cent in its temperate zone.</p>
<p>Despite these pockets of improvement, the overall picture remains cause for concern, according to co-author Daniel Pauly, principal investigator at <em>Sea Around Us.</em></p>
<p>“Despite the exceptions, our findings support previous suggestions of systematic and widespread overfishing of the coastal and continental shelf waters in much of the world over the last 60-plus years,” said Pauly. “Thus, pathways for improvements in effective fisheries management are needed, and such measures should be driven not only by clearly set total allowable annual catch limits, but also by well-enforced and sizeable no-take marine protected areas to allow stocks to rebuild.”</p>
<p>“Fishery biomass trends of exploited fish populations in marine ecoregions, climatic zones and ocean basins” was published in<em> Estuarine, Coastal and Shelf Science</em>.</p>


					
				</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://news.ubc.ca/2020/07/21/popular-seafood-species-in-sharp-decline-around-the-world/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24199767</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 15:23:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: MP3 to Text]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 27 | Comments 18 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24199025">thread link</a>) | @sabbakeynejad
<br/>
August 18, 2020 | https://www.veed.io/tools/mp3-to-text | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.veed.io/tools/mp3-to-text">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="w-node-73dd44c42c79-6e90db8c"><h2><strong>Turn your MP3 into text files, online</strong></h2><p>Do you want to transcribe the speech from your MP3 into a text file? Well, now you can, with VEED! VEED’s online auto transcription tool is fast, free, and easy to use. Compatible not just with MP3s, but with WAVs, AACs, OGGs, M4As, and even video files - you can convert to text with the click of a button</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.veed.io/tools/mp3-to-text</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24199025</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 14:33:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[If founders treated their investors the same way they treated their employees]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 660 | Comments 253 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24198228">thread link</a>) | @whack
<br/>
August 18, 2020 | https://software.rajivprab.com/2020/08/18/if-founders-treated-their-investors-the-same-way-they-treated-their-employees/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://software.rajivprab.com/2020/08/18/if-founders-treated-their-investors-the-same-way-they-treated-their-employees/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<div><figure><a href="https://www.techinasia.com/talk/turned-500k-pissed-investors-shut-startup" target="_blank"><img data-attachment-id="354" data-permalink="https://software.rajivprab.com/exit/" data-orig-file="https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/exit.png" data-orig-size="1400,1049" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="exit" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/exit.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/exit.png?w=1024" src="https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/exit.png?w=1024" alt="" srcset="https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/exit.png?w=1024 1024w, https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/exit.png?w=150 150w, https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/exit.png?w=300 300w, https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/exit.png?w=768 768w, https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/exit.png 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"></a></figure></div>



<p><em>Founder</em>: Hey Joe! How are you doing? Everyone here loved meeting you, and we would really love to have you on board as our investor! We really respect your expertise, and think this could be a great partnership. What do you say?</p>



<p><em>Investor</em>: Glad to hear! Can you give me more details about how much money you’re looking for, and what I would be getting?</p>



<p><em>Founder</em>: Sure. We’re looking for a $100,000 commitment, and in return, you would be getting 0.1% of the company.</p>



<p><em>Investor</em>: In order for me to value your company accurately, do you mind sharing your financial books with me?</p>



<p><em>Founder</em>: Unfortunately, we can’t do that. That information is classified.</p>



<p><em>Investor</em>: You shared them with your earlier investors though?</p>



<p><em>Founder</em>: Yes, but I’m afraid we can’t share it with you.</p>



<p><em>Investor</em>: Ok. I guess we’ll just have to make do with the valuation from your most recent funding round. Can you share more details about that?</p>



<p><em>Founder</em>: Sure. At our recent round 2 months ago, we were valued at $30M, post-money.</p>



<p><em>Investor</em>: So, 0.1% of your company works out to $30,000… you’re asking me to commit $100,000 in exchange for $30,000 worth of equity?</p>



<p><em>Founder</em>: No no no Joe. You’re not looking at it the right way. You can’t just value 0.1% of the company as being worth $30,000. No one has any idea where we’re going to end up in the future. How would you even value an early-stage startup like us anyway?</p>



<p><em>Investor</em>: Well clearly you were able to agree on a valuation with your previous investors…</p>



<p><em>Founder</em>: Yes, but that’s not the right way to approach this Joe. Startup outcomes are completely bimodal. Either we’re going to be successful, in which case your equity will be worth an astounding amount, even though you’re getting so little. Or we’re going to fail, in which case it will be worthless, no matter how much equity you have.</p>



<p><em>Investor</em>: Well, I’m still concerned about the expected return for the risk I’m taking. And you still haven’t explained why you’re quoting me a valuation that’s so much higher than the valuation that you agreed to with your previous investors.</p>



<p><em>Founder</em>: Look Joe, we’re looking for someone who believes in us and our vision. Someone who believes that we’re going to be the next unicorn. And when that happens, your $100,000 investment will grow into a cool $1M! Surely that’s a fair return on your investment? If you don’t believe in that vision, and if you aren’t willing to make sacrifices to be part of our team, maybe we don’t want you as our investor.</p>



<p><em>Investor</em>: Well, I do believe in your vision and want to be a part of it. I just want to get the same amount of preferred stock that your other investors…</p>



<p><em>Founder</em>: Hold up! Who said anything about preferred stock. I’m afraid only our other investors will be getting preferred stock, not you.</p>



<p><em>Investor</em>: So you’re both quoting me a higher valuation, <em>and</em> I’ll be getting only common stock?</p>



<p><em>Founder</em>: Not exactly. You’ll be getting options for common stock, with a strike price set to the company’s current Fair-Market-Value.</p>



<p><em>Investor</em>: So when you guys eventually get to a liquidity event, I can then exercise these options and make money off them?</p>



<p><em>Founder</em>: If everything goes well! We’ll need you to continue investing in us, every year, until we get acquired or go IPO. If at any point you decide that you don’t want to continue investing more money, you’ll have 90 days to exercise your options immediately. Otherwise, you’ll lose them forever.</p>



<p><em>Investor</em>: But that’s so risky! Exercising those options is going to be very expensive, and that’s going to increase my risk even further because the stock is still illiquid! Not to mention that if the startup does become a unicorn like you were saying, I’ll get hit with a massive AMT bill that I won’t even be able to pay!</p>



<p><em>Founder</em>: I think we’re getting ahead of ourselves here Joe. That’s all so far away! Who knows what’s going to happen 5 years from now. Most startups don’t grow that much you know. Let’s just finish the deal now, and if the need arises, the board can vote to change the terms of your options in the future.</p>



<p><em>Investor</em>: And what if the board chooses not to? What if the startup does grow quite a bit, and I get hit with a huge AMT bill? My money would already be committed by then and I’d be SOL. Can’t you guys just replace this 90-day clause with a 10-year expiry, so that I wouldn’t have to deal with all these risks?</p>



<p><em>Founder</em>: I’m afraid we can’t do that for you Joe. Besides, we want investors who are committed to us for the long haul. If you don’t want to keep investing in us for the next 10 years, maybe you don’t deserve to keep your equity. It would be best for everyone if we took away your equity and gave it to the people who are still with us.</p>



<p><em>Founder</em>: … So, what do you say? Can we count on your $100,000?</p>



<p><em>Investor</em>: Yeah… no. I think I’m going to go invest in Google instead.</p>



<hr>



<p><em>If you’re taking a $X pay cut to join a startup, you’re really investing $X in them. Far be it from me to tell you how to spend your money, but make sure you’re happy with what you’re getting in return. Shout out to </em><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://dangelo.quora.com/10-Year-Exercise-Periods-Make-Sense" target="_blank"><em>Adam D’Angelo</em></a><em>, </em><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blog.samaltman.com/employee-equity" target="_blank"><em>Sam Altman</em></a><em> and </em><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1ZJZbv4J6FZ8Dnb0JuMhJxTnwl-dwqx5xl0s65DE3wO8/preview#" target="_blank"><em>Matt Mochary</em></a><em> for fighting the good fight and bringing some rationality into these discussions</em>.</p>



<p><em><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24198228" target="_blank">Discussion thread on Hacker News</a><br><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/ic0xhc/if_founders_treated_their_investors_the_same_way/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Discussion thread on /r/programming</a></em></p>
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://software.rajivprab.com/2020/08/18/if-founders-treated-their-investors-the-same-way-they-treated-their-employees/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24198228</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 13:23:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How many pieces can a puzzle have?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 21 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24197668">thread link</a>) | @sfg
<br/>
August 18, 2020 | https://gottwurfelt.com/2020/08/17/how-many-pieces-can-a-puzzle-have/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://gottwurfelt.com/2020/08/17/how-many-pieces-can-a-puzzle-have/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-2595">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>
		<p>Patrick Honner tweeted a few days ago:</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">My 7 yo pointed out that our 300 piece puzzle actually contains 18 x 18 = 324 pieces and I just don’t know what to believe anymore.</p>
<p>— Patrick Honner (@MrHonner) <a href="https://twitter.com/MrHonner/status/1291737149570781186?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 7, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p>Of course you could easily make a 300-piece puzzle, for example 15 by 20. And you could make a 299-piece puzzle — that factors as 13 times 23. But a 301-piece puzzle would have to be 7 by 43, assuming that the pieces form a nice grid,and that doesn’t seem like a “reasonable” size for a puzzle.</p>
<p>So which numbers could actually be reasonable sizes for puzzles? This could be nice to know if, say, you want to know if you have all the edge pieces. (But a 500-piece puzzle could be 20 x 25, or some reasonable slightly larger numbers like 19 x 27 = 513, or 18 x 28 = 504.) It’s a nice puzzle nonetheless.</p>
<p>So let’s say that a number is a “puzzle number” if it’s of the form <img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=m+%5Ctimes+n&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="m \times n" title="m \times n"> with <img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=m+%5Cle+n+%5Cle+2m&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="m \le n \le 2m" title="m \le n \le 2m"> — that is, a puzzle has to have an aspect ratio between 1 (square) and 2. (The choice of 2 is arbitrary here, but any other constant would be more arbitrary.) We can easily work out the first few puzzle numbers:</p>
<p><img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=2+%3D+1+%5Ctimes+2%2C+4+%3D+2+%5Ctimes+2%2C+6+%3D+2+%5Ctimes+3%2C+8+%3D+2+%5Ctimes+4%2C+9+%3D+3+%5Ctimes+3&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="2 = 1 \times 2, 4 = 2 \times 2, 6 = 2 \times 3, 8 = 2 \times 4, 9 = 3 \times 3" title="2 = 1 \times 2, 4 = 2 \times 2, 6 = 2 \times 3, 8 = 2 \times 4, 9 = 3 \times 3"><br>
which is enough to find them in the OEIS: that’s <a href="https://oeis.org/A071562">A071562</a>, defined as “Numbers n such that the sum of the middle divisors of n (A071090) is not zero.” (What’s a “middle divisor”, you ask? It’s a divisor of <img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=n&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="n" title="n"> that’s between <img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%5Csqrt%7Bn%2F2%7D&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="\sqrt{n/2}" title="\sqrt{n/2}"> and <img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%5Csqrt%7B2n%7D&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="\sqrt{2n}" title="\sqrt{2n}">.) Titling it that way seems a bit strange to me: I’d have called it “Numbers such that the number of middle divisors of n (<a href="https://oeis.org/A067742">A067742</a>) is nonzero”.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://oeis.org/A071562/b071562.txt">first 10,000 puzzle numbers</a> have been calculated; the 10,000th is 35,956. There are 43 under 100, 336 under 1,000, and 2,932 under 10,000 — it doesn’t appear that they have contant density. It’s not hard to take this further — there are 26870 under <img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=10%5E5&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="10^5" title="10^5">, 252,756 under <img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=10%5E6&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="10^6" title="10^6">, 2409731 under <img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=10%5E7&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="10^7" title="10^7">, and  23169860 under <img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=10%5E8&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="10^8" title="10^8">. For example, in R, you can generate the puzzle numbers as follows. (This take a few seconds to run. Note that you don’t have to compute any prime factorizations.)</p>
<p><code>N = 10^8<br>
= rep(0, N)</code></p><p><code>
<p>for (m in 1:floor(sqrt(N))){<br>
max_n = min(2*m,floor(N/m))<br>
a[m*(m:max_n)] = a[m*(m:max_n)]+1<br>
}</p>
</code></p><p><code>puzzle = which(a &gt;= 1)<br>
</code></p>
<p>I had at first thought this sequence had a natural density, because I was only trying numbers up to a few hundred in my head, and because the <a href="https://oeis.org/A067742">number of middle divisors</a> appears to average somewhere around <img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%5Clog%282%29&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="\log(2)" title="\log(2)">. There’s a nice heuristic for this – a middle divisor of <img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=n&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="n" title="n"> is somewhere between <img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%5Csqrt%7Bn%2F2%7D&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="\sqrt{n/2}" title="\sqrt{n/2}"> and <img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%5Csqrt%7B2n%7D&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="\sqrt{2n}" title="\sqrt{2n}">; the “probability” that a number is divisible by <img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=k&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="k" title="k"> is <img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=1%2Fk&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="1/k" title="1/k">, so the “expected number” of middle divisors of <img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=n&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="n" title="n"> is</p>
<p><img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%5Csum_%7Bk%3D%5Csqrt%7Bn%2F2%7D%7D%5E%7B%5Csqrt%7B2n%7D%7D+%7B1+%5Cover+k%7D+%5Capprox+%5Cint_%7B%5Csqrt%7Bn%2F2%7D%7D%5E%7B%5Csqrt%7B2n%7D%7D+%7B1+%5Cover+x%7D+%5C%3A+dx+%3D+%5Clog+%5Csqrt%7B2n%7D+-+%5Clog+%5Csqrt%7Bn%2F2%7D+%3D+%5Clog+%5Csqrt%7B4%7D+%3D+%5Clog+2&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="\sum_{k=\sqrt{n/2}}^{\sqrt{2n}} {1 \over k} \approx \int_{\sqrt{n/2}}^{\sqrt{2n}} {1 \over x} \: dx = \log \sqrt{2n} - \log \sqrt{n/2} = \log \sqrt{4} = \log 2" title="\sum_{k=\sqrt{n/2}}^{\sqrt{2n}} {1 \over k} \approx \int_{\sqrt{n/2}}^{\sqrt{2n}} {1 \over x} \: dx = \log \sqrt{2n} - \log \sqrt{n/2} = \log \sqrt{4} = \log 2">.</p>
<p>But there must be more numbers as you go further out that have many middle divisors, and more zeroes. This is similar to the behavior you see for the problem of “how many ways can an integer be written as a sum of two squares”. In that case the “average” is <img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%5Cpi%2F4&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="\pi/4" title="\pi/4">, but an integer greater than one can be written as a sum of two squares if and only if its prime decomposition contains no prime congruent to 3 mod 4 raised to an odd power; asymptotically the number of positive integers below <img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=x&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="x" title="x"> which are the sum of two squares goes like <img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=bx%2F%5Csqrt%7B%5Clog+x%7D&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="bx/\sqrt{\log x}" title="bx/\sqrt{\log x}"> for a constant <img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=b&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="b" title="b"> (the constant is the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Landau%E2%80%93Ramanujan_constant">Landau-Ramanujan constant</a>). That connection might stem from the fact that both sequences are multiplicative. For sums of two squares, that follows from the factorization-based characterization or from the fact that</p>
<p><img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%28a%5E2+%2B+b%5E2%29+%28c%5E2+%2B+d%5E2%29+%3D+%28ac-bd%29%5E2+%2B+%28ad+%2B+bc%29%5E2&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="(a^2 + b^2) (c^2 + d^2) = (ac-bd)^2 + (ad + bc)^2" title="(a^2 + b^2) (c^2 + d^2) = (ac-bd)^2 + (ad + bc)^2">.</p>
<p>For puzzle numbers, it follows from a remark of Franklin T. Adams-Watters in the <a href="https://oeis.org/A071562">OEIS entry</a>. So numbers which have lots of factors both tend to be sums of two squares and to be puzzle numbers in many different ways; as we get to bigger numbers those start “crowding out” the smaller numbers.</p>
<p>The math internet has noticed this at least once before. John D. Cook <a href="https://www.johndcook.com/blog/2014/07/07/a-puzzle-puzzle/">wrote in 2014</a>: <q>Jigsaw puzzles that say they have 1,000 pieces have approximately 1,000 pieces, but probably not exactly 1,000. Jigsaw puzzle pieces are typically arranged in a grid, so the number of pieces along a side has to be a divisor of the total number of pieces. This means there aren’t very many ways to make a puzzle with exactly 1,000 pieces, and most have awkward aspect ratios.</q></p>
<p>1000 as 25-by-40 seems reasonable, but 27 x 37 = 999 or 28 x 36 = 1008 would also work.  I assume that you wouldn’t actually see a 999-piece puzzle because the lawyers would claim calling that 1000 was false advertising.   A <a href="https://www.puzzlehobby.com/how-to-count-puzzles-pieces.html">puzzle blog</a> indicates that most “500-piece” puzzles are actually 27 x 19 = 513 and most “1000-piece” puzzles are 38 x 27 = 1026 – both of these aspect ratios are approximations of <img src="https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%5Csqrt%7B2%7D&amp;bg=ffffff&amp;fg=404040&amp;s=0" alt="\sqrt{2}" title="\sqrt{2}">.   That is a good aspect ratio to use if you want the ability to make both “500-piece” and “1000-piece” (or more generally, “N-piece” and “2N-piece”) versions of the same puzzle.  Similarly the A0, A1, … series of paper sizes used in most of the world have that aspect ratio and therefore an An piece of paper can be cut into two A(n+1) pieces.</p>
			</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://gottwurfelt.com/2020/08/17/how-many-pieces-can-a-puzzle-have/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24197668</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 12:10:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Xplain – Explaining X11 for the rest of us (2017)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 305 | Comments 80 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24197528">thread link</a>) | @pcr910303
<br/>
August 18, 2020 | https://magcius.github.io/xplain/article/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://magcius.github.io/xplain/article/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
        

        

        <section id="introduction">
        <h3>Introduction</h3>
        <p>
            The goal of Explanations is to try to allow people to play with fun parts of computers. Graphics,
            compression, audio. The tagline is my biggest inspiration: "Play, don't show", riffing off the
            typical "Show, don't tell" rule of writers and authors everywhere. Why bother giving a diagram when
            I give you an inspector and let you poke at things yourself!
        </p>
        <p>
            It takes me a long time to write an Explanation, so these might not come out as quick as you like,
            but I do plan on writing these as long as I'm able to. I also don't claim to be the world's expert
            on most everything I'm writing about. I might be wrong! Please let me know by
            <a href="mailto:jstpierre@mecheye.net">email</a> or through
            <a href="https://github.com/magcius/xplain/issues/new">a GitHub issue</a>.
        </p>
        <p>
            Previously, this series was known as "Xplain" and was more focused on the X11 window system and
            protocol, but I've been slowly moving towards anything that interests me, and I'm hijacking this
            project for it since I really like the format and style I've developed. The code for every single
            one of these demos is available in the
            <a href="https://github.com/magcius/xplain">GitHub repo</a>, and I do try to comment heavily and
            go into even more depth there! Play with the code! Use it for one of your own projects! It's all
            MIT/X11 licensed. I very much appreciate followup questions and any sort of feedback through the
            links mentioned above.
        </p>
        </section>

        <section id="toc">
        <h3>Table of Contents</h3>
        <ol>
        </ol>
        </section>

        <section id="credits">
        <h3>Credit where credit's due</h3>
        <p>
            The source code to this article and all demos is freely available under the MIT/X11 license on
            <a href="http://github.com/magcius/xplain">GitHub</a> for inspection.
        </p>
        <p>
            Some of the more tricky code in there has been ported from the
            <a href="http://cgit.freedesktop.org/xorg/xserver">Xorg X server</a> itself along with its helper library,
            <a href="http://cgit.freedesktop.org/pixman/">pixman</a>.
        </p>
        <p>
            Some of the images in this article have been adapted from other images on the web. The two kitten images
            in the Expose event demo were adapted from photos taken by
            <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/titrans/">quatre mains</a> and
            <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/fazen/">fazen</a>, shared under a
            <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/">CC-BY-2.0</a> license. Thanks to
            <a href="http://placekitten.com/attribution.html">[placekitten]</a> for finding these images for me.
        </p>
        <p>
            The cursors and icons used in the demos have been adapted GNOME's default theme,
            <a href="https://git.gnome.org/browse/adwaita-icon-theme/">Adwaita</a>.
            Some of the icons in the inspector have been adapted from the
            <a href="https://github.com/gnome-design-team/gnome-icons/tree/master/art-libre-symbolic">GNOME Art
            Libre Symbolic Icon Theme</a>, shared under the LGPL and CC-BY-SA-3.0. All rights reserved.
        </p>
        <p>
            Special thanks to <a href="http://keithp.com/">Keith Packard</a>,
            <a href="https://blogs.oracle.com/alanc/">Alan Coopersmith</a>,
            <a href="http://people.freedesktop.org/~ajax/">Adam Jackson</a>,
            <a href="http://who-t.blogspot.com/">Peter Hutterer</a>, and
            <a href="http://fishsoup.net/">Owen Taylor</a> for digging into the source code, protocols, mailing lists
            and other archives to help me figure out some of the more odd and hairier X11 semantics when I was working
            on this. Sorry for driving you guys crazy with this project.
        </p>
        <p>
            Thanks to my friends and colleagues who have sent me feedback on work-in-progress articles,
            and to anybody who has sent me a pull request. You guys rock.
        </p>
        </section>

        
    </article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://magcius.github.io/xplain/article/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24197528</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 11:44:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Haskell Mini-Patterns Handbook]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 287 | Comments 28 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24196836">thread link</a>) | @gluegadget
<br/>
August 18, 2020 | https://kowainik.github.io/posts/haskell-mini-patterns | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://kowainik.github.io/posts/haskell-mini-patterns">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          <div>
              <div>
              <p>Navigating in the ocean of Haskell possibilities is challenging even though Haskell is a powerful language that helps to implement robust and maintainable programs. The language supplies you with tons of awesome approaches, but it is not always trivial to see how and where to use them properly.</p>
<p>Fortunately, like any other mainstream programming language, Haskell also has its best-practices and recommended ways for producing high-quality code. Knowing Haskell programming patterns helps you create better libraries and applications and make their users more pleased. And, yes, Haskell actually has FP-oriented programming patterns in addition to the best-practices shared with other languages.</p>
<p>If you are aware of the best ways to solve common problems, you can become a better Haskell developer by using more efficient programming techniques specific to the language. Likewise, you can apply Haskell-specific patterns successfully outside of Haskell.</p>
<p>This blog post contains a structured collection of some programming mini-patterns in Haskell with the detailed description and examples, some small “quality of life” improvements that would help everyone on their developer journey.</p>
<p>📚 In this article, each pattern contains at least one task with the hidden solution, so you can test your understanding of a pattern by solving the proposed task.</p>
<h2 id="newtype">Newtype<a href="#newtype">🔗</a></h2>
<div>

<p>Newtype</p>

<p>Lightweight data wrapper.</p>

<p>When using the same primitive type (<code>Int</code>, <code>Text</code>, etc.) to represent semantically different entities (name, title, description, etc.).</p>

<div>
<ol type="1">
<li>Improves maintainability.</li>
<li>Increases code readability.</li>
<li>Enables writing custom instances.</li>
<li>Allows reusing instance definitions with <a href="https://downloads.haskell.org/ghc/latest/docs/html/users_guide/glasgow_exts.html#deriving-via">DerivingVia</a>.</li>
</ol>
</div>

<div>
<ol type="1">
<li>Additional wrapping and unwrapping.</li>
<li>Deriving boilerplate is required to duplicate existing behaviour of the underlying type.</li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
<p>One of the most common and useful Haskell features is <code>newtype</code>. <code>newtype</code> is an ordinary data type with the name and a constructor. However, you can define a data type as <code>newtype</code> instead of <code>data</code> only if it has <strong>exactly</strong> one constructor with <strong>exactly</strong> one field.</p>
<p>It is extremely easy to define a <code>newtype</code> in Haskell as no extra effort is required from the user compared to the data type declaration. For example, the following are the valid <code>newtype</code> definitions:</p>
<div id="cb1"><pre><code><span id="cb1-1"><span>-- + Valid definition of a wrapper around Double</span></span>
<span id="cb1-2"><span>newtype</span> <span>Volume</span> <span>=</span> <span>Volume</span> <span>Double</span></span>
<span id="cb1-3"></span>
<span id="cb1-4"><span>-- + Also valid newtype definition with the record field</span></span>
<span id="cb1-5"><span>newtype</span> <span>Size</span> <span>=</span> <span>Size</span></span>
<span id="cb1-6">    {<span> unSize ::</span> <span>Int</span></span>
<span id="cb1-7">    }</span></code></pre></div>
<p>But you can’t declare the following data types as a <code>newtype</code>:</p>
<div id="cb2"><pre><code><span id="cb2-1"><span>-- - Invalid newtype definition: more than 1 field</span></span>
<span id="cb2-2"><span>newtype</span> <span>Point</span> <span>=</span> <span>Point</span></span>
<span id="cb2-3">    {<span> pointX ::</span> <span>Int</span></span>
<span id="cb2-4">    ,<span> pointY ::</span> <span>Int</span></span>
<span id="cb2-5">    }</span>
<span id="cb2-6"></span>
<span id="cb2-7"><span>-- - Ivalid newtype definition: more than 1 constructor</span></span>
<span id="cb2-8"><span>newtype</span> <span>Shape</span></span>
<span id="cb2-9">    <span>=</span> <span>Circle</span> <span>Double</span></span>
<span id="cb2-10">    <span>|</span> <span>Square</span> <span>Double</span></span></code></pre></div>
<p><code>newtype</code>s have a lot of great benefits but I’m going to focus only on the <em>code maintainability</em> in this section.</p>
<p>You can think of a <code>newtype</code> as a lightweight data type. Newtype has the same representation in memory as the wrapped type. Wrapping and unwrapping are also free operations in runtime. So, <code>newtype</code> is a <strong>zero-cost</strong> abstraction.</p>
<p>Notwithstanding from the compiler point of view, different <code>newtype</code>s are different data types. And since they don’t have any runtime overhead compared to the ordinary data types, you can provide a safer interface to your API without sacrificing performance.</p>
<p>Shall we look at the example now. Consider, that you have a function which takes a password, a hash and verifies whether the given hash is the hash of the given password. Since both password and hash are merely textual data, we could write the following function:</p>
<div id="cb3"><pre><code><span id="cb3-1"><span>validateHash ::</span> <span>ByteString</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>ByteString</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Bool</span></span></code></pre></div>
<p>The problem with this function is that you can easily pass arguments in a different order and get faulty results. And you need to think about proper order of arguments each time you are calling this function. Should it be <code>validateHash password hash</code> or <code>validateHash hash password</code>? This approach is error-prone.</p>
<p>But if you define the following <code>newtype</code>s instead:</p>
<div id="cb4"><pre><code><span id="cb4-1"><span>newtype</span> <span>Password</span> <span>=</span> <span>Password</span></span>
<span id="cb4-2">    {<span> unPassword ::</span> <span>ByteString</span></span>
<span id="cb4-3">    }</span>
<span id="cb4-4"></span>
<span id="cb4-5"><span>newtype</span> <span>PasswordHash</span> <span>=</span> <span>PasswordHash</span></span>
<span id="cb4-6">    {<span> unPasswordHash ::</span> <span>ByteString</span></span>
<span id="cb4-7">    }</span></code></pre></div>
<p>You can implement a more type-safe version of the <code>validateHash</code> function, and additionally this improves the code readability:</p>
<div id="cb5"><pre><code><span id="cb5-1"><span>validateHash ::</span> <span>Password</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>PasswordHash</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Bool</span></span></code></pre></div>
<p>Now, <code>validateHash hash password</code> is a compile-time error, and it makes it impossible to confuse the order of arguments.</p>
<hr>
<p>Another popular way of increasing code readability without sacrificing performance is introducing a new alias (which is simply another name for a data type) by using the <code>type</code> keyword. Unfortunately, this approach is only a partial solution since it helps only a developer, not the compiler as the compiler doesn’t see the difference between type alias and type itself. And if you don’t help your compiler, the compiler won’t be there for you when you need it.</p>
<p>For example, the following code is flawed:</p>
<div id="cb6"><pre><code><span id="cb6-1"><span>type</span> <span>Attack</span>  <span>=</span> <span>Int</span></span>
<span id="cb6-2"><span>type</span> <span>Defense</span> <span>=</span> <span>Int</span></span>
<span id="cb6-3"></span>
<span id="cb6-4"><span>calculateDamage ::</span> <span>Attack</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Defense</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Attack</span></span></code></pre></div>
<p>Of course, the above type signature is better than <code>Int -&gt; Int -&gt; Int</code>, but the compiler sees it exactly like this. So, you still can write <code>calculateDamage monsterDefense playerAttack</code> and get a runtime bug.</p>
<p>The approach of using <code>type</code>s instead of <code>newtype</code> can bring even more damage when you have a lot of similar data types. The more types you have the harder to maintain them without external help. Below you can see a code sample from one of the Haskell libraries:</p>
<div id="cb7"><pre><code><span id="cb7-1"><span>type</span> <span>WorkerId</span> <span>=</span> <span>UUID</span></span>
<span id="cb7-2"><span>type</span> <span>SupervisorId</span> <span>=</span> <span>UUID</span></span>
<span id="cb7-3"><span>type</span> <span>ProcessId</span> <span>=</span> <span>UUID</span></span>
<span id="cb7-4"><span>type</span> <span>ProcessName</span> <span>=</span> <span>Text</span></span>
<span id="cb7-5"><span>type</span> <span>SupervisorName</span> <span>=</span> <span>Text</span></span>
<span id="cb7-6"><span>type</span> <span>WorkerName</span> <span>=</span> <span>Text</span></span></code></pre></div>
<p>The library safety can be improved by replacing all these type aliases with <code>newtype</code>s, and it can even help to discover some bugs that happen due to passing arguments in the wrong order.</p>
<p>Moreover, the <code>newtype</code> approach is more flexible since you can provide your custom instances or restrict some instances allowing you to create values in an unsafe way.</p>
<p>The cost of using <code>newtype</code> is small — you only need to wrap and unwrap it when necessary. But the benefits hugely outweigh this small price.</p>
<section id="newtype-task">
<h3>Newtype: Task<a href="#newtype-task">🔗</a></h3>
<p>Improve the following code by applying the <strong>Newtype</strong> pattern.</p>
<div id="cb8"><pre><code><span id="cb8-1"><span>data</span> <span>Player</span> <span>=</span> <span>Player</span></span>
<span id="cb8-2">    {<span> playerHealth    ::</span> <span>Int</span></span>
<span id="cb8-3">    ,<span> playerArmor     ::</span> <span>Int</span></span>
<span id="cb8-4">    ,<span> playerAttack    ::</span> <span>Int</span></span>
<span id="cb8-5">    ,<span> playerDexterity ::</span> <span>Int</span></span>
<span id="cb8-6">    ,<span> playerStrength  ::</span> <span>Int</span></span>
<span id="cb8-7">    }</span>
<span id="cb8-8"></span>
<span id="cb8-9"><span>calculatePlayerDamage ::</span> <span>Int</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Int</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Int</span></span>
<span id="cb8-10">calculatePlayerDamage attack strength <span>=</span> attack <span>+</span> strength</span>
<span id="cb8-11"></span>
<span id="cb8-12"><span>calculatePlayerDefense ::</span> <span>Int</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Int</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Int</span></span>
<span id="cb8-13">calculatePlayerDefense armor dexterity <span>=</span> armor <span>*</span> dexterity</span>
<span id="cb8-14"></span>
<span id="cb8-15"><span>calculateHit ::</span> <span>Int</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Int</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Int</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Int</span></span>
<span id="cb8-16">calculateHit damage defense health <span>=</span> health <span>+</span> defense <span>-</span> damage</span>
<span id="cb8-17"></span>
<span id="cb8-18"><span>-- The second player hits first player and the new first player is returned</span></span>
<span id="cb8-19"><span>hitPlayer ::</span> <span>Player</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Player</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Player</span></span>
<span id="cb8-20">hitPlayer player1 player2 <span>=</span></span>
<span id="cb8-21">    <span>let</span> damage <span>=</span> calculatePlayerDamage</span>
<span id="cb8-22">            (playerAttack player2)</span>
<span id="cb8-23">            (playerStrength player2)</span>
<span id="cb8-24">        defense <span>=</span> calculatePlayerDefense</span>
<span id="cb8-25">            (playerArmor player1)</span>
<span id="cb8-26">            (playerDexterity player1)</span>
<span id="cb8-27">        newHealth <span>=</span> calculateHit</span>
<span id="cb8-28">            damage</span>
<span id="cb8-29">            defense</span>
<span id="cb8-30">            (playerHealth player1)</span>
<span id="cb8-31">    <span>in</span> player1 { playerHealth <span>=</span> newHealth }</span></code></pre></div>

<div id="solutionNewtype1">
<h4 id="newtype-solution-1">Newtype: Solution 1<a href="#newtype-solution-1">🔗</a></h4>
<div id="cb9"><pre><code><span id="cb9-1"><span>newtype</span> <span>Health</span>    <span>=</span> <span>Health</span>    <span>Int</span></span>
<span id="cb9-2"><span>newtype</span> <span>Armor</span>     <span>=</span> <span>Armor</span>     <span>Int</span></span>
<span id="cb9-3"><span>newtype</span> <span>Attack</span>    <span>=</span> <span>Attack</span>    <span>Int</span></span>
<span id="cb9-4"><span>newtype</span> <span>Dexterity</span> <span>=</span> <span>Dexterity</span> <span>Int</span></span>
<span id="cb9-5"><span>newtype</span> <span>Strength</span>  <span>=</span> <span>Strength</span>  <span>Int</span></span>
<span id="cb9-6"><span>newtype</span> <span>Damage</span>    <span>=</span> <span>Damage</span>    <span>Int</span></span>
<span id="cb9-7"><span>newtype</span> <span>Defense</span>   <span>=</span> <span>Defense</span>   <span>Int</span></span>
<span id="cb9-8"></span>
<span id="cb9-9"><span>data</span> <span>Player</span> <span>=</span> <span>Player</span></span>
<span id="cb9-10">    {<span> playerHealth    ::</span> <span>Health</span></span>
<span id="cb9-11">    ,<span> playerArmor     ::</span> <span>Armor</span></span>
<span id="cb9-12">    ,<span> playerAttack    ::</span> <span>Attack</span></span>
<span id="cb9-13">    ,<span> playerDexterity ::</span> <span>Dexterity</span></span>
<span id="cb9-14">    ,<span> playerStrength  ::</span> <span>Strength</span></span>
<span id="cb9-15">    }</span>
<span id="cb9-16"></span>
<span id="cb9-17"><span>calculatePlayerDamage ::</span> <span>Attack</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Strength</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Damage</span></span>
<span id="cb9-18">calculatePlayerDamage (<span>Attack</span> attack) (<span>Strength</span> strength) <span>=</span></span>
<span id="cb9-19">    <span>Damage</span> (attack <span>+</span> strength)</span>
<span id="cb9-20"></span>
<span id="cb9-21"><span>calculatePlayerDefense ::</span> <span>Armor</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Dexterity</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Defense</span></span>
<span id="cb9-22">calculatePlayerDefense (<span>Armor</span> armor) (<span>Dexterity</span> dexterity) <span>=</span></span>
<span id="cb9-23">    <span>Defense</span> (armor <span>*</span> dexterity)</span>
<span id="cb9-24"></span>
<span id="cb9-25"><span>calculateHit ::</span> <span>Damage</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Defense</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Health</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Health</span></span>
<span id="cb9-26">calculateHit (<span>Damage</span> damage) (<span>Defense</span> defense) (<span>Health</span> health) <span>=</span></span>
<span id="cb9-27">    <span>Health</span> (health <span>+</span> defense <span>-</span> damage)</span>
<span id="cb9-28"></span>
<span id="cb9-29"><span>-- The second player hits first player and the new first player is returned</span></span>
<span id="cb9-30"><span>hitPlayer ::</span> <span>Player</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Player</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Player</span></span>
<span id="cb9-31">hitPlayer player1 player2 <span>=</span></span>
<span id="cb9-32">    <span>let</span> damage <span>=</span> calculatePlayerDamage</span>
<span id="cb9-33">            (playerAttack player2)</span>
<span id="cb9-34">            (playerStrength player2)</span>
<span id="cb9-35">        defense <span>=</span> calculatePlayerDefense</span>
<span id="cb9-36">            (playerArmor player1)</span>
<span id="cb9-37">            (playerDexterity player1)</span>
<span id="cb9-38">        newHealth <span>=</span> calculateHit</span>
<span id="cb9-39">            damage</span>
<span id="cb9-40">            defense</span>
<span id="cb9-41">            (playerHealth player1)</span>
<span id="cb9-42">    <span>in</span> player1 { playerHealth <span>=</span> newHealth }</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Notice how the implementation of the <code>hitPlayer</code> function hasn’t changed at all. However, if you try to swap some of the arguments in different functions now, the compiler will prevent you from accidentally committing an error.</p>
</div>
</section>
<h2 id="smart-constructor">Smart constructor<a href="#smart-constructor">🔗</a></h2>
<div>

<p>Smart constructor</p>

<p>Providing idiomatic ways for constructing values.</p>

<div>
<ol type="1">
<li>When a data type restricts some values (e.g.&nbsp;not every <code>ByteString</code> is a valid <code>Password</code>).</li>
<li>When you want to make construction of big data types easier.</li>
<li>To avoid runtime errors.</li>
<li>To make illegal states unrepresentable.</li>
</ol>
</div>

<div>
<ol type="1">
<li>More structured and maintainable code.</li>
<li>Separation of concepts.</li>
<li>Control of erroneous data inputs.</li>
</ol>
</div>

<div>
<ol type="1">
<li>Some extra code.</li>
<li>Decide on the approach details.</li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
<p>Once you have a <code>newtype</code>, first you need to create its value to work with it. And sometimes you want to validate a value before proceeding with it. Usually you would create a value of a data type by using its constructor. However, when programming in a modular way, you want to have boundaries in your interface and avoid providing unsafe ways of constructing values without validation.</p>
<p>This programming pattern in Haskell is called <strong>smart constructor</strong>. It can be understood better by looking at the implementation of such approach based on the <code>Password</code> data type:</p>
<div id="cb10"><pre><code><span id="cb10-1"><span>module</span> <span>Password</span></span>
<span id="cb10-2">    ( <span>Password</span> (unPassword)</span>
<span id="cb10-3">    , mkPassword</span>
<span id="cb10-4">    ) <span>where</span></span>
<span id="cb10-5"></span>
<span id="cb10-6"><span>import</span> <span>Data.Byte…</span></span></code></pre></div></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://kowainik.github.io/posts/haskell-mini-patterns">https://kowainik.github.io/posts/haskell-mini-patterns</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://kowainik.github.io/posts/haskell-mini-patterns</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24196836</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 09:45:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Old salt mine is the first emission-free compressed air energy facility (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 58 | Comments 78 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24196490">thread link</a>) | @luu
<br/>
August 18, 2020 | https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/london/goderich-ontario-compressed-air-energy-storage-1.5369478 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/london/goderich-ontario-compressed-air-energy-storage-1.5369478">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>A Toronto-based energy company has converted an old Goderich salt mine into an energy storage facility that uses compressed air instead of batteries. The company says the technology is fuel-free and could one day save you money on your hydro bill.</p><div><figure><div><p><img alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5373151.1574725406!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/hydrostor-goderich.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Hydrostor's A-CAES commercial demonstration plant in Goderich, On. <!-- --> <!-- -->(Hydrostor)</figcaption></figure><p><span><p>Abandoned mines often cause real environmental problems&nbsp;– but a&nbsp;former salt cavern deep below the picturesque town of Goderich&nbsp;may just&nbsp;hold the key to a cheaper, greener energy future in Ontario.&nbsp;</p>  <p>On Friday, Toronto-based energy and technology company Hydrostor launched the first zero-emission advanced compressed air storage facility in the world, located on the grounds of&nbsp;a deserted solution mine salt cavern once used in the production of brine and table salt near the Maitland River.&nbsp;</p>  <p>The company says it will use the subterranean chambers and tunnels deep below the Ontario beach town to&nbsp;capture surplus energy that would otherwise be wasted and&nbsp;store it for later use.&nbsp;</p>  <p>The state-of-the-art energy storage&nbsp;facility is one of only three in the world, but Hydrostor&nbsp;CEO and co-founder Curtis VanWalleghem&nbsp;said Goderich is the only one that has a zero carbon footprint.&nbsp;</p>  <p>"This is the world's first emission-free compressed air facility," he said. "We don't consume any other fuel,&nbsp;just air and water."</p>  <h2>How compressed air energy storage works</h2>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5370487.1574460403!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/goderich-compressed-air-facility.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5370487.1574460403!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/goderich-compressed-air-facility.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5370487.1574460403!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/goderich-compressed-air-facility.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5370487.1574460403!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/goderich-compressed-air-facility.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5370487.1574460403!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/goderich-compressed-air-facility.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5370487.1574460403!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/goderich-compressed-air-facility.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Toronto-based HydroStor co-owns the Goderich compressed air facility along with fellow energy company NRStor.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Supplied)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>Hydrostor's Goderich facility relies on the fact&nbsp;Ontario's electricity producers generate more power than we consume as a province. Ontario sells off this&nbsp;excess electricity&nbsp;to U.S. states when demand is low, often at rates below the cost of production. ​</p>  <p>​​​​​​VanWalleghem said his company's facility uses those times to charge up,&nbsp;soaking up the excess power through its air compressor, bottling up what would otherwise be wasted energy as compressed air for later use.&nbsp;</p>  <p>When the power grid gets hungry, Hydrostor can then release that&nbsp;stored air, generating power for the system.&nbsp;</p>  <p>"When the grid wants power again we open a valve and the air comes out," VanWalleghem said. "It goes through an air turbine returning the air to the atmosphere, producing power."</p>  <h2>Facility can power 2,000 homes for five hours</h2>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.3344067.1448914636!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/hydrostor-ceo.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.3344067.1448914636!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/hydrostor-ceo.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.3344067.1448914636!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/hydrostor-ceo.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.3344067.1448914636!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/hydrostor-ceo.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.3344067.1448914636!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/hydrostor-ceo.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.3344067.1448914636!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/hydrostor-ceo.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Curtis VanWalleghem is the CEO of Toronto-based Hydrostor, which sinks giant balloons underwater in Lake Ontario and uses compressed air to store electricity.<!-- --> <!-- -->(CBC)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>The Hydrostor facility can keep up to 10 megawatts of power, enough to keep the lights on in about 2,000 homes, or approximately half the town of Goderich for about five hours.&nbsp;</p>  <p>The plant still loses about a third of its stored energy through inefficiencies, but compared to a similar capacity battery, it's not only half the cost,&nbsp;the facility&nbsp;has a service life of 50 years, five to 10 times longer than a battery.</p>  <p>VanWalleghem&nbsp;said his company's technology is a cost-effective solution to a problem Ontario has been dealing with for years.</p>  <p>"This does lay a path forward to reducing the cost of electricity," he said.</p>  <h2>Ontario electricity bills the highest in Canada</h2>  <p>In Ontario, electricity certainly doesn't come cheap. A 2017 study by the Fraser Institute&nbsp;suggests <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/toronto/ontario-hydro-fraser-institute-study-1.4212668">Ontario families pay&nbsp;the highest electricity bills in Canada</a>, with households in Toronto and Ottawa often paying double the electricity rates of homes in other major Canadian cities.&nbsp;</p>  <p>What's more, Ontario families can only expect their household bills to climb. A&nbsp;leaked cabinet 2017 memo from the former Liberal government under Kathleen Wynne predicted <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/toronto/ontario-hydro-bills-projections-cabinet-document-1.4110539">hydro rates will undergo a steep surge</a> within the next decade.&nbsp;</p>  <p>Part of the reason Wynne was turfed by voters in the 2018 election was over the mess that is Ontario's hydro system, but ever since her successor, Progressive Conservative Premier Doug Ford took over,&nbsp;Ontario hasn't fared much better.</p>  <p><a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/toronto/former-hydro-one-ceo-to-receive-millions-from-stock-options-pension-benefits-1.4746914">Ontario was forced to pay untold millions in awards and benefits to Mayo Schmidt</a>, the former CEO of Hydro One and a man whom Ford pressured to leave after he targeted the executive's $6-million salary.&nbsp;</p>  <h2>Can you sell green technology in Doug Ford's Ontario?&nbsp;</h2>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5368758.1574373254!/cpImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/ont-federal-council-20191121.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5368758.1574373254!/cpImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/ont-federal-council-20191121.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5368758.1574373254!/cpImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/ont-federal-council-20191121.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5368758.1574373254!/cpImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/ont-federal-council-20191121.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5368758.1574373254!/cpImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/ont-federal-council-20191121.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5368758.1574373254!/cpImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/ont-federal-council-20191121.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Ontario Premier Doug Ford speaks to the media outside of his office in the Ontario Legislature in Toronto on Thursday November 21, 2019.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Chris Young/Canadian Press)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>Ford also appeared to play a central role in the decision by U.S. regulators, who <a href="https://www.utc.wa.gov/aboutUs/Lists/News/DispForm.aspx?ID=570">denied Hydro One's&nbsp;proposed takeover</a> of Spokane based Avista Corp., citing political interference by the Ford government.&nbsp;</p>  <p>Ford is also famous for the fact he&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/toronto/doug-ford-green-energy-wind-turbines-cancelled-230-million-1.5364815">spent $231 million dollars to kill green energy contracts in the province</a>.&nbsp;So what makes VanWalleghem think his idea has long-term potential&nbsp;in Doug Ford's Ontario?&nbsp;</p>  <p>"Obviously the more wind and solar you have on the grid, the more sense it makes for storage," he said. "Long-term they will likely add more wind and solar but in the short-term they don't see the need for that extra energy."</p>  <p>"What they do need is that peaking capacity that comes when you can call it and that's the sort of thing we can offer."</p>  <p>VanWalleghem&nbsp;and his colleagues are so convinced in their technology that they're branching out overseas, building a similar facility in Adelaide, Australia.&nbsp;</p>  <p>With the hope that one day, when governments truly go to carbon-free energy sources such as wind and solar, they have a way to store the energy, even when the sun isn't shining.</p></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/london/goderich-ontario-compressed-air-energy-storage-1.5369478</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24196490</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 08:44:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[APL386 Unicode – An APL Font]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 131 | Comments 61 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24196025">thread link</a>) | @chrispsn
<br/>
August 18, 2020 | https://abrudz.github.io/APL386/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://abrudz.github.io/APL386/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
    
    <p>APL font based on Adrian Smith's <a href="https://apl385.com/fonts/index.htm">APL385</a> font with a fun, whimsical look, inspired by Comic Sans Serif.</p>
    <p>Supports every special character used by any APL implementation:</p>
    <blockquote>+-×÷⌈⌊*⍟|!○~∨∧⍱⍲&lt;≤=≥&gt;≠.@≡≢⍴,⍪⍳↑↓?⍒⍋⍉⌽⊖∊⊥⊤⍎⍕⌹⊂⊃∪∩⍷⌷∘→←⎕⍞/⌿\⍀¨⍣&amp;⍨⌶#⊆⍥⊣⊢⍠⍤⌸⌺⍸()[];⍝⋄:⍬{}∇#⍺⍵⍶⍹"ᐵᑈ√⍡⍁∙⌾⍢⍫$…∞⍛⍧%⊇⍮⍭⊙⍦π⍇⍈⍐⍗λχ</blockquote>
    <p>And many additional mathematical and typographical symbols:</p>
    <blockquote>¦‖∫¬°±∓µ·∵¼½¾↔↕∉≉≣⊖⊛⊻⊼⊽⋔⌈⌉⌊⌋<br>`´¡¿‼‽¢£¤¥ © ® ºª«»‘’‚‛“”„‟§¶♀♂♔♕♖♗♘♙♚♛♜♝♞♟♠♡♢♣♤♥♦♧</blockquote>
    <p>Single and double line drawing characters, and blocks and shades:</p>
    <blockquote>┌─┬┐ ╔═╦╗ ▁▂▃▄▅▆▇█<br>
               │ ││ ║ ║║ █▉▊▋▌▍▎▏<br>
               ├─┼┤ ╠═╬╣ ▌▀▄▐<br>
               └─┴┘ ╚═╩╝ ░▒▓</blockquote>
    <p>The full Unicode APL range, including both uppercase and lowercase underscored alphabets, and as-of-yet unused symbols:</p>
    <blockquote>ⒶⒷⒸⒹⒺⒻⒼⒽⒾⒿⓀⓁⓂⓃⓄⓅⓆⓇⓈⓉⓊⓋⓌⓍⓎⓏ<br>ⓐⓑⓒⓓⓔⓕⓖⓗⓘⓙⓚⓛⓜⓝⓞⓟⓠⓡⓢⓣⓤⓥⓦⓧⓨⓩ<br>⌻⌼⍁⍂⍃⍄⍅⍆⍊⍌⍍⍏⍑⍓⍔⍖⍘⍚⍯⍰</blockquote>
    <p>Extensive set of accented Latin letters:</p>
    <blockquote>ÀÁÂÃÄÅÆÇÈÉÊËÌÍÎÏÐÑÒÓÔÕÖ×ØÙÚÛÜÝÞßàáâãäåæçèéêëìíîïðñòóôõö÷øùúûüýþÿĆćĈĉĊċĖėĠġĢģĤĥĨĩİıĴĵĶķĹĺĻļŃńŅņŔŕŖŗŚśŜŝŨũŴŵŶŷŸŹźŻżƒǴǵǸǹǼǽǾǿȨȩȮȯ</blockquote>
    <p>Full support for Greek:</p>
    <blockquote>Ά·ΈΉΊΌΎΏΐΑΒΓΔΕΖΗΘΙΚΛΜΝΞΟΠΡΣΤΥΦΧΨΩΪΫάέήίΰαβγδεζηθικλμνξοπρςστυφχψωϊϋόύώϕϖϜϝϲϳϴϵ϶ϷϸϹϼϽϾϿ</blockquote>
    <p>And Cyrillic:</p>
    <blockquote>ЀЁЂЃЄЅІЇЈЌЍЎЏАБВГДЕЖЗИЙКЛМНОПРСТУФХЦЧШЩЪЫЬЭЮЯабвгдежзийклмнопрстуфхцчшщъыьэюяѐёѓєѕіїјў</blockquote>
    <p>Sample APL code:</p>
    <blockquote><pre>w←⊃(⊃0⍴⍵){                           ⍝┌┌─2─┐       monadic; use ↓
    (e a)←|⍺                         ⍝├ 0 0 1 1 1  dyadic; use /
    T←⌽⍣(0&gt;⊃⌽⍺)                      ⍝└──→⍺⍺←─────┐
    Pad←⍵⍵⍉(T⊣)⍪⍵⍪(T⊢)               ⍝ ┌⍺┐  ⌺     │
    need←(1+e),1↓⍴⍵                  ⍝ ┌─────⍵⍵──┐┘
    a=0:(1↓need⍴0↑⍵)Pad(1↓need⍴0↑⊢⍵) ⍝  0 0│1 2 3 4 5│0 0  Zero
    a=1:(1↓need⍴1↑⍵)Pad(1↓need⍴1↑⊖⍵) ⍝  1 1│1 2 3 4 5│5 5  Replicate
    a=2:(⊖¯1↓need⍴⊢⍵)Pad(¯1↓need⍴⊖⍵) ⍝  2 1│1 2 3 4 5│5 4  Reverse
    a=3:(⊖⊢1↓need⍴⊢⍵)Pad(⊢1↓need⍴⊖⍵) ⍝  3 2│1 2 3 4 5│4 3  Mirror
    a=4:(⊖¯1↓need⍴⊖⍵)Pad(¯1↓need⍴⊢⍵) ⍝  4 5│1 2 3 4 5│1 2  Wrap
}(¯1⌽⍳≢⍴⍵)/(⌽extra,¨⍺⊣0),⊂⍵          ⍝     └────⍵────┘</pre></blockquote>
    <p>Sample text:</p>
    <blockquote>APL (named after the book A Programming Language) is a programming language developed in the 1960s by Kenneth E. Iverson. Its central datatype is the multidimensional array. It uses a large range of special graphic symbols to represent most functions and operators, leading to very concise code. It has been an important influence on the development of concept modeling, spreadsheets, functional programming, and computer math packages. It has also inspired several other programming languages.</blockquote>
  

</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://abrudz.github.io/APL386/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24196025</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 07:11:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Architecture of the Nintendo DS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 340 | Comments 92 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24195751">thread link</a>) | @Polylactic_acid
<br/>
August 17, 2020 | https://www.copetti.org/projects/consoles/nintendo-ds/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.copetti.org/projects/consoles/nintendo-ds/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div class="page"><nav id="navbar"></nav><div><ul><li><a href="#cover-model">Model</a></li><li><a href="#cover-motherboard">Motherboard</a></li><li><a href="#cover-diagram">Diagram</a></li></ul><div><div id="cover-diagram"><a href="https://www.copetti.org/images/consoles/nintendods/diagram.png"><picture>
<img alt="Diagram" src="https://www.copetti.org/images/consoles/nintendods/diagram.png" data-src="https://www.copetti.org/images/consoles/nintendods/diagram.png"></picture></a><figcaption>If you have trouble following the components: Top is only accessed by ARM9, bottom section is ARM7-only, middle section is shared</figcaption></div></div></div><hr><h2 id="a-quick-introduction">A quick introduction</h2><p>This console is an interesting answer to many needs that weren’t possible to fulfil in the handheld ecosystem. There will be some innovation and a few compromises, but this combination may pave the way for new and ingenious content.</p><hr><h2 id="cpu">CPU</h2><p>As with Nintendo’s <a href="https://www.copetti.org/projects/consoles/game-boy-advance/">previous portable console</a>, the system revolves around a big chip named <strong>CPU NTR</strong>. ‘NTR’ is shorthand for ‘Nitro’, the codename of the original Nintendo DS.</p><p>Now, CPU NTR implements an interesting multi-processor architecture using two different ARM CPUs, this design was done before ARM Holdings officially released multi-processor solutions. So, their functioning may be considered a bit unorthodox taking into account the present technology available.</p><p>While this is not the first parallel system analysed for <a href="https://www.copetti.org/projects/consoles/">this series</a>, its design is very different from the rest. For instance, we are not talking about the ‘experimental’ master-slave configuration that the <a href="https://www.copetti.org/projects/consoles/sega-saturn/">Saturn</a> debuted or the ‘co-processor’ approach found on the <a href="https://www.copetti.org/projects/consoles/playstation/">PS1</a> or <a href="https://www.copetti.org/projects/consoles/nintendo-64/">N64</a>. The Nintendo DS includes two very independent computers that will perform exclusive operations, each one having a dedicated bus. This co-dependency will condition the overall performance of this console.</p><p>That being said, let’s take a look now at the two CPUs:</p><div><ul><li id="tab-1-1-arm7tdmi-link"><a href="#tab-1-1-arm7tdmi">ARM7TDMI</a></li><li id="tab-1-2-arm946e-s-link"><a href="#tab-1-2-arm946e-s">ARM946E-S</a></li></ul><div><div id="tab-1-1-arm7tdmi"><h4>ARM7TDMI</h4><div><a href="https://www.copetti.org/images/consoles/nintendods/cpu/arm7_core.8a9851c20df1dda3c252ae75f544a8ce7a6749026fa4bc870027741cda1003b4.png"><picture>
<img name="image_cover" alt="Image" src="https://www.copetti.org/images/consoles/nintendods/cpu/arm7_core.8a9851c20df1dda3c252ae75f544a8ce7a6749026fa4bc870027741cda1003b4.png" data-src="https://www.copetti.org/images/consoles/nintendods/cpu/arm7_core.8a9851c20df1dda3c252ae75f544a8ce7a6749026fa4bc870027741cda1003b4.png"></picture></a><figcaption>ARM7 structure and components</figcaption></div><p>Starting with the more familiar one, the <strong>ARM7TDMI</strong> is the same CPU found on the <a href="https://www.copetti.org/projects/consoles/game-boy-advance/#cpu">GameBoy Advance</a> but now running at <strong>~34 MHz</strong> (double its original speed). It still includes all its original features (especially <a href="https://www.copetti.org/projects/consoles/game-boy-advance/#whats-new">Thumb</a>).</p><p>Now for the changes: Because Nintendo’s engineers placed the ARM7 next to most of the I/O ports, this CPU will be tasked with arbitrating and assisting I/O operations. In fact, no other processor can directly connect to the I/O. As you can see, this is not the ‘main’ processor that will be in charge of the system, but rather the ‘sub-processor’ offloading the main CPU by passing data around many components.</p></div><div id="tab-1-2-arm946e-s"><h4>ARM946E-S</h4><div><a href="https://www.copetti.org/images/consoles/nintendods/cpu/arm9_core.213329ca27287083c84d30b27fb9da63edd81998406a10b9ee7289089d0fe94d.png"><picture>
<img name="image_cover" alt="Image" src="https://www.copetti.org/images/consoles/nintendods/cpu/arm9_core.213329ca27287083c84d30b27fb9da63edd81998406a10b9ee7289089d0fe94d.png" data-src="https://www.copetti.org/images/consoles/nintendods/cpu/arm9_core.213329ca27287083c84d30b27fb9da63edd81998406a10b9ee7289089d0fe94d.png"></picture></a><figcaption>ARM9 structure and components</figcaption></div><p>Here is the ‘main’ CPU of the Nintendo DS running at <strong>~67 MHz</strong>. If you ignore the ill-fated ARM8 series, you could say the ARM946E-S is the ‘next-gen’ version of the ARM7. Part of the <strong>ARM9 series</strong>, this core in particular not only inherits all the features of the <strong>ARM7TDMI</strong> but also includes some additional bits:</p><ul><li>The <strong>ARMv5TE ISA</strong>: Compared to the previous v4, features some new instructions and a faster multiplier.<ul><li>If you take a look at the core name, the letter ‘E’ means <strong>Enhanced DSP</strong> which implies that lots of these new instructions have to do with applications for signal processing.</li></ul></li><li><strong>5-stage Pipeline</strong>: This is another increment from the previous 3-stage pipeline.</li><li><strong>12 KB of L1 Cache</strong>: The core now features cache, where 8 KB are allocated for instructions and 4 KB for data.</li><li><strong>48 KB of Tightly-Coupled Memory</strong> or ‘TCM’: Similar to <a href="https://www.copetti.org/projects/consoles/playstation/#cpu">Scratchpad memory</a>, however this one discriminates between instructions (32 KB) and data (16 KB).</li></ul><p>Nintendo also added the following components around it:</p><ul><li>A <strong>Divisor and Square root unit</strong> to speed up these type of operations (the ARM9 by itself is not capable of performing this type of math).</li><li>A <strong>Direct Memory Access Controller</strong>: Accelerates memory transfers without depending on the CPU. Combined with the use of cache, both CPU and DMA can potentially work concurrently.<ul><li>Cache and DMA can provide a lot of performance but also create new problems, such as data integrity. So programmers will have to manually maintain memory consistency by flushing the <a href="https://www.copetti.org/projects/consoles/playstation-2/#preventing-past-mishaps">write-buffer</a> before triggering DMA, for instance.</li></ul></li></ul></div></div></div><p>I guess with hardware like this, it’s easy to figure out the <em>real</em> reason kids loved this console, eh?</p><h4 id="interconnection">Interconnection</h4><p>So far I’ve talked about how the two CPUs work individually. But to work as a whole, they require to co-operate constantly. To accomplish this, both CPUs directly ‘talk’ to each other using a dedicated <strong>FIFO unit</strong>, this block of data holds two 64-byte queues (up to 16 elements) for <strong>bi-directional communication</strong>.</p><div><a href="https://www.copetti.org/images/consoles/nintendods/cpu/fifo.4c452b5f9236fb1e98454d2f90d2cab902ee4c561e165e8eaf8a8fc0cd7a05f4.png"><picture>
<img name="image_cover" alt="Image" src="https://www.copetti.org/images/consoles/nintendods/cpu/fifo.4c452b5f9236fb1e98454d2f90d2cab902ee4c561e165e8eaf8a8fc0cd7a05f4.png" data-src="https://www.copetti.org/images/consoles/nintendods/cpu/fifo.4c452b5f9236fb1e98454d2f90d2cab902ee4c561e165e8eaf8a8fc0cd7a05f4.png"></picture></a><figcaption>Representation of FIFO unit</figcaption></div><p>This works as follows: The ‘sender’ CPU (that effectively needs to send the other a message) places a 32-bit block of data in the queue, the CPU acting as a ‘receiver’ can then pull that block from the queue and perform the required operations with it.</p><p>Whenever there’s a value written on the queue, either CPU can fetch it manually (<strong>polling</strong>) however, this requires to constantly check for new values (which can be expensive). Alternatively, an <strong>interrupt unit</strong> can be activated to notify the receiver whenever there’s a new value in the queue.</p><h4 id="main-memory">Main memory</h4><p>Just like its predecessor, RAM is spread around many different locations, enabling to prioritise data placement by speed of access. In summary, we have the following general-purpose memory available:</p><div><div><a href="https://www.copetti.org/images/consoles/nintendods/cpu/ram.99e9bd12e464182ef51ea4aa89a7fc60323a46a72550afbacd737957372cf190.png"><picture>
<img name="image_cover" alt="Image" src="https://www.copetti.org/images/consoles/nintendods/cpu/ram.99e9bd12e464182ef51ea4aa89a7fc60323a46a72550afbacd737957372cf190.png" data-src="https://www.copetti.org/images/consoles/nintendods/cpu/ram.99e9bd12e464182ef51ea4aa89a7fc60323a46a72550afbacd737957372cf190.png"></picture></a><figcaption>RAM model of this console</figcaption></div><ul><li><strong>32 KB of WRAM</strong> (Work RAM) using a <strong>32-bit</strong> bus: To hold fast data shared between the ARM7 and ARM9.<ul><li>Bear in mind that only one CPU can access the same address at a time.</li></ul></li><li><strong>64 KB of WRAM</strong> using a <strong>32-bit</strong> bus: For fast data as well, but only accessible from the ARM7, like the GBA had.</li><li><strong>4 MB of PSRAM</strong> using a <strong>16-bit</strong> bus: A slower type, available from either CPU and it’s controlled by a memory interface unit.<ul><li>Pseudo SRAM or ‘PSRAM’ is a variant of DRAM which, by contrast, performs refreshes from within the chip. Therefore, behaving like SRAM (the faster, but more expensive alternative to DRAM). This design reminds me of <a href="https://www.copetti.org/projects/consoles/gamecube/#clever-memory-system">1T‑SRAM</a>.</li></ul></li></ul></div><h4 id="backwards-compatibility">Backwards compatibility</h4><p>Even though the architecture is significantly different from its predecessor, it still managed to maintain the critical bits that would grant it native compatibility with GameBoy Advance games.</p><p>But for the DS to revert to an ‘internal’ GBA, the former includes a set of software routines that set the console in <strong>AGB Compatibility Mode</strong>. In doing so, it effectively halts the ARM9, disables most of the ‘special’ hardware, redirects the buses, puts the ARM7 in charge and slows it down at 16.78 MHz. Finally, the ARM7 proceeds to boot the original AGB BIOS which bootstraps the GamePak cartridge (just like an original GameBoy Advance). This mode still exhibits some features not found in the original console, such as displaying the game with black margins (we’ll see in the next section that the new screen resolution happens to be bigger). Moreover, since the DS has two screens, users can set which screen will be used to display the GBA game.</p><p>Once in GBA mode <strong>there’s no going back</strong>, the console must be reset to re-activate the rest of the hardware.</p><h4 id="secrets-and-limitations">Secrets and limitations</h4><p>With so many sophisticated components fitted in a single and inexpensive chip, it’s no mystery that some issues emerged due to the way they were forced to work with each other.</p><div><ul><li id="tab-2-1-unused-power-link"><a href="#tab-2-1-unused-power">Unused Power</a></li><li id="tab-2-2-a-question-about-the-hardware-choice-link"><a href="#tab-2-2-a-question-about-the-hardware-choice">A question about the hardware choice</a></li></ul><div><div id="tab-2-1-unused-power"><h4>Unused Power</h4><p>Sometimes I wonder how Nintendo planned the way the two CPU’s would be used, and if they already assumed some performance would be hit by the design they chose.</p><p>Let me start with the ARM9, this CPU runs at twice the speed of the ARM7, but most (if not all) of the I/O depends on the ARM7, so the ARM9 is vulnerable to excessive stalling until the ARM7 answers. If that wasn’t enough, <strong>ARM9’s external bus runs at half the speed</strong>, so there are a few bottlenecks identified.</p><p>Additionally, the Main Memory bus is only <strong>16-bit wide</strong>. Thus, whenever any CPU needs to fetch a word (32-bit wide) from memory, the interface <strong>stalls the CPU</strong> (up to 3 ‘wait’ cycles) until a full world is reconstructed. The worst impact happens when memory access is not sequential, which makes it stall for every single access. This issue will also arise when instructions are fetched (unfortunately, ARM didn’t support sequential opcode fetching back then) which, to my dismay, also affects Thumb code (since every 16-bit fetch is done as a 32-bit block). On the other hand, this penalty (as some sources call it) can be alleviated by making full use of cache and TCM.</p><p>All in all, this means that in the worst case, the ‘whooping’ ARM9’s 66 MHz horsepower is practically reduced to a mere ~8&nbsp;MHz. That is if the program makes an abysmal use of cache/TCM.</p></div><div id="tab-2-2-a-question-about-the-hardware-choice"><h4>A question about the hardware choice</h4><p>Back when I read about the CPU of the GameBoy Advance, I was really surprised by the potential of the ARM7: The CPU not only performed its designated tasks, but could also assist with others, such as providing audio sequencing or pseudo-3D graphics.</p><p>Now, during the commercialisation ARM7, ARM Holdings joined forces with DEC to design a high-end version of ARM’s chips. For this, DEC grabbed the datapath design of their processor, <strong>Alpha</strong>, and mixed it with ARM’s. The result was a new series of CPUs called <strong>StrongARM</strong> which was surprisingly <em>fast</em>. At the expense of removing certain features (Thumb and debug), DEC managed to cross the megahertz threshold by reaching speeds of up to 233 MHz. As a normal user prepared to buy a new ARM PC (let’s say a <em>RiscPC</em>), you could either choose one with the old ARM710 at 40 MHz or another one with a StrongARM running ~582% faster. The impact of StrongARM was so disruptive that ARM Holdings absorbed some of StrongARMs features to produce their next line of CPUs, starting with ARM9. And the rest is history.</p><p>But here’s where my question resides: Considering the new developments in the ARM world, why did Nintendo ultimately choose an awfully slow ARM9 combined by an even slower ARM7, instead of a faster ARM9 (or even a StrongARM)? To give you an idea, other companies like Apple just adopted the StrongARM with their Newton PDA line.</p><p>I don’t mean to criticise Nintendo’s choice, but I believe the amount of emerging technology was just too great for me to ignore. I guess their choice was done in an effort to preserve battery life and maintain production costs (by using the same CPU found in the GBA).</p></div></div></div><hr><h2 id="graphics">Graphics</h2><p>This section is a bit unusual because not only this console has multiple screens to draw, but also a combination of traditional tile engines working …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.copetti.org/projects/consoles/nintendo-ds/">https://www.copetti.org/projects/consoles/nintendo-ds/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.copetti.org/projects/consoles/nintendo-ds/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24195751</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 06:06:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Made in India CSS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 66 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24195745">thread link</a>) | @amitmerchant
<br/>
August 17, 2020 | https://nishantpainter.github.io/made-in-india-css/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nishantpainter.github.io/made-in-india-css/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section id="introduction">
      <div>
        <div>
          
          <p>
            Tricolor background patterns created using CSS linear and radial
            gradients.
          </p>
          <p><a href="https://nishantpainter.github.io/made-in-india-css/css/made-in-india.css" download="">
            Download CSS
          </a>
        </p></div>
      </div>
    </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nishantpainter.github.io/made-in-india-css/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24195745</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 06:05:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Ultraviolet Hubble Movie]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 25 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24195667">thread link</a>) | @simonebrunozzi
<br/>
August 17, 2020 | http://www.planetarylightshow.com/europa/prop_15424/v16-odr316bcq.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.planetarylightshow.com/europa/prop_15424/v16-odr316bcq.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
     
     <div>
   <p><a href="http://www.planetarylightshow.com/europa/prop_15424/v70-odr370khq-vmax7.html">|&lt;&lt;</a>  &nbsp;&nbsp;
   <a href="http://www.planetarylightshow.com/europa/prop_15424/v18-odr318dhq-vmax7.html">&lt;</a>  &nbsp;&nbsp;
   <a href="http://www.planetarylightshow.com/europa/prop_15424/v07-odr307jfq-vmax7.html">&gt;</a>  &nbsp;&nbsp;
   <a href="http://www.planetarylightshow.com/europa/prop_15424/v09-odr309cfq-vmax7.html">&gt;&gt;|</a> 
  
  
  &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<span title="Flux stretch maximum (cts/100s/pix)">Saturation level</span>:
    
    &nbsp;<em>7</em>
    
    &nbsp;<a href="http://www.planetarylightshow.com/europa/prop_15424/v16-odr316bcq-vmax15.html">15</a> 
    
    &nbsp;<a href="http://www.planetarylightshow.com/europa/prop_15424/v16-odr316bcq-vmax20.html">20</a> 
    
    &nbsp;<a href="http://www.planetarylightshow.com/europa/prop_15424/v16-odr316bcq-vmax40.html">40</a> 
    
    &nbsp;<a href="http://www.planetarylightshow.com/europa/prop_15424/v16-odr316bcq-vmax60.html">60</a> 
    
    &nbsp;<a href="http://www.planetarylightshow.com/europa/prop_15424/v16-odr316bcq-vmax80.html">80</a> 
    
    &nbsp;<a href="http://www.planetarylightshow.com/europa/prop_15424/v16-odr316bcq-vmax100.html">100</a> 
    
  
</p></div>
     
     <center>
     <p><img src="http://www.planetarylightshow.com/static/img/europa_15424_v16_odr316bcq_vmax7.gif" height="auto" width="85%">
     
     </p><br>
     
     <table>
         
             <tbody><tr>
             <td>target</td>
             <td>europa</td>
             </tr>
         
             <tr>
             <td>targname</td>
             <td>EUROPA-TRANSIT-16</td>
             </tr>
         
             <tr>
             <td>tardescr</td>
             <td>SATELLITE; Europa</td>
             </tr>
         
             <tr>
             <td>proposal</td>
             <td><a href="http://archive.stsci.edu/hst/search.php?sci_pep_id=15424&amp;sci_obset_id=%2A&amp;max_records=50000&amp;max_rpp=5000&amp;ordercolumn1=sci_start_time&amp;action=Search">15424</a></td>
             </tr>
         
             <tr>
             <td>obset</td>
             <td><a href="http://archive.stsci.edu/hst/search.php?sci_pep_id=15424&amp;sci_obset_id=16&amp;max_records=50000&amp;max_rpp=5000&amp;ordercolumn1=sci_start_time&amp;action=Search">16</a></td>
             </tr>
         
             <tr>
             <td>rootname</td>
             <td>ODR316BCQ</td>
             </tr>
         
             <tr>
             <td>start</td>
             <td>2019-06-15 02:05:27</td>
             </tr>
         
             <tr>
             <td>exptime</td>
             <td>2500.2</td>
             </tr>
         
             <tr>
             <td>obstype</td>
             <td>IMAGING</td>
             </tr>
         
             <tr>
             <td>opt_elem</td>
             <td>MIRFUV</td>
             </tr>
         
             <tr>
             <td>aperture</td>
             <td>F25SRF2</td>
             </tr>
         
             <tr>
             <td>distance (AU)</td>
             <td>4.28</td>
             </tr>
         
             <tr>
             <td>pixel scale (km/pix)</td>
             <td>75.974</td>
             </tr>
         
             <tr>
             <td>equatorial angular width (arcsec)</td>
             <td>1.006</td>
             </tr>
         
             <tr>
             <td>solar illumination %</td>
             <td>99.99</td>
             </tr>
         
             <tr>
             <td>Sun-Observer-Target angle (deg)</td>
             <td>175.16 trailing the sun</td>
             </tr>
         
             <tr>
             <td>Sun-&gt;Target-&gt;Observer angle (deg)</td>
             <td>0.92</td>
             </tr>
         
     </tbody></table></center><br>
   
   
   
   
   
   
   <center><p><a href="http://www.planetarylightshow.com/static/img/europa_odr316bcq_slew_correction.png">
   <img src="http://www.planetarylightshow.com/static/img/europa_odr316bcq_slew_correction.png">
   </a></p></center>
   
   
   
   <center><p><a href="http://www.planetarylightshow.com/static/img/multiframe_odr316bcq_vmax175.png">
   <img src="http://www.planetarylightshow.com/static/img/multiframe_odr316bcq_vmax175.png">
   </a></p></center>
   
   
   <div>
   <p><a href="http://www.planetarylightshow.com/europa/prop_15424/v70-odr370khq-vmax7.html#bottom">|&lt;&lt;</a>  &nbsp;&nbsp;
   <a href="http://www.planetarylightshow.com/europa/prop_15424/v18-odr318dhq-vmax7.html#bottom">&lt;</a>  &nbsp;&nbsp;
   <a href="http://www.planetarylightshow.com/europa/prop_15424/v07-odr307jfq-vmax7.html#bottom">&gt;</a>  &nbsp;&nbsp;
   <a href="http://www.planetarylightshow.com/europa/prop_15424/v09-odr309cfq-vmax7.html#bottom">&gt;&gt;|</a> 
</p></div>
   </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.planetarylightshow.com/europa/prop_15424/v16-odr316bcq.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24195667</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 05:46:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Let’s Learn x86-64 Assembly: Part 0 – Setup and First Steps]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 168 | Comments 37 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24195627">thread link</a>) | @nice_byte
<br/>
August 17, 2020 | https://gpfault.net/posts/asm-tut-0.txt.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://gpfault.net/posts/asm-tut-0.txt.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">
    <main role="main">

        
        
<p><img src="https://gpfault.net/assets/post-img/asm-tut-0/header.png">
</p>

<p>
The way I was taught x86 assembly at the university had been completely outdated for many years by the time I had my first class. It was around 2008 or 2009, and 64-bit processors had already started becoming a thing even in my neck of the woods. Meanwhile, we were doing DOS, real-mode, memory segmentation and all the other stuff from the bad old days.
</p>

<p>
Nevertheless, I picked up enough of it during the classes (and over the subsequent years) to be able to understand the stuff coming out of the other end of a compiler, and that has helped me a few times. However, I've never manually written any substantial amount of x86 assembly for something non-trivial. Due to being locked up inside (on account of a global pandemic), I decided to change that situation, to pass the time.
</p>

<p>
I wanted to focus on x86-64 specifically, and completely forget/skip any and all legacy crap that is no longer relevant for this architecture. After getting a bit deeper into it, I also decided to publish my notes in the form of tutorials on this blog since there seems to be a desire for this type of content.
</p>

<p>
Everything I write in these posts will be a normal, 64-bit, Windows program. We'll be using Windows because that is the OS I'm running on all of my non-work machines, and when you drop down to the level of writing assembly it starts becoming incresingly impossible to ignore the operating system you're running on. I will also try to go as "from scratch" as possible - no libraries, we're only allowed to call out to the operating system and that's it.
</p>

<p>
In this first, introductory part (yeah, I'm planning a series and I know I will regret this later), I will talk about the tools we will need, show how to use them, explain how I generally think about programming in assembly and show how to write what is perhaps the smallest viable Windows program.
</p>

<h2>Getting the Tools</h2>
<p>There are two main tools that we will use throughout this series.</p>

<h3>Assembler</h3>

<p>
CPUs execute machine code - an efficient representation of instructions for the processor that is almost completely impenetrable to humans. The assembly language is a human-readable representation of it. A program that converts this symbolic representation into machine code ready to be executed by a CPU is called an <b>assembler</b>.
</p>

<p>
There is no single, agreed-upon standard for x86-64 assembly language. There are many assemblers out there, and even though some of them share a great deal of similarities, each has its own set of features and quirks. It is therefore important which assembler you choose. In this series, we will be using 
<a href="http://flatassembler.net/">Flat Assembler</a> (or FASM for short). I like it because it's small, easy to obtain and use, has a nice macro system and comes with a handy little editor.</p>

<h3>Debugger</h3>

<p>
Another important tool is the debugger. We'll use it to examine the state of our programs. While I'm pretty sure it's possible to use Visual Studio's integrated debugger for this, I think a standalone debugger is better when all you want to do is look at the disassembly, memory and registers. I've always used <a href="http://ollydbg.de/">OllyDbg</a> for stuff like that, but unfortunately it does not have a 64-bit version. Therefore we will be using <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/p/windbg-preview/9pgjgd53tn86?activetab=pivot:overviewtab">WinDbg</a>. The version linked here is a revamp of this venerable tool with a slightly nicer interface. Alternatively, you can get the non-Windows-store version <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-hardware/drivers/debugger/debugger-download-tools">here</a> as part of the Windows 10 SDK. Just make sure you deselect everything else besides WinDbg during installation. For our purposes, the two versions are mostly interchangeable.
</p>

<h2>Thinking in Assembly</h2>

<p>
Now that we have our tools, I want to spend a bit of time to discuss some basics. For the purpose of these tutorials I'm assuming some knowledge of languages like C or C++, but little or no previous exposure to assembly, therefore many readers will find this stuff familiar.
</p>
<h3>A 10000-foot view</h3>
<p>
CPUs only "know" how to do a fixed number of certain things. When you hear someone talk about an "instruction set", they're referring to the set of things a particular CPU has been designed to do, and the term "instruction" just means "one of the things a CPU can do". Most instructions are parameterized in one way or another, and they're generally really simple. Usually an instruction is somthing along the lines of "write a given 8-bit value to a given location in memory", or "interpreting the values from registers A and B as 16-bit signed integers, multiply them and record the result into register A".
</p>

<p>
Below is a simple mental model of the architecture that we'll start with.
</p>

<p><img src="https://gpfault.net/assets/post-img/asm-tut-0/diag0.png">
</p>

<p>
 This skips a <i>ton</i> of things (there can be more than one core executing instructions and reading/writing memory, there's different levels of cache, etc. etc.), but should serve as a good starting point.
</p>

<p>
 To be effective at low-level programming or debugging you need to understand that every high-level concept eventually maps to this low-level model, and learning how the mapping works will help you.
</p>

<h3>Registers</h3>
<p>
 You can think of <b>registers</b> as a special kind of memory built right into the CPU that is very small, but extremely fast to access. There are many different kinds of registers in x86-64, and for now we'll concern ourselves only with the so-called <i>general-purpose</i> registers, of which there are sixteen. Each of them is 64 bits wide, and for each of them the lower byte, word and double-word can be addressed individually (incidentally, 1 "word" = 2 bytes, 1 "double-word" = 4 bytes, in case you haven't heard this terminology before).
 </p>
 
 <table>
 <tbody><tr>
  <td><b>Register</b></td>
  <td><b>Lower byte</b></td>
  <td><b>Lower word</b></td>
  <td><b>Lower dword</b></td>
 </tr>
 <tr>
  <td>rax</td> <td>al</td> <td>ax</td> <td>eax</td>
 </tr>
 <tr>
  <td>rbx</td> <td>bl</td> <td>bx</td> <td>ebx</td>
 </tr>
 <tr>
  <td>rcx</td> <td>cl</td> <td>cx</td> <td>ecx</td>
 </tr>
 <tr>
  <td>rdx</td> <td>dl</td> <td>dx</td> <td>edx</td>
 </tr>
 <tr>
  <td>rsp</td> <td>spl</td> <td>sp</td> <td>esp</td>
 </tr>
 <tr>
  <td>rsi</td> <td>sil</td> <td>si</td> <td>esi</td>
 </tr>
 <tr>
  <td>rdi</td> <td>dil</td> <td>di</td> <td>edi</td>
 </tr>
 <tr>
  <td>rbp</td> <td>bpl</td> <td>bp</td> <td>ebp</td>
 </tr>
 <tr>
  <td>r8</td> <td>r8b</td> <td>r8w</td> <td>r8d</td>
 </tr>
 <tr>
  <td>r9</td> <td>r9b</td> <td>r9w</td> <td>r9d</td>
 </tr>
 <tr>
  <td>r10</td> <td>r10b</td> <td>r10w</td> <td>r10d</td>
 </tr>
 <tr>
  <td>r11</td> <td>r11b</td> <td>r11w</td> <td>r11d</td>
 </tr>
 <tr>
  <td>r12</td> <td>r12b</td> <td>r12w</td> <td>r12d</td>
 </tr> 
 <tr>
  <td>r13</td> <td>r13b</td> <td>r13w</td> <td>r13d</td>
 </tr> 
 <tr>
  <td>r14</td> <td>r14b</td> <td>r14w</td> <td>r14d</td>
 </tr> 
 <tr>
  <td>r15</td> <td>r15b</td> <td>r15w</td> <td>r15d</td>
 </tr>   
</tbody></table>  

<p>Additionally, the higher 8 bits of <code>rax</code>, <code>rbx</code>, <code>rcx</code> and <code>rdx</code> can be referred to as <code>ah</code>, <code>bh</code>, <code>ch</code> and <code>dh</code>.</p>

<p>
Note that even though I said those were "general-purpose" registers, some instructions can only be used with certain registers, and some registers have special meaning for certain instructions. In particular, <code>rsp</code> holds the stack pointer (which is used by instructions like <code>push</code>, <code>pop</code>, <code>call</code> and <code>ret</code>), and <code>rsi</code> and <code>rdi</code> serve as source and destination index for "string manipulation" instructions. Another example where certain registers get "special treatment" are the multiplication instructions, which require one of the multiplier values to be in the register <code>rax</code>, and write the result into the pair of registers <code>rax</code> and <code>rdx</code>.
</p>

<p>
In addition to these registers, we will also consider the special registers <code>rip</code> and <code>rflags</code>. <code>rip</code> holds the address of the next instruction to execute. It is modified by control flow instructions like <code>call</code> or <code>jmp</code>. <code>rflags</code> holds a bunch of binary flags indicating various aspects of the program's state, such as whether the result of the last arithmetic operation was less, equal or greater than zero. The behavior of many instructions depends on those flags, and many instructions update certain flags as part of their execution. The flags register can also be read and written "wholesale" using special instructions.
</p>

<p>
There are a lot more registers on x86-64. Most of them are used for SIMD or floating-point instructions, and we'll not be considering them in this series.
</p>

<h3>Memory and Addresses</h3>

<p>
You can think of memory as a large array of byte-sized "cells", numbered starting at 0. We'll call these numbers "memory addresses". Simple, right?
</p>
<p>
Well... addressing memory used to be rather annoying back in the old days. You see, registers in old x86 processors used to be only 16-bit wide. Sixteen bits is enough to address 64 kilobytes worth of memory, but not more. The hardware was actually capable of using addresses as wide as 20 bits, but you had put a "base" address into a special segment register, and instructions that read or wrote memory would use a 16-bit offset into that segment to obtain the final 20-bit "linear" address. There were separate segment registers for code, data and stack portions (and a few more "extra" ones), and segments could overlap. 
</p>
<p>
In x86-64 these concerns are non-existant. The segment registers for code, data and stack are still present, and they're loaded with some special values, but as a user-space programmer you needn't concern yourself with them. For all intents and purposes you can assume that all segments start at 0 and extend for the entire addressable length of memory. So, as far as we're concerned, on x86-64 our programs see memory as a "flat" contiguous array of bytes, with sequential addresses, starting at 0, just like we said in the beginning of this section...
</p>
<p>
Okay, I may have distorted the truth a little bit. Things aren't quite as simple. While it is true that on 64-bit Windows your programs see memory as a flat contiguous array of bytes with addresses starting at 0, it is actually an elaborate illusion maintained by the OS and CPU working together.
</p>
<p>
The truth is, if you were really able to read and write any byte in memory willy-nilly, you'd stomp all over other programs' code and data (something that indeed could happen in the Bad Old Days). To prevent that, special protection mechanisms exist. I won't get too deep into their inner workings here because this stuff matters mostly for OS developers. Nevertheless, here's a very short overview:
</p>
<p>
Each process gets a "flat" address space as described above (we'll call it the "virtual address space"). For each process, the OS sets up a <a href="https://wiki.osdev.org/Paging">mapping</a> between its virtual addresses and actual physical addresses in memory. This mapping is respected by the hardware: the "virtual" addresses get translated to physical addresses dynamically at runtime. Thus, the same address (e.g. 0x410F119C) can map to two different locations in physical memory for two different processes. This, in a nutshell, is how the separation between processes in enforced.
</p>

<p>
The final thing I want to invite your attention to here is how the instructions and data which they operate on are held in the same …</p></main></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://gpfault.net/posts/asm-tut-0.txt.html">https://gpfault.net/posts/asm-tut-0.txt.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://gpfault.net/posts/asm-tut-0.txt.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24195627</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 05:39:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[1-Euro Houses]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 153 | Comments 177 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24195000">thread link</a>) | @Shinobuu
<br/>
August 17, 2020 | https://1eurohouses.com/case-a-1-euro-houses/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://1eurohouses.com/case-a-1-euro-houses/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">

<div>
		<div id="primary">
		<main id="main" role="main">

		
			<article id="post-2882">
	<!-- .entry-header -->


	<div>
		
		<!-- Per Emanuele -->
		<p>This post is also available in: 
    <span><a href="https://casea1euro.it/case-a-1-euro/"><span lang="it">Italiano</span><span><span> (</span>Italian<span>)</span></span></a></span></p><h3>Become a homeowner by spending only 1 euro.</h3>
<p>It seems impossible, however, thanks to a particular initiative that is becoming more and more popular, this can become a reality. The project <strong>Case a 1 euro (1-euro houses)</strong> has sprung from a few Italian municipalities with the intent to counter the population outflow and to give a new birth to troubled areas.<br>
With this operation <strong>Case a 1 euro (1-euro houses)</strong> we try to repopulate gorgeous villages that are being deserted, with the young population leaving and the elderly slowly fading away.</p>
<p>This unprecedented proposal has struggled initially, but it’s gaining popularity in recent times. This long-term strategy is attractive for those who are looking for low-cost real estate investments in Italy, and to simply restore prestige to Italian villages famous all over the world for their extraordinary beauty, and for that vintage spirit so cherished nowadays.</p>
<p>[metaslider id=”207″]
</p><p>Additionally, the <strong>Project Case a 1 euro (1-euro houses)</strong> could positively shock to the Italian real estate market facilitating access to homes by young people, for whom it is becoming increasingly difficult to take out a mortgage.</p>
<p>Last but not least, the repopulation of these small villages also promotes tourist activities, regenerating the economy of the entire area. To enhance the tourism economy, it is possible to repurpose an old building as a boutique hotel, a B&amp;B, or even to create a bigger project involving multiple premises in the same village to create a scattered hotel.</p>
<p>In conclusion, there are many very interesting possibilities and implications.</p>
		
		</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->
</article><!-- #post-## -->

			
            
		
		</main><!-- #main -->
	</div><!-- #primary -->
	
	

	<!-- #secondary -->
</div>

	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://1eurohouses.com/case-a-1-euro-houses/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24195000</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 03:34:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Building AGI Using Language Models]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 25 | Comments 19 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24194407">thread link</a>) | @leogao
<br/>
August 17, 2020 | https://leogao.dev/2020/08/17/Building-AGI-Using-Language-Models/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://leogao.dev/2020/08/17/Building-AGI-Using-Language-Models/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
      
        <!-- TOC -->
        
        <p><img src="https://leogao.dev/images/agi-lms/sunset1-glitch.png" alt=""></p>
<p><span>Despite the buzz around GPT-3, it is, in and of itself, not AGI.</span> In many ways, this makes it similar to AlphaGo or Deep Blue; while approaching human ability in one domain (playing Chess/Go, or writing <em>really</em> impressively), it doesn’t really seem like it will do <span><a href="https://wiki.lesswrong.com/wiki/Intelligence_explosion" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Scary AGI Things™</a></span> any more than AlphaGo is going to be turning the Earth into paperclips anytime soon. While its writings are impressive at emulating humans, GPT-3 (or any potential future GPT-x) has no memory of past interactions, nor is it able to follow goals or maximize utility. However, language modelling has one <em>crucial</em> difference from Chess or Go or image classification. Natural language essentially encodes information about the world—the <em>entire</em> world, not just the world of the Goban, in a much more expressive way than any other modality ever could.<sup><a href="#fn1" id="fnref1">[1]</a></sup> By harnessing the world model embedded in the language model, it may be possible to build a proto-AGI.</p>

<p>The explicit goal of a language model is only to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maximum_likelihood_estimation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">maximize likelihood</a> of the model on natural language data. In the <a href="https://leogao.dev/2019/10/27/The-Difficulties-of-Text-Generation-with-Autoregressive-Language-Models/">autoregressive formulation</a> that GPT-3 uses, this means being able to predict the next word as well as possible. However, this objective places much more weight on large, text-scale differences like grammar and spelling than fine, subtle differences in semantic meaning and logical coherency, which reflect as very subtle shifts in distribution. Once the former are near-perfect, though, the only place left to keep improving is the latter.</p>
<p>At the extreme, any model whose loss reaches the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Entropy_(information_theory)" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shannon entropy</a> of <a href="https://cs.stanford.edu/people/eroberts/courses/soco/projects/1999-00/information-theory/entropy_of_english_9.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">natural language</a>—the theoretical lowest loss a language model can possibly achieve, due to the inherent randomness of language—will be <em>completely indistinguishable</em> from writings by a real human in every way, and the closer we get to it, the more abstract the effect on quality of each bit of improvement in loss. Or, said differently, stringing words together using <a href="https://github.com/jsvine/markovify#markovify-in-the-wild" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Markov chain generators</a> gets you 50% of the way there, figuring out grammar gets you another 50% of the remaining distance, staying on topic across paragraphs gets you another 50% of the remaining distance, being logically consistent gets you another 50% of the remaining distance, and so on.<sup><a href="#fn2" id="fnref2">[2]</a></sup></p>
<p><span><span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mtable><mtr><mtd><mrow><mi>H</mi><mo>(</mo><mi>X</mi><mo>)</mo><mo>=</mo><mo>−</mo><mi mathvariant="double-struck">E</mi><mo>[</mo><mi>log</mi><mi mathvariant="double-struck">P</mi><mo>(</mo><mi>X</mi><mo>)</mo><mo>]</mo><mo>=</mo><mo>−</mo><msub><mo>∑</mo><mrow><mi>x</mi><mo>∈</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Ω</mi></mrow></msub><msub><mi>f</mi><mi>X</mi></msub><mo>(</mo><mi>x</mi><mo>)</mo><mi>log</mi><msub><mi>f</mi><mi>X</mi></msub><mo>(</mo><mi>x</mi><mo>)</mo></mrow></mtd></mtr></mtable></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">\begin{aligned}
H(X) = -\mathbb E[\log \mathbb P(X)] = -\sum_{x \in \Omega} f_X(x) \log f_X(x)
\end{aligned}</annotation></semantics></math></span></span></span></p><p><span>Shannon Entropy: the number of bits necessary, on average to specify one piece of text.</span></p>
<p>Why? Because if you have a coherent-but-not-logically consistent model, becoming more logically consistent helps you predict language better. Having a model of human behavior helps you predict language better. Having a model of the world helps you predict language better. As the low-hanging fruits of grammar and basic logical coherence are taken, the only place left for the model to keep improving the loss is a world model. Predicting text is <a href="http://mattmahoney.net/dc/rationale.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">equivalent to AI</a>.</p>
<p>The thing about GPT-3 that <a href="https://leogao.dev/2020/05/29/GPT-3-A-Brief-Summary/">makes it so important</a> is that it provides evidence that as long as we keep increasing the model size, we can keep driving down the loss, <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2001.08361" target="_blank" rel="noopener">possibly right up until</a> it hits the Shannon entropy of text. No need for clever architectures or complex handcrafted heuristics. Just by scaling it up we can get a better language model, and a better language model entails a better world model.</p>
<p>But how do we use this language model if it’s buried implicitly-represented inside GPT-x, though? Well, we can literally just <em>ask</em> it, in natural language, what it thinks will happen next given a sequence of events, and its output distribution will approximate the distribution of what the average human thinks would happen next after those events. Great—we’ve got ourselves a usable world model.</p>
<p>“But wait!” you say, “<a href="https://aiweirdness.com/post/621186154843324416/all-your-questions-answered" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Various</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/eigenrobot/status/1284042570507542528" target="_blank" rel="noopener">experiments</a> have shown that GPT-3 often fails at world modelling, and just conjecturing that adding more parameters will fix the problem is a <em>massive</em> leap!” If you’re thinking this, you’re absolutely correct. The biggest and most likely to be wrong assumption that I’m making is that larger models will develop better world models. Since as loss approaches the Shannon entropy its world modelling ability has to become about as good than the average human on the internet<sup><a href="#fn3" id="fnref3">[3]</a></sup>, this boils down to two questions: “Will we really make models whose loss gets close enough to the Shannon entropy?” and “How close is close enough, in order to have the world modelling capabilities to make all this practical?”</p>
<p><img src="https://leogao.dev/images/gpt3/perf_scaling_compute.png" alt="Loss keeps going down with more parameters and compute. (<a href='https://arxiv.org/abs/2005.14165'>Source</a>)"></p>
<p>The answer to the first question is “most likely”—that’s the <a href="https://leogao.dev/2020/05/29/GPT-3-A-Brief-Summary/">main takeaway of GPT-3</a>. The answer to the second question is… nobody knows. Some have demonstrated <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23990902" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ways of making GPT-3 better at world modelling</a>, but this alone is probably not sufficient. When models with 1 trillion, then 10 trillion, then 100 trillion parameters become available, we will have empirical evidence to see whether this assumption is correct. If GPT-x demonstrates uncanny ability to predict outcomes in the real world, then this just might work.</p>

<p>A world model alone does not an agent make, though.<sup><a href="#fn4" id="fnref4">[4]</a></sup> So what does it take to make a world model into an agent? Well, first off we need a goal, such as <a href="https://wiki.lesswrong.com/wiki/Paperclip_maximizer" target="_blank" rel="noopener">“maximize number of paperclips”</a>. Then, we just ask the world model “What action can I take to maximize the number of paperclips I have?” Simple, right? Actually, not quite. The problem is that our world model probably won’t be able to consider all the possible things that could happen next well enough to make a reasonable answer.</p>
<p><img src="https://leogao.dev/images/agi-lms/mesa.png" alt="GPT-3 considers mesa-optimization. (Source: OpenAI API)"></p>
<p>So what can we do instead? Well, asking the world model for a list of things you could do in a given world state would probably not be outside the capabilities of a sufficiently powerful language model (think: “I am in situation <span>xyz</span>. Here is a list of things I could do:”). Similarly, asking the world model how much reward you’d get in some hypothetical world where you took a sequence of actions would probably be possible too—imagine asking something along the lines of “I go to ebay. I look up paperclips, sorted by price ascending. I spend $100 on the first item on the list. How many paperclips will I have?”<sup><a href="#fn5" id="fnref5">[5]</a></sup> This will let us figure out what actions the agent can take in any given step (policy function), as well as how much reward each sequence of steps will net the agent (value function).</p>
<p>So now, to estimate the state-action value of any action, we can simply do <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monte_Carlo_tree_search" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Monte Carlo Tree Search</a> to estimate the state-action values! Starting from a given agent state, we can roll out sequences of actions using the world model. By integrating over all rollouts, we can know how much future expected reward the agent can expect to get for each action it considers. Then, we can simply use, for example, a greedy policy with that state-action value function, to decide on actions to take.</p>
<p><img src="https://leogao.dev/images/agi-lms/mcts.png" alt="Monte Carlo Tree Search visualized (<a href='https://www.researchgate.net/figure/Phases-of-the-Monte-Carlo-tree-search-algorithm-A-search-tree-rooted-at-the-current_fig1_312172859'>Source</a>)"></p>
<p>Each of these actions is likely to be very high level, such as “figure out the cheapest way to buy paperclips”, but thanks to the flexibility of language we can describe very complex ideas with short sequences of tokens. To actually execute these abstract actions once the agent decides on an action, that action can be broken down using the language model into smaller sub-goals such as “figure out the cheapest paperclips on Amazon”, similar to <a href="https://papers.nips.cc/paper/6233-hierarchical-deep-reinforcement-learning-integrating-temporal-abstraction-and-intrinsic-motivation.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hierarchical Reinforcement Learning</a>. Possibly even just breaking actions down into a detailed list of instructions would be feasible, depending on the capabilities of the model and how abstract the actions are.</p>
<p>We can represent the agent state as natural language, too. Since the agent state is just a compressed representation of the observations, we can ask the language model to summarize the important information of any observations for its own internal world state. The language model could be used to periodically prune (i.e forget) the information inside its state, too, to make room for more observations.</p>
<p>Altogether, this gets us a system where we can pass observations from the outside world in, spend some time thinking about what to do, and output an action in natural language.</p>
<p>To handle input, you could have an input module that turns various modalities of observations into summarized text with respect to the current agent state. For instance, you could use something like <a href="https://openai.com/blog/image-gpt/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">iGPT</a> to input camera images or screenshots, or raw HTML from webpages that the agent requests. How exactly this is done is tangential to the point; all that matters is that somehow the inputs are all converted to text and added to the agent state. The examples I have provided are just to convince you that it’s absolutely not insurmountable.</p>
<p>Finally, to get the model to actually act in the world, you could again use the language model to translate natural language into <a href="https://www.pscp.tv/Microsoft/1OyKAYWPRrWKb?t=29m19s" target="_blank" rel="noopener">code that is then executed</a>, or <a href="https://vimeo.com/427943407/98fe5258a7" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shell commands</a>, or sequences of keypresses, or any of a number of other possible ways. Like input, there are an infinitude of different ways to solve the output problem, and which one turns out to be the best is entirely irrelevant to our discussion; all that matters is that it’s possible to get various modalities in and out of the text-only agent.<sup><a href="#fn6" id="fnref6">[6]</a></sup></p>
<p><img src="https://leogao.dev/images/agi-lms/paperclipsamzn.png" alt="An example of an input module taking a screenshot input combined with the current agent state to give an observation with the information needed by the agent."></p>

<p>This is more a thought experiment than something that’s actually going to happen tomorrow; GPT-3 today just isn’t good enough at world modelling. Also, this method depends heavily on at least one major assumption—that bigger future models will have much better world modelling capabilities—and a bunch of other smaller implicit assumptions. <strong><span>However</span></strong>, this might be the closest thing we ever get to a chance to <a href="https://intelligence.org/2017/10/13/fire-alarm/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sound the fire alarm</a> for AGI: there’s now a concrete path to proto-AGI that has a non-negligible chance of working.</p>
<p><em>Thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/zitterbewegung" target="_blank" rel="noopener">zitterbewegung</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/realmeatyhuman" target="_blank" rel="noopener">realmeatyhuman</a>, and <a href="https://twitter.com/theshawwn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shawn Presser</a> for taking the time to provide feedback on the draft of this blog post!</em></p>
<h4 id="To-cite">To cite:</h4>
<figure><table><tbody><tr><td><pre><span>1</span><br><span>2</span><br><span>3</span><br><span>4</span><br><span>5</span><br><span>6</span><br><span>7</span><br></pre></td><td><pre><span>@article{lg2020agilms,</span><br><span>  title   = "Building AGI Using Language Models",</span><br><span>  author  = "Gao, Leo",</span><br><span>  journal = "leogao.dev",</span><br><span>  year    = "2020",</span><br><span>  url     = "https://leogao.dev/2020/08/17/Building-AGI-Using-Language-Models/"</span><br><span>}</span><br></pre></td></tr></tbody></table></figure>
<!--[^toolai]: One common line of argument is that such "tool AIs" are good enough and have desirable safety properties, and therefore agentistic AI need not ever be developed. One argument against this idea is that [agent AI will inevitably be more economically valuable than tool AI](https://www.gwern.net/Tool-AI), which would encourage their development.-->
<!--

Going from a model that just strings uniformly chosen words together to a simple [Markov chain generator](https://github.com/jsvine/markovify#markovify-in-the-wild) makes a *massive* difference, but the loss difference between a Markov chain generator and GPT-2 is much smaller despite GPT-2 being able to manage grammatically correct sentences nearly all of the time, and the loss difference between GPT-2 and GPT-3 is smaller still, despite massive subjective improvements in quality. 

The difference between "the quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog" and "shxixpgozcvoomz jcxfgabsdcxfrevogjsqewdnmkj" is *massive*, but the difference between "the quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog" and "the quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog"

Going from a model that just strings uniformly chosen words together to a model that uses words in the same [Zipf distribution](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zipf%27s_law) as regular text earns a large decrease in loss, because if you always pick common words like "the" you have a much better chance of being right than picking rare words. Another big decrease comes from considering n-gram frequencies rather than just single-word frequencies; this is the driving idea behind [Markov chain generators](https://github.com/jsvine/markovify#markovify-in-the-wild), which generate surprisingly good text considering how just how simple they are. Now, these 

-->
<hr>
<section>
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Images aren’t nearly as good as text for encoding unambiguous, complex ideas, unless you put text <em>in</em> images, but at that point that’s just …</p></li></ol></section></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://leogao.dev/2020/08/17/Building-AGI-Using-Language-Models/">https://leogao.dev/2020/08/17/Building-AGI-Using-Language-Models/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://leogao.dev/2020/08/17/Building-AGI-Using-Language-Models/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24194407</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 01:34:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[An Interview with Simon Kelley, the author of dnsmasq]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 31 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24193836">thread link</a>) | @apsec112
<br/>
August 17, 2020 | https://joshuakugler.com/an-interview-with-simon-kelley-the-author-of-dnsmasq.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://joshuakugler.com/an-interview-with-simon-kelley-the-author-of-dnsmasq.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                
                <p><em>This is the first in what will, hopefully, become a series. I would like to highlight projects that are widely used, even to the point of being part of critical infrastructure, but are nevertheless small projects with small (often unsponsored) development teams. We start the series talking to Simon&nbsp;Kelley.</em></p>
<p>dnsmasq is one of the unsung heroes of the Internet: a small piece of software used very widely, but with a <em>very</em> small development team, and no corporate backing. It is used as the <span>DHCP</span> and caching <span>DNS</span> server on a wide variety of home-market routers, as well as other devices, and is the default <span>DHCP</span> and <span>DNS</span> caching server for libvirt, and by extension, OpenStack. A couple years ago, I contacted Simon Kelley, the author of dnsmasq, and asked if he was up for an interview. He was, but my blog wasn’t in a maintainable position at that point, so it got pushed back. I contacted him again recently, and we managed to make it happen. This interview was conducted via e-mail on December 10,&nbsp;2017.</p>

<p>Simon, thank you for taking time out of your schedule (when you could be
programming) to answer my questions. This is quite an honor, and I hope you
enjoy the&nbsp;questions.</p>
<p>What itch were you scratching, that is, what was your original need and
intention for&nbsp;dnsmasq?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Long ago, around the turn of the century, I had a <span>PC</span>, running Linux, and
a net connection via a dial-up modem. If the <span>PC</span> was not connected to the
net then Netscape navigator would return an error immediately, because
the <span>UDP</span> packet doing a <span>DNS</span> query got a “no route to host” error. Then I
got a second-hand 486 laptop, and discovered that I could connect
that to my <span>PC</span> and give it a net connection too, using this amazing thing
called ip-masquerading (what later became <span>NAT</span>.) But when the Netscape on the
laptop would send the <span>UDP</span> <span>DNS</span> query to the <span>ISP</span>, it would get to the
desktop, where it would evaporate, and Netscape would hang (it was
single-threaded, at least in the <span>DNS</span> code) for a long time-out. I wanted
to fix that annoying behaviour. The <span>IP</span>-masquerade use is where the
DNSmasq name came&nbsp;from.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Did you intend to release it as open source from the&nbsp;beginning?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>To the extent that I intended to release it,&nbsp;yes.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>How much did you know about <span>DNS</span> and <span>DHCP</span> when you&nbsp;started?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Almost nothing, about the internals anyway. I started with <span>RFC</span> 1035 and
went from&nbsp;there.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>What is the most interesting bug you’ve run&nbsp;into?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Not one of mine - I found a Linux kernel bug once, in the <span>API</span> to control
the <span>ARP</span> cache. The bug was long-ago fixed, but in a sense, the
work-around still persists in dnsmasq. It was difficult to find because
it was intermittent and hard to reproduce, and it took a long time to
consider that the problem may not have been mine, but in the&nbsp;Kernel.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Related: when fixing a bug (found by you or reported), what has been your
most “What was I thinking when I wrote that”&nbsp;moment?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Plenty of those. I once found a “&amp;” versus “&amp;&amp;” confusion which nobody
had spotted as a functional error, by code&nbsp;inspection.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Have you ever found bugs in other <span>DHCP</span> and <span>DNS</span> products/libraries as a
result of your testing? What was the most interesting one? Feel free to share
others, if you&nbsp;wish.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There are lots of <span>DHCP</span> clients in things like printers and scanners and
general IoT devices which behave badly and need workarounds. Intel
produced some awful bugs in <span>PXE</span> implementations which went into netboot
<span>ROMS</span> and never got&nbsp;updated.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>What was your most “you’ve got to be kidding me” moment when learning new
corners of <span>DHCP</span> and <span>DNS</span> and/or your biggest “I wish I had known that when I
started”&nbsp;moment?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>It’s always amused me that the format of a <span>DNS</span> packet - which is very
size constrained to fit into <span>UDP</span> packets, wastes 16 bits for a count of
the number of questions in a query. This has been constrained to be
exactly one for all of the life of <span>DNS</span>, so the 16 bits are completely
wasted. <span>DNS</span> in general is an amazingly under-specified and obscure area.
It’s been around forever, and is developed by people who have been
around for a long time and grown up with it. They tend to vastly
underestimate how much implied knowledge they are assuming when writing
RFCs. As for what I wished I’d known: I wished I’d found the <span>RFC</span> which
is an errata  to the original three <span>DNSSEC</span> RFCs earlier; I found several
of the bugs the hard&nbsp;way.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>What was your reaction when you found out dnsmasq was used as the default
forwarder/<span>DHCP</span> server for OpenStack? What is it like having your project used
in one the most well known open source projects in the&nbsp;world?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>That happened after dnsmasq was incorporated into Android, so it was
sort of an anti-climax after getting into the majority of smart phones on
the&nbsp;planet.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>[ed. note: point&nbsp;taken]</p>
<p>Besides OpenStack, what are some of the most interesting use cases you’ve
heard about for&nbsp;dnsmasq?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I took some patches from someone who was providing satellite Internet to
trans-oceanic sailors. Bandwidth costs were high enough that it made
sense to audit almost every byte sent and received, including for <span>DNS</span>&nbsp;resolution.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Have you ever gotten contributions (code or otherwise) back from router
manufacturers that have used&nbsp;dnsmasq?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Probably, but I don’t remember anything significant in terms of code.
Comcast paid for a year of my time to implement <span>DNSSEC</span>, which was pretty
good of&nbsp;them.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>What kind of contributions have you turned&nbsp;down?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>That’s people who make a patch to solve their particular problem and
don’t give any thought to making it general, or generally&nbsp;useful.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Could you talk about one significant or difficult contribution you turned down
and why? - From my co-worker <a href="https://twitter.com/eduncan911">Eric Duncan&nbsp;@eduncan911</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>The one that’s happened over and over again is to change the behaviour
on receiving a “no-such-domain” reply from an upstream nameserver.
People want to implement local <span>DNS</span> hacks by getting dnsmasq to keep
trying another upstream server when the first returns <span>NXDOMAIN</span>, but
that’s always seemed to me to be a really bad thing to do: <span>NXDOMAIN</span> is a
valid answer, and not a failure&nbsp;return.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Do you have a group of steady contributors, or is it pretty much just you
(and occasional&nbsp;contributions)?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There are steady contributors, but long-term, it’s just&nbsp;me.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>You are pretty active on the mailing list. For the second quarter of 2017,
nearly 80 messages of the 229 are from you. How much time do you spend on the
project (code and helping&nbsp;users)?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Very variable, and less than I used to. I used to have a job with a very
<span>FOSS</span>-friendly employer. I was sitting in front of computer most days,
and my boss was happy for me to spend time on dnsmasq. Nowadays, I’m
semi-retired, and I spend my days doing other stuff, so I have to make
time to sit down and work on&nbsp;dnsmasq.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>What is your motivation for self-hosting, vs. moving to something like
Github or&nbsp;Bitbucket?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The self-hosting setup existed before Github etc, or at least before
they were visible and known to be reliable. It works, so I’ve never had
the activation energy to move it. I’m a sysadmin and I like having a
host to do my stuff, my&nbsp;way.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Your <span>FAQ</span> says it will run on Linux, *<span>BSD</span>, and embedded systems. What is the
most interesting platform you’ve heard of using&nbsp;dnsmasq?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Somebody ran it on <span>QNX</span> once, I&nbsp;believe.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Commit 1 in the dnsmasq git repository happened on January 22, 2004, and
says it is an “import of dnsmasq-2.0.tar.gz.”  When was your first public
release (version 0.4)? How long had you been working on it before&nbsp;then?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Around 2000. There were quite a few releases in the 1.x series, which
were before the <span>DHCP</span> server was added. It didn’t seem worth adding those
when I moved into&nbsp;git.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>What are your future plans, dreams, and hopes for&nbsp;dnsmasq?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Like all code that’s 15 years old, there are deep design decisions and
trade-off that are hard to change but which don’t necessarily make sense
any more. I’d like to do a version 3.0 which addresses those, but I’m
not sure I have the commitment left in me to do&nbsp;it.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In relation to the <a href="https://security.googleblog.com/2017/10/behind-masq-yet-more-dns-and-dhcp.html">recent security fixes contributed by Google</a> did
you know they were working on dnsmasq, or did the fixes come as a&nbsp;suprise?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>They didn’t tell me they were working on dnsmasq before they started,
but once they’d found holes, they let me know well before the public
disclosure. There’s a whole raft of stuff which happens in case like
this, and the Google security people were really good at helping to work
through it.  A lot is helping distributions to get patched packages ready in
advance: I spend a lot of effort helping people backport the fixes to
the older&nbsp;versions.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Have any steps been taken to do a full audit, or is that what Google&nbsp;did?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There have been quite a few audits over the years, before Google did its
stuff. <span>SUSE</span> did one, and the Mozilla foundation sponsored one. The
Google people used fuzzing to find the holes that had been missed by the
audits - it’s very&nbsp;impressive.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Has the  recent security news changed the development process&nbsp;any?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I plan to use Google’s service to do ongoing fuzzing of new&nbsp;releases.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Anything significant on the dnsmasq road map? Are there additions that could
be done, or do you cover all of the <span>DNS</span>/<span>DHCP</span> spec&nbsp;now?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I don’t cover the whole spec - the <span>USP</span> [ed. note: Unique Selling Point] is to cover the bits that my
users need, without carrying the bloat of everything else. I guess that
new stuff is still likely in the area of IPv6 address/name management.
IPv6 will take over the world one day, won’t&nbsp;it?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>[ed. note: We&nbsp;hope.]</p>
<p>Do you have a Patreon, Flattr, or other funding source to which people could&nbsp;contribute?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I have a PayPal account at simon@thekelleys.org.uk. Contributions
happily&nbsp;accepted.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Thanks again! I hope our paths will cross some&nbsp;day!</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I hope that’s useful. Please feel free to come back with more questions,
or for clarifications on the&nbsp;answers.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>That wraps it up! I greatly appreciate Simon taking time to do this. If you have questions, ask them in the&nbsp;comments.</p>
<p>The official page for dnsmasq can be found <a href="http://www.thekelleys.org.uk/dnsmasq/doc.html">on the Kelley’s&nbsp;page</a></p>
<p>Who should I interview next? Let me&nbsp;know!</p>
<p><em>Tha…</em></p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://joshuakugler.com/an-interview-with-simon-kelley-the-author-of-dnsmasq.html">https://joshuakugler.com/an-interview-with-simon-kelley-the-author-of-dnsmasq.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://joshuakugler.com/an-interview-with-simon-kelley-the-author-of-dnsmasq.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24193836</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:12:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Using, Understanding, and Unraveling the OCaml Language]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 80 | Comments 11 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24193795">thread link</a>) | @rabidsnail
<br/>
August 17, 2020 | http://caml.inria.fr/pub/docs/u3-ocaml/index.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://caml.inria.fr/pub/docs/u3-ocaml/index.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<tbody><tr><td><h3><a href="http://cristal.inria.fr/~remy"><span size="5">Didier R</span><span size="5">é</span><span size="5">my</span></a><span size="5">
</span></h3><h3><a href="http://www-sop.inria.fr/oasis/Caminha00/index.html">APPSEM'2000 summer school</a><sup><a name="text1" href="#note1">1</a></sup></h3></td></tr>
</tbody></div><p>Copyright ©&nbsp;2000, 2001 by Didier Rémy.
</p><p>
To correctly preview mathematical symbols, you may need 
to adjust your 
<a href="http://pauillac.inria.fr/~maranget/hevea/doc/browser.html">browser configuration</a>. 
</p></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://caml.inria.fr/pub/docs/u3-ocaml/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24193795</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:08:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
