<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 10]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 10. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 20:20:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-10.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 20:20:46 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: NeuralCam Live – Using ML to Turn iPhones into Smart Webcams]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 13 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24129714">thread link</a>) | @soonpls
<br/>
August 12, 2020 | https://neural.cam/news/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://neural.cam/news/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <div id="main">
    <div>
      <div>
        <div role="article">

          <div>
            

<p>Hey everyone, <br>

Today is a big day for NeuralCam. We have three announcements to make: some news about NeuralCam as a company, a major update for our NightMode app and a brand new <strong>Smart Camera app.</strong>
</p><br>
<h3>
NeuralCam - building Smart Camera Apps
</h3>
<div><p>Let’s start by talking a bit about cameras and AI. </p><p>

At NeuralCam, we think that one of the biggest leaps in technology over the past years has been the advances Deep Learning brought in the area of Computer Vision. It gives computers the ability to see - to understand patterns, images and video similarly to how people do.
 </p></div>



<p>Ultimately, we think this technology will give birth to a new category of cameras - <b>Smart Cameras</b> - that will have a profound impact on every activity that involves capturing and processing images.
</p>

<p>We see this change similar to the transformation from classic cellular phones to the modern smartphone we witnessed 10 years ago. We believe that martphones themselves seem to be the ideal smart camera platform: they have high quality cameras and enough processing power to run modern AI algorithms on-device.
</p>
<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/smartcameras.png">
</p>

<p>So, we can all have our own personal smart cameras in our pockets, all that’s needed is the right ML software. This ML software is what we call Smart Camera Apps, and these are the type of apps we’re building at NeuralCam.
</p>

<p>Whenever we see a visual task we might say “there’s a Smart Cam App for that”. We’ve been doing a lot of research and prototyping and we’re more and more confident that smart camera apps will play a key role in every industry, from Education through Healthcare to Entertainment, and we can’t wait to contribute something in each of these areas.

</p>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/smartapps.png">
</p>

<p>However, the first category that is naturally most likely to change is almost analogous to the camera itself: photography and videography. Thus, this is what we’ve decided to start with, building AI powered Photo &amp; Video apps over the next few years. 
</p>

<p>Our first smart photo app we’ve launched is the NeuralCam NightMode app, which brought Night Mode to all iPhones and all iPhone camera lenses. But, NeuralCam is more than the Night Mode app. We think of NeuralCam as a range of smart camera apps in different categories for various use cases. 
</p>



<p>So, one of the things we did is update our brand to reflect this change. This is the first thing we’d like to show you today, a fresh NeuralCam: 
</p>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/nclogo.png"></p>

<p>And this is the new NeuralCam NightMode:</p>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/NightModeLogo.png">
<br>
</p>
<p>Ok, so that’s the story of NeuralCam - the company. The second thing we want to show you is an update to our NightMode app. 

</p>

<h3 id="when-they-ghost-mid-project">NeuralCam NightMode</h3>

<p>We <a href="https://www.producthunt.com/posts/neuralcam" target="_blank">launched</a> our first smart camera app, NeuralCam NightMode, about a year ago, last August. It brought NightMode to the iPhone and the response from the users and critics <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2019/08/30/iphone-camera-app-for-night-shots/" target="_blank">was amazing.</a>
</p>

<p>We’ve been <a href="https://petapixel.com/2019/08/28/neuralcam-night-photo-app-brings-ai-powered-low-light-mode-to-iphones/" target="_blank">covered</a> <a href="https://bgr.com/2019/10/25/iphone-11-pro-camera-review-features-with-night-mode-app/" target="_blank">in many</a> <a href="https://bgr.com/2019/08/30/iphone-11-release-date-soon-specs-camera-night-mode/" target="_blank">major</a> <a href="https://thenextweb.com/apple/2019/08/29/this-app-uses-ai-to-add-a-pixel-style-night-photography-mode-to-your-iphone/" target="_blank">press</a> <a href="https://www.slashgear.com/neuralcam-iphone-app-uses-ai-to-capture-bright-images-at-night-26588672/" target="_blank">publications</a>, got lots of love letters from users, and been recognized as the best NightMode app out there. 
</p>
<p>While Apple has launched a built-in night mode on the iPhone 11 in the meantime, NeuralCam continues to be the NightMode solution for devices or iPhone cameras without a native NightMode - like the newly launched iPhone SE or even the UltraWide &amp; Selfie cameras on the iPhone 11 Pro. </p>
<p>Since its launch, people have used NeuralCam NightMode to take more than 10M low light photos. 
</p>

<div><p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/10M.png"></p></div>

<p>Now, with a major update, we have made our NightMode app even better: we've made some major improvements to our algorithm so that it supports higher resolutions on older devices too; we’ve updated the UI to be in-line with the new NeuralCam brand and we’ve officially added iPad support.</p><p>This is how the update NeuralCam NightMode app looks like on an iPad:</p>
<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/nmupdate.png">
<br>
</p>

<h3 id="when-they-ghost-mid-project">NeuralCam Live</h3>

<p>The popularity of video calls has exploded lately. In the current global context, most of us use video calls a lot for both getting our job done or to keep in touch with loved ones. For something used as often, we really need to have the best possible tools. 

</p>

<p>Looking at the things out there, we realized that there’s a weak link in all this video call experience, and it’s the webcams. </p><p>We’ve got laptop webcams (quite bad), dedicated webcams (a bit better) or apps that let you use your iPhone as a webcam (best quality). However, these products really only differ from one another in the resolution of the video they provide. 
</p>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/webcams.png">
<br>
</p>

<p> The problem with webcams is that they’re mostly the same as they were 10 years ago, they do the same thing only slightly better. In the meantime, this cool new technology called Deep Learning came along which could add a whole new dimension to webcams and possibly change the whole video call experience - but nobody uses it. 

</p>

<p>
It turns out that one of the main reasons for Deep Learning not being used with webcams is that no webcam has the processing power required to run the required ML algorithms. Except there is one device which, when converted to a webcam, could do all this: the iPhone in our pocket.
</p>

<p>It’s got one of the best cameras in the smartphone industry and with its fast processors and dedicated machine learning hardware, it is capable of running even video processing machine learning algorithms in real-time. It just needs the right SmartCam App software to do all this. 
  </p><p>We've built this software - we call it NeuralCam Live and it turns the iPhone into the <strong>world’s smartest webcam.</strong>
  </p>
<div><p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/LiveLogo.png"></p></div>







<p>
	Ok, so how are we going to do that?
</p>
<br>

<h3 id="when-they-ghost-mid-project">Technology</h3>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/tech.png">
<br>
</p>

<p>First, we need the software that connects the iPhone to the laptop and makes it appear just like a regular webcam when connected through a USB cable. 
</p>

<p>This software has two modules: the first one is an iOS app that provides the webcam functionality, while the second one is a plugin that’s installed on the laptop to make the iOS app appear as a webcam. Once you install both of these components, all you have to do is select the NeuralCam Live Camera in Zoom, Google Meet or your video call platform of choice.
</p>

<p>So, that was quite easy, now comes the fun part. </p><p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/engine.png">
<br>
</p>

<p> The second component we need is the machine learning software to make our smart webcam... well, smart. We call it the <b>LiveEngine</b> </p>

<p>Machine learning, as a generic technology, can help us in two ways when it comes to webcams: we can use it to recognize things in the video feed or generate new video content, improved in some way. </p><p>We’ve developed multiple machine learning modules, some proprietary, some built on top of existing CoreML models and we’ve grouped them in three different machine learning frameworks that cover both video generation and analysis: the Style Framework, the Enhance Framework and the Gesture Framework. Let’s take a quick look at each of these. 
</p>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/f_style.png">
<br>
</p>


<p>The <b>Style Framework</b> is a deep learning-based machine learning framework that edits video similarly to a professional colorist. 
</p>
<p>Its Neural Nets were trained on images edited by hand by professionals in a range of different editing styles. The results are quite amazing, generating pro-looking videosf, very close in terms of style to the professionally edited frames it was trained on and it does all this in real-time at 30fps locally, on the user’s iPhone.
</p>
<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/f_enhance.png">
<br>
</p>

<p>The <b>Enhance Framework</b> contains our set of machine learning models that can enhance a video in a bunch of different ways. </p>

<p>Our real-time video denoising and brightening models in this category achieve levels of quality and performance that are much better than traditional algorithms and make features such as video low light enhancement or face smoothing possible.
</p>
<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/f_recognition.png">
<br>
</p>

<p>The <b>Recognition Framework</b> is the part of our LiveEngine that is meant to make our smart camera apps understand what they “see”. </p>

<p>It uses a combination of machine learning models provided by the iPhone SDK and adds a number of proprietary elements to detect faces, user gestures or other different patterns in the live video feed. In the app, we can use this type of technology to blur unwanted gestures or guide you to set up an ideal environment for a call.
</p>

<p>Together, all these elements form what we call the LiveEngine - the ever-evolving software module that makes NeuralCam Live a smart webcam.
</p>

<h3>Features</h3>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/NCFeats.png">
<br>
</p>

<p>Now, let’s take a look at the actual product. </p>
<p>The iPhone app exposes all of the functionality of the smart iPhone webcam in a simple layout, most of the features can be accessed by just tapping a button on the screen. It also shows a nice preview of the current video feed. 
</p>
<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/smartwebcam.png">
<br>
</p>


<p>So, using all this technology, what more can a smart webcam do compared to a traditional webcam? 
</p>

<p>In terms of the outcome they provide to the user, we’ve realized that most of the AI features we’ve built fit nicely in two categories: making you look better and helping you avoid embarrassing mistakes.
</p>

<p>Let’s take a look at these features one-by-one: 
</p>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/fiq.png">
<br>
</p>

<h4>Face &amp; Image Quality Meter
</h4>



<p>The Face &amp; Image Quality Meter detects the amount of face lighting, type of face position and background and displays an overall Face Image Quality score. 
</p>

<p>It helps you set up an optimal video-call environment and helps you avoid making typical mistakes, such as sitting with your back towards a bright window or in an unfavorable low angle.
</p>
<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/styles.png">
  <br>
  </p>

<h4>Pro Video Styling</h4>

<p>
  
  Using the Style Framework, NeuralCam Live edits the video feed like a professional colorist would, in a range of different styles. The end-result is a more impactful look, allowing you to choose the style that best fits your mood, the type of call or the environment you're in.

</p>
<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/lowlight.png">
  <br>
  </p>

<h4>
  
  Low-light Mode
</h4>

<p>It wouldn't be a NeuralCam product without a Night Mode, right? </p>
<p>NeuralCam Live’s Low Light Mode brightens up your video with a similar (though a lot more lightweight) technique used in our Night Mode photo app. It allows you to look good in video calls even in low light settings, a gentle light from your monitor is usually enough to provide a nice video feed. 
</p>

<p>
  
  And just in case you need to light up things even more, you can use the face-following Ring Light …</p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://neural.cam/news/">https://neural.cam/news/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://neural.cam/news/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24129714</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 08:25:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Amazon’s business model meets Sweden’s labor unions]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 75 | Comments 77 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24129279">thread link</a>) | @ptr
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://www.politico.eu/article/amazons-cut-price-culture-meets-swedens-unions/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.politico.eu/article/amazons-cut-price-culture-meets-swedens-unions/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
							
							
							

							
							<div id="amazon-polly-audio-table">
				<p>Press play to listen to this article</p>
				
		</div><p>It's Sweden's storied worker protections and climate-conscious citizens welcoming Amazon's ruthless drive for low prices. What could go wrong?</p>
<p>Stockholm is preparing for a tug-of-war with one of the world’s most powerful companies — which just announced its entry into the Swedish market — and hopes that its arrival will mean the country of 10 million will be able to change Amazon, instead of being changed by it.</p>
<p>Amazon's plans — dubbed “<a href="https://www.ehandel.se/har-ar-amazon-se-det-blir-en-helsvensk-lansering" target="_blank">Project Dancing Queen</a>,” after the hit song by Swedish pop group Abba — don't have a lot of detail, but analysts believe its Swedish store will go live in the fall, in time for November’s Black Friday online shopping bonanza.</p>
<p>“Amazon has been supporting Swedish customers and selling partners across our different European stores for many years, but the next step is to bring a full retail offering to Sweden and we are making those plans now,” said Alex Ootes, Amazon’s vice president for EU expansion, in a statement.</p>
<p>Amazon’s turbo-capitalism corporate culture goes against the grain of Sweden and the rest of the Nordic countries, which pride themselves in their strong labor unions and sustainability.</p>
<blockquote><p>“Swedish e-commerce is still like regular retail without shopping malls” <em>— Jonas Arnberg, CEO of market-research firm HUI</em></p></blockquote>
<p>But the country also has an affluent, internet-savvy market ripe for Alexa, Kindles, Prime and the thousands of items on Amazon's online store, the company believes. Around 68 percent of Swedes shopped online in 2018, and they spent an average of €200 per online transaction. In total, the Nordic countries spent over €22 billion online in 2018, according to a <a href="https://www.postnord.fi/siteassets/raportit/verkkokauppa-pohjoismaissa/ecommerce-in-the-nordics-2019.pdf" target="_blank">study</a> by PostNord, the country’s postal service.</p>
<p>There's not a lot of competition in online marketplaces, and nobody can match Amazon’s massive cornucopia of goods.</p>
<p>“Swedish e-commerce is still like regular retail without shopping malls,” said Jonas Arnberg, the CEO of HUI, a market research company.</p>
<p>Amazon will change that, and force local players to adopt e-commerce faster than they would have otherwise.</p>
<p>“It’s a perfect storm in e-commerce now. The COVID-19 impact took us two to three years forward in digitalization. With Amazon’s entry it is going to go even further,” said Kristoffer Väliharju, the CEO of CDON, a Nordic online marketplace. Väliharju is optimistic about CDON’s chances of taking on the tech giant, but said companies without a strong e-commerce game will likely take a big hit.</p>
<p>Initially, Swedish and Nordic clients will be mainly served from German warehouses — known as fulfillment centers in Amazon-speak — with trucks driving up to Sweden through Denmark, and a fulfillment center operated by local partner Kuehne + Nagel in the Swedish town of Eskilstuna, near Stockholm.</p>
<p>Analysts believe local warehouses are inevitable if Amazon is to offer one of its most unique selling points: quick delivery.</p>
<h3>When in Stockholm</h3>
<p>Establishing a local operation will be a major challenge for the company. American Amazon’s <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/08/22/how-amazon-is-fighting-back-against-workers-efforts-to-unionize.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">anti-union stance</a> and <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2015/08/16/technology/inside-amazon-wrestling-big-ideas-in-a-bruising-workplace.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">working culture</a> is the antithesis of pro-union Sweden. (Swedish Prime Minister Stefan Löfven's political career is rooted in union activism dating from his time as a welder.)</p>
<p>The Swedish labor market is regulated by collective agreements between companies and unions, giving workers plenty of power over corporate decisions. Approximately 70 percent of Swedish workers belong to a union.</p>
<p>“If Amazon wants to succeed in Sweden, they need to work very closely with unions,” said Arne Andersson, an e-commerce expert at PostNord.</p>
<p>Amazon has not yet contacted Handels, the union representing warehouse workers, its political coordinator Emelie Wärn told POLITICO.</p>
<div id="attachment_1432138"><p><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1432138" src="https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-714x476.jpg" alt="" width="714" height="476" srcset="https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-714x476.jpg 714w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-300x200.jpg 300w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-768x512.jpg 768w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-1160x773.jpg 1160w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-380x253.jpg 380w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-171x114.jpg 171w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-90x60.jpg 90w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-104x69.jpg 104w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-200x133.jpg 200w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-390x260.jpg 390w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-54x36.jpg 54w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-1080x720.jpg 1080w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-333x222.jpg 333w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-1120x746.jpg 1120w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-600x400.jpg 600w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 714px) 100vw, 714px"></p><p id="caption-attachment-1432138">Sweden's warehouse-workers union, Handels, has successfully negotiated with fashion chain Uniqlo in the past | Sean Gallup/Getty Images</p></div>
<p>“Amazon is welcome to Sweden, but they have to sign a collective agreement. We will work very hard to get them to do that,” Wärn said.</p>
<p>“The fact that international companies takes interest in the Swedish market place is a positive thing. As an employer in Sweden you are obliged to follow Swedish labor legislation, which includes regulations regarding collective bargaining,” said Eva Nordmark, Sweden’s minister of employment, adding that approximately 90 percent of the employees in Sweden are covered by collective bargaining agreements.</p>
<p>The minimum wage for a card-carrying Swedish warehouse worker is 142.50 Swedish krona (€13.85) per hour before tax, according to Handels. In contrast, Amazon’s Polish warehouse workers who serve the German market <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/coronavirus-amazon-employees-rage/">earn</a> 20 zlotys (around €4.50). Amazon said its workers in Germany earn a base pay of €11.10 an hour.</p>
<p>But the union is confident it will be able to negotiate with the tech goliath. Handels has done similar deals with Japanese fashion chain Uniqlo, Wärn said as an example.</p>
<p>But Uniqlo is not Amazon, and Handels' confidence might be misplaced, according to Markus Varsikko, a retail consultant at Dash Retail, which helps businesses use Amazon's marketplace.</p>
<p>“Amazon is a realist. If they can operate in Germany, they can operate in Sweden. It is an American company with American culture and thinking, and it is far from what we are used to here,” Varsikko said, arguing that Sweden's companies and workers might have to adapt — not the tech giant.</p>
<h3>Handels and Greta</h3>
<p>Amazon might also have to polish its sustainability credentials to appease Swedish consumers.</p>
<p>“What makes the Swedish market unique is that there is a great focus on companies to do good, be transparent and sustainable. For many Swedes, this is even more important than a wide range and low price,” said Niclas Eriksson, the CEO of electronics retailer Elgiganten. And thanks to local activist Greta Thunberg, consumers are <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/cancel-your-amazon-prime-subscription-save-the-planet/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">becoming increasingly aware</a> of the carbon footprint of services like next-day delivery.</p>
<blockquote><p>European consumer groups have slammed Amazon for selling dangerous and illegal products such as toxic toys and exploding power banks on its platform.</p></blockquote>
<p>Plus Amazon's insistence on lower prices might not be its winning ticket.</p>
<p>The foray into the Swedish market by another e-commerce company, Wish, may serve as a cautionary tale. The American online marketplace, which mostly sells cheap items from China, tried and failed to take over the market a few years ago. The company first wooed consumers with dirt-cheap products such as electronics and clothes, only for Swedes to be disappointed by the quality of the products and frustrated by not being able to return products to sellers.</p>
<p>"[Wish] was cheap, it was a great marketplace, but it was also crap,” said PostNord’s Andersson. Wish did not respond to a request for comment.</p>
<p>Amazon's had troubles with quality control too. European consumer groups have <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/online-marketplaces-rife-with-unsafe-and-illegal-items-study-shows/">slammed</a> the company for selling dangerous and illegal products such as toxic toys and exploding power banks on its platform. The European Commission also put pressure on online platforms to control scammers and price gouging during the coronavirus pandemic.</p>
<p>CDON’s Väliharju said Swedish customers are very quality-conscious, and aware of their rights as consumers. Consumer groups and <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/how-big-brands-chanel-canon-louis-vuitton-nike-are-taking-on-big-tech-silicon-valley-at-last/">brands</a> have criticized Amazon and others for not holding sufficient information about their sellers, especially for products that come from outside the European Union that could be dangerous or counterfeit.</p>
<p>“Amazon absolutely could be well met by Swedish consumers in the beginning,” said Arnberg, the CEO of HUI, citing Amazon’s promise of low prices, a big range of products and fast delivery.</p>
<p>“But in the long run they will have to adjust to Sweden."</p>
<p><em>This article has been updated to include Amazon's partnership with a warehouse provider in Sweden, and Amazon workers' wages in Germany.</em></p>
<p><em>This article is part of </em><span>POLITICO</span><em>’s premium Tech policy coverage: Pro Technology. Our expert journalism and suite of policy intelligence tools allow you to seamlessly search, track and understand the developments and stakeholders shaping EU Tech policy and driving decisions impacting your industry. Email <a href="mailto:pro@politico.eu" target="_blank">pro@politico.eu</a> with the code ‘TECH’ for a complimentary trial.</em></p>

							
							
							<!--/.story-supplement-->

						</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.politico.eu/article/amazons-cut-price-culture-meets-swedens-unions/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24129279</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 06:58:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Chris Hedges: America’s Death March]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 15 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24128745">thread link</a>) | @cbHXBY1D
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://scheerpost.com/2020/08/10/chris-hedges-americas-death-march/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://scheerpost.com/2020/08/10/chris-hedges-americas-death-march/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
		Regardless of the outcome, the election will not stop the rise of hypernationalism, crisis cults and other signs of an empire's terminal decline. 	</p><div>
		
<p><strong>By Chris Hedges </strong>/ Original to Scheerpost</p>



<p>The terminal decline of the United States will not be solved by elections. The political rot and depravity will continue to eat away at the soul of the nation, spawning what anthropologists call crisis cults — movements led by demagogues that prey on an unbearable psychological and financial distress. These crisis cults, already well established among followers of the Christian Right and Donald Trump, peddle magical thinking and an infantilism that promises — in exchange for all autonomy — prosperity, a return to a mythical past, order and security. The dark yearnings among the white working class for vengeance and moral renewal through violence, the unchecked greed and corruption of the corporate oligarchs and billionaires who manage our failed democracy, which has already instituted wholesale government surveillance and revoked most civil liberties, are part of the twisted pathologies that infect all civilizations sputtering towards oblivion. I witnessed the deaths of other nations during the collapse of the communist regimes in Eastern Europe and later in the former Yugoslavia. I have smelled this stench before.</p>



<p>The removal of Trump from office will only exacerbate the lust for racist violence he incites and the intoxicating elixir of white nationalism. The ruling elites, who first built a mafia economy and then built a mafia state, will continue under Biden, as they did under Trump, Barack Obama, George W. Bush, Bill Clinton and Ronald Reagan, to wantonly pillage and loot. The militarized police will not stop their lethal rampages in poor neighborhoods. The endless wars will not end. The bloated military budget will not be reduced. The world’s largest prison population will remain a stain upon the country. The manufacturing jobs shipped overseas will not return and the social inequality will grow. The for-profit health care system will gouge the public and price millions more out of the health care system. The language of hate and bigotry will be normalized as the primary form of communication. Internal enemies, including Muslims, immigrants and dissidents, will be defamed and attacked. The hypermasculinity that compensates for feelings of impotence will intensify. It will direct its venom towards women and all who fail to conform to rigid male stereotypes, especially artists, LGBTQ people and intellectuals. Lies, conspiracy theories, trivia and fake news — what Hannah Arendt called “nihilistic relativism” — will still dominate the airwaves and social media, mocking verifiable fact and truth. The ecocide, which presages the extinction of the human species and most other life forms, will barrel unabated towards its apocalyptic conclusion.</p>



<p>“We run heedlessly into the abyss after putting something in front of us to stop us seeing it,” Pascal wrote.</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="3971" data-permalink="https://scheerpost.com/2020/08/10/chris-hedges-americas-death-march/death-march/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?fit=2560%2C1978&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2560,1978" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="Death March" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?fit=300%2C232&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?fit=780%2C603&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="780" height="603" src="https://i1.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March.jpg?resize=780%2C603&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C791&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C232&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C594&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1187&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1583&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C927&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 780px) 100vw, 780px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C791&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C232&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C594&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1187&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1583&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C927&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" data-lazy-src="https://i1.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March.jpg?resize=780%2C603&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><figcaption>[Art by Mr. Fish/Original to Scheerpost]</figcaption></figure>



<hr>



<p>The worse it gets — and it will get worse as the pandemic hits us in wave after deadly wave with an estimated <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/08/06/health/us-coronavirus-thursday/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener follow" data-wpel-link="external">300,000 Americans dead by December</a> and possibly 400,000 by January — the more desperate the nation will become. Tens of millions of people will be thrown into destitution, evicted from their homes and abandoned. Social collapse, as Peter Drucker observed in Weimar Germany in the 1930s, brings with it a loss of faith in ruling institutions and ruling ideologies. With no apparent answers or solutions to mounting chaos and catastrophe — and Biden and the Democratic Party have already precluded the kind of New Deal programs and assault on oligarchic power that saved us during the Great Depression — demagogues and charlatans need only denounce all institutions, all politicians, and all political and social conventions while conjuring up hosts of phantom enemies. Drucker saw that Nazism succeeded not because people believed in its fantastic promises, but in spite of them. Nazi absurdities, he pointed out, had been “witnessed by a hostile press, a hostile radio, a hostile cinema, a hostile church, and a hostile government which untiringly pointed out the Nazi lies, the Nazi inconsistency, the unattainability of their promises, and the dangers and folly of their course.” Nobody, he noted, “would have been a Nazi if rational belief in the Nazi promises had been a prerequisite.” The poet, playwright and socialist revolutionary Ernst Toller, who was forced into exile and stripped of his citizenship when the Nazis took power in 1933, wrote much the same in his autobiography: “The people are tired of reason, tired of thought and reflection. They ask, what has reason done in the last few years, what good have insights and knowledge done us.” After Toller committed suicide in 1939, W.H. Auden in his poem “In Memory of Ernst Toller” wrote:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We are lived by powers we pretend to understand:<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They arrange our loves; it is they who direct at the end<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The enemy bullet, the sickness, or even our hand.</p>



<p>The poor, the vulnerable, those who are not white or not Christian, those who are undocumented or who do not mindlessly repeat the cant of a perverted Christian nationalism, will be offered up in a crisis to the god of death, a familiar form of human sacrifice that plagues sick societies. Once these enemies are purged from the nation, we are promised, America will recover its lost glory, except that once one enemy is obliterated another takes its place. Crisis cults require a steady escalation of conflict. This is what made the war in the former Yugoslavia inevitable. Once one stage of conflict reaches a crescendo it loses its efficacy. It must be replaced by ever more brutal and deadly confrontations. The intoxication and addiction to greater and greater levels of violence to purge the society of evil led to genocide in Germany and the former Yugoslavia. We are not immune. It is what Ernst Jünger called a “feast of death.”</p>



<p>These crisis cults are, as Drucker understood, irrational and schizophrenic. They have no coherent ideology. They turn morality upside down. They appeal exclusively to emotions. Burlesque and celebrity culture become politics. Depravity becomes morality. Atrocities and murder become heroism. Crime and fraud become justice. Greed and nepotism become civic virtues. What these cults stand for today, they condemn tomorrow. At the height of the reign of terror on May 6, 1794 during the French Revolution, Maximilien Robespierre announced that the Committee for Public Safety now recognized the existence of God. The French revolutionaries, fanatical atheists who had desecrated churches and confiscated church property, murdered hundreds of priests and forced another 30,000 into exile, instantly reversed themselves to send to the guillotine those who disparaged religion. In the end, exhausted by the moral confusion and internal contradictions, these crisis cults yearn for self-annihilation.</p>



<p>The French sociologist <a href="https://www.britannica.com/biography/Emile-Durkheim" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener follow" data-wpel-link="external">Emile Durkheim</a> in his classic book “<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Suicide-Penguin-Classics-Emile-Durkheim-ebook/dp/B002RI9XE2" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener follow" data-wpel-link="external">On Suicide</a>” found that when social bonds are shattered, when a population no longer feels it has a place or meaning in a society, personal and collective acts of self-destruction proliferate. Societies are held together by a web of social bonds that give individuals a sense of being part of a collective and engaged in a project larger than the self. This collective expresses itself through rituals, such as elections and democratic participation or an appeal to patriotism, and shared national beliefs. The bonds provide meaning, a sense of purpose, status and dignity. They offer psychological protection from impending mortality and the meaninglessness that comes with being isolated and alone. The breaking of these bonds plunges individuals into deep psychological distress. Durkheim called this state of hopelessness and despair anomie, which he defined as “ruleless-ness.”</p>



<p>Ruleless-ness means the norms that govern a society and create a sense of organic solidarity no longer function. The belief, for example, that if we work hard, obey the law and get a good education we can achieve stable employment, social status and mobility along with financial security becomes a lie. The old rules, imperfect and often untrue for poor people of color, nevertheless were not a complete fiction in the United States. They offered some Americans — especially those from the white working and middle class — modest social and economic advancement. The disintegration of these bonds has unleashed a widespread malaise Durkheim would have recognized. The self-destructive pathologies that plague the United States — opioid addiction, gambling, suicide, sexual sadism, hate groups and mass shootings — are products of this anomie. So is our political dysfunction. My book, “<a href="http://freshstore.truthdig.com/america-the-farewell-tour/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener follow" data-wpel-link="external">America: The Farewell Tour</a>,” is an examination of these pathologies and the widespread anomie that defines American society.</p>



<p>The economic structures, even before the pandemic, were reconfigured to mock faith in a meritocracy and the belief that hard work leads to a productive and valued role in society. American <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=define+economic+productivity&amp;ie=utf-8&amp;oe=utf-8&amp;client=firefox-b-1-ab" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener follow" data-wpel-link="external">productivity</a>, as The New York Times <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/11/magazine/americans-jobs-poverty-homeless.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener follow" data-wpel-link="external">pointed out</a>, has increased 77 percent since 1973 but hourly pay has grown only 12 percent. If the federal minimum wage was attached to productivity, the newspaper wrote, it would be more than $20 an hour now, not $7.25. Some 41.7 million workers, a third of the workforce, earn less than $12 an hour, and most of them do not have access to employer-sponsored health insurance. A decade after the 2008 financial meltdown, the Times wrote, the average middle class family’s net worth is more than $40,000 below what it was in 2007. The net worth of black families is down 40 percent, and for Latino families the figure has dropped 46 percent. Some four million evictions are filed each year. One in four tenant households spends <a href="https://www.jchs.harvard.edu/sites/default/files/Harvard_JCHS_Americas_Rental_Housing_2020.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener follow" data-wpel-link="external">about half its pretax income</a> …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://scheerpost.com/2020/08/10/chris-hedges-americas-death-march/">https://scheerpost.com/2020/08/10/chris-hedges-americas-death-march/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://scheerpost.com/2020/08/10/chris-hedges-americas-death-march/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24128745</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 05:05:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Dreamup: A codeless alternative to the Web]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 11 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24126916">thread link</a>) | @escot
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://blog.antipa.io/the-dreamup/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.antipa.io/the-dreamup/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.antipa.io/the-dreamup/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24126916</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 22:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Let's Build a 28-Core Raspberry Pi Cluster]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 126 | Comments 86 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24126719">thread link</a>) | @ColinWright
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://ikarus.sg/how-i-built-kraken/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ikarus.sg/how-i-built-kraken/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">
    <div>

        <article>

            

            <figure>
                <img srcset="https://ikarus.sg/content/images/size/w300/2020/06/kraken-anim.gif 300w,
                            https://ikarus.sg/content/images/size/w600/2020/06/kraken-anim.gif 600w,
                            https://ikarus.sg/content/images/size/w1000/2020/06/kraken-anim.gif 1000w,
                            https://ikarus.sg/content/images/size/w2000/2020/06/kraken-anim.gif 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 400px,
                        (max-width: 1170px) 1170px,
                            2000px" src="https://ikarus.sg/content/images/size/w2000/2020/06/kraken-anim.gif" alt="Let's Build a 28-core Raspberry Pi Cluster!">
            </figure>

            <section>
                <div>
                    <p><em><em>This is the </em>second instalment of my<em> 'How I built' trilogy detailing the build process of all 3 of my clusters.</em> Read the first <a href="https://ikarus.sg/how-i-built-octopi">here</a>.</em></p><figure><img src="https://ikarus.sg/content/images/2020/06/timeline-2-1.png" alt="" srcset="https://ikarus.sg/content/images/size/w600/2020/06/timeline-2-1.png 600w, https://ikarus.sg/content/images/size/w1000/2020/06/timeline-2-1.png 1000w, https://ikarus.sg/content/images/size/w1600/2020/06/timeline-2-1.png 1600w, https://ikarus.sg/content/images/2020/06/timeline-2-1.png 2362w" sizes="(min-width: 1200px) 1200px"><figcaption>Where you are in the cluster timeline</figcaption></figure><h2 id="octopains">Octo<em>pains</em></h2><p>In October 2018, more than a year after <a href="https://ikarus.sg/how-i-built-octopi/">building my first cluster Octopi</a>, I had officially outgrown the cluster. I started noticing the performance bottlenecks started when I tried to run Wordpress on it, where a single page load of a newly installed Wordpress blog takes about <strong>10 seconds!</strong> Nevertheless, all that was unsurprising given the measly single-core 700MHz processor on each node.</p><p>At that point in time, I've graduated from university then and secured a job as a Data Scientist + Full-Stack Engineer at a startup and I thought to myself:</p><blockquote>What better a time to build myself a new cluster?</blockquote><h2 id="kraken">Kraken</h2><p>The second cluster was named <em>Kraken</em>.</p><blockquote>The <strong>kraken</strong> (/ˈkrɑːkən/)[1] is a legendary cephalopod-like sea monster of gigantic size in Scandinavian folklore. (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kraken">Wikipedia</a>)</blockquote><p>The Kraken is basically a much bigger and monstrous octopus, hence the name, symbolizing an evolution of the first cluster. It was built out of 7 Raspberry Pi 3Bs powered by a single USB charger. </p><p>With my first pay check, I had initially intended to <em>finally</em> build a cluster of 8 nodes but once again I was unable to realize this <em>cursed</em> idea. The maximum number of ports on a consumer-grade network switch was 8, enough for 7 nodes and a cable to the router. </p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Item</th>
<th>TP-Link 8-port Switch</th>
<th>TP-Link 16-Port Smart Switch</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Photo</td>
<td><img src="https://ikarus.sg/content/images/2020/06/71-bqPCPpIL._AC_SL1500_-copy-1.jpg" alt="71-bqPCPpIL.AC_SL1500-copy-1"></td>
<td><img src="https://ikarus.sg/content/images/2020/06/51iCTDaci8L._AC_SL1000_-copy-1.jpg" alt="51iCTDaci8L.AC_SL1000-copy-1"></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Cost (SGD)<sup>*</sup></strong></td>
<td><strong>S$26.46</strong></td>
<td><strong>S$195.03</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Cost (USD)</strong></td>
<td><strong>$18.99</strong></td>
<td><strong>$139.97</strong></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><sup>*</sup> SGD/USD exchange rate is 0.71770 as of the time of writing</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>An alternative was to use commercial-grade network switches with 16 ports but that was obviously was out of the question (and budget).</p><h3 id="cluster-specifications">Cluster Specifications</h3><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th></th>
<th>7 × Raspberry Pi 3 Model B</th>
<th>Overall</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>CPU</td>
<td>4 × Cortex-A53 1.2 GHz</td>
<td>28 × Cortex-A53 1.2 GHz</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>RAM</td>
<td>1GB</td>
<td>7GB</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>USB</td>
<td>4 × USB 2.0</td>
<td>28 × USB 2.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Storage</td>
<td>16GB MicroSD Class 10</td>
<td>128GB<sup>1</sup> Class 10</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><sup>1</sup>Comprised of 1 × 32GB, 6 × 16GB</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><figure><img src="https://ikarus.sg/content/images/2020/06/IMG_20181017_023248.jpg" alt=""><figcaption>The Kraken cluster is born! (No that's not my ceiling)</figcaption></figure><p>The total damage my wallet sustained from Kraken was <strong>S$626.63</strong> or in <strong>$449.73 USD</strong>, which was virtually all I had left for the month after subtracting expenses and education loan repayments.</p><h2 id="parts-list">Parts list</h2><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Item</th>
<th>Qty</th>
<th>Cost (SGD)</th>
<th>Cost (USD)<sup>*</sup></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Raspberry Pi 3 Model B</td>
<td>7</td>
<td>S$420.00</td>
<td>$301.43</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Anker PowerPort 10 60W 10-port USB Charger</td>
<td>1</td>
<td>S$32.58</td>
<td>$23.38</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>TP-Link TL-SF1008D 8-Port Ethernet Switch</td>
<td>1</td>
<td>S$20.00</td>
<td>$14.35</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Cat 5e 30cm cable</td>
<td>7</td>
<td>S$3.50</td>
<td>$2.51</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Cat 5e 1m cable</td>
<td>1</td>
<td>S$2.00</td>
<td>$1.44</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>MicroUSB charging cable</td>
<td>7</td>
<td>S$21.00</td>
<td>$15.07</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>16GB Class 10 MicroSD Card</td>
<td>7</td>
<td>S$70.00</td>
<td>$50.24</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>32GB Class 10 MicroSD Card</td>
<td>1</td>
<td>S$16.00</td>
<td>$11.48</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><sup>1</sup> GeauxRobot Raspberry Pi 7-Layer Dog Bone Stack</td>
<td>1</td>
<td>S$41.55</td>
<td>$29.82</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Total</strong></td>
<td></td>
<td><strong>S$626.63</strong></td>
<td><strong>$449.73</strong></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><sup>*</sup> SGD/USD exchange rate is 0.71770 as of the time of writing<br>
<sup>1</sup> Optional but handsome</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>Something noteworthy was that I chose a 32GB MicroSD card as storage for the first node as I had intended it to be the <s>master</s> main node of a Docker swarm setup and anticipated that I'd need additional storage for building and deploying Docker images.</p><figure><img src="https://ikarus.sg/content/images/2020/06/IMG_20181029_220049.jpg" alt=""><figcaption>Kraken (top) and Octopi (bottom) co-existing, shot with a potato</figcaption></figure><h2 id="kraken-gigabit-upgrade">Kraken gigabit upgrade</h2><p>One year later in September 2019, I found myself regularly hitting the bandwidth limit of 100Mbps on the built-in ethernet ports of Raspberry Pi 3Bs, especially when doing large file transfers in or out of the machines, where transfer speeds hover around a sad <strong>8MB/s</strong>.</p><p>I looked around and found Jeff Geerling's <a href="https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blogs/jeff-geerling/getting-gigabit-networking">blog post</a> where I learnt that I could use USB Gigabit ethernet adapters to increase the bandwidth to slightly over 200Mbps and so I bought a bunch of cheap Chinese USB Gigabit ethernet adapters and a gigabit switch and got down to upgrading.</p><figure><img src="https://ikarus.sg/content/images/2020/06/image.png" alt=""><figcaption>Cheap, sketchy, unbranded USB Gigabit Ethernet Adapter</figcaption></figure><h3 id="additional-parts-list">Additional parts list</h3><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Item</th>
<th>Qty</th>
<th>Cost (SGD)</th>
<th>Cost (USD)<sup>*</sup></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>TP-Link TL-SG108 8-Port Gigabit Switch</td>
<td>1</td>
<td>S$36.00</td>
<td>$26.56</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>USB 3.0 Gigabit RJ45 Ethernet Network Adapter</td>
<td>7</td>
<td>S$45.36</td>
<td>$32.55</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Total</strong></td>
<td></td>
<td><strong>S$82.36</strong></td>
<td><strong>$59.11</strong></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><sup>*</sup> SGD/USD exchange rate is 0.71770 as of the time of writing</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>After the upgrade, this is how Kraken looked like:</p><figure><img src="https://ikarus.sg/content/images/2020/06/ezgif-5-2cc44081e2b5.gif" alt=""><figcaption>Gigabit Kraken, Octopi and my cable management nightmare</figcaption></figure><p>This upgrade brings the total cost of the cluster to <strong>S$708.99</strong> or <strong>$508.84 USD</strong>.</p><h2 id="benchmarks">Benchmarks</h2><p>Running <code>iperf</code> before the upgrade, we see a maximum bandwidth of <strong>93.1 Mbps</strong>.</p><pre><code>~ ❯ iperf -c 192.168.3.11
------------------------------------------------------------
Client connecting to 192.168.3.11, TCP port 5001
TCP window size:  129 KByte (default)
------------------------------------------------------------
[  4] local 192.168.3.71 port 57041 connected with 192.168.3.11 port 5001
[ ID] Interval       Transfer     Bandwidth
[  4]  0.0-10.0 sec   111 MBytes  93.1 Mbits/sec</code></pre><p>Running <code>iperf</code> after installing the gigabit adapter, we see a maximum bandwidth of <strong>224 Mbps</strong>!</p><pre><code>~ ❯ iperf -c 192.168.3.11
------------------------------------------------------------
Client connecting to 192.168.3.11, TCP port 5001
TCP window size:  145 KByte (default)
------------------------------------------------------------
[  4] local 192.168.3.71 port 57298 connected with 192.168.3.11 port 5001
[ ID] Interval       Transfer     Bandwidth
[  4]  0.0-10.0 sec   268 MBytes   224 Mbits/sec</code></pre><p>With that simple mod, I've gained <strong>131Mbps per node</strong>. However, these are still only <em>theoretical</em> speeds as typical usage scenarios involve writing data received from network to disk, but <code>iperf</code> only receives data from the network and <em>does not write data to disk</em>.</p><h3 id="some-caveats">Some caveats</h3><p>Sustained full utilization of this newly available bandwidth is <em>highly unlikely in typical usage</em>, even in web serving. It will mostly aid in transferring large assets like images faster for the first load, after which the images will be cached by users browsers.</p><p>Additionally, the actual bandwidth is still constrained by the notorious shared USB 2.0 bus in the Raspberry Pi models 1 to 3. </p><p>For the uninitiated, the 480Mbps theoretical unidirectional bandwidth in a single USB 2.0 bus is shared between the Ethernet Port, the SD card slot and all USB ports.</p><h4 id="bandwidth-distribution-may-look-like-this-">Bandwidth distribution may look like this:</h4><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Operation</th>
<th>Read bandwidth</th>
<th>Write bandwidth</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Actual available bandwidth</td>
<td>200Mbps</td>
<td>200Mbps</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>SD Card</td>
<td>-80Mbps</td>
<td>-80Mbps</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Ethernet disconnected</td>
<td>-0Mbps</td>
<td>-0Mbps</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>No USB usage</td>
<td>-0Mbps</td>
<td>-0Mbps</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Available for GbE</strong></td>
<td><strong>120Mbps</strong></td>
<td><strong>120Mbps</strong></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>Even though the tabulated numbers give the impression that there is no performance gain from this upgrade, they represent the worst case scenario where typically, one would expect mostly reads and few writes in web-servers. </p><h4 id="bandwidth-distribution-should-typically-look-like-this-in-real-world-">Bandwidth distribution should typically look like this in real-world:</h4><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Operation</th>
<th>Read bandwidth</th>
<th>Write bandwidth</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Actual available bandwidth</td>
<td>300Mbps</td>
<td>100Mbps</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>SD Card</td>
<td>-100Mbps</td>
<td>-50Mbps</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Ethernet disconnected</td>
<td>-0Mbps</td>
<td>-0Mbps</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>No USB usage</td>
<td>-0Mbps</td>
<td>-0Mbps</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Available for GbE</strong></td>
<td><strong>200Mbps</strong></td>
<td><strong>50Mbps</strong></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><h2 id="should-you-build-this-cluster">Should you build this cluster?</h2><h3 id="this-build-is-for-you-if-you-">This build is for you if you:</h3><ul><li>You wish to learn Docker and its associated frameworks </li><li>You do not want to spend a fortune on procuring multiple Raspberry Pi 4Bs to set up a cluster</li><li>Want to explore <em>Kubernetes</em></li></ul><h3 id="this-build-is-not-for-you-if-you-">This build is not for you if you:</h3><ul><li>Are already familiar with the Docker ecosystem</li><li>Are looking for high-performance home setups</li></ul><h2 id="my-two-cents">My two cents</h2><p>I highly recommend building this cluster for anyone who's keen on getting into Docker and Kubernetes for 2 main reasons.</p><p>Firstly, this cluster is compatible with the latest versions of officially supported Docker images. Raspberry Pi 3Bs run on the <em>armv7</em> &nbsp;CPU architecture, which happens to be the current lowest common denominator among Arm processors today. </p><p>Latest Arm processors (<em>arm64</em>) are backward-compatible with all code written and compiled on <em>armv7</em>. In contrast, <em>arm64 </em>processors are not backward-compatible with <em>armv6</em> processors (Raspberry Pi 1 and 2), so they are essentially in the process of being phased out from the community.</p><p>Secondly, this cluster would be perfect for most but the most bandwidth demanding applications, from hosting your own blog, file sync service, media library managers, link-shorteners, note-taking applications and so on. The only time it would not perform as intended is when your application demands heavy sustained writes, such as when encoding videos, given the USB 2.0 bus bottlenecks in the Raspberry Pi 3, which is resolved only in Raspberry Pi 4.</p><p>All in all, building a Raspberry Pi 3 cluster is, in my opinion, the most cost-effective way of learning Docker and clustering in general, and will remain so in the foreseeable future. So if you are just getting into Docker, I'd highly recommend this build.</p><h2 id="what-s-next">What's next?</h2><p>In my next post in this series, I shall introduce the <em>Leviathan</em> cluster which I have built specifically for high I/O applications, capable of real-time video transcoding and streaming of HEVC -&gt; h264 videos.</p>
                </div>
            </section>

                <section>
    <h3>Subscribe to Ikarus.sg</h3>
    <p>Get the latest posts delivered right to your inbox</p>
    <form data-members-form="subscribe">
        
        <p><strong>Great!</strong> Check your inbox and click the link to confirm your subscription.
        </p>
        <p>
            Please enter a valid email address!
        </p>
    </form>
</section>
            
                       

        </article>

    </div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ikarus.sg/how-i-built-kraken/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24126719</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 22:25:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Sputnik V – The First Registered Covid-19 Vaccine]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 17 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24126096">thread link</a>) | @tejohnso
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://sputnikvaccine.com/about-vaccine/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://sputnikvaccine.com/about-vaccine/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<h3>Safety and efficacy</h3>
<p>After the start of the COVID-19 pandemic Russian researchers extracted a fragment of genetic material from novel coronavirus SARS-COV-2, which codes information about the structure of the spike S-protein, which forms the virus’ “crown” and is responsible for connection with human cells. They inserted it into a familiar adenovirus vector for delivery into a human cell creating the world’s first COVID-19 vaccine.</p>
<p>In order to ensure lasting immunity Russian scientists came up with a breakthrough idea to use two different types of adenovirus vectors (rAd26 and rAd5) for the first and second vaccination, boosting the effect of the vaccine.</p>
<p>The use of human adenoviruses as vectors is safe because these viruses, which cause the common cold, are not novel and have been around for thousands of years.</p> </div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://sputnikvaccine.com/about-vaccine/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24126096</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 21:18:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Systems Monitoring with Prometheus and Grafana]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 152 | Comments 67 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24126088">thread link</a>) | @jsulak
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://flightaware.engineering/systems-monitoring-with-prometheus-grafana/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://flightaware.engineering/systems-monitoring-with-prometheus-grafana/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
	<article>
		<div>

			<section>
				<p><em> Caroline Rodewig and Garrett McGrath are members of FlightAware's Flight Tracking Wing. As lead for the Predictive Technology Crew, Caroline works to expand the scope and quality of our predictive applications. Garrett is the lead for the Aviation Platform Crew and responsible for the performance, reliability and observability of multi-machine Hyperfeed. </em></p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><h2 id="monitoringhyperfeedthehistoryandchallengesofadistributedsystem">Monitoring Hyperfeed: The History and Challenges of a Distributed System</h2>
<p>The Aviation Platform crew (for an explanation of crews and wings,<a href="https://flightaware.engineering/crews-wings-and-alliances-part-1-the-principles-of-how-we-work/" target="_see this blog post"> see this blog post</a>) revolves around the performance and reliability of Hyperfeed<sup><a href="#fn1" id="fnref1">[1]</a></sup>. Hyperfeed is FlightAware’s core flight tracking engine. Its output powers the company’s most salient offerings: the <a href="https://flightaware.com/live/flight/ABW140" target="_blank"> flight pages</a> on the website, <a href="https://flightaware.com/commercial/firehose/" target="_blank">Firehose</a>, <a href="https://flightaware.com/commercial/flightxml/">FlightXML</a>, and <a href="https://flightaware.com/commercial/premium/">flight alerts</a>. So if Hyperfeed stops working, so does much of FlightAware. Given the impact of a Hyperfeed outage, we need to know immediately if something goes—or might go—wrong so that we can act swiftly and precisely to remedy the situation. For maintaining the requisite accuracy and timeliness of Hyperfeed’s output, we rely heavily on monitoring<sup><a href="#fn2" id="fnref2">[2]</a></sup>. To that end, we have recently begun adopting Prometheus, a time-series metrics database, and Grafana, a powerful visualization platform. The introduction of these tools marks a significant upgrade and improvement to Hyperfeed’s current monitoring stack. It is hoped that by sharing our experience and the reasons for adoption that we can help inform the decision-making of others in an analogous situation.</p>
<p>Before discussing Prometheus and the many enhancements it brings to our monitoring of Hyperfeed, it helps to provide some context by examining what we currently use and how it has evolved over time. In its current form, Hyperfeed is a distributed system composed of a constellation of more than a dozen components and sub-systems spread across multiple machines for performance and fault-tolerance. Its sub-systems include a number of other well-known services: Postgres, Zookeeper, Kafka, and RabbitMQ. It wasn’t always like this, though. When I started working on Hyperfeed in 2016, it was not distributed; its components all ran on a single machine (this is not strictly true as it also used a Postgres database running on a separate server). Naturally, monitoring at that time was relatively less complex: it had markedly less surface area to cover. We were able to do the job effectively with a combination of custom, in-house tools and a heavy dose of Zabbix.</p>
<p>Our custom monitoring tools mostly consisted of some scripts that followed Hyperfeed’s output and its logging statements looking for problems, e.g., the output has stopped completely, the output is out of date, or an excess number of tracebacks happened. These tools were specific to Hyperfeed and did not generalize well to other software. Zabbix, on the other hand, has been FlightAware’s primary monitoring and alerting framework. It is used throughout the company and not specific to any piece of software. When applied to Hyperfeed, Zabbix monitored some key characteristics of the server running the application such as CPU, memory, disk, and network usage. Moreover, the aforementioned custom tools fed their data into Zabbix so that they could be used for alerting an engineer if something went haywire. On top of that, Zabbix gave us a basic web interface for viewing the data it collected in a graphical format. Back when Hyperfeed fit snugly on a single server, this sort of monitoring served us well: Zabbix was a one-stop shop for all things monitoring. But as the demands placed on Hyperfeed grew, so did its operational complexity.</p>
<p>Eventually, a single-machine architecture was not enough to handle the increased volume of Hyperfeed’s input, which was precipitated by FlightAware acquiring <a href="https://flightaware.com/commercial/aireon/" target="_blank">new data sources</a>, and expanding its <a href="https://flightaware.com/adsb/" target="_blank">existing data sources</a>. In order to accommodate this change in scale, it was necessary to distribute Hyperfeed across multiple machines. When this happened, we continued using (and still do use) custom tools and Zabbix for monitoring. Our custom tools, though, and the data we send to Zabbix necessarily expanded, too. Although distributing Hyperfeed across multiple machines was necessary and improved the performance and reliability of the system, it also brought with it new challenges and difficulties, particularly in terms of monitoring<sup><a href="#fn3" id="fnref3">[3]</a></sup>.</p>
<p>Given their origin, our custom tools were not designed with a distributed setting in mind. As such, they lacked the ability to easily aggregate data across multiple machines and were somewhat cumbersome to operate as Hyperfeed’s architecture progressed. In addition, Zabbix started creaking and revealing some rough edges as we placed more demands on it. A core issue was that Zabbix does really well at monitoring particular machines but not as well at system or application level monitoring, especially in a context where services can move around from machine to machine as failures occur or as an intentional part of the design. In a distributed setting, it also imposes non-trivial operational burdens, e.g., when adding new monitoring points or spreading the collection load across machines. Moreover, Zabbix combines all monitoring functions into a single monolith rather than the current best practice of loosely coupling monitoring tasks like collecting data, long-term storage, querying data, alerting with deduplication and aggregation, and visualization/dashboarding (for further details on monitoring system best practices, see the <a href="https://landing.google.com/sre/workbook/chapters/monitoring/" target="_blank">Google SRE workbook’s monitoring chapter</a>).</p>
<p>As Hyperfeed moved to a distributed architecture, a change driven by business demands and an increased volume of flight tracking data, it became clear that our monitoring tools, while mostly satisfactory in alerting us when something failed in the system, neglected to provide us with many of the other benefits that monitoring can offer. In particular, we were weak in whitebox monitoring and visualization<sup><a href="#fn4" id="fnref4">[4]</a></sup>.Whitebox monitoring is especially important for analyzing long-term trends, comparing experimental groups, and in guiding capacity planning and other engineering decision making. Some information can only come from the vantage point provided by whitebox monitoring. For visualization we had Zabbix, but its capabilities there are fairly limited and inflexible. Given all of this, we started looking for a new solution to fill in the gaps in our monitoring approach, something designed for dynamic, distributed systems. We chose Prometheus and Grafana. This combo of tools addresses the shortcomings of our current approach, and also brings with it a number of additional virtues.</p>
<h2 id="upgradingmonitoringwithprometheusandgrafana">Upgrading Monitoring with Prometheus and Grafana</h2>
<h3 id="prometheustimeseriesmetrics">Prometheus: Time-Series Metrics</h3>
<p>In an idealized monitoring practice, every event or state of a system is recorded so that it is available if needed: no detail is left out. Unfortunately, this only works in a hypothetical, theoretical scenario since it is impossible to store, process, and work with the quantity of data generated continuously by modern systems. Instead of capturing everything, one must grapple with what to monitor: how to turn the endless torrent of events in a system into something comprehensible, manageable, and actionable. To this end, Prometheus provides time-series metrics, which track aggregations of events in a system over some period of time, where an event refers to anything that might occur and can be quantified or measured. Some example events include a function getting called, CPU usage going up, a web request being made, a client connecting to a service or a cache hit happens.<sup><a href="#fn5" id="fnref5">[5]</a></sup> Fundamentally, the monitoring offered by Prometheus periodically takes a snapshot of some of the events in a system, typically measuring how often or how quickly each event occurred. The value of a snapshot at any given point is often of less interest than its relative value: how the frequency of an event changes over time provides the actionable insight and value of metrics-based monitoring. To make this more concrete, in the case of flight tracking some example time-series metrics of interest might be:</p>
<ul>
<li>Departures per second</li>
<li>Arrivals per day</li>
<li>Cancellations per minute</li>
<li>Diversions per hour</li>
<li>Flight plans created per second</li>
<li>Input messages processed per second</li>
<li>Output messages generated per second</li>
<li>99th percentile of the time taken to process an ADS-B position over the last 6 months</li>
</ul>
<p>Note that in order to keep the amount of data captured manageable, the contents of the input messages that trigger each of these events get aggregated away. With metrics, the rate of departures, for example, are measured throughout the system, but any single departure cannot be investigated. As succinctly summarized by <a href="https://www.datadoghq.com/blog/monitoring-101-collecting-data/" target="_blank">Datadog</a>, metrics provide “the big, broad-stroke measures that can help you quickly answer the most pressing questions about a system’s internal health and performance.“ Metrics can also capture resource utilization, like CPU, memory, or disk, and metadata like code revisions and configuration values. Time-series metrics, despite necessarily omitting a lot of detail, are still quite versatile, yielding practicable monitoring data for critical activities throughout a system.</p>
<h3 id="dataandoperationalmodel">Data and Operational Model</h3>
<p>One of Prometheus’ main selling points is that it provides a powerful and conceptually straightforward data model for extracting metrics from a system of interest and tracking their rate of change over time. Each time-series metric tracked by Prometheus includes the following information:</p>
<ul>
<li>Metric name: a string indicating what the metric is for, e.g., <code>hyperfeed_departures_total</code>.</li>
<li>Help documentation: a string describing what the metric is for or where it comes from.</li>
<li>Metric type: four types are provided, but two of them provide the atomic building blocks of the others. The fundamental types are counters, which can only go up or reset, and gauges, which can be set to any value.</li>
<li>Labels: key-value pairs attaching additional dimensions to the metric. Labels …</li></ul></section></div></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://flightaware.engineering/systems-monitoring-with-prometheus-grafana/">https://flightaware.engineering/systems-monitoring-with-prometheus-grafana/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://flightaware.engineering/systems-monitoring-with-prometheus-grafana/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24126088</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 21:17:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Sixty years of Green Eggs and Ham]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 78 | Comments 44 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24125898">thread link</a>) | @amanuensis
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://brianjayjones.com/2020/08/11/sixty-years-of-green-eggs-and-ham/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://brianjayjones.com/2020/08/11/sixty-years-of-green-eggs-and-ham/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
				
<div><figure><img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="6307" data-permalink="https://brianjayjones.com/efarhx7waaqrfiu/" data-orig-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efarhx7waaqrfiu.jpeg" data-orig-size="482,654" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Green Eggs and Ham 1st edition" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efarhx7waaqrfiu.jpeg?w=221" data-large-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efarhx7waaqrfiu.jpeg?w=482" src="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efarhx7waaqrfiu.jpeg" alt="" width="214" height="290" srcset="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efarhx7waaqrfiu.jpeg?w=214&amp;h=290 214w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efarhx7waaqrfiu.jpeg?w=428&amp;h=580 428w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efarhx7waaqrfiu.jpeg?w=111&amp;h=150 111w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efarhx7waaqrfiu.jpeg?w=221&amp;h=300 221w" sizes="(max-width: 214px) 100vw, 214px"><figcaption>Try it, try it! You will see.</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Sixty years ago this week — on August 12, 1960 — Dr. Seuss published what would become his biggest-selling book of all time. Written as the result of a $50 bet between Seuss and his friend and publisher at Random House, Bennett Cerf, the book, by some estimates, has sold north of 200 million copies.*</p>



<p>The book? <em>Green Eggs and Ham.</em></p>



<p>When I discuss <em>Becoming Dr. Seuss </em>with audiences, Seuss fans tell me they have warm memories of this one; it’s the book that taught them how to read, or it’s the first book they received as a gift — or, as grown-ups, it’s a book they can still quote and recite word-for-word. And it <em>is </em>a great book–but it’s an important one, too, both in the Seuss library and in the overall oeuvre of children’s literature. There’s a lot going on between its colorful orange boards, the result of sweat, inspiration, and no small amount of luck. But to truly appreciate how smart, and how important <em>Green Eggs and Ham</em> is, we need to go back a few years before its 1960 publication to get some background and some context. </p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="6310" data-permalink="https://brianjayjones.com/efardaxxoae-iwe/" data-orig-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efardaxxoae-iwe.jpeg" data-orig-size="900,1200" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="efardaxxoae-iwe" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efardaxxoae-iwe.jpeg?w=225" data-large-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efardaxxoae-iwe.jpeg?w=500" src="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efardaxxoae-iwe.jpeg?w=500" alt="" width="236" height="315" srcset="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efardaxxoae-iwe.jpeg?w=236 236w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efardaxxoae-iwe.jpeg?w=472 472w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efardaxxoae-iwe.jpeg?w=113 113w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efardaxxoae-iwe.jpeg?w=225 225w" sizes="(max-width: 236px) 100vw, 236px"></figure></div>



<p>Let’s start, then, by checking in with this May 1954 issue of LIFE magazine (that’s comedic actress Kaye Ballard on the cover, by the way, who was burning up Broadway in the musical <em>The Golden Apple</em> and would later make an appearance on <em>The Muppet Show</em>) which features an article by Pulitzer Prize winning novelist John Hersey titled, “Why Do Students Bog Down on the First ‘R’?” The cover text teases the article as  “Why Can’t My Child Read?” but the gist is the same: namely, Hersey was discouraged by the low rates of childhood literacy in the United States, and placed the blame for children’s lack of interest in reading squarely on the shoulders of the ponderous <em>Dick and Jane </em>standard reading primers on which several generations of children had been raised. </p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="6313" data-permalink="https://brianjayjones.com/efarm2txsaeescx/" data-orig-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efarm2txsaeescx.jpeg" data-orig-size="594,473" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="efarm2txsaeescx" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efarm2txsaeescx.jpeg?w=300" data-large-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efarm2txsaeescx.jpeg?w=500" src="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efarm2txsaeescx.jpeg?w=594" alt="" width="282" height="224" srcset="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efarm2txsaeescx.jpeg?w=282 282w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efarm2txsaeescx.jpeg?w=564 564w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efarm2txsaeescx.jpeg?w=150 150w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efarm2txsaeescx.jpeg?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 282px) 100vw, 282px"><figcaption>John Hersey</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>The real problem, as Hersey saw it, was that Dick and Jane were<em> terrible</em>. The text — with its now-easily lampooned, “Look, Jane, look. See the ball?” syntax — was bad enough, but Hersey thought the artwork was even worse–“insipid illustrations depicting the slicked-up lives of other children,” he railed. No one, he concluded, was interested in reading about Dick and Jane and their lives of quiet desperation. At the very least, suggested Hersey, couldn’t they get Dr. Seuss to illustrate the otherwise turgid text?</p>



<p>They never would get Dr. Seuss to illustrate Dick and Jane; instead, Seuss was approached by William Spaulding, an editor of children’s books at Random House rival Houghton Mifflin, who had read Hersey’s article and begged Dr. Seuss to “write me a story that first graders can’t put down.”</p>



<p>But there was a catch. Putting aside all their other problems, Dick and Jane were at least living their dull lives inside an actual reading primer, operating under a strict educator-approved vocabulary list of about 300 unique words at the first grade reading level. For his book, then, Dr. Seuss would have to play by those same rules, using only the words on the sanctioned reading list. Seuss told Spaulding he’d take the list home and “play with it.”</p>



<p>He played with it for nearly a year. It was, he said later, an “impossible and ridiculous task…I was forbidden to use any words beyond the list. I almost threw the job up.” Eventually, he decided to read through the list one last time, vowing that “if I find two words that rhyme and make sense to me, that’s the title.” Unfortunately,<em> tall </em>and <em>ball</em> were a bust.</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="6315" data-permalink="https://brianjayjones.com/efasfsvwoaegedt/" data-orig-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efasfsvwoaegedt.jpeg" data-orig-size="654,874" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="efasfsvwoaegedt" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efasfsvwoaegedt.jpeg?w=224" data-large-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efasfsvwoaegedt.jpeg?w=500" src="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efasfsvwoaegedt.jpeg?w=654" alt="" width="223" height="298" srcset="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efasfsvwoaegedt.jpeg?w=223 223w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efasfsvwoaegedt.jpeg?w=446 446w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efasfsvwoaegedt.jpeg?w=112 112w" sizes="(max-width: 223px) 100vw, 223px"></figure></div>



<p><em>Cat </em>and <em>hat</em>, however, were not.</p>



<p>After another year of work, Dr. Seuss published <em>The Cat in the Hat</em> in the Spring of 1957.** For <em>Cat</em>, Seuss had used 236 unique words from the word list. (His total word count, with repeated words, is about 1,600.) It was Seuss’ first real blockbuster of a book — the one that permitted him to finally devote himself full-time to writing and drawing books for children. But more importantly, <em>Cat in the Hat </em>is a bestseller with a pedagogy; with its reliance on the officially-sanctioned word list, it’s a book teachers approved of, one parents loved, and one kids actually wanted to read. In 1957, that was a game changer.</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="6317" data-permalink="https://brianjayjones.com/efaswqjxkaa0gtw/" data-orig-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efaswqjxkaa0gtw.jpeg" data-orig-size="264,206" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="efaswqjxkaa0gtw" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efaswqjxkaa0gtw.jpeg?w=264" data-large-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efaswqjxkaa0gtw.jpeg?w=264" src="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efaswqjxkaa0gtw.jpeg?w=264" alt="" width="203" height="158" srcset="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efaswqjxkaa0gtw.jpeg?w=203 203w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efaswqjxkaa0gtw.jpeg?w=150 150w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efaswqjxkaa0gtw.jpeg 264w" sizes="(max-width: 203px) 100vw, 203px"></figure></div>



<p>Inspired by the huge success of the Cat, Random House created a new imprint called Beginner Books, aimed squarely at beginning readers and which continued to lean on the educator-approved word list. Dr. Seuss was brought in as the imprint’s president and editor–a seat from which he would not only recruit and work with other writers and artists on children’s books (one of the most popular of which was P.D. Eastman’s <em>Go, Dog. Go!</em>) but would also regularly produce his own books under the new logo, featuring the Cat himself.</p>



<p>Among the first books Dr. Seuss produced for the Beginner Books imprint was <em>One Fish Two Fish Red Fish Blue Fish</em>, completed in 1959. <em>One Fish</em> was an experiment for Seuss, as he was deliberately using an even more restrictive word list of short words, and placing the accompanying drawings as close to the text as he possibly could, like so:</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="6320" data-permalink="https://brianjayjones.com/efatbsrxkaepoay/" data-orig-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efatbsrxkaepoay.jpeg" data-orig-size="431,640" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="efatbsrxkaepoay" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efatbsrxkaepoay.jpeg?w=202" data-large-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efatbsrxkaepoay.jpeg?w=431" src="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efatbsrxkaepoay.jpeg?w=431" alt="" srcset="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efatbsrxkaepoay.jpeg 431w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efatbsrxkaepoay.jpeg?w=101 101w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efatbsrxkaepoay.jpeg?w=202 202w" sizes="(max-width: 431px) 100vw, 431px"></figure></div>



<p>It would be the prototype for a new line of books Seuss was already informally calling “Beginner Beginner Books,” aimed at very early readers with limited vocabularies. Soon, there would be a new imprint at Random House, overseen by Seuss, and formally designated with the moniker Bright &amp; Early Books. The Bright &amp; Early Books relied on an approved vocabulary list of only 182 simple words—a little more than half as large as the already restrictive list adhered to by Beginner Books.</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="6325" data-permalink="https://brianjayjones.com/7116irubhll-_ac_sl1500_/" data-orig-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/7116irubhll._ac_sl1500_.jpg" data-orig-size="1121,1500" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="7116irubhll._ac_sl1500_" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/7116irubhll._ac_sl1500_.jpg?w=224" data-large-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/7116irubhll._ac_sl1500_.jpg?w=500" src="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/7116irubhll._ac_sl1500_.jpg?w=765" alt="" width="265" height="355" srcset="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/7116irubhll._ac_sl1500_.jpg?w=265 265w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/7116irubhll._ac_sl1500_.jpg?w=530 530w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/7116irubhll._ac_sl1500_.jpg?w=112 112w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/7116irubhll._ac_sl1500_.jpg?w=224 224w" sizes="(max-width: 265px) 100vw, 265px"><figcaption>Bennett Cerf</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Still with me? In 1959, Random House publisher Bennett Cerf approached Dr. Seuss and gleefully pointed out that the new Bright &amp; Early imprint relied on a tight list of 182 words. Then he laid down a playful and very specific challenge: <em>could Dr. Seuss write a book using only 50 of those words?</em> </p>



<p>Cerf bet Dr. Seuss $50 that he couldn’t. </p>



<p>Challenge accepted.</p>



<p>Seuss, who who had agonized and struggled with a broader and less restrictive word list as he worked on <em>The Cat in the Hat, </em>nevertheless rose to the occasion. But it’s probably no coincidence that the resulting book was all about convincing someone to do something they didn’t really want to do.</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="6331" data-permalink="https://brianjayjones.com/efasdwvwaaaddy5/" data-orig-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efasdwvwaaaddy5.jpeg" data-orig-size="733,1024" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="efasdwvwaaaddy5" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efasdwvwaaaddy5.jpeg?w=215" data-large-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efasdwvwaaaddy5.jpeg?w=500" src="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efasdwvwaaaddy5.jpeg?w=733" alt="" width="256" height="358" srcset="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efasdwvwaaaddy5.jpeg?w=256 256w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efasdwvwaaaddy5.jpeg?w=512 512w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efasdwvwaaaddy5.jpeg?w=107 107w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efasdwvwaaaddy5.jpeg?w=215 215w" sizes="(max-width: 256px) 100vw, 256px"></figure></div>



<p><em>Green Eggs and Ham </em>would be its own kind of misery, requiring Seuss to create complicated charts, checklists, and multiple word counts as he struggled to keep track of the words he was using. He also imposed on himself a requirement to stick with one-syllable words, though he would make an exception for “anywhere,” which was made up of two short words that young readers would know.</p>



<p>Rhyming, too, could be tough with a fifty word restriction. “The agony is terrific at times, and the attribution is horrible,” he said. “If you’re doing it in quatrains and get to the end of four lines and can’t make it work, then it’s like unraveling a sock. You take some of your best stuff and throw it away.”</p>



<p>Dr. Seuss delivered <em>Green Eggs and Ham</em> to Cerf at Random House in 1960. He was glad to be done with it, and somewhat nervous about how it would be received.</p>



<p>We all know how it turned out. “The good doctor has scored another triumph,” exclaimed the <em>New York Times</em>, while one reviewer wrote presciently of <em>Green Eggs and Ham</em>: “A vocabulary of only fifty words, but they will long be remembered.”</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="6335" data-permalink="https://brianjayjones.com/efaurzkxsaecaon/" data-orig-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efaurzkxsaecaon.jpeg" data-orig-size="590,433" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="efaurzkxsaecaon" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efaurzkxsaecaon.jpeg?w=300" data-large-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efaurzkxsaecaon.jpeg?w=500" src="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efaurzkxsaecaon.jpeg?w=590" alt="" width="338" height="247" srcset="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efaurzkxsaecaon.jpeg?w=338 338w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efaurzkxsaecaon.jpeg?w=150 150w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efaurzkxsaecaon.jpeg?w=300 300w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/efaurzkxsaecaon.jpeg 590w" sizes="(max-width: 338px) 100vw, 338px"></figure></div>



<p>For the rest of his life, Dr. Seuss would find himself at book signings and dinners in his honor where he would be served plates filled with green eggs and ham. “Deplorable stuff,” he said later, “The worst was on a yacht in six-foot seas.”</p>



<p>Generations of readers would look for hidden meanings and metaphors in its text—but for Dr. Seuss, <em>Green Eggs and Ham</em> was only ever about one thing: “Cerf bet me fifty bucks I couldn’t write a book using only 50 words,” he said later. “I did it to show I could.”</p>



<p>Oh, and Seuss also said later that Bennett Cerf never paid him his fifty dollars. </p>



<p>Regardless, Happy 60th Birthday to <em>Green Eggs and Ham</em>. Thank you, thank you, Sam I Am (and Dr. Seuss!)</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="6337" data-permalink="https://brianjayjones.com/6a0120a74be1cf970b01348008829c970c-800wi/" data-orig-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/6a0120a74be1cf970b01348008829c970c-800wi.jpg" data-orig-size="530,737" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="6a0120a74be1cf970b01348008829c970c-800wi" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/6a0120a74be1cf970b01348008829c970c-800wi.jpg?w=216" data-large-file="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/6a0120a74be1cf970b01348008829c970c-800wi.jpg?w=500" src="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/6a0120a74be1cf970b01348008829c970c-800wi.jpg?w=530" alt="" srcset="https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/6a0120a74be1cf970b01348008829c970c-800wi.jpg 530w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/6a0120a74be1cf970b01348008829c970c-800wi.jpg?w=108 108w, https://brianjayjones.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/6a0120a74be1cf970b01348008829c970c-800wi.jpg?w=216 216w" sizes="(max-width: 530px) 100vw, 530px"></figure>



<p>* Publishers can be persnickety about releasing sales figures on the record. Total sales for <em>Green Eggs </em>are reported as anywhere from 8 million to 15 million to 200 million.</p>



<p>* * In a trade-off deal, Random House–Dr. Seuss’s normal publisher–permitted Houghton Mifflin to publish the textbook version of <em>Cat in the Hat </em>for schools, while Random House retained the trade rights. As it turned out, few schools bought the textbook version. Random House would make a mint off the Cat; Houghton — where the idea had originated in the first place! — not so much. Random House would eventually acquire the textbook rights back from its rival, and promptly shelve them, preferring to issue only the trade edition.</p>
							</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://brianjayjones.com/2020/08/11/sixty-years-of-green-eggs-and-ham/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24125898</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 20:58:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Fravia’s web-searching lore (2009)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 23 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24125649">thread link</a>) | @homarp
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | http://biostatisticien.eu/www.searchlores.org/indexo.htm | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://biostatisticien.eu/www.searchlores.org/indexo.htm">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://biostatisticien.eu/www.searchlores.org/indexo.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24125649</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 20:33:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Never use a dependency that you could replace with an afternoon of programming]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 312 | Comments 290 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24123878">thread link</a>) | @earthboundkid
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://blog.carlmjohnson.net/post/2020/avoid-dependencies/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.carlmjohnson.net/post/2020/avoid-dependencies/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><blockquote><p>In short, I think it’s become entirely too easy for people using certain programming languages to use libraries from the wide world of clowns that is the Internet. Their ecosystems make it very very easy to become reliant on this stuff. Trouble is, those libraries are frequently 💩. If something about it is broken, you might not be able to code around it, and may have to actually deal with them to get it fixed.</p><p>Repeat 100 times, and now you have a real problem brewing.</p></blockquote><p>I have a simple rule: <strong>never use a dependency that you could replace with an afternoon of programming</strong>.</p><hr><p>No dependency is so self-explanatory that you will be able to get it working with less than a few hours of:</p><ul><li>Searching online to see what solutions to the problem exist.</li><li>Reading the docs to make sure it actually works for your problem.</li><li>Reading the code to make sure it’s not complete 💩.</li><li>Actually wiring it up in your dependency system.</li><li>Figuring how to tell the dependency to solve your problem.</li></ul><p>If you spent that same amount of time writing your own tool:</p><ul><li>You’ll know exactly how it works and what its shortcomings are.</li><li>You’ll have something that solves exactly your problem instead of a general problems, so it is certainly shorter and often faster.</li></ul><p>Many times, the best approach is first searching online and reading the code to a few other solutions, then writing your own with the knowledge you’ve gained from seeing how they work.</p><p>There is an argument that dependencies solve bugs so you don’t have to. This can be true, but it’s also true that a general solution will have many bugs that you don’t care about in your specific solution because it is much harder to write a general program than a specific one.</p><p>The long and the short of it is that any code that can be written in less than an afternoon should be handled yourself.</p><p>And don’t forget about this:</p><blockquote><p>There’s a predictable cycle in software ecosystems. Unix, Perl, Windows, Python, PHP/Wordpress… All have followed a pattern where first the standard library is great, then user libraries take off, then there’s DLL hell, finally it’s overrun by low quality user-made libraries.</p><p><a href="https://pic.twitter.com/oFs1ua61nq"><img src="https://blog.carlmjohnson.net/post/img/2020-dependencies.png" alt="The dialectic of dependencies"></a></p><p>— Carl Johnson (<a href="https://twitter.com/carlmjohnson">@carlmjohnson</a>) <a href="https://twitter.com/carlmjohnson/status/982747054614220800">April 7, 2018</a></p></blockquote></section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.carlmjohnson.net/post/2020/avoid-dependencies/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24123878</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 18:26:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Elite do-gooders 'fixing' the world are part of the problem: Giridharadas]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 112 | Comments 282 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24123546">thread link</a>) | @colinprince
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://www.cbc.ca/radio/ideas/how-elite-do-gooders-fixing-the-world-are-part-of-the-problem-anand-giridharadas-1.5441573 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/radio/ideas/how-elite-do-gooders-fixing-the-world-are-part-of-the-problem-anand-giridharadas-1.5441573">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Should the world’s problems be solved by unelected elites? Surely these are decisions we all need to be part of. Anand Giridharadas argues if we don’t trust the institutions we have for fixing the world, then let's build better institutions — this time, from the bottom up.</p><div><figure><div><p><img alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5441647.1580158986!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/anand-giridharadas-and-bookcover.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>In his book, Winner Takes All, former New York Times columnist Anand Giridharadas investigates how the global elite’s efforts to 'change the world' also obscure their role in causing the problem.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Alfred Knopf Publishing/Mackenzie Stroh)</figcaption></figure><p><span></span><span>Listen<!-- --> to the full episode</span><span>53:59</span></p><p><span><p><em>* Originally published on January 27, 2020.</em></p>  <p>"We've got about 400 people in this room.... Imagine if dinner was carted into this room, and four people got half the food. The night would end in violence," Anand Giridharadas told <em>IDEAS</em> host Nahlah Ayed at a public event hosted by <a href="https://www.samaracanada.com/" target="_blank">the Samara Centre for Democracy</a>.</p>  <p>"But somehow you scale it up to the level of the society &nbsp;— millions and millions of people — and you make it money instead of food, and people are like,&nbsp;'Yeah I guess that's okay,'" Giridharadas added.</p>  <p>The journalist and author has been investigating how global elites in the U.S. have been "changing the world" and dominating the news with their efforts. In his book&nbsp;<em>Winners Take All: The Elite Charade of Changing the World</em>, Giridharadas lays out how the the rich and powerful have been fighting for equality and injustice, branding themselves as socially engaged agents of change and pouring millions — if not trillions — of tax-avoided dollars into social causes.&nbsp;</p>  <p>But, he warns, in all of this good, their role in causing the problems they later seek to solve is obscured.</p>  <p>"If all these people on the top are doing all this nice stuff, but year by year they are increasing their concentration of wealth and power, their monopolies are getting more monopolistic, their tech companies are becoming more abusive of privacy and democracy —&nbsp;not less —&nbsp;if their influence over politics is increasing, not decreasing, then what is all this do-gooding doing?"&nbsp;</p>  <h2>'If only' solutions</h2>  <p>The New York University professor argues that the conventional wisdom out there to solve the world's problems stems from an "if only" approach, suggesting maybe there needs to be more than just one Mark Zuckerberg to fix this.</p>  <p>"If only we had an effective altruism movement, so that when you give money away you could be guided to give it more rationally. If you give it to this NGO, it will have more impact than if you give it to that one. If only Chinese billionaires could be persuaded to donate philanthropically at the same percentage that American billionaires do," he explained.</p>  <p>"If only, if only, if only."</p>  <p>This "if only" solution got Giridharadas thinking about an equal and opposite possibility.</p>  <p>"Maybe all this extraordinary elite helping in our time is how we maintain a system — an architecture of extraordinary elite hoarding," he told Ayed.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5180043.1580159463!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/britain-facebook-privacy.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5180043.1580159463!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/britain-facebook-privacy.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5180043.1580159463!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/britain-facebook-privacy.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5180043.1580159463!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/britain-facebook-privacy.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5180043.1580159463!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/britain-facebook-privacy.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5180043.1580159463!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/britain-facebook-privacy.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>'While you don't have individually the power to dethrone a Mark Zuckerberg, what you do have the power to do ... is to start joining things. Click less, join more,' says Anand Giridharadas.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Marcio Jose Sanchez/Associated Press)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>He suggests real change involves the loss of power for global elites. Why should the decisions be left to permitting the rich to decide what's important — a hospital wing, a legal aid centre, a new well in the village? These are decisions that should involve everyone, including elected representatives and governments, Giridharadas argues.</p>  <p>When the rich and powerful not only get involved in change but get into the front row of social change, "they change 'change,'" said the former McKinsey analyst.</p>  <p>"They change what kinds of change are acceptable. They change the discourse we have about change."</p>  <h2>Make democracy</h2>  <p>If the institutions that are set up aren't to be trusted, Giridharadas proposes it's time to build better institutions — this time, from the bottom up.</p>  <p>He sees a possibility to make democracy better by organizing the world differently.</p>  <p>"While you don't have individually the power to dethrone a Mark Zuckerberg, what you do have the power to do — today, tomorrow and the next day — is to start joining things," he told Ayed.</p>  <p>Giridharadas calls on people to join organizations, membership lists and movements that work toward building cross-racial, cross-class coalitions of people — with a goal to create a future that benefits most people.&nbsp;</p>  <p>"If we build movements to that effect, I think we can end this age of capital. I think we can usher in the age of reform and I think we can resume the idea of democracy as the place we go to change the world."</p>  <hr>  <p><em>* This episode was produced by Philip Coulter.</em></p></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/radio/ideas/how-elite-do-gooders-fixing-the-world-are-part-of-the-problem-anand-giridharadas-1.5441573</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24123546</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 18:02:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Classic books for tech leads or those aspiring to be]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 200 | Comments 53 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24123372">thread link</a>) | @bmgoss
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://sourcelevel.io/blog/3-classic-books-for-tech-leads-or-those-aspiring-to-be | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://sourcelevel.io/blog/3-classic-books-for-tech-leads-or-those-aspiring-to-be">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-url="https://sourcelevel.io/blog/3-classic-books-for-tech-leads-or-those-aspiring-to-be" data-title="3 Classic Books for Tech Leads (or those aspiring to be)"><p>Books are the best resource for sharing knowledge in a not-assisted way. They go deep into a topic, or more briefly over a bunch of them. Although, as a Software Engineer, I learned a lot from blog posts, tweets, and conference talks, it was books that prepared me for the <a href="https://sourcelevel.io/tech-lead-everything-software-engineers-need-to-know-to-become-a-great-technology-leader">Tech Lead role</a>.</p>
<p>For this article, I created a list of 3 classic books I consider essential for whose transitioning — or desires to transition — to a leadership position in technology.</p>
<p>Books can teach us many things. It’s familiar to us to feel like there’re too many things to learn and too little time to absorb it. We tend to get anxious and overloaded with the content easily. Relax.</p>
<p>Take your time on reading, and take your time practicing it. Theory and practice converge at some point, and you realize you’ve been a leader for quite some time.</p>
<p>It’s been quite a while since their publication. So, you may notice some old stories during your reading. However, I think they are classic, and as any other book in this category, they aged very well.</p>

<p>Start receiving <strong>hand-picked content<br></strong><span>with high quality from <strong>experienced engineering leaders</strong> in your email regularly!</span></p>
<p><a href="https://sourcelevel.io/software-engineering-newsletter">Subscribe to our weekly Newsletter</a></p>

<p>That said, let’s go to the list.</p>
<h2>1. Peopleware: Productive Projects and Teams</h2>
<p>The book was first published in 1987. The authors, Tom DeMarco and Timothy R. Lister talk about managing people through lots of stories. The stories may sound outdated and unlikely to happen nowadays, but their essence is still valid.</p>
<p>Many things stated by the two authors are kind of obvious, like<em> how expensive the turnover is, that we should include the team in the hiring process and that methodologies are restrictive</em>.</p>
<p>It’s a fantastic opportunity to recapitulate those topics; <strong>some were written more than 30 years ago</strong>.</p>
<p>Peopleware was the first book that I recall to mention the need for a sociological view, not only a technical one over projects and teams. As such, Tom and Timothy’s theories are still valid.</p>
<p>Among the theories, I how they state the importance of peer view (or <a href="https://sourcelevel.io/everything-about-code-review-from-peer-review-to-automated-code-review">Code Review</a>, in our case), and that knowledge workers, like software engineers, are continuously working their soft and hard skills.</p>
<p>The theories go through the traps of <a href="https://sourcelevel.io/how-tech-leads-and-team-leads-can-measure-teams-productivity">software engineering productivity</a>, how office influences how we work, the impact of quality in our work, and much more.</p>
<h2>2. Driving technical change: Why People on Your Team Don’t Act on Good Ideas, and How to Convince Them They Should</h2>
<p>If you’re new on persuasion and influence, the Driving Technical Change book is an excellent start. It’s full of anecdotes that surface how to gain skeptics buy-in for your ideas. It was published in 2010 and written by Terrence Ryan.</p>
<p>The content works pretty well for <em>an introductory approach on how to expose your ideas, find allies, and, most importantly, check whether your proposals are plausible</em>.</p>
<p>The book also lists some <strong>categories of skepticism, which was very valuable to me</strong>. I could better understand how the team responded to my inclinations and how I responded to others. This awareness is an excellent start for those wanting to manage large teams.</p>
<p>I confess the book is not very practical, and that may be a disadvantage against it. However, it was very relevant when I read it for the first time, and I strongly suggest you read this short (~200 pages) book even though it won’t answer all your questions or tell you exactly what to do.</p>
<h2>3. The Mythical Man-Month: Essays on Software Engineering</h2>
<p>If you thought Peopleware was old because it was published in the late 80s, well, my next recommendation is 15 years earlier.</p>
<p>The Mythical Man-Month by Fred Brooks was<strong> first published in 1975 (almost 50 years ago!)</strong> and covers <a href="https://sourcelevel.io/software-engineering-newsletter">software engineering and management topics</a>.</p>
<p>The author creates the concept of man-month. It’s the unit for the amount of work of a person in a month. Then, he defends that adding more people to a late project makes it later. It’s known as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brooks%27s_law">Brook’s law</a>.</p>
<p>It relates to the latest and hottest discussions in the agile world about “coordination costs”: <strong>when you increase the number of people in a group, organizing work gets harder</strong>. Thus, it requires more meetings and management efforts to align everybody, which delays the software development even more.</p>
<p>It’s an inspiring book, a classic one, which, in a certain way, is still modern and worth the reading.</p>
<div itemtype="http://schema.org/Person" itemscope="" itemprop="author"><p><img alt="" src="https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/eada2a1e2181b03b4f1a76359e3f8b5b?s=100&amp;d=blank&amp;r=r" srcset="https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/eada2a1e2181b03b4f1a76359e3f8b5b?s=200&amp;d=blank&amp;r=r 2x" height="100" width="100" itemprop="image"></p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://sourcelevel.io/blog/3-classic-books-for-tech-leads-or-those-aspiring-to-be</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24123372</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 17:49:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Bevy: A data-driven game engine and app framework built in Rust]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 442 | Comments 68 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24123283">thread link</a>) | @adamnemecek
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://bevyengine.org/news/introducing-bevy/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bevyengine.org/news/introducing-bevy/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>After months of work, I am ecstatic to finally announce <strong>Bevy Engine</strong>!</p>
<p>Bevy is a refreshingly simple data-driven game engine and app framework built in Rust. It is <a href="https://github.com/bevyengine/bevy">free and open-source</a> forever!</p>
<p>It has the following design goals:</p>
<ul>
<li><b>Capable</b>: Offer a complete 2D and 3D feature set</li>
<li><b>Simple</b>: Easy for newbies to pick up, but infinitely flexible for power users</li>
<li><b>Data Focused</b>: Data-oriented architecture using the Entity Component System paradigm </li>
<li><b>Modular</b>: Use only what you need. Replace what you don't like</li>
<li><b>Fast</b>: App logic should run quickly, and when possible, in parallel</li>
<li><b>Productive</b>: Changes should compile quickly ... waiting isn't fun</li>
</ul>
<p>Bevy has a number of features that I think set it apart from other engines:</p>
<ul>
<li><b>Bevy ECS</b>: A custom Entity Component System with unrivaled usability and blisteringly-fast performance</li>
<li><b>Render Graphs</b>: Easily build your own multi-threaded render pipelines using Render Graph nodes</li>
<li><b>Bevy UI</b>: A custom ECS-driven UI framework built specifically for Bevy</li>
<li><b>Productive Compile Times</b>: Expect changes to compile in ~0.8-3.0 seconds with the "fast compiles" config</li>
</ul>
<p>It also has many features most people expect from a modern, general purpose engine:</p>
<ul>
<li><b>Cross Platform</b>: Windows, MacOS, and Linux (with planned support for mobile and web)</li>
<li><b>3D</b>: Lights, meshes, textures, MSAA, and GLTF loading</li>
<li><b>Sprites</b>: Render individual images as sprites, render from sprite sheets, and dynamically generate new sprite sheets</li>
<li><b>Assets</b>: An extensible, event driven asset system that loads assets asynchronously in background threads</li>
<li><b>Scenes</b>: Save ECS Worlds to human-readable scene files and load scene files into ECS Worlds</li>
<li><b>Plugins</b>: All engine and app features are implemented as modular plugins</li>
<li><b>Sound</b>: Load audio files as assets and play them from within systems</li>
<li><b>Multiple Render Backends</b>: Vulkan, DirectX 12, and Metal (with more on the way thanks to <a href="https://github.com/gfx-rs/wgpu-rs">wgpu</a>)</li>
<li><b>Data Driven Shaders</b>: Easily bind ECS components directly to shader uniforms</li>
<li><b>Hot Asset Reloading</b>: Automatically reload changes to assets at runtime without recompiles or restarts</li>
<li><b>Events</b>: Efficiently consume and produce Events from within ECS systems</li>
<li><b>Properties</b>: Dynamically get and set component fields using a string version of their names</li>
<li><b>Hierarchical Transforms</b>: Create parent-child relationships between entities that propagate Transforms down the hierarchy </li>
</ul>
<p>That being said, Bevy is still in the very early stages. I consider it to be in the "prototyping" phase: features are missing, APIs will change, and documentation is sparse. <span>I don't yet recommend using Bevy in serious projects unless you are willing to deal with gaps and instability</span>.</p>
<p>Hopefully at this point you are either (1) jazzed about Bevy or (2) not reading anymore. If you want to dive in right now, <a href="https://bevyengine.org/learn/book/introduction/">The Bevy Book</a> is the best place to get started. You can also keep reading to find out what the current state of Bevy is and where we'd like to take it.</p>
<p><strong>Quick note to the reader</strong>: in this article you will find text formatted like this: <a href="https://docs.rs/bevy_render/latest/bevy_render/texture/struct.Texture.html"><code>Texture</code>
</a></p>
<p>This formatting indicates that the text is a Rust type that links to API documentation. I encourage you to click on anything that seems interesting to you!</p>
<h2 id="bevy-apps">Bevy Apps</h2>
<p>First, lets see what a Bevy App actually looks like. The simplest App looks like this:</p>
<pre><code><span>use </span><span>bevy</span><span>::</span><span>prelude</span><span>::*;

</span><span>fn </span><span>main</span><span>() {
    </span><span>App</span><span>::</span><span>build</span><span>().</span><span>run</span><span>();
}
</span></code></pre>
<p>Thats it! This App pulls in no features and literally does nothing. Running the program would just immediately terminate. We can make it a little more interesting by doing this:</p>
<pre><code><span>fn </span><span>main</span><span>() {
    </span><span>App</span><span>::</span><span>build</span><span>()
        .</span><span>add_default_plugins</span><span>()
        .</span><span>run</span><span>();
}
</span></code></pre>
<p><a href="https://docs.rs/bevy/latest/bevy/trait.AddDefaultPlugins.html#method.add_default_plugins"><code>add_default_plugins()</code>
</a> adds all of the features you probably expect from a game engine: a 2D / 3D renderer, asset loading, a UI system, windows, input, etc</p>
<p>You can also register the default <a href="https://docs.rs/bevy_app/latest/bevy_app/trait.Plugin.html"><code>Plugins</code>
</a> manually like this:</p>
<pre><code><span>fn </span><span>main</span><span>() {
    </span><span>App</span><span>::</span><span>build</span><span>()
        .</span><span>add_plugin</span><span>(</span><span>CorePlugin</span><span>::</span><span>default</span><span>())
        .</span><span>add_plugin</span><span>(</span><span>InputPlugin</span><span>::</span><span>default</span><span>())
        .</span><span>add_plugin</span><span>(</span><span>WindowPlugin</span><span>::</span><span>default</span><span>())
        .</span><span>add_plugin</span><span>(</span><span>RenderPlugin</span><span>::</span><span>default</span><span>())
        .</span><span>add_plugin</span><span>(</span><span>UiPlugin</span><span>::</span><span>default</span><span>())
        </span><span>/* more plugins here ... omitted for brevity */
        </span><span>.</span><span>run</span><span>();
}
</span></code></pre>
<p>And of course you can also create your own plugins. In fact, all engine and game logic is built using plugins. Hopefully now you understand what we mean by modular: you are free to add/remove plugins based on your project's unique needs. However I expect that most people will stick to <a href="https://docs.rs/bevy/latest/bevy/trait.AddDefaultPlugins.html#method.add_default_plugins"><code>add_default_plugins()</code>
</a> for simplicity, at least initially. </p>
<h2 id="bevy-ecs">Bevy ECS</h2>
<p>All Bevy engine and game logic is built on top of a custom <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Entity_component_system">Entity Component System</a> (or ECS for short). Entity Component Systems are a software paradigm that involves breaking data up into Components. Entities are unique ids assigned to groups of Components. For example, one entity might might have a <code>Position</code> and <code>Velocity</code> component, whereas another entity might have a <code>Position</code> and <code>UI</code> component. Systems are logic that runs on a specific set of component types. You might have a <code>movement</code> system that runs on all entities with a <code>Position</code> and <code>Velocity</code> component.</p>
<p>The ECS pattern encourages clean, decoupled designs by forcing you to break up your app data and logic into its core components.</p>
<p>Unlike other Rust ECS implementations, which require complex lifetimes, traits, builder patterns, or macros, Bevy ECS uses normal Rust datatypes for all of these concepts:</p>
<ul>
<li><b>Components</b>: normal Rust structs</li>
<li><b>Systems</b>: normal Rust functions</li>
<li><b>Entities</b>: a type containing a unique integer</li>
</ul>
<p>There are already plenty of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2rW7ALyHaas">great introductions</a> to the ECS paradigm, so I'll leave "getting up to speed on ECS" as an exercise for the reader and skip right to what makes Bevy's ECS so special:</p>
<h3 id="ergonomics">Ergonomics</h3>
<p>I'm going to make a wild (and unverifiable) claim here: Bevy ECS is the most ergonomic ECS <em>in existence</em>:</p>
<pre><code><span>use </span><span>bevy</span><span>::</span><span>prelude</span><span>::*;

</span><span>struct </span><span>Velocity</span><span>(</span><span>f32</span><span>);
</span><span>struct </span><span>Position</span><span>(</span><span>f32</span><span>);

</span><span>// this system spawns entities with the Position and Velocity components
</span><span>fn </span><span>setup</span><span>(</span><span>mut </span><span>commands</span><span>:</span><span> Commands</span><span>) {</span><span>
    commands
        </span><span>.</span><span>spawn</span><span>((</span><span>Position</span><span>(</span><span>0.0</span><span>),</span><span> Velocity</span><span>(</span><span>1.0</span><span>),))
        .</span><span>spawn</span><span>((</span><span>Position</span><span>(</span><span>1.0</span><span>),</span><span> Velocity</span><span>(</span><span>2.0</span><span>),));
}

</span><span>// this system runs on each entity with a Position and Velocity component
</span><span>fn </span><span>movement</span><span>(</span><span>mut </span><span>position</span><span>: </span><span>Mut</span><span>&lt;</span><span>Position</span><span>&gt;</span><span>, </span><span>velocity</span><span>: &amp;</span><span>Velocity</span><span>) {</span><span>
    position</span><span>.</span><span>0 </span><span>+=</span><span> velocity</span><span>.</span><span>0</span><span>;
}

</span><span>// the app entry point. hopefully you recognize it from the examples above!
</span><span>fn </span><span>main</span><span>() {
    </span><span>App</span><span>::</span><span>build</span><span>()
        .</span><span>add_startup_system</span><span>(</span><span>setup</span><span>.</span><span>system</span><span>())
        .</span><span>add_system</span><span>(</span><span>movement</span><span>.</span><span>system</span><span>())
        .</span><span>run</span><span>();
}
</span></code></pre>
<p>That is a complete self-contained Bevy app with automatic parallel system scheduling and global change detection. In my opinion, you <a href="https://github.com/amethyst/specs/blob/master/examples/basic.rs">won't</a> find <a href="https://github.com/TomGillen/legion">any</a> ECS <a href="https://github.com/leudz/shipyard/blob/master/bunny_demo/src/systems.rs">with</a> better <a href="https://github.com/Unity-Technologies/EntityComponentSystemSamples/tree/master/ECSSamples/Assets/HelloCube">clarity</a> or ergonomics. Building games (and engines) involves writing a large number of systems, so I heavily invested in making ECS code easy to write <em>and</em> easy to read.</p>
<h3 id="performance">Performance</h3>
<p>One of the reasons the ECS paradigm is so popular is that it has the potential to make game logic <em>super</em> fast, primarily for these two reasons:</p>
<ol>
<li><b>Iteration Speed</b>: Components are packed tightly together to optimize for cache-locality, which makes iterating over them blazing fast</li>
<li><b>Parallelism</b>: Systems declare read/write dependencies, which enables automatic and efficient lock-free parallel scheduling</li>
</ol>
<p>Bevy ECS does both of these things about as well as it can. According to the popular <code>ecs_bench</code> benchmark, Bevy ECS is the fastest Rust ECS by a pretty wide margin:</p>
<h4 id="system-iteration-in-nanoseconds-less-is-better">System Iteration (in nanoseconds, less is better)</h4>
<p><img src="https://bevyengine.org/news/introducing-bevy/ecs_iter.svg" alt="ecs iter performance graph"></p>
<h4 id="world-setup-in-nanoseconds-less-is-better">World Setup (in nanoseconds, less is better)</h4>
<p><img src="https://bevyengine.org/news/introducing-bevy/ecs_build.svg" alt="ecs iter performance graph"></p>
<p>Note that <code>ecs_bench</code> is a single threaded benchmark, so it doesn't illustrate the multi-threading capabilities of these framework. And as always, please be aware that <code>ecs_bench</code> is a micro benchmark and it doesn't illustrate the performance of a complex game. There is a lot of nuance in the ECS performance space and each of the ECS implementations above will perform differently under different workloads. </p>
<p>I have pushed my version of <code>ecs_bench</code> <a href="https://github.com/cart/ecs_bench">here</a> if anyone wants to double-check my methodology. For some reasonable amount of time I will post updates here if anyone reports a problem or my results are not (on average) reproducible.</p>
<h3 id="features">Features</h3>
<p>Now you might be thinking "Ok @cart, so Bevy ECS has great performance and ergonomics, but <em>surely</em> this means you had to compromise on features!"</p>
<p>... <strong>NOPE</strong> Bevy has you covered:</p>
<h4 id="for-each-systems">For Each Systems</h4>
<pre><code><span>// "for each systems" run once on each entity containing the given components
</span><span>fn </span><span>system</span><span>(</span><span>position</span><span>: </span><span>Mut</span><span>&lt;</span><span>Position</span><span>&gt;</span><span>, </span><span>velocity</span><span>: &amp;</span><span>Velocity</span><span>) {
    </span><span>// do something
</span><span>}
</span></code></pre><h4 id="query-systems">Query Systems</h4>
<pre><code><span>// this "query system" is the same as the system above, but gives you control over iteration
</span><span>fn </span><span>system</span><span>(</span><span>mut </span><span>query</span><span>: </span><span>Query</span><span>&lt;(&amp;</span><span>Position, </span><span>&amp;</span><span>mut</span><span> Velocity</span><span>)&gt;) {
    </span><span>for </span><span>(</span><span>position</span><span>, </span><span>mut</span><span> velocity</span><span>) in &amp;</span><span>mut</span><span> query</span><span>.</span><span>iter</span><span>() {
        </span><span>// do something
    </span><span>}
}
</span></code></pre><h4 id="change-detection">Change Detection</h4>
<pre><code><span>// Added&lt;T&gt; queries only run when the given component has been added
</span><span>fn </span><span>system</span><span>(</span><span>mut </span><span>query</span><span>: </span><span>Query</span><span>&lt;</span><span>Added</span><span>&lt;</span><span>Position</span><span>&gt;&gt;) {
    </span><span>for</span><span> position </span><span>in &amp;</span><span>mut</span><span> query</span><span>.</span><span>iter</span><span>() {
        </span><span>// do something
    </span><span>}
}

</span><span>// Mutated&lt;T&gt; queries only run when the given component has been mutated
</span><span>fn </span><span>system</span><span>(</span><span>mut </span><span>query</span><span>: </span><span>Query</span><span>&lt;</span><span>Mutated</span><span>&lt;</span><span>Position</span><span>&gt;&gt;) {
    </span><span>for</span><span> position </span><span>in &amp;</span><span>mut</span><span> query</span><span>.</span><span>iter</span><span>() {
        </span><span>// do something
    </span><span>}
}

</span><span>// Changed&lt;T&gt; queries only run when the given component has been added or mutated
</span><span>fn </span><span>system</span><span>(</span><span>mut </span><span>query</span><span>: </span><span>Query</span><span>&lt;</span><span>Changed</span><span>&lt;</span><span>Position</span><span>&gt;&gt;) {
    </span><span>for</span><span> position </span><span>in &amp;</span><span>mut</span><span> query</span><span>.</span><span>iter</span><span>() {
        </span><span>// do something
    </span><span>}
}

</span><span>// query.removed&lt;T&gt;() will iterate over every entity where the component T was removed this update
</span><span>fn </span><span>system</span><span>(</span><span>mut </span><span>query</span><span>: </span><span>Query</span><span>&lt;&amp;</span><span>Position</span><span>&gt;</span><span>&gt;</span><span>) {
    </span><span>for</span><span> entity </span><span>in</span><span> query</span><span>.</span><span>removed</span><span>::&lt;</span><span>Velocity</span><span>&gt;() {
        </span><span>// do something
    </span><span>}
}
</span></code></pre><h4 id="multiple-queries">Multiple Queries</h4>
<pre><code><span>fn </span><span>system</span><span>(</span><span>mut </span><span>wall_query</span><span>: </span><span>Query</span><span>&lt;&amp;</span><span>Wall</span><span>&gt;</span><span>, </span><span>mut </span><span>player_query</span><span>: </span><span>Query</span><span>&lt;&amp;</span><span>Player</span><span>&gt;) {
    </span><span>for</span><span> player </span><span>in &amp;</span><span>mut</span><span> player_query</span><span>.</span><span>iter</span><span>() {
        </span><span>for</span><span> wall </span><span>in &amp;</span><span>mut</span><span> wall_query</span><span>.</span><span>iter</span><span>() {
            </span><span>if</span><span> player</span><span>.</span><span>collides_with</span><span>(</span><span>wall</span><span>) {
                </span><span>println!</span><span>("</span><span>ouch</span><span>");
            }
        }
    }
}
</span></code></pre><h4 id="entity-queries-and-direct-component-access">Entity Queries and Direct Component Access</h4>
<pre><code><span>fn </span><span>system</span><span>(</span><span>mut </span><span>entity_query</span><span>: </span><span>Query</span><span>&lt;</span><span>Entity</span><span>&gt;</span><span>, </span><span>mut </span><span>player_query</span><span>: </span><span>Query</span><span>&lt;&amp;</span><span>Player</span><span>&gt;) {
    </span><span>for</span><span> entity </span><span>in &amp;</span><span>mut</span><span> entity_query</span><span>.</span><span>iter</span><span>() {
       </span><span>if let </span><span>Some</span><span>(</span><span>player</span><span>) =</span><span> player_query</span><span>.</span><span>get</span><span>::&lt;</span><span>Player</span><span>&gt;(</span><span>entity</span><span>) {
           </span><span>// the current entity has a …</span></code></pre></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://bevyengine.org/news/introducing-bevy/">https://bevyengine.org/news/introducing-bevy/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bevyengine.org/news/introducing-bevy/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24123283</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 17:44:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Developer won’t get hit by a bus, they’ll get hired by Netflix]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 260 | Comments 412 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24122265">thread link</a>) | @deltamidway
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://www.neomindlabs.com/post/your-developer-wont-get-hit-by-a-bus-theyll-get-hired-by-netflix | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.neomindlabs.com/post/your-developer-wont-get-hit-by-a-bus-theyll-get-hired-by-netflix">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div><div><p>You may have heard of the “bus factor.” The strategy and processes designed to cover for the sudden loss of a teammate. The story goes: you want more than one person in your business to have domain knowledge because they might get hit by a bus! Your business would lose all that experience and expertise in one tragic accident. The premise in isolation sounds ridiculous, but mitigating the “bus factor” is serious business.</p><p>Everything gets a lot easier if you select the right software and framework, primarily if you use Ruby on Rails. Rails itself is a full-stack framework that has a best practice for every piece of a web application. If you are committed to doing things “the Rails way,” you cut the total cost of ownership by A LOT. “Staying on the Rails” makes any new developer productive almost immediately (and will keep them “out of the weeds”). Sticking to the standards evangelized by the community and adding proper documentation (possibly in the form of useful tests) makes onboarding a breeze, which creates more productive developers, which makes hiring more accessible, which reduces your “bus factor.” <br></p><p>The only guaranteed way to save money is to spend it on reducing your “bus factor”. By investing in making the code of your application more straightforward and easier to understand, you make it easier to add developers and reduce the future occurrence of bugs. You’ll make working on your code more enjoyable (reducing the likelihood your developers will want to leave), and possibly most importantly: reduce the barriers (time/money) to building new features. If you haven’t been keeping an eye on this, and find yourself in a position to hire someone, then these tasks will be their first job <strong>every time you hire</strong>.<br></p><p>Thankfully, I have no personal experience with a colleague getting hit by a bus, but I know a few that have been hired by Netflix. Remember to look both ways before crossing a street and never underestimate the amount of money the FAANGs have to poach your talent. It is effortless to lose good talent. When (not if) your developer leaves to make $500k+ a year in the valley, you’ll be in a much better position with a lower bus factor to quickly fill the gap and keep moving forward.</p><p>‍</p></div></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.neomindlabs.com/post/your-developer-wont-get-hit-by-a-bus-theyll-get-hired-by-netflix</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24122265</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 16:34:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The case for why Google should be regulated as a public utility]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 276 | Comments 374 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24120981">thread link</a>) | @abhivyas5
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://www.rankscience.com/blog/why-google-should-be-regulated-as-a-public-utility | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.rankscience.com/blog/why-google-should-be-regulated-as-a-public-utility">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                    <div id="post-444">
		<div>	
		<p><img src="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-10.49.49-AM.png" alt="google monopoly regulation" width="655" height="340" srcset="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-10.49.49-AM.png 655w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-10.49.49-AM-300x156.png 300w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-10.49.49-AM-600x311.png 600w" sizes="(max-width: 655px) 100vw, 655px"></p>
<p><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/1178728529187495937/xbH7cGaT_400x400.jpg" alt="Ryan Bednar" width="55" height="55"></p>
<p>By <strong><a href="https://twitter.com/ryanbed">Ryan Bednar</a></strong> (CEO of <a href="https://www.rankscience.com/">RankScience</a>)</p>
<p><span>Last week on July 29, 2020, the CEOs of the most powerful tech companies in the world—including Google, Facebook, Amazon, and Apple—were called in to testify in front of the House Antitrust Subcommittee. The event was widely considered to be mostly political theater, a performance act for Congress to look like they’re hard on Big Tech. But the tech titans took it seriously, knowing the one thing that actually determines whether antitrust legislation moves forward: how each company fares in the court of public opinion. The company taking the most heat from both Democrats and Republicans was, without a doubt, Google. They’re also the company that’s most likely to be regulated.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>The antitrust case against Google is the most straightforward of any of the big tech companies. Google started out as an almost benevolent index of the world wide web, showing users ten blue, unbiased links for whatever users were searching for. But over the years, Google has steadily favored showing their own products above organic search results, even when their own products arguably aren’t as good. Rand Fishkin </span><a href="https://sparktoro.com/blog/google-in-2020-from-everyones-search-engine-to-everyones-competitor/"><span>says that</span></a><span> in 2020, Google has gone “from everyone’s search engine to everyone’s competitor.”</span></p>
<p><span>As the founder of an SEO company, </span><a href="https://www.rankscience.com/"><span>RankScience</span></a><span>, and as someone who’s been working in growth and digital marketing for more than a decade, I’ve had a front-row seat to watch Google devour screen real estate to feature its own products. From my point of view, Google is squeezing businesses more than ever and the game is increasingly rigged in Google’s favor. Small and local businesses have almost no chance at succeeding with SEO because they don’t have the budget or resources for it. To make things worse, so much screen real estate is now taken up by Google’s own products, small businesses have no choice but to pay Google for search traffic. Even if users are searching directly for a business’s name, Google controls the appearance and experience of interacting with that business.</span></p>
<p><span>Local restaurants, for example, are forced to use Google’s partner ChowNow in order to have convenient “Order Pickup” or “Order Delivery” buttons in search results for their own name, which charges an added hefty fee to the restaurant for each order, hurting their already thin margins. During the global pandemic, this is an incredibly predatory shakedown. No small business should be forced to use Google’s preferred ordering mechanism, and pay a tax to Google, simply to allow a customer to search for their business. </span></p>
<p><img src="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/IMG_7745-582x1024.png" alt="google chownow local businesses" width="582" height="1024" srcset="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/IMG_7745-582x1024.png 582w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/IMG_7745-171x300.png 171w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/IMG_7745-768x1351.png 768w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/IMG_7745-600x1055.png 600w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/IMG_7745.png 821w" sizes="(max-width: 582px) 100vw, 582px"></p>

<p dir="ltr">Ben Thompson of Stratechery wrote a great post summarizing the <a href="https://stratechery.com/2019/tech-and-antitrust/">antitrust issues each tech behemoth has</a>, yet highlights his issues with Google’s position: “Google’s anticompetitive behavior is relatively clear…the company consistently favors its own properties in search results, particularly ‘above-the-fold’…that is, results that are not actually search results but which seek to answer the user’s query directly.” A few examples:</p>
<p><img src="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-10.23.49-AM.png" alt="ben thompson stratechery google antitrust regulation issues" srcset="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-10.23.49-AM.png 419w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-10.23.49-AM-300x179.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 419px) 100vw, 419px"></p>
<p><span>Take a look below at how Google-owned YouTube results take up the vast majority of the screen on a simple video search. Other competing video products like Vimeo or Twitch don’t get the same visual treatment or preference in search results. You can barely see the first organic search result for this query:</span></p>
<p><img src="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-05-at-9.53.37-AM-929x1024.png" alt="google YouTube video search results" srcset="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-05-at-9.53.37-AM-929x1024.png 929w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-05-at-9.53.37-AM-272x300.png 272w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-05-at-9.53.37-AM-768x847.png 768w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-05-at-9.53.37-AM-600x662.png 600w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-05-at-9.53.37-AM.png 956w" sizes="(max-width: 929px) 100vw, 929px"></p>

<p><span>The problem gets even worse when we’re talking about more lucrative search categories, like flight search or finding a hotel. On the flight search example below (which also includes a Covid-19 travel warning), Google Ads and Google’s own Flights product take up the entire screen, any organic search results pushed below the fold. When searching for “hotels near cape may, nj” the actual organic search results were almost two pages below the fold. How many users do you think scroll that far, instead of clicking on Google’s products?</span></p>
<p><img src="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/google-flight-search-seo.png" alt="google flight search seo antitrust" srcset="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/google-flight-search-seo.png 443w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/google-flight-search-seo-260x300.png 260w" sizes="(max-width: 443px) 100vw, 443px"> </p>
<p><img src="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/google-hotel-search.png" alt="google hotel search" srcset="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/google-hotel-search.png 255w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/google-hotel-search-149x300.png 149w" sizes="(max-width: 255px) 100vw, 255px"></p>
<p><span>Yelp, TripAdvisor, and other companies have been complaining about unfair treatment by Google </span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/07/01/technology/yelp-google-european-union-antitrust.html"><span>for years</span></a><span>, but left unfettered, Google is only going to continue to expand their own products into more search categories over time. The list of companies with grievances against Google is growing. The landscape for businesses to compete in search is increasingly competitive, and the companies who succeed in search over the long-run are using advanced tactics like SEO A/B testing and NLP content optimization, which the average business can’t afford.</span></p>
<p><span>On a recent episode of the </span><a href="https://www.allinpodcast.co/"><span>All-In Podcast</span></a><span>, Jason Calacanis, Chamath Palihapitiya, and esteemed guests engage in a rigorous and detailed debate about Big Tech antitrust and censorship (I recommend </span><a href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/0Ewtt593ZsFT5QXJSB97wR?si=Ej5Bx4UMRwqrU4ruSog06w"><span>giving it a listen</span></a><span> if you haven’t, as it covers the strongest arguments both for and against Big Tech regulation). Chamath says what I think most people don’t want to admit:&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></p>
<blockquote><p><b>The internet is now a pervasive and critical part of human infrastructure. As such, there needs to be people that regulate and manage the internet</b><span>—the same way that the FAA manages and regulates planes, and wind turbines, etc.… Let’s take aviation [for example], it’s impossible for you to go into your garage and build a plane that takes people from point A to point B. Take agriculture [for example], it’s impossible for you to build up a farm and supply it to Safeway, without any checks and balances.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>There are very specific kinds of businesses and business models that should be overseen. The first and most important thing is a body [that] oversees the collection of user data and privacy and identification. The second one is essentially something that tears the fig leaf off of internet companies and says, you know what, you are the equivalent of a publisher and a platform, some weird hybrid that we didn’t think could exist when we wrote these rules, so we’re now going to adapt these rules. If you think about it, nobody is happy with the internet publishers today. The left thinks that it skews right, the right thinks it skews left—everybody is confused. Nobody gets what they want and somebody has to step in.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>You go to a movie and it tells you who can go to the movie or not. You buy an album and it tells you whether there’s explicit lyrics or not. Before you turn on the TV, there’s some rating agency that tells you whether your kid should be watching with you. My point is: what is the equivalent version here? We all need to think about what it is, but for there to be nothing is crazy.&nbsp;</span></p></blockquote>
<p><span>Google search is fundamentally the gateway to the internet for the majority of people and an arbiter of truth in our digital age. Google has a </span><a href="https://www.internetlivestats.com/google-search-statistics/"><span>dominant market monopoly position</span></a><span>, a treasure trove of sensitive information on hundreds of millions of users. It’s incentivized to return value to shareholders and extract more value from search over time, which is at odds with doing right by businesses and citizens. Their business model doesn’t require them to act in the long-term interest of businesses and citizens, and because they have a monopoly on a utility that’s become essential to our day-to-day lives, the only solution is for the government to enforce guidelines on fair behavior within search.</span></p>
<h3>Related Posts</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.rankscience.com/coderwall-seo-split-test">How Coderwall grew SEO traffic by 57% with a single SEO A/B test</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.rankscience.com/blog/how-businesses-boost-sales-with-seo-a-b-testing-on-ecommerce-sites">How eCommerce sites are using SEO A/B testing to boost sales</a></li>
</ul>
<p><img src="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Outline_Logo.png" alt="" width="157" height="157" srcset="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Outline_Logo.png 157w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Outline_Logo-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 157px) 100vw, 157px"></p>
<p>Get Data-Driven about growing your traffic with <a href="https://www.rankscience.com/">RankScience</a>.</p>

		
	</div>

	</div>
    
                </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.rankscience.com/blog/why-google-should-be-regulated-as-a-public-utility</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24120981</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 15:00:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Browser Extensions I Can't Live Without]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 169 | Comments 158 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24120614">thread link</a>) | @maskys
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://blog.maskys.com/my-best-chrome-extensions/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.maskys.com/my-best-chrome-extensions/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">
<div>
<article>

<figure>
<img srcset="https://blog.maskys.com/content/images/size/w300/2020/08/best-chrome-extensions.jpg 300w,
                            https://blog.maskys.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/08/best-chrome-extensions.jpg 600w,
                            https://blog.maskys.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/08/best-chrome-extensions.jpg 1000w,
                            https://blog.maskys.com/content/images/size/w2000/2020/08/best-chrome-extensions.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 400px,
                            (max-width: 1170px) 700px,
                            1400px" src="https://blog.maskys.com/content/images/size/w2000/2020/08/best-chrome-extensions.jpg" alt="Browser Extensions I Can't Live Without">
</figure>
<section>
<div>
<p>Dramatic title, I know, but lately I've had a few people ask me what extensions I use, and through sharing my list I've learnt of even better ones, so what better way to amplify these positive effects than to leverage the internet? 😛</p><p>Without further ado, let's jump into it.</p><h3 id="privacy-badger-ublock-origin"><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/privacy-badger/pkehgijcmpdhfbdbbnkijodmdjhbjlgp">Privacy Badger</a> + <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/ublock-origin/cjpalhdlnbpafiamejdnhcphjbkeiagm?hl=en">UBlock Origin</a></h3><p>Let's block all the ads! Sites look cleaner, load waayy faster, and pry less. These are the first extensions I install on <em>any</em> browser. </p><h3 id="nano-defender"><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/nano-defender/ggolfgbegefeeoocgjbmkembbncoadlb?hl=en">Nano Defender</a></h3><p>Let's block all the anti-adblockers! Many sites these days will try to get you to turn off your adblocker, but once you set up <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/nano-defender/ggolfgbegefeeoocgjbmkembbncoadlb?hl=en">Nano Defender</a>, you'll no longer have to deal with that. Note: To use alongside Ublock Origin, I had to go through a <a href="https://jspenguin2017.github.io/uBlockProtector/#extra-installation-steps-for-ublock-origin">few extra steps</a> first.</p><h3 id="hover-unpaywall-bypass-paywalls"><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/hover-bypass-paywalls-sub/ajbennpkmbahpfdalicgaogjbfhngeok/related">Hover</a> + <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/unpaywall/iplffkdpngmdjhlpjmppncnlhomiipha?hl=en">Unpaywall</a>/ ByPass Paywalls</h3><p>Let's block all the login/paywalls! Are you starting to see a pattern here? 😛 The web can be full of thrash sometimes. With <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/hover-bypass-paywalls-sub/ajbennpkmbahpfdalicgaogjbfhngeok">Hover</a> &amp; <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/unpaywall/iplffkdpngmdjhlpjmppncnlhomiipha?hl=en">Unpaywall</a>, I can say goodbye to Medium and journal paywalls. If you're a fan of open source and have an extra minute to spend, check out this <a href="https://github.com/iamadamdev/bypass-paywalls-chrome">extension</a> instead.</p><h3 id="shut-up"><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/shut-up-comment-blocker/oklfoejikkmejobodofaimigojomlfim?hl=en">Shut Up</a></h3><p>Sometimes when I'm consuming content, I'll be tempted to see what others are saying about it. That's... not always good. Let these xkcd comics illustrate my point:</p><figure><img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/youtube.png" alt="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/youtube.png"></figure><figure><img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/listen_to_yourself.png" alt="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/listen_to_yourself.png"></figure><figure><img src="https://blog.maskys.com/content/images/2020/08/image.png"></figure><p><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/shut-up-comment-blocker/oklfoejikkmejobodofaimigojomlfim?hl=en">Shut Up</a> disables comments everywhere. When I trust a platform's audience enough to read the unfiltered outputs from their brains, I enable comments for just that site. Sometimes I turn it back off immediately 💀</p><h3 id="reader-mode"><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/reader-mode/llimhhconnjiflfimocjggfjdlmlhblm?hl=en">Reader Mode</a></h3><p>Occasionally, even after all these purges, the content on a site will still be ridiculously hard to read- sometimes because they used a funky font and set the size to 8px, or sometimes because there are a million other article suggestions, plus three sidebars, plus an obnoxious navigation header that never goes away. In cases like these, I just use <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/reader-mode/llimhhconnjiflfimocjggfjdlmlhblm?hl=en">Reader Mode</a>.</p><h3 id="grammarly"><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/grammarly-for-chrome/kbfnbcaeplbcioakkpcpgfkobkghlhen?hl=en">Grammarly</a></h3><p><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/grammarly-for-chrome/kbfnbcaeplbcioakkpcpgfkobkghlhen?hl=en">Grammarly</a> effortlessly corrects any pesky spelling and grammatical mistakes I make.</p><h3 id="video-speed-controller"><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/video-speed-controller/nffaoalbilbmmfgbnbgppjihopabppdk?hl=en">Video Speed Controller</a></h3><p><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/video-speed-controller/nffaoalbilbmmfgbnbgppjihopabppdk?hl=en">Video Speed Controller</a> allows you to control the playback speed on any site. Set the default pace to 1.10x and you'll go through videos 10% faster without even noticing. Or if you're on other end of the spectrum like me, and Youtube's 2x doesn't match your pace, set it to 2.5x+ to get through lengthy monologues as fast as possible 😼</p><h3 id="the-great-suspender"><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/the-great-suspender/klbibkeccnjlkjkiokjodocebajanakg?hl=en">The Great Suspender</a></h3><p>Makes Chrome use less resources by suspending tabs you're not using. Computers run much more smoothly when this is enabled, especially if you're a compulsive tab opener.</p><h3 id="tab-snooze"><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/tab-snooze/pdiebiamhaleloakpcgmpnenggpjbcbm?hl=en">Tab Snooze</a></h3><p>Ran into an interesting rabbit hole or website that you'd really like to check out, but don't have the time right now? Use <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/tab-snooze/pdiebiamhaleloakpcgmpnenggpjbcbm?hl=en">Tab Snooze</a>, and it'll magically reopen the tabs later.</p><h3 id="google-keep-notion-web-clipper"><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/google-keep-chrome-extens/lpcaedmchfhocbbapmcbpinfpgnhiddi?hl=en">Google Keep</a>/ <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/notion-web-clipper/knheggckgoiihginacbkhaalnibhilkk?hl=en">Notion Web Clipper</a></h3><p>I used to use <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/google-keep-chrome-extens/lpcaedmchfhocbbapmcbpinfpgnhiddi?hl=en">Google Keep</a> heavily before, to save snippets and links and to add my own notes to the stuff I read online, but I've started moving towards <a href="https://blog.maskys.com/my-best-chrome-extensions/notion.so">Notion</a> these days, as it's a lot more organized. An important feature both have is that they're cross-platform, which means I can type out a fresh thought on my phone and flesh out the concept on my PC later.</p><h3 id="news-feed-eradicator-for-facebook"><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/news-feed-eradicator-for/fjcldmjmjhkklehbacihaiopjklihlgg?hl=en">News Feed Eradicator for Facebook</a></h3><p>I rarely use FB these days, and that's in large part thanks to this extension. I can just pop in to share something interesting or to tell people NOT to message me on Messenger, without being sucked in by the infinite feed.</p><h3 id="minimal-twitter"><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/minimal-twitter/pobhoodpcipjmedfenaigbeloiidbflp?hl=en">Minimal Twitter</a></h3><p>I do use Twitter, and this completely cleans up the interface. I mean, just look at this demo video</p><figure><iframe width="480" height="270" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rOkKhPiUYxY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></figure><h3 id="view-image"><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/view-image/jpcmhcelnjdmblfmjabdeclccemkghjk?hl=en">View Image</a></h3><p>Brings back the view image button on Google Images! 🤗</p><h3 id="simplify-gmail"><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/simplify-gmail/pbmlfaiicoikhdbjagjbglnbfcbcojpj/related?hl=en">Simplify Gmail</a></h3><p>Recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/matejmecka?lang=en">Matej</a>, this lovely extension cleans up Gmail's UI and hides the obnoxious logo.</p><hr><h2 id="nerd-section">Nerd Section</h2><p>These extensions aren't for everyone, but as a developer/designer they're super nifty.</p><h3 id="refined-github"><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/refined-github/hlepfoohegkhhmjieoechaddaejaokhf?hl=en">Refined Github</a></h3><p>Super awesome extension that adds tons of features to Github.</p><h3 id="whatfont"><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/whatfont/jabopobgcpjmedljpbcaablpmlmfcogm?hl=en">WhatFont</a></h3><p>Enable WhatFont, hover over any text on any site, and you'll instantly be shown the font family and other text properties! No more digging through CSS in Dev Tools 😤</p><h3 id="whatruns-wappalyzer"><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/whatruns/cmkdbmfndkfgebldhnkbfhlneefdaaip?hl=en">WhatRuns</a>+<a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/wappalyzer/gppongmhjkpfnbhagpmjfkannfbllamg/related">Wappalyzer</a></h3><p>I use these when I want a quick overview of what stack/tools a site is using. The results are pretty basic though, so if I want to dig deeper I just end up googling it.</p><h3 id="epubpress"><a href="https://blog.maskys.com/p/40951844-a4a2-4b15-9442-1da99e6736b6/">Epubpress</a></h3><p>Whenever I have a lengthy article that I want to take my time to read, like this guide on <a href="https://www.narative.co/articles/building-product-market-fit-with-relationship-marketing">Building product-market fit with relationship marketing</a><strong>, </strong>I use EpubPress to turn it into an .epub that I can later read offline, usually on my Kindle.</p><hr><p>Aand that's it! This is my list as of now. I'd be happy to discover your favorite extensions- just leave a comment. For more lists of cool stuff, you might want to check my <a href="https://www.notion.so/2b95db6bd2064534b41c8801e5ae3670?v=d0d74412ade046cc9a5123ec8a3c9ce4">stash.</a> To be notified when I share other useful stuff like this, you can follow me on <a href="https://twitter.com/maskys_">Twitter.</a></p>
</div>
</section>


</article>
</div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.maskys.com/my-best-chrome-extensions/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24120614</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 14:29:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[That coworker who never stops refactoring]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 284 | Comments 209 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24120359">thread link</a>) | @mcrittenden
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://critter.blog/2020/08/11/that-coworker-who-never-stops-refactoring/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://critter.blog/2020/08/11/that-coworker-who-never-stops-refactoring/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-content" role="main">

	
<article id="post-602">

	
<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>

		<div>

			
<p>Fred is on your team. He takes 5 times longer to build a feature than anyone else. When asked what’s the hold up, Fred responds that he’s tweaking a class definition or adding some out of scope automation instead of just building the dang thing that the ticket says to build. Fred drives the team nuts, and he often gets called a gold plater, or unproductive, or slow. </p>



<p>But in my experience, Fred isn’t slow at all. He’s just as productive as everyone else, but he’s solving different problems than the ones he was asked to solve.</p>



<p><strong>Fred is more interested in providing value to other developers than to users.</strong> </p>



<p>Your team probably pushes back on that. Fred’s feedback (if he gets any at all, which is a topic for another post) is that he needs to work on his velocity and get through his tickets faster. In other words, you’re telling him to stop doing the thing that he loves. He can’t just change his interest, so the best case scenario is that he’ll push hard for a few months on the boring stuff until he burns out and quits, or falls back into his old habits.</p>



<p>Maybe Fred doesn’t need to change. Maybe he’s just <a href="https://www.entrepreneur.com/article/331248">in the wrong seat</a>. What if the team leaned into what gets Fred excited? If he doesn’t care about providing value to users, but loves providing value to his fellow developers, then could that be his full time job? His responsibilities could include:</p>



<ul><li>Automating anything that can possibly be automated</li><li>Making local environments run faster and smoother</li><li>Refactoring and managing tech debt</li><li>Quick and thorough code review</li><li>Streamlining the deploy process</li><li>Writing missing automated tests</li></ul>



<p>Doesn’t it seem powerful, to have a person on your team completely dedicated to helping other developers be as productive as they can be? Imagine reaching out to Fred the second you had code ready for review, or when a build fails and you aren’t sure why, or when your can’t figure out why your debugger stopped debugging, or when you notice that some function over here basically does the same thing as some other function over there. </p>



<p>He loves that stuff, and he’s probably really good at it, because as they say, “being enthusiastic is worth 25 IQ points”. So maybe try letting him do it?</p>



<p><em>Feel free to <a href="https://twitter.com/mcrittenden">tweet at me</a> or check out the <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24120359">thread on Hacker News</a>.</em></p>

		</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	</div><!-- .post-inner -->

	<!-- .section-inner -->

	
	<!-- .pagination-single -->

	
</article><!-- .post -->

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://critter.blog/2020/08/11/that-coworker-who-never-stops-refactoring/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24120359</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 14:06:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Single Page Applications using Rust]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 760 | Comments 401 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24120311">thread link</a>) | @rkwz
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | http://www.sheshbabu.com/posts/rust-wasm-yew-single-page-application/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.sheshbabu.com/posts/rust-wasm-yew-single-page-application/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>WebAssembly (wasm) allows code written in languages other than JavaScript to run on browsers. If you haven’t been paying attention, all the major browsers support wasm and <a href="https://caniuse.com/#feat=wasm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">globally more than 90% of users</a> have browsers that can run wasm.</p>
<p>Since Rust compiles to wasm, is it possible to build SPAs (Single Page Applications) purely in Rust and without writing a single line of JavaScript? The short answer is YES! Read on to learn more or visit the <a href="https://rustmart-yew.netlify.app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">demo site</a> if you can’t contain your excitement!</p>
<p>We’ll be building a simple ecommerce site called “RustMart” that will have 2 pages:</p>
<ul>
<li>HomePage - list all the products that the customer can add to cart</li>
<li>ProductDetailPage - show the product details when a product card is clicked</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="http://www.sheshbabu.com/images/2020-rust-wasm-yew-single-page-application/rust-wasm-yew-single-page-application-1.png" alt=""></p>
<p>I’m using this example as it tests the minimal set of capabilities required to build modern SPAs:</p>
<ul>
<li>Navigate between multiple pages without page reload</li>
<li>Make network requests without page reload</li>
<li>Ability to reuse UI components across multiple pages</li>
<li>Update components in different layers of the UI hierarchy</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Setup"><a href="#Setup" title="Setup"></a>Setup</h2><p>Follow this <a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/tools/install" target="_blank" rel="noopener">link</a> to install Rust if you haven’t done so already.</p>
<p>Install these Rust tools:</p>
<pre><code>$ cargo install wasm-pack          # Compile Rust to Wasm and generate JS interop code
$ cargo install cargo-make         # Task runner
$ cargo install simple-http-server # Simple server to serve assets</code></pre>
<p>Create a new project:</p>
<pre><code>$ cargo new --lib rustmart &amp;&amp; cd rustmart</code></pre>
<p>We’ll be using the <a href="https://yew.rs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><code>Yew</code></a> library to build UI components. Let’s add this and wasm dependencies to <code>Cargo.toml</code>:</p>
<pre><code>[lib]
crate-type = ["cdylib", "rlib"]

[dependencies]
yew = "0.17"
wasm-bindgen = "0.2"</code></pre>
<p>Create a new file named <code>Makefile.toml</code> and add this:</p>
<pre><code>[tasks.build]
command = "wasm-pack"
args = ["build", "--dev", "--target", "web", "--out-name", "wasm", "--out-dir", "./static"]
watch = { ignore_pattern = "static/*" }

[tasks.serve]
command = "simple-http-server"
args = ["-i", "./static/", "-p", "3000", "--nocache", "--try-file", "./static/index.html"]</code></pre>
<p>Start the build task:</p>
<pre><code>$ cargo make build</code></pre>
<p>If you’re new to Rust, I’ve written some <a href="http://www.sheshbabu.com/tags/Rust-Beginners/">guides for beginners</a> which will help you follow this post better.</p>
<h2 id="Hello-World"><a href="#Hello-World" title="Hello World"></a>Hello World</h2><p>Let’s start with a simple “hello world” example:</p>
<p>Create <code>static/index.html</code> and add this:</p>
<pre><code><span>&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;</span>
<span><span><span>&lt;</span>html</span> <span>lang</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>en<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>head</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
    <span><span><span>&lt;</span>meta</span> <span>charset</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>utf-8<span>"</span></span> <span>/&gt;</span></span>
    <span><span><span>&lt;</span>title</span><span>&gt;</span></span>RustMart<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>title</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
    <span><span><span>&lt;</span>script</span> <span>type</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>module<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span><span>
      <span>import</span> init <span>from</span> <span>"/wasm.js"</span><span>;</span>
      <span>init</span><span>(</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>
    </span><span><span><span>&lt;/</span>script</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
    <span><span><span>&lt;</span>link</span> <span>rel</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>shortcut icon<span>"</span></span> <span>href</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>#<span>"</span></span> <span>/&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;/</span>head</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>body</span><span>&gt;</span></span><span><span><span>&lt;/</span>body</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>html</span><span>&gt;</span></span></code></pre>
<p>Add this to <code>src/lib.rs</code>:</p>
<pre><code>
<span>use</span> wasm_bindgen<span>:</span><span>:</span>prelude<span>:</span><span>:</span><span>*</span><span>;</span>
<span>use</span> yew<span>:</span><span>:</span>prelude<span>:</span><span>:</span><span>*</span><span>;</span>

<span>struct</span> Hello <span>{</span><span>}</span>

<span>impl</span> Component <span>for</span> Hello <span>{</span>
    <span>type</span> Message <span>=</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>
    <span>type</span> Properties <span>=</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>

    <span>fn</span> <span>create</span><span>(</span>_<span>:</span> Self<span>:</span><span>:</span>Properties<span>,</span> _<span>:</span> ComponentLink<span>&lt;</span>Self<span>&gt;</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> Self <span>{</span>
        Self <span>{</span><span>}</span>
    <span>}</span>

    <span>fn</span> <span>update</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>mut</span> <span>self</span><span>,</span> _<span>:</span> Self<span>:</span><span>:</span>Message<span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> ShouldRender <span>{</span>
        <span>true</span>
    <span>}</span>

    <span>fn</span> <span>change</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>mut</span> <span>self</span><span>,</span> _<span>:</span> Self<span>:</span><span>:</span>Properties<span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> ShouldRender <span>{</span>
        <span>true</span>
    <span>}</span>

    <span>fn</span> <span>view</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>self</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> Html <span>{</span>
        <span>html!</span> <span>{</span> <span>&lt;</span>span<span>&gt;</span><span>{</span><span>"Hello World!"</span><span>}</span><span>&lt;</span><span>/</span>span<span>&gt;</span> <span>}</span>
    <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>#[wasm_bindgen(start)]</span>
<span>pub</span> <span>fn</span> <span>run_app</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    App<span>:</span><span>:</span><span>&lt;</span>Hello<span>&gt;</span><span>:</span><span>:</span><span>new</span><span>(</span><span>)</span><span>.</span><span>mount_to_body</span><span>(</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre>
<p>Lot of things going on but you can see that we’re creating a new component named “Hello” that renders <code>&lt;span&gt;Hello World!&lt;/span&gt;</code> into the DOM. We’ll learn more about Yew components later.</p>
<p>Start the serve task in a new terminal and load <code>http://localhost:3000</code> in your browser</p>
<pre><code>$ cargo make serve</code></pre>
<p><img src="http://www.sheshbabu.com/images/2020-rust-wasm-yew-single-page-application/image-1.png" alt=""></p>
<p>It works!! It’s only “hello world” but this is fully written in Rust.</p>
<p>Let’s learn about components and other SPA concepts before proceeding further.</p>
<h2 id="Thinking-in-Components"><a href="#Thinking-in-Components" title="Thinking in Components"></a>Thinking in Components</h2><p>Building UIs by composing components and passing data in a unidirectional way is a paradigm shift in the frontend world. It’s a huge improvement in the way we reason about UI and it’s very hard to go back to imperative DOM manipulation once you get used to this.</p>
<p>A <code>Component</code> in libraries like React, Vue, Yew, Flutter etc have these features:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ability to be composed into bigger components</li>
<li><code>Props</code> - Pass data and callbacks from that component to its child components.</li>
<li><code>State</code> - Manipulate state local to that component.</li>
<li><code>AppState</code> - Manipulate global state.</li>
<li>Listen to lifecycle events like “Instantiated”, “Mounted in DOM” etc</li>
<li>Perform side effects like fetching remote data, manipulating localstorage etc</li>
</ul>
<p>A component gets updated (re-rendered) when one of the following happens:</p>
<ul>
<li>Parent component is re-rendered</li>
<li><code>Props</code> changes</li>
<li><code>State</code> changes</li>
<li><code>AppState</code> changes</li>
</ul>
<p>So, instead of imperatively updating the UI when user interaction, network requests etc happen, we update the data (Props, State, AppState) and the UI is updated based on this data. This what someone means when they say “UI is a function of state”.</p>
<p>The exact details differ across different libraries but this should give you a general idea. If you’re new to this, this way of thinking might take sometime to “click” and get used to.</p>
<h2 id="HomePage"><a href="#HomePage" title="HomePage"></a>HomePage</h2><p>Let’s build the HomePage first. We’ll be building the HomePage as a monolithic component and later decompose it into smaller reusable components.</p>
<p>Let’s create the following files:</p>
<pre><code>
<span>use</span> yew<span>:</span><span>:</span>prelude<span>:</span><span>:</span><span>*</span><span>;</span>

<span>pub</span> <span>struct</span> Home <span>{</span><span>}</span>

<span>impl</span> Component <span>for</span> Home <span>{</span>
    <span>type</span> Message <span>=</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>
    <span>type</span> Properties <span>=</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>

    <span>fn</span> <span>create</span><span>(</span>_<span>:</span> Self<span>:</span><span>:</span>Properties<span>,</span> _<span>:</span> ComponentLink<span>&lt;</span>Self<span>&gt;</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> Self <span>{</span>
        Self <span>{</span><span>}</span>
    <span>}</span>

    <span>fn</span> <span>update</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>mut</span> <span>self</span><span>,</span> _<span>:</span> Self<span>:</span><span>:</span>Message<span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> ShouldRender <span>{</span>
        <span>true</span>
    <span>}</span>

    <span>fn</span> <span>change</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>mut</span> <span>self</span><span>,</span> _<span>:</span> Self<span>:</span><span>:</span>Properties<span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> ShouldRender <span>{</span>
        <span>true</span>
    <span>}</span>

    <span>fn</span> <span>view</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>self</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> Html <span>{</span>
        <span>html!</span> <span>{</span> <span>&lt;</span>span<span>&gt;</span><span>{</span><span>"Home Sweet Home!"</span><span>}</span><span>&lt;</span><span>/</span>span<span>&gt;</span> <span>}</span>
    <span>}</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre>
<pre><code>
<span>mod</span> home<span>;</span>

<span>pub</span> <span>use</span> home<span>:</span><span>:</span>Home<span>;</span></code></pre>
<p>Let’s update the <code>src/lib.rs</code> to import the HomePage component:</p>
<pre><code>  // src/lib.rs
<span>+ mod pages;</span>

<span>+ use pages::Home;</span>
  use wasm_bindgen::prelude::*;
  use yew::prelude::*;

<span>- struct Hello {}</span>

<span>- impl Component for Hello {</span>
<span>-     type Message = ();</span>
<span>-     type Properties = ();</span>

<span>-     fn create(_: Self::Properties, _: ComponentLink&lt;Self&gt;) -&gt; Self {</span>
<span>-         Self {}</span>
<span>-     }</span>

<span>-     fn update(&amp;mut self, _: Self::Message) -&gt; ShouldRender {</span>
<span>-         true</span>
<span>-     }</span>

<span>-     fn change(&amp;mut self, _: Self::Properties) -&gt; ShouldRender {</span>
<span>-         true</span>
<span>-     }</span>

<span>-     fn view(&amp;self) -&gt; Html {</span>
<span>-         html! { &lt;span&gt;{"Hello World!"}&lt;/span&gt; }</span>
<span>-     }</span>
<span>- }</span>

  #[wasm_bindgen(start)]
  pub fn run_app() {
<span>-   App::&lt;Hello&gt;::new().mount_to_body();</span>
<span>+   App::&lt;Home&gt;::new().mount_to_body();</span>
  }</code></pre>
<p>Now, you should see “Home Sweet Home!” instead of “Hello World!” rendered in your browser.</p>
<p>Let’s start designing the <code>State</code> of this component:</p>
<ul>
<li>We need to store a list of products retrieved from server</li>
<li>Store the products the user has added to cart</li>
</ul>
<p>We create a simple struct to hold the <code>Product</code> details:</p>
<pre><code><span>struct</span> Product <span>{</span>
    name<span>:</span> String<span>,</span>
    description<span>:</span> String<span>,</span>
    image<span>:</span> String<span>,</span>
    price<span>:</span> f64<span>,</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre>
<p>We then create a new struct <code>State</code> with field called <code>products</code> to hold the products from server:</p>
<pre><code><span>struct</span> State <span>{</span>
    products<span>:</span> Vec<span>&lt;</span>Product<span>&gt;</span><span>,</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre>
<p>Here’s the full list of changes in the HomePage component:</p>
<pre><code>  use yew::prelude::*;

<span>+ struct Product {</span>
<span>+     id: i32,</span>
<span>+     name: String,</span>
<span>+     description: String,</span>
<span>+     image: String,</span>
<span>+     price: f64,</span>
<span>+ }</span>

<span>+ struct State {</span>
<span>+     products: Vec&lt;Product&gt;,</span>
<span>+ }</span>

<span>- pub struct Home {}</span>
<span>+ pub struct Home {</span>
<span>+     state: State,</span>
<span>+ }</span>

  impl Component for Home {
      type Message = ();
      type Properties = ();

      fn create(_: Self::Properties, _: ComponentLink&lt;Self&gt;) -&gt; Self {
<span>+       let products: Vec&lt;Product&gt; = vec![</span>
<span>+           Product {</span>
<span>+               id: 1,</span>
<span>+               name: "Apple".to_string(),</span>
<span>+               description: "An apple a day keeps the doctor away".to_string(),</span>
<span>+               image: "/products/apple.png".to_string(),</span>
<span>+               price: 3.65,</span>
<span>+           },</span>
<span>+           Product {</span>
<span>+               id: 2,</span>
<span>+               name: "Banana".to_string(),</span>
<span>+               description: "An old banana leaf was once young and green".to_string(),</span>
<span>+               image: "/products/banana.png".to_string(),</span>
<span>+               price: 7.99,</span>
<span>+           },</span>
<span>+       ];</span>

<span>-       Self {}</span>
<span>+       Self {</span>
<span>+           state: State {</span>
<span>+               products,</span>
<span>+           },</span>
<span>+       }</span>
      }

      fn update(&amp;mut self, _: Self::Message) -&gt; ShouldRender {
          true
      }

      fn change(&amp;mut self, _: Self::Properties) -&gt; ShouldRender {
          true
      }

      fn view(&amp;self) -&gt; Html {
<span>+        let products: Vec&lt;Html&gt; = self</span>
<span>+            .state</span>
<span>+            .products</span>
<span>+            .iter()</span>
<span>+            .map(|product: &amp;Product| {</span>
<span>+                html! {</span>
<span>+                  &lt;div&gt;</span>
<span>+                    &lt;img src={&amp;product.image}/&gt;</span>
<span>+                    &lt;div&gt;{&amp;product.name}&lt;/div&gt;</span>
<span>+                    &lt;div&gt;{"$"}{&amp;product.price}&lt;/div&gt;</span>
<span>+                  &lt;/div&gt;</span>
<span>+                }</span>
<span>+            })</span>
<span>+            .collect();</span>
<span>+</span>
<span>+        html! { &lt;span&gt;{products}&lt;/span&gt; }</span>
<span>-        html! { &lt;span&gt;{"Home!"}&lt;/span&gt; }</span>
      }
  }</code></pre>
<p>The <code>create</code> lifecycle method is invoked when the component is created and this is where we set the initial state. For the time being, we’ve created a mock list of products and assigned it to the <code>products</code> inside the state as initial value. Later, we’ll fetch this list using network request.</p>
<p>The <code>view</code> lifecycle method is invoked when the component is rendered. Here we’ve iterated over <code>products</code> inside state to generate product cards. If you’re familiar with React, this is same as the <code>render</code> method and the <code>html!</code> macro is similar to <code>JSX</code>.</p>
<p>Save some random images as <code>static/products/apple.png</code> and <code>static/products/banana.png</code> and you’ll get this UI:</p>
<p><img src="http://www.sheshbabu.com/images/2020-rust-wasm-yew-single-page-application/image-2.png" alt=""></p>
<p>Let’s implement the “add to cart” functionality:</p>
<ul>
<li>We keep track of all products added to cart in a new state field called <code>cart_products</code></li>
<li>We render a “add to cart” button for each product</li>
<li>Add logic to update the <code>cart_products</code> state when “add to cart” button is clicked</li>
</ul>
<pre><code>  use yew::prelude::*;

<span>+ #[derive(Clone)]</span>
  struct Product {
      id: i32,
      name: String,
      description: String,
      image: String,
      price: f64,
  }

<span>+ struct CartProduct {</span>
<span>+     product: Product,</span>
<span>+     quantity: i32,</span>
<span>+ }</span>

  struct State {
      products: Vec&lt;Product&gt;,
<span>+     cart_products: Vec&lt;CartProduct&gt;,</span>
  }

  pub struct Home {
      …</code></pre></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://www.sheshbabu.com/posts/rust-wasm-yew-single-page-application/">http://www.sheshbabu.com/posts/rust-wasm-yew-single-page-application/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.sheshbabu.com/posts/rust-wasm-yew-single-page-application/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24120311</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 14:00:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to stop procrastinating by using the Fogg Behavior Model]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 606 | Comments 201 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24120275">thread link</a>) | @vitabenes
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://www.deprocrastination.co/blog/how-to-stop-procrastinating-by-using-the-fogg-behavior-model | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.deprocrastination.co/blog/how-to-stop-procrastinating-by-using-the-fogg-behavior-model">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article><p>B J Fogg is a Stanford professor who came up with a simple model of behavior that helps us understand why we take action or not take action at any given moment.</p><img src="https://www.deprocrastination.co/assets/illustrations/fbm.png" alt="Fogg Behavior Model"><p>According to FBM, there are three things we need to do something:</p><ul><li>Motivation</li><li>Ability</li><li>Trigger</li></ul><p>The key is that we need to have all three at the same time in order to act.</p><p>Since our problem is procrastination, we'll focus on how we fail at each one of these.</p><h2>Motivation X Procrastination</h2><img src="https://www.deprocrastination.co/assets/illustrations/fbm_no_motivation.png" alt="Fogg Behavior Model - no motivation"><p>Sometimes we have the ability to do something, and even have a trigger like a time window and a to-do item, but we don't feel motivated.</p><p>We stare at a list of tasks, and stare, and stare, and none of them seem particularly exciting.</p><p>So we do something else - procrastinate.</p><p>The thing is,&nbsp;<strong>motivation doesn't come out of the blue.</strong></p><p>We often have a fantasy in our heads of ourselves, sitting down to work, feeling inspired and tearing into work with a smile on our faces.</p><p>That's often not how it goes.</p><p>On the days when we don't feel motivated,&nbsp;<strong>we need to build motivation.</strong></p><h3>How to build motivation</h3><p>We feel motivated when we viscerally feel how an action is&nbsp;<strong>meaningful, or valuable</strong>&nbsp;to us and when we&nbsp;<strong>believe we can</strong>&nbsp;take it (we'll get to this in the next part).</p><p>Therefore, we don't feel motivated when we don't see the meaning or value hiding behind a to-do item.</p><p>What to do about it then?</p><p><strong>Remind yourself of the why.</strong></p><p>There probably was a reason why you wrote down a task or got one assigned to you.</p><p>Was it to help you learn something?        Was it to make you money?        Was it to help someone?</p><p>Take a task you're putting off, and try to remember in vivid detail why you thought you needed to do it.</p><p>The important part is not only to know the reason, but to feel it, to get excited about it. How to do that? Link the task to a personal goal that you want to achieve. Attach exciting reasons to the task.</p><p><em>Write a thesis</em>&nbsp;  - not motivating.</p><p>Write a thesis to successfully complete a degree and do cutting-edge research.<br>Write a thesis to deepen your understanding of a subject and get recognized by others in your field.<br>Write a thesis to help others see things more clearly and make progress.</p><p><strong>Add personal, meaningful reasons to the tasks that you put off. Make yourself remember why you took them on.</strong></p><h2>Ability X Procrastination</h2><img src="https://www.deprocrastination.co/assets/illustrations/fbm_no_ability.png" alt="Fogg Behavior Model - no ability"><p>Sometimes we feel motivated, but every task on our plate seems just too darn hard, like standing at the foot of 5 different mountains in the Himalayas and having to decide which one to climb.</p><p>When everything seems hard, it's easy to succumb to procrastination and check email, or social media, or play games. All those actions are much easier than&nbsp;<em>work.</em></p><p>But when&nbsp;<strong>we're finally done with our procrastination, we'll often find that our work hasn't gotten any easier while we procrastinated.</strong>&nbsp;In fact, it seems even harder.</p><p>That's clearly not a good cycle.</p><p>Instead of avoiding anything hard, let's&nbsp;<strong>turn down the difficulty dial by focusing on small steps.</strong></p><p>You probably can't climb the whole mountain at once, but you can ascend a few hundred feet.        You probably can't write a whole thesis at once, but you can write 5 paragraphs.        You probably can't build a business at once, but you can write a blog post, or design a prototype, or contact 10 prospects.</p><p>In short, you need to&nbsp;<strong>break it down</strong>&nbsp;into pieces you are able to complete.</p><h3>How to break work down</h3><p>With mental work, it's often not obvious what all the things we need to do are.</p><p>We need to identify them, to list them.</p><p>If you need to create a presentation, you'll need to research the topic, find images, create the slides, and rehearse. Those are 4 distinct types of activity, 4 smaller pieces that you can take on, one by one.</p><p>When you break down work into parts, it becomes clearer what you feel you can or cannot do.</p><p><strong>Identify the distinct parts that form the whole.</strong></p><p>But even when you identify the parts, they can still intimidate you and seem too hard in their own right. What to do then?</p><p><strong>Create a simple timeline.</strong></p><p>We aren't naturally good at planning work through time. We don't look at a task like "Create a sales report" and see a detailed calendar in our heads with all the tasks neatly organized.</p><p>But we can learn to do that. How?</p><p>We just need a simple timeline.</p><p>It doesn't have to be complicated.</p><ol><li>Start with the due date.</li><li>Go back day by day (or week by week) and write down what you'd like to have done by then, until you arrive at today.</li><li>Put this timeline where you'll see it (remember: out of sight, out of mind).</li><li>Start working on the first piece of the puzzle.</li></ol><p>You might have a 20 slide presentation you'll be delivering 10 days from now.</p><p><em>Day 10</em>&nbsp;</p><ul><li>Rehearse 3x and deliver presentation</li></ul><p><em>Day 9</em></p><ul><li>Add finishing touches</li><li>List sources</li></ul><p>...</p><p><em>Day 5</em></p><ul><li>Create first 10 slides</li></ul><p><em>Day 3</em></p><ul><li>Write out the main points</li></ul><p><em>Day 2</em></p><ul><li>Read through the materials</li></ul><p><em>Day 1</em></p><ul><li>Make a list of at least 10 articles and other resources to use</li></ul><p>Even a simple, bulleted timeline like this can make a large project more manageable and ensure that you have the time to learn what you need to do to be able to accomplish your mission.</p><h2>Trigger X Procrastination</h2><img src="https://www.deprocrastination.co/assets/illustrations/fbm_no_trigger.png" alt="Fogg Behavior Model - no trigger"><p>And sometimes, we feel motivated and able, but we don't know where to start - we're missing a trigger.</p><p>Professional athletes have a coach. Coach is the person who says what to do, and when. Their job is about motivating, cultivating ability, and giving triggers.</p><p>Now do this, now that, now this here, now rest. There's a tight, minute-by-minute plan.</p><p>As a result, the athletes know exactly what to focus on at any given moment.</p><p>Unfortunately,&nbsp;<strong>modern work often doesn't have a built-in trigger.</strong></p><p>A professor doesn't tell you when to research, when to write an outline, when to start writing, when to stop writing, when to edit... there are no stopwatches, only vague directions and loooong time windows (days, weeks, months - not minutes).</p><p>As a result,&nbsp;<strong><em>we</em>&nbsp;have to make the decision to start—we have to trigger ourselves into action.</strong></p><p>In effect, we often leave the trigger to circumstance - we start working just before a deadline because we suddenly understand that if we don't start RIGHT NOW, we won't make it. Deadline becomes the only trigger we obey.</p><p>But that doesn't make for a consistent work ethic and healthy work-related confidence.</p><h2>How to add a trigger</h2><p>The key to an effective trigger is a sense of&nbsp;<em>I'm supposed to be doing this, right now.</em></p><p>The timeline exercise from the previous section can help with the first part - identifying a concrete task that will be triggered. However, a timeline doesn't provide us with a&nbsp;<em>cue.</em></p><p>We need to&nbsp;<strong>create a cue.</strong></p><p>One moment that can be used as a trigger is sitting down to work.&nbsp;<strong>When you sit down to work, you can take your to-do list and give yourself 5-15 minutes to decide which task to start with.</strong>&nbsp;If you don't know after the time has passed, pick one at random.<br>Cue #1: sitting down to work = time to find the first task.<br>Cue #2: time limit ends = time to work.</p><p>Another cue takes a little foresight and preparation.</p><p><strong>At the end of one work day, determine where you want to start the next day and put it into your calendar.</strong></p><p>Want to start writing a doc for your teammate? Put it on your calendar at 9–9:30AM, add a reminder and a link to the doc.</p><p>Want to start with a brainstorm? Take a sheet of paper, write the topic in its center, and put it on your desk so that it's the first thing you see tomorrow morning.</p><p>Want to start by looking up flights for a business trip? Download a picture of a plane and make it your wallpaper.</p><p>You can be as creative as you want, but the main point is this:<br><strong>define a specific task to do, at a specific place, at a specific moment in time - and make sure you can't miss the cue.</strong></p><img src="https://www.deprocrastination.co/assets/illustrations/fbm.png" alt="Fogg Behavior Model"><p>That's it.</p><p>Build up your motivation by reinforcing personal, meaningful reasons to do something.</p><p>Break down complex tasks into simple parts and plan them through time by creating a simple timeline.</p><p>And define a concrete trigger that will help you start your work.</p><br><hr><p><a href="https://www.deprocrastination.co/blog/how-to-stop-procrastinating-by-using-the-fogg-behavior-model-part-2">Read How to stop procrastinating by using the Fogg Behavior Model - Part 2 here</a></p></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.deprocrastination.co/blog/how-to-stop-procrastinating-by-using-the-fogg-behavior-model</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24120275</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 13:57:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[BuckleScript Is Rebranding]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 93 | Comments 60 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24119838">thread link</a>) | @yawaramin
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://reasonml.org/blog/bucklescript-is-rebranding | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://reasonml.org/blog/bucklescript-is-rebranding">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><h2><span><span><a href="#refactoring-our-brand"><svg height="0.8em" width="0.8em" viewBox="0 0 20.003 19.944"><path d="M11.927 7.908a4.819 4.819 0 00-3.968-1.3 5.091 5.091 0 00-2.921 1.508L1.47 11.684a4.82 4.82 0 00.192 7.122 4.994 4.994 0 006.76-.4l3.7-3.776a.109.109 0 00-.067-.184s-.649.029-1.132.006a10.116 10.116 0 01-1.35-.226.308.308 0 00-.243.088l-2.529 2.609a2.733 2.733 0 01-3.583.319 2.64 2.64 0 01-.247-3.951l3.755-3.753a2.7 2.7 0 013.654-.073.108.108 0 00.15 0l1.4-1.4a.114.114 0 00-.003-.157z"></path><path d="M8.076 12.036a4.822 4.822 0 003.967 1.3 5.089 5.089 0 002.922-1.509l3.568-3.568a4.818 4.818 0 00-.192-7.121 5 5 0 00-6.761.4l-3.7 3.777a.108.108 0 00.067.183s.648-.028 1.132-.006a10.151 10.151 0 011.35.226.3.3 0 00.243-.088l2.529-2.608a2.732 2.732 0 013.581-.319 2.638 2.638 0 01.249 3.95l-3.755 3.754a2.706 2.706 0 01-3.654.073.107.107 0 00-.15 0l-1.4 1.4a.113.113 0 00.004.156z"></path></svg></a><a id="refactoring-our-brand"></a></span></span>Refactoring our Brand</h2><p>We're pleased to announce that BuckleScript is getting a brand new name: <strong>ReScript</strong>.</p><p>BuckleScript started with the idea that programmers deserve a great typed language that compiles to fast and readable JavaScript. This idea took root and, over the years, we've gradually started tackling the surrounding challenges, such as:</p><ul><li><p>a fast and reliable build system much needed in front-end development, </p></li><li><p>various JS interop features that spawned an ecosystem of well typed libraries,</p></li><li><p>a production-ready standard library,</p></li><li><p>and recently, a fresh, solid syntax.</p></li></ul><p>These developments have attracted many people into our community. But one bigger challenge persisted: newcomers dropped out at the sheer amount of extra incongruent tools and learning overhead from having to understand OCaml concepts, Reason concepts, and BuckleScript's own concepts. Take, for example, what's required to make a ReasonReact app:</p><ul><li><p>Knowledge of React.</p></li><li><p>Knowledge of JS.</p></li><li><p>Knowledge of ReasonReact's specific idioms (that we've tried hard to keep to a minimum).</p></li><li><p>Knowledge of OCaml idioms, on top of which BuckleScript is built.</p></li><li><p>Knowledge of BuckleScript's JS interop and the build system.</p></li><li><p>Knowledge of the Reason syntax.</p></li></ul><p>Ironically, the more documentation we pile up, the more mental overhead newcomers suffered. During the various BuckleScript &amp; Reason meetups, we've frequently seen folks' enthusiasm crushed at the sheer prospect of making a web app while keeping 5+ tabs' worth of documentations open. This was discouraging, both for said eager developers and for us maintainers. </p><p>The adoption barrier is real, and it's about time we finally solve it.</p><p>Today, we'll start to truly unify the various BuckleScript-related projects under a single name: ReScript. This includes:</p><ul><li><p>The compiler, the build system and the syntax unified and shipping under a single install. Likewise for future efforts such as editor plugin.</p></li><li><p>A single documentation site which covers the above: <a href="https://rescript-lang.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer">rescript-lang.org</a>.</p></li><li><p>Streamlined communication through said website, a <a href="https://forum.rescript-lang.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer">new dedicated forum</a> and a new <a href="http://twitter.com/rescriptlang" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitter account</a>.</p></li><li><p>The renaming of various tools, always in a backward-compatible way.</p></li></ul><p>In short, all JS-related tools are now called ReScript. Previously, due to the messy situation, most real-world BuckleScript adoption came from a few heroic community members suffering through the technical and social risk of spreading our tech to their coworkers. From today onward, you can simply tell to your coworkers: "this is ReScript", and point to them a clear starting point instead of sending them to various incompatible sources, with a risk of losing goodwill and credibility.</p><p>It's worth emphasizing that while this rebranding seems to be very disruptive, in reality it's mostly a bunch of name changes for the same tech. To reiterate our stance on existing userland code:</p><ul><li><p>Please read our <a href="https://reasonml.org/blog/a-note-on-bucklescripts-future-commitments" rel="noopener noreferrer">previous post</a> on backward compatibility with pure OCaml &amp; Reason syntax.</p></li><li><p>The current Reason website will keep existing, with proper redirects to our new one when relevant. Existing Reason-to-JS users' code keep working, as per above post. Reason itself will continue tackling the parts BuckleScript didn't tackle before, such as native.</p></li><li><p>The various BuckleScript binaries will keep working. Instead of renaming those, we'd create new binaries instead.</p></li><li><p>The BuckleScript docs will redirect to the new site without breaking links.</p></li></ul><p>Thank you for your support and keep shipping. A brighter future awaits us!</p><p>Stay safe,</p><p>The ReScript team (Bob, Cheng, Cristiano, Maxim, Patrick, Ricky).</p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://reasonml.org/blog/bucklescript-is-rebranding</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24119838</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 13:03:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Mon Valley communities test “time credits”, a new form of currency]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 76 | Comments 78 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24119181">thread link</a>) | @tantalor
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://www.wesa.fm/post/while-investment-dollars-remain-scarce-mon-valley-communities-test-new-form-currency | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.wesa.fm/post/while-investment-dollars-remain-scarce-mon-valley-communities-test-new-form-currency">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div property="content:encoded"><div>   <div id="jp-interface--5f36d4c5dabdc">                            <p>90.5 WESA’s An-Li Herring reports that some local groups seek to establish an alternative currency so that neighborhoods in the Mon Valley can invest in themselves.</p>       </div> </div>  <p>Sitting in a grassy lot along Braddock’s main avenue, Jona Reyes dreams of restoring the energy that she says once coursed through the neighborhood. Since steel’s decline more than 30 years ago, the Mon Valley community has suffered from chronic disinvestment.</p>  <p>“When you look at what changed, it was the community aspect of it. It’s like, let’s get back to relying on one another and building up ourselves,” Reyes says as traffic rolls through Braddock’s commercial district, a sparse collection of businesses scattered among empty storefronts and vacant lots.</p>  <p>Reyes is the director of Neighbors Helping Neighbors, a grassroots group that links volunteers with people who need services such as a car ride or home repair. The goal, Reyes says, is to establish an “alternative economy.”</p> <div>   <div>     <p><a href="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/x_large/public/202008/IMG_6592.jpg">       <img src="https://www.wesa.fm/sites/wesa/files/styles/default/public/202008/IMG_6592.jpg" alt="As director of the grassroots group Neighbors Helping Neighbors, Jona Reyes has helped to build a network of about 200 residents who can offer and solicit services such as car rides or home repairs. The residents live in Braddock, North Braddock, and neighboring communities." data-interchange-default="https://www.wesa.fm/sites/wesa/files/styles/default/public/202008/IMG_6592.jpg" data-interchange-small="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/small/public/202008/IMG_6592.jpg" data-interchange-medium="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/medium/public/202008/IMG_6592.jpg" data-interchange-large="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/large/public/202008/IMG_6592.jpg">            </a></p>   </div> </div>   <p>“Our needs can be met, especially in low-income communities … if we lean on one another and look out for one another,” Reyes says.</p>  <p>Reyes’ group got a boost earlier this year from an organization called involveMINT. About five years ago, involveMINT developed a digital currency, called “time credits,” to share with people who invest their time in the community. The East Liberty-based venture initially focused its efforts in Pittsburgh’s Hazelwood neighborhood. But by working with Neighbors Helping Neighbors, the group hopes to begin circulating time credits in and around Braddock.</p>  <p>So far, involveMINT and Neighbors Helping Neighbors have enlisted about 10 local businesses to accept the credits as payment. While the units <a href="https://www.theselc.org/community-currencies-faq">are considered taxable earnings</a>, they reflect a deeper contribution to the community, said involveMINT executive director Dan Little.</p>  <p>“Money is scarce in the communities that arguably would need it most,”&nbsp; Little noted of the lack of funding in places like Braddock. “So the idea is [that] by having an alternative currency, you’re creating an alternative channel for commerce to happen, when that money is not available.”</p>  <div>   <div>     <p><a href="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/x_large/public/202008/IMG_6595.jpg">       <img src="https://www.wesa.fm/sites/wesa/files/styles/default/public/202008/IMG_6595.jpg" alt="Dan Little, executive director of involveMINT, began to develop time credits as an alternative form of currency in 2015. His organization first arranged a program in Hazelwood, where participants earn time credits for collecting food waste and turning it into compost. They can redeem the credits at Dylamato's Market in Hazelwood. " data-interchange-default="https://www.wesa.fm/sites/wesa/files/styles/default/public/202008/IMG_6595.jpg" data-interchange-small="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/small/public/202008/IMG_6595.jpg" data-interchange-medium="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/medium/public/202008/IMG_6595.jpg" data-interchange-large="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/large/public/202008/IMG_6595.jpg">            </a></p>   </div> </div>  <p>Communities <a href="https://ideas.ted.com/why-your-city-should-have-its-own-currency/">throughout the world</a> have established local currencies with varying levels of success. The idea <a href="https://www.forbes.com/2006/02/11/local-currencies-ithaca_cz_el_money06_0214local.html#eb379bf5b4cd">grew especially popular during the Great Depression</a>, when market failures dried up the supply of cash in circulation. Propronents say alternative currencies help to stimulate local economies by encouraging firms and residents to do business with others who participate in their community's homegrown currency system.</p>  <p>Little added that COVID-19, and the economic turmoil it has caused, further underscore the value of reducing communities’ reliance on dollars.</p>  <p>Although the federal government has <a href="https://www.irs.gov/coronavirus/economic-impact-payment-information-center#eligibility">distributed coronavirus stimulus payments to qualifying households</a>, Little noted, “for many people, that barely covers rent … And with local businesses, we know that they have seen a tremendous decrease in revenue.”</p>  <p>By using time credits created, or minted, by involveMINT, Little said, businesses can establish a new source of revenue, and use those funds to buy more supplies locally. Little noted that the coronavirus pandemic has revealed the fragility of global supply chains.</p>  <p>“[The new currency] may not be a panacea. It’s not going to pay for everything. But it’s going to get [users] some access to things that are local,” Little said.</p>  <p><strong>‘It will help to unify the community’</strong></p>  <p>COVID-19 prompted Neighbors Helping Neighbors and involveMINT to launch a grocery delivery service as one option for earning time credits. The program aims to help those who are vulnerable to the disease and, thus, should avoid stores.</p>  <p>Retiree Cynthia Underwood is one of several community members who have signed up to make deliveries. Her clients include seniors such as Myrtle Walker, who’s physically unable to go down stairs. In fact, when Underwood makes a delivery, the 72-year-old drops a key from her second-floor apartment window so that Underwood can let herself in.</p> <div>   <div>     <p><a href="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/x_large/public/202008/myrtle_walker_2.jpg">       <img src="https://www.wesa.fm/sites/wesa/files/styles/default/public/202008/myrtle_walker_2.jpg" alt="Braddock resident Myrtle Walker relies on an oxygen generator to manage her lung disease. Because her condition puts her at a heightened risk of succumbing to COVID-19, Walker no longer goes to the grocery store." data-interchange-default="https://www.wesa.fm/sites/wesa/files/styles/default/public/202008/myrtle_walker_2.jpg" data-interchange-small="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/small/public/202008/myrtle_walker_2.jpg" data-interchange-medium="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/medium/public/202008/myrtle_walker_2.jpg" data-interchange-large="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/large/public/202008/myrtle_walker_2.jpg">            </a></p>   </div> </div>   <p>Walker, who also suffers from lung disease, has not gone shopping since COVID-19 broke out in the U.S.</p>  <p>“I haven’t been in a store, I don’t think, for about maybe three, four months … So, I count on her,” Walker said of Underwood.</p>  <p>Underwood earns 15 time credits for every hour she spends making deliveries. Each unit is supposed to be worth a dollar. But for Underwood, a native of Rankin, the most important benefit is the possibility that participants will invest in each other.</p>  <p>“I think it will help to unify the community a little more and have people have a more vested interest in each other,” Underwood said.</p>  <div>   <div>     <p><a href="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/x_large/public/202008/IMG_6623.jpg">       <img src="https://www.wesa.fm/sites/wesa/files/styles/default/public/202008/IMG_6623.jpg" alt="Cynthia Underwood previously worked for the Internal Revenue Service, but now that she's retired, she volunteers frequently in Pittsburgh's east suburbs. She delivers groceries once or twice a week in exchange for time credits." data-interchange-default="https://www.wesa.fm/sites/wesa/files/styles/default/public/202008/IMG_6623.jpg" data-interchange-small="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/small/public/202008/IMG_6623.jpg" data-interchange-medium="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/medium/public/202008/IMG_6623.jpg" data-interchange-large="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/large/public/202008/IMG_6623.jpg">            </a></p>   </div> </div>  <p>Urban agriculture nonprofit Grow Pittsburgh found similar reasons to accept time credits at its produce stand in Braddock for similar reasons. Grow Pittsburgh’s director of farm education, Denele Hughson, said time credits are rooted in the same philosophy as her organization, which strives to empower communities like Braddock to draw on existing assets to cultivate their own food economies.</p>  <p>Hughson noted that her organization can use the time credits to buy compost from the local company Worm Return. And she said Grow Pittsburgh will use the units to pay for a few additional hours of work at its urban farm.</p>  <p>“Someone who’s just looking to volunteer for a few hours a week, and in exchange for that they actually get something tangible that they can use it on&nbsp;– I think that would be amazing,” Hughson said.</p>  <p><strong>‘Funny money?’</strong></p> <p>The success of any currency, including the dollar, depends on whether people trust it. And whether they trust it depends on how much they see others use it.</p>  <p>Circulation has been a challenge for local currencies elsewhere. In Ithaca, N.Y., for example, a currency called Ithaca HOURS went defunct after about two decades. Erik Lehmann was the last person to chair the Ithaca HOURS board.</p>  <p>“Towards the end, it was basically like a coupon,” he said of the HOURS. “It wasn’t a full currency. Most vendors that accepted it didn’t accept it at full face value.”</p> <div>   <div>     <p><a href="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/x_large/public/202008/grow_pittsburgh_farm_stand.jpg">       <img src="https://www.wesa.fm/sites/wesa/files/styles/default/public/202008/grow_pittsburgh_farm_stand.jpg" alt="Grow Pittsburgh is one of about 10 local organizations that have agreed to accept time credits as payment. The urban agriculture nonprofit operates a farm and produce stand in Braddock." data-interchange-default="https://www.wesa.fm/sites/wesa/files/styles/default/public/202008/grow_pittsburgh_farm_stand.jpg" data-interchange-small="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/small/public/202008/grow_pittsburgh_farm_stand.jpg" data-interchange-medium="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/medium/public/202008/grow_pittsburgh_farm_stand.jpg" data-interchange-large="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/large/public/202008/grow_pittsburgh_farm_stand.jpg">            </a></p>   </div> </div>   <p>Lehmann said there were not enough ways in Ithaca to redeem the alternative currency. While at one time about 300 businesses had signed up to accept the HOURS, Lehamann said, “There weren’t the Wegman’s and the big banks and the big landlords."</p>  <p>In Philadelphia, a local currency called Equal Dollars <a href="https://generocity.org/philly/2014/07/14/equal-dollars-alternative-currency-out-of-circulation-after-19-years/">faced a similar hurdle</a>, though it too had been in circulation for about 20 years. Former Equal Dollars director Deneene Brockington said, because most businesses had nowhere to spend Equal Dollars, they simply donated them to charities of their choosing.</p>  <p>“That kind of resonated with some people and some local businesses: They got to participate in something local and then donate to a community organization that then was able to use those dollars as a way to thank their people for community service,” Brockington said.</p>  <p>Equal Dollars ultimately dissolved in 2014 because, Brockington said, the nonprofit that ran it, Resources for Human Development, decided to stop funding the program. Brockington noted that staffers like her, who managed the Equal Dollars program, still needed to be paid in U.S. dollars. After all, they couldn't use alternative currency to pay their bills.</p>  <p>Scott Morris, who is leading an effort to launch a new currency in Ithaca, called Ithacash, has also struggled to secure funding for personnel. He said it's a necessary expense, to ensure that professionals can educate people and businesses on how to use the units, recruit more participants into the network, and manage the complexities associated with sustaining that network.</p>  <p>"The business model has never been easy to deal with because it’s like, ‘Look, we’re making our own money, and so you should pay us some regular money for it.’ And [potential funders] are just going to be like, ‘Well, this is the real money. Why do you want my real money for your funny money?’” Morris said.</p>  <div>   <div>     <p><a href="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/x_large/public/202008/IMG_6601.jpg">       <img src="https://www.wesa.fm/sites/wesa/files/styles/default/public/202008/IMG_6601.jpg" alt="Neighbors Helping Neighbors and involveMINT receive some donations for their grocery delivery service from Dorothy Gey's food distribution site in Braddock. Gey receives contributions from 412 Food Rescue, Gordon Food Service, and local food pantries." data-interchange-default="https://www.wesa.fm/sites/wesa/files/styles/default/public/202008/IMG_6601.jpg" data-interchange-small="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/small/public/202008/IMG_6601.jpg" data-interchange-medium="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/medium/public/202008/IMG_6601.jpg" data-interchange-large="https://mediad.publicbroadcasting.net/p/wesa/files/styles/large/public/202008/IMG_6601.jpg">            </a></p>   </div> </div>  <p>But Morris noted that mainstream investors have <a href="https://www.marketplace.org/2020/08/03/sustainable-investing-esg-covid-19-social-environmental-causes/">grown increasingly conscious of the social and environmental impacts of their contributions investments</a>, and that COVID-19 has shaken people’s confidence in traditional markets.</p>  <p>“Now, I think we’re at the point … where we can make a very solid business case for why these [local currency models] are worth paying regular money for,” he said.</p>  <p>In Pittsburgh, involveMINT’s Dan Little said his bottom line is whether the communities that use his organization's time credits gain the resources they need to invest in themselves.</p>  <p>Considering the market hasn't addressed this need, Little said, the credits' fate is “almost in some ways about survival. It’s like … let’s see what the community can do to help itself.”</p> </div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.wesa.fm/post/while-investment-dollars-remain-scarce-mon-valley-communities-test-new-form-currency</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24119181</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 11:21:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Creating a QR Code step by step]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 301 | Comments 39 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24119124">thread link</a>) | @creolabs
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://www.nayuki.io/page/creating-a-qr-code-step-by-step | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.nayuki.io/page/creating-a-qr-code-step-by-step">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>

<p>This JavaScript demo application visualizes in detailed steps, how a text string is encoded into a QR Code barcode symbol. The content of this page essentially explains and justifies how my <a href="https://www.nayuki.io/page/qr-code-generator-library">QR Code generator library</a> works internally.</p>

<h2>User input</h2>


<h2>QR Code output</h2>
<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" version="1.1" id="output-qr-code"></svg>
<hr>

<h2>Step-by-step process</h2>
<p id="show-hide-steps">Show/hide each step: </p>
<section>
	<h3>0. Analyze Unicode characters</h3>
	<p>Number of code points in the input text string: <span id="num-code-points"></span></p>
	<p>Details of each character:</p>
	<table id="character-analysis">
		<thead>
			<tr>
				<th><abbr title="Index in input string">Index</abbr></th>
				<th><abbr title="The character itself">Char</abbr></th>
				<th><abbr title="Unicode code point value in hexadecimal">CP hex</abbr></th>
				<th><abbr title="Encodable in numeric mode">NM</abbr></th>
				<th><abbr title="Encodable in alphanumeric mode">AM</abbr></th>
				<th><abbr title="Encodable in byte mode">BM</abbr></th>
				<th><abbr title="Encodable in kanji mode">KM</abbr></th>
			</tr>
		</thead>
		<tbody></tbody>
	</table>
	<p>Can every character be encoded in:</p>
	<table id="character-mode-summary">
		<thead>
			<tr>
				<th>Mode</th>
				<th>Encodable</th>
			</tr>
		</thead>
		<tbody></tbody>
	</table>
	<p>Chosen segment mode to encode all characters: <span id="chosen-segment-mode"></span></p>
</section>

<section>
	<h3>1. Create data segment</h3>
	<p>Convert each character to bits. For numeric and alphanumeric modes, consecutive characters are grouped together before being encoded into bits. For byte mode, a character produces either 8, 16, 24, or 32 bits.</p>
	<table id="data-segment-chars">
		<thead>
			<tr>
				<th>Index</th>
				<th>Char</th>
				<th>Values (hex)</th>
				<th>Value</th>
				<th>Combined</th>
				<th>Bits</th>
			</tr>
		</thead>
		<tbody></tbody>
	</table>
	<p>The created single segment:</p>
	<ul>
		<li>Mode: <span id="segment-mode"></span></li>
		<li>Count: <span id="segment-count"></span></li>
		<li>Data: <span id="segment-data"></span></li>
	</ul>
	<p>(This demo program always creates a single segment for simplicity. But it is possible to <a href="https://www.nayuki.io/page/optimal-text-segmentation-for-qr-codes">segment the text optimally</a> to minimize the total bit length.)</p>
</section>

<section>
	<h3>2. Fit to version number</h3>
	<p>Total bit length needed to represent the list of segments, depending on version:</p>
	<table id="segment-size">
		<thead>
			<tr>
				<th>Range</th>
				<th>Num bits</th>
				<th>Num codewords</th>
			</tr>
		</thead>
		<tbody>
			<tr>
				<td>Version 1 ~ 9</td>
				<td></td>
				<td></td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Version 10 ~ 26</td>
				<td></td>
				<td></td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Version 27 ~ 40</td>
				<td></td>
				<td></td>
			</tr>
		</tbody>
	</table>
	<p>(Note: A codeword is defined as 8 bits, also known as a byte.)</p>
	<p>QR Code capacity of data codewords per version and error correction level, and whether the data fits:</p>
	<table id="codewords-per-version">
		<thead>
			<tr>
				<th>Version</th>
				<th>ECC <abbr title="low">L</abbr></th>
				<th>ECC <abbr title="medium">M</abbr></th>
				<th>ECC <abbr title="quartile">Q</abbr></th>
				<th>ECC <abbr title="high">H</abbr></th>
			</tr>
		</thead>
		<tbody></tbody>
	</table>
	<p>Chosen version number: <span id="chosen-version"></span></p>
</section>

<section>
	<h3>3. Concatenate segments, add padding, make codewords</h3>
	<p>Join a variety of bit strings together:</p>
	<table id="segment-and-padding-bits">
		<thead>
			<tr>
				<th>Item</th>
				<th>Bit data</th>
				<th><abbr title="Number of">Num</abbr> bits</th>
				<th><abbr title="Cumulative number of">Sum</abbr> bits</th>
			</tr>
		</thead>
		<tbody></tbody>
	</table>
	<p>Notes:</p>
	<ul>
		<li><p>The segment mode is always a 4-bit field.</p></li>
		<li><p>The character count’s field width depends on the mode and version.</p></li>
		<li><p>The terminator is normally four “0” bits, but fewer if the data codeword capacity is reached.</p></li>
		<li><p>The bit padding is between zero to seven “0” bits, to fill all unused bits in the last byte.</p></li>
		<li><p>The byte padding consists of alternating hex <span>EC</span> and <span>11</span> until the capacity is reached.</p></li>
	</ul>
	<p id="full-bitstream">The entire sequence of data bits: <span></span></p>
	<p>The entire sequence of data codeword bytes (by splitting the bit stream 8 bits at a time) (displayed in hexadecimal): <span id="all-data-codewords"></span></p>
</section>

<section>
	<h3>4. Split blocks, add ECC, interleave</h3>
	<p>Statistics about all blocks:</p>
	<table id="block-stats">
		<tbody>
			<tr><td>Number of data codewords:      </td><td></td></tr>
			<tr><td>Number of blocks:              </td><td></td></tr>
			<tr><td>Data codewords per short block:</td><td></td></tr>
			<tr><td>Data codewords per long block: </td><td></td></tr>
			<tr><td>ECC codewords per any block:   </td><td></td></tr>
			<tr><td>Number of short blocks:        </td><td></td></tr>
			<tr><td>Number of long blocks:         </td><td></td></tr>
		</tbody>
	</table>
	<p>Split the sequence of data codewords (green) into short and long blocks; then for each block, compute the ECC codewords (blue) and append them to the end of the block:</p>
	<table id="blocks-and-ecc">
		<thead>
			<tr>
				<th rowspan="2" colspan="2"></th>
				<th>Block index</th>
			</tr>
		</thead>
		<tbody></tbody>
	</table>
	<p>(Note: The math behind computing the Reed-Solomon error correction codes is omitted because it is long, tedious, and not very interesting.)</p>
	<p>The final sequence of codewords formed by interleaving data/ECC codewords from different blocks: <span id="interleaved-codewords"></span></p>
	<p id="final-bit-sequence">The final sequence of bits to draw in the zig-zag scan: <span></span></p>
</section>

<section>
	<h3>5. Draw fixed patterns</h3>
	<p>Draw the horizontal and vertical <strong>timing patterns</strong> (on both row 6 and column 6, counting from 0 starting at the top left corner):</p>
	<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" version="1.1" id="timing-patterns"></svg>
	<p>Draw the 7×7 <strong>finder patterns</strong> on the three corners and 1-module separators (which overwrites some timing modules):</p>
	<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" version="1.1" id="finder-patterns"></svg>
	<div id="alignment-patterns-container">
		<p>Draw the grid of 5×5 <strong>alignment patterns</strong> (but skipping the three finder corners):</p>
		<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" version="1.1" id="alignment-patterns"></svg>
	</div>
	<p>Draw temporary dummy <strong>format bits</strong> (adjacent to the finders):</p>
	<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" version="1.1" id="dummy-format-bits"></svg>
	<div id="version-information-container">
		<p>Draw the two 6×3 <strong>version information</strong> blocks (adjacent to the finders):</p>
		<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" version="1.1" id="version-information"></svg>
	</div>
</section>

<section>
	<h3>6. Draw codewords and remainder</h3>
	<p>Compute the zig-zag scan (which starts from the bottom right corner) to visit all unfilled modules (i.e. skipping function modules):</p>
	<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" version="1.1" id="zig-zag-scan"></svg>
	<p>Draw data/ECC modules according to the zig-zag scan order and bit values from the final sequence of codewords:</p>
	<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" version="1.1" id="codewords-and-remainder"></svg>
	<p>(For example, the codeword byte <span>C5</span> produces the sequence of modules [black, black, white, white, white, black, white, black].)</p>
</section>

<section>
	<h3>7. Try applying each mask</h3>
	<p>Show:
		
	</p>
	<p>The <strong>mask pattern</strong> (only affects non-function modules):</p>
	<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" version="1.1" id="mask-pattern"></svg>
	<p><strong>XOR the mask</strong> to the modules of data, ECC, and remainder:</p>
	<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" version="1.1" id="masked-qr-code"></svg>
	<p>Draw the actual <strong>format bits</strong> (adjacent to the finders):</p>
	<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" version="1.1" id="masked-qr-with-format"></svg>
</section>

<section>
	<h3>8. Find penalty patterns</h3>
	<p>Horizontal runs of same color modules (each at least 5 long):</p>
	<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" version="1.1" id="horizontal-runs"></svg>
	<p>Vertical runs of same color modules (each at least 5 long):</p>
	<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" version="1.1" id="vertical-runs"></svg>
	<p>2×2 boxes of same color modules:</p>
	<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" version="1.1" id="two-by-two-boxes"></svg>
	<p>Horizontal finder-like patterns:</p>
	<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" version="1.1" id="horizontal-false-finders"></svg>
	<p>Vertical finder-like patterns:</p>
	<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" version="1.1" id="vertical-false-finders"></svg>
	<p>Balance of black/white modules:</p>
	<table id="black-white-balance">
		<tbody>
			<tr><td>Side length:        </td><td></td></tr>
			<tr><td>Total modules:      </td><td></td></tr>
			<tr><td>White modules:      </td><td></td></tr>
			<tr><td>Black modules:      </td><td></td></tr>
			<tr><td>Proportion black:   </td><td></td></tr>
			<tr><td>Deviation from half:</td><td></td></tr>
		</tbody>
	</table>
</section>

<section>
	<h3>9. Calculate penalty points, select best mask</h3>
	<table>
		<thead>
			<tr>
				<th><abbr title="Mask pattern number">Mask</abbr></th>
				<th><abbr title="Linear same-color run penalty points">RunP</abbr></th>
				<th><abbr title="2×2 same-color box penalty points">BoxP</abbr></th>
				<th><abbr title="Finder-like pattern penalty points">FindP</abbr></th>
				<th><abbr title="Black/white balance penalty points">BalP</abbr></th>
				<th><abbr title="Total penalty points">TotalP</abbr></th>
			</tr>
		</thead>
		<tbody id="select-best-mask"></tbody>
	</table>
	<p>Lowest total penalty points: Mask pattern <span id="lowest-penalty-mask"></span></p>
	<p>How penalties are calculated:</p>
	<ul>
		<li><p>RunP: 3 points for each 5-module linear run of the same color, 4 points for each 6-module run, 5 points for each 7-module run, 6 points for each 8-module run, etc. Runs cannot overlap.</p></li>
		<li><p>BoxP: 3 points for each 2×2 box of the same color. Boxes can overlap.</p></li>
		<li><p>FindP: 40 points for each finder-like pattern. Finder patterns can overlap.</p></li>
		<li><p>BalP: 0 points if the proportion of black modules is in the range [45%, 55%]; 10 points if within [40%, 60%]; 20 points if within [35%, 65%]; 30 points if within [30%, 70%]; etc.</p></li>
	</ul>
</section>


<hr>
<p>This web application’s source TypeScript code (<a href="https://www.nayuki.io/res/creating-a-qr-code-step-by-step/creating-qr-code-steps.ts">file 0</a>, <a href="https://www.nayuki.io/res/creating-a-qr-code-step-by-step/instrumented-qrcodegen.ts">file 1</a>) and <a href="https://www.nayuki.io/res/creating-a-qr-code-step-by-step/creating-qr-code-steps.js">compiled JavaScript code</a> are available for viewing.</p>

<h2>More info</h2>
<ul>
	<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/QR_code#Design">Wikipedia: QR code - Design</a></li>
	<li><a href="https://www.thonky.com/qr-code-tutorial/">Thonky.com: QR Code Tutorial</a></li>
	<li><a href="https://research.swtch.com/qart">research!rsc (Russ Cox): QArt Codes</a></li>
</ul>

</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.nayuki.io/page/creating-a-qr-code-step-by-step</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24119124</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 11:10:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Keyboard with Blank Keycaps Made Me an Expert Typist]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 44 | Comments 103 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24119122">thread link</a>) | @bojanvidanovic
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://bojanvidanovic.com/posts/a-keyboard-with-blank-keycaps-made-me-an-expert-typist | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bojanvidanovic.com/posts/a-keyboard-with-blank-keycaps-made-me-an-expert-typist">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>If you are someone like me who spends hours and hours a day typing then you
might be interested in investing in learning how to properly type, more
precisely on learning how to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Touch_typing">touch-type</a>.
My story begins 2 years ago when I saw one person typing so fluently and elegantly with almost no effort, focusing on
the result and not the process that it triggered in me to start noting how
badly I was typing and how badly many others were typing.</p>
<p>The problem is that almost all people are a self-taught typist and everyone
with their technique, this technique is usually correlated with inefficiency,
and sometimes speed. I saw many people typing very fast with only 4 fingers, which
in result makes more noise by jumping from one letter to another very fast but
on that particular keyboard, on another keyboard they would struggle because
the muscle memory doesn’t recognize a different keyboard. And it makes so much
harder improving the speed when not using all of your fingers.</p>
<p>I had the same problem as the majority of people, and I wasn’t recognizing it.
For years I would use 4-6 fingers and always from time to time I would
take a look at the keyboard for a specific character or a letter. The right
hand would type the keys on the left side and opposite. That was my typing
technique.</p>
<p>So I started doing some research and got to know better how touch-typing works.
Luckily the web is full of touch-typing resources and training websites, that
I settled for <a href="https://www.typingclub.com/">TypingClub</a>. The website is full of exercises and statistics
on your writing progress in beautiful UI that it satisfies all of my nerdy
requirements, and it’s completely free or supports the services and get some
additional features with as little as 7.50 euros a month.</p>
<p><img data-srcset="https://res.cloudinary.com/bojan/image/upload/w_480,q_auto,f_auto//v1597142168/0_gtN8lOemEF_7I5bb_yinkzd.png 480w,
                  https://res.cloudinary.com/bojan/image/upload/w_640,q_auto,f_auto//v1597142168/0_gtN8lOemEF_7I5bb_yinkzd.png 640w,
                  https://res.cloudinary.com/bojan/image/upload/w_960,q_auto,f_auto//v1597142168/0_gtN8lOemEF_7I5bb_yinkzd.png 960w,
                  https://res.cloudinary.com/bojan/image/upload/w_1280,q_auto,f_auto//v1597142168/0_gtN8lOemEF_7I5bb_yinkzd.png 1280w" data-sizes="auto" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/bojan/image/upload/c_scale,e_blur:250,f_auto,q_auto:low,w_42//v1597142168/0_gtN8lOemEF_7I5bb_yinkzd.png" alt="touch-type fingers" srcset="https://res.cloudinary.com/bojan/image/upload/w_480,q_auto,f_auto//v1597142168/0_gtN8lOemEF_7I5bb_yinkzd.png 480w,
                  https://res.cloudinary.com/bojan/image/upload/w_640,q_auto,f_auto//v1597142168/0_gtN8lOemEF_7I5bb_yinkzd.png 640w,
                  https://res.cloudinary.com/bojan/image/upload/w_960,q_auto,f_auto//v1597142168/0_gtN8lOemEF_7I5bb_yinkzd.png 960w,
                  https://res.cloudinary.com/bojan/image/upload/w_1280,q_auto,f_auto//v1597142168/0_gtN8lOemEF_7I5bb_yinkzd.png 1280w"></p><p>Doing the research and signing up for the website was the easy part, the hard
part was creating a practicing routing and trying to touch-type as much as
possible. That is easier said than done. The beggining was painful, I was slow at
work and I was wasting a lot of my concentration on typing. My fingers were
feeling tired and sometimes in pain, they have never done anything like that.
Changing the muscle memory and rewiring my brain after many years to something
almost unknown was getting into my way.</p>
<p>So I decided to make a switch from an <a href="https://amzn.to/31H9Qgc">Apple keyboard</a> to a mechanical keyboard.
And I got the idea that if I get a keyboard with the blank keycaps I would be
obligated to learn to touch-type and forget about looking at the keyboard. The
idea was promising but also scary for the scenarios like typing a password,
typing with one hand.. so again I did some research! And many people confirmed
my idea and I decided to follow it.</p>
<p>Finding a good keyboard that would last and endure a lot typing was my initial
idea, but there aren’t many keyboards with blank keycaps unless you customize
it. So the list came down to these candidates:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/3acp0On">Das Keyboard 4</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/3kBK9WP">Filco Ninja Majestouch-2</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2XQ3Mkj">Happy Hacking Keyboard (HHKB) Professional2</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Filco keyboard is a little different than the other two, by having the keycaps
printed on the bottom side instead on top. This would work better in cases like
typing a password or typing anything with one hand. For someone who doesn’t
want to go extreme this is a good solution.</p>
<p>All of these keyboards are exceptionally good, but having already had
experience with MX Cherry switches, I decided to give a try to Topre
switches with an HHKB. It’s more Vim-style orianted by having no arrow keys
with a clean and minimal design.</p>
<p><img data-srcset="https://res.cloudinary.com/bojan/image/upload/w_480,q_auto,f_auto//v1597142565/IMG_4062_rirfiv.jpg 480w,
                  https://res.cloudinary.com/bojan/image/upload/w_640,q_auto,f_auto//v1597142565/IMG_4062_rirfiv.jpg 640w,
                  https://res.cloudinary.com/bojan/image/upload/w_960,q_auto,f_auto//v1597142565/IMG_4062_rirfiv.jpg 960w,
                  https://res.cloudinary.com/bojan/image/upload/w_1280,q_auto,f_auto//v1597142565/IMG_4062_rirfiv.jpg 1280w" data-sizes="auto" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/bojan/image/upload/c_scale,e_blur:250,f_auto,q_auto:low,w_42//v1597142565/IMG_4062_rirfiv.jpg" alt="Happy Hacking Keyboard" srcset="https://res.cloudinary.com/bojan/image/upload/w_480,q_auto,f_auto//v1597142565/IMG_4062_rirfiv.jpg 480w,
                  https://res.cloudinary.com/bojan/image/upload/w_640,q_auto,f_auto//v1597142565/IMG_4062_rirfiv.jpg 640w,
                  https://res.cloudinary.com/bojan/image/upload/w_960,q_auto,f_auto//v1597142565/IMG_4062_rirfiv.jpg 960w,
                  https://res.cloudinary.com/bojan/image/upload/w_1280,q_auto,f_auto//v1597142565/IMG_4062_rirfiv.jpg 1280w"></p><p>After purchasing the new keyboard there was no going back, I had the tool
and the school to deep dive into this. At the begging I was struggling, but
a keyboard like this pushes you to learn a proper fingers placement on the
home row and unlink all the habits of looking down for a key. It took time
and a lot of practice but it paid off. Today I type comfortably on a blank
keyboard with the average speed of 70-90 wpm and I’m still improving. It is
a huge productivity boost.</p>
<section id="mc_embed_signup">

</section>
<section>
<img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/bojan/image/twitter_name/w_100,h_100,c_fill,r_max/bojan_vidanovic.jpg" width="100" height="100">

</section>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bojanvidanovic.com/posts/a-keyboard-with-blank-keycaps-made-me-an-expert-typist</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24119122</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 11:09:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[JuliaDB]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 198 | Comments 52 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24119118">thread link</a>) | @dunefox
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://juliadata.github.io/JuliaDB.jl/latest/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://juliadata.github.io/JuliaDB.jl/latest/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="docs"><header><nav><ul><li><a href="">Overview</a></li></ul><a href="https://github.com/JuliaComputing/JuliaDB.jl/blob/master/docs/src/index.md"><span></span> Edit on GitHub</a></nav><hr><p><span>Overview</span><a href="#"></a></p></header><center>
<img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/25916/36773410-843e61b0-1c7f-11e8-818b-3edb08da8f41.png" width="200">
</center><p><strong>JuliaDB is a package for working with persistent data sets.</strong></p><p>We recognized the need for an all-Julia, end-to-end tool that can</p><ol><li>Load multi-dimensional datasets quickly and incrementally.</li><li>Index the data and perform filter, aggregate, sort and join operations.</li><li>Save results and load them efficiently later.</li><li>Readily use Julia's built-in <a href="https://docs.julialang.org/en/v1/manual/parallel-computing/">parallelism</a> to fully utilize any machine or cluster.</li></ol><p>We built JuliaDB to fill this void.</p><p>JuliaDB provides distributed table and array datastructures with convenient functions to load data from CSV. JuliaDB is Julia all the way down. This means queries can be composed with Julia code that may use a vast ecosystem of packages.</p><h2><a id="Quickstart-1" href="#Quickstart-1">Quickstart</a></h2><pre><code>using Pkg
Pkg.add("JuliaDB")

using JuliaDB

# Create a table where the first column is the "primary key"
t = table(rand(Bool, 10), rand(10), pkey=1)</code></pre><h2><a id="Parallelism-1" href="#Parallelism-1">Parallelism</a></h2><p>The parallel/distributed features of JuliaDB are available by either:</p><ol><li>Starting Julia with <code>N</code> workers: <code>julia -p N</code></li><li>Calling <code>addprocs(N)</code> before <code>using JuliaDB</code></li></ol><div><p>Note</p><p>Multiple processes may not be beneficial for datasets with less than a few million rows.</p></div><h2><a id="Additional-Resources-1" href="#Additional-Resources-1">Additional Resources</a></h2><ul><li><a href="https://julialang.slack.com/messages/C86LDBEBD/">#juliadb Channel in the JuliaLang Slack</a></li><li><a href="https://discourse.julialang.org/">JuliaLang Discourse</a></li><li><a href="https://github.com/JuliaComputing/JuliaDB.jl/issues">Issue Tracker</a></li></ul></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://juliadata.github.io/JuliaDB.jl/latest/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24119118</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 11:09:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I accidentally built a nudity/porn platform]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 458 | Comments 315 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24119024">thread link</a>) | @elazzabi_
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://elazzabi.com/2020/08/11/the-day-i-accidentally-built-a-nudity-porn-platform/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://elazzabi.com/2020/08/11/the-day-i-accidentally-built-a-nudity-porn-platform/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>I didn’t know that my next project will turn into a nudity platform and a home for spammers. But it did happen while I wasn’t paying attention. And here are the details.</p>



<p>For the next 5/10 years, I’ve decided that my mission will be: “<strong>Can a Moroccan build an online business and make a living from Morocco?</strong>“. I currently launch multiple projects and give them some time to take off. My blog <a href="https://remote.ma/">remote.ma</a>, my jobs board <a href="https://okjob.io/">okjob.io</a>, and other projects are all examples of this. The project I’m talking about today, was also serving the same purpose in theory, but it was a flop.</p>



<p>That project is <a href="https://mylink.fyi/">mylink.fyi</a>, a personal and unique link for all your other links. I built it during my weekends given I already have a full-time job and it took me two months approximately. It’s like <a href="https://linktr.ee/">linktree</a> and other competitors, but I tried to make it different. No ads, no logo, a clean interface, a 100% score in performance… My idea was: take a competitor product, remove all features you don’t need, and make it crazy fast. You have a 14 days free trial to test it out, but you need to upgrade your account afterwards.</p>



<p>I launched it in February 2020 with a completely different identity. I took my name, and thus my followers and my authority, out of the equation. <strong>I wanted to replicate “someone starting from scratch” as close as possible</strong>. I did use the service for my links (and <a href="https://remote.ma/">remote.ma</a>‘s links) but I never advertised the service on my personal account. You can see the <a href="https://www.producthunt.com/posts/mylink-fyi">Product Hunt</a> launch, and the imaginary <a href="https://twitter.com/HamidNekcha">Twitter account</a> I created.</p>



<p>Given how I built the app, I optimized it in a way I’ll only pay hosting fees when the site is having a lot of traffic. Like 1M+ visits per month. So I forgot about it, and kept an eye on the bills I get. Two weeks after launch, I had 100 users. No premium account.</p>



<p>Three months went by with 0$ bills. But in June, I received <strong>my non-zero bill</strong>, it’s exciting the app is taking off! I logged to Firebase (the infrastructure I’m using) and found a total of 1000 users! Wow, that’s a lot.</p>



<p>I took a look at the emails, and quickly saw that something was off. I’ve seen multiple accounts with the same email structure, something like emily123@gmail.com, emily456@gmail.com… I knew something isn’t right given there is a lot of them. So I decided to take a closer look and see the links they are sharing.</p>



<p>That’s when I discovered <strong>they were sharing porn and nudes links</strong>. These links aren’t permitted on social media, so they used mylink.fyi to “shadow” them. For these platforms, they are mylink.fyi links. But once you visit it, you’ll see a link for the banned site. <strong>There were hundreds of accounts doing this</strong>. And new ones get created every day. Once the trial period is over, they create a new email, a new account, and then repeat the same process. Oups!</p>



<p>I decided to remove all my links from the platform given it’s probably known for “porn and nudes” now. I logged to Instagram, and got a weird message: “<strong>Your profile link is not working</strong>“. I didn’t know what that means, but once I visited my profile, I’ve seen I can’t click on the mylink.fyi link. Wow, what’s that? I visited my other profile, and got the same message and the same problem! I later discovered that Instagram banned all mylink.fyi links from the platform. A customer also confirmed to me via email that Snapchat started blocking links. Heh, I’m banned by Instagram and Snapchat! From all scenarios I had in mind, <strong>this is not something I prepared for</strong>.</p>



<p>The first thing I tried is reducing the trial period from 14 days to 5 days. I was hoping I’ll make them stop. But nothing changed, I can’t outplay them. Damn it! Other solutions include: requiring credit cards for trial periods, ban all adult content from the platform… But they all require me to put extra effort in the project. And I don’t have time for that.</p>



<p>I disabled signups on mylink.fyi for now, and after all trials reach their end, I’ll take the service off. If you’re interested in acquiring the domain name, and/or the app, <a href="https://elazzabi.com/contact/">let’s talk</a>.</p>



<p><strong>That’s it for your daily dose of weird Internet anecdotes.</strong></p>



<p>If you’re interested in stories about building online products and businesses, follow me on <strong><a href="https://twitter.com/elazzabi_">Twitter</a></strong>, or consider joining my mailing list 🙂</p>



<p><em>Do not miss my next post! Drop your email in the box below and get it straight to your inbox</em>:</p>




	</div><div>
			<div>
				<p><img alt="" src="https://0.gravatar.com/avatar/998c72cb6049caeefc3a976a96bf3e6b?s=80&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" height="80" width="80">		</p><!-- .author-avatar -->
		
		<p>
			<h2>Published by <span>Ahmed</span></h2>
		</p><!-- .author-heading -->

		<p>
			Howdy 👋,

I’m Ahmed from Morocco and I build things using code, a.k.a a Software Engineer.

I hold an electrical engineering degree and I’m a self taught software developer. I figured out my love for building things when I started my first online business at the age of 17.

I blog at elazzabi.com and remote.ma.			<a href="https://elazzabi.com/author/elazzabiahmed/" rel="author">
				View all posts by Ahmed			</a>
		</p><!-- .author-bio -->
	</div><!-- .entry-auhtor -->
		<p><strong>Published</strong>
			<time datetime="2020-08-11T10:41:28+00:00">August 11, 2020</time><time datetime="2020-08-11T17:31:14+00:00">August 11, 2020</time>		</p><!-- .site-posted-on -->
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://elazzabi.com/2020/08/11/the-day-i-accidentally-built-a-nudity-porn-platform/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24119024</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 10:47:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Predictions as a Substitute for Reviews]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 53 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24118052">thread link</a>) | @luu
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://acesounderglass.com/2020/08/06/predictions-as-a-substitute-for-reviews/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://acesounderglass.com/2020/08/06/predictions-as-a-substitute-for-reviews/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-11130">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	
	
	<div>
		<h3>Introduction</h3>
<p dir="ltr">There is a lot of praise for weekly reviews. There is noticeably less doing of weekly reviews, even among the people doing the praising. It’s a very hard habit to keep up. We could spend a lot of time diving into why that is and how to fix it in a systematic way… or I could tell you how I use <a href="https://predictionbook.com/">PredictionBook</a> to get many of the promised benefits of weekly reviews without any willpower.</p>
<p dir="ltr">In a nutshell, when I find myself making a choice about how to spend time or money that’s dependent on some expectation, I write out the expectation as a prediction (with % likelihood) in PredictionBook, which then automatically prompts me to evaluate the prediction at a date I set. This has so many benefits I’m struggling to figure out where to start. If I had to sum them up in a phrase, it would be “more contact with reality”. But to expand on that…</p>

<figure><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/Q0ozB77P5ESZiGHUbcOOwEKmLkOnfe6DrHZJsRiJyWH8izn9qVWP2qO1dqem9SQO5si1RFMZ8UjhfGFKSqJkg8zcjvuo4g5_agcJ9Z610wSw-8WxabmUknYTMaXcEylDiS9WJL3Z" width="286" height="190"><figcaption>What contact with reality may look like</figcaption></figure>

<h3>Benefits</h3>
<p dir="ltr">Making the prediction forces me to assess my anticipated outcomes and do an expected value calculation. This in turn forces me to be explicit about what I value, and how I will know if I got it. It also makes it explicit when I’m doing something because I expect the median or modal outcome to be good, vs. when I’m doing it for the long tail of unlikely but super good outcomes. It also gives me a chance to say “huh, that EV is not competitive” and do something else.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Evaluating the prompt gives me more information on how my plans are working out. <a href="https://blog.andymatuschak.org/post/159979927467/satisfaction-and-progress-in-open-ended-work">Andy Matuschak</a> talks about the dilemma of knowledge work, where you can’t make a plan for success but leaving things open ended often leads nowhere. His solution to this is to give himself unstructured time, but then look back and see if it worked out the way he wanted, and if it didn’t, do something different next time. Predictions provide a really natural, lightweight prompt for this reflection.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Sometimes I withdraw a question for being poorly phrased- often when my answer makes the decision sound “bad” but I feel like it was actually “good”, or vice versa. This is an easy way to notice I was wrong about what I valued and look for what is actually driving my decisions.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Then there are the framing benefits. It’s easier to view something as an experiment if you’re explicitly writing down “5% chance of success”, which makes failure feel less bad. I didn’t fail to make something work, I executed the correct algorithm and it failed to produce results this particular time.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Making an explicit prediction and writing it down closes open loops in my head, freeing RAM for other things.</p>
<p dir="ltr">It’s helpful to notice when the habit doesn’t trigger. For example, I have a meeting planned today (when I’m writing this) that I just “didn’t feel inspired” to make a prediction for. When I looked closer I realized that’s because I was kind of eh on this meeting but felt obliged to take it, and was avoiding that fact. I don’t know how this is going to work out because I’m choosing to work on this blog post before tackling that, but I still credit the prediction habit with noticing, which is the first step towards better choices.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Also it seems like this might make my predictions more accurate, which has all kinds of applications. But to be honest that’s not what’s reinforcing this.</p>

<h3>Examples</h3>
<p dir="ltr">So we’re on the same page, here are some sample predictions, and the decisions that rested on them:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Reading Pavlov and his School will lead to behavior change in the area of learning or sleep (20%)</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation"><span>Should I buy a physical copy of Pavlov and his School and spend the time to read it?</span></p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Talking with my friend Jane on 8/1 will be energizing (95%)</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Should I take a call with Jane?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Bob the recruiter will describe a job that I am at all capable of and interested in doing (3%)</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Should I take a call with Bob?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">I will judge the seminar on 7/28 will be worth the interruption of flow (40%)</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Should I spend money and time on this seminar?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Sam will finish task Y by 7/31 (20%)</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">No immediate decision riding on this one, but it sure seems useful to calibrate on how well I can predict a project partner’s productivity.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">I will play with an Oculus Quest at least an hour a week (98%)</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Should I buy a Quest?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">California will catch fire to the point I need to keep my windows closed (95%)</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Should I buy an air conditioner?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Company Z will offer me at least an hour of work (15%)</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">No immediate decision</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Supplement S will improve my sleep to the point I don’t need a nap (3%)</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Should I buy and use supplement S?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<h3>Instructions</h3>
<p dir="ltr">If I were starting from scratch, here are the instructions I would want to receive (many of which I did receive, from <a href="https://www.lesswrong.com/users/raemon">Raemon</a>)</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Create an account on <a href="https://predictionbook.com/">PredictionBook.com</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Go to Settings to correct your time zone and set your prediction default to “visible to creator” rather than “visible to public” (unless you’d like them to be public by default).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Create a handful of predictions that will resolve over the next week (PredictionBook will e-mail you when they should be resolved).</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">The goal is twofold:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Quickly get feedback about how this feels for you.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Get yourself in the habit of making and resolving predictions.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">When making predictions, try to hone in on things that are decision-relevant to you; that you would do something different based on if the prediction was true or not.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Create a link to <a href="https://predictionbook.com/predictions/new">https://predictionbook.com/predictions/new</a> in your browser so you can access it easily.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">As you take more actions based on predictions (implicit or explicit), notice that you are doing so, and register the predictions in PredictionBook</p>
</li>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Resolve predictions as you are prompted to do so.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">After a week or two, check in with yourself and how you feel about the project. For calibration: I found creating the initial predictions kind of a pain but by a week in the project was naturally rewarding and required no will power on my part.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p dir="ltr">This should take &lt; 30 minutes, and it should take &lt; 45 minutes total to get a good sense of whether this is working for you.</p>

<h3>Why Does This Work?</h3>
<p dir="ltr">I’ve been thinking a lot about flow and distraction recently. One thing I’ve noticed is that it takes an awful long time, measured in hours, to get into the mindset for certain tasks. Those tasks then feel amazing, unless I’m pulled out of them prematurely, which hurts (and makes it take even longer to get into the next time). There’s a lot of implications of this that I’ll hopefully get to in some other post; the relevance here is that I think weekly reviews might be one of those tasks that requires a lot of time to get into the required headspace and hurts to leave prematurely. This makes them costly- much more costly then I would have estimated before I learned to bill tasks for their prep time. It’s also something of an all or nothing task- doing 50% of your weekly review does not get you nearly 50% of the benefits of a full weekly review.</p>
<p dir="ltr">But predictions, both making and evaluating, integrate into my life pretty naturally most of the time, and scale gracefully. Writing them up can take as little as 15 seconds, and when it takes longer, it’s because I’ve discovered something important I need to work out. Doing this fits in naturally with the process of making plans, so I don’t need to spend time getting into the right head space. Evaluating them is usually trivial- and if it’s not, it’s highlighting a problem with my models.</p>

<h3>Tips and Tricks</h3>
<p dir="ltr">“I will enjoy X” is very rarely the right prediction for me to make, because enjoyment is a tricky thing for me. I don’t like admitting I didn’t enjoy something, and sometimes I will burn a lot of energy trying to make something enjoyable, which can be a bad decision even if it works. My equivalent is “X will be energizing”</p>
<p dir="ltr">When trying to create predictions, think about what you’ll be spending money and time on in the next week. How do you think those things are going to go? What outcomes would make you change your decision?</p>

<h3>Caveats</h3>
<p dir="ltr">My original inspiration for this experiment, <a href="https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/jL7uDE5oH4HddYq4u/raemon-s-scratchpad?commentId=nuWrC9MxrgsjjS69W">Raemon</a>, hasn’t gotten the benefits I describe. He’s more focused on improving his prediction calibration and accuracy, and so far hasn’t done as much decision-relevant predictions. I’ve encouraged him to try it my way and hopefully he’ll comment after he’s spent a few weeks on that.</p>
<p dir="ltr">PredictionBook is pleasantly lightweight but it’s already a little cluttered with predictions. If I really do solidify this habit I may need to find or create a better system.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I’ve been doing this for about a month. People have kept up weekly reviews for longer before letting them fall by the wayside. I’m writing this up now because the act of solidifying a habit makes me worse at writing about it. I’ve set a reminder for 12/1 to write an update.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Thanks to <a href="https://www.lesswrong.com/users/raemon">Raemon</a> for pushing me to a better version this post and for initiating the experiment in the first place.</p>

	</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://acesounderglass.com/2020/08/06/predictions-as-a-substitute-for-reviews/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24118052</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 07:33:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Golang Desktop App with Webview/Lorca, WASM and Bazel]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 153 | Comments 114 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24117758">thread link</a>) | @grahar64
<br/>
August 10, 2020 | https://maori.geek.nz/golang-desktop-app-with-webview-lorca-wasm-and-bazel-3283813bf89 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://maori.geek.nz/golang-desktop-app-with-webview-lorca-wasm-and-bazel-3283813bf89">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section><div><div><div><div><div><div><p><a href="https://maori.geek.nz/@GrahamJenson?source=post_page-----3283813bf89----------------------" rel="noopener"><img alt="Graham Jenson" src="https://miro.medium.com/fit/c/96/96/0*1bdqD2hM_lzBk_GT.jpeg" width="48" height="48"></a></p></div></div></div></div><p id="0ce9">On my quest towards building a GoLang Desktop application I found some useful frameworks, <a href="https://github.com/zserge/lorca" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lorca</a> and <a href="https://github.com/webview/webview" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Webview</a> (which I wrote about in <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://maori.geek.nz/golang-desktop-app-webview-vs-lorca-vs-electron-a5e6b2869391">my previous post</a>). These frameworks create a window which GoLang can inject HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to build the UI.</p><p id="c60c">But I don’t want to write JavaScript(!) and deal with all the complexities that comes with it like npm, webpack, typescript… Fortunately, I can just compile GoLang to <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/WebAssembly" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WebAssembly</a> (WASM) and use that in place of JavaScript. WASM is a binary format that can be executed natively in <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/WebAssembly" target="_blank" rel="noopener">most modern browsers</a>. <em>My </em><a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://maori.geek.nz/a-web-app-using-bazel-golang-wasm-and-proto-c020914f4341"><em>previous post</em></a><em> showed how to build a WASM web-app with the Bazel.</em></p><p id="14af">Also, using WASM in a desktop app (as opposed to a web app) dodges two of its main downsides:</p><ol><li id="a01f"><strong>Large WASM binaries</strong> (especially from GoLang): these take a long time to send over the network increasing loading times. In a desktop app the binary isn’t transferred over the network, so less overhead.</li><li id="c65b"><strong>Browser incompatibility: </strong>Some WebAssembly methods are unavailable in browsers and older browsers are not supported at all. In a desktop app the “browser” is controlled (Chrome for Lorca and Safari for webview), so no compatibility issues.</li></ol><p id="382a">Let’s get started and build the app.</p><h2 id="ad5c">The Main Desktop App</h2><p id="04fb">First, I want to sketch out the <code>main</code> function for the app:</p><pre><span id="49df">func main() {<br> // Create the Data URI of index.html<br> url := fmt.Sprintf(<br>  "data:text/html,%s", <br>  url.PathEscape(assets.INDEX_HTML)<br> )</span><span id="6f7e"> // Create Lorca UI<br> ui, _ := lorca.New(url, "", 600, 200)<br> defer ui.Close()</span><span id="7141"> // Create a JS function that returns the WASM binary in base64 <br> ui.Bind("getWASM", func() string { return assets.WASM_BIN })</span><span id="4a42"> // Initialize the wasm_exec.js script<br> ui.Eval(assets.WASM_EXEC_JS)</span><span id="77ea"> // Call the initial JS functions to load the WASM<br> ui.Eval(assets.INIT_JS)</span><span id="cbed"> &lt;-ui.Done()<br>}</span></pre><p id="6eb4"><em>Note: the core difference between with webview, is using </em><code><em>Init</em></code><em> instead of </em><code><em>Eval</em></code></p><p id="062d">This app will start a Chrome window then:</p><ol><li id="9913">load the webpage with HTML <code>assets.INDEX_HTML</code></li><li id="79c2">define a function <code>getWASM</code> that is a promise of <code>assets.WASM_BIN</code>, the WASM binary as a base64 encoded string</li><li id="c64f">load the JS GoLang WASM library <code>assets.WASM_EXEC_JS</code> copied from <code>$(go env <strong>GOROOT</strong>)/misc/wasm/wasm_exec.js</code></li><li id="7f2e">load the JS initialization script <code>assets.INIT_JS</code></li></ol><figure><div><div><div><p><img alt="Image for post" src="https://miro.medium.com/max/1676/1*tezB3wIacBS6kH32xAxeqw.png" width="838" height="287" srcset="https://miro.medium.com/max/552/1*tezB3wIacBS6kH32xAxeqw.png 276w, https://miro.medium.com/max/1104/1*tezB3wIacBS6kH32xAxeqw.png 552w, https://miro.medium.com/max/1280/1*tezB3wIacBS6kH32xAxeqw.png 640w, https://miro.medium.com/max/1400/1*tezB3wIacBS6kH32xAxeqw.png 700w" sizes="700px" data-old-src="https://miro.medium.com/max/60/1*tezB3wIacBS6kH32xAxeqw.png?q=20"></p></div></div></div></figure><p id="ce8d">This is pretty simple example Lorca app, it is basically the demo example. The main complication is the <code>assets</code> package and how it can be created. This is where Bazel comes in.</p><h2 id="74f4">Embedding Files in GoLang Binary using Bazel</h2><p id="8571"><em>Note: an easier way to do this was pointed out to me using the </em><code><a href="https://github.com/bazelbuild/rules_go/blob/fbbbfde2dff5072fe118b369a699d456ec756b0c/go/extras.rst#id3" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>go_embed_data</em></a></code><em> rule, better to use that.</em></p><p id="9249">The <code>assets</code> package contains the HTML, JS and WASM files as string constants. There are GoLang tools like <a href="https://github.com/markbates/pkger" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pkger</a> or <a href="https://github.com/go-bindata/go-bindata" target="_blank" rel="noopener">go-bindata</a> to do this, but we can keep this simple with a Bazel rule in <code>to_go_constant.bzl</code>:</p><pre><span id="aace">def to_go_constant(name, package, constant, file, base64 = False):<br> pkgStr = '&lt;(echo "package %s")' % package<br> conStr = '&lt;(echo "const %s string = \`")' % constant<br> suffix = '&lt;(echo "\`")'<br> genGo = 'cat %s %s - %s ' % (pkgStr, conStr, suffix)</span><span id="56aa">if base64:<br>  printContents = 'cat $(SRCS) | base64'<br> else:<br>  printContents = 'cat $(SRCS)'</span><span id="8c11">native.genrule(<br>  name = name,<br>  srcs = [file],<br>  outs = [name + ".go"],<br>  cmd =  printContents + ' | ' + genGo + '&gt; $@'<br> )</span></pre><p id="e3d4">This rule uses <code>cat</code> to take a <code>file</code> and output a <code>.go</code> file with the <code>package</code> and <code>const</code> defined. If <code>base64=True</code> then the file is base64 encoded.</p><p id="2176">An example of this rule in action is adding the <code>assets.INDEX_HTML</code> built from the file <code>index.html</code>:</p><pre><span id="90f6">load("//:to_go_constant.bzl", "to_go_constant")</span><span id="fba4">to_go_constant(<br>    name = "index",<br>    constant = "INDEX_HTML",<br>    file = ":index.html",<br>    package = "assets",<br>)</span></pre><p id="16e5">This takes the <code>index.html </code>file:</p><pre><span id="5a54">&lt;html&gt;<br>&lt;body&gt;<br> &lt;!-- add stuff here --&gt;<br>&lt;/body&gt;<br>&lt;/html&gt;</span></pre><p id="4a53">and creates the <code>index.go</code> file:</p><pre><span id="e546">package assets<br>const INDEX_HTML string = `&lt;html&gt;<br>&lt;body&gt;<br> &lt;!-- add stuff here --&gt;<br>&lt;/body&gt;<br>&lt;/html&gt;`</span></pre><p id="8cd7"><code>index.go</code> can be added to the <code>go_library</code> rule for the <code>assets</code> package:</p><pre><span id="f437">go_library(<br>    name = "go_default_library",<br>    srcs = [<br>        "assets.go",<br>        ":index.go",  # keep<br>    ],<br>    importpath = "github.com/.../assets",<br>)</span></pre><p id="1cbf">Now the <code>INDEX_HTML</code> constant is in the assets package.</p><p id="4aa6">It is straight forward for most the other files, but a bit more complicated for the WASM binary data:</p><pre><span id="758f">to_go_constant(<br>    name = "wasmbin",<br>    base64 = True,<br>    constant = "WASM_BIN",<br>    file = "//project/wasm",<br>    package = "assets",<br>)</span></pre><p id="cc54">The file <code>//project/wasm</code> refers to the generated <code>go_binary</code> rule that compiles the WASM (as described below). <code>base64</code> is also <code>True</code> so that the binary data can be encoded as a constant.</p><p id="6b53"><em>Note: There is one minor issue is the </em><code><em>wasm_exec.js</em></code><em> file, it has a few </em><code><em>`</em></code><em>’s in it that must be replaced.</em></p><h2 id="dede">The WASM part</h2><p id="406c">The WASM binary is the client-side GoLang application running in the browser. This example injects a <code>Hello World</code> <code>&lt;p&gt;</code> tag into the body:</p><pre><span id="a864">package main</span><span id="bd53">import (<br> "fmt"<br> "syscall/js"<br>)</span><span id="8acd">func main() {<br> fmt.Println("Hello World")</span><span id="b814"> document := js.Global().Get("document")<br> p := document.Call("createElement", "p")<br> p.Set("innerHTML", "Hello World")<br> document.Get("body").Call("appendChild", p)<br>}</span></pre><p id="7de3">The <code>go_binary</code> rule for this just needs <code>goos="js"</code> and <code>goarch="wasm"</code> for its output to be a WASM binary, e.g.:</p><pre><span id="d208">go_binary(<br>    name = "wasm",<br>    embed = [":go_default_library"],<br>    goarch = "wasm",<br>    goos = "js",<br>    visibility = ["//visibility:public"],<br>)</span></pre><p id="f178">The output of this rule is used to above to create the <code>WASM_BIN</code> constant above.</p><h2 id="71cd">Initializing the App</h2><p id="8bd2"><code>assets.INIT_JS</code> is built from <code>init.js:</code></p><pre><span id="7b05">loadWebASM = () =&gt; {<br> const go = new Go();<br> getWASM().then( (b64) =&gt; {<br>   // Decode and convert to ArrayBuffer<br>   buf = Uint8Array.from(atob(b64), c =&gt; c.charCodeAt(0)).buffer<br>   return WebAssembly.instantiate(buf, go.importObject)<br> }).then((result) =&gt; {<br>    go.run(result.instance);<br>  }).catch((err) =&gt; {<br>    console.error("loading wasm failed: " + err);<br>  });<br>}</span><span id="e6cf">loadWebASM()</span></pre><p id="c227">This code takes the <code>WASM_BIN</code> promised by <code>getWASM</code>, then decodes and converts it to an ArrayBuffer. This buffer is passed to the <code><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Global_Objects/WebAssembly/instantiate" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WebAssembly.instantiate</a></code> function that compiles and initializes the application to an <code>instance</code>, which is then <code>go.run</code>. <strong>This is the only JavaScript needed.</strong></p><h2 id="1f97">Pure GoLang Desktop App</h2><p id="29e8">The above code is all that is needed to now write pure(-ish) GoLang desktop applications. This also makes it easy to convert other WASM apps to desktop applications, e.g. I converted the WASM app at <a href="https://github.com/olivewind/go-webassembly-canvas" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://github.com/olivewind/go-webassembly-canvas</a> to a desktop application with minimal effort:</p><figure><div><div><p><img alt="Image for post" src="https://miro.medium.com/max/998/1*SR_WdfWLKkNX_nFAEc2Kdw.png" width="499" height="502" srcset="https://miro.medium.com/max/552/1*SR_WdfWLKkNX_nFAEc2Kdw.png 276w, https://miro.medium.com/max/998/1*SR_WdfWLKkNX_nFAEc2Kdw.png 499w" sizes="499px" data-old-src="https://miro.medium.com/max/60/1*SR_WdfWLKkNX_nFAEc2Kdw.png?q=20"></p></div></div></figure><h2 id="5c7c">Conclusion</h2><p id="80dd">There are many libraries and tools written in GoLang that could use a nice user interface, e.g. <a href="https://www.terraform.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">terraform</a> and <a href="https://www.docker.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">docker</a> (just off the top of my head). A web app does not fit their requirements very well since they are editing local files and talking to local daemons. The alternative is then to reimplement or bind their API and integrations to another language which is complicated, error prone and a lot of work. A method of building pure GoLang desktop applications makes a lot of sense for these kinds of tools.</p><p id="93db">This approach can pretty quickly create a distributable, single executable, desktop application with minimal external dependencies. An app that can reuse many GoLang libraries and tools that have already been built. I suppose the worst part of this approach is that it throws away years of development on JavaScript tools like React and Vue. But that just means I have to write more Go to reimplement them, so it isn’t that bad :)</p></div></div></section></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://maori.geek.nz/golang-desktop-app-with-webview-lorca-wasm-and-bazel-3283813bf89</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24117758</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 06:41:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Parallel Seam Carving]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 178 | Comments 27 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24117330">thread link</a>) | @ngzhian
<br/>
August 10, 2020 | https://shwestrick.github.io/2020/07/29/seam-carve.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://shwestrick.github.io/2020/07/29/seam-carve.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seam_carving">Seam carving</a> is a technique
for <em>content-aware resizing</em>, which changes the size of an image while
attempting to preserve the interesting content of the image. The basic
idea behind the technique is to remove <strong><em>low-energy seams</em></strong>: paths of pixels
that are similar to their surroundings. A removed seam can be either vertical or
horizontal, to reduce either the width or height of an image.</p>

<p>For example, here’s a panorama I took a few years ago near Spruce Knob, WV.</p>

<p><img width="100%" src="https://shwestrick.github.io/assets/seam-carve/pano.jpg"></p>

<p>The image is super wide, but we can carve it down.
Here’s an animation of the process, generated by the
<a href="https://github.com/MPLLang/mpl/pull/123">seam-carver I implemented recently</a>
as a parallel benchmark for
<a href="https://github.com/mpllang/mpl"><code>mpl</code></a>.</p>

<video width="100%" loop="" autoplay="" muted="" playsinline="">
  <source src="https://shwestrick.github.io/assets/seam-carve/carve.mp4" type="video/mp4">
</video>

<p>Getting real parallel speedups in this implementation turned out to be an
interesting challenge. For typical images, which are fairly small,
I found that the most obvious approach for parallelizing the algorithm was not
able to extract enough parallelism, because it required too small of a
<em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Granularity_%28parallel_computing%29">grain size</a></em>.
So, I designed a new way of parallelizing the algorithm which works much
better on small images. This post presents some of the details.</p>

<h2 id="the-seam-carving-algorithm">The Seam Carving Algorithm</h2>

<p>The idea behind seam-carving is to consider all possible seams in an image,
select the one which is least important, and remove it. A <strong><em>seam</em></strong> is a path of
pixels that cuts across an image, touching one pixel in each row (or column)
along the way. When we remove a seam, we reduce either the width or height
of the image by 1. We can repeat this process as many times as desired to
shrink the image.</p>

<p>We’ll base the “importance” of seams on a notion of pixel <strong><em>energy</em></strong>, which
can be defined in
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Image_gradient">many different ways</a>.
For seam-carving, the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Color_difference">color difference</a> gradient
seems to work well, which measures how different a pixel’s color is in
comparison to its surroundings. The <strong><em>energy of a seam</em></strong> is just the
cumulative energies of all pixels touched by the seam. With this setup,
the seam with <em>minimum energy</em> should be unimportant and safe to remove from
an image.</p>

<p>To compute <em>minimum seam energies</em>, we can use a simple
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dynamic_programming">dynamic programming</a>
algorithm. For simplicity here, let’s focus on vertical seams. Let
\(M(i,j)\) be the minimum energy of
any partial seam that ends at row \(i\) and column \(j\), and let
\(E(i,j)\) be the energy of the pixel at that position. These minimum seam
energies are related by the following equation:</p><p>

\[M(i,j) = E(i,j) + \min(M(i-1,j-1), M(i-1,j), M(i-1,j+1))\]

</p><p>A picture might help. For each position, we look at the minimum partial
seams that end above it, pick the smallest, and then add the next pixel.</p>

<p><img width="250px" src="https://shwestrick.github.io/assets/seam-carve/equation.svg"></p>

<p>Once \(M\) has been fully computed, we can find the minimum overall seam by
working backwards, from bottom to top, by walking upwards along the path of
minimum seam energies starting at the smallest in the bottommost row.</p>

<h2 id="finding-the-minimum-seam-in-parallel">Finding the minimum seam in parallel</h2>



<p>The dependencies within the equation for \(M\) appear to offer a lot of
parallelism. Perhaps the most immediately obvious approach is to compute
\(M\) in <strong><em>row-major</em></strong> order,
where first we do all of row 0, and then all of row 1, etc. With this ordering,
the values within a row can be computed entirely in parallel, because each
\(M(i, j)\) only depends on three values \(M(i-1, \ldots)\) from the previous row.</p>

<p>However, there’s a major problem in practice with row-major order:
typical images are only at most a few thousand pixels wide, and each pixel
only requires a small amount of work. That’s not enough work (per row)
to parallelize effectively! We’ll need a
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Granularity_%28parallel_computing%29">granularity</a>
of at least, say, a thousand pixels to amortize the cost of parallelism itself.</p>

<p>This pretty much rules out using row-major order for typical, small images.
Is there a better to compute \(M\) without reducing the grain size?</p>



<p>To extract more parallelism without reducing the grain size, we need a
better way to partition up the work. This is something that probably
<em>could</em> be done “automatically” (e.g. take a look at
<a href="https://dblp.uni-trier.de/pers/c/Chowdhury:Rezaul_Alam.html">Rezaul Chowdhury</a>’s
work), but here we’ll just try to design something ourselves.</p>

<p>What are all of the dependencies for a single value \(M(i,j)\)? Visually,
the dependencies form a triangle with the pointy-end pointing down:</p>

<p><img width="300px" src="https://shwestrick.github.io/assets/seam-carve/depend.svg"></p>

<p>We can use triangles like these to split up the work in a nice way. First,
imagine grouping adjacent rows into <strong><em>strips</em></strong>. Within one strip,
cover the top of the strip with a bunch downward-pointing triangles. The
leftover space will look like a bunch of upward-pointing triangles, each
of which has all of its dependencies already satisfied (this is not immediately
obvious but drawing a picture will help). So, we
can process one strip in two parallel rounds, where first we do a bunch of
downward-pointing triangles in parallel, and then we do a bunch of
upward-pointing triangles to fill in the leftover space.</p>

<p>Here’s a picture using triangles that are 6 pixels wide at the base. Note that
if we use triangles of even base-width, then these tile naturally with no
overlap.</p>

<p><img width="350px" src="https://shwestrick.github.io/assets/seam-carve/strips.svg"></p>

<p>How wide should each triangle be in practice? Recall that we’re shooting for a
target granularity of maybe one or two thousand pixels. This corresponds to
triangles with base-widths of somewhere between 64 (1056 pixels in the triangle)
and 90 (2070 pixels in the triangle).</p>

<p>So, in a smallish image, e.g. 1000 pixels wide, we can fit
at least 11 triangles horizontally, suggesting a maximum possible
speedup of 11x or more. This is a big improvement over the row-major strategy,
which (using a granularity of 1000 pixels) would not be able to extract any
parallelism from such an image.</p>

<h2 id="implementation-and-performance">Implementation and performance</h2>

<p>With <a href="https://github.com/mpllang/mpl"><code>mpl</code></a>, I implemented both the row-major
and triangular strategies to compare their performance. The code for the
triangular strategy is available in the <code>examples/src/seam-carve/</code> subdirectory
of the <a href="https://github.com/mpllang/mpl"><code>mpl</code></a> repo. I’ll leave the row-major
code as an exercise to the reader. (It’s not too bad!)</p>

<p>Here are some performance numbers for
removing 10 seams from an image of size approximately 2600x600. I did a little
bit of tuning, and ended up choosing a row-major granularity of 1000 pixels,
and a triangular base-width granularity of 88 (1980 pixels).</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Strategy</th>
      <th>P = 1</th>
      <th>P = 10</th>
      <th>P = 20</th>
      <th>P = 30</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>row-major</td>
      <td>0.66</td>
      <td>0.38</td>
      <td>0.38</td>
      <td>0.38</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>triangular</td>
      <td>0.78</td>
      <td>0.17</td>
      <td>0.12</td>
      <td>0.09</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>On 1 processor (P = 1), the row-major strategy is faster by about 15%, but
on more processors quickly hits a maximum speedup of about 2x, seeing no
additional improvement above 10 processors.
In contrast, the triangular strategy continues to get faster as the number
of processors increases, with self-speedups of about 5x on 10 processors,
6.5x on 20, and 9x on 30.</p>

<p>Despite having a mild amount of overhead on 1 processor, we can see that
the triangular strategy provides significant gains. On higher core counts,
it is as much as 4x faster than the row-major strategy.</p>

<h2 id="discussion">Discussion</h2>

<p>One might wonder: why are the speedups we got so far away from theoretical
limits? With a base-width of 88, shouldn’t we be able to get up to 30x speedup
on an image of width 2600? Well, unfortunately, there are a large number of
barriers to achieving such good speedup in practice: ineffective cache
utilization, memory bandwidth bottlenecks, non-optimal scheduling… and
many more.</p>

<p>In the case of seam carving, there are two major limiting factors.</p>
<ol>
  <li>Seam carving is largely memory-bound, i.e., for each memory access it
  only does a small amount of work before the next access. To get around this
  bottleneck, we might need better cache utilization, and so we would have to
  more carefully lay out the values of \(M(i,j)\) in memory. (For this
  implementation, I used a simple flat-array layout, where \(M(i,j)\) lives at
  index \(iW + j\). We could instead try storing these values in a
  hierarchical structure, indexing first by strip, and then by triangle, to
  better improve locality.)</li>
  <li>Seam carving has high span, performing a small amount of work in
  between each synchronization. For example in the row-major strategy, we use
  a barrier between each row, and in the triangular strategy, we use two
  barriers per strip. This can cause the scheduler to perform too many thread
  migrations. To mitigate this, one thing we could try is to let triangles
  overlap slightly, to increase the size of each strip. This trades a small
  amount of duplicated work for fewer barrier synchronizations overall, which
  could prove to be hugely beneficial.</li>
</ol>

<!--
In code, we could do this in MPL as follows:


<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-sml" data-lang="sml"><span class="kr">let</span>
  <span class="kr">val</span> <span class="nv">w</span> <span class="p">=</span> <span class="p">...</span> <span class="c">(*</span><span class="cm"> width *)</span>
  <span class="kr">val</span> <span class="nv">h</span> <span class="p">=</span> <span class="p">...</span> <span class="c">(*</span><span class="cm"> height *)</span>
  <span class="kr">fun</span> <span class="nf">E</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="n">i</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">j</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">=</span> <span class="p">...</span> <span class="c">(*</span><span class="cm"> energy *)</span>

  <span class="c">(*</span><span class="cm"> Store M as an array, where (i, j) is at index i*w+j.
   * Use setM to update values in the table, and M (which
   * gracefully handles out-of-bounds) for lookup. *)</span>
  <span class="kr">val</span> <span class="nv">arrayM</span> <span class="p">=</span> <span class="n">alloc</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="n">w</span> <span class="n">*</span> <span class="n">h</span><span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="kr">fun</span> <span class="nf">setM</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="n">i</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">j</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="n">x</span> <span class="p">=</span> <span class="nn">Array</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">update</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="n">arrayM</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">i*w+j</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">x</span><span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="kr">fun</span> <span class="nf">M</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="n">i</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">j</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">=</span>
    <span class="kr">if</span> <span class="n">i</span> <span class="n">&lt;</span> <span class="mi">0</span> <span class="kr">then</span>
      <span class="mf">0.0</span>
    <span class="kr">else</span> <span class="kr">if</span> <span class="n">j</span> <span class="n">&lt;</span> <span class="mi">0</span> <span class="kr">orelse</span> <span class="n">j</span> <span class="n">&gt;</span> <span class="n">w</span> <span class="kr">then</span>
      <span class="nn">Real</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">posInf</span>
    <span class="kr">else</span>
      <span class="nn">Array</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">sub</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="n">arrayM</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">i*w+j</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="kr">in</span>
  <span class="n">for</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">h</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="kr">fn</span> <span class="n">i</span> <span class="p">=&gt;</span>
    <span class="n">parfor</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">w</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="kr">fn</span> <span class="n">j</span> <span class="p">=&gt;</span>
      <span class="n">setM</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="n">i</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">j</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">(</span> <span class="n">E</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">i</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">j</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="n">+</span> <span class="n">min</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">M</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">i-</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">j-</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">),</span> <span class="n">M</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">i-</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">j</span><span class="p">),</span> <span class="n">M</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">i-</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">j+</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">))</span> <span class="p">)</span>
    <span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="p">)</span>
<span class="kr">end</span></code></pre></figure>

-->

  </div>

  
    





  

  
</article>

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://shwestrick.github.io/2020/07/29/seam-carve.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24117330</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 05:07:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
