<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 12:55:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 12:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Parable of Alien Chess]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 96 | Comments 92 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25642635">thread link</a>) | @krebs_liebhaber
<br/>
January 4, 2021 | https://lukesmith.xyz/articles/chess | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://lukesmith.xyz/articles/chess">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">


<a href="https://lukesmith.xyz/articles/pix/alien_pepe.jpg">
<img src="https://lukesmith.xyz/articles/pix/alien_pepe_small.gif" alt="Alien" title="Save before they delete it again.">
</a>

by <a href="https://lukesmith.xyz/index.html">Luke Smith</a>

<p>
<i>A parable on the Logical Postivist "interpretation" of scientific models.
<!-- Granted, I use the term "logical positivist" in a somewhat expanded but specific sense, -->
<!-- loosely the idea that "science is good models" or what was called in the past "instrumentalism." -->
</i>
</p>

<h2>The Parable</h2>

<p>
Suppose an alien race comes to Earth and wants to observe our games.
They are very interested in chess, despite the fact that they have eyes with properties that make it impossible to make out what actually happens on a chess board.
(The whites and blacks and squares all blur together.)
</p>

<p>
They can still learn about chess experimentally, they know they can sit two players (a so-called "white" and "black" player) down to play it, and they can tell behaviorally who at the end wins.
</p>

<p>
After extensive experimentation, they realize this: 50% of the time, the white player wins and 50% of the time, the black player wins (we'll ignore draws and any first-move advantage for the example).
</p>

<h3>The "best" model</h3>

<p>
A logical positivist alien thus creates the ultimate, long-term model of chess as an iterated game:
Chess amounts to just a drawn-out coin flip.
Half of the time white wins, half of the time black wins, just as if they were tossing a quarter.
</p>

<p>
The aliens then decide to model chess as a coin flip, as a 50-50 game with no underlying principles.
While this statistical technique might not be useful for predicting a single game, over the long run and over iterated games, <em>it is the most efficient and parsimonious possible model</em>.
</p>

<h3>"Inferior" models</h3>

<p>
Suppose, however that a "crank" scientist of the alien race posits that "God doesn't play dice" and that chess is a more complicated game, despite the fact that the aliens cannot observe it.
Suppose even he asks around and determines from humans that there are actually pieces on the board with functions, and he even devises a machine that allows his alien eyes to see the first move of the game of chess.
</p>

<p>
Seeing this move allows him to create a new theory and model of the game,
one that takes into account the first move made and he tries to generate a new set of probabilities of victory based on that move.
The model he makes, is of course highly arbitrary, stipulated and <em>ad hoc</em>.
In fact,
this model is inferior on many inevitable accounts.
For example:
</p>

<ol>
    <li>It is less predictive over iterated games than the coin flip model.</li>
    <li>It is not as parsimonious/minimal as the coin flip model.</li>
    <li>It adds new variables to the theory (pieces) that are suspect.</li>
</ol>

<h2>Which model is "right?"</h2>

<h3>Which model is closer to truth?</h3>

<p>
Since we, unlike the aliens, are not prevented by defect from observing chess, we know that the second, "inferior" theory of chess is truer.
Its theoretical categories, if apparently arbitrary in the eyes of the aliens, are getting at the actual underlying mechanics of chess.
Even if the model is less effective, it is certainly <em>righter</em>.
</p>

<h3>Which will cause fruitful scientific inquiry?</h3>

<p>
The coin flip model is a scientific dead-end.
Firstly, the coin flip model is constructed statistically, which presents the underlying mechanism to be randomness, and thus unworth of inquiry.
This isn't statistics hoisted above random variation we know to exist, instead, it's utterly blind statistics that covers over whatever principles underlie it.
</p>

<p>
Secondly and more importantly, in order to actually improve that model, it has to <em>lose</em> empirical solvency:
embracing the abstractions of pieces means introducing mess and
deviating in some way from the empircal generalization that half of all chess games are won by white and half by black.
</p>

<h3>This is not an abnormal circumstance.</h3>

<p>
The parable here, really an <em>example</em> is not abnormal.
In most affairs in science, whether that be physics or neuroscience or economics or chemistry, we are exactly like the partially-blind aliens.
</p>

<h3>"But science isn't about truth!"</h3>

<p>
Yeah, it is dude.
</p>

<p>
Even if you are pretending that science is about "models" or fitting equations and the like, again, the well-fit model is impossible to perfect, while the flawed, yet more true to reality model does have a potential over the long-term to be a superior one.
After exhaustive inquiry, an alien race might not only discover the pieces and the full set of rules behind chess, they might be able to predict what moves are good or bad and predict individual chess games.
Even on the standards of mere instrumentalism, the mindless positivistic theory is still actually inferior.
</p>

<h2>Local maxima</h2>

<img src="https://lukesmith.xyz/articles/pix/maximum.gif" alt="Local maximum">

<h3>The plot</h3>

<p>
One of the ways I visualize science and models is that each model is really like an n-dimensional optimization plot.
"Truth," or if you deny truth as metaphysics, "accuracy in data" or "well-fit equations" are upwards and the goal of science is to get further that way.
</p>

<p>
At the point you're at, you can tell which direction you can go to move upward, or, which little changes you can make to improve your model.
That is what incremental science is, after all: don't change assumptions and just fine-tune your equations.
The endless fine-tuning is sometimes thought of as "progress."
Of course I don't think that this is <em>bad</em>, but it is a very minor and scientifically less important part of science as a whole.
</p>

<p>
The reality of incremental science is that once you're at a local maximum, once you've fine-tuned your equations about as perfectly as possible,
it's over.
Everything next to you <em>looks</em> like a disimprovement.
It <em>looks</em> just like those inferior theories of alien chess that posit the existence of pieces.
From that, you might erroneously conclude that you have found the <em>global</em> maximum, which
due to the nature of the complexity of the universe and the multiplicity of
possible answers and theories, you flatly haven't.
</p>

<p>
Logical positivism is kind of theoretical lobotomy that implicitly tells scientists that they should never, ever, ever change foundational assumptions:
tweaking equations like an oblivious autist is Science®️ and everything else is "philosophy" or "metaphysics" or "pseudoscience."
This amounts to keeping each scientific field on whatever local maximum is closest, utterly unable to extricate themselves from it even when they see on the horizon abberant data.
<strong>If you want to understand the stagnation of science or any other specific field, this is where it comes from.</strong>
</p>

<h3>Purposefully "bad" science</h3>

<p>
In <i><a href="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/notrelated/S02E01_-_Against_Method_and_For_Pseudoscience.ogg">Against Method</a></i>, Paul Feyerabend, in what an unreflective mind might misinterpret as a "troll," says that it is important for science that people have biases, financial interests, interfering religious and political doctrines and the like in science.
Looking at the plot, you might now see why.
When we are stuck on a local maximum, every new data keeps our already-optimized model where it is no matter how low that maximum actually is.
What you need to shake it up is an external shock that totally moves our theoretical position somewhere new on the plot where we can try to optimize at another point, and then compare.
</p>

<h3>Basic assumptions</h3>

<p>
A prudent person should be able to question, "Am I even on the right track or am I playing with some model that has a fundamental flaw?"
I can guarantee you, optimizing for data and fitting math and equations is easy.
<strong>All theoretical programs are wrong because they make incorrect core assumptions.</strong>
This is very hard for the ego of scientists because it means:
</p>

<ol>
    <li>Possibly illiterate dilettantes on the internet might see and bring to attention legitimate theoretical flaws.</li>
    <li>All the years you spend in graduate school counting angels on pinheads in your respective theoretical framework is mostly a waste of time.</li>
    <li>The borders of science are borders more of a sociological club than being the border of raw rigor.</li>
    <li>Most of the scientific work is not meaningful outside of the theoretical framework that gave rise to it.</li>
</ol>

    <hr>
    




</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://lukesmith.xyz/articles/chess</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25642635</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 05:58:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Blocking Pinterest may reduce your data usage]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 109 | Comments 88 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25642392">thread link</a>) | @rukshn
<br/>
January 4, 2021 | https://ruky.me/2021/01/05/you-might-want-to-block-pinterest-to-save-your-data/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ruky.me/2021/01/05/you-might-want-to-block-pinterest-to-save-your-data/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p><em>I guess this is the first blog post of the new year, even though I’m not someone who is keen on celebrating a new year, I sincerely hope every one would have a very bright 2021.</em></p>
<p>Most of you are enjoying unlimited internet at your homes, but sadly <a href="https://ruky.me/2020/12/28/sri-lanka-need-unlimited-internet-connections/">I’m coming from a part of the world that charges according to the data I use. </a></p>
<p>I basically pay for my data and I have monthly cap, and if I exceed that data limit I will have to buy an expensive data add-on. So data is something precious to me.</p>
<p>In the month of December, may be due to a technical error by the ISP my data add-on finished and I made a tweet criticizing them.</p>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Scammed again by <a href="https://twitter.com/SriLankaTelecom?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@SriLankaTelecom</a> you should be ashamed of your practices </p><p>Bought a zoom package and data add-on today because I need zoom to work</p><p>But then suddenly by noon the internet got slower. And I checked why</p><p>My data add-on has expired but my 100% zoom data remaining</p></div>— Rukshan (@JustRuky) <a href="https://twitter.com/JustRuky/status/1344554873744855040?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 31, 2020</a></blockquote>
<p>The ISP was kind enough to reach out to me and I received an email detailing the data use of my internet connection.</p>
<p>It is a table with the websites/protocols I used, the data transmitted to that website/protocol in bytes.</p>
<p>One thing that immediately caught my eye was what’s at number 2, it was <strong>Pinterest</strong>.</p>
<figure><img data-attachment-id="114" data-permalink="https://ruky.me/2021/01/05/you-might-want-to-block-pinterest-to-save-your-data/img_0074/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/ruky.me/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_0074.jpg?fit=1194%2C276&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1194,276" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="img_0074" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/ruky.me/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_0074.jpg?fit=300%2C69&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/ruky.me/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_0074.jpg?fit=1024%2C237&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="237" src="https://i0.wp.com/ruky.me/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_0074.jpg?resize=1024%2C237&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/ruky.me/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_0074.jpg?resize=1024%2C237&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/ruky.me/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_0074.jpg?resize=300%2C69&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/ruky.me/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_0074.jpg?resize=768%2C178&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/ruky.me/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_0074.jpg?w=1194&amp;ssl=1 1194w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i0.wp.com/ruky.me/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_0074.jpg?resize=1024%2C237&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/ruky.me/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_0074.jpg?resize=300%2C69&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/ruky.me/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_0074.jpg?resize=768%2C178&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/ruky.me/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_0074.jpg?w=1194&amp;ssl=1 1194w" data-lazy-src="https://i0.wp.com/ruky.me/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_0074.jpg?resize=1024%2C237&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP/yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7 "><figcaption>The 17 connections to Pinterest has downloaded more than 1GB of data</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>There has been 17 connections to Pinterest and Pinterest has sent me more than 1.2GB of data.</strong></p>
<p>Even the 2000+ requests to Facebook has only downloaded roughly 300MB of data.</p>
<p>Why Pinterest is sending so much data in just 17 requests? What do they contain?</p>
<p>Maybe they are preloading or caching images for better user experience. But still 1.28GB of images is likely to have more than 1000 images.</p>
<p>Another explanation can that the ISP is trying to give me an explanation why my data vanished. But both explanations doesn’t make any sense.</p>
<p>Since data is valuable to me I will try to block requests to Pinterest, and see if that will make a difference to my data usage.</p>
<p>I’ll request another report at the end of the month to see my data usage for the month of January to compare before and after blocking Pinterest.</p>
<p>Has anyone had a similar experience in Pinterest or is it just me?</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ruky.me/2021/01/05/you-might-want-to-block-pinterest-to-save-your-data/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25642392</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 05:17:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Telegram publishes users' locations online]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 394 | Comments 178 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25641399">thread link</a>) | @Nullslash
<br/>
January 4, 2021 | https://blog.ahmed.nyc/2021/01/if-you-use-this-feature-on-telegram.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.ahmed.nyc/2021/01/if-you-use-this-feature-on-telegram.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="post-body-2299938338217590975" itemprop="description articleBody">
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">A few years ago, while using the Line app, I noticed a feature called "People nearby." The feature lets you connect with other Line users within the same area. The feature would give you the exact distance from you to the other users. If someone spoofs their latitude, longitude, they can triangulate a user and find their location. I reported an issue in the&nbsp;</span><a href="https://line.me/en/" target="_blank"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Line app</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true">, and They paid me $1000 for it. They fixed it by adding a random number to the user's destination. You can find my name&nbsp;</span><a href="https://bugbounty.linecorp.com/en/halloffame/2017/" target="_blank"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">here</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true">.&nbsp;</span></p><p>A few days ago, I installed Telegram, and I noticed that they have the same feature. I tried to see if I can unmask other users' locations, and I found they have the same issue I discovered in the Line app a few years ago. I reported the problem to Telegram security, and they said it's not an issue.&nbsp;<strong>If you enable the feature of making yourself visible on the map, you're publishing your home address online. </strong><span>Lot of users don't know this when they enable that feature. This is what they said when I emailed them:</span>&nbsp;</p><blockquote><p>From:<span>	</span>security@telegram.org</p><p>To: me</p><p>Hello,</p><p>Thanks for reaching us out. Users in the People Nearby section</p><p>intentionally share their location, and this feature is disabled by</p><p>default. It's expected that determining the exact location is possible</p><p>under certain conditions.</p><p>Unfortunately, this case is not covered by our bug bounty program.</p></blockquote><p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Disclosure timeline:&nbsp;</span></p><ul><li><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Contacted Telegram on December 22nd with full details of how to exploit the information.</span></li></ul><ul><li><span data-preserver-spaces="true">They responded on December 23rd; they asked me to create a video of the PoC 🙄</span></li></ul><ul><li><span data-preserver-spaces="true">I made a video on the same day and sent it to them.</span></li></ul><ul><li><span data-preserver-spaces="true">They responded after 14 days, saying their bug bounty program does not cover the issue.</span></li></ul><p><span>So, here is how it works in detail:<br></span><span>Open Telegram, and go to people near me, there is an option to see how far people are from your location.</span></p><p><span id="docs-internal-guid-53f1000f-7fff-b4b2-905d-ee47865be904"><span><span><img height="351" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/JbKyjueKloPEbmeyE9ZbcVkATBhRNlY4hjl8NZZOhHn4lgt56UnjR3HjAVP2Z5MNSAAe0jzL3rKNjfLI3QCueXXe6inocEKB5RwX9b6A3kIydvA74fjzmfZlEjkH0bNrfQUYR80I" width="268"></span></span></span></p><div><p>After you click on it, it will show a list of people near you like the following:</p></div><p><span id="docs-internal-guid-684e7a7b-7fff-37c6-a5fc-5d6693280cf8"><span><span><img height="478" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/umUhHMfl3qKMXVgyIdX3pXnKuronNR29XQgzc_WoX0imTtVPTvEWBLhK5x-WZvu3vz-KEInZy5lZGIOLdSO0DUP33G3Iv-758309YimhtEMxU1xM63QKoGeTJq473VIGLT0N78Yh" width="276"></span></span></span></p><p>If you notice, Telegram is telling me how far each person is far from me. An adversary can spoof their location for three points and use them to draw three triangulation circles. To spoof a GPS location, the adversary can do one of the following options:</p><div><div><p>1-Use hardware GPS spoofer (Very hard to get, and the FCC will fine you hard if you use such a device)<br>2-Use root to spoof to GPS (Medium)<br>3-Just walk around the area, collect the GPS latitude and longitude of yourself, and how far the target person is from you (Super easy)</p></div><p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">For the sake of the demonstration, I will go with option number two. There is an app in the play store called&nbsp;</span><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.lexa.fakegps" target="_blank"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">GPS spoof</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true">; download it and install it. For some reason, the app doesn't work with Android 11; I used Android 7 instead. After it, collect 3 locations of a user for unmasking.</span></p><p><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><p>4-Spoof the location near the user within a 7 miles radius limit. That's the limit Telegram has in place. The targeted user lives in Bay Ridge, so I spoofed the address to the Bay Ridge area. Then collect how far that person is from that point. Repeat three times like the following:</p><p><span id="docs-internal-guid-39370a7c-7fff-d4b2-7c98-923492b72907"><p dir="ltr"><span><span><img height="281" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/jpBnx1GgSBqLo7XCheaHJMsFff8977ZW3T-T853_rrvi-Ela1dS1BLXNExYOaO-I3ROdEByW6v1woZG7MfxC2O2a5z6ArOPApDVI8YUFo1MYntYsVhdgFZ_XBd2L71ULH2BCT5PL" width="159"></span></span><span><span><img height="281" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/YZPfdHypa3L3B9ZDucwylK3bwBmRnhswS2oHdKuJjMu8DjvKZNxNEmRzehFtk0WdM_QOz3WkLhljISpwhCjF5SMLbUXi0srUGrGTL7BmiWp-A3MBt3DNfLlbtpGtHVSg1DsKaPRB" width="163"></span></span><span><span><img height="284" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/2pazuJRtclJd6-PKGIY5YJp7TH_B-JDQWE5OSz0zfhQyANYIQocBoqqNStCp-i7zscV2ckkX2IRfFQ_7-VjXa13GHkWIwioMj9unPiLe8LBxmVOI1rHe_vM4WRtUWVuzOFvXG-0T" width="162"></span></span></p><p dir="ltr"><span><span><img height="283" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/s6VyofBRsNeMj1Wa9eL3KCEQq01d9R9F6iGoxWiIcDmH_UbjU4yA0cxyy10uzCkZJjUGiUzjWHIya1OkHhDFoCezB1H5BmozDmY62ueuAMFxCbdVGkrFJPCLK4aDx-k0CEAEUNiG" width="159"></span></span><span><span><img height="285" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/JyNBgZBtw3UzT37VSfK6Ma-gO8pk4lKqzV5e3md9O4GYVayN8CwQ0Om_RRAr7btAiCL6mmixCjHws4Ba7jiIJpYvTurhqp2r9cUufZCiQwTm3cMDX_unnbFEehZO-Jhnhf6oAONM" width="162"></span></span><span><span><img height="285" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/ECWiWe3T86oAkn25lmYcHmkdf74i_PPiwGJpddtv9k6IoW9lstqwbZu6yvPjbyUWjwV3DWG0XngaPrwAYYZL7Yjp5A9wCMZ3AMvjREuDy7XCPXBCJJIPBx6oZsw2J3NXlhPqGiXS" width="161"></span></span></p><p dir="ltr"><span><span><img height="288" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/bbnj35dH1xShYmEAcVqxKaUm4VWLKQVqoitSekn6qWGsEnqcyaBLvG4ieI1Kc-guB-Gov0fQ3ziSlpTS-BKSgA7B9cCh153b7qNV8TBduNYWUlhX027R3w7IiitLbm3l5k3GHJQo=w163-h288" width="163"></span></span><span><span><img height="278" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/qyXn90Ir58knd4dwSjf9j1qi_lx2jvY0RgYoOMgrVeSnTbD5QrTBKAf7ZiGb3wwjUYLiqDcZJRonYPr9GV3ekTTIh9r8Vve3mhy7TqSMMQyl9dJBq0sU5hllZ6U4Ay0i1mgg2u-r=w157-h278" width="157"></span></span><span><span><img height="280" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/fbADLbmhYgNppqnXeWjEnR0U8sNP4IgLNhmKsDmGuNAUICttr0Hg1WUAdkxRWsK3p9AcUkSnlHfMtAUpr0E4LrqQd3UKcpHehl6cXbdbmMAcsUwsH-WRXGeX_U81AZ2JBlLje5vS=w158-h280" width="158"></span></span></p><div><p>5-Open Google Earth Pro, search for latitude, the longitude of the spoofed locations, and use the ruler to draw a circle with the target user destination from each location. Here is the result:</p></div><p dir="ltr"><span id="docs-internal-guid-95b4c21c-7fff-a99e-599a-63c2737e7191"><span><span><img height="377" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/nLdF4cxdiW-GN4fXpfwiSy87aGQuqk4MPLu_aSjvOl2I7mj_ElfnI4CN_6iJCsJhrJhQs8u6E2imNeQrpPql9PzRQG760TpJqKt4uJwnXwkwUIjSPKAFgQH8o5sLW62b-Yf42znN" width="594"></span></span></span></p><p><span>The intersection of the three circles is the location of the user. To verify this, I added one of the users and asked them if they live near the point.</span></p><p dir="ltr"><span><span id="docs-internal-guid-267fb593-7fff-119e-00ae-01c6045c0efb"><span><span><img height="569" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/l53s1fb3kWCRiZk5MbG0Y9MOEJqzDuSpew4lATjxGd8o4jDEMPZvpdtphQCEwUWQTsyGcZ6tNt1C3RkMAqTR6yXZ7ddGzp7zbprAyFkPwnP1WenVcpWRP8sX9tU5Zyz98kr9KIGD" width="276"></span></span></span></span></p><p dir="ltr">I was able to get that user's exact home address.</p><p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Telegram told me it's not an issue. If you use this feature, please make sure to disable it. Unless you want your location to be accessible by everyone.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Unfortunately, Telegram poor application security can be reflected with the number of scammers they have within that feature. Telegram allows users to create local groups within a geographical area. Many scammers spoof their location and try to sell fake bitcoin investments, hacking tools, SSNs that are used for unemployment fraud, and so on. The amount of illegal activities I saw there make the&nbsp;</span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Silk_Road_(marketplace)" target="_blank"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Silkroad&nbsp;</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true">look like amateurs ran it.&nbsp;<br></span></p></span></p></span></p></div>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.ahmed.nyc/2021/01/if-you-use-this-feature-on-telegram.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25641399</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 02:41:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Vons, Pavilions to Replace Drivers with Independent Contractors]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 83 | Comments 105 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25640294">thread link</a>) | @danso
<br/>
January 4, 2021 | https://knock-la.com/vons-fires-delivery-drivers-prop-22-e899ee24ffd0 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://knock-la.com/vons-fires-delivery-drivers-prop-22-e899ee24ffd0">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><div><div><h2 id="19f8">News</h2><h2 id="a67f">California begins to see the devastating effects of Proposition 22.</h2><div><div><div><p><a href="https://medium.com/@mydickerson?source=post_page-----e899ee24ffd0--------------------------------" rel="noopener"><img alt="Mike Dickerson" src="https://miro.medium.com/fit/c/96/96/1*53IHqPFrt1okeXEPGL9a2Q.jpeg" width="48" height="48"></a></p></div></div></div><figure><div role="button" tabindex="0"><div><div><p><img alt="Image for post" src="https://miro.medium.com/max/9806/1*LzqfF7ZQEYRE_TnBHrdVpQ.jpeg" width="4903" height="2712" srcset="https://miro.medium.com/max/552/1*LzqfF7ZQEYRE_TnBHrdVpQ.jpeg 276w, https://miro.medium.com/max/1104/1*LzqfF7ZQEYRE_TnBHrdVpQ.jpeg 552w, https://miro.medium.com/max/1280/1*LzqfF7ZQEYRE_TnBHrdVpQ.jpeg 640w, https://miro.medium.com/max/1400/1*LzqfF7ZQEYRE_TnBHrdVpQ.jpeg 700w" sizes="700px" data-old-src="https://miro.medium.com/max/60/1*LzqfF7ZQEYRE_TnBHrdVpQ.jpeg?q=20"></p></div></div></div><figcaption>(Source: <a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Aves_en_Vons.JPG" rel="noopener">AdriÃ¡n CerÃ³n</a>, <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 4.0</a>, via Wikimedia Commons)</figcaption></figure><p id="fcd4">When Dylanâ€™s grocery delivery arrived a few days before New Years, it came with some bad news. The delivery driver who brought his groceries from Vons mentioned that drivers across the state are getting fired by Vons, Pavilions, and other California stores owned by Albertsons Companies in late February. Stores will instead turn to a third-party delivery service using independent contractors.</p><p id="d033">â€œI was disturbed and disappointed that Vons would eliminate these jobs. I felt like they were the only remaining company that treated delivery drivers ethically but no longer,â€� said Dylan.</p><p id="1f42">After publication, an Albertsons representative sent the following statement: â€œWe will transition that portion of our eCommerce operations to third-party logistics providers.â€� She added â€œWhile we know that this move will help us create a more efficient operation, it wasnâ€™t a decision we made lightly or without a great deal of consideration.â€�</p><p id="10d5">Drivers under the Albertsons Companies umbrella are employees, while Ralphs delivery is operated by Instacart and Target uses Shipt, a similar app. At Bay Area stores, drivers are unionized, and will not be affected by the layoffs. For southern California shoppers, this move leaves them without a grocery delivery option that treats drivers as employees.</p><p id="baaa">Unions are vowing to fight the change, says Jim Araby, Director of Strategic Campaigns at UCFW5. â€œThe only drivers that kept their jobs were the unionized drivers in the Bay Area. All the other drivers in California were laid off because they were non-union. We represent those drivers and they will keep their job.â€�</p><p id="4b12">These layoffs are unsurprising after the passage of Proposition 22, which gutted worker protections while making it easier for companies to shift financial burdens onto newly-designated â€œindependent contractors.â€� In a <a rel="noopener" href="https://knock-la.com/the-case-for-voting-no-on-ca-prop-22-a64d25b2828d">piece for KNOCK</a> last year, Keith F. Eberl predicted this exact outcome in the opening paragraph:</p><blockquote><p id="95b6">â€œContrary to the companiesâ€™ deceptive ad campaign and intimidating messages to their workers, Prop 22 does not preserve driver flexibility or save drivers from politicians. What Prop 22 does do is change current law so the companies can shift their costs to the driver and diminish or remove driversâ€™ rights, protections, and benefits. Prop 22 will also block driversâ€™ ability to organize so they canâ€™t collectively bargain a contract. In addition, this proposition will block local governments from writing or enforcing protections for drivers.â€�</p></blockquote><p id="a03f">The only surprise is the speed at which Albertsons reversed course on its commitments to workers. This move comes after nearly a year of celebrating grocery store workers for feeding communities. <a href="https://www.vons.com/steps-we-are-taking-at-your-grocery-store.html" rel="noopener">Earlier this year</a>, Albertsons Companies President &amp; CEO Vivek Sankaran said the company was â€œtaking care of our team.â€� Albertsons Companies â€œare workingâ€¦ to ensure that every member of our team who faces a crisis can have peace of mind that we will help them get through it.â€�</p><p id="c5d5">Albertsons was happy to reap public goodwill during the pandemic. But once Prop 22 gave the company the option of replacing workers with lower-paid contractors, they jumped at the opportunity. Employees received notice during the holidays that their employment would end one month into the new year.</p><p id="66cc">Early in the pandemic, union members demanded hazard pay, additional medical leave, and employee protections during the pandemic. In March, Safeway and Northern California grocery workers <a href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/business/article/Coronavirus-Safeway-reaches-new-agreement-for-15150811.php" rel="noopener">reached an agreement</a> providing these additional benefits.</p><p id="452b">Labor and management were able to cooperate in April, requesting that grocery workers be designated as first responders. In an April j<a href="https://www.albertsonscompanies.com/helping-you-through-covid-19/albertsons-companies-ucfw-launch-joint-effort.html" rel="noopener">oint statement</a>, Sankaran and United Food and Commercial Workers International Union (UFCW) President Marc Perrone wrote:</p><blockquote><p id="c86a">â€œThis joint action is an example of how all Americans must work together to protect everyone working on the frontlines. This includesâ€¦ associates at our nationâ€™s grocery stores who are providing communities with the essential food and supplies needed to weather this public health crisis.â€�</p></blockquote><p id="0a33">Negotiations in October <a href="https://www.ocregister.com/2020/10/08/grocery-warehouse-workers-truck-drivers-give-notice-of-potential-strike/" rel="noopener">turned contentious</a>, as members of the Teamsters issued a notice of potential strike due to rising healthcare costs. Lou Villavazo, who chairs the bargaining effort, told the <a href="https://www.ocregister.com/2020/10/08/grocery-warehouse-workers-truck-drivers-give-notice-of-potential-strike/" rel="noopener">Orange County Register</a> that â€œemployers have been bargaining in bad faith. Weâ€™ve had over 18 bargaining sessions with them and we provided our economic proposal â€¦ but no response.â€�</p><p id="e2db">Organized labor made the difference for drivers in the Bay Area, who will remain as employees for now. But without the power of a union, southern California drivers lack an organizational structure through which to fight back.</p><p id="b343">Many, myself included, turned to Vons and Albertsons stores for their groceries, knowing that drivers were employed with benefits. Unionized drivers offered a clear alternative to the <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-12-24/no-holiday-cheer-for-gig-workers-hunting-your-last-minute-gifts" rel="noopener">hellscape of gig-economy apps</a> like Instacart.</p><p id="a579">In a <a href="https://www.albertsonscompanies.com/newsroom/appreciation-pay-for-front-line-associates.html" rel="noopener">March 2020 statement</a>, Sankaran said â€œthese times are unprecedented in the grocery industryâ€¦ [a] simple â€˜thank youâ€™ doesnâ€™t seem like quite enough.â€� He was right. Delivery drivers deserve healthcare, job protections, and fair wages. Workers won those fights this year because they fought as a union. With DoorDash taking over in February, that united front will be gone.</p><p id="26c2">You can contact Albertsons Companies and let them know what you think of this move:</p><p id="2910">Vons Retail Store/Corporate Phone Number: 877â€“723â€“3929</p><p id="2f7e">Albertsons Retail Store/Corporate Phone Number: 877â€“723â€“3929</p><p id="2b59"><em>EDITORâ€™S NOTE: After publication, Albertsonâ€™s responded to KNOCKâ€™s request for comment. This piece has since been edited to clarify that union drivers will not be laid off and that workers facing layoffs in Southern California are non-union, as well as to include statements from both Albertsons and UCFW5. The scheduled date of the layoffs was also corrected.</em></p></div></div></section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://knock-la.com/vons-fires-delivery-drivers-prop-22-e899ee24ffd0</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25640294</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:25:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[My Google Traffic Has Fallen to Zero]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 372 | Comments 265 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25640217">thread link</a>) | @josephjrobison
<br/>
January 4, 2021 | https://www.goodcheapandfast.com/2020 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.goodcheapandfast.com/2020">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-nc-base="header" data-controller="AncillaryLayout">
      

      

      <div>

        

        <div>
          
            
              
                
                  
                
              
            
          

          <main>
            
              <section data-content-field="main-content">
                <div data-type="page" data-updated-on="1608230832114" id="page-5fd3a159f92762251f1c6eca"><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-016a72dee6b3751c6cf2"><p><h3>Google's December 2020 Core Algorithm Update drove this website's traffic to new highs last week, then it fell to zero.</h3></p></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1607704925648_14759"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5bbe4cb0d745625c9d104763/1607705105493-A75SVPI65VJDT5XKLWXI/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kEYoQxTi5oKpiEba6WUyZp4UqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYy7Mythp_T-mtop-vrsUOmeInPi9iDjx9w8K4ZfjXt2ds6qln6HpuaNqwonEk3tr1DAktcgtHSS7CyIBz9i8uwd7zs2yPjc1ECvpa5Zm_kMqw/Eo9bZOCWMAARRGD.jpeg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5bbe4cb0d745625c9d104763/1607705105493-A75SVPI65VJDT5XKLWXI/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kEYoQxTi5oKpiEba6WUyZp4UqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYy7Mythp_T-mtop-vrsUOmeInPi9iDjx9w8K4ZfjXt2ds6qln6HpuaNqwonEk3tr1DAktcgtHSS7CyIBz9i8uwd7zs2yPjc1ECvpa5Zm_kMqw/Eo9bZOCWMAARRGD.jpeg" data-image-dimensions="1536x549" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Eo9bZOCWMAARRGD.jpeg" data-load="false" data-image-id="5fd3a211c4a2b267e28574c8" data-type="image" src="https://www.goodcheapandfast.com/Eo9bZOCWMAARRGD.jpeg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1607704925648_15047"><div><p>This website stopped receiving referrals from Google last night. It's a total wipeout after two years of building a business that's also my full-time focus and my family's sole source of income. I'm heartbroken and confused.</p><h2><strong>The Cruelest Year</strong></h2><p>2020 has been awful, and despite this new challenge that I face, I still count myself blessed. A friend of mine has lived in a veritable shoebox for a decade, pumping every hour and cent he had into building two of the most beloved bars in New York City. He filed for bankruptcy last month. Another friend attended a family reunion in February; it was the last time that she'd see several of her relatives (who died from COVID-19 in the weeks that followed).</p><p>Again, no matter what happens to this site, I really do feel fortunate and blessed.</p><h2><strong>The Risk of Relying on Big Tech</strong></h2><p>As much as I've tried to diversify <em>Good, Cheap and Fast</em>'<em>s</em> revenue and traffic, I haven’t escaped the gravitational pull of Amazon and Google. This poses major risks and I advise caution to anyone considering a similar business model.</p><p>In April of this year, Amazon <a href="https://searchengineland.com/amazon-affiliate-commission-rates-cut-332966">reduced the affiliate commissions</a> that it pays to online publishers. My revenue fell by 41% as a result. It was a crushing blow that I attempted to mitigate by joining other affiliate programs, but they didn't pan out. The median conversion rate of the 70 other websites that I linked to was a meager 0.8%, which is approximately 1/10 of the conversion rate on Amazon.&nbsp;</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1607784280213_34634"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          
        

        
          
          <figcaption>
            <p>Best Buy is a great company. Nevertheless, my visitors are 6,500% more likely to make a purchase from Amazon.</p>
          </figcaption>
        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1607784280213_34922"><div><p>Then, <a href="https://www.mariehaynes.com/may-2020-core-google-update/">Google's May 2020 algorithm update</a> cut my traffic by around 70%.</p><p>I didn't publish much on this website between March and April because I was focused on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/johndefeo_for-anyone-looking-for-coronavirus-newsupdates-activity-6644299863842447360-xaYA/">learning about COVID-19</a> with the goal of keeping my family safe. It's reasonable to assume that this hiatus may have resulted in this site being on the wrong side of Google's algorithm, so from May until now, I've worked seven days a week on improving this site -- around 1,200 hours in total.</p><p>My Google traffic gradually recovered, reached new highs, then it went terminal.</p><h2><strong>Doing the Right Thing</strong></h2></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1607784280213_18633"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5bbe4cb0d745625c9d104763/1607784443523-YRG92MPU12H93L80Q7PT/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kJeCjys4TeC3DGU_a1akXtdZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpyUUXYGPH9DHj5celJrvHX8W6t_uE79Pi8unyS9KZtA3CYWXOatDWau0S9eSkX7oGw/Screen+Shot+2020-12-12+at+9.47.00+AM.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5bbe4cb0d745625c9d104763/1607784443523-YRG92MPU12H93L80Q7PT/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kJeCjys4TeC3DGU_a1akXtdZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpyUUXYGPH9DHj5celJrvHX8W6t_uE79Pi8unyS9KZtA3CYWXOatDWau0S9eSkX7oGw/Screen+Shot+2020-12-12+at+9.47.00+AM.png" data-image-dimensions="659x872" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="This website is committed to privacy; it was one of the first 100 companies to endorse the  Contract for the Web ." data-load="false" data-image-id="5fd4d7fb164d0f203c51bdf9" data-type="image" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5bbe4cb0d745625c9d104763/1607784443523-YRG92MPU12H93L80Q7PT/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kJeCjys4TeC3DGU_a1akXtdZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpyUUXYGPH9DHj5celJrvHX8W6t_uE79Pi8unyS9KZtA3CYWXOatDWau0S9eSkX7oGw/Screen+Shot+2020-12-12+at+9.47.00+AM.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
          
          <figcaption>
            <p>This website is committed to privacy; it was one of the first 100 companies to endorse the <a href="https://contractfortheweb.org/">Contract for the Web</a>.</p>
          </figcaption>
        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1607784280213_18921"><p>Since I launched this site in Oct. 2018, it has never contained ads, trackers nor slideshows. I don't collect any personally identifiable information. I don't allow guest posts or third-party content. I'm completely transparent about how this website makes money as well as the methods and limitations of my product selection methodology. Every affiliate link on this site is properly disclosed and wrapped in a "rel sponsored" tag. I take the time to read scientific and medical research as it relates to the topics that I cover, and when I find a product that is potentially harmful (like weighted eye masks), I share my findings with every major publisher who has written positive things about that product. I use my expertise to <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/johndefeo_if-you-support-a-charity-via-amazonsmile-activity-6737737229449379840-vc6I/">support charity</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/johndefeo_to-my-friends-in-journalism-be-cautious-activity-6733095426775404544-FbxR/">to teach colleagues about scams</a>. All of these factors have built trust in my brand. I know this because the percentage of my visitors who go forth to make a purchase has climbed steadily for two years.</p></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1607784280213_68769"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5bbe4cb0d745625c9d104763/1607785322376-GN0139MP1XEGAGBNW4VL/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kFqYFZLDQ5urJwi9gnzSGHJZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIERTuUcWuFWTMfMjVW38Nggz8HmC14XFJR0_lAEGtGZ8/Screen+Shot+2020-12-12+at+10.01.20+AM.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5bbe4cb0d745625c9d104763/1607785322376-GN0139MP1XEGAGBNW4VL/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kFqYFZLDQ5urJwi9gnzSGHJZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIERTuUcWuFWTMfMjVW38Nggz8HmC14XFJR0_lAEGtGZ8/Screen+Shot+2020-12-12+at+10.01.20+AM.png" data-image-dimensions="849x518" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="My traffic and revenue are subject to forces outside my control, however, this stat measures the factors in my control." data-load="false" data-image-id="5fd4db6ae5ac582896f9dcc2" data-type="image" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5bbe4cb0d745625c9d104763/1607785322376-GN0139MP1XEGAGBNW4VL/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kFqYFZLDQ5urJwi9gnzSGHJZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIERTuUcWuFWTMfMjVW38Nggz8HmC14XFJR0_lAEGtGZ8/Screen+Shot+2020-12-12+at+10.01.20+AM.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
          
          <figcaption>
            <p>My traffic and revenue are subject to forces outside my control, however, this stat measures the factors in my control.</p>
          </figcaption>
        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1607784280213_69057"><div><p>But, as much as I'd like this website to be a destination, it will never be one.&nbsp;</p><p><em>Good, Cheap and Fast</em> was profiled by big name websites like <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90274504/hate-browsing-amazon-this-is-the-ultimate-no-frills-shopping-site">Fast Company</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/kottke/status/1067547920617086976">Kottke</a>. These media mentions drove hundreds of thousands of visits. Nevertheless, if someone who was referred to this website two years ago is looking for a cheap portable generator today, he or she is much more likely to Google "cheap portable generator" than to come to my homepage.</p><p>It's understandable. Alas, without search visibility, this site in invisible.</p><h2><strong>Can a Domain Be Cursed?</strong></h2><p>I did my due diligence before I registered goodcheapandfast.com. It had no backlink history and it had only existed previously as a parked domain in 2013. There are no obvious skeletons in this domain's closet, yet strange things have been afoot, almost since day one.</p><p>For example, Bing didn't even index this website's homepage a month after <em>Good, Cheap and Fast</em> was linked to from websites like Esquire and Slate. I contacted bingwb@microsoft.com with my concerns and received this response:</p><blockquote><p>Good day and thank you for your patience while we investigated the issue.</p><p>Firstly, I am happy to provide you information that our product review group succeeded in removing the block of the site. After submitting your site to be reviewed the team has decided to lift the  block. Please allow up to 2-3 weeks for your site to be crawled indexed and serving again.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>I am unable to provide you the specifics of the block as our product review team does not share details of the block.</p></blockquote><p>The mystery didn't end there. Two years later, this website has received fewer than 100 total referrals from Bing. That's not normal and neither is this: Since 2019, pages on this website started dropping in-and-out of Google's results. An article that ranked #1 would disappear entirely, then reappear, then disappear, then reappear. These were like mini strokes. Sometimes the traffic bounced back in full; other times it gradually faded away.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1607704925648_28921"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5bbe4cb0d745625c9d104763/1607705806377-HKE2K8E19Z6N7L9RDYFI/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kBBWv4dEpfcKRhEc-mPgvhhZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIH_TPfyAj5DK2q4KS84c9dntObHZV9V2os84uj8Aa0M0KMshLAGzx4R3EDFOm1kBS/Google-Indexing-Bugs.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5bbe4cb0d745625c9d104763/1607705806377-HKE2K8E19Z6N7L9RDYFI/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kBBWv4dEpfcKRhEc-mPgvhhZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIH_TPfyAj5DK2q4KS84c9dntObHZV9V2os84uj8Aa0M0KMshLAGzx4R3EDFOm1kBS/Google-Indexing-Bugs.jpg" data-image-dimensions="750x229" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="I have a hard time describing the frustration and confusion that I’ve felt watching my fate swing like a pendulum." data-load="false" data-image-id="5fd3a4ce872d8f1a0acde79a" data-type="image" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5bbe4cb0d745625c9d104763/1607705806377-HKE2K8E19Z6N7L9RDYFI/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kBBWv4dEpfcKRhEc-mPgvhhZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIH_TPfyAj5DK2q4KS84c9dntObHZV9V2os84uj8Aa0M0KMshLAGzx4R3EDFOm1kBS/Google-Indexing-Bugs.jpg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
          
          <figcaption>
            <p>I have a hard time describing the frustration and confusion that I’ve felt watching my fate swing like a pendulum.</p>
          </figcaption>
        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1607704925648_29209"><div><p>I've managed dozens of websites over the last 17 years -- most recently as the head of content strategy and search engine optimization for one of the largest publishing companies in the U.S. -- and I've never seen anything like this before.</p><h2><strong>The Lunatic Fringe</strong></h2><p>I’m not too proud to ask for help, especially when my livelihood depends on it, so I swallowed any professional embarrassment and shared my plight with Google spokespersons and online marketing professionals. The best that I've gotten in return was a <a href="https://twitter.com/dannysullivan/status/1327323523828703232">superficial acknowledgement</a> that resulted in a dead end.</p><p>I get it. My situation is weird and it's not easily explainable. But, the ramifications are very real and they threaten my financial (and mental) well being.</p><blockquote><p>(The closest analogue that I've had to this experience was dealing with the State of NJ Treasury, trying to recover unclaimed property that was purchased by Anthony DeFeo, in the custody of John Anthony DeFeo for the benefit of John William Anthony DeFeo. It dragged on for two years.)</p></blockquote><p>There's an old proverb, "Who knows what is good and what is bad." </p><p>Maybe my own plight, which admittedly doesn't even register as a drop in the sea of 2020 misery, is part of something good that has yet to reveal itself. </p><p>I'm doing the best that I can to stay positive, but it isn't easy.</p><p>———</p><p><strong>Update, 12/15</strong> - My traffic has settled into a 90% loss. I at least feel better (in a sad way) that I have been heard and explicitly told <a href="https://twitter.com/dannysullivan/status/1338949972507590656">that there is no recourse</a>.</p><p><strong>Postscript</strong> - If you’ve made it this far and you’re feeling magnanimous, I humbly ask that you share <a href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/trying-to-raise-much-as-possible-fight-my-cancer">my friend Chris May’s online fundraiser</a>. Chris was laid off earlier this year, then diagnosed with Stage 4 colon cancer. He is 45 years old.</p></div></div></div></div><div><div><div><div><div data-block-json="{&quot;hSize&quot;:null,&quot;floatDir&quot;:null,&quot;collectionId&quot;:&quot;5c9fa5b8971a1874e4775783&quot;,&quot;design&quot;:&quot;list&quot;,&quot;headerText&quot;:&quot;Featured&quot;,&quot;textSize&quot;:&quot;medium&quot;,&quot;pageSize&quot;:10,&quot;imageAspectRatio&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;columnWidth&quot;:270,&quot;gutter&quot;:60,&quot;listImageSize&quot;:10,&quot;listImageAlignment&quot;:&quot;left&quot;,&quot;slidesPerRow&quot;:3,&quot;textAlignment&quot;:&quot;left&quot;,&quot;showTitle&quot;:true,&quot;showThumbnail&quot;:true,&quot;showExcerpt&quot;:true,&quot;showReadMoreLink&quot;:false,&quot;showPrice&quot;:true,&quot;productQuickViewEnabled&quot;:false,&quot;showPastOrUpcomingEvents&quot;:&quot;upcoming&quot;,&quot;metadataPosition&quot;:&quot;below-content&quot;,&quot;primaryMetadata&quot;:&quot;none&quot;,&quot;secondaryMetadata&quot;:&quot;none&quot;,&quot;filter&quot;:{&quot;categoryIds&quot;:null},&quot;autoCrop&quot;:true,&quot;lightbox&quot;:true,&quot;mixedContent&quot;:true,&quot;blockId&quot;:&quot;a748e58d2531d057b519&quot;}" data-block-type="55" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1607704925648_36997"><div>



<div>

  <div>

    

    <div>

      

        <div data-click-through-url="https://www.goodcheapandfast.com/about">

          
            <!-- Thumbnail -->
            

  
  <div>
    <a href="https://www.goodcheapandfast.com/about" data-title="John DeFeo, Founder of Good, Cheap and Fast" data-description="<p class=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;>&quot;Good, cheap and fast -- pick two,&quot; is one of my favorite sayings. It's usually true, however, I built this website to help you find top-rated, inexpensive products within minutes. Here's the catch: It's a slow process behind the scenes.</p><p class=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;>Since 2018, I've spent thousands of hours scouring the web for above-average products that sell for below-average prices. Along the way, I've learned how to spot counterfeit goods, disingenuous sellers, fake reviews (and real reviews that aren't particularly helpful).</p><p class=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;><em>Good, Cheap and Fast</em> has no ads, no slideshows and no tracking pixels. I value your time and your privacy and I hope that others will do the same.</p><p class=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;>In the recent past, I was head of insights for the company that published <em>AnandTech</em>, <em>Laptop Mag</em>, <em>Tom's Guide</em> and <em>Tom's Hardware</em> (as well as educational sites like <em>Space.com</em> and <em>Live Science</em>). I worked with product reviewers, lab testers and journalists each day for six years.</p><p class=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;>Before that, I was director of business intelligence for <em>The Street</em> (a financial media company) and a strategist at publications like <em>Car &amp;amp; Driver</em>, <em>Elle</em>, <em>Popular Photography</em> and <em>Woman's Day</em>. I also co-founded <em>Debonair</em>, a men's fashion and lifestyle publication. I’m a graduate of New York University’s Tisch School of the Arts and I live in Brooklyn, New York.</p><p class=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;>You can contact me via <a href=&quot;mailto:john@goodcheapandfast.com&quot; target=&quot;&quot;><strong>e-mail</strong></a> or find me on <a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/johndefeo/&quot; target=&quot;&quot;><strong>LinkedIn</strong></a>, <a href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/person/john-defeo-10a7&quot; target=&quot;&quot;><strong>Crunchbase</strong></a> and <a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/johndefeo&quot; target=&quot;&quot;><strong>Twitter</strong></a>.</p>">
      <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5bbe4cb0d745625c9d104763/1601559434612-IKX5K2REA2KKRY4S6S57/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPJXHKy2-mnvrsdpGQjlhod7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmihaE5rlzFBImxTetd_yW5btdZx37rH5fuWDtePBPDaHF5LxdCVHkNEqSYPsUQCdT/John-W-DeFeo-Headshot.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5bbe4cb0d745625c9d104763/1601559434612-IKX5K2REA2KKRY4S6S57/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPJXHKy2-mnvrsdpGQjlhod7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmihaE5rlzFBImxTetd_yW5btdZx37rH5fuWDtePBPDaHF5LxdCVHkNEqSYPsUQCdT/John-W-DeFeo-Headshot.jpg" data-image-dimensions="1000x1000" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="John DeFeo, Founder of Good, Cheap and Fast" data-load="false" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5bbe4cb0d745625c9d104763/1601559434612-IKX5K2REA2KKRY4S6S57/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPJXHKy2-mnvrsdpGQjlhod7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmihaE5rlzFBImxTetd_yW5btdZx37rH5fuWDtePBPDaHF5LxdCVHkNEqSYPsUQCdT/John-W-DeFeo-Headshot.jpg">

    

    

        

        

      </p>
    </a>

    <!-- Products: Quick View -->
    

  </div>
  



          

          <div data-animation-role="content">

            <!-- Metadata (Above Title) -->
            

            
              <!-- Title -->
              
            

            <!-- Metadata (Below Title) -->
            

            
              
            

            
              

              
              <!--- Gallery: Caption Description -->
                <div><p>"Good, cheap and fast -- pick two," is one of my favorite sayings. It's usually true, however, I built this website to help you find top-rated, inexpensive products within minutes. Here's the catch: It's a slow process behind the scenes.</p><p>Since 2018, I've spent thousands of hours scouring the web for above-average products that sell for below-average prices. Along the way, I've learned how to spot counterfeit goods, disingenuous sellers, fake reviews (and real reviews that aren't particularly helpful).</p><p><em>Good, Cheap and Fast</em> has no ads, no slideshows and no tracking pixels. I value your time and your privacy and I hope that others will do the same.</p><p>In the recent past, I was head of insights for the company that published <em>AnandTech</em>, <em>Laptop Mag</em>, <em>Tom's Guide</em> and <em>Tom's Hardware</em> (as well as educational sites like <em>Space.com</em> and <em>Live Science</em>). I worked with product reviewers, lab testers and journalists …</p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section></main></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.goodcheapandfast.com/2020">https://www.goodcheapandfast.com/2020</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.goodcheapandfast.com/2020</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25640217</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:17:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ZX81 Webserver]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 109 | Comments 43 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25638936">thread link</a>) | @nickt
<br/>
January 4, 2021 | http://zx81-siggi.zx-team.org/index.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://zx81-siggi.zx-team.org/index.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://zx81-siggi.zx-team.org/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25638936</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 22:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Quitting a New Job]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 184 | Comments 213 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25637922">thread link</a>) | @fullung
<br/>
January 4, 2021 | https://yolken.net/blog/quitting-a-new-job | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://yolken.net/blog/quitting-a-new-job">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
    <div>
      <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>Two years ago, I did something that I’d never done in my career before- I left a job
(at <a href="https://nuro.ai/">Nuro</a>) only a few months after starting it. In this post, I want to explain
what happened and what I learned from the experience.</p>

<h2 id="what-happened">What happened</h2>

<h4 id="the-job-switch">The job switch</h4>

<p>Back in the spring of 2019, I decided to leave <a href="https://www.stripe.com/">Stripe</a>, where I’d
been a software engineer for about a year and a half. The full details are best left
to a separate post, but at a high level I just wasn’t very happy with my personal situation; the
work I was doing in compute infrastructure had the unfortunate combination of being both
overly stressful and underappreciated. At the same time, I felt like my career prospects
were limited because the upper rungs of Stripe’s engineering individual contributor (IC) ladder put
a lot of emphasis on cross-team coordination and other, managerial-like activities that I didn’t
enjoy and felt I wasn’t very good at.</p>

<p>Given how hot the job market was at the time and the number of other, seemingly more interesting
opportunities available, I figured that I had nothing to lose by interviewing elsewhere.</p>

<p>After a few weekends of furiously-paced <a href="https://yolken.net/blog/master-coding-interviews">Leetcoding</a>, I was ready.
Unlike my previous job searches, there wasn’t any particular company that I was aspiring
to get into; instead, I just went through my <a href="https://yolken.net/blog/six-years-of-emails">backlog of recruiting emails</a>
and wrote back to a bunch that looked interesting. Among the messages I responded to was one
about <a href="https://nuro.ai/">Nuro</a>, an autonomous vehicle startup that was attempting to do driverless
grocery delivery.</p>

<p>Over the following weeks, I went through the full recruitment slog, starting with lots of
recruiter phone calls, then following up with technical phone screens for a subset of
those, then doing onsite interviews for a subset of those. In the end, I got offers from seven
places, including Nuro.</p>

<p>During the process, I didn’t fall in love with any of the options. But, there
was something that made me feel more optimistic about Nuro than the other choices. Being a
hardware-oriented, robotics company, it was just really different from all of my previous employers,
and, after years of feeling stuck in my career, maybe different was good.</p>

<p>The company was super secretive about its technology; I wasn’t allowed to tour the office, for
instance, because they had hardware prototypes lying around that only employees were allowed to
see. I also wasn’t invited to ride along in their test cars, which would have been both fun and
informative. The external signs were good, though- they had raised a billion dollars from Softbank
and others, and the employee reviews on <a href="https://www.glassdoor.com/">Glassdoor</a> were gushing.</p>

<p>Aside from being in a somewhat different space than my previous employers, another potential
downside was the commute. Stripe and my three jobs before that were all within a 15 minute walk
of my apartment in San Francisco. Nuro’s office was 40 miles away in Mountain View, which was
more than an hour each way by train. But, I had done longer commutes earlier in my career and figured
that I could handle it.</p>

<p>In the end, I went with my impulses and signed the offer. I had my last day at Stripe, took a short
vacation, and then showed up at the Nuro office, brimming with optimism, for my first day two weeks
later.</p>

<h4 id="realizing-my-mistake">Realizing my mistake</h4>

<p>Unfortunately, that optimism lasted for a grand total of 2 days. By Wednesday of my first week,
as I was riding the train home, I realized that I had made a mistake. My colleagues were
friendly and smart, and the company was doing interesting things, but the job just felt like a
lifestyle downgrade to me.</p>

<p>At Stripe and each of my jobs before that, I had had a short commute to a beautiful office, and
got to experience the instant gratification associated with developing purely software-based
products. Now, I was stuck taking a crowded train to a dark office littered with hardware parts,
working on a product that would take many years to reach mass-market adoption due to pesky little
things like manufacturing and road safety.</p>

<p>I had left Stripe seeking an upgrade, but instead I got a downgrade. And, while minor improvements
were possible, it seemed unlikely that things would completely change for the better in the near
term.</p>

<h4 id="getting-back-on-track">Getting back on track</h4>

<p>At this point, I had three choices:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Quit immediately</li>
  <li>Start exploring new opportunities but don’t quit until something better is lined up</li>
  <li>Stick it out for at least a year</li>
</ol>

<p>My first instinct was to take option 1 and just go back to Stripe. When I reached out to my HR
contact, though, I found out that I’d have to go through team matching again and also get a new
offer; even though I’d left on good terms less than a month before, I couldn’t just revert back to
my previous position and pay. This was disappointing, but after giving it a little more thought,
I figured it was for the best because I had left Stripe for specific reasons; going back
to my old job wouldn’t fix those or make me feel better about them.</p>

<p>Another variant of option 1 would be to quit and take one of the other offers I had gotten
during my search. But, I had already rejected those for what I thought were good reasons,
so this didn’t feel like the best way out.</p>

<p>Option 3 was the one that would look the least bad from a resume perspective, and this seems to be
what a lot of people in tech do when they don’t like a job. But, life is short, I was really feeling
unhappy with the choice I had made, and I figured it wasn’t really fair to my colleagues at Nuro to
stick in a job that my heart wasn’t in.</p>

<p>So, in the end, I decided that option 2 was the best fit for me. I continued at Nuro and did my best
to get up-to-speed and to contribute to my team’s work, but at the same time jumped right back
into the job market. In addition to keeping things open with Stripe, I
<a href="https://yolken.net/blog/triplebyte-review">tried Triplebyte</a>, responded to more recruiter emails, and also
reached out to some former colleagues about the companies they were now at.</p>

<p>I then went through the whole recruitment process with a new set of companies. This time,
though, I was a lot pickier about where I interviewed (nothing in hardware or with long commutes!);
after a few weeks, I had four new choices including an updated offer from Stripe. After
a good amount of due diligence, significantly more than I had done in my previous search, I
decided to go to <a href="https://segment.com/">Segment</a>.</p>

<p>When I put in my notice at Nuro, people were surprised that I was leaving so soon, but ultimately
were understanding. I left, took a short vacation, and then started at Segment. Thankfully,
the new job was a much better fit for me, and I’m much happier now!</p>

<h2 id="lessons-learned">Lessons learned</h2>

<h4 id="do-your-due-diligence">Do your due diligence</h4>

<p>Switching jobs is a big deal, and it shouldn’t be done impulsively. Ideally, your due
diligence before signing a new offer should include:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Meeting with the team you’ll be working with in a low-stress, non-interview setting</li>
  <li>Touring the office and understanding what your specific workspace will be like</li>
  <li>Trying out the commute for a few days (if it’s significantly different than your current one)</li>
  <li>Trying out any new languages/technologies that you’ll be using on the job</li>
  <li>Getting hands-on demos of the company’s products (if they’re not freely accessible to consumers
  already)</li>
  <li>Seeing a summary of the company’s income and expenses over time (if not public)</li>
</ol>

<p>Learning about these things doesn’t guarantee that you’ll be happy in your new job, but it
at least reduces the risk of any unexpected surprises after you start.</p>

<h4 id="its-ok-to-quit-after-a-few-weeks-just-dont-make-it-a-pattern">It’s ok to quit after a few weeks (just don’t make it a pattern)</h4>

<p>When I started my second job search, I was worried that the short
tenure in the job I was trying to leave would be a turn-off to perspective employers. In reality,
however, it wasn’t a big deal- people asked about it, but seemed satisfied with my 20 second
summary and then moved on to other things.</p>

<p>The sense I get is that you’re allowed to quit a new job once in your career without any
repercussions. If you do it multiple times, however, then recruiters and hiring managers might
have second thoughts about interviewing you without strong internal references or some other signal
that you’ll be a good employee.</p>

<h4 id="switch-teams-before-quitting">Switch teams before quitting</h4>

<p>As I noted in a <a href="https://yolken.net/blog/leaving-a-job">previous post</a>, switching teams is a lot easier than
switching jobs. I didn’t do this before I left Stripe because there weren’t any other teams that I
was super enthusiastic about at the time. But, in retrospect, I probably should have given this a
try before quitting.</p>

<p>Even if the new team hadn’t been a perfect fit, it would have at least bought some time and given
me some additional experience that could help in future work. This is what I did at Google
and Airbnb, and in both cases the “second team” was what really opened up new opportunities for me.</p>

  </div>

  
</article>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://yolken.net/blog/quitting-a-new-job</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25637922</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 21:00:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Jack Ma hasn't been seen publicly in 2 months]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 86 | Comments 19 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25636045">thread link</a>) | @rukshn
<br/>
January 4, 2021 | https://www.businessinsider.in/tech/news/where-is-jack-ma-alibabas-billionaire-founder-is-reportedly-missing-following-chinas-crackdowns-on-his-companies/articleshow/80094868.cms | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.businessinsider.in/tech/news/where-is-jack-ma-alibabas-billionaire-founder-is-reportedly-missing-following-chinas-crackdowns-on-his-companies/articleshow/80094868.cms">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div id="datatxt80094868read"><div data-den="denmark"><div><ul>
 <li>The Chinese billionaire <a target="_blank" href="https://au.finance.yahoo.com/news/jack-ma-missing-232138645.html" rel="nofollow">Jack Ma is thought to be missing</a>, Jessica Yun reported for Yahoo Finance on Sunday.</li>
 <li>The <keyword keytype="Company" smid="0" usetype="2" keywordseo="Alibaba" actualkeyword="Alibaba">Alibaba</keyword> and <keyword keytype="UnKnown" smid="0" usetype="2" keywordseo="Ant-Group" actualkeyword="Ant Group">Ant Group</keyword> founder has not been seen publicly in more than two months, and he was abruptly <a target="_blank" href="https://www.ft.com/content/a91dfeae-da1e-4348-8212-bbfbe94d93bd" rel="nofollow">replaced as a judge</a> on the African talent show he founded.</li>
 <li>Chinese regulators have recently <a target="_blank" href="https://www.businessinsider.com/alibaba-antitrust-jack-ma-ant-group-beijing-regulators-2020-12" rel="nofollow">cracked down on Ma's business empire</a>, halting Ant Group's initial public offering in November and <a target="_blank" href="https://www.businessinsider.com/alibaba-antitrust-jack-ma-ant-group-beijing-regulators-2020-12" rel="nofollow">launching an antitrust investigation into Alibaba</a> in December.</li>
 <li>In October, Ma <a target="_blank" href="https://www.businessinsider.com/what-happened-ant-group-ipo-jack-ma-alipay-2020-11" rel="nofollow">criticized China's banking rules</a>.</li>
 <li>Ma, who has <a target="_blank" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/billionaires/profiles/jack-y-ma/?sref=BLKWHazc" rel="nofollow">a net worth of $50.6 billion</a>, was <keyword keytype="country" smid="0" usetype="2" keywordseo="China" actualkeyword="China">China</keyword>'s richest man until recently.</li>
</ul>
<p data-pos="4">Jack Ma, the 56-year-old billionaire founder of Alibaba and Ant Group, <a target="_blank" href="https://au.finance.yahoo.com/news/jack-ma-missing-232138645.html" rel="nofollow">hasn't been seen publicly in more than two months</a>, Jessica Yun reported for Yahoo Finance on Sunday.</p>
<p data-pos="6">Ma has been in the spotlight recently as China has cracked down on his business empire. In late December, Chinese regulators <a target="_blank" href="https://www.businessinsider.com/alibaba-antitrust-jack-ma-ant-group-beijing-regulators-2020-12" rel="nofollow">launched an antitrust investigation into Alibaba</a>, the country's biggest e-commerce company, sometimes referred to as "the Amazon of China." And in November, China introduced regulations that halted what would have been <a target="_blank" href="https://www.businessinsider.com/jack-ma-offered-parts-ant-group-to-china-2020-12" rel="nofollow">a massive initial public offering for Ant Group</a>, Ma's fintech company.</p><p>
The new rules came weeks after Ma <a target="_blank" href="https://www.businessinsider.com/jack-ma-financial-regulations-ant-group-alibaba-2020-10" rel="nofollow">criticized China's financial regulatory system</a> at a conference in Shanghai. Ma reportedly dismissed the global financial regulations used by China as "an old people's club" and said that "we can't use yesterday's methods to regulate the future."</p><p>
Blair Silverberg, the CEO of the debt-financing startup Capital, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.businessinsider.com/what-happened-ant-group-ipo-jack-ma-alipay-2020-11" rel="nofollow">told Business Insider's Katie Canales in November</a> that the regulations were introduced "so the government can assert its supremacy over </p><keyword keytype="person" smid="0" usetype="2" keywordseo="Jack-Ma" actualkeyword="Jack Ma">Jack Ma</keyword><p>."
</p><p data-pos="12">In November, Ma was replaced as a judge on the African talent show he founded, "Africa's Business Heroes," <a target="_blank" href="https://www.ft.com/content/a91dfeae-da1e-4348-8212-bbfbe94d93bd" rel="nofollow">the Financial Times reported</a>. The talent show did not immediately respond to Business Insider's request for comment, but an Alibaba representative said Ma could no longer be on the judging panel for the show's finale, which was filmed in November but has not yet been released," due to a scheduling conflict."</p><p>
"We do not have anything to add beyond that," the representative said in response to questions about Ma's whereabouts.</p><p><span>Advertisement</span></p><figure><div></div></figure><hr>
<p data-pos="16">Ma <a target="_blank" href="https://www.businessinsider.com/alibaba-jack-ma-stepping-down-successor-may-face-challenges-2019-9" rel="nofollow">stepped down as Alibaba's chairman</a> in 2019.</p>
<div data-msid="80094785"><figure><img src="https://www.businessinsider.in/photo/80094785/Master.jpg" data-original="/photo/80094785/Master.jpg" title="" alt="Where is Jack Ma? Alibaba's billionaire founder hasn't been seen publicly in 2 months following China's crackdowns on his companies" width="" height=""><figcaption><span>Ma stepped down as chairman of Alibaba in 2019.</span><span>Wang HE/Getty Images</span></figcaption></figure></div><p>
Until recently, Ma was <a target="_blank" href="https://www.businessinsider.com/alibaba-antitrust-jack-ma-ant-group-beijing-regulators-2020-12" rel="nofollow">China's richest man</a>, with a fortune of more than $60 billion. But Ma's net worth has <a target="_blank" href="https://markets.businessinsider.com/news/stocks/jack-ma-net-worth-rich-list-falls-china-alibaba-ant-2020-12-1029925654" rel="nofollow">taken a $12 billion hit</a> over the past two months as China has tightened the rules for the fintech industry. Ma is now worth $50.6 billion, making him the fourth-richest person in China, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/billionaires/?sref=BLKWHazc" rel="nofollow">according to the Bloomberg Billionaires Index</a>.
As speculation about Ma's whereabouts spread, a prediction about Ma from another billionaire Chinese businessman recirculated on social media.</p>
<p data-pos="24">In <a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4cwXifDaCjE&amp;t=702s%3Futm_source%3DOrganic&amp;utm_medium=Twitter&amp;utm_campaign=43718_YTEDGE_KA_SMT_RV_W1_TSNAP_RV_W1_TSNAP" rel="nofollow">a video interview in August 2019</a>, Guo Wengui, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/10/magazine/the-mystery-of-the-exiled-billionaire-whistleblower.html" rel="nofollow">who fled China as a fugitive in 2014</a> and has described himself as a whistleblower exposing corruption in the country, said Ma would likely end up in jail or dead in the next year because China wanted to "take back" Ma's lucrative Ant Group.</p>
<p data-pos="26">Last week, the Chinese government ordered Ant Group, which owns Alipay, China's largest digital-payment platform, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2020/dec/28/china-orders-alibaba-founder-jack-ma-break-up-fintech-ant" rel="nofollow">to scale back its operations</a> after expressing concerns that its corporate governance was "not sound."</p><p>
A representative for Ant Group did not immediately respond to Business Insider's request for comment for this story.</p>
</div></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.businessinsider.in/tech/news/where-is-jack-ma-alibabas-billionaire-founder-is-reportedly-missing-following-chinas-crackdowns-on-his-companies/articleshow/80094868.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25636045</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 18:48:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The many ways of splitting a rectangle in many]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 70 | Comments 10 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25633447">thread link</a>) | @cuentasombra
<br/>
January 4, 2021 | https://www.alfonsobeato.net/math/the-many-ways-of-splitting-a-rectangle-in-many/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.alfonsobeato.net/math/the-many-ways-of-splitting-a-rectangle-in-many/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-558">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	
	
	<div>
		
<p>These days, in the covid world we live in we have multiple videoconferences every day, with colleagues, family, friends… The average number of people attending has grown, and when I was in a call some time ago, I wondered, what would be the “optimal” way of splitting the videconference application window among the people in the call? What would be the definition of “optimal”? And, in how many ways could the space be split?, as sometimes you might prefer, for instance, one where space is shared equally or one where the current speaker has predominance.</p>



<p>This intrigued me, and I started some research to try to find answers to these questions. I started with the assumption that the videoconference application owns a window on the screen, which is a rectangle (we will call it the bounding rectangle), and we want to divide it in \(N\) different rectangles, being \(N\) the number of people in the call. We can define different criteria for optimizing like, say, dividing equally the window area among the callers. However, for that we need to define mathematically the dividing rectangles, and here is where the first difficulty arises, as the mathematical description changes depending on how you split the window. For instance, two of the ways of dividing the bounding rectangle (let’s call that “rectangulation”) for \(N=3\) are as displayed:</p>



<div><div>
<figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.alfonsobeato.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/N3.svg" alt="" width="755" height="355"><figcaption>Figure 1 – two possible ways of dividing a rectangle in three</figcaption></figure>




</div></div>



<p>Here we assign a width and a height to each rectangle. Note that optimizing means assigning values to these \(w_i\) and \(h_i\) to fulfill the optimizations criteria, which is like moving the “walls” between rectangles. The height \(h\) and width \(w\) of the bounding rectangle are considered fixed. In each rectangulation, it is possible to expose the implicit restrictions by equations that relate widths and heights of the different rectangles. For the first one in the image, the equations are:</p>



<p>$$\begin{array}{lcl}<br>w_1+w_2 &amp; = &amp; w \\<br>w_1 &amp; = &amp; w_3 \\<br>h_1+h_3 &amp; = &amp; h \\<br>h_1+h_3 &amp; = &amp; h_2 \\<br> \end{array}$$</p>



<p>For the second one:</p>



<p>$$\begin{array}{lcl}<br>w_1+w_2+w_3 &amp; = &amp; w \\<br>h_1 &amp; = &amp; h \\<br>h_1 &amp; = &amp; h_2 \\<br>h_2 &amp; = &amp; h_3<br>\end{array}$$</p>



<p>When we optimize we need to take into account these restrictions, which implies that for each rectangulation we have a different optimization problem with different solutions due to having different restrictions/equations in each case. The conclusion is that we need to solve the optimization problem for all possible rectangulations for a given \(N\), and then compare the different optimal values to select the best one. In summary, the steps we need to follow are</p>



<ol><li>Find all possible rectangulations for \(N\) callers</li><li>Decide an optimization criteria</li><li>Solve the optimization problem for all rectangulations, finding the best sizes for each way of splitting the bounding rectangle</li><li> Choose the best rectangulation by finding out which of them has the optimal solution that fulfills better the optimization criteria</li></ol>



<p>In the following sections we will go through each of these steps. I have developed some python code that implements the algorithms and that includes some unit tests that drive them and will be mentioned in different parts of the article. You can find it in <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://github.com/alfonsosanchezbeato/optimal-rectangulations" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/alfonsosanchezbeato/optimal-rectangulations" target="_blank">github</a>. If on an Ubuntu system, you can install dependencies and clone the repository from the command line with:</p>



<p><code>$ sudo apt install python3-pip</code><br><code>$ pip3 install numpy matplotlib scipy sympy</code><br><code>$ git clone https://github.com/alfonsosanchezbeato/optimal-rectangulations</code></p>



<p>N.B. In the mathematical expressions we use one-based indexes but, for practical reasons, the code uses zero-based indexes.</p>



<h2>Rectangulating a rectangle</h2>



<p>There is quite a bit of mathematical literature on the topic of rectangulations, motivated by applications like placing elements in integrated circuits. Depending on how you define them there can be more or less ways to “rectangulate” a rectangle. We want to take into account all possible rectangulations, but at the same time we need to be careful to avoid duplications. In our framework, a single rectangulation is one that can represent all rectangle sets that can fulfill a given set of equations as those shown at the beginning. Practically, that means that we can slide segments in the rectangulation (without changing the vertical or horizontal orientation) along the limiting segments, as that will not change the relationship that the equations describe. Each of these rectangulations is a class of equivalence of all possible rectangle sets described by a set of equations, and we need to find each of them and then find the optimal rectangles sizes for them, so we cover all possibilities. It turns out that each of these equivalence classes can be represented by what is called in the literature mosaic floorplans or diagonal rectangulations.</p>



<p>How to obtain these rectangulations? I will follow (mostly) the method explained in <span id="easy-footnote-1-558"></span><span><a href="#easy-footnote-bottom-1-558" title="S. Law, N. Reading, The Hopf algebra of diagonal rectangulations, Preprint, 2010. <a rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1011.2118&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>arXiv:1011.2118</a>."><sup>1</sup></a></span>. First, we create a matrix of size \(N\)x\(N\), which conceptually splits the bounding rectangle in cells. We will call it the rectangulation matrix. We number the rectangles consecutively and put the numbers in the matrix diagonal. Then, we choose a permutation (any can do) for the numbers. This permutation determines how the rectangulation will look like. Finally, we follow the order in the permutation to create the rectangles, one by one. To build each rectangle, the rules are</p>



<ol><li> Start from the free cell as left and bottom as possible that can include the cell with the rectangle number</li><li>Do not include cells with numbers for other rectangles</li><li>Make it as big as possible, with the restriction that it must not surpass the right of the rectangle below it and it must not surpass the top of the rectangle to its left. The bottom and left walls of the bounding rectangle are considered bottom and left rectangles for rectangles touching them. </li></ol>



<p>This defines a map between permutations and diagonal rectangulations that we will call \(\rho\). Figure 2 illustrates this procedure for the rectangulation \(\rho(4,1,3,5,2)\).</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="425" height="656" src="https://www.alfonsobeato.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/rectangulation.svg" alt=""><figcaption>Figure 2 – rectangulation for \(\rho(4,1,3,5,2)\)</figcaption></figure>



<p>This is implemented in the <code><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://github.com/alfonsosanchezbeato/optimal-rectangulations/blob/blog-release/rectangles.py#L48" target="_blank">do_diagonal_rectangulation()</a></code> function. There is a test to create random rectangulations that can be run with</p>



<p><code>$ ./rect_test.py TestRectangles.<a href="https://github.com/alfonsosanchezbeato/optimal-rectangulations/blob/blog-release/rect_test.py#L183" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/alfonsosanchezbeato/optimal-rectangulations/blob/blog-release/rect_test.py#L183" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">test_diagonal_rectangulation_random</a></code></p>



<p>Figure 3 shows an example of a run, with numbered rectangles. The sizes are as returned by <code><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://github.com/alfonsosanchezbeato/optimal-rectangulations/blob/blog-release/rectangles.py#L48" target="_blank">do_diagonal_rectangulation()</a></code>, so we can see that all rectangles have part of them in the top-left to bottom-right diagonal.</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.alfonsobeato.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/random_rect.svg" alt="" width="394" height="379"><figcaption>Figure 3 – rectangulation for N=10</figcaption></figure>



<p>It turns out that this map between permutations and diagonal rectangulations is surjective, so it would be interesting to filter out the permutations that produce duplicated rectangulations to reduce the number of calculations. Fortunately, it has been proved that it is possible to establish a bijection between a subset of permutations, called Baxter permutations, and diagonal rectangulations<span id="easy-footnote-2-558"></span><span><a href="#easy-footnote-bottom-2-558" title="E. Ackerman, G. Barequet, R. Pinter, A bijection between permutations and floorplans, and its applications, Discrete Appl.<br>Math. 154 (12) (2006) 1674–1684."><sup>2</sup></a></span>.</p>



<h3>Baxter permutations</h3>



<p>Baxter permutations can be defined by using the generalized pattern avoidance framework<span id="easy-footnote-3-558"></span><span><a href="#easy-footnote-bottom-3-558" title="E. Babson, E. Steingrímsson, Generalized permutation patterns and a classification of the Mahonian statistics, Sém. Lothar.<br>Combin. 44 (2000) Art. B44b, 18 pp. (electronic)."><sup>3</sup></a></span>. The way it works is that a sequence is Baxter if there is no subsequence of 4 elements that you can find in it that matches one of the generalized patterns 3-14-2 and 2-41-3. This is an interesting topic but I do not want to digress too much: I have based my implementation on the definition of section 2 of <span id="easy-footnote-4-558"></span><span><a href="#easy-footnote-bottom-4-558" title="N. Reading,Generic rectangulations.European J. Combin.33(2012) 610–623 <a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1105.3093&quot;>arXiv:1105.3093</a>."><sup>4</sup></a></span>. The function <code><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://github.com/alfonsosanchezbeato/optimal-rectangulations/blob/blog-release/rectangles.py#L337" target="_blank">is_baxter_permutation()</a></code> checks whether a sequence is Baxter or not by generating all possible subsequences of 4 elements and checking if they avoid the mentioned patterns. An example using it can be run with</p>



<p><code>$ ./rect_test.py TestRectangles.<a href="https://github.com/alfonsosanchezbeato/optimal-rectangulations/blob/blog-release/rect_test.py#L234" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/alfonsosanchezbeato/optimal-rectangulations/blob/blog-release/rect_test.py#L234" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">test_baxter_permutation</a></code></p>



<p>Using Baxter permutations to filter out permutations can save lots of time for bigger \(N\). For instance, for \(N=10\), only around 10% of the permutations are Baxter. There is a closed form formula for the number of Baxter permutations as a function of \(N\)<span id="easy-footnote-5-558"></span><span><a href="#easy-footnote-bottom-5-558" title="F.R.K. Chung, R.L. Graham, V.E. Hoggatt Jr., M. Kleiman, The number of Baxter permutations, J. Combin. Theory Ser. A 24<br>(3) (1978) 382–394."><sup>5</sup></a></span>, so we can compare easily with the total number of permutations, \(N!\).</p>



<h3>Rectangle equations</h3>



<p>Once we have a rectangulation, we need to extract the equations that define the relations between widths and heights across the rectangles. To do this, we can loop through the rectangulation matrix and detect the limits between rectangles, which define horizontal and vertical segments. When found, we will create an equation that defines that the sum of the widths/heights of the rectangles at each side of the segment must be equal. There will be also two equations for the  bounding rectangle that make the sum of width/height of rectangles at the side be equal to the total width/height. Note that these are 2 and not 4 equations, as 2 of the 4 we can extract would be linearly dependent on the full set of equations (this can be seen because if we take the equation on one side and follow the parallel segments equations while moving to the opposite side we can deduce the rectangles that touch the bounding rectangle at the opposite limit). Example of the equation sets that would be extracted are those we have already seen for the rectangulations in figure 1. In the slightly more complex case of figure 2, the equations would be</p>



<p>$$\begin{array}{lcl}<br>w_1+w_2 &amp; = &amp; w \\<br>w_2 &amp; = &amp; w_3+w_5 \\<br>w_1+w_3 &amp; = &amp; w_4 \\<br>h_1+h_4 &amp; = &amp; h \\<br>h_1 &amp; = &amp; h_2+h_3 \\<br>h_3+h_4 &amp; = &amp; h_5<br>\end{array}$$</p>



<p>The function that implements this algorithm is <code><a href="https://github.com/alfonsosanchezbeato/optimal-rectangulations/blob/blog-release/rectangles.py#L93" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/alfonsosanchezbeato/optimal-rectangulations/blob/blog-release/rectangles.py#L93" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">build_rectangulation_equations()</a></code>. It returns a matrix with the equation coefficients that will be used when optimizing the rectangulations.</p>



<p>The final number of linearly independent equations we will get will be always \(N+1\). This is a corollary of Lemma 2.3 from <span id="easy-footnote-6-558"></span><span><a href="#easy-footnote-bottom-6-558" title="E. Ackerman, G. Barequet, R. Pinter, On the number of rectangulations of a planar point set, J. Combin. Theory Ser. A 113 (6) (2006) 1072–1091."><sup>6</sup></a></span>. This lemma defines two operations, “Flip” and “Rotate”, that allow transforming any rectangulation on another one by a finite number of these operations. These operations do not modify the number of segments in the rectangulation. Therefore, we could transform any rectangulation in one having only, say, vertical segments. This rectangulation …</p></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.alfonsobeato.net/math/the-many-ways-of-splitting-a-rectangle-in-many/">https://www.alfonsobeato.net/math/the-many-ways-of-splitting-a-rectangle-in-many/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.alfonsobeato.net/math/the-many-ways-of-splitting-a-rectangle-in-many/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25633447</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 16:25:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Fair-Code Automation with n8n.io]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 127 | Comments 36 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25632892">thread link</a>) | @lebaux
<br/>
January 4, 2021 | https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/opensourced-ifttt-with-n8n-io/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/opensourced-ifttt-with-n8n-io/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">
    <div>

        <article>

            

            <figure>
                <img srcset="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w300/2021/01/1_vU8pW6v8lZj-1dTLzujZTg.png 300w,
                            https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w600/2021/01/1_vU8pW6v8lZj-1dTLzujZTg.png 600w,
                            https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w1000/2021/01/1_vU8pW6v8lZj-1dTLzujZTg.png 1000w,
                            https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w2000/2021/01/1_vU8pW6v8lZj-1dTLzujZTg.png 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 400px,
                        (max-width: 1170px) 1170px,
                            2000px" src="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w2000/2021/01/1_vU8pW6v8lZj-1dTLzujZTg.png" alt="Fair-Code Automation with n8n.io">
            </figure>

            <section>
                <div>
                    <p>I recently installed a rocket.chat server which I covered here</p><figure><a href="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/rocket-chat/"><div><p>Rocket Chat, yes it’s better than Teams.</p><p>There are a fair few Rocket Chat blogs published over the last few weeks. Sothis post is going to show you how to install it and some cool things you can dowith it. Rocket.Chat - The Leading Communication HubLead with a Communication Hub thatallows total control of your data. All in one platform…</p><p><img src="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/favicon.png"><span>Tech Blog Posts - David Field</span></p></div><p><img src="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/2020/12/rocket_banner.png"></p></a></figure><p>One of the features I really like is the integration with Rocket Chat and Zapier. While it works really well, its also very expensive (at time of writing) from the free tier to the next one up.</p><p>Turns out the free tier is really just for dev work, as soon as you start using it, it depletes very quickly.</p><p>I understand this, its a business model, and one many businesses use. However as I look to take the entire project self hosted I was interested to see what was available for performing the Zapier/IFTTT type functionality.</p><h3 id="n8n">n8n</h3><p>After a look around I setup n8n</p><figure><a href="https://n8n.io/"><div><p>n8n</p><p>n8n is an extendable workflow automation tool which enables you to connect anything to everything via its open, fair-code model.</p><p><img src="https://n8n.io/favicon.ico"><span>Blog Twitter Github LinkedIn Facebook YouTube</span></p></div><p><img src="https://n8n.io/og-image.jpg"></p></a></figure><p>The business has only been "public" since Oct 2019 and describes itself as </p><blockquote><a href="http://n8n.io/" rel="noopener noreferrer">n8n</a>, a Berlin-based company that has built a “fair code” workflow automation platform to let developers quickly integrate any of the apps that they use to work together automatically — from standard third-party APIs to internal tools created by developers themselves</blockquote><p>From my perspective its a a web gui interface backed by code which takes items from X and passes them through gates to Y and displays them.</p><p>Off the bat its not as intuative as the aforementioned Zapier and IFTTT and you will need to get your hands dirty with some code. There is however good comunity support (considering this has only been around for a short time) which is google aware as well.</p><p>I was able to setup a quick and simple n8n workflow for Rocket chat with a bit of googling without reading the documentation.</p><h3 id="installation">Installation</h3><p>n8n is an npm app, and the site does show examples of both running and installing it as an npm app. However I found the quickets method of getting something up and running to see what it looked like was to use the docker container</p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><pre><code># Spin up a basic container
docker run -it --rm \
--name n8n \
-p 5678:5678 \
-v ~/.n8n:/home/node/.n8n \
n8nio/n8n:latest</code></pre>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>This will get you what can only be classed as a dev environment, it has no credntials to login with, the webhook stuff only listens on localhost etc. The idea here is to quickly get a test environment to see if n8n is for you.</p><h3 id="proper-installation">Proper Installation</h3><p>If you'd like something a lot more stable and secure setup then head over to the n8n Docker Hub page</p><figure><a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/n8nio/n8n"><div><p>Docker Hub</p></div></a></figure><p>Where there ware plenty of options for getting n8n setup in different types of production environment.</p><p>I chose to go a little hybrid in my docker compose as at current i'm using this at home.</p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><pre><code>nano docker-compose.yaml</code></pre>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><pre><code>version: "3"

services:
  n8n:
    image: n8nio/n8n
    restart: always
    ports:
      - "5678:5678"
    environment:
      - N8N_BASIC_AUTH_ACTIVE=true
      - N8N_BASIC_AUTH_USER
      - N8N_BASIC_AUTH_PASSWORD
      - N8N_HOST=${SUBDOMAIN}.${DOMAIN_NAME}
      - N8N_PORT=5678
      - N8N_PROTOCOL=http
      - NODE_ENV=production
      - WEBHOOK_TUNNEL_URL=http://10.10.100.10/
    volumes:
      - /var/run/docker.sock:/var/run/docker.sock
      - ${DATA_FOLDER}/.n8n:/home/node/.n8n</code></pre>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>Then crerated a hidden environment file</p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><pre><code>nano .env</code></pre>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><pre><code># Folder where data should be saved
DATA_FOLDER=/opt/applications/n8n

# The top level domain to serve from
DOMAIN_NAME=my.lan

# The subdomain to serve from
SUBDOMAIN=n8n

# DOMAIN_NAME and SUBDOMAIN combined decide where n8n will be reachable from
# above example would result in: http://n8n.my.lan

# The user name to use for autentication - IMPORTANT ALWAYS CHANGE!
N8N_BASIC_AUTH_USER=admin

# The password to use for autentication - IMPORTANT ALWAYS CHANGE!
N8N_BASIC_AUTH_PASSWORD=eNtErAsAsSyPaSsWoRdHeRe

# Optional timezone to set which gets used by Cron-Node by default
# If not set New York time will be used
GENERIC_TIMEZONE=Europe/London

# The email address to use for the SSL certificate creation
SSL_EMAIL=anexample@gmail.com</code></pre>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>running this up with Docker compose</p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><pre><code>docker-compose up -d</code></pre>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>Should spin up an n8n environment asking for creds on </p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><pre><code>http://n8n.my.lan:5678</code></pre>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>Enter the creds you provided an you'll be away to go.</p><h3 id="first-screen">First Screen</h3><p>Once you launch n8n you'll be taken to the webgui home screen</p><figure><img src="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.26.10---Display-1.png" alt="" srcset="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w600/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.26.10---Display-1.png 600w, https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w1000/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.26.10---Display-1.png 1000w, https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w1600/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.26.10---Display-1.png 1600w, https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.26.10---Display-1.png 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>A blank canvas of imagination </p><p>Clicking on the Plus in the top right creates nodes, nodes are the steps of the workflow.</p><figure><img src="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.26.44---Display-2.png" alt="" srcset="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w600/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.26.44---Display-2.png 600w, https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w1000/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.26.44---Display-2.png 1000w, https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.26.44---Display-2.png 1504w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>And on the left hand side is a menu system for saving, exporting, importing etc.</p><figure><img src="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.32.55---Display-2.png" alt=""></figure><p>So the interfaced is pretty sparse, its supposed to be</p><p>There is a good n8n video covering the basics</p><figure><iframe width="267" height="200" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4lcJZM_u1iY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></figure><h2 id="basic-workflow">Basic Workflow</h2><p>Rather than trying to read all the documentation I jumped straight in as I had a workflow I wanted to try and get working. </p><h3 id="input">Input</h3><p>My Input is a set of rss feeds, for this example i've chosen comics </p><figure><img src="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.37.14---Display-2.png" alt="" srcset="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w600/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.37.14---Display-2.png 600w, https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.37.14---Display-2.png 757w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><h3 id="output">Output</h3><p>The output was to daily get the latest comic from the feed to the "dailycomics" channel in my Rocket Chat feed.</p><h3 id="the-result">The Result</h3><p>What I ended up with was this</p><ul><li>Cron node runs the job at 7am each day</li><li>Several RSS feeds are then checked</li><li>Because this would provide me with the last weeks worth of output for each RSS feed there is some code to only take the last feed</li><li>Push this to Rocket chat using a personal token.</li></ul><figure><img src="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-10.41.06---Display-1.png" alt="" srcset="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w600/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-10.41.06---Display-1.png 600w, https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w1000/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-10.41.06---Display-1.png 1000w, https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w1600/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-10.41.06---Display-1.png 1600w, https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-10.41.06---Display-1.png 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><h3 id="what-does-this-look-like">What does this look like?</h3><p>If we double click on each node type its possible to see how this is setup</p><p><strong>Cron</strong></p><p>The Cron Node is a built in node and in this example i've setup the task to run twice a day</p><figure><img src="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.46.32---Display-2.png" alt="" srcset="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w600/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.46.32---Display-2.png 600w, https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w1000/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.46.32---Display-2.png 1000w, https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.46.32---Display-2.png 1201w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p><strong>RSS</strong></p><p>This is a very basic built in node and needs the URL of the RSS feed</p><figure><img src="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/2021/01/rssnode.png" alt="" srcset="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w600/2021/01/rssnode.png 600w, https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w1000/2021/01/rssnode.png 1000w, https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/2021/01/rssnode.png 1210w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p><strong>Function</strong></p><p>These code blocks are interesting as there isn't an obvious node to use with them, however if you drag and drop code blocks onto the interface n8n will create an appropriate node block. this is handy as well in the support forums where there are lots of code blocks answering questions. Copy them and paste into the n8n interface and a node is created.</p><p>This is javascript code stating just the latest item in the rss list.</p><figure><img src="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.49.13---Display-2.png" alt="" srcset="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w600/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.49.13---Display-2.png 600w, https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w1000/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.49.13---Display-2.png 1000w, https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.49.13---Display-2.png 1200w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p><strong>Rocket.Chat</strong></p><p>Rocket Chat again is a built in node type and is after some core information</p><figure><img src="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.52.43---Display-2.png" alt="" srcset="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w600/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.52.43---Display-2.png 600w, https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w1000/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.52.43---Display-2.png 1000w, https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.52.43---Display-2.png 1197w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>What will need to be setup are the creds used to communicate with Rocket Chat</p><p>Which can be done using Create new</p><figure><img src="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.53.48---Display-2.png" alt="" srcset="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w600/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.53.48---Display-2.png 600w, https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w1000/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.53.48---Display-2.png 1000w, https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.53.48---Display-2.png 1201w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Then enter the personal toen information from Rocket Chat</p><figure><img src="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.53.52---Display-2.png" alt="" srcset="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w600/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.53.52---Display-2.png 600w, https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/size/w1000/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.53.52---Display-2.png 1000w, https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/content/images/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-04-at-11.53.52---Display-2.png 1113w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Click on Create </p><p>And its done.</p><h3 id="what-that-looks-like-as-code">What that looks like as code</h3><p>n8n provides an interface to download all of this as code, you'll notice that there are no creds stored in the downloaded json file, these are stored in the associated mongoDb</p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><pre><code>{
</code></pre>
<p>"name": "rss to rocket.chat",<br>
"nodes": [<br>
{<br>
"parameters": {},<br>
"name": "Start",<br>
"type": "n8n-nodes-base.start",<br>
"typeVersion": 1,<br>
"position": [<br>
250,<br>
300<br>
]<br>
},<br>
{<br>
"parameters": {<br>
"url": "=https://www.comicsrss.com/rss/calvinandhobbes.rss"<br>
},<br>
"name": "RSS - Calvin and Hobbes",<br>
"type": "n8n-nodes-base.rssFeedRead",<br>
"typeVersion": 1,<br>
"position": [<br>
540,<br>
890<br>
]<br>
},<br>
{<br>
"parameters": {<br>
"url": "<a href="https://www.comicsrss.com/rss/dilbert.rss">https://www.comicsrss.com/rss/dilbert.rss</a>"<br>
},<br>
"name": "RSS Feed - Dilbert",<br>
"type": "n8n-nodes-base.rssFeedRead",<br>
"typeVersion": 1,<br>
"position": [<br>
550,<br>
710<br>
]<br>
},<br>
{<br>
"parameters": {<br>
"url": "<a href="https://www.comicsrss.com/rss/fredbasset.rss">https://www.comicsrss.com/rss/fredbasset.rss</a>"<br>
},<br>
"name": "RSS Feed - Fred Bassett",<br>
"type": "n8n-nodes-base.rssFeedRead",<br>
"typeVersion": 1,<br>
"position": [<br>
550,<br>
550<br>
]<br>
},<br>
{<br>
"parameters": {<br>
"channel": "dailycomics",<br>
"text": "={{$json["title"]}}\n{{$json["link"]}}",<br>
"jsonParameters": true,<br>
"options": {}<br>
},<br>
"name": "RocketChat",<br>
"type": "n8n-nodes-base.rocketchat",<br>
"typeVersion": 1,<br>
"position": [<br>
1190,<br>
650<br>
],<br>
"alwaysOutputData": false<br>
},<br>
{<br>
"parameters": {<br>
"functionCode": "return [\n  items[0]\n];"<br>
},<br>
"name": "Only First Function",<br>
"type": "n8n-nodes-base.function",<br>
"typeVersion": 1,<br>
"position": [<br>
890,<br>
640<br>
]<br>
},<br>
{<br>
"parameters": {<br>
"triggerTimes": {<br>
"item": [<br>
{<br>
"hour": 7<br>
},<br>
{<br>
"hour": 19<br>
}<br>
]<br>
}<br>
},<br>
"name": "Cron",<br>
"type": "n8n-nodes-base.cron",<br>
"typeVersion": 1,<br>
"position": [<br>
300,<br>
740<br>
]<br>
},<br>
{<br>
"parameters": {<br>
"url": "<a href="https://www.comicsrss.com/rss/garfield.rss">https://www.comicsrss.com/rss/garfield.rss</a>"<br>
},<br>
"name": "RSS Feed R- Garfield",<br>
"type": "n8n-nodes-base.rssFeedRead",<br>
"typeVersion": 1,<br>
"position": [<br>
560,<br>
390<br>
]<br>
},<br>
{<br>
"parameters": {<br>
"url": "<a href="https://www.comicsrss.com/rss/hagarthehorrible.rss">https://www.comicsrss.com/rss/hagarthehorrible.rss</a>"<br>
},<br>
"name": "RSS Feed - Hagar",<br>
"type": "n8n-nodes-base.rssFeedRead",<br>
"typeVersion": 1,<br>
"position": [<br>
550,<br>
240<br>
]<br>
},<br>
{<br>
"parameters": {<br>
"url": "<a href="https://www.comicsrss.com/rss/wizardofid.rss">https://www.comicsrss.com/rss/wizardofid.rss</a>"<br>
},<br>
"name": "RSS Feed Read",<br>
"type": "n8n-nodes-base.rssFeedRead",<br>
"typeVersion": 1,<br>
"position": [<br>
540,<br>
1060<br>
]<br>
}<br>
],<br>
"connections": {<br>
"RSS Feed - Dilbert": {<br>
"main": [<br>
[<br>
{<br>
"node": "Only First Function",<br>
"type": "main",<br>
"index": 0<br>
}<br>
]<br>
]<br>
},<br>
"RSS Feed - Fred Bassett": {<br>
"main": [<br>
[<br>
{<br>
"node": "Only First Function",<br>
"type": "main",<br>
"index": 0<br>
}<br>
]<br>
]<br>
},<br>
"RSS - Calvin and Hobbes": {<br>
"main": [<br>
[<br>
{<br>
"node": "Only First Function",<br>
"type": "main",<br>
"index": 0<br>
}<br>
]<br>
]<br>
},<br>
"Only First Function": {<br>
"main": [<br>
[<br>
{<br>
"node": "RocketChat",<br>
"type": "main",<br>
"index": 0<br>
}<br>
]<br>
]<br>
},<br>
"Cron": {<br>
"main": [<br>
[<br>
{<br>
"node": "RSS Feed - Fred Bassett",<br>
"type": "main",<br>
"index": 0<br>
},<br>
{<br>
"node": "RSS Feed - Dilbert",<br>
"type": "main",<br>
"index": 0<br>
},<br>
{<br>
"node": "RSS - Calvin and Hobbes",<br>
"type": "main",<br>
"index": 0<br>
},<br>
{<br>
"node": "RSS Feed R- Garfield",<br>
"type": "main",<br>
"index": 0<br>
},<br>
{<br>
"node": "RSS Feed - Hagar",<br>
"type": "main",<br>
"index": 0<br>
},<br>
{<br>
"node": "RSS Feed Read",<br>
"type": "main",<br>
"index": 0<br>
}<br>
]<br>
]<br>
},<br>
"RSS Feed R- Garfield": {<br>
"main": [<br>
[<br>
{<br>
"node": "Only First Function",<br>
"type": "main",<br>
"index": 0<br>
}<br>
]<br>
]<br>
},<br>
"RSS Feed - Hagar": {<br>
"main": [<br>
[<br>
{<br>
"node": "Only First Function",<br>
"type": "main",<br>
"index": 0<br>
}<br>
]<br>
]<br>
},<br>
"RSS Feed Read": {<br>
"main": [<br>
[<br>
{<br>
"node": "Only First Function",<br>
"type": "main",<br>
"index": 0<br>
}<br>
]<br>
]<br>
}<br>
},<br>
"active": true,<br>
"settings": {},<br>
"id": "1"<br>
}</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>This code can also be imported back into n8n if you need to rebuild.. as I did, and all i needed to do was setup the …</p></div></section></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/opensourced-ifttt-with-n8n-io/">https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/opensourced-ifttt-with-n8n-io/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://tech.davidfield.co.uk/opensourced-ifttt-with-n8n-io/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25632892</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 15:54:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[BadEconomics: Putting $400M of Bitcoin on your company balance sheet]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 166 | Comments 551 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25632757">thread link</a>) | @nikivi
<br/>
January 4, 2021 | https://www.singlelunch.com/2020/10/21/badeconomics-putting-400m-of-bitcoin-on-your-company-balance-sheet/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.singlelunch.com/2020/10/21/badeconomics-putting-400m-of-bitcoin-on-your-company-balance-sheet/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-1230">
	
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>
		<p>
  This is an excuse to have a blog post on the economics of Bitcoin to refer people to. <br> <b>Intended Audience:</b> Laypersons interested or confused about Bitcoin. <br> <b>Reading Time:</b> 15min
</p>
<p>A couple of months ago, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MicroStrategy">MicroStrategy</a> (MSTR) had a spare $400M of cash which it decided to shift to Bitcoin (BTC).</p>
<p>When a company has a pile of spare money it doesn’t know what to do with, it’ll normally do <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Share_repurchase">buybacks</a> or start paying <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dividend">dividends</a>. That gives the money back to the shareholders, and from an economic perspective the money can get better invested in other more promising companies<a href="#footnote-1-1230" id="note-1-1230" rel="footnote">1</a>. If you have a huge pile of of cash, you probably should be doing other things than leave it in a bank account to gather dust<a href="#footnote-2-1230" id="note-2-1230" rel="footnote">2</a>.</p>
<p>However, this statement from MicroStrategy CEO Michael Saylor exists to make it clear he’s buying into BTC for all the wrong reasons<a href="#footnote-3-1230" id="note-3-1230" rel="footnote">3</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“This is not a speculation, nor is it a hedge. This was a deliberate corporate strategy to adopt a bitcoin standard.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Let’s unpack it and jump into the economics Bitcoin:</p>

<p>No.</p>
<p>Or rather BTC doesn’t act as money and there’s no serious future path for BTC to become a form of money. Let’s go back to basics. There are 3 main economic problems money solves:</p>
<p><strong>1. Medium of Exchange.</strong> Before money we had to barter, which led to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coincidence_of_wants">double coincidence of wants</a> problem. When everyone accepts the same money you can buy something from someone even if they don’t like the stuff you own.</p>
<p>As a medium of exchange, BTC is not good. There are significant transaction fees and transaction waiting times built-in to BTC and these worsen the more popular BTC get.</p>
<p>You can test BTC’s usefulness as a medium of exchange for yourself right now: try to order a pizza or to buy a random item with BTC. How many additional hurdles do you have to go through? How many fewer options do you have than if you used a regular currency? How much overhead (time, fees) is there?</p>
<p><strong>2. Unit of Account.</strong> A unit of account is what you compare the value of objects against. We denominate BTC in terms of how many USD they’re worth, so BTC is not a unit of account presently. We can say it’s because of lack of adoption, but really it’s also because the market value of BTC is so volatile.</p>
<p>If I buy a $1000 table today or in 2017, it’s roughly a $1000 table. We can’t say that a 0.4BTC table was a 0.4BTC table in 2017. We’ll expand on this in the next point:</p>
<p><strong>3. Store of Value.</strong> When you create economic value, you don’t want to be forced to use up the value you created right away.</p>
<p>For instance, if I fix your washing machine and you pay me in avocados, I’d be annoyed. I’d have to consume my payment before it becomes brown, squishy and disgusting<a href="#footnote-4-1230" id="note-4-1230" rel="footnote">4</a>. Avocado fruit is not good money because avocados loses value very fast.</p>
<p>On the other hand, well-run currencies like the USD, GBP, CAD, EUR, etc. all lose their value at a <strong>low</strong> and most importantly <strong>fairly predictible</strong> rate<a href="#footnote-5-1230" id="note-5-1230" rel="footnote">5</a>. Let’s look at the chart of the USD against BTC:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-10-18-at-8.40.24-AM.png?resize=660%2C173&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="660" height="173" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-10-18-at-8.40.24-AM.png?w=3058&amp;ssl=1 3058w, https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-10-18-at-8.40.24-AM.png?resize=300%2C79&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-10-18-at-8.40.24-AM.png?resize=1024%2C269&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-10-18-at-8.40.24-AM.png?resize=768%2C201&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-10-18-at-8.40.24-AM.png?resize=1536%2C403&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-10-18-at-8.40.24-AM.png?resize=2048%2C537&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-10-18-at-8.40.24-AM.png?w=1320&amp;ssl=1 1320w, https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-10-18-at-8.40.24-AM.png?w=1980&amp;ssl=1 1980w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p>While the dollar loses value at a predictible rate, BTC is all over the place, which is bad.</p>
<p>One important use money is to write loan contracts. Loans are great. They let people spend now against their future potential earnings, so they can buy houses or start businesses without first saving up for a decade. Loans are good for the economy.</p>
<p>If you want to sign something that says <em>“I owe you this much for that much time”</em> then you need to be able to roughly predict the value of the debt in at the point in time where it’s due.</p>
<p>Otherwise you’ll have a hard time pricing the risk of the loan effectively. This means that you need to charge higher interests. The risk of making a loan in BTC needs to be priced into the interest of a BTC-denominated loan, which means much higher interest rates. High interests on loans are bad, because buying houses and starting businesses are good things.</p>

<p>Some people think that going back to a standard where our money was denominated by a stock of gold (the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gold_standard">Gold Standard</a>) would solve economic problems. This is nonsense.</p>
<p>Having control over supply of your currency is a good thing, as long as it’s well run.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/vLdKpu5.png?resize=660%2C480&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="660" height="480" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/vLdKpu5.png?w=1056&amp;ssl=1 1056w, https://i2.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/vLdKpu5.png?resize=300%2C218&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/vLdKpu5.png?resize=1024%2C745&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/vLdKpu5.png?resize=768%2C559&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p>Remember that what is desirable is low <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Variance">variance</a> in the value, not the value itself. When there are wild fluctuations in value, it’s hard for money to do its job well.</p>
<p>Since the 1970s, the USD has been a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fiat_money">fiat money</a> with no intrinsic value. This means we control the supply of money.</p>
<p>Let’s look at a classic poorly drawn econ101 graph:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Supply-Demand.png?resize=660%2C495&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="660" height="495" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Supply-Demand.png?w=1024&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Supply-Demand.png?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Supply-Demand.png?resize=768%2C576&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p>The market price for USD is where supply meets demand. The problem with a currency based on an item whose supply is fixed is that the price will necessarily fluctuate in response to changes in demand.</p>
<p>Imagine, if you will, that a pandemic strikes and that the demand for currency takes a sharp drop. The US imports less, people don’t buy anything anymore, etc. If you can’t print money, you get deflation, which is worsens everything <a href="#footnote-6-1230" id="note-6-1230" rel="footnote">6</a>. On the other hand, if you can make the <a href="https://brrr.money/">money printers go brrrr</a> you can stabilize the price:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/brrrrrr-1.png?resize=660%2C242&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="660" height="242" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/brrrrrr-1.png?w=928&amp;ssl=1 928w, https://i1.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/brrrrrr-1.png?resize=300%2C110&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/brrrrrr-1.png?resize=768%2C281&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p>Having your currency be based on a fixed supply isn’t just bad because in/deflation is hard to control <a href="#footnote-7-1230" id="note-7-1230" rel="footnote">7</a>.</p>
<p>It’s also a national security risk…</p>
<p><strong>The story of the guy who crashed gold prices in North Africa</strong></p>
<p>In the 1200s, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mansa_Musa">Mansa Munsa</a>, the emperor of the Mali, was rich and a devout Muslim and wanted everyone to know it. So he embarked on a pilgrimage to make it rain all the way to Mecca.</p>
<p>He in fact made it rain so hard he increased the overall supply of gold and unintentionally <a href="https://www.ancient.eu/Mansa_Musa_I/">crashed gold prices in Cairo by 20%</a>, wreaking an economic havoc in North Africa that lasted a decade.</p>
<p>This story is fun, the larger point that having your inflation be at the mercy of foreign nations is an undesirable attribute in any currency. The US likes to call some countries <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Currency_manipulator">currency manipulators</a>, but this problem would be serious under a gold standard.</p>

<p>Since the USD is based on nothing except the US government’s word<a href="#footnote-8-1230" id="note-8-1230" rel="footnote">8</a>, how can we trust USD not to be mismanaged?</p>
<p>The answer is that you can probably trust the fed until political stooges get put in place. Currently, the US’s central bank managing the USD, the Federal Reserve (the Fed for friends &amp; family), has administrative authority. The fed can say <strong>“no”</strong> to dumb requests from the president.</p>
<p>People who have no idea what the fed does like to chant “audit the fed”, but the fed is already one of the best audited US federal entities. The transcripts of <a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/monetarypolicy/fomccalendars.htm">all their meetings</a> are out in the open. As is their <a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/monetarypolicy/bst_fedsbalancesheet.htm">balance sheet</a>, <a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/newsevents/pressreleases.htm">what they plan to do and why</a>. If the US should audit anything it’s the Department of Defense which operates without <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/national/archive/2013/11/accounting-fraud-and-waste-routine-pentagon/355233/"><em>any accounting at all</em>.</a></p>
<p>It’s easy to see when a central bank will go rogue: it’s when political yes-men are elected to the board.</p>
<p>For example, before printing themselves into hyperinflation, the Venezuelan president appointed a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-venezuela-economy-idUSKBN0UL27820160107">sociologist who publicly stated “Inflation does not exist in real life”</a> and instead is a made up capitalist lie. Note what happened mere months after his gaining control over the Venezuelan currency:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Time_BsF_would_take_to_lose_90_percent_of_its_value.png?resize=660%2C453&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="660" height="453" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Time_BsF_would_take_to_lose_90_percent_of_its_value.png?w=1552&amp;ssl=1 1552w, https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Time_BsF_would_take_to_lose_90_percent_of_its_value.png?resize=300%2C206&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Time_BsF_would_take_to_lose_90_percent_of_its_value.png?resize=1024%2C703&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Time_BsF_would_take_to_lose_90_percent_of_its_value.png?resize=768%2C528&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Time_BsF_would_take_to_lose_90_percent_of_its_value.png?resize=1536%2C1055&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Time_BsF_would_take_to_lose_90_percent_of_its_value.png?w=1320&amp;ssl=1 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p>This is a key policy. One paper I really like, <a href="https://www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/sargent1984.pdf">Sargent (1984) “The end of 4 big inflations”</a> states:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The essential measures that ended hyperinflation in each of Germany, Austria, Hungary, and Poland were, first, the creation of an independent central bank that was legally committed to refuse the government’s demand or additional unsecured credit and, second, a simultaneous alteration in the fiscal policy regime.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In english: <em>hyperinflation stops when the central bank can say “no” to the government.”</em></p>
<p>The US Fed, like other well good central banks, is run by a <a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/monetarypolicy/fomc.htm">bunch of nerds</a><a href="#footnote-9-1230" id="note-9-1230" rel="footnote">9</a>. When it prints money, even as aggressively as it has it does so for good reasons. You can see why they started printing on March 15th as the COVID lockdowns started:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The Federal Reserve is prepared to use its full range of tools to support the flow of credit to households and businesses and thereby promote its maximum employment and price stability goals.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In english: <em>We’re going to keep printing and lowering rates until jobs are back and inflation is under control. If we print until the sun is blotted out, we’ll print in the shade.</em></p>

<p>Gold is a good asset for doomsday-preppers. If society crashes, gold will still have value.</p>
<p>How do we know that?</p>
<p>Gold has held value throughout multiple historic catastrophes over thousands of years. It had value before and after the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Late_Bronze_Age_collapse">Bronze Age Collapse</a>, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fall_of_the_Western_Roman_Empire">Fall of the Western Roman Empire</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mongol_invasions_and_conquests">Gengis Khan being Gengis Khan</a>.</p>
<p>Even if you erased humanity and started over, the new humans would still find gold to be economically valuable. When Europeans d̶i̶s̶c̶o̶v̶e̶r̶e̶d̶ c̶o̶n̶q̶u̶e̶r̶e̶d̶ g̶e̶n̶o̶c̶i̶d̶e̶d̶ went to America, they found gold to be <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Muisca_mythology">an important item over there too</a>. This is about equivalent to finding humans on Alpha-Centauri and learning that they think gold is a good store of value as well.</p>
<p>Some people are puzzled at this: we don’t even use gold for much! But it has great properties:</p>
<p>First, gold is hard to fake and impossible to manufacture. This makes it good to ascertain payment.</p>
<p>Second, gold doesnt react to oxygen, so it doesn’t rust or tarnish. So it keeps value over time unlike most other materials.</p>
<p>Last, gold is <strong>pretty</strong>. This might sound frivolous, and you may not like it, but jewelry has actual value to humans.</p>
<p>It’s no coincidence if you look at a list of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_wealthiest_families">wealthiest families</a>, a large number of them trade in luxury goods.</p>
<p>To paraphrase <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Theory_of_the_Leisure_Class">Veblen</a> humans have a profound desire to signal social status, for the same reason peacocks have unwieldy tails. Gold is a great way to achieve that.</p>
<p>On the other hand, BTC lacks all these attributes. Its value is largely based on common perception of value. There are a few fundamental drivers of demand:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Means of Exchange:</strong> if people seriously start using BTC to buy pizzas, then this creates a real demand for the currency to accomplish the short-term exchanges. As we saw previously, I’m not personally sold on this one and it’s currently a negligible fraction of overall demand.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Criminal uses:</strong> Probably the largest inbuilt …</p></li></ul></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.singlelunch.com/2020/10/21/badeconomics-putting-400m-of-bitcoin-on-your-company-balance-sheet/">https://www.singlelunch.com/2020/10/21/badeconomics-putting-400m-of-bitcoin-on-your-company-balance-sheet/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.singlelunch.com/2020/10/21/badeconomics-putting-400m-of-bitcoin-on-your-company-balance-sheet/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25632757</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 15:44:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why I'm Lukewarm on Graph Neural Networks]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 141 | Comments 43 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25632592">thread link</a>) | @VHRanger
<br/>
January 4, 2021 | https://www.singlelunch.com/2020/12/28/why-im-lukewarm-on-graph-neural-networks/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.singlelunch.com/2020/12/28/why-im-lukewarm-on-graph-neural-networks/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-1311">
	
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>
		<p><b>TL;DR:</b> GNNs can provide wins over simpler embedding methods, but we’re at a point where other research directions matter more
</p>
<p>I’m only lukewarm on Graph Neural Networks (GNNs). There, I said it.</p>
<p>It might sound crazy GNNs are one of the hottest fields in machine learning right now. <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2003.00982.pdf">There</a> were at least <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2002.11867.pdf">four</a> <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1812.08434.pdf">review</a> <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2005.00687.pdf">papers</a> just in the last few months. I think some progress can come of this research, but we’re also focusing on some incorrect places.</p>
<p>But first, let’s take a step back and go over the basics.</p>

<p>We say graphs are a “non-euclidean” data type, but that’s not really true. A regular graph <a href="#footnote-1-1311" id="note-1-1311" rel="footnote">1</a> is just another way to think about a particular flavor of square matrix called the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adjacency_matrix">adjacency matrix</a>:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/AdjacencyMatrices_1002.gif?resize=412%2C271&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="412" height="271" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p>It’s weird, we look at run-of-the-mill matrix full of real numbers and decide to call it “non-euclidean”.</p>
<p>This is for practical reasons. Most graphs are fairly sparse, so the matrix is full of zeros. At this point, <em>where the non-zero numbers are</em> matters most, which makes the problem closer to (computationally hard) discrete math rather than (easy) continuous, gradient-friendly math.</p>
<p><strong>If you had the full matrix, life would be easy</strong></p>
<p>If we step out of the pesky realm of physics for a minute, and assume carrying the full adjacency matrix around isn’t a problem, we solve a bunch of problems.</p>
<p>First, network node embeddings <a href="#footnote-2-1311" id="note-2-1311" rel="footnote">2</a> aren’t a thing anymore. A node is a just row in the matrix, so it’s already a vector of numbers.</p>
<p>Second, all network prediction problems are solved. A powerful enough and well-tuned model <a href="#footnote-3-1311" id="note-3-1311" rel="footnote">3</a> will simply extract all information between the network and whichever target variable we’re attaching to nodes.</p>
<p><strong>NLP is also just fancy matrix compression</strong></p>
<p>Let’s take a tangent away from graphs to NLP. Most NLP we do can be <a href="https://thegradient.pub/transformers-are-graph-neural-networks/">thought of in terms of graphs</a> as we’ll see, so it’s not a big digression.</p>
<p>First, note that Ye Olde word embedding models like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word2vec">Word2Vec</a> and <a href="https://nlp.stanford.edu/pubs/glove.pdf">GloVe</a> are <a href="https://papers.nips.cc/paper/2014/file/feab05aa91085b7a8012516bc3533958-Paper.pdf">just matrix factorization</a>.</p>
<p>The GloVe algorithm works on a variation of the old <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bag-of-words_model">bag of words</a> matrix. It goes through the sentences and creates a (implicit) <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Co-occurrence">co-occurence</a> graph where nodes are words and the edges are weighed by how often the words appear together in a sentence.</p>
<p>Glove then does matrix factorization <a href="#footnote-4-1311" id="note-4-1311" rel="footnote">4</a> on the matrix representation of that co-occurence graph, Word2Vec is mathematically equivalent<a href="#footnote-5-1311" id="note-5-1311" rel="footnote">5</a>.</p>
<p>You can read more on this in my <a href="https://www.singlelunch.com/2020/02/16/embeddings-from-the-ground-up/">post on embeddings</a> and the one (with code) on <a href="https://www.singlelunch.com/2019/01/27/word-embeddings-from-the-ground-up/">word embeddings</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Even language models are also just matrix compression</strong></p>
<p>Language models are all the rage. They dominate most of the <a href="https://nlpprogress.com/">state of the art</a> in NLP.</p>
<p>Let’s take BERT as our main example<a href="#footnote-6-1311" id="note-6-1311" rel="footnote">6</a>. BERT predicts a word given the context of the rest of the sentence:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/bert.png?resize=660%2C208&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="660" height="208" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/bert.png?w=1024&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/bert.png?resize=300%2C94&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/bert.png?resize=768%2C242&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p>This grows the matrix we’re factoring from flat co-occurences on pairs of words to co-occurences conditional on the sentence’s context<a href="#footnote-7-1311" id="note-7-1311" rel="footnote">7</a>:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-28-at-1.59.34-PM.png?resize=660%2C291&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="660" height="291" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-28-at-1.59.34-PM.png?w=999&amp;ssl=1 999w, https://i1.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-28-at-1.59.34-PM.png?resize=300%2C132&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-28-at-1.59.34-PM.png?resize=768%2C339&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p>We’re growing the “ideal matrix” we’re factoring combinatorially <a href="#footnote-8-1311" id="note-8-1311" rel="footnote">8</a>. As noted by <a href="http://socsci.uci.edu/~rfutrell/papers/hahn2019estimating.pdf">Hanh &amp; Futrell</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>[…] human language—and language modelling—has infinite statistical complexity but that it can be approximated well at lower levels. This observation has two implications: 1) We can obtain good results with comparatively small models; and 2) there is a lot of potential for scaling up our models. Language models tackle such a large problem space that they probably approximate a compression of the entire language in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kolmogorov_complexity">Kolmogorov Complexity</a> sense. It’s also possible that huge language models just <a href="https://bair.berkeley.edu/blog/2020/12/20/lmmem/">memorize a lot of it</a> rather than compress the information, for what it’s worth.</p>
</blockquote>
<h3>Can we upsample any graph like language models do?</h3>
<p>We’re already doing it.</p>
<p>Let’s call a <strong>first-order</strong> embedding of a graph a method that works by directly factoring the graph’s adjacency matrix or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laplacian_matrix">Laplacian matrix</a>. If you embed a graph using <a href="http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download;jsessionid=1F03130B02DC485C78BF364266B6F0CA?doi=10.1.1.19.8100&amp;rep=rep1&amp;type=pdf">Laplacian Eigenmaps</a> or by taking the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Principal_component_analysis">principal components</a> of the Laplacian, that’s first order. Similarly, GloVe is a first-order method on the graph of word co-occurences. One of my favorites first order methods for graphs is <a href="https://www.ijcai.org/Proceedings/2019/0594.pdf">ProNE</a>, which works as well as most methods while being two orders of magnitude faster.</p>
<p>A <strong>higher-order</strong> method embeds the original matrix plus connections of neighbours-of-neighbours (2nd degree) and deeper k-step connections. <a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/2806416.2806512">GraRep</a>, shows you can always generate higher-order representations from first order methods by augmenting the graph matrix <a href="#footnote-9-1311" id="note-9-1311" rel="footnote">9</a>.</p>
<p>Higher order method are the “upsampling” we do on graphs. GNNs that sample on large neighborhoods and random-walk based methods like node2vec are doing higher-order embeddings.</p>

<p>Most GNN papers in the last 5 years present empirical numbers that are useless for practitioners to decide on what to use.</p>
<p>As noted in the <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2005.00687.pdf">OpenGraphsBenchmark</a> (OGB) paper, GNN papers do their empirical section on a handful of tiny graphs (Cora, CiteSeer, PubMed) with 2000-20,000 nodes. These datasets can’t seriously differentiate between methods.</p>
<p>Recent efforts are directly fixing this, but the reasons why researchers focused on tiny, useless datasets for so long are worth discussing.</p>
<p><strong>Performance matters by task</strong></p>
<p>One fact that surprises a lot of people is that even though language models have the best performance in a lot of NLP tasks, if all you’re doing is cram sentence embeddings into a downstream model, there <a href="https://openreview.net/pdf?id=SyK00v5xx">isn’t much gained</a> from language models embeddings over simple methods like summing the individual Word2Vec word embeddings <a href="#footnote-10-1311" id="note-10-1311" rel="footnote">10</a>.</p>
<p>Similarly, <a href="https://github.com/VHRanger/nodevectors/blob/master/examples/link%20prediction.ipynb">I find</a> that for many graphs <strong>simple first-order methods perform just as well on graph clustering and node label prediction tasks than higher-order embedding methods</strong>. In fact higher-order methods are massively computationally wasteful for these usecases <a href="#footnote-11-1311" id="note-11-1311" rel="footnote">11</a></p>
<p>Recommended first order embedding methods are ProNE and my <a href="https://github.com/VHRanger/nodevectors">GGVec with order=1</a> <a href="#footnote-12-1311" id="note-12-1311" rel="footnote">12</a>.</p>
<p>Higher order methods normally perform better on the link prediction tasks<a href="#footnote-13-1311" id="note-13-1311" rel="footnote">13</a>.</p>
<p>Interestingly, the gap in link prediction performance is inexistant for artificially created graphs. This suggests higher order methods do learn some of the structure intrinsic to <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1310.2636.pdf">real world graphs</a>.</p>
<p>For visualization, first order methods are better. Visualizations of higher order methods tend to have artifacts of their sampling. For instance, Node2Vec visualizations tend to have elongated/filament-like structures which come from the embeddings coming from long single strand random walks. See the following visualizations by <a href="http://byowen.com/">Owen Cornec</a> <a href="#footnote-14-1311" id="note-14-1311" rel="footnote">14</a>:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-28-at-1.59.34-PM-1.png?resize=660%2C253&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="660" height="253" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-28-at-1.59.34-PM-1.png?w=994&amp;ssl=1 994w, https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-28-at-1.59.34-PM-1.png?resize=300%2C115&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.singlelunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-28-at-1.59.34-PM-1.png?resize=768%2C294&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p>Lastly, sometimes simple methods soundly beat higher order methods (there’s an instance of it in the OGB paper).</p>
<p>The problem here is that <strong>we don’t know when any method is better than another</strong> and <strong>we definitely don’t know the reason</strong>.</p>
<p>There’s definitely a reason different graph types respond better/worse to being represented by various methods. This is currently an open question.</p>
<p>A big part of why is that the research space is inundated under useless new algorithms because…</p>

<p>Here’s the cynic’s view of how machine learning papers are made:</p>
<ol>
<li>Take an existing algorithm</li>
<li>Add some new layer/hyperparameter, make a cute mathematical story for why it matters</li>
<li>Gridsearch your hyperparameters until you beat baselines from the original paper you aped</li>
<li>Absolutely don’t gridsearch stuff you’re comparing against in your results section</li>
<li>Make a cute ACRONYM for your new method, put impossible to use python 2 code on github <a href="#footnote-15-1311" id="note-15-1311" rel="footnote">15</a> and bask in the citations</li>
</ol>
<p>I’m <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1807.03341.pdf">not</a> the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Kee4ch3miVA">only one</a> with these views on the state reproducible research. At least it’s gotten slightly better in the last 2 years.</p>
<h3>Sidebar: I hate Node2Vec</h3>
<p>A side project of mine is a <a href="https://github.com/VHRanger/nodevectors">node embedding library</a> and the most popular method in it is by far Node2Vec. Don’t use Node2Vec.</p>
<p><a href="https://cs.stanford.edu/~jure/pubs/node2vec-kdd16.pdf">Node2Vec</a> with <code>p=1; q=1</code> is the <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1403.6652.pdf">Deepwalk</a> algorithm. Deepwalk is an actual innovation.</p>
<p>The Node2Vec authors closely followed the steps 1-5 including bonus points on step 5 by getting word2vec name recognition.</p>
<p>This is not academic fraud — the hyperparameters <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1911.11726.pdf">do help a tiny bit</a> if you gridsearch really hard. But it’s the presentable-to-your-parents sister of where you make the ML community worse off to progress your academic career. And certainly Node2Vec doesn’t deserve 7500 citations.</p>

<p>We’ve known how to train neural networks for well over 40 years. Yet they only exploded in popularity with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AlexNet">AlexNet</a> in 2012. This is because implementations and hardware came to a point where deep learning was <strong>practical</strong>.</p>
<p>Similarly, we’ve known about factoring word co-occurence matrices into Word embeddings for at least 20 years.</p>
<p>But word embeddings only exploded in 2013 with Word2Vec. The breakthrough here was that the minibatch-based methods let you train a Wikipedia-scale embedding model on commodity hardware<a href="#footnote-16-1311" id="note-16-1311" rel="footnote">16</a>.</p>
<p>It’s hard for methods in a field to make progress if training on a small amount of data takes days or weeks. You’re disincentivized to explore new methods. If you want progress, your stuff has to run in reasonable time on commodity hardware. Even Google’s original search algorithm <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_data_centers#Original_hardware">initially ran on commodity hardware</a> <a href="#footnote-17-1311" id="note-17-1311" rel="footnote">17</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Efficiency is paramount to progress</strong></p>
<p>The reason deep learning research took off the way it did is because of improvements in <a href="https://openai.com/blog/ai-and-efficiency/">efficiency</a> as well as much better libraries and hardware support<a href="#footnote-18-1311" id="note-18-1311" rel="footnote">18</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Academic code is terrible</strong></p>
<p>Any amount of time you spend gridsearching Node2Vec on <code>p</code> and <code>q</code> is all put to better use gridsearching Deepwalk itself <a href="#footnote-19-1311" id="note-19-1311" rel="footnote">19</a>. The problem is that people don’t gridsearch over deepwalk because implementations are all terrible.</p>
<p>I wrote the <a href="https://www.singlelunch.com/2019/08/01/700x-faster-node2vec-models-fastest-random-walks-on-a-graph/">Nodevectors library</a> to have a fast deepwalk implementation because it took <strong>32 hours</strong> to embed a graph with a measly 150,000 nodes using the reference Node2Vec implementation (the same takes 3min with Nodevectors). It’s no wonder people don’t gridsearch on Deepwalk a gridsearch would take weeks with the terrible reference implementations.</p>
<p>To give an example, in the original paper of <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1706.02216.pdf">GraphSAGE</a> they their algorithm to DeepWalk with walk lengths of 5 <a href="#footnote-20-1311" id="note-20-1311" rel="footnote">20</a>. From their paper:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We did observe DeepWalk’s performance could improve with further training, and in some cases it could become competitive with the unsupervised GraphSAGE approaches (but not the supervised approaches) if we let it run for &gt;1000× …</p></blockquote></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.singlelunch.com/2020/12/28/why-im-lukewarm-on-graph-neural-networks/">https://www.singlelunch.com/2020/12/28/why-im-lukewarm-on-graph-neural-networks/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.singlelunch.com/2020/12/28/why-im-lukewarm-on-graph-neural-networks/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25632592</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 15:34:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[China: The Disappearing Millionaires (2019) [video]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 233 | Comments 171 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25629774">thread link</a>) | @aminozuur
<br/>
January 4, 2021 | https://www.arte.tv/en/videos/083456-000-A/china-the-disappearing-millionaires/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.arte.tv/en/videos/083456-000-A/china-the-disappearing-millionaires/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section><div role="region" aria-label="program.videoplayer" id="video_player" tabindex="-1"><div><div><div></div></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><label for="autoplay-hide-for-large"><span>Autoplay</span><span></span></label></p><p><h2>Up next</h2></p></div><div><div><a href="https://www.arte.tv/en/videos/094601-000-A/haiti-an-island-adrift/"><div></div><div><h3>Haiti: An Island Adrift</h3><h4>ARTE Reportage</h4><p>23 min</p></div></a></div></div></div></div></section><section><div><p>25 min</p><p>Available from 12/11/2019 to 28/05/2022</p></div></section><section><div><p>China's self-made millionaires and billionaires were a major part of the country's success story. But now, they may have fallen out of favour with the CPP. One by one, they go missing, or commit 'suicide.' One billionaire who fled to the US is ringing the alarm.&nbsp;</p></div></section><div><section></section><div><section><br><div><ul><li><div><div><p>Director</p><!-- --><p> :</p></div></div><ul><p><li>Sébastien Le Belzic</li></p></ul></li><li><div><div><p>Producer</p><!-- --><p> :</p></div></div><ul><p><li>Anthony Dufour</li></p></ul></li></ul><ul><li><div><div><p>Author</p><!-- --><p> :</p></div></div><ul><p><li>Sébastien Le Belzic</li></p></ul></li><li><div><div><p>Country</p><!-- --><p> :</p></div></div><ul><p><li>France</li></p></ul></li><li><div><div><p>Year</p><!-- --><p> :</p></div></div><ul><p><li>2019</li></p></ul></li></ul></div></section></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.arte.tv/en/videos/083456-000-A/china-the-disappearing-millionaires/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25629774</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 10:59:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Verified Programming in F*: A Tutorial]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 156 | Comments 67 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25629058">thread link</a>) | @jstrieb
<br/>
January 4, 2021 | http://fstar-lang.org/tutorial/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://fstar-lang.org/tutorial/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://fstar-lang.org/tutorial/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25629058</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 09:04:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
