<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 5]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 5. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 12:20:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-5.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 12:20:06 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Beginner's Guide to Abstraction]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 140 | Comments 34 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23735991">thread link</a>) | @jesseduffield
<br/>
July 4, 2020 | https://jesseduffield.com/beginners-guide-to-abstraction/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jesseduffield.com/beginners-guide-to-abstraction/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-75">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	
	
	<div>
		<p>In <em>The Pragmatic Programmer</em>, Andrew Hunt and David Thomas introduced the DRY (Don't Repeat Yourself) principle. The rationale being that if you see the same code copy+pasted 10 times you should probably factor that code into its own method/class.</p>
<p>But then Sandi Metz came along and <a href="https://www.sandimetz.com/blog/2016/1/20/the-wrong-abstraction">said</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Duplication is far cheaper than the wrong abstraction.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And so the eternal war began.</p>
<h3>What is abstraction?</h3>
<p>For the purposes of this post I'm referring to the kind of abstraction as described in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abstraction_(computer_science)#Abstraction_in_object_oriented_programming">Abstraction Principle</a>, which Wikipedia describes like so:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In software engineering and programming language theory, the abstraction principle (or the principle of abstraction) is a basic dictum that aims to reduce duplication of information in a program (usually with emphasis on code duplication) whenever practical by making use of abstractions provided by the programming language or software libraries</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This post has nothing to say about the conceptual kind of abstraction where from the concrete examples of 'Parrot' and 'Sparrow' you create an abstraction of 'Bird'. This post is about duplicated code, how to respond to it, and how to respond to other people's responses to it.</p>
<p>I define the verb 'abstraction' to be an <em>attempt</em> to reduce complexity by combining repeated commonality into some generalisation. And so, the noun 'abstraction' is the result of that attempt. If you're somebody who believes abstraction is by definition a <em>successful</em> attempt, feel free to substitute the term 'wrong abstraction' with 'failure to abstract' throughout this post.</p>
<p>The process of abstraction typically goes like this:<br>
1) you identify different chunks of code that you think are all essentially doing the same thing<br>
2) you create a method or a class with a narrow interface which can be substituted in for all the chunks of code you found<br>
3) you go and swap out the chunks of code with a call to your method/class</p>
<h3>Abstraction is always a gamble</h3>
<p>In the world of software engineering, when requirements are always changing, every abstraction is a gamble. When you make an abstraction over some concrete things, you're making a bet that the concrete things are more similar than they are different, and that their similarities are not mere coincidences: that there is a common purpose shared by the concrete things which would lead them to evolve in lockstep as requirements evolve. If you win the bet, your codebase will be easier to work in and adding new use cases via your abstraction will be trivially easy. If you lose, you'll see a flash of fear in your colleague's eyes whenever they're assigned a ticket to make yet another extension to the misfigured monster that the once-innocent abstraction has now become</p>
<p>But risk abounds everywhere, and leaving duplicated code unabstracted is its own gamble. You're betting that the chunks of code will evolve in separate directions as requirements change and that their current similarities are more coincidence than a reflection of their common purpose. Win the bet and your colleague gets to sleep soundly at night knowing they won't be facing the abstraction monster at work the next day. Lose, and code that should have evolved in lockstep is now implemented in completely different ways across different files, where a developer fixes a bug identified in one place, only for the same bug to be reported days later in a completely different file.</p>
<p>Your job is to get good at making the right bets.</p>
<h3>The right/wrong abstraction</h3>
<p>You'll know that you've made the <em>right</em> abstraction when a long time passes and you haven't needed to expand the interface (an example of expanding the interface is adding an optional flag argument). You'll also know you've made the right abstraction when another developer doesn't find it that much harder to understand how the code behaves for a given use case than if somebody had written the code to satisfy the use case without the abstraction.</p>
<p>You'll know you've made the <em>wrong</em> abstraction when after a while the interface has been expanded to support various optional flags, each for a different use case, and you need to be a genius to reason about what the code will actually do for a given use case. By the way, if you have a string arg that merely gets fed into a switch statement inside a method and for each new use case you come up with a new accepted value for it, you <em>are</em> expanding the implicit interface, even if that fact isn't captured in your type system.</p>
<p>There is plenty of daylight between the perfect abstraction and the completely wrong abstraction (perhaps the interface needs to be fundamentally changed but afterwards you're back to having a good abstraction), and so the point of this section isn't to prescribe how much you should be abstracting, but to encourage you to think about both perspectives and be able to make a case in a PR review for why you think an abstraction should/should-not exist.</p>
<h3>Do you over or under-abstract?</h3>
<p>Given it is impossible to make the right decision with regards to abstraction every time, you are probably either somebody who over-abstracts or somebody who under-abstracts.</p>
<p>If common feedback on your PR reviews is that you should DRY up your code, you could probably benefit from doing a scan for duplicated code before submitting a PR and considering whether it belongs in its own method/class.</p>
<p>If you commonly get feedback that your methods are hard to understand because they support too many disparate use cases at once, you are probaby over-abstracting and should consider whether you should increase your tolerance for duplication.</p>
<p>Note that it's not always as simple as under-abstracting vs over-abstracting. Sometimes abstraction is appropriate, but you might take the wrong approach. If an abstraction is deemed wrong by the team, that doesn't mean no abstraction is necessarily the best alternative.</p>
<h3>Under-abstraction examples</h3>
<p>The main sign that you could be under-abstracting is that you have a heap of code doing the exact same thing called in a heap of places with no obvious reason why anybody would want the code to diverge.</p>
<h4>Example: Hard-coded formulas</h4>
<h5>Bad:</h5>
<pre><code># sphere has radius of 11
sphere_volume = 4*Math::PI/3*11**3
puts "the volume of the sphere is #{sphere_volume} cm^3"
...

radius = calculate_radius
volume = 4*Math::PI/3*radius**3
sphere.volume = volume</code></pre>
<h5>Good:</h5>
<pre><code>def sphere_volume(radius)
  4*Math::PI/3*radius**3
end

# sphere has radius of 11
sphere_volume = sphere_volume(11)
puts "the volume of the sphere is #{sphere_volume} cm^3"
...

radius = calculate_radius
volume = sphere_volume(radius)
sphere.volume = volume</code></pre>
<p>Why is it a good idea to abstract the formula for a sphere's volume into its own method? Because if mathematicians ever found out they got the formula wrong, you would want to go through all the places in your code that you used the formula and update it to be correct. That is, we know ahead of time that we want the code to be in lockstep. This is as safe a gamble as you can get.</p>
<h3>Over-abstraction examples</h3>
<p>The main sign that you're over-abstracting is that your method accepts a bunch of optional args:</p>
<h4>Example: Bloated method</h4>
<h5>Bad:</h5>
<pre><code>def average(arr, type = Integer, ignore_nulls = false)
  if arr.any?(&amp;:nil?)
    if ignore_nulls
      arr = arr.compact
    else
      return nil
    end
  end

  if type == String
    arr = arr.map(&amp;:to_i)
  end

  arr.sum / arr.size
end

puts average([1,2,3])
=&gt; 2

puts average(['1','2','3'], String)
=&gt; 2

puts average(['1','2','3', nil], String, true)
=&gt; 2

puts average([1, 2, 3, nil], Integer, false)
=&gt; nil</code></pre>
<p>If you want to know how the <code>average</code> method behaves when you're dealing with an array of strings with no <code>nil</code> values, you have to read through the first if condition which has nothing to do with your use case before reaching the code that does. Likewise if you want to know how the <code>average</code> method behaves when the array contains either nils or integers, the second if condition is irrelevant, but you'll still need to read through that to understand how the whole thing works.</p>
<p>If each of the use cases came up dozens or hundreds of times, maybe then it would make sense to retain the abstraction, but when the number of optional arguments is roughly equal to the number of different use cases, chances are you've got the wrong abstraction.</p>
<h5>Good:</h5>
<pre><code>def average(arr)
  arr.sum / arr.size
end

puts average([1,2,3])
=&gt; 2

arr = ['1','2','3'].map(&amp;:to_i)
puts average(arr)
=&gt; 2

arr = ['1','2','3', nil].compact.map(&amp;:to_i)
puts average(arr)
=&gt; 2

arr = [1, 2, 3, nil]
if arr.any?(&amp;:nil?)
  puts nil
else
  puts average(arr)
end
=&gt; nil</code></pre>
<p>In this case we're not removing the abstraction altogether: we're just keeping the part that actually applies to all cases. Now understanding the logic of any one invocation of our <code>average</code> method is trivial.</p>
<p>We now have <code>.map(&amp;:to_i)</code> being duplicated whereas it only appeared once in the <code>Bad</code> alternative, but it's a small cost for a vast improvement.</p>
<p>Note that looking at the <code>Good</code> variant, it's clear that the behaviour is quite different from one use case to the next, but that is not at all clear in the <code>Bad</code> variant because the method calls all look so simple and it was anybody's guess how much code inside <code>average</code> applied to each use case.</p>
<p>This is why abstractions go bad over time: because as you expand the interface more and more, it becomes harder and harder to judge how appropriate the abstraction is to any given use case, and developers end up assuming that all that convoluted code is vaguely relevant to the majority of use cases when in fact it's not.</p>
<h4>Example: Awkward class</h4>
<h5>Bad:</h5>
<pre><code>class Shape
  def initialize(radius: nil, width: nil, type:)
    @radius = radius
    @width = width
    @type = type
  end

  def area
    case @type
    when :square
      @width ** 2
    when :circle
      (@radius ** 2) * Math::PI
    end
  end

  def perimeter
    case @type
    when :square
      @width * 4
    when :circle
      @radius * 2 * Math::PI
    end
  end

  def diameter
    case @type
    when :square
      nil
    when :circle
 …</code></pre></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://jesseduffield.com/beginners-guide-to-abstraction/">https://jesseduffield.com/beginners-guide-to-abstraction/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jesseduffield.com/beginners-guide-to-abstraction/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23735991</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 01:12:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: FAANG Compensation Calculators]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 26 | Comments 10 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23735469">thread link</a>) | @refrigerator
<br/>
July 4, 2020 | https://mackgrenfell.com/compensation-calculators/facebook | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://mackgrenfell.com/compensation-calculators/facebook">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>These calculators show what you can expect to earn at different tech companies, accounting for career progression. </p><p>Data from <a href="https://levels.fyi/" target="_blank">levels.fyi</a>. Models built in <a href="https://causal.app/?utm_source=compensation_calculators" target="_blank">Causal</a>. Special thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/miraan_tabrez" target="_blank">Miraan</a>.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://mackgrenfell.com/compensation-calculators/facebook</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23735469</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 22:56:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How I grew my Shopify micro-SaaS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 123 | Comments 46 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23734539">thread link</a>) | @amrrs
<br/>
July 4, 2020 | https://www.preetamnath.com/blog/grow-shopify-micro-saas-to-25k-mrr-in-14-months | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.preetamnath.com/blog/grow-shopify-micro-saas-to-25k-mrr-in-14-months">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>14 months ago, my co-founder <a href="https://twitter.com/sankalpjonna" target="_blank">Sankalp</a> and I set out to build a business that can sustain our livelihood while allowing us the freedom to live life on our terms. </p><p>When we started, we each had roughly 12 months of savings to survive on, assuming we made $0. Hence our minimum goal was to make $1,500/mo and the case where we would be celebrating with champagne was set to $3,000/mo.</p><p>We launched our app on April 24, 2019. The first paid plan was launched on June 4, 2019. Around the same time, we got <a href="https://www.preetamnath.com/blog/shopify-micro-saas-growth" target="_blank">featured by Shopify</a>. Here's a <a href="https://apps.shopify.com/whatsapp-chat-button" target="_blank">link to the app</a> if you want to check it out.</p><p>14 months later, we grew past $25,000 in MRR while remaining a 2 person team.</p><figure id="w-node-e5ce9f7f0ba4-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f004959a0b62d53946fd901_shopify%20earnings%20growth.png" alt=""></p><figcaption><em>Note:&nbsp;Earnings reflect after a 1 month delay</em></figcaption></figure><p>I’m so proud of what we have built here.</p><p>If life is a video game, and there’s 100 levels to it, I feel like we have finally crossed level 1.</p><p>Here's what we've been up to in the 14 months since launch:</p><ul role="list"><li>20,000 active merchants (users) on the app</li><li>1,500+ paying merchants (customers)</li><li>450,000 automated WhatsApp messages sent in June</li><li>2.2 million WhatsApp chat messages initiated in June</li><li>Highest rated 5.0 🌟 app for all things WhatsApp with 500+ reviews</li><li>Users from 50+ countries around the world</li></ul><figure id="w-node-0cd8870c808c-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f007ba5d6c3b3532b0aa784_paying%20customers%20countries.png" alt=""></p></figure><p>We did a lot of things right, but we also messed up here and there. I've tried to capture an honest and accurate account of our journey so far.</p><h2>11 key learnings and mistakes from our journey<br></h2><h3>1- Learning: Always keep moving the needle</h3><p>Running your own business and having 100% freedom and flexibility is a gift or a curse, depending on how you use it. It’s easy to get lost in building, polishing, bringing your ideas to life. But remember, the only things that matter are what move the needle. </p><p>For every decision related to your business, you should always run it through a set of questions that help you filter out whether your idea is aligned to your business goals.</p><ul role="list"><li>Does it help our app get more users</li><li>Does it help convert more users to paying customers</li><li>Does it help users derive more value and ROI from the app</li><li>Does it meaningfully improve user experience</li><li>Does it reduce our support ticket load</li><li>Does it have any unintended 2nd order consequences that can bite us later</li></ul><p>Ultimately, you want to keep making decisions that move the needle for your business - by bringing you more customers and revenue, or making it easier and less time consuming to run the business (if that’s one of your goals, it is for us).<br></p><h3>2- Learning: Help users realise value as soon as possible</h3><p>From our research, we learnt that Shopify merchants are mostly solopreneurs or teams of 2-10. They are always time and resource crunched.</p><p>We wanted to enable our users to start using the app with the least amount of setup time or steps. This reflects in in the user experience of the app. </p><p>For example, when a first time user enters their phone number and hits the “Save” button, at this time the user is looking to test our app and see if it fits their needs. We speed that up by&nbsp;automatically enabling the chat button on first save, along with the best default configuration for all chat button related settings.</p><figure id="w-node-4b9a52f7ced2-2f0d8df6"><p><iframe allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/o3oeGyv-JJs"></iframe></p></figure><p>Another example, when a user wants to start sending automated messages, all they have to do is click on the “Enable” button. All the app’s default configuration is automatically applied and the user can start seeing value immediately.</p><figure id="w-node-4bee860d412d-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f004a6e594ffa16384d47ca_automated-message-setup-1.png" alt=""></p></figure><figure id="w-node-8c9743f7a3e0-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f004a858d5f7ceaad74de97_automated-message-setup-2.png" alt=""></p></figure><h3>3- Learning: Care about your users, they can feel it</h3><p>Users are on a mission to achieve their goals. They typically need your help when there’s something that stops them from getting there.</p><p>From day 1, we were clear on providing the best possible support. Our users would be thrilled to see bug fixes deployed in 15 minutes, WhatsApp &amp; email replies in 5 minutes, and so on. We were fast, we were responsive.</p><p>This worked in our favour - users showered us with positive reviews which is how we managed 500+ reviews while staying 5.0 star rated.</p><figure id="w-node-f55f45993a1f-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f004affbd3802acac60056d_superlemon%20whatsapp%20app%20shopify%20reviews.png" alt=""></p></figure><p>But customer support isn’t only about getting reviews. We’ve had users who prefer using our app instead of competitors because</p><p><strong>A-</strong> We reply quickly</p><p><strong>B-</strong> We proactively provide information beyond the immediate premise of the query</p><figure id="w-node-e499fce41f50-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f0065d67e883834a7802cc8_review-users-care.png" alt=""></p><figcaption><em>Your users can feel when you genuinely care about them</em></figcaption></figure><h3>4- Learning: Be smart about managing and reducing support ticket volume</h3><p>The downside of trying to be a customer support hero is, you only have finite hours in the day, and you don’t want to spend most of it replying to customers. </p><p>We took 3 specific initiatives to reduce support tickets.</p><p><strong>1- Embed FAQs within the product</strong></p><p>We found that users would have FAQs around specific features, and they wouldn’t really go to the help center and reference it. To them, it’s simpler to ask for help.</p><p>To solve this problem, we embedded FAQs inside the product itself. </p><p>Here are a few examples where we included the most commonly asked question beside the feature configuration. </p><figure id="w-node-1def5927520e-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f004c97d6c3b3b5f30a4556_faq-inside-product-1.png" alt=""></p></figure><figure id="w-node-11706312cf8a-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f004ca08216b9c33aaef853_faq-inside-product-2.png" alt=""></p></figure><figure id="w-node-9239f016ade1-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f004ca87bc6f87761475470_faq-inside-product-3.png" alt=""></p></figure><p>The results were always immediately noticeable. Where we would get 10 questions a week about X, would drop to 1-2, thereby freeing us up from answering repetitive support questions.</p><p><strong>2- Fix repetitive bugs</strong></p><p>If a bug appears more than thrice in a span of days, the third time is when we go ahead and permanently fix it. Why thrice? That way we don’t overwhelm ourselves with trying to fix every single bug, but only the ones that appear repeatedly and take up support time.</p><p><strong>3- Remove WhatsApp chat support and go with Email only</strong></p><p>During initial days, we found it useful to let our users contact us on WhatsApp. It lead to tons of conversations which shaped our understanding of the user’s needs and how we can better solve them. </p><p>But having WhatsApp as a support channel had 3 issues:</p><p><strong>1-</strong> With time, we discovered that people find dropping a message on WhatsApp to be very low barrier. Which means they wouldn’t take a moment to look around, be patient enough to find out how the issue that they are about to describe has already been solved inside the app. It’s just easier to WhatsApp us.</p><p><strong>2-</strong> We also discovered that users had an unrealistic expectation of quick replies and quick resolutions on WhatsApp. Granted, we would be quick whenever possible. But if it’s 11pm at night and the user asks if a bug is fixed 10 minutes later, it can get a bit annoying.</p><p><strong>3-</strong> I started dreading picking up my phone, seeing it full of support tickets every morning.</p><p>To solve this, we removed the WhatsApp chat button from our own app, and replaced it with an Email support button instead. All 3 problems listed above got resolved to a great degree.</p><figure id="w-node-09f7b09a3b19-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f004d01e45cb8848d6cf0f7_Email%20support%20only.png" alt=""></p></figure><p>We also made numerous smaller tweaks to optimise our support flow. One of the tiny but powerful tweaks was to automatically populate the email subject line with the user’s Shopify store url. That made it so much faster for us to look up the specific user instead of a meaningless back and forth of “what’s your store url”.</p><figure id="w-node-280b459e613d-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f00533cbd380208b160157f_store%20url.jpg" alt=""></p></figure><p>Our efforts have paid off. Unless we’re building new features, we spend only about <strong>15-30 minutes per day</strong> on customer support.<br></p><h3>5- Learning: Say No, often</h3><p>Users ask for all sorts of functionality. It doesn’t mean you should build them. </p><p>Whenever we get feature requests, we add a card in our internal Notion board and judge the card against 3 factors</p><p><strong>1-</strong> how many times do we receive the same request</p><p><strong>2-</strong> does the feature align with the rest of our product</p><p><strong>3-</strong> does the feature add core value to the user</p><p>Many times, we found users requesting features that would save them the hassle of using another app. Now, if that functionality enhances the rest of our app, it’s the right feature to add. But if it doesn’t, then we politely decline.</p><figure id="w-node-2831ff295f9b-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f00517014696c60a040b940_politely%20saying%20no.png" alt=""></p></figure><p>There are 2 types of responses we give to customers regarding feature requests:</p><p><strong>1-</strong> Tell them that this feature isn’t requested by other users that much, and since we are a small team with limited resources, we may not be prioritising this feature in the near future.</p><p><strong>2-</strong> Tell them that this feature is already part of our roadmap, and that we will reach out to them whenever it’s ready. I generally avoid giving timelines, to account for “life happens, plans change”.</p><p>This learning extends beyond just feature requests. </p><p>In the past year, we have received tons of business proposals, partnerships, integration requests, collaborative marketing invitations etc. Saying No allowed us to remain focused on what’s really important.<br></p><h3>6- Mistake: Optimise top of the funnel</h3><p>I was under the impression that during build phase, we shouldn’t focus too much on optimisation. After all, you don’t want to get busy squeezing another 10% when the potential is to 10x. </p><p>In most cases, I think I made the right call. One place I made the wrong call was the user onboarding flow.</p><p>Until March 2020, users would install the app and directly land on the chat settings page, which is the starting point of the user’s journey. We were getting a steady flow of 10-15 paid trials initiated per day. </p><p>Adding a step of friction before this would be counterintuitive, right? It couldn’t possibly increase trials, right?</p><p>Sigh. </p><p>When we added one screen which asked the user upfront whether they want to continue with the Free plan, or start a trial for the Paid plan, daily paid trials DOUBLED overnight, while trial-to-paid conversion rate remained steady at 50%. </p><figure id="w-node-c2d582bcc858-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f004d9fda26a209aa082a72_onboarding%20trial%20doubled.png" alt=""></p></figure><p>The experiment took us a day to build, and after a week we concluded what was clearly the winner.</p><p>I normally advocate for focusing on building vs optimising in the early stages, but in this case I didn’t know that optimisation was waiting to unlock 100% increase in trials.</p><p>My takeaway here is - always keep your eyes open for bottlenecks at the top of funnel. </p><p>If there’s copy on your website, or a specific sign up flow that might be holding you back from getting 2x the users, you need to unblock it early and realise compounded gains over time.<br></p><h3>7- Mistake: Competition will copy, don’t completely ignore them</h3><p>In the past year, we’ve seen competitors copy our app interface, in-app descriptions, button designs, app listing text word-for-word in many cases. Initially we were furious, but instead we kept our head down and focused on customer’s needs. </p><p>Eventually we started ignoring our competitors, which was a mistake. While …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.preetamnath.com/blog/grow-shopify-micro-saas-to-25k-mrr-in-14-months">https://www.preetamnath.com/blog/grow-shopify-micro-saas-to-25k-mrr-in-14-months</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.preetamnath.com/blog/grow-shopify-micro-saas-to-25k-mrr-in-14-months</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23734539</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 20:00:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[De-escalating social media conflict]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 412 | Comments 209 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23734535">thread link</a>) | @npunt
<br/>
July 4, 2020 | https://nickpunt.com/blog/deescalating-social-media/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nickpunt.com/blog/deescalating-social-media/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
    <p>Social media has a conflict problem.</p><p>Spending even a few minutes on public social media can expose us to dozens of people we know little about, talking about things we know little about. In such a public place, any individual's reputation, perspectives, and history are difficult to ascertain, and therefore their words must be taken at face value. Coupled with an almost complete lack of standards for participation in the community and a high degree of variance in knowledge among participants, and the environment naturally skews toward conflict and tribalism.</p><p>One particular effect of this environment is that small misunderstandings, mistakes, or disagreements can unexpectedly explode due to the public nature of discourse and assumptions of bad faith. Meanwhile, very few tools exist to moderate these effects.</p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>This is why it's my belief that <mark>as designed today, social media is out of balance</mark>. It is far easier to escalate than it is to de-escalate, and this is a major problem that companies like Twitter and Facebook need to address.</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>This got me thinking about what particular use cases need de-escalation, and whether there's something simple we can do to test the waters and address these types of problems. </p><h2 id="target-use-case-admitting-mistakes">Target Use Case: Admitting Mistakes</h2><p>One obvious issue is that <strong>people are wrong about a lot of things, but struggle to admit their mistakes</strong>. This is why many cultures have created elaborate norms around face-saving. Unfortunately, social media largely lacks these cultural norms, and even makes the problem worse in three ways:</p><ol><li><strong>No social proof</strong> - Admitting mistakes is quite difficult if nobody else is seen (genuinely) admitting mistakes, as we rely heavily on social proof to sense-make around norms. An escalation-oriented culture means there's less genuine "I was wrong" on social media than there should be.</li><li><strong>No respite</strong> - as the visibility of a mistake travels across social media, the poster is subject to a constant deluge of new readers calling them out, with the combined energy of the outraged far exceeding that of the poster. This prevents them from having the necessary emotional cool-down period to respond thoughtfully.</li><li><strong>Digging in</strong> - when feeling personally attacked, its human nature to prefer to dig in rather than apologize. Social media's escalation-oriented culture plays into this human fallibility.</li></ol><p>Take Twitter as an example environment. If we write something that turns out to be wrong and a pile-on begins, we're going to be swimming upstream fighting it. Our options are:</p><ol><li><strong>Ignore</strong> replies and hopefully let it die out</li><li><strong>Delete</strong> your tweet, posting another tweet saying "I was wrong"</li><li><strong>Reply</strong> to your tweet, posting "I was wrong"</li></ol><p>However, none of these are great. If we ignore<strong><em> </em></strong>replies, the simple amplification effects of likes, replies, retweets, and subtweets leave us exposed and the situation can get out of hand. If we delete and post another, people are unlikely to see our follow-up, as corrections are rarely viral. Similarly, even if we reply, only our viral mistake will be seen in the feed of others. </p><p>Let's also not forget the human tendency to not fully walk back statements, and instead offer unsatisfying explanations that can accidentally further enflame situations. Blaming, justifying, minimizing, or excusing are all self-sabotaging ways that people qualify their apologies to preserve their self-esteem or resolve their own cognitive dissonance, and social media is right there ready to give us this kind of rope to hang ourselves with when we're under assault.</p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>In all these cases, a person's reputation in the minds of others is damaged because <mark>social media engagement engines favor the drama of the mistake over the correction and reconciliation</mark>, which leads few people to see or remember anything other than the mistake.</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>This seems like a perfect use case to design for, so I came up with a little design change I call the Twitter Mea Culpa.</p><h2 id="design-exploration-twitter-mea-culpa">Design Exploration: Twitter Mea Culpa</h2><p>Twitter Mea Culpa is a way for a poster to flag their tweet as a mistake and de-escalate a situation, using the same action menu that deleting a post uses, and the same visual design as flagged tweets:</p><figure><img src="https://nickpunt.com/content/images/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Blue-w-Menu-NoLabel-1.png" alt="" srcset="https://nickpunt.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Blue-w-Menu-NoLabel-1.png 600w, https://nickpunt.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Blue-w-Menu-NoLabel-1.png 1000w, https://nickpunt.com/content/images/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Blue-w-Menu-NoLabel-1.png 1260w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption>Twitter Mea Culpa: flagging a post as a mistake</figcaption></figure><h3 id="clear-language">Clear Language</h3><!--kg-card-begin: html--><figure><a href="https://nickpunt.com/content/images/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Language-1.png"><img src="https://nickpunt.com/content/images/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Language-1.png" alt="" srcset="https://nickpunt.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Language-1.png 600w, https://nickpunt.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Language-1.png 1000w, https://nickpunt.com/content/images/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Language-1.png 1198w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></a><figcaption>Language:<em> @user has indicated they made a mistake in this tweet</em></figcaption></figure><!--kg-card-end: html--><p>I picked this language carefully for several reasons:</p><ol><li>Create separation between the individual and what they say (the specific post), which reduces ego threat.</li><li>Use an active voice to indicate responsibility (<em>I made a mistake</em> not <em>Mistakes were made</em>).</li><li>Indicate the poster was the one who chose to flag the post, not Twitter or any other user, to reduce the impression to other users that the poster was censored.</li><li>State the mistake unequivocally and leaving no room for ambiguity about whether it is actually a mistake, to reduce inauthentic use and self-sabotage.</li><li>Avoid direct use of 'sorry' or 'I apologize' language, because for some people these words are extremely <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-squeaky-wheel/201305/5-reasons-why-some-people-will-never-say-sorry">emotionally challenging</a> to use.</li></ol><h3 id="disable-amplification">Disable Amplification</h3><!--kg-card-begin: html--><figure><a href="https://nickpunt.com/content/images/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Amplification-1.png"><img src="https://nickpunt.com/content/images/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Amplification-1.png" alt="" srcset="https://nickpunt.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Amplification-1.png 600w, https://nickpunt.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Amplification-1.png 1000w, https://nickpunt.com/content/images/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Amplification-1.png 1262w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></a></figure><!--kg-card-end: html--><p>Much like rules violations, once a user admits a mistake, the Mea Culpa tweet is no longer amplified. This means:</p><ul><li>The tweet is no longer made visible on everyone's home feed</li><li>Users cannot reply, like, or retweet without comment</li><li>Users may retweet <em>with</em> comment, to allow users to amplify the correction (e.g. <em>I thought this wasn't the case, looks like they realized it</em>)</li></ul><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>By admitting a mistake, the poster stops the runaway train of replies and amplifications of their mistake, and the reputation damage that follows. In other words, <mark>Mea Culpas are intentionally designed to favor respectful debate and ability to cool off over maximal information exchange</mark>.</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><figure><img src="https://nickpunt.com/content/images/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-ExampleViolation.png" alt=""><figcaption>How Twitter handles rules violations today; notice the lack of like/reply/retweet counts</figcaption></figure><p>This amplification disabling is how rules violations work today. However admitting a mistake is much more innocuous, so I would recommend that existing replies, retweets, and likes remain accessible, which is not the case with violations. After all, sometimes mistakes can create interesting conversation.</p><h3 id="surface-corrections">Surface Corrections</h3><p>One possible exception to the disable amplification rule is that a Mea Culpa tweet could show up again <em>within the home feeds of users who originally reacted to it</em>. This would basically be like issuing a correction, which would be intended to help limit accidental falsehoods from spreading. </p><figure><img src="https://nickpunt.com/content/images/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-FeedCorrection-1.png" alt="" srcset="https://nickpunt.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-FeedCorrection-1.png 600w, https://nickpunt.com/content/images/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-FeedCorrection-1.png 707w"><figcaption>Mistake correction shown in Home Feed, shown because user liked the tweet</figcaption></figure><p>For instance, if someone tweeted an unsubstantiated rumor and we liked or replied to it, when we go back to our home feed a day or two later we'd see their tweet with the notice that they'd made a mistake.</p><p>This seems like the right thing to do, and a way to help social media stay more focused on truth.</p><h3 id="culture-of-use">Culture of Use</h3><p>Twitter Mea Culpa is meant to solve for a few specific use cases that involve the poster's authentic desire for de-escalation at some level:</p><ol><li><strong>I'm actually wrong </strong>- when the poster knows they are wrong and wants to stop hearing from people and just correct their mistake.</li><li><strong>I'm right if you look at it this way</strong> - when the poster is struggling to understand in what ways or from what perspectives they're wrong, but can tell they are a little bit wrong, and are considering explaining themselves.</li><li><strong>Fine, I give up </strong>- when the poster is struggling to apologize or admit they're wrong, as is often the case when people feel vulnerable or when their ego is bruised, and are starting to think it might be better to tap out than to continue.</li></ol><p>Today, the <em><strong>I'm actually wrong</strong></em><strong> </strong>case is an obvious flaw in the system, where posters have to constantly reply to people saying <em>"yeah, I know, I know, I was wrong, look at my other tweet"</em>. In this case, their reputation is less at risk and they're already at a point of emotional acceptance, so it's simply a matter of unnecessary UX friction.</p><p>The much more interesting and subtle cases are <strong><em>I'm right if you look at it this way</em></strong> and <strong><em>Fine, I give up</em></strong>. Posters in these situations may not yet have the emotional distance to gain proper perspective, still feeling a connection between what they said and who they are (ego threat). As mentioned before, the lack of respite in social media can keep people in this emotional state for a lot longer than they might otherwise be, as each new notification they receive keeps them in a state of alert.</p><p>In these situations, there's an emotional temptation to respond when it's often best not to, given the escalating nature of the medium. The temptation comes from a poster having only one tool at their disposal to repair their reputation: replying to the tweets contributing to their threatened feelings. </p><p>With Mea Culpa, users gain a second tool specifically designed to de-escalate, that only requires their acknowledgement that a) they may be at least partly wrong, and b) they do not wish to continue. When in use, it can cut off potentially escalating conversations early, giving everyone else who sees the tweet the signal to step back because the poster may not have meant it and (at least partially) admits their mistake.</p><p>There is no guarantee that most or all conversations would de-escalate after a Mea Culpa, but in imagining the possible uses for it, I think it would help considerably.</p><h3 id="correcting-for-inauthenticity">Correcting for Inauthenticity</h3><p>Unfortunately, there are also many bad faith actors on social media, and there's potential for any feature to be used in a way that means something other than what was intended, creating a culture of alternate use and meaning. A few anti-patterns may emerge here:</p><ol><li><strong>Growth hacking</strong> - a user posts something intentionally fabulist they want others to see, get a lot of engagement, and then post a mistake tag to try to have people see it again.</li><li><strong>Ironic opposite</strong> - a user flags everything they post as a mistake, either in protest or just as an ironic statement.</li><li><strong>Just kidding </strong>- a user posts something boundary-pushing to float it as an idea, then walks it back with a mistake tag.</li><li><strong>I had to do it </strong>- a user posts something boundary-pushing that they believe, then walks it back with a mistake tag as a …</li></ol></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://nickpunt.com/blog/deescalating-social-media/">https://nickpunt.com/blog/deescalating-social-media/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nickpunt.com/blog/deescalating-social-media/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23734535</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 19:59:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Iran dumps Flight 752 investigator, airspace open to conceal 'imminent' attack]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 95 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23733910">thread link</a>) | @refurb
<br/>
July 4, 2020 | https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/audio-recording-iran-lead-investigator-flight-ps752-1.5636450 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/audio-recording-iran-lead-investigator-flight-ps752-1.5636450">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>A newly released audio recording suggests Iran's highest authorities allowed commercial airliners to fly in and out of Tehran during the period of intense military activity when Flight 752 was shot down — because closing the airspace would have given away the regime's plan to strike U.S. military bases in Iraq.</p><div><figure><div><p><img alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5636477.1593791704!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/plane-crash.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>The head of Iran's investigation into Flight PS752 has been replaced following the release of a recording of a conversation he had with a victim's relation in Canada.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Reuters)</figcaption></figure><p><span><p>A newly released audio recording suggests Iran's highest authorities allowed commercial airliners to fly in and out of Tehran during the period of intense military activity when Flight 752 was shot down — because closing the airspace would have given away the regime's plan to strike U.S. military bases in Iraq.</p>  <p>CBC News obtained a recording of a&nbsp;91-minute conversation that took place March 7&nbsp;between a victim's family member in Canada and Hassan Rezaeifar, who was appointed the head of Iran's investigation into the downing of the Kyiv-bound Ukraine International Airlines aircraft. The crash of Flight 752 killed 176 people, including 57 Canadians.</p>  <p>The recording, which reveals a number of damning details about the downing of the plane and Iran's response, is also in the custody of Canadian authorities.</p>  <p>Less than 24 hours after CBC News emailed Rezaeifar a copy of the recording and requested a response Thursday, news broke that he had been removed from his role overseeing Iran's investigation into the downing of Flight 752. Families in the United Kingdom — which has&nbsp;an embassy in Iran — were notified this morning that a new investigator is now in charge.</p>  <h2>Airspace kept open to avoid signalling&nbsp;attack:&nbsp;Rezaeifar</h2>  <p>In the recording, Rezaeifar said closing the airspace over Tehran could have exposed Iran's pending ballistic missile attack on U.S. air bases in Iraq in advance. That attack was retaliation for the United States' killing of Iran's top military leader,&nbsp;Gen.&nbsp;Qasem Soleimani.</p>  <p>"Some say we should have cleared the airspace," Rezaeifar said in Farsi on the recording. "The National Security Council is in charge.</p>  <p>"But let's say we had cleared the airspace. Wouldn't [it] give away our imminent attack?"</p>  <p>Flight 752 was shot down just four hours after the strike on the U.S. base. Rezaeifar added that&nbsp;closing the airspace could have meant cancelling flights. Iran earns hundreds of thousands of dollars <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/iran-airspace-canadians-downed-flight-1.5481818" target="_blank">daily in fees for allowing flights in its airspace.</a></p>  <p>"Ok, let's assume we had delayed the Ukrainian flight for ten hours. Wouldn't it have cancelled all other flights after?" said Rezaeifar on the call.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5636474.1593790216!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/flight-752-crash.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5636474.1593790216!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/flight-752-crash.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5636474.1593790216!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/flight-752-crash.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5636474.1593790216!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/flight-752-crash.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5636474.1593790216!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/flight-752-crash.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5636474.1593790216!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/flight-752-crash.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Investigators pick up debris at the crash site of the Ukraine International Airlines plane shot down after takeoff from Iran's Imam Khomeini Airport on Jan. 8, 2020. <!-- --> <!-- -->(Nazanin Tabatabaee/WANA via Reuters)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>Thomas Juneau, an associate professor of international affairs at the University of Ottawa and former analyst of&nbsp;Middle East affairs, said Iran has been insisting the investigation will be independent — and the audio recording proves&nbsp;it's not.&nbsp;</p>  <p>"Having the lead investigator saying those things on that phone call really damages that fiction," said Juneau. "By removing him, they're trying to protect that facade."</p>  <h2>Passengers used as human shields, says expert</h2>  <p>Payam Akhavan, a Canadian-Iranian international law professor at McGill University and former UN prosecutor at The Hague, also reviewed CBC's copy of the recording. Akhavan argues the audio is a new piece of evidence showing the highest levels of Iran's government chose to keep planes full of people in the sky on a day of intense military activity.&nbsp;</p>  <p>"The senior leadership of the government willingly and knowingly disregarded these risks," said Akhavan. "This is not just a question of human error or mistake. It's a question of criminal&nbsp;recklessness.</p>  <p>"To knowingly put civilian aircraft in harm's way, to use civilian airliners in effect as human shields, clearly implicates criminal responsibility."</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5421757.1593792034!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/ps752-victims.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5421757.1593792034!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/ps752-victims.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5421757.1593792034!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/ps752-victims.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5421757.1593792034!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/ps752-victims.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5421757.1593792034!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/ps752-victims.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5421757.1593792034!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/ps752-victims.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Dozens of Canadians, as well as students and academics studying in Canada, were killed in the downing of Flight 752.<!-- --> <!-- -->(CBC)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <h2>Crash investigator in immediate contact with military</h2>  <p>Akhavan also said the audio implicates&nbsp;the investigation team in a cover-up.</p>  <p>In the recording,&nbsp;Rezaeifar —&nbsp;who was the head of the accident investigation board at the Iran Civil Aviation Organization at the time — says he&nbsp;picked up the phone five minutes after the plane crashed and was in immediate contact with Iran's military.</p>  <p>Rezaeifar said Amir-Ali Hajizadeh, the commander of the Aerospace Force of the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC), admitted the military was ordered to shoot missiles due to national security concerns.</p>  <p>"I was informed at 6:30 a.m. and I called the IRGC at 6:35 a.m. and asked, 'Did you have a missile attack?'" Rezaeifar says in the recording. "Mr. Hajizadeh explained and said&nbsp;yes, and we had orders. He said there are some national security considerations in the country."</p>  <p>On January 11, Iran's military admitted it unintentionally shot down the plane and blamed human error, saying the military&nbsp;mistook the jetliner for a hostile target. That acknowledgement&nbsp;came after three days of denial and after satellite evidence showed&nbsp;that missiles had hit the aircraft.</p>  <p>Rezaeifar did not respond to CBC's request for a comment. His name is used throughout the audio recording&nbsp;and CBC News has copies of messages sent from his Instagram account setting up the phone call.</p>  <h2>Victim's family member 'intimidated'</h2>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5521619.1585951192!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_300/javad-soleimani.jpeg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5521619.1585951192!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_460/javad-soleimani.jpeg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5521619.1585951192!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_620/javad-soleimani.jpeg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5521619.1585951192!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_780/javad-soleimani.jpeg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5521619.1585951192!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/javad-soleimani.jpeg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5521619.1585951192!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_780/javad-soleimani.jpeg"></p></div><figcaption>Javad Soleimani's wife Elnaz Nabiy died in the destruction of Flight PS752.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Supplied)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>Javad Soleimani (no relation to Gen.&nbsp;Qasem Soleimani) was&nbsp;the Edmonton PhD student on the other end of the call with Rezaeifar. He said&nbsp;Rezaeifar&nbsp;pressured him&nbsp;to remove an&nbsp;Instagram&nbsp;post critical of the Iranian regime. Soleimani has been an outspoken critic of Tehran since his wife Elnaz Nabiy died in the crash.</p>  <p>In that Instagram post, Soleimani wrote Iranians&nbsp;won't forget about the crimes the regime has committed against its own people.</p>  <p>"Please delete it from your Instagram," Rezaeifar tells&nbsp;Soleimani on the call. "Do you agree that out of 83 million people of Iran, only 10 or 12 people have hurt you? Why should those other 82 million people be insulted by this post?"</p>  <p>He then asks Soleimani if he thinks the Canadian government is more "benevolent" toward him.&nbsp;</p>  <p>"Are you certain that the whole Canadian government is good and uncorrupt?" asked Rezaeifar.</p>  <p>Two days later, Soleimani&nbsp;said,&nbsp;Iran's Ministry of Intelligence contacted his family members in Iran to exert more pressure on them about his behaviour on social media.&nbsp;</p>  <ul>   <li> <p><a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/iran-flight-752-ukraine-international-airlines-crash-1.5521377" target="_blank"><strong>Families of Flight 752 victims report threats, acts of intimidation — and blame Tehran</strong></a></p> </li>  </ul>  <p>"It's ridiculous," Soleimani told CBC News. "They just wanted to somehow threaten me to stop criticizing the regime on social media because I had many followers on Instagram.</p>  <p>"They tried to force me to be silent ... but honestly, I have nothing to lose. And I told him,&nbsp;I told him I have nothing to lose,&nbsp;so you cannot stop me by just threatening me by conversation over the phone."</p>  <h2>'Inappropriate' for investigator to pressure&nbsp;family member</h2>  <p>Juneau said it's "totally inappropriate" and "absurd" for the lead crash&nbsp;investigator&nbsp;to put pressure on&nbsp;a victim's family member in Canada. He also said it's not surprising.</p>  <p>"I did not expect the investigation to be independent and few serious analysts did," Juneau said. "This basically confirms it.</p>  <p>"It's not very smart. It's just not a good move."</p>  <p>He said the practice&nbsp;of the Islamic Republic is to exert psychological&nbsp;pressure,&nbsp;and often physical&nbsp;pressure, on anyone opposed to the regime,&nbsp;at home and abroad.</p>  <p>Juneau said he wants to know the extent of Rezaeifar's relationship with the IRGC and Iran's&nbsp;Ministry of Intelligence. He cautions the details of what Rezaeifar said on the recording might not be accurate, and might have been meant to exert pressure on Soleimani.</p>  <p>"Is it true?" said Juneau. "Is he boasting? Is he exaggerating some things to increase the level of intimidation towards family members? These are all questions that we don't know the answer to."</p>  <p>Syrine Khoury, press secretary to&nbsp;Foreign&nbsp;Affairs Minister&nbsp;François-Philippe Champagne, sent a written statement to CBC&nbsp;saying "interference with Canadian citizens is totally unacceptable, very troubling and won't be tolerated.</p>  <p>"The government of Canada denounces any and all attempts to coerce or pressure Canadians, especially those suffering the loss of a loved one," she added. "The government of Canada encourages anyone who feels threatened, unsafe or vulnerable to contact local law enforcement authorities."</p>  <p>Ralph Goodale, Canada's special adviser to the Trudeau government on the&nbsp;Flight 752 file, said the phone call&nbsp;"constitutes outrageous behaviour."</p>  <p>"It's wrong on every count of procedure, propriety, appropriateness. It's simply completely wrong," he said.&nbsp;</p>  <p>He added the International Coordination and Response Group formed by&nbsp;Canada, Ukraine, Sweden, Afghanistan and the United Kingdom to support victims' families will be investigating&nbsp;Rezaeifar's&nbsp;"interesting and provocative" comments about keeping the airspace open to see if there's truth to the remarks.&nbsp;</p>  <h2>Audio casts doubt on past reports</h2>  <p>Hamed Esmaeilion, the interim spokesperson for the association representing the families of the Canadian victims, said the recording raises serious concerns about the two reports Iran's Civil Aviation Organization has already published about Flight 752. Esmaeilion lost his wife, Parisa Eghbalian, and their nine-year-old daughter Reera in the destruction&nbsp;of Flight 752.</p>  <p>"I don't see any different between Rezaeifar and the new investigator," he said. "CAO is not independent. The whole organization is closely working with the IRGC."</p>  <p>Iran is expected to publish another report on the crash&nbsp;before heading to France on July 20 to download and analyze the plane's flight data recorders, according …</p></span></p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/audio-recording-iran-lead-investigator-flight-ps752-1.5636450">https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/audio-recording-iran-lead-investigator-flight-ps752-1.5636450</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/audio-recording-iran-lead-investigator-flight-ps752-1.5636450</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23733910</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 18:10:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Who killed the air-powered vehicle?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23733299">thread link</a>) | @HermanMartinus
<br/>
July 4, 2020 | https://herman.bearblog.dev/air-powered-vehicle/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://herman.bearblog.dev/air-powered-vehicle/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<div><h2>Compressed air is a sustainable alternative to batteries and fossil fuels. Despite this, it has been disappearing from the public eye.</h2>
<p>I first became interested in compressed air as a fuel source during a visit to The Hartebeesthoek Radio Astronomy Observatory (HartRAO) during a cub-scout camp many years ago. We made rockets out of Coca-Cola bottles pumped up with a bicycle pump; makeshift fins held on with cello-tape. After a brief pumping the pent-up energy overcame the nozzle’s friction, the bottle-rocket would detach from the pump, and would blast off into space.</p>
<p>Alternative forms of energy storage have always been fascinating. From <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pumped-storage_hydroelectricity"> pumped hydroelectric energy storage</a> to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flywheel_energy_storage">flywheel energy storage</a> . I recently stumbled upon this article on Low-Tech magazine about <a href="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2018/05/ditch-the-batteries-off-grid-compressed-air-energy-storage.html"> compressed air energy storage (CAES)</a> . It rekindled my interest in using compressed air as a way to conserve power, overcoming the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Duck_curve"> duck’s head problem</a> of some sustainable energy production techniques like solar and wind power.</p>
<p>The concept of CAES is fairly simple: compress air while there is energy production (the sun is up) for later use. The flow of energy can then be turned up or down depending on the demand by increasing or decreasing the flow of air.</p>
<p>Larger-scale CAES plants are fairly inefficient since compressing air generates heat (the second law of thermodynamics) and decompressing air cools it down significantly. Due to this, we will not be talking about CAES for large scale power storage, but for powering vehicles. Specifically, the humble bike.</p>
<p>A compressed-air vehicle is fuelled by tanks of pressurised atmospheric gas and propelled by the release and expansion of the gas within a pneumatic motor. These vehicles are comparable to battery-powered vehicles, with energy generation being displaced from the vehicle itself to a power plant where lower source emissions are possible and the net production of pollutants can be reduced.</p>
<p>The energy is stored in a pressurised tank on the vehicle which can be refilled or swapped out (hypothetically) at service stations, or refilled by plugging an onboard compressor into the electricity grid. Compressed air in 300 bar containers has energy density comparable to lead-acid batteries.</p>
<p>There have been few examples of compressed air vehicles in history such as the Gottardbahn pneumatic locomotive and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fireless_locomotive"> Fireless locomotives</a> .</p>
<p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/0/07/CompressedAirLocomotive_Section1_AdolpheBraun1811to1877.jpg" alt=" Gotthardbahn"></p>
<p>Torpedos have also been known to use compressed air as a propulsion mechanism.</p>
<h3>What makes pneumatic vehicles interesting?</h3>
<p>The sounds of a city are the sounds of traffic. During the first week of lockdown was the first time I had ever heard a truly quiet city. The sounds of vehicles dominate the soundscape of cities. A city without internal combustion engines would be a much more peaceful place to live.</p>
<p>The cost of building pneumatic bikes are potentially much smaller than both internal combustion and electric motorbikes due to the simplicity of their design and the lack of special materials required in their construction. Lest we forget, internal combustion engines work by carefully exploding fuel and directing the explosions in a useful way.</p>
<p>Compressed-air vehicles are comparable in many ways to electric vehicles in their advantages but without the need for environmentally hazardous chemicals such as gasoline or battery acids/metals. Cylinders also do not need to be changed out every few years like electrochemical batteries and have a much longer operational life due to the simplicity of their structure.</p>
<p>The rate of self-discharge is very low when compared to batteries that deplete their charge slowly over time. Therefore, the vehicle may be left unused for longer periods than electric alternatives.</p>
<p>These cylinders can be swapped out at filling stations easily or charged while parked using solar power or done at home by hooking it up to the electrical grid.</p>
<p>Due to social distancing measures taken in big cities such as London and Paris, cycling for transport has spiked again, with new cycle-only paths and roads becoming the norm. Having personal vehicles as opposed to taking public transport will be standard for the foreseeable future while we deal with this pandemic.</p>
<h3>There are some downsides</h3>
<p>Any conversion of energy between forms results in a loss. For compressed-air cars, energy is lost when electrical energy is converted to compressed air, and when that stored energy is converted into kinetic energy to turn the motor.</p>
<p>When air expands it cools dramatically. This energy loss could be used for something, but for now let’s just assume that it is lost to the atmosphere on an air-powered motorbike. Similarly, tanks get very hot when filled rapidly. SCUBA tanks can be immersed in water to cool them while being filled, but this also results in energy loss.</p>
<p>Refuelling a compressed air container at home may take as long as 4 hours, while refilling on specialised equipment may fill the tank in 3 minutes while dealing with the excess heat in some (hopefully productive) way.</p>
<p>The final issue with CAES for propulsion is that while batteries can somewhat maintain their voltage throughout their discharge, the pressure of compressed air tanks falls as the air is released, effectively providing less propulsion over time.</p>
<h3>Experimental cars and bikes</h3>
<p>For this article, we will be focussing specifically on bikes, as there are a few problems with air-powered cars as the power necessary to propel a car is vastly greater than the amount necessary to propel a bike. While the majority of the energy required for driving a car is used in moving the car itself, the inverse is true for a bike where an air propelled bike would likely weigh half of the weight of the rider.</p>
<p>There have been a whole host of functional prototypes for bikes running on nothing but compressed air. The <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20110218141158/http://www.ecofriend.org/entry/eco-bikes-green-speed-air-powered-motorcycle-aims-to-smash-land-speed-record/"> Green Speed Air Powered Motorcycle</a> using the Angelo Di Pietro compressed air engine made some noise in 2009.</p>
<p><img src="https://inhabitat.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2012/11/o2-pursuit-final_363-600x480.jpg" alt="O2 Pursuit"></p>
<p>In 2011 the <a href="https://www.coroflot.com/deanbenstead/O2-Pursuit-Prototype"> O2 Pursuit Prototype by Dean Benstead</a> boasted a range of 100km per tank and top speeds of 140km/h, using a modified Yamaha WR250R and also using EngineAir’s Angelo Di Pietro motor. It even won a <a href="https://newatlas.com/2012-james-dyson-award-finalists/24630/"> James Dyson award</a></p>
<p>There have been multiple successful engineering projects. Some built by engineering students, some by hippies or handymen at home. <a href="https://bikeportland.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/pneu-Cory-lead-ted-800x789.jpg"> Cory Little</a></p>
<p>Even Peugeot, Suzuki, Toyota, and Tata had some form of air-powered vehicles in the works.</p>
<h3>Then things go silent</h3>
<p>My research on pneumatic vehicles took me on nostalgia-inducing trips through the “old internet” of personal blogs, unmaintained news sites, and enthusiast journals. There were a LOT of broken links as web pages were removed over the years, domains expired, and server fans stopped spinning.</p>
<p>Around 2012 talk about pneumatic and air-powered vehicles goes quiet. The plans of releasing some promising pneumatic motorbikes to the public seems to completely disappear. Toyota, Tata, Peugeot and Suzuki (as far as I can tell) abandon their plans to release air powered vehicles. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AIRPod"> 1</a> <a href="https://www.lesechos.fr/2015/01/psa-la-revolution-de-lhybrid-air-naura-pas-lieu-190742">2</a></p>
<p>I’m generally not a conspiracy theorist, but I believe that air-powered vehicles may have been suppressed (see what I did there). The technology is sound, and if prototypes built by engineering students can work well enough, imagine what could happen if a well-funded company developed an air-powered motorbike.</p>
<p>Maybe there’s something I don’t know about. Maybe the tech is actually a lot more complicated than I am led to believe, but that still leaves the question: Who killed the pneumatic bike?</p>
</div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://herman.bearblog.dev/air-powered-vehicle/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23733299</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 16:27:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Uber wants to cut costs by shifting its engineering to India]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 61 | Comments 101 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23731891">thread link</a>) | @SQL2219
<br/>
July 4, 2020 | https://www.businessinsider.in/business/news/uber-is-struggling-due-to-covid19-now-it-wants-to-cut-costs-by-shifting-its-engineering-to-india/articleshow/76768028.cms | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.businessinsider.in/business/news/uber-is-struggling-due-to-covid19-now-it-wants-to-cut-costs-by-shifting-its-engineering-to-india/articleshow/76768028.cms">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div id="datatxt76768028read"><div data-den="denmark"><div><ul>
 <li><keyword keytype="person" smid="0" usetype="2" keywordseo="Uber-CEO" actualkeyword="Uber CEO">Uber CEO</keyword> Dara Khosrowshahi is eager to shift engineering innovation to India as it will be cheaper for the company, said a report by The Information.</li>
 <li>Globally, Uber lost $2.9 billion in the first three months of the year because of the coronavirus pandemic. </li>
 <li>Khosrowshahi had earlier said that the impact of COVID-19 would be drastic for the company. </li>
</ul><p>Ride hailing giant Uber has been severely impacted by the coronavirus pandemic across the world. Globally, Uber lost 
<a target="_blank" href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/uber-earnings-q1-161-million-loss-ridership-falls-3-percent/" rel="nofollow">$2.9 billion</a> in the first three months of the year because of the coronavirus pandemic. 
</p><p>
And now, in a step to cut costs by shifting its engineering jobs to India, said a report by 
<a target="_blank" href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/uber-ceo-wants-to-shift-more-engineering-jobs-to-india-sparking-internal-debate?shared=53eda2af81f50ffb" rel="nofollow">The Information.</a> According to the report, Uber CEO Dara Khosrowshahi is eager to shift engineering innovation to India as it will be cheaper for the company.
</p><keyword keytype="person" smid="0" usetype="2" keywordseo="Uber-India" actualkeyword="Uber India">Uber India</keyword><p> didn’t comment on the same. 
</p><p>
<span>Advertisement</span></p><hr><p>Khosrowshahi had earlier said that the impact of COVID-19 would be drastic for the company. 
</p><p>
    "I won't sugarcoat it. COVID-19 has had a dramatic impact on rides, with the business down globally around 80% in April,” he 
<a target="_blank" href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/uber-earnings-q1-161-million-loss-ridership-falls-3-percent/" rel="nofollow">said</a> during the conference call for its earnings. 
</p><p>
Earlier, as a part of its massive global layoff of 6,700 employees, Uber India had laid off 600 employees in India. “The impact of Covid-19 and the unpredictable nature of the recovery has left Uber IndiaSA with no choice but to reduce the size of its workforce. Around 600 full time positions across driver and rider support, as well as other functions, are being impacted. These reductions are part of previously announced global job cuts this month,” Pradeep Parameswaran, President, Uber India and South Asia had said during the layoffs in May 2020. 
</p><p><span>Advertisement</span></p><hr><p>However, Uber’s wish to shift its engineering to India is not something new. During his visit to India in 2019, Khosrowshahi had said that India is going to be a big source of innovation for them. “One example is the Uber Lite app, was designed and built in India and moved to over 30 countries around the world,” he had said.
</p><p>
Manik Gupta who was then the Chief Product Officer of Uber had said that Uber is proud of the engineering and product talent based out of Bengaluru and Hyderabad. “We have a goal to double the headcount in these offices and have 1,000 people to build innovative products out of India,” he had said.
</p><p>
    SEE ALSO:
<br>
<a href="https://www.businessinsider.in/business/telecom/news/vodafone-idea-news-how-much-cash-does-vodafone-idea-need-to-survive/articleshow/76766763.cms">Only cash can save Vodafone Idea from a slow death⁠— and it needs a lot of it</a>
<br data-name="47" data-nm1="br"><span>Advertisement</span></p><hr>

<p><a href="https://www.businessinsider.in/business/news/reliance-jio-gets-investment-from-intel-capital/articleshow/76761995.cms">Reliance Jio gets ₹1894.5 crore from Intel Capital – the 12th investment in 11 weeks</a></p></div></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.businessinsider.in/business/news/uber-is-struggling-due-to-covid19-now-it-wants-to-cut-costs-by-shifting-its-engineering-to-india/articleshow/76768028.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23731891</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 12:48:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Welcome to MaXX Interactive Desktop]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 19 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23731714">thread link</a>) | @rbanffy
<br/>
July 4, 2020 | https://maxxinteractive.com/books/misc/page/welcome-to-maxx-interactive-desktop | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://maxxinteractive.com/books/misc/page/welcome-to-maxx-interactive-desktop">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div dir="auto">

    

    

            <blockquote id="bkmrk-new-version-of-maxx-">
<h4 id="bkmrk-%C2%A0-1"><strong><em>New version of MaXX Interactive Desktop is now </em><a href="https://maxxinteractive.com/books/mid-v21-installation-guide"><em>available</em></a></strong></h4>
<h5 id="bkmrk-%3E%3E-link-to-release-n"><em><strong><a title="July 4th 2020 - Release Day for MaXX Desktop v2.1" href="https://maxxinteractive.com/books/whats-new/page/july-4th-2020---release-day-for-maxx-desktop-v21-a8a">&gt;&gt; Link to Release Notes &lt;&lt;</a></strong></em></h5>
</blockquote>

<hr id="bkmrk-"><h5 id="bkmrk-yes-the-maxx-interac"><em><strong>Yes the MaXX Interactive Desktop is the little brother of the great SGI Desktop on IRIX!</strong></em></h5>

<p id="bkmrk--0"><strong><a href="https://cdn.maxxinteractive.com/uploads/images/gallery/2020-05/Screenshot-from-2020-05-30-09-53-45.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img src="https://cdn.maxxinteractive.com/uploads/images/gallery/2020-05/scaled-1680-/Screenshot-from-2020-05-30-09-53-45.png" alt="Screenshot-from-2020-05-30-09-53-45.png"></a><br>MaXX Desktop v2.1 in Modern look and feel</strong></p>
<h3 id="bkmrk-introduction">Introduction</h3>
<p id="bkmrk-the-maxx-interactive">The MaXX Interactive Desktop a.k.a.&nbsp; MaXX Desktop or MID is the continuation of the 5dwm.org project released many years back. &nbsp; By the way, the 5dwm.org website is not associated with us anymore and we do not endorse its content, although it's ours and was miss-appropriated from us a few years ago.&nbsp; Back to our regular program :)&nbsp; So don't be mistaken, there is only one other real implementation of the IRIX Interactive Desktop(IID) and&nbsp; it's MaXX Desktop!</p>
<p id="bkmrk-more-info-on-the-ori"><a title="Not just a theme..." href="https://maxxinteractive.com/books/misc/page/not-just-a-theme"><strong>&gt;&gt; More details on what MaXX Desktop is made of</strong></a></p>
<h3 id="bkmrk-our-mission"><br>Our Mission</h3>
<p id="bkmrk-our-goal-is-to-bring">Our mission is to bring back this great user experience which focused on performance, stability and productivity while sporting a smooth-clean-minimalism look and feel&nbsp; with low-resources consumption. A smart desktop that puts the user's application in the forefront.&nbsp; <em><strong>More for your creativity.</strong></em></p>
<p id="bkmrk-so-there-is-no-surpr">So there is no surprises here, MaXX Desktop is a highly tuned Workstation Environment which can leverage&nbsp; multi-core&nbsp; workload processing, robust asynchronous multi-threaded POSIX Messaging, hardware acceleration and GPU specific optimizations that&nbsp; makes the MaXX Desktop so fast, light-weight and dependable. Enough geekin' out for now, although, we are and proud to be.</p>
<p id="bkmrk-maxx-desktop-is-a-tr">MaXX Desktop is a true re-implementation of the SGI Desktop while respecting the classic/retro SGI look and feel (which is very important for us to get it right), but also to expand and build on top of those solid foundations with a more modern-current user experience.&nbsp; See it as the <em>classic</em> or<em>original&nbsp;</em> look and feel of the desktop and a new <em>modern</em> take.&nbsp; We want the modern look to be/feel like a natural evolution of the classic SGI look, as if SGI did it themselves throughout several years perfecting an already pretty awesome recipe. &nbsp; The modern look still supports SGI Color Schemes and introduce UTF-8 support, anti-aliased font rendering, more hardware acceleration and a new virtual-desktop manager.</p>
<p id="bkmrk-we-believe-in-a-high">We believe in a High Performance Desktop Environment that provides the right set of tools to maximize creativity and productivity without sacrificing&nbsp; your system resources to some eye candy non-sense.&nbsp;<em> <strong>Again, less is more... And it keeps you focused.<br></strong></em></p>
<h3 id="bkmrk-from-the-ground-up">From the Ground Up</h3>
<p id="bkmrk-maxx-desktop-is-desi">The MaXX&nbsp; Desktop is designed from the ground up for speed,&nbsp; fast/responsive, lightweight/simplicity over eye-candidness, but more importantly, to get the heck out of your way... The name <em>MaXX Interactive</em> doesn't mean maximum visual interaction, which are distractions or so what we call, UI noises. It's means maximum creativity with interactive assistance from the Desktop. In may ways, it's made for you and your brain so that it can relax, focus on let the creative juice flowing with far fever distractions. We see desktop notifications in a very different way, but this is for another discussion. In short, the MaXX Desktop let you focus on the creative&nbsp; tasks ahead without interference or visual distractions.<em><strong>&nbsp; Our design philosophy is simple, do more with less...</strong></em></p>
<h3 id="bkmrk-experience-matter">Experience Matters</h3>
<p id="bkmrk-finally%2C-our-team-me">Our team is sharing the same vision of making use of the right set of technologies, using industry proven best practices and guide lines to build the right software, the right way.&nbsp; We aim at providing a consistent and pleasant user experience built on top of modern and stable foundations but yet flexible.&nbsp; Every good and useful piece of tech deserves to be future-proof...&nbsp; This is where&nbsp; several decades of experience in building battle-proven mission critical systems and high performance Enterprise class applications comes in.&nbsp; If it's architect-ed properly,&nbsp; it can evolve without breaking apart!</p>
<h3 id="bkmrk-is-maxx-desktop-for-">Is MaXX Desktop for you?</h3>
<p id="bkmrk-maxx-desktop%27s-typic">MaXX Desktop's typical users are: 2D/3D Computer Graphics Artists, Motion Pictures and Special Effects Studios, Software/Game Developers, Visualization/Simulation, Virtual Reality power-users or Oil and Gas research to name a few.&nbsp; MaXX Desktop is also for anyone who wants get a break from all the surrounding noises and to create stuff while sporting a very unique/cool daily driver!&nbsp; <em><strong>Then, MaXX&nbsp; is for you too!&nbsp;</strong></em></p>
<hr id="bkmrk--1"><h3 id="bkmrk-navigation">Navigation</h3>
<p id="bkmrk-this-site-is-powered"><em>This site is powered by <a href="https://www.bookstackapp.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>BookStack</strong></a> (a type of Wiki engine) and you can navigate it by using the upper-right links 'Shelves and Books'.&nbsp; You may use the search bar on top or the convenient links below.</em></p>
<p id="bkmrk-the-maxx-desktop-tea">The MaXX Desktop team</p>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://maxxinteractive.com/books/misc/page/welcome-to-maxx-interactive-desktop</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23731714</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 12:01:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Targeted MitM attacks using information leakage in SSH clients [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 67 | Comments 82 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23731310">thread link</a>) | @based2
<br/>
July 4, 2020 | https://www.fzi.de/fileadmin/user_upload/2020-06-26-FSA-2020-2.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.fzi.de/fileadmin/user_upload/2020-06-26-FSA-2020-2.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.fzi.de/fileadmin/user_upload/2020-06-26-FSA-2020-2.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23731310</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 10:01:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Learn to Create and Flex Flexagons]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 62 | Comments 13 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23730865">thread link</a>) | @bhy
<br/>
July 4, 2020 | http://loki3.com/flex/explore/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://loki3.com/flex/explore/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          <div>
            
            <h2>Learn to create and flex flexagons</h2>
            
          </div>
          <hr>
          <div>
            <div><p><img src="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/static/pinch-flex.jpg"></p><canvas width="300" height="100"></canvas>
            </div>
          </div>
          <a href="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/pinch-flex.html"><p> Chapter 1: Flexagon Intro </p><p> Exploring the hidden sides of hexaflexagons </p></a>
          <ul>
            <li>Introduces the <em>hexaflexagon</em>, with
              <!-- -->6
              <!-- --> equilateral triangles per side, and the <em>pinch flex</em>, a way of folding a flexagon to
              reveal previously hidden sides</li>
            <li>Let’s you explore how to visit every side of a flexagon</li>
            <li>Describes <em>flex notation</em>, which can be used to precisely describe a sequence of flexes</li>
            <li>Introduces the <em>Tuckerman Traverse</em> <!-- -->as a technique for visiting every side of a flexagon
              using the pinch flex</li>
            <li>Provides both a flexagon simulation and the unfolded strip for all hexaflexagons with
              <!-- -->3
              <!-- -->,
              <!-- -->4
              <!-- -->,
              <!-- -->5
              <!-- -->,
              <!-- -->6
              <!-- -->,
              <!-- -->7
              <!-- -->, and
              <!-- -->8
              <!-- --> sides so you can make your own</li>
            <li>Shows flexagons made up of different shapes of triangles, like using angles of
              <!-- -->3
              <!-- -->0
              <!-- -->-
              <!-- -->6
              <!-- -->0
              <!-- -->-
              <!-- -->9
              <!-- -->0
              <!-- --> or
              <!-- -->5
              <!-- -->4
              <!-- -->-
              <!-- -->5
              <!-- -->4
              <!-- -->-
              <!-- -->7
              <!-- -->2
              <!-- -->, and different numbers of triangles per side, like
              <!-- -->4
              <!-- -->,
              <!-- -->8
              <!-- -->,
              <!-- -->1
              <!-- -->0
              <!-- -->, or
              <!-- -->1
              <!-- -->2</li>
          </ul>
          <hr>
          <div>
            <div>
              <div><p><img src="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/static/F/F1.jpg" width="320" height="240"></p>
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
          <a href="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/flexing.html"><p> Chapter 2: Flexing Flexagons </p><p> A short tour of different ways to flex a flexagon </p></a>
          <ul>
            <li>Describes a naming convention for a wide variety of triangle flexagons, like <em>pentaflexagon</em>
              <!-- -->and <em>silver octaflexagon</em></li>
            <li>Defines a <em>minimal flexagon</em> <!-- -->as the simplest flexagon that supports a given flex</li>
            <li>Demonstrates a sampling of interesting flexes on triangle flexagons: the pyramid shuffle, flip flex,
              tuck flex, v-flex, and silver tetra flex</li>
            <li>Shows that once you generalize the types of flexes you use, the concept of “sides” of a flexagon is no
              longer sufficient for understanding all the states you can explore</li>
          </ul>
          <hr>
          
          <a href="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/generators.html"><p> Chapter 3: Generating Sequences </p><p> Creating flexagons with flex sequences </p></a>
          <ul>
            <li>Summarizes the <em>flex notation</em> <!-- -->that was previously introduced for describing sequences of
              flexes</li>
            <li>Defines a <em>generating sequence</em> <!-- -->as a sequence of flexes used to create the structure
              necessary for performing them on a given flexagon</li>
            <li>Shows how different flexes move you around a pinch flex diagram</li>
            <li>Gives you an interactive tool for typing in generating sequences to see what pinch flex diagram is
              generated</li>
            <li>Allows you to type in generating sequences consisting of any of the flexes introduced so far on a wide
              variety of triangle flexagons, giving you the unfolded strip that can be used to construct a working
              flexagon</li>
          </ul>
          <hr>
          <div>
            <div>
              <div><p><img src="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/static/P4-4-4/1.jpg" width="320" height="240"></p>
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
          <a href="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/pinch-variations.html"><p> Chapter 4: Pinch Flex Variations </p><p> Relatives of the pinch flex on different flexagons </p></a>
          <ul>
            <li>Describes a class of flexes that are related to the standard pinch flex</li>
            <li>Shows the minimal flexagon for a variety of flexes (e.g. P
              <!-- -->3
              <!-- -->3
              <!-- -->4
              <!-- --> and P
              <!-- -->3
              <!-- -->3
              <!-- -->3
              <!-- -->3
              <!-- -->) on several flexagons (e.g. the enneaflexagon and decaflexagon)</li>
            <li>Demonstrates generating sequences using these flexes to create interesting flexagons</li>
          </ul>
          <hr>
          <div>
            <p><img src="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/static/slot-example.jpg"></p>
            </div>
            <a href="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/slot-flexes.html"><p> Chapter 5: Slot Flexes </p><p> Flexes that involve sliding leaves through slots </p></a>
            <ul>
              <li>Describes a class of flexes called <em>slot flexes</em></li>
              <li>Demonstrates the related flexes called the <em>slot half</em> <!-- -->and <em>slot pocket</em></li>
              <li>Shows four <em>slot tuck flex</em> <!-- -->variants</li>
              <li>Finishes with the <em>slot triple pocket flex</em> <!-- -->on a pentaflexagon</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>
            <div>
              <p><em>pre</em>:
                <code>[[[1,2],3], 4, 5, [6,7], 8, 9]</code><br><em>post</em>:
                <code>[2, 4, 5, [6,7], 8, [-1,[9,-3]]]</code></p>
            </div>
            <a href="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/new-flexes.html"><p> Chapter 6: New flexes </p><p> How to define flexes with pat notation </p></a>
            <ul>
              <li>Describes using <em>pat notation</em> <!-- -->for the internal structure of a flexagon</li>
              <li>Shows how to define what a flex does by using pat notation to enumerate a flexagon’s structure before
                and after a flex</li>
              <li>Demonstrates using a flex definition to predict where you can do a flex and to predict exactly how a
                flexagon will change if you do the flex</li>
              <li>Provides definitions of the flexes discussed so far for hexaflexagons</li>
              <li>Lists additional details you need to fully understand when a flex can be performed</li>
              <li>Walks through an example of how to define a new flex and how to add it to the flexagon simulator</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>
            <div>
              <div>
                <ul>
                  <li><code>I ~= (Sh&gt;&gt;T'&gt;^T&lt;&lt;^) 2</code></li>
                  <li><code>I ~= (Ltb&gt;P&gt;P&gt;) 12</code></li>
                  <li><code>P ~= T&gt;&gt;&gt;V&gt;&gt;&gt;</code> so
                    <code>T' ~= &gt;&gt;&gt;V&gt;&gt;&gt;^P^</code></li>
                </ul>
              </div>
            </div>
            <a href="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/flex-sequences.html"><p> Chapter 7: Flex Sequences </p><p> Cycles, traversals, primes, and equalities </p></a>
            <ul>
              <li>Tools for finding cycles, flex sequences that end where they begin</li>
              <li>Examples of traversals, cycles that visit every state of a flexagon</li>
              <li><em>Prime flexes</em> <!-- -->that can’t be replaced by other flexes</li>
              <li>Sequences of flexes that are equal or almost equal to each other</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>
            <a href="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/playground.html"><p> Appendix: Flexagon Playground </p><p> General tools for exploring flexagons </p></a>
            <ul>
              <li>Tools for creating new flexagons from generating sequences or scripts and exploring them using a
                variety of flexes</li>
              <li>Get the unfolded strip for any of your creations so you can try out the physical version</li>
              <li>An explorer that can find all the states accessible with a specified set of flexes from any flexagon
              </li>
            </ul>
            <hr>
            <a href="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/flex-compendium.html"><p> Appendix: Flex Compendium </p><p> Details about flexes on triangle flexagons </p></a>
            <ul>
              <li>Reference guide to a wide variety of flexes on triangle flexagons</li>
              <li>Shows sample slides and sample strips to fold on various triangle flexagons</li>
              <li>Shows flex definitions in pat notation, etc.</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>
            <a href="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/references.html"><p> Flexagon References </p><p> Sources for additional flexagon information </p></a>
            <ul>
              <li>Bibliography for papers and publications</li>
              <li>Additional references</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>
            <p>For additional information, see <a href="http://loki3.com/flex/">loki3.com</a>.</p>
          </div><div>
              <p>Copyright © 2018-2019 Scott Sherman</p>
            </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://loki3.com/flex/explore/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23730865</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 07:57:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Investigation into EU institutions’ use of Microsoft products and services]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 8 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23730721">thread link</a>) | @pkz
<br/>
July 4, 2020 | https://edps.europa.eu/sites/edp/files/publication/20-07-02_edps_euis_microsoft_contract_investigation_en.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://edps.europa.eu/sites/edp/files/publication/20-07-02_edps_euis_microsoft_contract_investigation_en.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
<header>
<h2>EDPS Public Paper on</h2>

<p>2 July 2020</p>
<div>
<p>The European Data Protection Supervisor (EDPS) is the independent supervisory authority established by Article 52 of <a href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/PDF/?uri=CELEX:32018R1725&amp;from=EN">Regulation (EU) 2018/1725</a> responsible for:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>Monitoring and ensuring the application of the provisions of Regulation (EU) 2018/1725 and any other EU act relating to the protection of the fundamental rights and freedoms of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data by a EU institution or body;</p></li>
<li><p>Advising EU institutions and bodies and data subjects on all matters concerning the processing of personal data.</p></li>
</ul>
<p>To this end, the EDPS fulfils its duties in accordance with Article 57 of Regulation (EU) 2018/1725 and exercises the powers granted in Article 58 of Regulation (EU) 2018/1725.</p>
<p>The power to investigate is one of the tools established to monitor and ensure compliance with Regulation (EU) 2018/1725.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>This paper presents the issues raised by the EDPS’ own-initiative investigation into European institutions’, bodies’, offices’ and agencies’ (‘EU institutions’) use of Microsoft products and services. These findings and recommendations from the investigation are likely to be of wider interest than just of the EU institutions: they may be of particular interest to all public authorities in EU/EEA Member States.</p>
<p>The EDPS assessed the compliance of the licensing agreement between Microsoft and the EU institutions against the requirements laid down in Regulation (EU) 2018/1725<span data-cites="regulation20181725"><a href="#fn1" id="fnref1" role="doc-noteref"><sup>1</sup></a></span> which sets out the rules for data protection in the EU institutions, bodies, offices and agencies as well as the duties and powers of the European Data Protection Supervisor (EDPS).</p>
<p>In the interest of a coherent approach to personal data protection throughout the Union, and the free movement of personal data within the Union, the legislators aligned Regulation (EU) 2018/1725 as far as possible with the data protection rules of Regulation (EU) 2016/679<span data-cites="gdpr"><a href="#fn2" id="fnref2" role="doc-noteref"><sup>2</sup></a></span> (‘General Data Protection Regulation’ - GDPR). Whenever the provisions of Regulation (EU 2018/1725 follow the same principles as the provisions of the GDPR, these two sets of provisions should, under the case law of the Court of Justice of the European Union be interpreted homogeneously, in particular because the scheme of this Regulation should be understood as equivalent to the scheme of the GDPR.</p>
<p>The EDPS made the following key findings in its investigation into the EU institutions’ use of Microsoft products and services.</p>
<p>First, the licensing agreement between Microsoft and the EU institutions allowed Microsoft to define and change the parameters of its processing activities carried out on behalf of EU institutions and contractual data protection obligations. The discretion that Microsoft had, amounted to a broad right for Microsoft to act as a controller. Given the EU institutions’ role as public service institutions, the EDPS did not consider this appropriate. The EDPS recommended to EU institutions that they act to retain controllership.</p>
<p>Second, EU institutions needed to put in place a comprehensive and compliant controller-processor agreement and documented instructions of the EU institutions to the processors. Their lack of control over which sub-processors Microsoft used and lack of meaningful audit rights also presented significant issues. The EDPS made recommendations on how to improve the controller-processor agreement and put robust audit checks in place.</p>
<p>Third, EU institutions faced a number of linked issues concerning data location, international transfers and the risk of unlawful disclosure of data. They were unable to control the location of a large portion of the data processed by Microsoft. Nor did they properly control what was transferred out of the EU/EEA and how. There was also a lack of proper safeguards to protect data that left the EU/EEA. EU institutions also had few guarantees at their disposal to defend their privileges and immunities and ensure that Microsoft would only disclose personal data insofar as permitted by EU law. The EDPS made recommendations to assist EU institutions in addressing these issues.</p>
<p>Fourth, the EDPS considered the technical measures that the Commission had put in place to stem the flow of personal data generated by Microsoft products and services and sent to Microsoft. The EDPS recommended that all EU institutions perform tests using a revised and comprehensive approach, share among them the knowledge and technical solutions they developed to prevent unauthorised data flows to Microsoft and inform each other of any data protection issues they identify with the products or services.</p>
<p>Fifth, the EU institutions had insufficient clarity as to the nature, scope and purposes of the processing and the risks to data subjects to be able to meet their transparency obligations towards data subjects. The EDPS recommended that EU institutions seek the clarity and assurances allowing them to keep data subjects properly informed.</p>
</div>
</header>
<nav id="TOC">

<ul>
<li><a href="#introduction"><span>1</span> Introduction</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#context"><span>1.1</span> Context</a></li>
<li><a href="#general-recommendations"><span>1.2</span> General recommendations</a></li>
<li><a href="#the-inter-institutional-licence-agreement-ila"><span>1.3</span> The Inter-Institutional Licence Agreement (ILA)</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="#microsoft-as-controller"><span>2</span> Microsoft as controller</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#right-of-unilateral-amendment"><span>2.1</span> Right of unilateral amendment</a></li>
<li><a href="#limited-data-protection-obligations"><span>2.2</span> Limited data protection obligations</a></li>
<li><a href="#insufficient-purpose-limitation"><span>2.3</span> Insufficient purpose limitation</a></li>
<li><a href="#consequences"><span>2.4</span> Consequences</a></li>
<li><a href="#recommendations"><span>2.5</span> Recommendations</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="#the-controller-processor-agreement"><span>3</span> The controller-processor agreement</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#comprehensiveness-of-the-agreement"><span>3.1</span> Comprehensiveness of the agreement</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#assessment"><span>3.1.1</span> Assessment</a></li>
<li><a href="#recommendations-1"><span>3.1.2</span> Recommendations</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="#sub-processors"><span>3.2</span> Sub-processors</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#assessment-1"><span>3.2.1</span> Assessment</a></li>
<li><a href="#recommendations-2"><span>3.2.2</span> Recommendations</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="#audit-rights"><span>3.3</span> Audit rights</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#assessment-2"><span>3.3.1</span> Assessment</a></li>
<li><a href="#recommendations-3"><span>3.3.2</span> Recommendations</a></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="#data-location-transfers-and-disclosure"><span>4</span> Data location, transfers and disclosure</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#data-location"><span>4.1</span> Data location</a></li>
<li><a href="#international-transfers"><span>4.2</span> International transfers</a></li>
<li><a href="#unauthorised-disclosure"><span>4.3</span> Unauthorised disclosure</a></li>
<li><a href="#consequences-1"><span>4.4</span> Consequences</a></li>
<li><a href="#recommendations-4"><span>4.5</span> Recommendations</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="#technical-measures"><span>5</span> Technical measures</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#context-1"><span>5.1</span> Context</a></li>
<li><a href="#recommendations-5"><span>5.2</span> Recommendations</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="#transparency"><span>6</span> Transparency</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#recommendations-6"><span>6.1</span> Recommendations</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="#conclusion"><span>7</span> Conclusion</a></li>
</ul>
</nav>

<h2 data-number="1.1" id="context"> Context</h2>
<p>This paper presents the issues raised by the EDPS’ own-initiative investigation into European institutions’, bodies’, offices’ and agencies’ (‘EU institutions’) use of Microsoft products and services. It presents the EDPS’ findings and recommendations from the investigation to be shared with a wider audience, applying a high standard of transparency<a href="#fn3" id="fnref3" role="doc-noteref"><sup>3</sup></a>, while preserving the necessary confidentiality of certain elements of the EU institutions’ contract and of the EDPS’ investigation.</p>
<p>A large amount of personal data is processed through the EU institutions’ use of Microsoft products and services. Over 45&nbsp;000 staff of EU institutions, including the EDPS, are users of those products and services. In addition, staff use Microsoft products and services to process the personal data of people who are not staff.</p>
<p>The EDPS’ investigation focused on the terms of the <em>Inter-Institutional Licensing Agreement</em> (‘ILA’) that EU institutions signed with Microsoft in 2018. The EDPS also considered the technical measures that the European Commission, as the largest EU institution with a great variety of tasks, had implemented affecting the flow of personal data to Microsoft.</p>
<p>The EDPS issued its findings and recommendations to the EU institutions upon the closure of its investigation in March 2020. The purpose of the EDPS’ report was to provide EU institutions with forward-looking assistance in bringing their arrangements into compliance with data protection law. In particular, the EDPS’ findings and recommendations were oriented towards supporting the renegotiation of the ILA and EU institutions’ contract and implementation of robust technical and organisational measures that should accompany the contract.</p>
<p>EU institutions’ processing of personal data and the EDPS’ own supervisory and investigative powers are governed by Regulation (EU) 2018/1725.<span data-cites="regulation20181725"><a href="#fn4" id="fnref4" role="doc-noteref"><sup>4</sup></a></span> The EDPS assessed the compliance of the ILA against the requirements laid down in that regulation. Although Regulation (EU) 2018/1725 is a data protection regime that is tailored to the EU institutions and distinct from the better-known General Data Protection Regulation<span data-cites="gdpr"><a href="#fn5" id="fnref5" role="doc-noteref"><sup>5</sup></a></span> (‘GDPR’), the overlap between the provisions of Regulation (EU) 2018/1725 and those of the GDPR is extensive.</p>
<p>As a consequence, the EDPS’ findings and recommendations are likely to be of wider interest than to EU institutions.<a href="#fn6" id="fnref6" role="doc-noteref"><sup>6</sup></a> Not only is the law the EDPS applied in its investigation based on the same principles and shares the vast majority of provisions with the GDPR, but the agreement signed by EU institutions is based on standard Microsoft volume-licensing documents and therefore likely to bear similarities to agreements concluded by other organisations. The EDPS’ findings and recommendations may be of particular interest to public authorities in EU member states.</p>
<p>They are also likely to be of relevance beyond the conclusion and implementation of volume licensing agreements for Microsoft products and services. In the EDPS’ view, organisations outsourcing provision or operation of digital services from other service providers are likely to come across similar issues.</p>
<h2 data-number="1.2" id="general-recommendations"> General recommendations</h2>
<p>The EDPS recommended that EU institutions carefully consider any purchases of Microsoft products and services or new uses of existing products and services until after they have analysed and implemented the recommendations of the EDPS. They should involve their Data Protection Officers when deciding how to implement the recommendations of the EDPS. The EU institutions should properly embed data protection in each specific public information and communications technology procurement procedure, specifying the security and data protection measures to be implemented in respect of the particular products and services that are being procured.</p>
<p>This will help EU institutions, from the start, to procure products and services with appropriate contractual and other organisational measures, technical and security measures so that the processing of personal data through those tools complies with Regulation (EU) 2018/1725, in particular with the principle of data protection by design and by default.<span data-cites="regulation20181725"><a href="#fn7" id="fnref7" role="doc-noteref"><sup>7</sup></a></span></p>
<h2 data-number="1.3" id="the-inter-institutional-licence-agreement-ila"> The Inter-Institutional Licence Agreement (ILA)</h2>
<p>The ILA that the EDPS examined had a complex structure with a multiplicity of interlocking documents …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://edps.europa.eu/sites/edp/files/publication/20-07-02_edps_euis_microsoft_contract_investigation_en.html">https://edps.europa.eu/sites/edp/files/publication/20-07-02_edps_euis_microsoft_contract_investigation_en.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://edps.europa.eu/sites/edp/files/publication/20-07-02_edps_euis_microsoft_contract_investigation_en.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23730721</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 07:17:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A look at the Gemini protocol: a brutally simple alternative to the web]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 376 | Comments 304 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23730408">thread link</a>) | @flatlanderwoman
<br/>
July 3, 2020 | https://toffelblog.xyz/blog/gemini-overview/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://toffelblog.xyz/blog/gemini-overview/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<article>

<p>Published on <b>2020-06-18</b></p>
<p>I have really come to hate the World Wide Web. It is bloated at every level! Websites themselves are doubling in size at an alarming rate. The web standards are expanding at an alarming rate. Trying to build a web browser that works with the modern web from scratch, would take the manpower equivalent to the Snowy Mountains Scheme or the Manhattan Project (no hyperbole).</p>
<p>The state of the web has lead me to only one conclusion: It is broken beyond repair.</p>
<p>I don't think the web can replaced, but we can still look for simpler (open standards) alternatives to move our works to. Gemini is one of these alternatives that I have taken interest in recently. A fairly recent protocol, created in 2019, Gemini defines a markdown-inspired document format, and it's own protocol to serve these documents, or other files.</p>
<p>If you a looking for a 1:1 clone for the early web, you will probably be disappointed. Gemini takes way more design hints from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gopher_(protocol)">Gopher</a> then it ever will from the web. Gopher (widely considered a predecessor to the web) is built on the idea of text only documents. Gemini expands on this idea by offering basic formatting, and fixing drawbacks unaccounted for in the original Gopher protocol.</p>
<p>Gemini shys away from many standard features of the web. Although there may be plenty of benefits that one accustomed to web wouldn't be able to identify. For example the lack of styling sheets may mean that Gemini sites look plain, however this allows your readers to decide on a colour scheme which suits them best. A night reader would prefer a dark theme, someone with a vision impairment will prefer high contrast, the list goes on.</p>
<p>Gemini offers no in-line image support no client-side scripting (such as Javascript). But server-side scripting (CGI) can work, so you could expect Gemini to be a valid interface for some online services.</p>
<p>The Gemini transport protocol is unsuitable for the transfer of large files, since it misses many features that protocols such as FTP or HTTP use to recover from network instability.</p>
<p>The internet protocols of old aren't encrypted by default, since security wasn't seen as being important back in the late-80's/early-90's. Thankfully Gemini, being a recent protocol, mandates the use of TLS. There is no unencrypted version of Gemini available.</p>
<p>I could totally see Gemini being used as an alternative particularly for the non-commercial individuals who use text as a primary medium. Blogs, poems, recipes, tutorials are perfect for the Gemini format. There are always ways around the lack of media functionality, since although Gemini lacks in-line images, you can still use in-line links to images. As time goes on I could imagine some Gemini browsers providing a fancy image viewer for links to images.</p>
<p>Now, what does Gemini currently have to offer? The best way to find out is to head over to the official site: <code>gemini.circumlunar.space</code> in your Gemini browser. Here you can find two search engines dedicated to finding pages based on what you search for. And two aggregators which acts as a news feed of Gemini posts.</p>
<p>Personally I enjoy scrolling through the aggregators and seeing what people are blogging about, I find interesting stuff frequently.</p>
<p>From a server management perspective, Gemini is just a diet-Web. You buy a domain name (using the web), obtain or rent a server, install a Gemini server, and start serving your site. In order to post to Gemini you either need to self-host, or take advantage of Gemini hosting which is currently on offer by circumlunar.space. No fancy P2P or Blockchain solution here, just a good old client/server model.</p>
<p>I will no doubt keep an eye on Gemini, and serving my blog posts to Gemini should be easy since they are already in markdown. No promises yet though.</p>
<p>I will leave you with the following quote and some interesting links I found.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"When I picture it in my head I think of the early web as more of a library. Over time it has transitioned into a shopping mall." - chris_f (Hacker News comments)</p>
</blockquote>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://gemini.circumlunar.space/">(www) Project Gemini</a> - The official website for the Gemini project. FAQ is recommended reading. (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23042424">hn thread</a>)</li>
<li><a href="gemini://gemini.circumlunar.space/">(gmi) Project Gemini</a> - The defacto Gemini main page.</li>
<li><a href="gemini://gemini.circumlunar.space/software/">(gmi) Gemini software</a> - The official page on Gemini lists out some clients and servers.</li>
<li><a href="gemini://gempaper.strangled.net/mirrorlist/">(gmi) List of services with a gemini mirror</a> - Includes Wikipedia, YouTube and Lobste.rs.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://portal.mozz.us/gemini/gemini.circumlunar.space/">portal.mozz.us</a> - A Gemini gateway for Web users.</li>
<li><a href="https://sr.ht/~julienxx/Castor/">Castor</a> - A browser for Gemini, Gopher and Finger. Written in Rust and GTK. Still early days, but probably the most normie friendly. (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23161922">hn thread</a>)</li>
<li><a href="https://framagit.org/waweic/gemini-client">Android</a> - Barebones Android client.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.marmaladefoo.com/pages/geminaut">GemiNaut</a> - GUI client for Windows users.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/makeworld-the-better-one/md2gemini">md2gemini</a> - Python library that converts markdown to gemini.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23730408">Comments on Hacker News</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/coding/comments/hl6qfv/a_look_at_the_gemini_protocol_a_brutally_simple/">Comments on reddit r/coding</a></p>

</article>

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://toffelblog.xyz/blog/gemini-overview/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23730408</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 05:44:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Closos: Specification of a Lisp operating system (2013) [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 82 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23730107">thread link</a>) | @ska80
<br/>
July 3, 2020 | http://metamodular.com/closos.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://metamodular.com/closos.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>û¨&lt;“
endstream
endobj
20 0 obj
&lt;&lt;
/Length 662       
/Filter /FlateDecode
&gt;&gt;
stream
xÚåVMSÛ0½çWø(l´ú´Ž|=@§¸'Úƒ“ˆÄƒ±SÛaÊ¿ïÊ²ÓJÓ2Ó“eKZï{zoW,ZD,:�d“½Ð°Ä2Qv–¤ZGdb…ˆ²ytEŠ;ú5û°wÂíöJÁÒDp��úE‡çÙñyvé—NØðƒ½Û{âq£Ò°UÑØrFNófš/�E
dV—¥›uE]Ñ˜ƒ5)á&amp;d±›/è„ˆb‰’vˆ—���&amp;gå†tM�A™¯‡€B’ÐX1öÞÛdGWÈ‚Ð„S fw†=$ˆ}ôü¸&amp;î–�ËçÈŒ²Øœƒàã9Ô
�¥¶o¶"&lt;ý%f5BäÓ²žæe@·¶¡j-ßËy?þÈs£E¸L„Õ�,w¸t3ŠÐoVH�º¨(²ÒÕ
#Yj‰€çºNo\—ÑTŒÒZVÅ·õÀo�Ó¤jWEã¥Mý’û0&gt;þä_..114û¿gþšç@Å“¦ÒS=�êñçhÎÖFúz„¤—õ"n»KÔzÃÏ&amp;d9±½o;w‹[¹…×Ñ‘P/Ð‘	&nbsp;MÐÑ‘»+fCåž7Ø/0a×ød%€"òÙ"2ÿwé–¨Žß«ÌüTYÑ+ì†ò”¸®
*yÿÔÀK$+ÿDÖXô�Šö&amp;0ÔËÓSæå©Ì›�÷
†–ü¡¡U�X¥øŽ¡…ÁoCc8CÂ€+²¿
-ÁUst¶w2×À‰TÁÉ»¥�í6—}l&nbsp;Ü’Ïíx—ËÛ&gt;‚VÊùìkÜ¾¯F§äSñ'Võ}ÉÆ|8ËºŸ˜­o]åÏ´Ÿ¯}÷Ëü�¦ßc5#ÍZš—ÙƒbZõ¢ÉWK_Xï=•Iëc=dÿ¬š»ï¾MX©‰b;¿ŸÇÙäi€{
endstream
endobj
25 0 obj
&lt;&lt;
/Length 1006      
/Filter /FlateDecode
&gt;&gt;
stream
xÚ�VI¯ä4¾¿_‘£#ÑÁKœEœ1h0HÓ$†ƒ_âî¥ãVìL3ÿž*—“×óÔ#qr-®ª¯WÂ³sÆ³Ÿx:¿;&gt;}ýFÕ™äEUI�OYÛR¨Ls^´ZdÇ&gt;û‹}?˜k°K~Pºd"ÿûøXñL–EÝÔ­xvÐM¡DMoç\¶,,.?ÀÙ¯]ÝœìÚL”…*+™ìªª�M²…ÈBpÎþL€xUÅ5ûyôW¢žœÙÅ„q&gt;“ÌòÁ^È`ôIT™€$x»!TeÁyK‘¾Íe#’W¤ÞÁ)ë¯({Ÿ¼"ý�kŽ·ß½'þä$8ó@f.l	pI�@Äsv�ˆVŸ(²Á.Ä¸ÏÃpD*T¡Ë„tK­T’…X¤&nbsp;#hÙ0;û¤st&gt;“˜˜Û2†`gbÆt¦¤�Â¤ÌöV$ÎÃë`·&lt;ºuêD0tœ]º˜Mÿ(�0ÄºÊ²�@â¼�Nù¡ŽHD®„foòF1¬.^�Jq]JØù$q§í
©ž@tëR"|&lt;�ª·öÅÐÉÄLÞ%*�r©®ÿ£#ºÚŠ¤k¶zë7™%"”#á§ð&gt;æØqºB@?Ž‹›#èšR˜äa‘“›IA÷åòd:K/ckœ€ )¶Õât&nbsp;2¢V•ÆD–ôôæžDIW¥Ô¡¬ª._ÔÉo@·˜9Õ¦t»ˆÚ?ðùÅâ›JÊ‚ërß*ÕÊÔpÕŠ‡
/ù–Ý&gt;c½wÎ»K¢ÆÞšäÆ%Ç7Z: 1$Ø&amp;éËcÛ9ŠhÆ9åÿ¨h¤%‡²ûCB¦?p¥ì²O
O‹»eÿ}ÚwÀ½Ò(£ÊylŽnR�AŒ°°"tgíä€œŠYî†�pßç|ÿð•¬[¬	¶/¾°ÖË¦¨J½­u™Öúo‹{ž$ÍÂmÄÕƒûû.»}›§5®t&amp;|‹´|YãPîÝ3}2¤fÇ8¤µÆÖtöˆÁ-‡•¼•üÞ›(³hÁkôv]rxO.‡òuHYÿðSrØÌà3TÈí#ù‹‹^5ŒV:¶6êdð™ª=Å¸aIòº‰h»¥³X"z»¤)îI@s�Ôï¿¾ý“¨Û0nÍ�,ÒÆ?jëþUPœ–±&lt;½qˆ¶æw±Új
ÂÎ]®+,Ol\&gt;huYBƒ7¶ðQ¼í¢¹ÇP2˜žî:h'.Ÿîá¦éñ3M8s0°}¿`S"ã¯°Ø¾!:ìŸœÓ;
Ä%¶µñ#ç
lÁg¤&amp;KbwX=JpA&amp;«ûý…%)+vŒŸ§ÁMi¹ìý¯*�,dÙÀöªU¥IýìÊÇ§ÿ-¢|
endstream
endobj
31 0 obj
&lt;&lt;
/Length 2378      
/Filter /FlateDecode
&gt;&gt;
stream
xÚ�É’Û¸õî¯Ð‘ªiÑ$¸çæ8žÄ©ÏÔ”\•ªLh’XÃEC�îî|}ÞŠTÓv’Þ{Á·/vç]°ûë›?ß¼ý1LwaàAîŽ§]øyšîÒ0ö‹(Ú«Ý?=µÿ×ñïoTÅò&nbsp;
R_…p
yÿ·w¿?üº?D‘òBÈ²Èûøéøë^eÞÏùüþøñçOxÍ›@þ}ÿãƒ\xˆ?Kr¾v¼Ôvˆ“À»ýccÚÀ²è†Éå`ôØr¨?ñúùÓÇÞ´?„ž5c·Ïú®4×qý•f1£x%f^øq‘;9¯Ã&gt;	½~�w d¬å¯ÖÂDÊÏ²Â}„ê(2ï3Ñèálð#U)_eÙîF~|Z_¯M]ê±î;Pg{O{•{Ú
2ÔãhdÇö¼Ž=2TË
ÚÚŽ(8¢("}`¾àefÐ�ZÝ4f`t|tkAÉQ¦&lt;£K&lt;|!^ƒ5“t¡J¼§K-‡tÇ@íÖÑ2Ðã©'¡êªPs„Ø«.��º	¼ãÅX#ä™3uãL~ŠNÕOMÅ›eß¶H™KNf´CU¢ÕƒÈ{ÄS/_4"_ö¡W£‹tg&amp;÷�œ]Y!Xñ²7šçQ&nbsp;ž7ILú~¯ÓÈD;‚sÂZFOý Ww=8â°¥Öµí‹„~€+ÜT�ŽRˆ®#Å[3^`ä¨˜@V�•5’{S·ºŒô¦åãYkPö†¼¤ˆ· 
ó¥/_ë+ùý–×«rFêNêN¸Òâì1E˜¬¶æ�É@,¢%Cñª�mÏàB#–)·p¤D'©äèfü‰ŸÇ¯ØoênS„(ñ‹T-7Žrï�u?&nbsp;e$7ºWÂ£yÖíµq2€ZO† ±Å¡Ÿ‡áZpŽMq’*	Ðµ¸†iÁ¡\qŒ†œÂ@IË$
‘ÈÃhoèi¯šÊ=›n–ï™yòˆµ‘©ú»R9µ�^·ô· 	(F¢DÜ
Væ	€–åèÎl@aæ’uÊHRÉÕ´1�ÊØúÜ™
~ˆå$	gÇ‡Íù»Ì?»èj#òQà,w©‘B˜*Õ
Ö
`£†ÚbùJ(^Eþ‡KÿóÀÂÙAÆÇfË‹ÂÔ/n‡P´e|›§³é 1ß¸'È“ìEa—ªøµ9¾Î,8s^,\¿ü¯y�£y�Ã¯ˆp×¼"aìŒ�è·ùR�(Ô-&amp;ÍÝÿÆ&amp;ünXË~¬”TU(¿ÈÔZMì&nbsp;�;Gt±	ð~Qv.LÇ �›æÄßñ‡¬ð3°Šó‡¡?�6Scî‡yºÆ~ƒÄ„UùA"ýÖ‘ÙÅÐo¡šlo"ÈCRæaC‚&nbsp;[Ð´åD&nbsp;Pý€O‡©cB/kUW¼Åˆ)Xs¨ˆ˜xKwR0iMÛ/‡­¤ÐêNŸ
¥
ø;Ú$ÀÒ#*ð§Ÿ&gt;K #…äC@?ZNþˆ°5ù‘À7·FK~"””ò:ú¹Õû•R!g”úIò8‚{îÐ)xK˜Æ©y$gƒC˜lpëz!²Ô6”p
«nÌ|\É°]Å!´^.xº˜¯•î&nbsp;ÃÍbT¹Í`Üøî¬ o�JZ`Çq‘±[ ™|Ä4
¨?Ï!�îó“=±}3ËM}umçÿK¿�„®„ß›ÝHëj‹ùA%Þ2PÖu8Ïý$�Çû5³*ñ*TfÿÆë'èä±™ïƒæ"€ñ"I©xýÉÜ/ãöË¸r !T�’]£ÔÏâ»Në
dâÀÝÂ­“í¡ÍÁý¿µ·°m¯xX£§Ùy‡{c Tµå”Ô[Ý<puàî)•Î0à†ß]tâgØ"�ûá÷‡mŸrÕš›(ðÌéqv\@+uk6*ñÊÛ�àÊî�àxÿÙùÀ½¨d‡èj ]="" ¯?×snÁŸ¹ž¡nšÉr‹Ê-Åëxæ^¶ëªm="" ª�s·àaxtd¢ÄöÉç="" ,éÊ9o˜áË="" Ýx="">Ã©€r†[÷*BÊÍ—‚dN¯Ã0]a´ÚTwÛß²(XP�¡Nä-=OŠL‰*$H¢a44·:¾J;òM§è#Š=wÜA$ø»ÆV‚lp9‹¥@1M¯©^ ,"öŒ	£7ËÊ,i‰ÃÌûe6‡\7GœÜGß7”bŸ�&nbsp;�üZwç	2ü&amp;“vZö‰ÎßJñ�ø?e/1	°ëF|ò60/.©OŒƒþ^f—Gß¼]ÁeFœ&gt;å0„s�Ü;0bžM9ñ��¾Û}GŠgê¡yaŠ;üŽ²Õxß}½l&gt;[îP
®ùË
@›‡Ë8�‹ùm$vã/…uº�Å%µØüD‘¹±ù '‚Â�$?á)“Úƒ�®{5Á‚˜nNB~{ÈÜÛÉÚê
B3ñDÓèº{$Š¢»ž0J¡Æl]d®™
³o¾,1è
Š«~øîk51†¹gF*=j†`šŸ¤œ[Ü…mC™¬aÆ~Lö‚Qw»PŸ®ëf°ï}-ÙY4Bœ‘Í8gÆÈY'ÉŸpØï€LF�SJãqÊÏ-Ãd*Xùåc$žf”aNÄ,F"ÄØú¹X¤B¶ñ•¬«¶Üœº½&lt;]°�Ø-ˆ@/×¼ü›Þâr	`®z°Ž(»wGx…á¢–næÖèl„fã¸ßb�l±É¹´?Y™]Š{Qázì1‚ÔûD
"î»æ…ÏR{DÆsÐÔ¡pÙ[Y™C9ÄTZÖ·CÔM¦Ì@O[ø~tâ•;¶&nbsp;àu0ã@6G#…÷ˆoL¸Aï}Xêä{(r=CÒÀ�IK&amp;œ†¾•C¼ØþD¯\³ÙÛ›î¢˜�YQÊ“œP;C m~óPÞ—Ú&lt;=ð»œøn©'~ÓSâk˜g�¹sï'0U¶Z®Z¸?`·l‹¯B’ëJÌV±Ùœù©*@Ö¡ÊE9¸šKDšQkÀ`õHœo™@–ˆ¯&nbsp;.iß%Eÿ›	ë Éª�vú¿2Ö»NXF’¼¬u³Õb§èa˜{z©®xÐx5Žþ&lt;³Þ•…\ÊBäÞš(Sß×š¤î3„è·v«S•Å^‰k@ïn–¡í�~‘¨•·/N ÿÑë2&lt;³&amp;ÙÜù2¦å\S?z¨�&nbsp;Ò($ýÝõÝŸ°×ÀA;Ë­Žoþù2¥&gt;
endstream
endobj
36 0 obj
&lt;&lt;
/Length 2370      
/Filter /FlateDecode
&gt;&gt;
stream
xÚuXYsã6~÷¯Ð#U5æx=n²“Œ·’Lv­ªl*ÉDBË&lt;öxýöJ²9/Ðh�&gt;¿f´9n¢Í�wßíî&gt;þ…ET¨Íî°)Š0Vz“*ZovÕæ�@…q¸½Ï2üº½WÁ¶q|ùî§O??nïµŽƒß¶*Ø}æÉ§ÿ&gt;&lt;î~ù‘g�¿?î�ï¯Ý¿&gt;þ&nbsp;Òë›tjBSd ]¢‘ç.É6°;ã8�AfIÎL¶Ã»_·÷F%A?TnÁÒîé[7Õ­qÉFIdGf«;þŸNŽî«mÏ�cÎþpY%!�º2ÖE˜Å^Æiè‡Õ·Äa¦”g+QÈ“­;C½½¼«ð€Í}œÅ¡Ñjs¯t˜˜‚wnœ›	8Í’Á¿å¿²oÏód§ºï˜P¹óNÁG¦Ô²2Îû‰Þã—-°XÒšpùý,P�8Œƒ=œ˜nB~Úé\GâF·rÒ^­2’Š¤è;à„ÿiÄ…”¤G†§W
XÌè,x S‚FéÊj.ëîÈœ–OèÜËÍyÐƒ›uè�Ž÷òrkÅ'pÓàþžëÁ]Ëœ°È=H2°S®­U0õÌ°gÅò¤íiVÕxóŸ‘6 …«pzK†`LpÔ4L_ökÍ³?‚
›±çÑ‰¤}ÞòùHÁu…«zÞ&amp;‰8ùd�~÷têçã	=='½ñl‡©.çÆP¡5ý*K&nbsp;T8ÿ¹®üÁì³ÚÜøl…q¾øöøÚÝó{üÂ�ÅËÓ°Mh¬þûàJ¤q¨ã%&nbsp;['&amp;ïê±UÆ©×ë„Ò½à"º¬$(òq°íø§hÓ'vXª'þg�
¯<sv” ù0¨[1(¿dºvƒóÅáÜð±ì»qnÙ="" øoú†="" ã4Ìå4ct†Þ£â8ŒÉ‹(™�¸ùßv2çcì›ø@ì÷£À¾i="" 1¬="" ÚÌnËúoûq(“û*#vËÝ?Ée½lèÅÓ{¹k|'‡Êüvè�="" ¥+Ý“="" 89%ÍÉ¦^k¥g^¨g¿âfÑ1’¬°œŽÄšbô(‹r™„ì`&€ŽspÖÒor¿&;¿Ø#0 ëc‡¾Žõ±íhxa‡Á="" É8e?Áÿ%¸qâŸ“Ës€ä�akš(æîÐÓl�²“cbçp55yòëš¨ÕìÄÄ½˜ó$„¦nkº="" '¶ªÒ1™ílka¢ô="" $÷µf…"…ë€ffô~³¯Š,1Çf¹8¨¹8(¦¡÷©ñ�4*a%e¤jv²tc_2o³€*b­Ì%@öâˆÃ“ã�”Éƒ~?a5="" ŸÅ©¤aaè‹ýam="" •3�—f‡‰©œ‡zz]Ç¡ÎrÏmá“Ÿ)±+="" r@e�¤^¨°�cÞÕžÏm]jüÆy†¾Å‘ybžÕ="" ¶i^™="" Œ,¶,!#3ßeu)="" ‡w’idlÜbeÆbÁ™¬œuàÖ²p][ñÀ+aÁ’ÂpéÐy="" eÒ6Þus�*Ñ]:8f°~0:Éº¶h ¬miëÈòÔüÆœ´s.‘ëäÏ!û¼½Ò="" zæŠ…šÎõuˆàagÒh‰5xäõªcsñxðóbrgnpú@ñ4ŠÆ·Œ–i7®j�­§="" m’|…n·Ý·c¿ßwòÕòk¿�-[="" h£="" Ý„¹Ê="" °�…Š¨Åi šx“…ú!i¶Ôaá‘³z�<t—›$daƒ\”&ìkyy…Š”k�vœvqy°dÇ}#Á¤rh±¾i:¤Ò4¾˜—&="" ×¿8ua1="" àúžt39á¢="" €ÿÊn3�*‚z•œxtrfp$€¼öv'û"·_kí±«§¹rk¶å¼l®Ý³8ÿ‘µç¤È="" 6Ó&'w¬é¦ëª¿l<ØzÀ| m� ;j*g*ßî(­@‡son;äp–eqkysoÑšn‚Ý‰ð—Š�n1xãÙž|›Ž�cùˆ="" ‚ÿèþ†›†�="" ÐhË~|ä!Ëkgúˆ#†Á•="fÞ•«ëÛa" „úÚ;®1j�}="" ö2¿¡poäj�™="" oœg!_l¡s©›š(økËz²n®ãfci›·yneh¸ä'd‘Î{w¤¾¨a#ôo8¤+ß¤h^atÃcfßÿôåñË#�'ûd‰yä)å›t’æ›Û�Ó©fï]ú:¯j="ÞCîˆ¸ï!RñÜ7Š“ÇÎð”KÍÈM“ï¤D½Ê«×/³?3}±¢“Un" Ù¹tÖŠd9\]Ô="" lh6="" ªv’Ä˜Üà!&="" Ót]="">bÄð­Âçbe(·pÆ	�¹¤òeŸ‰¸Ç¢×ò&amp;¦ñ"„nŒ�þÄ íÈÒ½ä@óÀUºOé,¥¾J^Ã9y¦Eî‘Ë	„F¤cé·&lt;Õå6�ØAÉ“+ÉÁ
ä¶5lea”.Ž¼Î&nbsp;×
"’õƒË'€Þ¢$ÌRý¦Rƒ“Öxui—–œÛ2öžv¶uÍëêuf:]{"¤¶�¼rå5	è'/üfo¯ˆUK—+jZS�sm.šáGkè ¡©¿©Ú;�{ß\T„*1ßzÊ*454ÚË¨ÅBœÈ2*&amp;K®:µÌ—A"w²eo©=	KïY¨'c$˜l	\#b�øt†tãÍç·O»»¿ïð{V´Qþ“&nbsp;ŠsÒÙ¦lïþø+ÚT°Ù"Ôà¡/ÄÙn”’¢9›ÍãÝ¿ùû¢É6	 €à¨eÐÔ€À,YœÜ`£�ÀvCªe"2É£â¢uªjÏ5tcäö·ý“os#ì›ñ‰�&amp;x°…j	:}Áy¾¤V˜�
Î¥ÀGi?5Érël÷®n7ÍõU¯’Ë9‚àœ™À'7z¾]ç�Œ‰Ò0É1œÀyãåFLÜoJJ5òEÍøŠe¡•Èx‚nÒ¤€—Áç-ÊÏáÏâÉH$9R&gt;žOJ±y–[‘Ë?½¹—vÔB}8é�¿pâ–Þï^¿†öW/üÇÏÿÄÂ_óôž”ùPH%§¬¥Ÿt
œ
4ö3šœI{‚õ¤q˜±Æayá7£—#MJ°-è¬&nbsp;êš˜Å34õ©Š`I$_�^w%~\�K¨á¦ƒÝÚ3š"¼‰¦·ÿ]ÿl€W
endstream
endobj
43 0 obj
&lt;&lt;
/Length 2250      
/Filter /FlateDecode
&gt;&gt;
stream
xÚ�Ù’ã¶ñ}¾B�TÕ
C&lt;ý¶&gt;6ÞT²v¼rÅUŽ+…•0#Öò�	pfå¯w7ºAQc®]É4�¾»Átó¸I7»ûrwÿF™Š:­åfÿ°)SQÅ¦�™¨µÞì�›Ÿ“lûËþï÷oT½DTi!”2å«o_¿ÿæ‡íNk•H±Ý•¥NÞ¾Ûÿ°UeòÝ×?~µûÝ;$s—òÝ//Þ1Á�NE™WDö0ô®9ÚÑ·;U—‰¡ái›ç‰qžVMw‡­ª—Ùn+Ûã”÷‡žÆÿ¤:7~žg­¥¹»8o;Lg:M¾ðè3Ò³Oá;¾±Ò.dü¡ã“fò§at¤žLmJQ—i�F¹�õF‹:¯IEX/„f¼�,Ež²ÐöÓ¹5M·ªªNº!ÈY‚8§íN&amp;MÿèhmFd£¬’~ð&lt;1~MÛ^hyjìhÆ
qjðìTcZTåÉk¢B;v!Ó…a|4}ó›ñ
(øËí¤yÆB�ê‘Ëdp˜ÊP%=Ž0çTò¡AZ¸3Œ`Hš~‡¬GÎžƒÑlO;½é,Z¢ÖUòoà)ˆlý‰Nèˆv…ÃÔ¡¥+´4‚føoÁeÈ,r©pæ?'öÿÑ¸óý÷ãð8šÎÝ«.”úÞùéáaÍZRçBÕYôùWk”¢ÔuÄ˜I‡‹�Oÿš¾¾Ò‡Ô&nbsp;7¥nçO`~ZÚÖÙ`4”Ðª¸µLÛ|Î»Æ£¬EU«x�BžfN�ÇÀìÿÀ$†<j^k™ln"ÿc`ðk„Ã¸do½¡�$�Ì! ªdq"Í9ëìo!ÊtÑý¡…°‹çÃ@ÕàÈÄ�Î–ÜÕ…È®â(_“¢•."^ãˆ¸?q~�y<]w†="">Ì
Îþ:Ùþ`	mx è”êâ­#pdUÁÇü8 Hm”ò,¤ÙÓíOáÖB&amp;­	Áû‘Vág´D!=ð'þøîíO4;7¤tÞè� ÛÒšræx¡¥½¶ÅÜSæ1Nfr|¼¡p³cg��ñv-)@6=£;€^zE�Ž;Mlžšã„Ù×nxðsâ
™
¡‡!$ÌáœÒ™ðÁô×Ê„Ñ�¹–�#�ü€cŠfÃeÌûš­3L~)çJ™¦qÁs!âTV°r³2­›Z�iTfÉ—“§íà2°kZ7Ð¬³¦wñ¬ám$‰#§CÜ|F‚¡¸­ýD‹£ñ†ögƒ»5u	•Žº¦…óC(šZeáF„þq2+6ÝÂÒ¡”&gt;TNŒg(Tk°*\ï´P-“[»×� 2ÈÓÑå:8L9ãæn$=&lt;¬‰õïÃP=çªN^÷H}ôdûX™’&amp;n¢â†F#ˆ!ÔE¤ ´·öèh'0&nbsp;+ó°è¨ªCá
i¾(T~<o(™Á§…j¹[µÔÌ˜9vhkr¼2�&˜f«…Ãâlfn‡¹ rò­b‘&eâñ8Óö»˜km7Œœˆo³äÌ|#%´&¹âš˜a×'9ïj¡„"ÜàëÆù¦?„ò¿Ó”4ä­Æd¤) aç<6�="" Â‚Ø†‰³ÐÂgxgl­$d`bÕ¢”%÷“Ó8Î¥]ÕylÒp‘�ç©á�Ör#˜qÁähÝg?œ="" ƒj‚Œåà”¤ýÎpq="" †€ìr="">t#µ…Vu5Çåj¡’<z2w7*�%«¤Ò :zª’whÀ="" è="" �jo="" 9wÉ8™="" @%w‰â £zµÊ÷äÉ;�õÂrÂ^„;:àà¯•="„ˆ¶W/³�¡usp_¼hö¡È-Ëo!t‘Aû«D" �kyþé�¦×Þ**2d�ó°[m="" r1}zèh×­evÎÝ="" æøªxt¢="ÝÁEéúRç»Ã±Ö‡@…ù€ªÂD�§�»&nbsp;f^sWëkzî" t©ojÒÕ™@Õ="" â›º="" •´ðvªø+q§ ãÊŠÿkóïŒÁ�ùºî%¼ìê2?os`~_±½_3av‹"«&(àyö="">4ÈP5DésÓ¶#Ç§h5gny0‚†%#vš…(du	Ü•^x¼UëlMƒ`Mo¡ÐJK/¦æ-++N¡2QþDàa˜Îø4	jq¢5+ëÛ¢=lû‡J2-æ§Ó@€`…Æò™Ãh��³ý¬!2C|B`Z\M˜­àI8uD#¤VÜŸ9…–�AÄ`|©â€eÅvàù¹®Íç
#5|¥¡€_3þ;²EŒ¤ÙòÏù\­D–æÑ‰Ð;V<m¥bÊùÆm÷6ˆ.Ì©†Ãuìr0»mx´aøÀsx0Ž÷pa8Þúyi~fgßÇu"gíða Ðß‹g·_3qårñ¦y{÷(müg%Ö2jŒ}ÈhŸšar1éÏØu›¶b|âñ#œe‘ä–y="" bfƒÊÕ‹—v?kÿúzct\ðv’¥Õ‘i¶û.f‘,c+æh="" �ÌfÑßdÉþ="" �y)£‘3="" $tü®àwuqÍ³�v\}á,k¸¼f@˜‡tŽ#w_ zm}€="">ÌÄf*ç&amp;4—±VËS¡�É›m¥ÂÓáö“Á‡Að‘âŠþÏ©ýLçrGšq×„óJú‘€†÷˜µ°·øSún‡ÈN³ð`ød�;×üf	ºLqƒo\\ÄÏSþè8ûÔPöÇç¼ +@ç®�£q5c!~x¼áÖ#ê(ËRjn2Y/èBêm#ÉÐçàöÃö!ki'^KéøB@l¯—…ò›ýÝ¯wNéFÆ_§Ðiä›Cw÷ó/éæ ©ÐuµyhÝFf¥¨ü÷ÐnÞßý‹~Âfå”²,0H+-ô¦ªD•U7ÿ3€âÑ,TI!s(=¢JëX–ãÏžj�†�V5ÿè8yþâþþùùY¸S3~¼ˆ*®»w?ô~h‡ÇË‡'Vuˆ“ïÚ©_Ž&nbsp;…ßâÊ‚
endstream
endobj
47 0 obj
&lt;&lt;
/Length 2340      
/Filter /FlateDecode
&gt;&gt;
stream
xÚ…XÉ’äÆ
½÷WðÈŽ˜¢¸³x´&amp;fävØš±»’CÒ!›du1šK‰INOûë�€K�hûPÅL $–dúÎ³ã;?Ü}ºûîc˜;�ïå~8§³“ç^DNÄ^EÎ©t~q/ôîY¹Ÿï�û�ûðè~úþ¯þöxˆ¢Ðýéá&gt;pO–Î‡ŸO?þ ½Ç=ž0î·Ó_¾û¤Û�¢4öâ&lt;#Ax“cî|•Ì9ÌìCä{Yr”AmÕöÃ-�ù®I´ûtfÜNs×\¯´©3Ö}gIú$ÉÜ?YÚ—&amp;Vq»g¡Ù7;V­(«¡þ‚µ«Rç¡o¥õÏ~ž7äE�›d&gt;‘—Ä¹ÈY˜¶‚÷µ.!JE²h\‡Ê”ï„7^*[‰žÆªÀ~—®þ}ª¬Ð^Y‚AG4fx®š7™yî‡ç~«ÎÍF‰^ž$!4KÂD¹wŒƒÕ|1í„‰ûñ&gt;�Ý©ip„Ä5e9TÖìÕ•’HÐÈ‹ßŽåhý0÷’0”õªÇé"9Šb³U±&nbsp;-ŠåÎ$Ç”žQ*túNš×¡ŒÏÜ×¡Æ!…Uë·é±Äë¡™õú–¯åšîy2Ï•Ý3ËfûP·§©ïåc&nbsp;i4Ö]©c{ùŽ3Î­êMZö?Ù^× ÕY]v\f*óÌzGëW?ñ¿ÔÃ8™†š�Î-ÙS†e±
ë?�ÌË3_'ñ‚Ü‰ÈÞz®hÏJw2/ñ5€ª¯Eu¥ƒDI¨GŠ’h£ôŒ°ÕÒéÌ8
¦aÿ£!Ü¤“v×ëzóáAäCƒXô–†&gt;¡+Ôþ|³•êbk²DäUÕ �ÉÿË^‚ÏJWD&nbsp;·Ët3.PçzáŽ%\h„²
M6–��¹EmFŽ|!;7†Ö£7†žŸ(8~^&lt;6Nq"4'B§©_8–¥'Ç@‹ÂX—ÚŽý b¡O a·ŽAª&nbsp;x0Š¾½Nc5èvSîùyGçˆ‚TOwhMGÑ’ÉÔ
Â�ºz9{9Hd6Æ› úd"&nbsp;Ë‚3qF]LÐ‰k˜bm!š™7;uIwDçÔˆC
š8Úñ°á?ø.ÖåŽø
)-†Ò¬Õ95ûí1r�1©/‡¨dŽkJÚ	Sê… ‹8[©çÞ^´&gt;+èoðÅ'9"šSJ¢GEÙ‹oÎÖ[MG,˜n×?âœŒ3qì‹ïLÒ E»Æ7Êa't)ŠÈûI¹¶Ÿ†yôÍ4JS´;ãT=ª€A{jæIÅqš1VceNÃÀŠá°Üc]L”Ö�xÞ£,‡Z°îSÝqî¢*‡†ù¨…ZÍßù‚ûÂ^¼÷žPO—™&nbsp;£æ9{©Bk„¢þÕ�âb‘%s›j ¢µ+Ìd©kkB3™ÀY´I:š eÕŠ�ãnLÌRF¶½eUxHÝˆ‡Pw4/³_Ñ0SîV_î�B3¬Ž�’:‡Kä�ÉÑ:UU¢¦ar¯Ã®cÝÖÿÖINhÌª`qÃcºŒ— ¥FY�CÝ.±¿Ý²¤HÓ,:ÿ_vN-¸Ü´øÚ1t9¼®åÂÄ‡?`¹ùÔŒàä}£k]B”Þ¼��
IG�÷²Ì¶îä€ô%ð±ã0£î5&lt;ÁNõ8˜aJ3Â?�4´+µçßNcÔÀd÷¹ÝŒÐš\ïÉè«FÉ‰“¾õLÐ•Ÿ&nbsp;ö|Û	8Ž1&nbsp;P7ÃêÐ7Í’ê@1âÇ¤÷]|9]0æ9ã]˜sP¢»=h›�.§hb/æÐù™2�2
)ÀˆÈê§ïUê¡¥Ä[ü+ÏeKä…Vœªå‚ö4QpEìuÔ;ó"PÉnÞé×‚a&nbsp;i‰—+Í4E&amp;.d’œãßê+™©ã‚z\¶iå0mpšXÛÂ*—4‘äRõäš%ž¤sì¢V»äWÊUý
5ƒ$¨�3À?¶Q¯‘iGÃ¼ìÔ‘YJw„›:2Þ«#3/q
[‡¡|}½ÔK´Ò&gt;3®4ª)&nbsp;˜Ó}KIA53Ý‚T%<r'6-Êdd~¹�ÓvcÃ 9c="" ÉÒ[µlü€vë¡mÕäjháf…ÔøÛ¨0& Ò·“öfö?(›–™†aÍ�z="" ¤ê+Á—^†¨{¦Ècbx·œ\ƒÁ¥¥ÊÍ‘éêdjéÀƒÏÒ‰jnðÌ<£ðÚm™„¬Çíh«‹÷2Þö|a%j¡Õmu»{&jébvÕív?œc·buœ¼‚y¡lk9�®k(j="˜Í&nbsp;c¥cžlßPMÄ×Œ,Ôº">C)d–°ÊŸÁß–û¸ã§¡û&nbsp;›.7j—ý,‰´s½Éfâëxª&amp;¥ûW
)
ø'obÂ×…Ø½,�){º^ûn–°ò�ÊÝšÁb¾Ó¤K0[×Õ™ð&lt;®Rqµ™µ÷Ü0Ûð�ÔªR¼QÚgc©Ø*àÉg-ÎS�4J]@ë®õ8±h$¢Ãã ¢ñ9ÞxÅ;l¡g,«¦âØuP#÷8JÑÈ}Ò’éì™3!Q©Ž§Šª^ou¨/Ïpx-Ê"Õz$•ú„Ž²¥Ôæw—\�It5¼tÆÙk‚™hìÞ¥TŠpÔüÌ¤E9‰òèš2äþÉÄ­@ËýUÓø¿$[¾7Äa�î¦î5eùé¬|Í¤®‘Q`
TjKº{6£.¤oN&lt;ÛÐEX¨sù.±:èFx¹xSJq¸y¨ûpºûý.&nbsp;¦ïóãad^�¢½ûå7ß)‰GgóKœWÙ:ALy(M©Ý8�w——È8sÊN„ã”v‚ ðÒ˜2¥¢ŒFn:âÈ9bzŒ�±$HOG_]êü†.t„q¸òŽ\|µìc10£9ŸíE¹Çó£®—¨)òÍ!nŠo–WªZéSècD‡‡'^�§ÅtãMçm•J4È&nbsp;/w7g&gt;ÈY2üoòÿ&gt;ïçÕxxxãQkÍq/•DþMþÛ¼ZÄ¸òbAn`ã‹~~¸Ð©*r÷©æ(š”×‰i°@â,�ÜOØŒuÂûIÒR/9Fôõ×ÚbŠj4Nô=jîD›ªVÒee®jG+£ckéå!ç‚Š˜êé2ÄèŒW–´i¼×þöK®þ‡ú 
endstream
endobj
50 0 obj
&lt;&lt;
/Length 2216      
/Filter /FlateDecode
&gt;&gt;
stream
xÚ•XÉ’ã6½×WðHE”X\Eræä¥ÛÓsðÒ–O¶£"¡¢HBÉ–Ë_ïÜ@QÕòDÌ‰ÈD"äò2Á8xâà»‡¯÷Oï“]�ÄQ×I°?eU»]°Kò¨Î²`ß¿†»Íïûÿ&gt;½Oëµ`ï¢45$òÍ¾úqÿîãf›ei˜D›mYfá‡ï÷7iþðí/ßì?üð=ªyˆeï·oEá6‹£²¨Xm£ÇÑ:
zÓ"Tmë€�Ä.ÏªÑ°QžÕáGÝèwšº×M•…�,rÜl“Ðn’Ð1m†qRC£eZ±ÖI7¸ô4˜?fÙ¨Q]§[¾u–¯O™Åe”�]äÚx¢M‘„|ª¼GÜòŒ,ÕÐ*Á;ñ²m’EE^óâN½Úy‚ue’5´¶7©ÉØ�7ÏÓ&nbsp;Œê2¦½“,“WAÕ…¨(XìÖ’UTì*Øó*vRx¼"
áþn‚›‘„‡Í6­Bm†gžœGžIÃÉ²ÄÙéÏh4nN2yÒ&lt;8;®éEuvV3^dÓÁeã:Êàl7·&gt;&nbsp;ªWX³+Â#ÉwSâÞ-yVX
Fx¹ÈÓpî[�«±ÃhÆidÊùûl&gt;óípÑi¥{·úVçñÔ1·àÓöÊèÙoûìTÏxŠ´¾¬�98åŒ=_M&lt;2ò+Ë\k~‹³L»«u�ùÙ¸iV�lÃñ4ÄHžÖçôf�LOn)½JbòÿÈ\ý§nfˆ4jR�Qé€0qAÝ

»äÐ.£$�É^u¦1ve-gÖ„›¹—Üã©F
¼d°¢ØiÈÊ;G¶(XVr`\ó»,9�éô4;/)¼í¬Ñ5IøÌòt</r'6-êdd~¹�óvcã></m¥bêùæm÷6ˆ.ì©†ãuìr0»mx´aøàsx0ž÷pa8þúyi~fgßçu"gíða></z2w7*�%«¤ò></o(™á§…j¹[µôì˜9vhkr¼2�&˜f«…ãâlfn‡¹></j^k™ln"ÿc`ðk„ã¸do½¡�$�ì!></sv”></puàî)•î0à†ß]tâgø"�ûá÷‡mÿrõš›(ðìéqv\@+uk6*ñêû�àêî�àxÿùùà½¨d‡èj></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://metamodular.com/closos.pdf">http://metamodular.com/closos.pdf</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://metamodular.com/closos.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23730107</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 04:24:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Lisp Badge: A single-board computer that you can program in uLisp]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 83 | Comments 13 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23729970">thread link</a>) | @lnyan
<br/>
July 3, 2020 | http://www.ulisp.com/show?2L0C | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.ulisp.com/show?2L0C">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">

<p>The Lisp Badge is a self-contained computer with its own display and keyboard, based on an ATmega1284, that you can program in uLisp:</p>
<p><img src="http://www.ulisp.com/pictures/3j/lispbadgehand.jpg" alt="LispBadgeHand.jpg" width="720" height="462"></p>
<p>You can use it to run programs that interface to components such as LEDs and push-buttons via the I/O pins, read the analogue inputs, and operate external devices via the I2C and SPI interfaces. It has a greyscale OLED display that gives 8 lines of 42 characters, and an integrated 45-key keyboard optimised for Lisp.</p>
<p>For details of how to build one see&nbsp;<a href="http://www.technoblogy.com/show?2AEE" target="_blank">Lisp Badge</a>&nbsp;on Technoblogy.</p>
<h3><span>Specification</span></h3>
<p><strong>Size:</strong> 107mm x 61mm (4.2" x 2.4").</p>
<p><strong>Display</strong>: 42 characters x 8 lines.</p>
<p><strong>Keyboard:</strong>&nbsp;Integrated 45-key keyboard providing upper and lower-case characters, digits, and the symbols required by uLisp.</p>
<p><strong>Memory available</strong>: 2816 Lisp cells (11264 bytes).</p>
<p><strong>EEPROM</strong>: 1024 Lisp cells (4096 bytes), allows you to save the Lisp workspace using <strong>save-image</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Processor:</strong> ATmega1284P</p>
<p><strong>Clock speed:</strong> 16 MHz.</p>
<p><strong>Current consumption:</strong> Approx. 20 mA.</p>
<h4><strong>Language</strong></h4>
<p>uLisp, a subset of Common Lisp, with 122 Lisp functions and special forms. For a full definition see <a href="http://www.ulisp.com/show?3L" target="_blank">uLisp Language Reference</a>.</p>
<p>The language includes two extensions, <strong>plot</strong> and <strong>plot3d</strong>, for plotting graphs and 3d functions.&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Types supported</strong>: list, symbol, integer, character, string, and stream.</p>
<p>An integer is a sequence of digits, optionally prefixed with "+" or "-". Integers can be between -32768 and 32767. You can enter numbers in hexadecimal, octal, or binary with the notations #x2A, #o52, or #b101010, all of which represent 42.</p>
<p>User-defined symbol names can have arbitrary names. Any sequence that isn't an integer can be used as a symbol; so, for example, 12a is a valid symbol.</p>
<p>There is one namespace for functions and variables; in other words, you cannot use the same name for a function and a variable.</p>
<p>Includes a mark and sweep garbage collector. Garbage collection takes 5 msec.</p>
<h4><strong>Interfaces</strong></h4>
<p>These interfaces are brought to headers at the edge of the Lisp Badge board. The numbers in brackets refer to Arduino pin numbers:</p>
<ul>
<li>Four analogue input pins using <strong>analogread</strong>: A0 to A3 (24 to 27) plus VCC and GND.</li>
<li>Two analogue outputs using <strong>analogwrite</strong>:&nbsp;MISO (6), and SCK (7).</li>
<li>Digital input and output using <strong>pinmode</strong>, <strong>digitalread</strong>, and <strong>digitalwrite</strong>:&nbsp;MOSI (5), MISO (6), SCK (7),&nbsp;RX0 (8), TX0 (9), SCL (16), SDA (17), and A0 to A3 (24 to 27)</li>
<li>I2C interface using <strong>with-i2c</strong> and <strong>restart-i2c</strong>: SCL (16) and SDA (17).</li>
<li>SPI interface using <strong>with-spi</strong>: MOSI (5), MISO (6), and SCK (7).</li>
<li>Serial interface (FTDI) using&nbsp;<strong>with-serial</strong>: RX0 (8) and TX0 (9).</li>
</ul>
<p>The shift key can be used as a digital input: SHIFT (23).</p>
<p>SCK (7) is connected to an LED on the front panel. This is an analogue output pin, so you can vary the brightness of the LED.</p>
<h3>Plotting extensions</h3>
<p>The Lisp Badge contains two plotting extensions, plot and plot3d, designed to allow plotting to the greyscale graphics display.</p>
<p><span>After generating a plot both functions wait for the ESC key to be pressed before displaying the uLisp prompt.</span></p>
<h3 id="plot">plot&nbsp;<span>function</span></h3>
<p><strong>Syntax:</strong>&nbsp;<code>(plot [<em>x-intercept y-intercept</em>] [<em>function</em>]...)</code></p>
<p>Plots up to four functions on the same graph, optionally with axes.</p>
<p>Each function should be a function of one parameter, the x coordinate, and it will be called with each value of x from 0 to 255. The function should return the y value, from 0 to 63.</p>
<p>If&nbsp;<em>x-intercept</em>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<em>y-intercept</em>&nbsp;are specified,&nbsp;<strong>plot3d</strong>&nbsp;draws axes through those intercepts.</p>
<p>For example, defining:</p>
<pre>(defun sine ()
  (let ((x 0) (y 2045))
    (lambda (n) 
      n
      (incf x (/ (* y 16) 163))
      (decf y (/ (* x 16) 163))
    (+ 32 (ash x -6)))))</pre>
<p>the following command:</p>
<pre>(plot 0 32 (sine))</pre>
<p>will plot:</p>
<p><img src="http://www.ulisp.com/pictures/3j/lispsine.jpg" alt="LispSine.jpg" width="600" height="211"></p>
<h4 id="plot3d">Plotting multiple functions</h4>
<p>The following example plots the voltages on the analogue inputs 0 to 3 once a second on a single plot. First define:</p>
<pre>(defun adc (n) (lambda (x) (delay 250) (/ (analogread n) 8)))</pre>
<p>Then give the command:</p>
<pre>(plot 0 0 (adc 0) (adc 1) (adc 2) (adc 3))</pre>
<h3>plot3d&nbsp;<span>function</span></h3>
<p><strong>Syntax:</strong>&nbsp;<code>(plot3d&nbsp;[<em>x-intercept y-intercept</em>] [<em>function</em>])</code></p>
<p>The function should be a function of two parameters, the x and y coordinates, and it will be called with each value of x from 0 to 255 and y from 0 to 63. The function should return the greyscale value to be plotted, from 0 to 15.</p>
<p>If&nbsp;<em>x-intercept</em>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<em>y-intercept</em>&nbsp;are specified,&nbsp;<strong>plot3d</strong>&nbsp;draws axes through those intercepts.</p>
<p>For example, defining:</p>
<pre>(defun p (x y) 
  (let ((a (/ (- x 128) 2))
        (b (- y 32))) 
    (min (abs (- (logand (/ (+ (* a a) (* b b) (* a b)) 16) 31) 15)) 15)))</pre>
<p>the following command:</p>
<pre>(plot3d 128 32 p)</pre>
<p>will plot:</p>
<p><img src="http://www.ulisp.com/pictures/3j/lispellipses.jpg" alt="LispEllipses.jpg" width="600" height="211"></p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.ulisp.com/show?2L0C</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23729970</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 03:54:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Nilfs – log-structured file system with versioning of the entire fs]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 9 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23729911">thread link</a>) | @SpaceInvader
<br/>
July 3, 2020 | https://nilfs.sourceforge.io/en/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nilfs.sourceforge.io/en/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main_column">
<h2>Welcome to NILFS</h2>
<p>
NILFS is a log-structured file system supporting versioning of the
entire file system and continuous snapshotting which allows users to
even restore files mistakenly overwritten or destroyed just a few seconds ago.
</p><p>
NILFS was developed by NTT Laboratories and published as an
open-source software under GPL license, and now available as a part
of Linux kernel.
</p><p>
This site provides information and resources
related to the NILFS filesystem.
</p>
<p>*** Fake site warning ***</p>
<p>
''www.nilfs.org'' has been reopened as a fake site by a third
party after we abandoned the domain in September 2014.
The fake site defaces the original content, leading visitors to
unrelated websites, so please be careful not to go to the site
mistakenly.  NILFS community and NTT are absolutely not related
to this fake site.
</p><p>
The official NILFS website is
<a href="https://nilfs.sourceforge.io/">nilfs.sourceforge.io</a>
or
<a href="https://nilfs.osdn.jp/">nilfs.osdn.jp</a> (mirror site).
Please use these sites when accessing information related to NILFS.
</p>

<h2>Latest News</h2>
<ul>
<li id="n132">NILFS utilities 2.2.8 was released. A maintenance release with some fixes.  Fix some build issues and minor bugs in mkfs.nilfs2.<br>
-- Aug 20, 2019 JST.</li>
<li id="n131">nilfs2-kmod7 version 1.1.2 was released.  Fix a race condition bug that causes file system corruption.  For details, please see <a href="https://raw.github.com/nilfs-dev/nilfs2-kmod7/v1.1.2/ChangeLog">ChangeLog file</a> or <a href="https://github.com/nilfs-dev/nilfs2-kmod7/commits/v1.1.2">commit logs</a>.<br>
-- Nov 18, 2017 JST.</li>
<li id="n130">nilfs2-kmod6 version 1.1.2 was released.  Fix a race condition bug that causes file system corruption.  For details, please see <a href="https://raw.github.com/nilfs-dev/nilfs2-kmod6/v1.1.2/ChangeLog">ChangeLog file</a> or <a href="https://github.com/nilfs-dev/nilfs2-kmod6/commits/v1.1.2">commit logs</a>.<br>
-- Nov 18, 2017 JST.</li>

</ul>
<p>
<a href="https://nilfs.sourceforge.io/en/oldnews.html">Old news</a>
</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nilfs.sourceforge.io/en/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23729911</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 03:40:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Where Am I? NYTimes or Google?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 1092 | Comments 339 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23729160">thread link</a>) | @rwoll
<br/>
July 3, 2020 | https://theinternetbytes.com/2020/07/03/where-am-i/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://theinternetbytes.com/2020/07/03/where-am-i/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            




            
<article>
    <header>
        
        <p>
            JULY 3, 2020
        </p>
    </header>
    <section>
        <p>Take a look at the below screenshot from Safari for iOS. What website am I on?</p>

<p><img src="https://theinternetbytes.com/images/amp-nytimes-example.png" alt="AMP Example with NYTimes"></p>

<p>Based on the contents of the page, I think I’m on The New York Times’ site.
However, based on the domain visible in the address bar,
I think I’m on <code>google.com</code>. If I click in the address bar
I see <code>https://www.google.com/amp/s/www.nytimes.com/2020/05/22/technology/google-antitrust.amp.html</code>.
So, where am I? What am I looking at? What’s up with the mix of Google and
New York Times’ branding? Do I trust the contents of the page or the address
bar? How does the content of the page and the address bar relate in this context
and elsewhere on the web?</p>

<p>Comments on a draft of this post can be viewed here: <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23729160">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23729160</a>.</p>

    </section>
</article>

        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://theinternetbytes.com/2020/07/03/where-am-i/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23729160</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 01:14:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Scaling Linux Services: Before accepting connections]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 162 | Comments 25 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23729072">thread link</a>) | @theojulienne
<br/>
July 3, 2020 | https://theojulienne.io/2020/07/03/scaling-linux-services-before-accepting-connections.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://theojulienne.io/2020/07/03/scaling-linux-services-before-accepting-connections.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
    <p>When writing services that accept TCP connections, we tend to think of our work as starting from the point where our service accepts a new client connection and finishing when we complete the request and close the socket. For services at scale, operations can happen at such a high rate that some of the default resource limits of the Linux kernel can break this abstraction and start causing impact to incoming connections outside of that connection lifecycle. This post focuses on some standard resource limitations that exist before the client socket is handed to the application - all of which came up during the course of investigating errors on production systems as part of my role at GitHub (in some cases, multiple times across different applications).</p>

<p>In its most basic form (ignoring non-blocking variants), listening for TCP connections requires a call to <code>listen()</code> to actually start allowing incoming connections, followed by repeated calls to <code>accept()</code> to take the next pending connection and return a file descriptor that is for that particular client. In C this pattern looks something like:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>int</span> <span>server_fd</span> <span>=</span> <span>socket</span><span>(</span><span>AF_INET</span><span>,</span> <span>SOCK_STREAM</span><span>,</span> <span>0</span><span>);</span>
<span>bind</span><span>(</span><span>server_fd</span><span>,</span> <span>/* ... */</span><span>);</span>

<span>// start listening for connections</span>
<span>listen</span><span>(</span><span>server_fd</span><span>,</span> <span>512</span><span>);</span>

<span>while</span> <span>(</span><span>running</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>// block until a connection arrives and then accept it</span>
    <span>int</span> <span>client_fd</span> <span>=</span> <span>accept</span><span>(</span><span>server_fd</span><span>,</span> <span>NULL</span><span>,</span> <span>NULL</span><span>);</span>

    <span>// ... handle client_fd ...</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>close</span><span>(</span><span>server_fd</span><span>);</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This is often hidden behind further layers of abstraction, and we tend to hide away all the implementation details of accepting connections and view it as a stream of new connections that we pick up and then process in parallel. However, when building a system that runs at a certain scale, this abstraction tends to break down because there are resource limitations introduced in the period where connections are being established but are not yet returned by <code>accept()</code>. Before that point, those client connections are considered as being part of the server/listen socket and not as independent resources exposed to the application.</p>

<p>The examples mentioned in this blog post will be reproducible in the lab from <i></i> <a href="https://github.com/theojulienne/blog-lab-scaling-accept">theojulienne/blog-lab-scaling-accept</a> - clone this repository bring up the lab, then poke around at these examples in a real system:</p>
<div><div><pre><code>$ git clone https://github.com/theojulienne/blog-lab-scaling-accept.git
$ cd blog-lab-scaling-accept
$ vagrant up
$ vagrant ssh
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="from-syn-to-accept">From SYN to accept()</h2>

<p>The Linux kernel maintains 2 queues of connections that maintain the backlog of connections that are not yet <code>accept()</code>ed by the application:</p>
<p><img alt="LISTEN backlogs" src="https://theojulienne.io/images/scaling-linux-services-before-accepting-connections/pre-accept-backlogs.png">
</p>

<p>When a SYN packet is received to initiate a new connection to a listen socket, a SYN-ACK is sent to the client and the half-completed connection state is stored in the “SYN backlog” or “Request Socket Queue”. This represents connections that have not yet been fully validated as having two-way communication between the hosts, because we haven’t yet validated that the remote end has received a packet from us (the SYN could have come from another host spoofing the source IP).</p>

<p>Once the client responds to the server’s SYN-ACK with an ACK, the connection has then completed the full <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Handshaking#TCP_three-way_handshake">TCP 3-way handshake</a>, and the server knows that two-way communication has been established. At this point, the client connection is ready to be provided to the application at a future call to <code>accept()</code>, and is added to the appropriately named “accept queue”.</p>

<h2 id="syn-backlog">SYN backlog</h2>

<p>Connections in the SYN backlog remain there for a period of time relative to the Round Trip Time between the server and the client. If there are N slots in the backlog then you can have at most N connections in this backlog per average RTT, after which the backlog overflows.</p>

<p>This won’t actually cause the connections to fail by default on Linux, but cause <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SYN_cookies">SYN cookies</a> to be sent instead. This is because when only a SYN packet has been received, the server hasn’t yet validated that the client is who they say they are, so they could be spoofing packets as coming from a different IP. This is a common Denial of Service attack called a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SYN_flood">SYN Flood</a>. Because this is so common, the Linux kernel has built in mitigation to SYN floods by sending a SYN cookie when there is no room in the SYN backlog for the new connection.</p>

<p>This means that even if the SYN backlog overflows under normal circumstances with no DoS attack, the kernel allows the connection to move further along in the handshake, and won’t store any resources for the connection until an ACK completes the handshake. Sending SYN cookies during normal circumstances does however indicate that the rate of connections is probably too high for the default limits - SYN cookies are really only meant for mitigating SYN floods.</p>

<p>Whether SYN cookies are enabled is controlled via the sysctl <code>net.ipv4.tcp_syncookies</code>, by default this is set to <code>1</code> which indicates that SYN cookies should be sent when the SYN backlog overflows, but can also be set to <code>0</code> to disable entirely or <code>2</code> to force SYN cookies to be sent 100% of the time.</p>

<p>When SYN cookies are enabled as needed (the default), they are triggered when the number of pending connections in the SYN backlog is more than the configured accept queue backlog size for the socket - the logic for this is <a href="https://github.com/torvalds/linux/blob/cb8e59cc87201af93dfbb6c3dccc8fcad72a09c2/net/ipv4/tcp_input.c#L6612-L6613">here</a>. When SYN cookies are fully disabled, <code>net.ipv4.tcp_max_syn_backlog</code> configures the number of connections allowed in the SYN backlog separately - the logic for this case is <a href="https://github.com/torvalds/linux/blob/cb8e59cc87201af93dfbb6c3dccc8fcad72a09c2/net/ipv4/tcp_input.c#L6670-L6672">here</a>.</p>

<p>In the default configuration where the backlog overflows and SYN cookies are sent, the kernel increments the <code>TCPReqQFullDoCookies</code> counter and logs this line to the kernel log, which is often confused for an indicator of a real SYN flood even when it’s just due to legitimate connections coming in too fast:</p>
<div><div><pre><code>TCP: request_sock_TCP: Possible SYN flooding on port 8080. Sending cookies.  Check SNMP counters.
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>If SYN cookies are explicitly disabled, the kernel increments the <code>TCPReqQFullDrop</code> counter and the following would be logged instead:</p>
<div><div><pre><code>TCP: request_sock_TCP: Possible SYN flooding on port 8080. Dropping request.  Check SNMP counters.
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>If you see this message for internal service-to-service connections, chances are you’re dealing with a scaling problem or a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thundering_herd_problem">thundering herd problem</a>, and not an actual SYN flood or intentional bad actor.</p>

<p>Those “SNMP Counters” that the kernel mentions are available in <code>nstat</code> in the network namespace:</p>
<div><div><pre><code>$ nstat -a | grep TCPReqQFull
TcpExtTCPReqQFullDoCookies      706                0.0
</code></pre></div></div>

<h3 id="syn-backlog-in-the-lab">SYN backlog in the lab</h3>

<p>To see how the SYN backlog behaves in the lab, we can simulate latency on local connections with the following:</p>
<div><div><pre><code>vagrant@blog-lab-scaling-accept:~$ sudo /vagrant/reset-lab.sh
vagrant@blog-lab-scaling-accept:~$ sudo tc qdisc add dev lo root netem delay 200ms
vagrant@blog-lab-scaling-accept:~$ ping 127.0.0.1
PING 127.0.0.1 (127.0.0.1) 56(84) bytes of data.
64 bytes from 127.0.0.1: icmp_seq=1 ttl=64 time=401 ms
64 bytes from 127.0.0.1: icmp_seq=2 ttl=64 time=400 ms
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This means we can now simulate overflowing the SYN backlog. To make it a bit easier to reproduce, reduce the size of the SYN backlog from the default of <code>128</code> by reducing <code>net.core.somaxconn</code> (because SYN cookies are enabled):</p>
<div><div><pre><code>vagrant@blog-lab-scaling-accept:~$ sudo sysctl net.core.somaxconn
net.core.somaxconn = 128
vagrant@blog-lab-scaling-accept:~$ sudo sysctl -w net.core.somaxconn=10
net.core.somaxconn = 10
vagrant@blog-lab-scaling-accept:~$ sudo systemctl restart nginx
vagrant@blog-lab-scaling-accept:~$ 
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>At this point, if more than 10 connections arrive within 400ms (before the SYN-ACK and ACK handshake complete), then 10 connections will be in the SYN backlog, which is the maximum configured. This will trigger SYN cookies to be sent, triggering the message and counters above. Let’s test out if this works, run a simulation that opens N concurrent connections:</p>
<div><div><pre><code>vagrant@blog-lab-scaling-accept:~$ python /vagrant/test_send_concurrent_connections.py 127.0.0.1:80 20
Waiting, Ctrl+C to exit.
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And verify that SYN cookies were sent as expected:</p>
<div><div><pre><code>vagrant@blog-lab-scaling-accept:~$ sudo dmesg -c
[ 2571.784749] TCP: request_sock_TCP: Possible SYN flooding on port 80. Sending cookies.  Check SNMP counters.
vagrant@blog-lab-scaling-accept:~$ sudo nstat | grep ReqQ
TcpExtTCPReqQFullDoCookies      10                 0.0
vagrant@blog-lab-scaling-accept:~$
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Try disabling the simulated latency with <code>sudo tc qdisc del dev lo root</code> and re-run the same test, now connections move through fast enough that SYN cookies are not sent.</p>

<p>This also demonstrates the way the Round Trip Time effects the amount of connections that can burst into a LISTEN socket - <code>test_send_concurrent_connections.py</code> does actually attempt to initiate complete connections and <code>nginx</code> on the other end is readily calling <code>accept()</code> as fast as it can, but because 20 connections are initiated at once, 20 SYN packets arrive before any handshake can continue, and the SYN backlog overflows. You can imagine that in the real world, with some of these values often defaulting to <code>128</code>, and users often being far away from servers (on the other side of the world), it’s pretty easy to accidentally trigger this scenario without a true SYN flood.</p>

<h2 id="accept-queue">Accept queue</h2>

<p>Once an ACK packet is received and validated, a new client connection is ready for the application to process. This connection is moved into the accept queue, waiting for the application to call <code>accept()</code> and receive it.</p>

<p>Unlike the SYN backlog, the accept queue has no backup plan for when it overflows. Back in the original call to <code>listen()</code>, a <code>backlog</code> argument was provided, which indicates how many connections can have completed the 3-way handshake and be waiting in the kernel for the application to accept.</p>

<p>This is the first common issue: If the <code>backlog</code> number provided to <code>listen()</code> is not large enough to contain any number of connections that could reasonably complete their handshake between 2 calls to <code>accept()</code>, then a connection will be dropped on the floor, and the application generally won’t even notice - the next call to …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://theojulienne.io/2020/07/03/scaling-linux-services-before-accepting-connections.html">https://theojulienne.io/2020/07/03/scaling-linux-services-before-accepting-connections.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://theojulienne.io/2020/07/03/scaling-linux-services-before-accepting-connections.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23729072</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:58:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Replace Keybase in 3 Easy Steps]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 10 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23728832">thread link</a>) | @figbert
<br/>
July 3, 2020 | https://figbert.com/posts/how-to-replace-keybase-in-three-easy-steps | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://figbert.com/posts/how-to-replace-keybase-in-three-easy-steps">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article><a href="https://figbert.com/posts/how-to-replace-keybase-in-three-easy-steps" rel="me">FIGBERT</a> <section> <p>Published by  on <time datetime="2020-07-03">7/3/2020</time></p> </section> <p>Ever since <a href="https://keybase.io/blog/keybase-joins-zoom" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Keybase was acquired by Zoom</a>, a <a href="https://medium.com/bugbountywriteup/zoom-zero-day-4-million-webcams-maybe-an-rce-just-get-them-to-visit-your-website-ac75c83f4ef5" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">company</a> <a href="https://theintercept.com/2020/03/31/zoom-meeting-encryption/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">with</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/c1truz_/status/1244737672930824193" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">a</a> <a href="https://protonmail.com/blog/zoom-privacy-issues/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">very</a> <a href="https://www.axios.com/zoom-closes-chinese-user-account-tiananmen-square-f218fed1-69af-4bdd-aac4-7eaf67f34084.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">bad</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/nicoagrant/status/1268020841054269440" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">history</a> <a href="https://citizenlab.ca/2020/04/move-fast-roll-your-own-crypto-a-quick-look-at-the-confidentiality-of-zoom-meetings/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">with</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/DanAmodio/status/1245329512889487361" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">security</a>/<a href="https://twitter.com/Ouren/status/1241398181205889024" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">privacy</a>, <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23103386" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">people wanted an alternative</a>. There have been a few different alternatives proposed: this is <del>the best</del> mine.</p>  <section><p>Ever since <a href="https://keybase.io/blog/keybase-joins-zoom" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Keybase was acquired by Zoom</a>, a <a href="https://medium.com/bugbountywriteup/zoom-zero-day-4-million-webcams-maybe-an-rce-just-get-them-to-visit-your-website-ac75c83f4ef5" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">company</a> <a href="https://theintercept.com/2020/03/31/zoom-meeting-encryption/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">with</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/c1truz_/status/1244737672930824193" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">a</a> <a href="https://protonmail.com/blog/zoom-privacy-issues/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">very</a> <a href="https://www.axios.com/zoom-closes-chinese-user-account-tiananmen-square-f218fed1-69af-4bdd-aac4-7eaf67f34084.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">bad</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/nicoagrant/status/1268020841054269440" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">history</a> <a href="https://citizenlab.ca/2020/04/move-fast-roll-your-own-crypto-a-quick-look-at-the-confidentiality-of-zoom-meetings/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">with</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/DanAmodio/status/1245329512889487361" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">security</a>/<a href="https://twitter.com/Ouren/status/1241398181205889024" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">privacy</a>, <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23103386" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">people wanted an alternative</a>. There have been a few different alternatives proposed: this is <del>the best</del> mine.</p> <h2 id="-what-is-keybase">## What is Keybase?</h2> <p>Before we talk about replacing <a href="https://keybase.io/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Keybase</a>, we should have a good idea of what Keybase actually is. It's main features are as follows (ordered as on the website):</p> <ul> <li>E2EE chats and messaging (people and teams).</li> <li>Cryptographic identity verification from around the net.</li> <li><a href="https://book.keybase.io/docs/files" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">KBFS</a> (Public signed file hosting, private E2EE file storage w/ sharing, <a href="https://book.keybase.io/docs/files#keybase-pub" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Static site hosting??</a>)</li> <li>Git repositories? Crypto? <a href="https://saltpack.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">An alternative to PGP?</a></li> </ul> <h2 id="-previous-attempts-to-replace-keybase">## Previous Attempts to Replace Keybase</h2> <p>I'm not the first person to try this, obviously. Some brave folks have tried to build Keybase alternatives, such as <a href="https://keys.pub/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">keys.pub</a> and the brand-new <a href="https://keyoxide.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Keyoxide</a>. I've tried both, but found that though they both are good in their own right, they are not the solutions that I am looking for.</p> <h2 id="-ok-time-for-the-steps">## OK Time for the Steps</h2> <h3 id="-step-1-chatmessaging">### Step #1: Chat/Messaging</h3> <p>There are a few great pre-existing options for encrypted messaging: <a href="https://signal.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Signal</a>, <a href="https://beta.protonmail.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">ProtonMail</a> if you want to go full email, <a href="https://telegram.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Telegram</a>, and <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">WhatsApp</a>. However, they all have their problems (though I use the first two on a daily basis). Signal requires a phone number, and is more of an iMessage/text replacement than a Slack-style chat app. Protonmail is literally not chat – it's email. Telegram is <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=6936539" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">not</a> <a href="https://translate.google.com/translate?hl=en&amp;sl=ru&amp;u=http://habrahabr.ru/post/206900/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">secure</a>. If you use WhatsApp for security you might be crazy –&nbsp;I only use it because it's <em>the way</em> to communicate with people in the Middle East and Africa.</p> <p>Instead, I would recommend you use <a href="https://matrix.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><strong>Matrix</strong></a>. Matrix is an "open network for secure, decentralized communication," and it's the perfect replacement for Keybase's chat <del>and I would argue most other chat apps too</del>. It utilizes E2E encrypted messaging, and can be self-hosted as well <del>or if you're cheap like me just get your friend to host</del>.</p> <p>In addition to a Matrix server, you also need a client. For this, I recommend <a href="https://about.riot.im/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><strong>Riot</strong></a>. Riot is a beautiful Matrix client with a bunch of awesome features, including Slack-like integrations, and apps for pretty much every major platform (Linux, MacOS, Windows, iOS, Android, and a web client). <del>Plus it looks a lot like Discord.</del></p> <h3 id="-step-2-identity-verification">### Step #2: Identity verification</h3> <p>Replacing Keybase's <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20140322062148/https://keybase.io/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">original function</a> is probably the most difficult part of this tutorial: cryptographically verified identity proofs is a great and innovative idea. I would swap this out with an <a href="https://indieweb.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><strong>IndieWeb</strong></a> profile –&nbsp;one <a href="http://microformats.org/wiki/h-card" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">part</a> of the larger <a href="http://microformats.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">microformats</a> HTML structure. There are some pretty great tutorials out there (I would recommend <a href="https://kevq.uk/how-to-create-an-indieweb-profile/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">this one</a> by the fantastic <a href="https://kevq.uk/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Kev Quirk</a> and <a href="https://randomgeekery.org/post/2020/04/indieweb-h-cards/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">this one</a> by <a href="https://randomgeekery.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Brian Wisti</a>), so I won't go into too much detail about exactly how to do that. However, it's important to note that though Kev recommends hiding your h-card with the <code>display: none;</code> property: <a href="https://indieweb.org/antipatterns#invisible_metadata" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">don't do that</a>. I just merged my about and contact pages onto my homepage, and added the microformats classes to my existing markup.</p> <p><img alt="My IndieWeb h-card" src="https://figbert.com/content/posts/how-to-replace-keybase-in-three-easy-steps/h-card.png"></p> <h3 id="-step-3-file-storage">### Step #3: File Storage</h3> <p>Replacing KBFS is easy to do, but hard to get right. Swapping to <a href="https://www.google.com/drive/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Google Drive</a> is probably the move that most people would make, but that abandons the entire security/encryption aspect of Keybase. There's also <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Dropbox</a>, but that has the same problems as above. <a href="https://twitter.com/ProtonMail/status/1278389663078768641" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">ProtonDrive</a> has potential, but it's not out yet. Enter <a href="https://syncthing.net/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><strong>Syncthing</strong></a>. <a href="https://tonsky.me/blog/syncthing/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Nikita Tonsky</a> wrote one of my favorite posts of all time about Syncthing – go read it. One reason Syncthing is so great is that it's not the same thing as KBFS or any of the other "Drive" solutions. Instead of being a file hosting system, it's a "continuous file synchronization program." You have no data limits other than your storage and no third-party to worry about. Plus, sharing folders is also incredibly easy. Just read the article.</p> <h3 id="-bonus-step-4-video-calling">### Bonus Step #4: Video Calling</h3> <p>It would be a shame to talk about text chat, or really any form of communication, in this new pandemic age without talking about video chat. After all, the whole reason I'm writing this article is because the new videocalling giant <a href="https://zoom.us/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Zoom</a>. So, how have I replaced Zoom and how does that relate to replacing Keybase? Well, Matrix happens to have a fantastic <a href="https://jitsi.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Jitsi Meet</a> <a href="https://matrix.org/blog/2020/04/06/running-your-own-secure-communication-service-with-matrix-and-jitsi" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">integration</a>. Plus, the folks over at Jitsi are <a href="https://jitsi.org/blog/e2ee/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">working on E2E encryption for their calls</a>. I've integrated Jitsi Meet into my self-hosted instance of Matrix, and now all my videocalls are just that – mine!</p> <h2 id="-summary">## Summary</h2> <ul> <li>Swapped chat to Matrix and Riot.</li> <li>Swapped identity verification to Indieweb.</li> <li>Swapped file storage/sync to Syncthing.</li> <li>Added videocalling to chat program via Jitsi.</li> </ul> <h2 id="-conclusion">## Conclusion</h2> <p>Keybase is a great service, and the people who work there should be really proud of what they've built. However, given Zoom's aquisition of the company, the stability and security of the product have been called into question. So, ever one to hop on a hype train, I jumped ship. I'm really happy with my solution, and I'd love to hear your thoughts as well <del>as soon as I set up webcomments</del>.</p> </section></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://figbert.com/posts/how-to-replace-keybase-in-three-easy-steps</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23728832</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:15:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
