<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 20]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 20. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 12:24:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-20.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 12:24:44 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Golang Desktop App with Webview/Lorca, WASM and Bazel]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 74 | Comments 45 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24117758">thread link</a>) | @grahar64
<br/>
August 10, 2020 | https://maori.geek.nz/golang-desktop-app-with-webview-lorca-wasm-and-bazel-3283813bf89 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://maori.geek.nz/golang-desktop-app-with-webview-lorca-wasm-and-bazel-3283813bf89">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section><div><div><div><div><div><div><p><a href="https://maori.geek.nz/@GrahamJenson?source=post_page-----3283813bf89----------------------" rel="noopener"><img alt="Graham Jenson" src="https://miro.medium.com/fit/c/96/96/0*1bdqD2hM_lzBk_GT.jpeg" width="48" height="48"></a></p></div></div></div></div><p id="0ce9">On my quest towards building a GoLang Desktop application I found some useful frameworks, <a href="https://github.com/zserge/lorca" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lorca</a> and <a href="https://github.com/webview/webview" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Webview</a> (which I wrote about in <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://maori.geek.nz/golang-desktop-app-webview-vs-lorca-vs-electron-a5e6b2869391">my previous post</a>). These frameworks create a window which GoLang can inject HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to build the UI.</p><p id="c60c">But I don’t want to write JavaScript(!) and deal with all the complexities that comes with it like npm, webpack, typescript… Fortunately, I can just compile GoLang to <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/WebAssembly" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WebAssembly</a> (WASM) and use that in place of JavaScript. WASM is a binary format that can be executed natively in <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/WebAssembly" target="_blank" rel="noopener">most modern browsers</a>. <em>My </em><a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://maori.geek.nz/a-web-app-using-bazel-golang-wasm-and-proto-c020914f4341"><em>previous post</em></a><em> showed how to build a WASM web-app with the Bazel.</em></p><p id="14af">Also, using WASM in a desktop app (as opposed to a web app) dodges two of its main downsides:</p><ol><li id="a01f"><strong>Large WASM binaries</strong> (especially from GoLang): these take a long time to send over the network increasing loading times. In a desktop app the binary isn’t transferred over the network, so less overhead.</li><li id="c65b"><strong>Browser incompatibility: </strong>Some WebAssembly methods are unavailable in browsers and older browsers are not supported at all. In a desktop app the “browser” is controlled (Chrome for Lorca and Safari for webview), so no compatibility issues.</li></ol><p id="382a">Let’s get started and build the app.</p><h2 id="ad5c">The Main Desktop App</h2><p id="04fb">First, I want to sketch out the <code>main</code> function for the app:</p><pre><span id="49df">func main() {<br> // Create the Data URI of index.html<br> url := fmt.Sprintf(<br>  "data:text/html,%s", <br>  url.PathEscape(assets.INDEX_HTML)<br> )</span><span id="6f7e"> // Create Lorca UI<br> ui, _ := lorca.New(url, "", 600, 200)<br> defer ui.Close()</span><span id="7141"> // Create a JS function that returns the WASM binary in base64 <br> ui.Bind("getWASM", func() string { return assets.WASM_BIN })</span><span id="4a42"> // Initialize the wasm_exec.js script<br> ui.Eval(assets.WASM_EXEC_JS)</span><span id="77ea"> // Call the initial JS functions to load the WASM<br> ui.Eval(assets.INIT_JS)</span><span id="cbed"> &lt;-ui.Done()<br>}</span></pre><p id="6eb4"><em>Note: the core difference between with webview, is using </em><code><em>Init</em></code><em> instead of </em><code><em>Eval</em></code></p><p id="062d">This app will start a Chrome window then:</p><ol><li id="9913">load the webpage with HTML <code>assets.INDEX_HTML</code></li><li id="79c2">define a function <code>getWASM</code> that is a promise of <code>assets.WASM_BIN</code>, the WASM binary as a base64 encoded string</li><li id="c64f">load the JS GoLang WASM library <code>assets.WASM_EXEC_JS</code> copied from <code>$(go env <strong>GOROOT</strong>)/misc/wasm/wasm_exec.js</code></li><li id="7f2e">load the JS initialization script <code>assets.INIT_JS</code></li></ol><figure><div><div><div><p><img alt="Image for post" src="https://miro.medium.com/max/1676/1*tezB3wIacBS6kH32xAxeqw.png" width="838" height="287" srcset="https://miro.medium.com/max/552/1*tezB3wIacBS6kH32xAxeqw.png 276w, https://miro.medium.com/max/1104/1*tezB3wIacBS6kH32xAxeqw.png 552w, https://miro.medium.com/max/1280/1*tezB3wIacBS6kH32xAxeqw.png 640w, https://miro.medium.com/max/1400/1*tezB3wIacBS6kH32xAxeqw.png 700w" sizes="700px" data-old-src="https://miro.medium.com/max/60/1*tezB3wIacBS6kH32xAxeqw.png?q=20"></p></div></div></div></figure><p id="ce8d">This is pretty simple example Lorca app, it is basically the demo example. The main complication is the <code>assets</code> package and how it can be created. This is where Bazel comes in.</p><h2 id="74f4">Embedding Files in GoLang Binary using Bazel</h2><p id="8571"><em>Note: an easier way to do this was pointed out to me using the </em><code><a href="https://github.com/bazelbuild/rules_go/blob/fbbbfde2dff5072fe118b369a699d456ec756b0c/go/extras.rst#id3" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>go_embed_data</em></a></code><em> rule, better to use that.</em></p><p id="9249">The <code>assets</code> package contains the HTML, JS and WASM files as string constants. There are GoLang tools like <a href="https://github.com/markbates/pkger" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pkger</a> or <a href="https://github.com/go-bindata/go-bindata" target="_blank" rel="noopener">go-bindata</a> to do this, but we can keep this simple with a Bazel rule in <code>to_go_constant.bzl</code>:</p><pre><span id="aace">def to_go_constant(name, package, constant, file, base64 = False):<br> pkgStr = '&lt;(echo "package %s")' % package<br> conStr = '&lt;(echo "const %s string = \`")' % constant<br> suffix = '&lt;(echo "\`")'<br> genGo = 'cat %s %s - %s ' % (pkgStr, conStr, suffix)</span><span id="56aa">if base64:<br>  printContents = 'cat $(SRCS) | base64'<br> else:<br>  printContents = 'cat $(SRCS)'</span><span id="8c11">native.genrule(<br>  name = name,<br>  srcs = [file],<br>  outs = [name + ".go"],<br>  cmd =  printContents + ' | ' + genGo + '&gt; $@'<br> )</span></pre><p id="e3d4">This rule uses <code>cat</code> to take a <code>file</code> and output a <code>.go</code> file with the <code>package</code> and <code>const</code> defined. If <code>base64=True</code> then the file is base64 encoded.</p><p id="2176">An example of this rule in action is adding the <code>assets.INDEX_HTML</code> built from the file <code>index.html</code>:</p><pre><span id="90f6">load("//:to_go_constant.bzl", "to_go_constant")</span><span id="fba4">to_go_constant(<br>    name = "index",<br>    constant = "INDEX_HTML",<br>    file = ":index.html",<br>    package = "assets",<br>)</span></pre><p id="16e5">This takes the <code>index.html </code>file:</p><pre><span id="5a54">&lt;html&gt;<br>&lt;body&gt;<br> &lt;!-- add stuff here --&gt;<br>&lt;/body&gt;<br>&lt;/html&gt;</span></pre><p id="4a53">and creates the <code>index.go</code> file:</p><pre><span id="e546">package assets<br>const INDEX_HTML string = `&lt;html&gt;<br>&lt;body&gt;<br> &lt;!-- add stuff here --&gt;<br>&lt;/body&gt;<br>&lt;/html&gt;`</span></pre><p id="8cd7"><code>index.go</code> can be added to the <code>go_library</code> rule for the <code>assets</code> package:</p><pre><span id="f437">go_library(<br>    name = "go_default_library",<br>    srcs = [<br>        "assets.go",<br>        ":index.go",  # keep<br>    ],<br>    importpath = "github.com/.../assets",<br>)</span></pre><p id="1cbf">Now the <code>INDEX_HTML</code> constant is in the assets package.</p><p id="4aa6">It is straight forward for most the other files, but a bit more complicated for the WASM binary data:</p><pre><span id="758f">to_go_constant(<br>    name = "wasmbin",<br>    base64 = True,<br>    constant = "WASM_BIN",<br>    file = "//project/wasm",<br>    package = "assets",<br>)</span></pre><p id="cc54">The file <code>//project/wasm</code> refers to the generated <code>go_binary</code> rule that compiles the WASM (as described below). <code>base64</code> is also <code>True</code> so that the binary data can be encoded as a constant.</p><p id="6b53"><em>Note: There is one minor issue is the </em><code><em>wasm_exec.js</em></code><em> file, it has a few </em><code><em>`</em></code><em>’s in it that must be replaced.</em></p><h2 id="dede">The WASM part</h2><p id="406c">The WASM binary is the client-side GoLang application running in the browser. This example injects a <code>Hello World</code> <code>&lt;p&gt;</code> tag into the body:</p><pre><span id="a864">package main</span><span id="bd53">import (<br> "fmt"<br> "syscall/js"<br>)</span><span id="8acd">func main() {<br> fmt.Println("Hello World")</span><span id="b814"> document := js.Global().Get("document")<br> p := document.Call("createElement", "p")<br> p.Set("innerHTML", "Hello World")<br> document.Get("body").Call("appendChild", p)<br>}</span></pre><p id="7de3">The <code>go_binary</code> rule for this just needs <code>goos="js"</code> and <code>goarch="wasm"</code> for its output to be a WASM binary, e.g.:</p><pre><span id="d208">go_binary(<br>    name = "wasm",<br>    embed = [":go_default_library"],<br>    goarch = "wasm",<br>    goos = "js",<br>    visibility = ["//visibility:public"],<br>)</span></pre><p id="f178">The output of this rule is used to above to create the <code>WASM_BIN</code> constant above.</p><h2 id="71cd">Initializing the App</h2><p id="8bd2"><code>assets.INIT_JS</code> is built from <code>init.js:</code></p><pre><span id="7b05">loadWebASM = () =&gt; {<br> const go = new Go();<br> getWASM().then( (b64) =&gt; {<br>   // Decode and convert to ArrayBuffer<br>   buf = Uint8Array.from(atob(b64), c =&gt; c.charCodeAt(0)).buffer<br>   return WebAssembly.instantiate(buf, go.importObject)<br> }).then((result) =&gt; {<br>    go.run(result.instance);<br>  }).catch((err) =&gt; {<br>    console.error("loading wasm failed: " + err);<br>  });<br>}</span><span id="e6cf">loadWebASM()</span></pre><p id="c227">This code takes the <code>WASM_BIN</code> promised by <code>getWASM</code>, then decodes and converts it to an ArrayBuffer. This buffer is passed to the <code><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Global_Objects/WebAssembly/instantiate" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WebAssembly.instantiate</a></code> function that compiles and initializes the application to an <code>instance</code>, which is then <code>go.run</code>. <strong>This is the only JavaScript needed.</strong></p><h2 id="1f97">Pure GoLang Desktop App</h2><p id="29e8">The above code is all that is needed to now write pure(-ish) GoLang desktop applications. This also makes it easy to convert other WASM apps to desktop applications, e.g. I converted the WASM app at <a href="https://github.com/olivewind/go-webassembly-canvas" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://github.com/olivewind/go-webassembly-canvas</a> to a desktop application with minimal effort:</p><figure><div><div><p><img alt="Image for post" src="https://miro.medium.com/max/998/1*SR_WdfWLKkNX_nFAEc2Kdw.png" width="499" height="502" srcset="https://miro.medium.com/max/552/1*SR_WdfWLKkNX_nFAEc2Kdw.png 276w, https://miro.medium.com/max/998/1*SR_WdfWLKkNX_nFAEc2Kdw.png 499w" sizes="499px" data-old-src="https://miro.medium.com/max/60/1*SR_WdfWLKkNX_nFAEc2Kdw.png?q=20"></p></div></div></figure><h2 id="5c7c">Conclusion</h2><p id="80dd">There are many libraries and tools written in GoLang that could use a nice user interface, e.g. <a href="https://www.terraform.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">terraform</a> and <a href="https://www.docker.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">docker</a> (just off the top of my head). A web app does not fit their requirements very well since they are editing local files and talking to local daemons. The alternative is then to reimplement or bind their API and integrations to another language which is complicated, error prone and a lot of work. A method of building pure GoLang desktop applications makes a lot of sense for these kinds of tools.</p><p id="93db">This approach can pretty quickly create a distributable, single executable, desktop application with minimal external dependencies. An app that can reuse many GoLang libraries and tools that have already been built. I suppose the worst part of this approach is that it throws away years of development on JavaScript tools like React and Vue. But that just means I have to write more Go to reimplement them, so it isn’t that bad :)</p></div></div></section></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://maori.geek.nz/golang-desktop-app-with-webview-lorca-wasm-and-bazel-3283813bf89</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24117758</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 06:41:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Wiltshire valley locals build their own mobile phone network]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 117 | Comments 26 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24111002">thread link</a>) | @ColinWright
<br/>
August 10, 2020 | https://www.newscabal.co.uk/wiltshire-valley-locals-build-their-own-mobile-phone-network/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.newscabal.co.uk/wiltshire-valley-locals-build-their-own-mobile-phone-network/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>The village hall in Bowerchalke is an unlikely setting for a mobile technology revolution. Yet local residents, surrounded by crocheted goods and local jams, have spent three years forging a mobile phone network to bridge their own “digital divide”. </p>
 <!-- A generated by theme --> 



 <!-- end A --> 


<p>The experimental Ch4lke Mobile, which runs over just five masts, can connect homes to a network capable of delivering broadband-like speeds, in an area that had been left behind by the digital revolution.</p>
<p>The fledgling network has just secured part of a £2.25m government grant to fill in England’s largest “not-spot” — an area with no mobile signal — and could offer a solution to other pockets in the country blighted by a lack of coverage.</p>
<p>The village sits in the picturesque Chalke valley in Wiltshire little more than 10 miles south of the world-famous Stonehenge. It is known for its high quality watercress and a number of celebrity residents, including film director Guy Ritchie and TV presenter <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/c72387ca-31aa-11ea-a329-0bcf87a328f2" data-trackable="link">James May</a>. </p>
<p>But perhaps more fortunately for its inhabitants, the village also boasts a small group of residents with technology backgrounds. </p>
<p>Ed Gairdner, who used to work with tech start ups in Silicon Valley, moved to the Chalke Valley from Hampshire four years ago and became frustrated at the paucity of coverage. “We looked at the coverage maps in Carphone Warehouse before buying phones. We tried to do our due diligence — but there is no coverage here,” he said.</p>
<figure><figcaption>
							The Ch4lke Mobile base station © Stuart Berman<br>
						</figcaption></figure>
<p>According to tests performed by network measurement company GWS signals are weak to non-existent in the valley. There is even a divide within the ‘digital divide’ as some residents with houses high on the downs get a signal while others have no coverage at all. “It became a non-discussion subject in the pub as it would start too many arguments,” said James Body, chair of the parish council.</p>
<p>Mr Body was unusually well placed when villagers began to complain to him about the lack of coverage. As a former officer in the British army’s Royal Signals, he spent a career in the military building networks and then went on to work in telecoms in the private sector.</p>
<p>Bowerchalke lies just a few miles west of the cathedral city of Salisbury, which now has one of the <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/cdf430ba-499f-11ea-aeb3-955839e06441" data-trackable="link">fastest broadband networks in the country</a>. But the steep, narrow Chalke valley has cut it off from the wireless revolution after an earlier government project failed to deliver five large mobile towers.</p>
<p>Despite few wanting the giant metallic structures, locals were angry at having no coverage. For Sue Lee, who runs a B&amp;B next to the village hall, the lack of connectivity has cost her business.</p>
<p>She describes various visitors abruptly leaving without paying after finding there was no mobile reception. She decided to harangue Mr Body. “Isn’t there anything we can do? It is ridiculous,” she recalled asking him. </p>
<p>Since then, Mr Body has spent three years working with the community to develop a test network that operates off small antennas attached to the chimneys of thatched cottages.</p>
<p>Inspired by an earlier initiative to set up a rural broadband network in Lancashire in north-west England called <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/32f013fc-91e1-11e9-aea1-2b1d33ac3271" data-trackable="link">B4rn</a>, the new mobile network relies on the willingness of the community to solve the problem themselves rather than wait for the government or the industry to sort it out.</p>
<p>This also helps to lower costs as there is no rental or paperwork. The small base stations, that house the antennas, are also less of an eyesore than a mobile tower. The company compares its array of small cells to fairy lights reaching “every nook and cranny” of the valley. </p>
<figure><figcaption>
							James Body, chair of the parish council, is a former engineer in the British army’s Royal Signals © Stuart Berman<br>
						</figcaption></figure>
<p>The government funding for Ch4lke will allow the network to move from the experimental phase — where it is still encountering gremlins such as the text messages it occasionally spits out welcoming people to Jersey — to a fully fledged system capable of delivering 5G speeds.</p>
<p>The small base stations are put up by the local TV installer: Mr Body’s house and the village hall already have one and with the funding in place the aim is to build the network out with about 50 across the valley.</p>
<p>The tiny network is pioneering with its use of a so-called neutral host network, which taps into unused spectrum — the frequencies that carry mobile signals — to interconnect with the large UK players — Vodafone, EE, O2 and Three.</p>
<p>Ch4lke Mobile, which is community owned, is using British-made hardware and software from a small Cambridge company called CellXica. The company is also working with O2 on a small trial at a Surrey train station but believes the ingenuity of the rural solution shows that British technology can play a bigger role in a UK market set to phase out radio equipment from China’s Huawei, the largest supplier.</p>
<figure><figcaption>
							The antenna on Bowerchalke village hall © Stuart Berman<br>
						</figcaption></figure>
<p>Ch4lke could offer a solution for other communities affected by not-spots in areas that the government-backed <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/cd83abc8-f70c-11e9-a79c-bc9acae3b654" data-trackable="link">Shared Rural Network</a> programme, launched earlier this year to fill in most of the rural areas with poor coverage, won’t reach. “I’d love to have our radios in every not spot in the country now we have proved this is working,” said Ant Timpson of CellXica.</p>
<p>However getting the large telecoms on-side remains a key part of the process. The government backing for this scheme will help its cause. For John Glen, the local MP, the initiative is an example of a community banding together finding a solution to a debilitating problem where the government and industry has failed. </p>
<p>“You need to think laterally. You can’t conceive of this in Whitehall,” he said, sitting in the village hall. “This will be transformative for social cohesion. Everyone needs to benefit from the B&amp;B owner to the tech entrepreneur to the 85 year old,” he said.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.newscabal.co.uk/wiltshire-valley-locals-build-their-own-mobile-phone-network/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24111002</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:27:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Wiki Bankruptcy]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 160 | Comments 135 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24109726">thread link</a>) | @mcrittenden
<br/>
August 10, 2020 | https://critter.blog/2020/08/10/wiki-bankruptcy/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://critter.blog/2020/08/10/wiki-bankruptcy/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-content" role="main">

	
<article id="post-585">

	
<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>

		<div>

			
<p><em>Update: this generated a pretty good <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24109726">Hacker News discussion</a>.</em></p>



<p>Does your company have a wiki? If you had to guess, what percentage of that wiki would you say is:</p>



<ul><li>Up to date</li><li>Still relevant</li><li>Viewed at least once per year by someone</li></ul>



<p>I’m going to take a wild guess that your answer is somewhere below 25%. If so, you’re saying that over 75% of your company’s wiki is either irrelevant, unused, or downright incorrect. In other words, the vast majority of your company’s wiki is at best not useful, and is at worst actively harmful if it’s giving people incorrect information. </p>



<p>This is called Wiki Rot. It’s spreading in companies worldwide, and it must be stopped. </p>



<p>What if you had to start over? What if, once a year, everything in your company’s wiki was deleted? Call it Wiki Bankruptcy. Here’s how it could go down:</p>



<ol><li>Tell everyone at your company that in 2 weeks, all wiki contents will be deleted. Let everyone take those 2 weeks to copy/back up/download any pages they want to keep.</li><li>After those 2 weeks end, you back up and delete everything in the wiki.</li><li>Tell everyone that they can now resume creating wiki pages, and are free to recreate the pages they thought were important.</li><li>For all of the people who realize they need stuff that they didn’t think about copying in step 1, allow them to access it from your back up from step 2. But do not allow linking directly to pages in that back up, or else you run the risk of people just continuing to read the backed up wiki pages.</li><li>Repeat after 1 year.</li></ol>



<p>Yes, it’s a huge pain, and there will be a couple weeks where everyone is grumpy about it. But Wiki Bankruptcy is the price we must pay to kill Wiki Rot. Wiki Bankruptcy ensures that the vast majority of your wiki will be up to date and relevant, and it’s a sure-fire way to clear out all the cruft nobody is ever looking at anymore.</p>



<p>Now, let’s hear all the reasons why you hate it. <a href="https://twitter.com/mcrittenden">Tweet me about it</a>!</p>

		</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	</div><!-- .post-inner -->

	<!-- .section-inner -->

	
	<!-- .pagination-single -->

	
</article><!-- .post -->

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://critter.blog/2020/08/10/wiki-bankruptcy/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24109726</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 14:39:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[If it's a nice problem to have, don't solve it now]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 131 | Comments 64 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24109636">thread link</a>) | @davnicwil
<br/>
August 10, 2020 | https://davnicwil.com/if-its-a-nice-problem-to-have-dont-solve-it-now | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://davnicwil.com/if-its-a-nice-problem-to-have-dont-solve-it-now">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-reactid="40"><div data-reactid="41"><div data-reactid="42"><p data-reactid="44">When building a product from scratch you need to do a lot of hard things all at once, with limited resources. The standard advice is to take an iterative approach, prioritising things and then cycling quickly through them, finding solutions just good enough to move things forwards before moving onto the next thing.</p><p data-reactid="45">It's good advice, but hard to follow in practice. Often when you explore solutions to a problem, even simple ones, the problem reveals itself to be more complex than you'd anticipated. You find sub-problems, and tangental problems, which look just as important as the original. It's easy to go off track and end up deep into the problem you were supposed to just find a quick solution to. After all, it's just one more thing, you're thinking about it, and you'll have to solve it at some point anyway. Why not now?</p><p data-reactid="46">I've made this mistake a lot. I'm trying to get better at being strict about saying "not now" to new problems that I discover in the middle of an iteration, and avoid getting sidetracked from shipping by working on things that can be left for later. I'd like to share a tactic I use to do this that has worked well for me. It's to ask a simple question about each new problem I encounter: "From my perspective right now, is this a nice problem to have?". If yes, I skip it. If no, I work on it immediately.</p><p data-reactid="48">An example to illustrate is signup functionality. Let's say I'm starting on a new product. Without signup, there's no possibility of getting any users, which is a problem. From my perspective right now, is this a nice problem to have? No - I have zero users right now, and can't get any until signup is done. The only way to move forwards is to build signup.</p><p data-reactid="49">Whilst I'm building signup, I realise that I probably also need reset password functionality. If a user signs up, but then forgets their password, that's a problem. But from my perspective right now, is this a nice problem to have? Actually, yes! I have zero users, but having this problem implies I would have users, which would be great. Reset password functionality is important, and will absolutely be required eventually, but I can do it later. First, I should ship anything that's stopping me from getting users in the first place.</p><p data-reactid="51">There are always tiers of functionality which build upon one another, and this simple question provides a neat hack to sort things in order of when they'll actually be useful so you can build and ship that functionality in faster iterations, rather than delaying shipping while you batch and build everything up front. Try it out when you next build something.</p></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://davnicwil.com/if-its-a-nice-problem-to-have-dont-solve-it-now</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24109636</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 14:30:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[C will never stop you from making mistakes]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 210 | Comments 202 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24108109">thread link</a>) | @ingve
<br/>
August 10, 2020 | https://thephd.github.io/your-c-compiler-and-standard-library-will-not-help-you | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thephd.github.io/your-c-compiler-and-standard-library-will-not-help-you">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
  
      <p>Short answer: because we said so.<!--more--></p>

<p>:)</p>



<p>Alright, fine, that’s too short to make it an article, dear reader, and my inflammatory words demand an explanation.</p>

<p>The C Committee meeting – originally scheduled for Freiburg, Germany but not happening there because <em>(* vague gesturing towards outside *)</em> – concluded Friday, August 7th. It went pretty well, with us making good progress on all fronts. Yes, we make real progress; I promise we do, and this is not a dead language.</p>

<p>As a side note I’ve also become the Project Editor for C so before you take this as an uninformed rant of a person too lazy to “make things better”, let me assure that I am, indeed, incredibly invested in making sure C can begin to meet the needs of developers without needing 50 vendor-specific extensions to build remotely nice/usable libraries and applications.</p>

<p>Still, I made a claim (the C Language will never stop you from making mistakes), and therefore I need to substantiate it. We could look at the thousands of CVEs and the inherent issues with tons of C Code, or the need for MISRA to vigorously police every last little potential C feature to prevent misuse (<a href="https://twitter.com/thephantomderp/status/1290824683399663616">hello, K&amp;R prototype declarations</a>…), or other more intricate and fun bugs related to portability and undefined behavior. But instead, we are just going to take the words from the horse’s mouth: the Committee itself.</p>



<p>No, dear reader, put the popcorn away. As with all ISO proceedings, I am not allowed to quote anyone verbatim, and this is not a name-and-shame article. It will, however, explain why things that we can easily diagnose and identify as bad behavior in standards-conforming ISO C will never go away. And we will start with a paper by Dr. Philipp Klaus Krause:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.open-std.org/jtc1/sc22/wg14/www/docs/n2526.htm">N2526, use const for data from the library that shall not be modified</a>.</p>

<p>N2526 is a very simple paper. “Some data returned by the library is <code>const</code> morally, spiritually, and in fact even by its implementation. It’s undefined behavior and wrong to write into it, so let’s stop teasing each other about it and put a ring on that finger bad boy!” … Okay, that’s not exactly what it says, but I’m sure the idea makes sense to you, dear reader. Originally, when the vote for this paper was taken, there was almost no votes against the paper. Then, a few people voiced their <em>strong</em> objections to the paper because it breaks old code. And, well, of course that’s bad: even my breath caught and I strained to think about this – adding <code>const</code>? C has no ABI that could be affected by this, C (their implementations) doesn’t even respect qualifiers, how are we breaking things?! So, let’s talk about why this would be a breaking change in the eyes of certain folk.</p>



<p>Or, as I like to call it, “The Type Safety Is For Losers Language”. Of course, that’s a mouthful, so “C” will have to do. You may be wondering why I would call a language like C as having no type safety. After all,</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>struct</span> <span>Meow</span> <span>{</span>
	<span>int</span> <span>a</span><span>;</span>
<span>};</span>

<span>struct</span> <span>Bark</span> <span>{</span>
	<span>double</span> <span>b</span><span>;</span>
	<span>void</span><span>*</span> <span>c</span><span>;</span>
<span>};</span>

<span>int</span> <span>main</span> <span>(</span><span>int</span> <span>argc</span><span>,</span> <span>char</span><span>*</span> <span>argv</span><span>[])</span> <span>{</span>
	<span>(</span><span>void</span><span>)</span><span>argc</span><span>;</span>
	<span>(</span><span>void</span><span>)</span><span>argv</span><span>;</span>

	<span>struct</span> <span>Meow</span> <span>cat</span><span>;</span>
	<span>struct</span> <span>Bark</span> <span>dog</span> <span>=</span> <span>cat</span><span>;</span>
	<span>// error: initializing 'struct Bark' with an expression of incompatible type 'struct Meow'</span>

	<span>return</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>I mean, let’s be honest: that looks like strong type safety to me, Jim! Of course, it only gets spicier from here:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>#include &lt;stdlib.h&gt;
</span>
<span>struct</span> <span>Meow</span> <span>{</span>
	<span>int</span> <span>a</span><span>;</span>
<span>};</span>

<span>struct</span> <span>Bark</span> <span>{</span>
	<span>double</span> <span>b</span><span>;</span>
	<span>void</span><span>*</span> <span>c</span><span>;</span>
<span>};</span>

<span>int</span> <span>main</span> <span>(</span><span>int</span> <span>argc</span><span>,</span> <span>char</span><span>*</span> <span>argv</span><span>[])</span> <span>{</span>
	<span>(</span><span>void</span><span>)</span><span>argc</span><span>;</span>
	<span>(</span><span>void</span><span>)</span><span>argv</span><span>;</span>

	<span>struct</span> <span>Meow</span><span>*</span> <span>p_cat</span> <span>=</span> <span>(</span><span>struct</span> <span>Meow</span><span>*</span><span>)</span><span>malloc</span><span>(</span><span>sizeof</span><span>(</span><span>struct</span> <span>Meow</span><span>));</span>
	<span>struct</span> <span>Bark</span><span>*</span> <span>p_dog</span> <span>=</span> <span>p_cat</span><span>;</span>
	<span>// :3</span>
	
	<span>return</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>f̵̞͟͞o̷r̰͇͎̞ ̡̝͍͍̥̗̖͖̲̮i͕͔̭̹̪̳͙͍̩ͅ ̷͖̙͈̗̯̙͓̲̻̩̱͖̺a̧̪̳̠̰̱͎̖̙̳̱͎̯̦̟͟m̶͓͔͉̺̩̙̖̞̼͈̖͇͇͇ ͇̘̬͕̯̕͢d͚o̢̳̱̙͠ͅg̴̨̦̬̥͓̯̩͞,̷̬͕͖͎̺͈̰̳̮͓̞ ͚d͎̀̕͢es̵̱͙̪͓͖͇̩̳̻͉͉̹̣͈͜͝t͖͈͉̩̭̙̺̬r̤̟̫͔̩̰̗̤͔̭̰̞̦̺ͅo̝̹̻ͅy̸͎͎͚̖̤̣̥̭̼̳͎e̘̟̰̣̫̹͇͍̦͓ͅr̙̙̳̠͔̙̖̯̺ͅ ̸̜̫̫̩̫̝͎̩̠̦̭̠̟o҉̛͢f̫̝͇ ҉̣̞̟a̪̲͎͇̣̠͖͖̮̥ͅl̷̛͈̦̰̜͍̲̟̬̘̝͕̰̮͠l̮̯̘͉̦͔̘̲̰̤͔̬̲͔</p>

<p>
Yes, two entirely unrelated pointer types can be set to one another in standards-conforming C. Most compilers warn, but it is standards-conforming to accept this code unless you crank up the <code>-Werror</code> <code>-Wall</code> <code>-Wpedantic</code> etc. etc. etc.</p>

<p>In fact, other pointer-related things the compiler can accept without an explicit cast are:</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>volatile</code> (who needs those semantics anyways?!)</li>
  <li><code>const</code> (write into all the read-only data you like!)</li>
  <li><code>_Atomic</code> (thread safety, shred shmafety!)</li>
</ul>

<p>Now, note I am not arguing that you should not be able to do these things at all. But when you’re working in C – wherein it is very easy to get yourself a 500, 1000-line function alongside variable names that do not describe WTF they are for – the Hard Facts™ is that you work primarily with pointers, and you lack any amount of safety at all insofar as the Core Language cares. (NOTE: It <strong>is</strong> a constraint violation, but there’s so much legacy code that every implementation ignores qualifiers anyhow, so your code won’t ever <em>stop</em> compiling because of this (<a href="https://twitter.com/fanf/status/1292826424345337868">thanks, @fanf!</a>)!) Every potential failure here is diagnosable – easily so – with a compiler, and they all warn, but they will never require you to cast to communicate to the compiler that you Seriously, Really Meant It. It also means – much more importantly – that the human beings who come after you will have no bloody idea if you meant to do this, either.</p>

<p>All someone has to do is strip the build of <code>-Werror</code> <code>-Wall</code> <code>-Wpedantic</code> and you’ll be off to the races in committing multithreading, read-only, and hardware register crimes.</p>

<p>Now, this is fair, right? If someone strips off all of these warning/error flags, they obviously do not care about whatever faux pas or silly gaffe you’ve committed. Which means that, at the end of the day, these warnings are ultimately irrelevant and harmless as far as standards-conforming, ISO C is concerned. And yet…</p>



<p>Yes.</p>

<p>This is a special kind of hell that C developers have grown comfortable with, and to a lesser extent C++ developers. Warnings are seen as annoyances; and, as is shown by ever turning on <code>-Weverything</code> or <code>/W4</code>, they very well are. Shadowing warnings from variables in the global namespace (thanks, every header and C library ever is now a problem), using “reserved” names (as the kids say, “<a href="https://wg14.link/n2493">lol nice one xd!!</a>”), and “this struct has padding because you used <code>alignof</code>” (… yes, yes I know it has padding, I explicitly asked it to increase my padding BECAUSE I USED <code>alignof</code> MR. COMPILER) are all incredibly time-wasting.</p>

<p>But they are warnings.</p>

<p>Even if they are annoying, they prevent problems. The fact that I can blithely <a href="https://godbolt.org/z/rEbPvd">ignore all qualifiers and dumpster all forms of read, write, thread, and read-only safety</a> is a serious issue when it comes to communicating intent and preventing bugs. Even the old K&amp;R syntax produced bugs in industrial and government codebases because users did the wrong thing. This is not because they are shit programmers: it’s because they are straddling codebases sometimes older than they are and gearing up to ride on a multi-million line technical liability. You cannot keep the entirety of the codebase in your head: this is what conventions, static analysis, high warning levels, and everything are supposed to combat. Unfortunately,</p>

<p>everyone likes to have Warning Free code.</p>

<p>This means that the moment a GCC developer makes a warning more sensitive to potential problematic cases, maintainers (not the original developers) will suddenly get hefty several-gigabyte logs containing all the newest vomit of warnings and other things from their old code. “This is stupid”, they say, “the code has been running for Y E A R S, why is GCC complaining now?”. This means that even doing something like adding <code>const</code> to a function signature, even if it is morally, spiritually, and factually the right thing to do, is avoided. “Breaking” people is “they now have to look at code which has questionable intentions”. This is code that would – on pain of Undefined Behavior – crash your chip or <a href="https://twitter.com/MalwareMinigun/status/1260061878614556684">corrupt your memory</a>. But that’s the other problem with being a C developer in today’s ecosystem, really.</p>

<h3 id="age-as-a-measure-of-quality">Age as a Measure of Quality</h3>

<p>How many people would have ever guessed <code>sudo</code> had a vulnerability as jaw-droppingly simple as “-1 or integer overflow gives you access to everything”? How many people thought Heartbleed would be a real problem? How many game developers are shipping stb’s “tiny” libraries without ever having run a fuzzer on them and realizing they contain more significant exploitable input vulnerabilities than they could imagine? This is not a dig at any of these pieces of code or the programmers behind them: they are providing a vital service that the world has depended on for decades, often with little to no support from anyone until a big problem exploded. But, the people worshipping and deploying these pieces of code end up fermenting a toxic adage under the auspice of survivorship bias:</p>

<p>“This code is so old and used by so many, how could it possibly have problems?”</p>

<p>By holding backwards compatibility and “not being a bother” as the highest ideals for C code, people who survive long enough in the industry begin to equate age with quality, as if codebases were barrels of wine in a cellar. The older and longer the code is used, the finer and more delectable the wine.</p>

<p>The reality is, unfortunately, far less romantic and cute: crawling with more bugs than you can shake a stick at, security vulnerabilities by the basketful, these technical liabilities only grow more risky with each passing day. Each system evolves into a half-alive, unaddressed, and partially-unmaintained rotting husk. They are gussied up and given the veneer of nobility and greatness when it is in fact an embalmed corpse, just waiting to be poked the wrong way before its festering, antediluvian pustules burst and fill your application with its finely aged botulism.</p>

<h3 id="okay-gross-but-like-what-about-the-c-standard">Okay… Gross, but like what about the C Standard?</h3>

<p>The problem I have noticed in my (incredibly short) tenure as a member is that we prefer backwards compatibility over all else, attributing old applications and their use cases over any chance at improving the safety, …</p></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://thephd.github.io/your-c-compiler-and-standard-library-will-not-help-you">https://thephd.github.io/your-c-compiler-and-standard-library-will-not-help-you</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thephd.github.io/your-c-compiler-and-standard-library-will-not-help-you</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24108109</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 11:32:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[One-Page Chess [video]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 47 | Comments 23 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24107984">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
August 10, 2020 | https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/post/110651/technical-tuesdays-follow-up-one-page-chess-done-for-now | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/post/110651/technical-tuesdays-follow-up-one-page-chess-done-for-now">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <div>
        <header>
            <p><a href="https://locals.com/" target="_blank" title="locals.com">
                    <img src="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/images/locals-logo-transparent.svg" alt="locals logo">
                </a>
            </p>
            <div>
                <div>
                    <p><a href="https://locals.com/" target="_blank" title="locals.com">
                        <img src="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/images/locals-logo-transparent.svg" alt="locals logo">
                    </a></p>
                    
                </div>
            </div>
            <div>
                <div>
                    <p><a href="https://locals.com/" target="_blank" title="locals.com">
                        <img src="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/images/locals-logo-transparent.svg" alt="locals logo">
                    </a></p>
                    
                </div>
            </div>
        </header>
        <section>
            
            <div>
                <div>
                    <div>
                        <p><span>
                            Shared post from
                        </span></p><p>
                            DanielBMarkham <br>
                            Community
                        </p>
                    </div>
                    <p><img src="https://cdn.rubinreport.com/images/avatars/92269/92269_xsgujuxuwvuchvt_thumb.jpeg" alt="community logo">
                    </p>
                </div>
                <article>
                    

<div>
    




    <div>
        <div>
                    <p>
                Technical Tuesdays (follow-up). One-Page Chess: Done For Now            </p>
                    <div>
                 <p>I've taken my Static Single Page Application to the next logical stopping point. Should I write a complete chess engine? How important is it to know when to stop coding? Here's a video walk-thru of the reasons for and design of the application.</p>
<p>Note: Dropbox was not working on my studio laptop, so the page I am demo'ing is actually a very old one. This is why a few errors come up during the demo. The repo master branch does not have these errors.</p>            </div>
                    </div>

            </div>


    
    



    <ul>
            </ul>

        
    
    


    
</div>



                    
                </article>
                <div><p>
                    Connect with DanielBMarkham and other
                    members of DanielBMarkham community.

                    </p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </section>
            <section>
            <h5>
                See what else the community is up to...
            </h5>
            <div>
                

<div>
    

<div>
    <div>
        <p><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/member/DanielBMarkham">
                <span>
                    <span>
                        <img src="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/images/creator-label.svg?v=0.01" alt="" title="">                    </span>
                </span>
        </a></p>
    </div>
    
</div>


    <div>
        <div>
                    <div>
                 <p>Wayback Wednesdays: Richelieu</p>
<p>On this day in 1624, Cardinal Armand Jean du Plessis, Duke of Richelieu (known simply as "Richelieu" ) was made president of the council of ministers of France</p>
<p>When I say "France", I mean something as we know it today, but back then it was anything but a country. There were severe internal differences, each little fiefdom had it's own lord, and national control was a rare if non-existent thing. The old joke is that the phrase "Holy Roman Empire" was wrong on all counts: It wasn't holy, it wasn't Roman, and it wasn't an Empire.</p>
<p>After the Western Roman Empire slowly disintegrated into little kingdoms, the people in the west still thought of themselves as Romans. Why wouldn't they? In fact, if you look at some very modern terms for leader, like "Tsar" and "Keiser", they're just different ways of saying Caesar.</p>
<p>But a disintegrated Western Europe was inherently unstable, no matter what they though they were. Add in the printing press and the ...</p>            </div>
                    </div>

            </div>


    
    



    <ul>
            </ul>

        
    
    


    
</div>




<div>
    

<div>
    <div>
        <p><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/member/DanielBMarkham">
                <span>
                    <span>
                        <img src="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/images/creator-label.svg?v=0.01" alt="" title="">                    </span>
                </span>
        </a></p>
    </div>
    
</div>


    <div>
        <div>
                    <div>
                 <p>Theory Tuesdays: The MAT</p>
<p>Fifteen years ago, I created the Markham Assessment Tool (MAT). The idea wasn't to implement processes, or make some new "maturity scale" for organizations to use to monitor and punish teams. Instead, every team, even the most successful ones, had things they should probably talk about but had been putting it off (or never realized it) The MAT was an effort to provide a standard language to begin conversations no matter how big or what the nature of the team was.</p>
<p>The first job was finding a detailed enough language to try to pinpoint where the conversations should happen. The default was a combination of the RUP and the CMMI's "common obstacles to process improvement" (Once again, this tool had nothing to do with process; it was just about creating a standard language that could be used by coaches across teams) Other combinations were used as well during field testing.</p>            </div>
                    </div>

            </div>


    
                    <p><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/">
                <img src="https://cdn.rubinreport.com/images/posts/originals/92269/92269_9oxcu8kporvhfxk.png" alt="post photo preview">
            </a></p>



    <ul>
            </ul>

        
    
    


    
</div>




<div>
    

<div>
    <div>
        <p><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/member/DanielBMarkham">
                <span>
                    <span>
                        <img src="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/images/creator-label.svg?v=0.01" alt="" title="">                    </span>
                </span>
        </a></p>
    </div>
    
</div>


    <div>
        <div>
                    <p>
                Theory Tuesdays: Behavior            </p>
                    <p>If you're going to make cool stuff happen for folks, you're going to need how to talk about behavior.</p>
                    </div>

            </div>


    
    



    <ul>
            </ul>

        
    
    


    
</div>


            </div>
            
            
        </section>
            <foolter>
            <div>
                <p><a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/locals-com/id1511032007">
                        <img src="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/images/app-store-badge.png" alt="app store">
                    </a>
                                                    <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.locals.localsapp">
                        <img src="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/images/google-play-badge.png" alt="google store">
                    </a>
                                </p>
            </div>
            
        </foolter>
    </div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/post/110651/technical-tuesdays-follow-up-one-page-chess-done-for-now</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24107984</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 11:18:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Start A Niche Content Site]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 56 | Comments 42 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24107671">thread link</a>) | @simonpurdon10
<br/>
August 10, 2020 | https://www.simonblogs.com/tutorials/how-to-start-a-niche-content-site | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.simonblogs.com/tutorials/how-to-start-a-niche-content-site">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Content sites are great, low barrier to entry businesses that (when done right) can generate a sustainable source of cash. </p><p>Not only that, but they’re also fun. Using the method I’m going to outline below, you can pick a topic that really interests you — learn more about it — and make money in the process.</p><p>I started two of my own content sites a few years ago. They were my first foray into internet businesses and affiliate marketing. When I started the first one (about running — Let’s Go Run), I had no idea what I was doing, and no money to do it. </p><p>I scrounged around the internet finding resources about SEO, keyword planning and blogging. I went through about three SemRush trial’s (sorry SemRush!) with different emails trying to come up with a keyword plan, and figure out why the hell my blog posts weren’t coming up on Google! Then, after about 4 months of working on it and putting out content religiously, I started ranking for one of my main keywords. </p><p>I made it to the front page of Google! I’ll never forget the excitement.</p><p>That got me hooked. I spent the next few years growing out that site, and creating another one with my mom (who loves golf). </p><p>I got them to the small-medium level (each had traffic of about 10k monthly visits) and then sold them online. I needed the cash to start what I thought was a ‘real’ business. </p><p>The thing is, I sold them way before I had monetized each of them properly. I just didn’t know what I was doing! And the buyer knew it. All the income was from affiliate earnings, and they were running off the same account (so I don’t have specific figures for each website), earning around about $80 to $100 mark per month combined.</p><p>Knowing what I do now about niche content sites, and their ability to generate a sustainable cash flow, I would have never sold those sites. </p><p>This is my approach to building content sites that are monetized effectively, and how you can too.</p><h2>Background</h2><h3>What Are They?</h3><p>A niche content site is just a website where people wanting to know about something in a certain niche go to find that out.</p><p>If you take any subreddit, and create content specifically tailored to that audience, it would be a niche content site.</p><figure><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5dc02eb64f3e3528360999cb/5f2a52457e66346b8d05835d_0*gL3fHRm-e86x0tgu.png" alt=""></p></figure><p>Swim University is the perfect example of a niche site: Everything you need to know about keeping a pool clean.</p><h3>How Do They Work?</h3><p>The fundamentals of it are as follows:</p><ol role="list"><li>Pick a specific niche.</li><li>Create content around that niche, and post it on the website.</li><li>Drive readers to that website.</li><li>Build an audience of readers.</li><li>Monetize that audience.</li></ol><h3>A Modified Approach</h3><p>The approach I’m going to give you here uses the framework above, but modifies the Monetization step slightly.</p><p>The goal is simple: <strong>Get to revenue as fast as possible.</strong></p><p>We’ll go into monetization further below, but the gist of it is this:</p><ul role="list"><li>Traditional niche site model requires a ton of traffic to make decent money (especially today).</li><li>My model requires a few thousand views a month with high intent and in a specific niche.</li></ul><h3>Examples</h3><p><strong>SwimUniversity.com</strong> (above) — Pool care</p><p><strong>GearLab.com</strong> — Outdoor gear reviews</p><figure><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5dc02eb64f3e3528360999cb/5f2a524647ea4173bd1d6c06_0*d8YHEXfmp62TptgH.png" alt=""></p></figure><p><strong>ApartmentTherapy.com — </strong>Kit out and care for your trendy apartment</p><figure><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5dc02eb64f3e3528360999cb/5f2a524669ed957a4dbc995f_0*9KPXKzA3bD2Qt04E.png" alt=""></p></figure><p><strong>Fatherly.com</strong> — A site for dad’s</p><figure><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5dc02eb64f3e3528360999cb/5f2a5245e566339d3104c7a4_0*kZ2EoL3V_m9I3aZ7.png" alt=""></p></figure><h3>Motivation</h3><p>Before you continue, understand your motivation for wanting to do this.</p><p>Here’s mine: <strong>Cash</strong>. Niche sites are great cash generators if you can get them right. As long as you have a steady flow of traffic, they can bring in a (mostly) reliable income every single month.</p><p>For me, that means not having to worry about rent as an expense.</p><p>For you, it might mean an additional income to fund your startup.</p><p>Get clear on your motivation to do this so that when things aren’t going so well, you know whether to knuckle down and commit, or bail out because it’s taking too much time and energy to achieve what you want.</p><p>These aren’t sexy businesses, but they work if you do ’em right.</p><h2>🚵 Pick A Niche</h2><p><strong>And validate it, too.</strong></p><p>This is my unconventional advice: <strong>Start with your interests</strong>.</p><p>The thesis behind that is: If you’re not interested in it, you’re not going to want to create content about it.</p><p>One thing I do know is that for this to be successful you have to commit to creating enough content.</p><p>There are a few things you need to consider when picking a niche, though.</p><h3><strong>Audience size</strong></h3><ul role="list"><li>You need a big enough audience to make this viable. <em>Golf</em> = too broad and too competitive. <em>Left-Handed Blind Golfers</em> = too niche. You get the point.</li><li>I would define niche as SwimUniversity.com (above).</li><li>I would define micro-niche as SwimUniversity.com but for glass fibre pools only.</li><li>As a guide — though this is very dependent on your audience and monetization method — your monthly search volume shouldn’t be lower than 30k visits (or 1k visitors a day).</li></ul><h3><strong>Can you monetize it?</strong></h3><ul role="list"><li>Does this audience typically spend money on this interest? Either directly or indirectly. If yes, then the answer will almost always be continue.</li></ul><p>or…</p><ul role="list"><li>Can you generate a ton of search traffic (100k monthly +), which you’d be able to monetize through Display Ads? This would require large search volume for your search keywords, as well as low domain authority for the competing sites. This is generally only available in completely unexplored niches (of which there are very few around).</li></ul><h3><strong>How does that audience consume most of their content?</strong></h3><ul role="list"><li>And can you create that content. If your niche consumes mainly blog posts, great. Low barrier. If they mostly consume well produced video content, and you have no experience doing that = bit higher barrier.</li></ul><h3>Do This Now</h3><ol role="list"><li>Write down all your interests, and then some. Aim for 50 ideas.</li><li>Rank them in order of how ‘niche’ they are. Ie: How many other people are there who share this interest in the world.</li><li>Then rank them in order of your interest in each of them.</li><li>Choose the top 5 combined ranking.</li><li>Sign up for a keyword volume research tool (Most of them offer free trials). I use <a href="https://app.kwfinder.com/#a5dca93d6feebf8609c185b05" target="_blank">Mangools</a>. It’s a lot cheaper (and a bit less powerful) than <a href="https://www.semrush.com/lp/all-in-one-marketing-toolkit/en/?ref=3487429516&amp;refer_source=15-business-ideas-blog-post&amp;utm_source=berush&amp;utm_medium=promo&amp;utm_campaign=link_landing_page:_all-in-one_marketing_toolkit" target="_blank">SEMrush </a>or Ahrefs, but it suits my needs perfectly.</li><li>Do a search for your topic and start collating and creating keywords with monthly search volume &gt; 500 and keyword difficulty &lt; 30. Go after long-tail keywords if you can’t find any.</li><li>If you’re new to this, I haven’t found a better resource than <a href="https://neilpatel.com/blog/keyword-research/?ref=SimonBlogs" target="_blank">Neil Patel’s guide to keyword research.</a></li><li>When you’re done, you should have a good idea of the amount of monthly traffic you can generate (remember, you’re going to have to rank on the first page for those search terms to get a <em>portion </em>of that traffic!).</li><li>Giving hard and fast rules about traffic volume and keyword difficulty targets is difficult.</li><li>Andrew Boscini put it well to me on Twitter the other day:</li></ol><figure><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5dc02eb64f3e3528360999cb/5f2a52453067ff4556a6074b_1*hPVtmGrOkuYQX1g7uGPTmQ.png" alt=""></p></figure><p>Are you going for a ton of traffic that converts in the low % range, or are you going more niche, with very high search intent?</p><p>I’d also recommend snooping around the following forums/places to get a sense for the community you’re diving into and what the pain points are:</p><ul role="list"><li><strong>Reddit </strong>(Find all the applicable sub-reddits)</li><li><strong>Quora </strong>(What questions are people asking)</li><li><strong>Websites</strong>/<strong>Forums </strong>(Who are you competing with)</li><li><strong>Wikipedia </strong>(What information can I give on this niche)</li><li><strong>Twitter </strong>(Do a search and see who the top authorities in the space are)</li><li><strong>Facebook Groups </strong>(How many are they, are they engaged or spammy?)</li></ul><p>As you pick up on areas of discussion, do a search for them as they relate to your niche in the keyword finder and add all those keywords to your list too.</p><h2>✍🏽 Content</h2><p>That’s the fun part done.</p><p>Now that you’ve got your keyword list defined, you need to start writing content. Religiously.</p><p>This is where most people fail on niche sites. They write a few (maybe 5 or 6) articles, and then they get bored and move on. That’s why I said earlier you need to pick a niche that you’re interested in.</p><p>As a guideline, you’re likely going to need to write 100-odd pieces of content in a year.</p><p>If you think that’s unachievable in the niche you’ve selected (because you’ll get bored or otherwise) you have two choices:</p><ol role="list"><li>Go back to the step above and choose a different niche that you’re going to be interested enough in.</li><li>Hire writers (money required).</li></ol><h3>Do This Now</h3><ol role="list"><li>Once you’ve decided on your niche, start writing. Open a Google Doc and begin on your first piece of content. Aim to put out 2 or 3 pieces for 3 or 4 days back to back.</li><li>You should be going after your most valuable keyword’s (high search, low keyword difficulty) first.</li><li>After 3 or 4 days, you’ll have a good idea for the tone/style of your content and you’ll be better positioned to register a domain and setup a home for your content.</li><li>Try and follow the theme of the example domains I showed above. Preferably including one of the main keywords which describes your niche in the url.</li><li>Don’t get hung up if the ideal .com domain isn’t available. There are other options:</li></ol><ul role="list"><li>Your country’s domain extension (only do this if you’re looking to only attract an audience in your own country)</li><li>.co is a great option</li><li>.io is well recognized in the tech-space</li></ul><p>Your domain name is not the be-all and end-all. A nice one is nice to have, but it’s not essential.</p><p>6. Without a doubt, Wordpress is the best option for a quick and easy setup.</p><p>Your domain/hosting provider will likely have some sort of installer for Wordpress available in the backend (Softaculous, usually) which will do it for you.</p><p>7. Install a theme. I get mine from <a href="https://creativemarket.com/themes/wordpress/blog?u=simonpurdon10" target="_blank">Creative Market.</a></p><p>Again, don’t get hung up on the details. You’ll be surprised by how little people care about the nitty-gritty things that seem to be a big deal to the website-owner.</p><p>If your site works well, looks reasonably good, loads quickly, with great content — that’ll do.</p><p>8. Post your content. Add images. Add external links (more on this later).</p><p>9. Add a method of collecting email addresses! Don’t just have a generic “Join our newsletter” either. No one wants to join just another newsletter.</p><p>Give your readers an actual incentive for signing up: “Join our newsletter for exclusive access to subscriber-only content”.</p><p>10. Remember to install:</p><ul role="list"><li><a href="https://yoast.com/wordpress/plugins/seo/" target="_blank">Yoast SEO plugin</a> (for on-site SEO help)</li><li>Google Analytics</li><li>Facebook Pixel</li></ul><h2>🖱️ Traffic</h2><p>Now for the most important (but also the most tedious, for me) part: <strong>Driving traffic.</strong></p><p>Putting up content and hoping …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.simonblogs.com/tutorials/how-to-start-a-niche-content-site">https://www.simonblogs.com/tutorials/how-to-start-a-niche-content-site</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.simonblogs.com/tutorials/how-to-start-a-niche-content-site</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24107671</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 10:43:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Apple Is Taking Legal Action Against a Small Company Because of Its Logo]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 50 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24107119">thread link</a>) | @Simturax
<br/>
August 10, 2020 | https://www.simturax.com/2020/08/apple-taking-legal-action-small-company-pear-shaped-logo.html?m=1 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.simturax.com/2020/08/apple-taking-legal-action-small-company-pear-shaped-logo.html?m=1">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>

<div>


<div id="post-body">

<p><b><span lang="EN-US">Apple is taking legal action against a
small company because of its pear-shaped logo, and requires the company to
change the logo, which would be similar to Apple's.</span></b><br>
<b><span lang="EN-US"><br></span></b>
<b><span lang="EN-US"><br></span></b></p>
<div>
<p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-venO35muDN4/XzEL2fI9yKI/AAAAAAAABPI/4HHDCSjWiIkPiNzhzAJVGtXFfu9-qzttACLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/apple-logo.jpg" imageanchor="1"><img alt="apple-logo-vs-prepear-logo" data-original-height="450" data-original-width="800" height="360" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-venO35muDN4/XzEL2fI9yKI/AAAAAAAABPI/4HHDCSjWiIkPiNzhzAJVGtXFfu9-qzttACLcBGAsYHQ/s640/apple-logo.jpg" title="apple-takes-legal-action-against-prepear" width="640"></a></p>

<br></div>
<p><span lang="EN-US">The American technology giant
Apple has taken legal action against a small company called Prepear, which is
an application and service that makes it easier for people to plan their meals
and find new recipes. The cause of action: Prepear chose to use a pear-shaped
fruit as its logo, which is too similar to Apple's logo, according to a message
posted on Instagram by the company's founders. The message describes Apple's
action as "a blow to Prepear," and indicates the intention to keep
the original logo and "send a message to large technology companies that
intimidation of small businesses has consequences.<o:p></o:p></span><br>
<span lang="EN-US"><br></span></p>

<div>
<blockquote data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/CDmcFEInZK7/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="12">
<div>



<p><span lang="EN-US"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CDmcFEInZK7/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" target="_blank">
<div>
<p>
View this post on Instagram</p>
</div>


</a> <br>
<div>
<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CDmcFEInZK7/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" target="_blank">Dear Instagram Friends- I NEED YOUR HELP! I know there are a lot of heavy things going on in the world right now, and this is nothing in comparison, but I need your help in a situation that is affecting me, my family, and my coworkers. Please help! Many of you know that I started a business called Prepear almost 5 years ago. It is an app that you can store all your recipes in one place, plan your meals, make grocery lists, and get your groceries delivered all in one place. Recently @apple yes, The trillion dollar Apple, has decided to oppose and go after our small business’ trademark saying our pear logo is too close to their apple logo and supposedly hurts their brand? This is a big blow to us at Prepear. To fight this it will cost tens of thousands of dollars. The CRAZY thing is that Apple has done this to dozens of other other small business fruit logo companies, and many have chosen to abandon their logo, or close doors. While the rest of the world is going out of their way to help small businesses during this pandemic, Apple has chosen to go after our small business. I’m not trying to get anyone to stop using or buying Apple products. I feel a moral obligation to take a stand against Apple's aggressive legal action against small businesses and fight for the right to keep our logo. We are defending ourselves against Apple not only to keep our logo, but to send a message to big tech companies that bullying small businesses has consequences. HOW YOU CAN HELP: 1 Sign the petition (link in my bio or in my stories) 2 Share that same link on Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, etc. http://chng.it/QPd2mRYW #savethepearfromapple</a></p></div>

</span></p></div>
</blockquote>
</div>

<div>
<p><span lang="EN-US"><br></span>
<span lang="EN-US">The Prepear company has been in
existence for 5 years. It is an application that allows users to store all
their recipes in one place, plan their meals, make shopping lists and have
their groceries delivered to the same place. The application is a derivative of
Super Healthy Kids, which offers recipes and feeding strategies and shares tips
and organizational tools for parents. The founders say they are facing
litigation from Apple. Apple is said to disagree with the Prepear logo, arguing
that its attributes are too similar to its own logo.<o:p></o:p></span><br>
<span lang="EN-US"><br></span>
<span lang="EN-US"><br></span>
<span lang="EN-US"></span></p>

</div>

<p><i><span lang="EN-US">"Apple opposed
the trademark application for our small company, Prepear, requiring us to
change our logo, which is obviously pear-shaped, used to represent our brand in
recipe management and meal planning,"</span></i><span lang="EN-US"> wrote the founders
of Prepear in a post on Instagram asking for help. Prepear is a small company
with only five employees, and the founders say legal fees have already cost
them "several thousand dollars", plus the dismissal of one team
member, in their legal battle against the iPhone manufacturer.<o:p></o:p></span></p>

<div>
<p><span lang="EN-US">In a petition on <a href="https://www.change.org/p/apple-save-the-pear-from-apple-end-apple-s-aggressive-opposition-of-small-businesses-with-fruit-logos?recruiter=1137882952&amp;recruited_by_id=ebcd47e0-d5d9-11ea-95f3-73a235808f2d&amp;utm_source=share_petition&amp;utm_medium=copylink&amp;utm_campaign=petition_dashboard" target="_blank">Change.org</a>,
Prepear is asking users to sign to ask Apple to drop its opposition to the
Prepear logo and "help prevent large technology companies from abusing
their position of power by attacking small companies that are already
struggling because of the effects of Covid-19. <o:p></o:p></span><br>
<span lang="EN-US"><br></span>
<span lang="EN-US"></span></p>
</div>

<p><span lang="EN-US">Prepear also points out that
before "<i>attacking us, Apple opposed dozens of other trademark
applications filed by small companies with fruit-related logos.</i> According
to Prepear, many of these small companies have had to change their logos or
even give up and shut down, as the limited means of most of them did not allow
them to fight the iPhone manufacturer in a lawsuit costing tens of thousands of
dollars.<o:p></o:p></span></p>

<div>
<p><i><span lang="EN-US">"It's a very
terrifying experience to be legally attacked by one of the world's largest
companies, even though we clearly haven't done anything wrong, and we
understand why most companies just give in and change their logos</span></i><span lang="EN-US">," the Prepear
founders' message on <a href="https://www.change.org/p/apple-save-the-pear-from-apple-end-apple-s-aggressive-opposition-of-small-businesses-with-fruit-logos?recruiter=1137882952&amp;recruited_by_id=ebcd47e0-d5d9-11ea-95f3-73a235808f2d&amp;utm_source=share_petition&amp;utm_medium=copylink&amp;utm_campaign=petition_dashboard" target="_blank">Change.org</a> says. We feel a moral obligation to take a
stand against Apple's aggressive lawsuit against small businesses and fight for
the right to keep our logo," they added.<o:p></o:p></span><br>
<span lang="EN-US"><br></span>
<span lang="EN-US"></span></p>
</div>

<h2>
<b><span lang="EN-US"><span>Sending a message
against the bullying of small businesses by the largest technology companies</span></span></b></h2>
<div>
<p><span lang="EN-US">According to Prepear, Apple has
opposed small businesses with fruit-related logos by launching costly lawsuits,
even when these logos do not resemble the Apple logo at all or are not in the
same industry as Apple. <i>"We're defending ourselves against Apple not
only to keep our logo, but also to send a message to large technology companies
that intimidation of small businesses has consequences,"</i> said the
company's founders.<o:p></o:p></span><br>
<span lang="EN-US"><br></span>
<span lang="EN-US"></span></p>
</div>

<p><span lang="EN-US">The iPhone In Canada website says
it received, on Sunday, more details on the trademark application for the
pear-shaped logo of Prepear, a free application available for download on iOS
and Android. In an email sent to the website, chief operating officer Russ
Monson says Prepear has been registering its trademark for the logo since
January 2017 and that the U.S. trademark office finally told it "<i>that
it was not in conflict with other registered trademarks and that it would
publish it for opposition.<o:p></o:p></i></span></p>

<p><i><span lang="EN-US">Everything seemed to
be coming to an end when, on the</span></i><span lang="EN-US"> "<i>last day of the
opposition period for the trademark, we were informed that Apple had requested
an extension of the opposition period, and then requested further extensions,
which placed our trademark in a legal limbo for a long period of time".<o:p></o:p></i></span></p>

<div>

<p><span lang="EN-US"><br></span>
<span lang="EN-US">According to Prepear's email,
Apple filed its effective opposition on the last day it was legally entitled to
do so. According to Monson, the additional extensions filed resulted in
additional legal costs for the small company, and to him, these extensions
"seemed to have been designed by their legal team to be as long, difficult
and expensive as possible for us.<o:p></o:p></span></p></div>

<div>
<p><span lang="EN-US">Monson goes on to explain that
Prepear was "naive enough" to think that they could discuss the issue
with Apple in a rational manner, as the two logos are different. But this was
not the case and the opposition has now reached the "discovery
phase", which, according to the COO, "will be the most expensive part
of this case for us". However, Prepear decided to move on to this phase at
Apple's request.<o:p></o:p></span><br>
<span lang="EN-US"><br></span>
<span lang="EN-US"></span></p>
</div>

<p><i><span lang="EN-US">"We believe that
this case is clearly frivolous, and that once the public is aware of Apple's
position on this issue, Apple will be more willing to drop the case rather than
let the public see how it is clearly hurting us for no apparent justifiable
reason,"</span></i><span lang="EN-US"> said Monson in his email to iPhone In Canada.<o:p></o:p></span></p>

<h2>
<b><span lang="EN-US"><span>Other companies have
already changed their logos as a result of Apple's lawsuits.</span></span></b></h2>
<p><span lang="EN-US">Some companies whose logos
(below) were attacked by Apple under the same conditions have given up. But the
founders of Prepear say they are lucky enough to attract enough media attention
"to expose this practice by Apple.<o:p></o:p></span></p>
<div>
<p><span lang="EN-US">Other logos have also been the
source of legal actions brought by Apple in the past, such as the case against
a Norwegian political party and a German bicycle path. The logo of the
political party in question depicts a red apple with a stem, a green leaf and
has the letter F in white on the front. Apple wrote a letter to the Norwegian
Patent and Trademark Office stating that this logo with a red apple looks like
its own logo.<o:p></o:p></span><br>
<span lang="EN-US"><br></span>
<span lang="EN-US"><br></span></p><p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-RJyJBHnhlS4/XzEMPhlQALI/AAAAAAAABPQ/5io3xrQne_cEldHOrcE6Cer2MdbIk-bngCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/logos-like-apple.jpg" imageanchor="1"><img alt="logos-like-apple" data-original-height="521" data-original-width="496" height="640" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-RJyJBHnhlS4/XzEMPhlQALI/AAAAAAAABPQ/5io3xrQne_cEldHOrcE6Cer2MdbIk-bngCLcBGAsYHQ/s640/logos-like-apple.jpg" title="apple-vs-prepear" width="608"></a></p>
</div>

<div>
<p><span lang="EN-US"><br></span>
<span lang="EN-US">In 2009, Apple also attacked
Woolworths, an Australian supermarket chain, which had just changed its logo.
Woolworths insisted at the time that its logo is nothing more or less than a
stylized "W", but Apple claimed it was an apple and therefore asked
them to stop using it! Hans Hulsbosch, the creator of the logo, said at the
time that the protection of the Apple logo was "taken to extremes".
"Based on this logic, they should attack all fruit sellers.<o:p></o:p></span><br>
<span lang="EN-US"><br></span>
<span lang="EN-US"></span></p>
</div>

<p><span lang="EN-US">Prepear says they are not asking
for a boycott of Apple products, but they are asking the iPhone manufacturer to
"stop attacking small businesses in frivolous affairs that seem designed
to make them spend so much money and time thinking about the business instead
of focusing on how to grow business and ensure to survive the current economic
crisis.<o:p></o:p></span></p>

<div>
<p><span lang="EN-US">The petition on Change.org has
now received 20,000 signatures, and Prepear hopes that Apple will drop the case
before moving on to more costly discovery and trial phases. Otherwise, small
businesses should give up using fruit as a logo for their brand.<o:p></o:p></span><br>
<span lang="EN-US"><br></span>
<span lang="EN-US"></span></p>
</div>




<br>
</div>

</div>

</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.simturax.com/2020/08/apple-taking-legal-action-small-company-pear-shaped-logo.html?m=1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24107119</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 09:10:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[We Can Do Better Than SQL]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 231 | Comments 233 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24106608">thread link</a>) | @kristianp
<br/>
August 10, 2020 | https://edgedb.com/blog/we-can-do-better-than-sql/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://edgedb.com/blog/we-can-do-better-than-sql/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="---post-root---"><section><div><p><img src="https://edgedb.com/static/sequel-6c9c39bd9420819bb16c0d735f6eae65.jpg" width="100%" height="100%"></p></div></section>
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<section id="we-can-do-better-than-sql">
<!-- -->
<p>The questions we often hear are “Why create a new query language?” and
            “What’s wrong with SQL?”.  This post contains answers to both.</p>
<p>Before we begin, let’s overview some of the history of how the relational
            model came to be, and how SQL was created.</p>
<div id="a-brief-history-of-the-relational-model-and-sql">
<h2 id="a-brief-history-of-the-relational-model-and-sql"><a href="https://edgedb.com/blog/we-can-do-better-than-sql#a-brief-history-of-the-relational-model-and-sql"><svg width="35" height="35" viewBox="0 0 35 35"><path d="M2.694 6.631h19.085v3.961h-1.944V8.574H4.636v10.962h15.199V17.52h1.944v3.96H2.694V6.632zM13.3 13.085h19.086v14.848H13.3v-3.962h1.942v2.019h15.2V15.027h-15.2v2.017H13.3v-3.96z" fill="#047CFF"></path></svg></a>A Brief History of the Relational Model and SQL</h2>
<p>The relational model was introduced by Edgar F. Codd in a seminal 1970 paper
                “A Relational Model of Data for Large Shared Data Banks” <span>[<a id="id1" href="https://edgedb.com/blog/we-can-do-better-than-sql#fcodd-1970">4</a>]</span>.
                There, Codd postulated that all data in a database can be represented in
                terms of sets of tuples, called <em>relations</em>. Codd also invented a form of
                first-order predicate logic to describe the database queries: <em>tuple
                    relational calculus</em>.</p>
<p>Codd’s ideas were revolutionary.  For the first time, a database,
                and a universal way to query it, was described in a succinct, consistent
                mathematical model.  This, naturally, created lots of interest in further
                research and, importantly, into practical implementation of the relational
                model.</p>
<p>In 1974 Donald Chamberlin and Raymond Boyce published a paper
                <span>[<a id="id2" href="https://edgedb.com/blog/we-can-do-better-than-sql#fchamberlin-1974">2</a>]</span>, which introduced “a set of simple operations on tabular
                structures, […] of equivalent power to the first order predicate calculus”.
                Chamberlin and Boyce felt that the formal relational query languages proposed
                at the time were too hard to understand for “users without formal training in
                mathematics or computer programming” and thought that the “predominant use of
                the language would be for ad-hoc queries” <span>[<a id="id3" href="https://edgedb.com/blog/we-can-do-better-than-sql#fchamberlin-2012">3</a>]</span>.  Initially,
                the authors did not consider SQL to be a “serious” language.  Nonetheless,
                the great interest in the commercial application of the relational model had
                pushed IBM to quickly adopt and productize SQL, which was also picked up by
                their quickly-rising competitor–Oracle.</p>
<p>IBM had an overwhelmingly large influence over the tech market at the time,
                so SQL became a de facto standard for relational databases, and then a proper
                standard with the publication of the first ANSI standard in 1989 that
                essentially circumscribed the most prominent existing implementations
                of SQL.  Subsequent versions of the standard continued to be primarily
                influenced by the commercial vendors.</p>
<p>Today, SQL is by far the most widely used database language.  But that does
                not necessarily mean that it represents the best of what we can do.
                In fact, SQL’s beginnings as a “simple, ad-hoc” language coupled with
                “design by implementation” from competing vendors had left the language with
                a baggage of severe issues.</p>
</div>
<div id="critique-of-sql">

<p>SQL, especially its earlier versions, was heavily criticized by the experts,
                including Codd himself <span>[<a id="id4" href="https://edgedb.com/blog/we-can-do-better-than-sql#fcodd-1990">6</a>]</span>, as well as C. J. Date, who published a
                multitude of papers and books on the subject (<span>[<a id="id5" href="https://edgedb.com/blog/we-can-do-better-than-sql#fdate-1985">7</a>]</span>, <span>[<a id="id6" href="https://edgedb.com/blog/we-can-do-better-than-sql#fdate-1987">9</a>]</span>,
                <span>[<a id="id7" href="https://edgedb.com/blog/we-can-do-better-than-sql#fdate-2009">10</a>]</span>).  While many of the early shortcomings were fixed in the later
                versions of the standard, some of the serious issues had been only further
                ingrained.</p>
<p>Some of the complaints here apply to SQL as a whole, while others are specific
                to a certain implementation.  We are primarily using PostgreSQL for the
                examples.</p>
<p>SQL’s shortcomings can be grouped into these categories:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>lack of proper orthogonality — SQL is hard to compose;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>lack of compactness — SQL is a large language;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>lack of consistency — SQL is inconsistent in syntax and semantics;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>poor system cohesion — SQL does not integrate well enough with
                        application languages and protocols.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<div id="lack-of-orthogonality">

<p>Orthogonality in a programming language means that a relatively small set
                    of primitive constructs can be combined in a relatively small number of ways.
                    A language with good orthogonality is smaller, more consistent, and is
                    easier to learn due to there being few exceptions from the overall set of
                    rules.  Conversely, bad orthogonality leads to a large language with many
                    exceptions and caveats.</p>
<p>A good example of orthogonality in a programming language is the ability to
                    substitute an arbitrary part of an expression with a variable, or a function
                    call, without any effect on the final result.</p>
<p>In SQL, such generic substitution is not possible, since there are <em>two</em>
                    mutually incompatible kinds of expressions:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>A <em>table expression</em> is a SQL expression that yields a table:
                            <code>SELECT * FROM table</code>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A <em>scalar expression</em> is a SQL expression that yields a single scalar value:
                            <code>SELECT count(*) FROM table</code>.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Table expressions can only be used in a <code>FROM</code> clause, in a function, or with
                    an operator that specifically expects a table expression as input.
                    What’s worse the scalar and table expressions may have exactly the same syntax,
                    which can be a source of further confusion.</p>
<p>For example, let’s imagine we needed to list the names of all department
                    heads in a company.  This query would do the job:</p>
<pre><span><span><span>SELECT</span> name
<span>FROM</span> emp
<span>WHERE</span> role <span>=</span> <span>'dept head'</span></span></span></pre>
<p>Now let’s say we needed to add this bit to a larger query that extracts
                    information about a department.  An intuitive way is to simply add the
                    above as a subquery to the target list of our larger query:</p>
<pre><span><span><span>SELECT</span>
    dept<span>.</span>name<span>,</span>
    <span>.</span><span>.</span><span>.</span>
    <span>(</span><span>SELECT</span> name <span>FROM</span> emp
     <span>WHERE</span> role <span>=</span> <span>'dept head'</span> <span>AND</span> deptno <span>=</span> dept<span>.</span><span>no</span><span>)</span>
<span>FROM</span>
    dept
    <span>.</span><span>.</span><span>.</span></span></span></pre>
<p>This is legal, but <em>only</em> if the subquery returns not more than one row.
                    Otherwise, an error would be raised at run time.  To account for multiple
                    department heads, we would need to rewrite the query using a join:</p>
<pre><span><span><span>SELECT</span>
    dept<span>.</span>name<span>,</span>
    <span>.</span><span>.</span><span>.</span>
    head<span>.</span>name
<span>FROM</span>
    dept
    <span>INNER</span> <span>JOIN</span> emp <span>AS</span> head
        <span>ON</span> <span>(</span>head<span>.</span>deptno <span>=</span> dept<span>.</span><span>no</span>
            <span>AND</span> head<span>.</span>role <span>=</span> <span>'dept head'</span><span>)</span>
    <span>.</span><span>.</span><span>.</span></span></span></pre>
<p>The difference in structure is large enough to make any sort of source-level
                    query reuse impractical.</p>
</div>
<div id="lack-of-compactness">

<div><p>Few claim that SQL is an elegant language characterized by orthogonality.
                        Some call it an elephant on clay feet.  With each addition, its body grows,
                        and it becomes less stable.  SQL standardization is largely the domain of
                        database vendors, not academic researchers without commercial interests
                        or users with user interests. <span>[<a id="id8" href="https://edgedb.com/blog/we-can-do-better-than-sql#fatzeni-2013">1</a>]</span></p><p>Paolo Atzeni et al.</p></div>
<p>SQL is not a small language. At the time of writing the PostgreSQL
                    implementation contains <b>469 keywords</b>. Just part 2 (out of 14) of the
                    SQL:2016 standard has <b>1732 pages</b>.</p>
<p>The main reason is that SQL, in line with its original goals, strives to be
                    an English-like language, catered to “non-professionals”.  However, with the
                    growth of the language, this verbosity has contributed <em>negatively</em> to the
                    ability to write and comprehend SQL queries.  We learnt this lesson with
                    COBOL, and the world has long since moved on to newer, more succinct
                    programming languages.</p>
<p>In addition to keyword proliferation, the orthogonality issues discussed
                    above make queries more verbose and harder to read.</p>
</div>
<div id="lack-of-consistency">

<p>SQL is arbitrarily inconsistent both in its syntax and semantics. What
                    makes things even worse is that different databases have their own version
                    of SQL, often incompatible with other SQL variants.</p>
<p>Here are a few examples of entirely different calling conventions in SQL:</p>
<pre><span><span><span>SELECT</span> substring<span>(</span><span>'PostgreSQL'</span> <span>from</span> <span>8</span> <span>for</span> <span>3</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>
<span>SELECT</span> substring<span>(</span><span>'PostgreSQL'</span><span>,</span> <span>8</span><span>,</span> <span>3</span><span>)</span><span>;</span> 

<span>SELECT</span> trim<span>(</span>both <span>from</span> <span>'yxSQLxx'</span><span>,</span> <span>'xyz'</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>
<span>SELECT</span> extract<span>(</span><span>day</span> <span>from</span> <span>timestamp</span> <span>'2001-02-16 20:38:40'</span><span>)</span><span>;</span></span></span></pre>
<p>There are two syntaxes that specify the ordering of the input set in an
                    aggregate function:</p>
<pre><span><span><span>SELECT</span> array_agg<span>(</span>foo <span>ORDER</span> <span>BY</span> bar<span>)</span></span></span></pre>
<p>and</p>
<pre><span><span><span>SELECT</span> rank<span>(</span>foo<span>)</span> <span>WITHIN</span> <span>GROUP</span> <span>(</span><span>ORDER</span> <span>BY</span> bar<span>)</span></span></span></pre>
<p>The list of inconsistencies like this does not end here and can be continued,
                    but that’s beyond the scope of this blog post.</p>
</div>
<div id="null-a-bag-of-surprises">

<div><p>In some cases of inadequate handling of missing information,
                        the problem is incorrectly perceived to be a problem of the
                        relational model. In fact, the problem stems from the inadequacies
                        of SQL and its non-conformance to the relational model. <span>[<a id="id9" href="https://edgedb.com/blog/we-can-do-better-than-sql#fcodd-1990">6</a>]</span></p><p>Edgar J. Codd</p></div>
<p>It has been extensively argued that <code>NULL</code> is the biggest misfeature of SQL
                    (<span>[<a id="id10" href="https://edgedb.com/blog/we-can-do-better-than-sql#fcodd-1987">5</a>]</span>, <span>[<a id="id11" href="https://edgedb.com/blog/we-can-do-better-than-sql#fdate-1986">8</a>]</span>, <span>[<a id="id12" href="https://edgedb.com/blog/we-can-do-better-than-sql#fdate-1987">9</a>]</span>).
                    In fact, the handling of <code>NULL</code> in contemporary SQL implementations is so
                    surprising, inconsistent, and dangerous that this topic deserves a separate
                    section.</p>
<p><code>NULL</code> is so special that it’s not equal to anything, including itself:</p>
<pre><span><span>postgres=# select NULL = NULL;
 ?column?
----------

(1 row)</span></span></pre>
<p>In fact, almost any operation on <code>NULL</code> will return <code>NULL</code> and the
                    effect may be very subtle:</p>
<pre><span><span>postgres=# CREATE TABLE x (a int, b text);
CREATE TABLE
postgres=# INSERT INTO x(a, b)
           VALUES (1, 'one'), (2, 'two'), (NULL, 'three')
           RETURNING a, b;
 a |   b
---+-------
 1 | one
 2 | two
   | three
(3 rows)

postgres=# SELECT * FROM x WHERE a NOT IN (1, null);
 a | b
---+---
(0 rows)</span></span></pre>
<p>But, in some cases <code>NULL</code>
<em>is</em> equal to itself, such as in <code>DISTINCT</code>:</p>
<pre><span><span>elvis=# SELECT DISTINCT *
        FROM (VALUES (1), (NULL), (NULL)) AS q;
 column1
---------

       1
(2 rows)</span></span></pre>
<p>or <code>UN…</code></p></div></div></section></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://edgedb.com/blog/we-can-do-better-than-sql/">https://edgedb.com/blog/we-can-do-better-than-sql/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://edgedb.com/blog/we-can-do-better-than-sql/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24106608</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 07:40:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I tried starting a manufacturing unit in India]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 246 | Comments 173 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24106545">thread link</a>) | @rohan_shah
<br/>
August 10, 2020 | https://superr.in/economy/i-tried-starting-a-manufacturing-unit-in-india/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://superr.in/economy/i-tried-starting-a-manufacturing-unit-in-india/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-content" role="main">

	
<article id="post-73">

	
<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>

		<div>

			
<h2>UPDATE</h2>



<p>It has been brought to my attention that there was a mistake by an entry level employee. </p>



<p>So the Revenue Department itself was supposed to get all the NOCs required by going to all those offices, but an entry level employee forgot to add my file to the list of NA’s to be done.</p>



<p>So now I have been told that all the NOC’s will be taken care of by the Revenue Department, Collector Office. </p>



<p>If any legal fees need to be paid, I will be informed by the Collector office (without me requiring to go to every office) and everything will be done in less than 2 months.</p>



<p>I am thankful to everyone for sharing my experience far and wide. But now my experience stands cleared and so does this post. </p>



<p>A lot of people have helped reach this post to very very high-in-the-hierarchy people in the state and central government as well as major national political parties. I am really very thankful to everyone.</p>



<p>I will try again in a few months and keep surveying the experience of people who get their NA done. Thank you again for all the co-operation.</p>



<p>I am also writing a post about “the real process required to obtain the NA permission”. I will try to get the higher authorities from the Collector office to record a video stating the actual procedure required and will publish such article soon.</p>



<p>Again Thank You Very Much.</p>



<p>I have removed the original post. I will update with next steps soon. </p>

		</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	</div><!-- .post-inner -->

	<!-- .section-inner -->

	
		<!-- .comments-wrapper -->

		
</article><!-- .post -->

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://superr.in/economy/i-tried-starting-a-manufacturing-unit-in-india/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24106545</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 07:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Codata in action, or how to connect FP and OOP]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 97 | Comments 51 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24105755">thread link</a>) | @siraben
<br/>
August 9, 2020 | https://www.javiercasas.com/articles/codata-in-action/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.javiercasas.com/articles/codata-in-action/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>My friend Juan Paucar directed me to a paper from the magnificent <a href="https://www.springer.com/gp/book/9783030171834">Programming Languages and Systems
28th European Symposium on Programming, ESOP 2019</a>, related to Codata. I have been very interested in codata, mainly because it relates to data in a category-theory way, but, as usual, I didn't understand many of the words involved. This paper helped me understand a lot, and also helped me understand and shape my mind on how to connect the worlds of FP and OOP. But, before that, we must go on tour over a bit of theory.</p>
<h2>Data</h2>
<p>Data, better understood as Haskell's <code>data</code> declaration, is nothing more than a type and a bunch of ways (functions) to create values of that type. I'm going to use the GADT syntax just because it makes the functions visible. Here is an example:</p>
<div data-language="haskell"><pre><code><span>data</span> <span>Foo</span> <span>where</span>
  <span>Foo1</span> <span>::</span> <span>Int</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>String</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Foo</span>
  <span>Foo2</span> <span>::</span> <span>Bool</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Foo</span></code></pre></div>
<p>For the folks that don't grasp GADTs yet, the above is equivalent to:</p>
<div data-language="haskell"><pre><code><span>data</span> <span>Foo</span>
  <span>=</span> <span>Foo1</span> <span>Int</span> <span>String</span>
  <span>|</span> <span>Foo2</span> <span>Bool</span></code></pre></div>
<p>But with the GADT syntax we can see the functions. <code>Foo1</code> is a constructor, but also a function. <code>Foo1</code> receives an Int and a String, and constructs a value of type <code>Foo</code>. Exactly the same happens with <code>Foo2</code>.</p>
<p>We just talked about constructors: a constructor is nothing more than a function that manufactures a value out of other values. But that pretty much defines every function as a constructor, which isn't helpful. We'll go a bit further: a constructor is a "primitive" function that makes a value of type T, and is not build out of other functions that make a value of type T. Also, a constructor is the function you define when you write a <code>data</code> declaration.</p>
<p>If there are constructors, there should be something that dismantles data, because data seems to be constructed by aggregating values. This thing that deconstructs data is called "eliminators". The universal eliminator in Haskell is the <code>case</code> statement:</p>
<div data-language="haskell"><pre><code><span>case</span> <span>myfoo</span> <span>of</span>
  <span>Foo1</span> <span>i</span> <span>s</span>  <span>-&gt;</span> <span>...</span>
  <span>Foo2</span> <span>b</span>    <span>-&gt;</span> <span>...</span></code></pre></div>
<p>The <code>case</code> statement accepts a parameter (what you put between the <code>case</code> and the <code>of</code>) and returns a value of some type. That's why all the branches in a <code>case</code> statement must have the same type, because when you write a <code>case</code> statement, you are writing a function like <code>mycase :: Foo -&gt; X</code>, but with a nicer syntax.</p>
<p>This means eliminators are not always in the shape of <code>case</code> statements. In reality, eliminators are just functions, and Haskell provides special syntax for these functions to be written in a better way. But, if we go to Lisp, for example, we also have constructors and eliminators.</p>
<p>In Lisp you can manufacture a list with a new head by using the constructor <code>cons</code> (this is why these data structure is called a <code>cons-cell</code>). <code>cons</code> is just another function with two parameters: the head and the tail of the list to be constructed, and returns the list. To destructure a cons-list, you have two eliminators: <code>car</code> and <code>cdr</code>. <code>car</code> takes a list and returns the head, <code>cdr</code> takes the list and returns the tail.</p>
<p>Haskell also offers eliminators, but everyone frowns at you if you use them too much: when you declare a record datatype, Haskell helpfully creates functions to access each of the fields:</p>
<div data-language="haskell"><pre><code><span>data</span> <span>FooRecord</span> <span>=</span> <span>FooRecord</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>fooField1</span> <span>::</span> <span>Int</span><span>,</span>
    <span>fooField2</span> <span>::</span> <span>String</span>
  <span>}</span>




</code></pre></div>
<p>Everyone frowns at you when you use these accessors because if <code>FooRecord</code> has more than a single constructor, and you use an eliminator for the other constructor, your program blows up in flames. This is no different to how <code>car</code> and <code>cdr</code> blow up in flames when you pass as parameter an empty list.</p>
<p>The point of all of this is that <code>data</code> is a declaration that offers a bunch of different ways to create a value, and your program chooses which one interests you for the current case.</p>
<h2>Category Theory</h2>
<p>Category Theory is a branch of Mathematics mainly used by haskellers to annoy everyone else. But, believe it or not, it's also useful to reason about programs. In Category Theory we have objects and we have arrows that interconnect the objects. For something to be a Category, its objects and arrows have to obey some rules.</p>
<p>One of the constructs of Category Theory is the co-category. A co-category is a category where the arrows have been reversed. If in category X, an arrow goes from A to B, in the category co-X, the arrow goes from B to A.</p>
<p>At this point, "codata" should be suspicious to you. It totally looks like "co-data", the co-category of "data". But, how does it actually look the category of "data"?</p>
<h3>The Category of data</h3>
<p>The "data" category is revealed to us as the <code>data</code> declaration. Let's have another look at the <code>Foo</code> example:</p>
<div data-language="haskell"><pre><code><span>data</span> <span>Foo</span> <span>where</span>
  <span>Foo1</span> <span>::</span> <span>Int</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>String</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Foo</span>
  <span>Foo2</span> <span>::</span> <span>Bool</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Foo</span></code></pre></div>
<p>In this case (but not in all categories) the types are the objects and the functions are the arrows. If we massage a little bit the code above, by using uncurrying, we can get to a data format that is a bit less arrow-ish and easier for our purposes:</p>
<div data-language="haskell"><pre><code><span>data</span> <span>Foo</span> <span>where</span>
  <span>Foo1</span> <span>::</span> <span>(</span><span>Int</span><span>,</span> <span>String</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Foo</span>
  <span>Foo2</span> <span>::</span> <span>Bool</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Foo</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Now <code>Foo1</code> takes a pair of Int and String and returns a <code>Foo</code>, and <code>Foo2</code> takes a <code>Bool</code> and returns a <code>Foo</code>. This is pretty much what every haskeller already knows: you don't have a <code>Foo</code> via <code>Foo1</code> until you provide both the <code>Int</code> and the <code>String</code>, no matter how many arrows are in the middle.</p>
<p>And now, the case statement:</p>
<div data-language="haskell"><pre><code><span>case</span> <span>myfoo</span> <span>of</span>
  <span>Foo1</span> <span>(</span><span>i</span><span>,</span> <span>s</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>what_to_do_if_Foo1</span> <span>i</span> <span>s</span>
  <span>Foo2</span> <span>b</span>      <span>-&gt;</span> <span>what_to_do_if_Foo2</span> <span>b</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Let's massage it a little bit to turn it into a function:</p>
<div data-language="haskell"><pre><code><span>fooEliminator</span> <span>::</span> <span>(</span><span>Foo</span><span>,</span> <span>(</span><span>(</span><span>Int</span><span>,</span> <span>String</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>a</span><span>)</span><span>,</span> <span>(</span><span>Bool</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>a</span><span>)</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>a</span>
<span>fooEliminator</span> <span>(</span><span>myfoo</span><span>,</span> <span>what_to_do_if_Foo1</span><span>,</span> <span>what_to_do_if_Foo2</span><span>)</span> <span>=</span>
  <span>case</span> <span>myfoo</span> <span>of</span>
    <span>Foo1</span> <span>(</span><span>i</span><span>,</span> <span>s</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>what_to_do_if_Foo1</span> <span>(</span><span>i</span><span>,</span> <span>s</span><span>)</span>
    <span>Foo2</span> <span>b</span>      <span>-&gt;</span> <span>what_to_do_if_Foo2</span> <span>b</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Now that we have converted <code>case</code> into a plain old function, we don't need to do hand-waiving and magic because everything is now plain old function composition and application. Also, all the uncurrying that all the haskellers are about to complain is just going to help us.</p>
<h3>The co-Category of data: co-data</h3>
<p>I massaged all these expressions and uncurried them because, otherwise it is confusing. I mean, a co-category is a category with the arrows flipped. Which poses the question: which arrows? All of them? Some of them? Everything is easier if there is a single arrow: it means we don't have to go figuring out which one.</p>
<p>So let's flip the arrow of the <code>Foo</code> data declaration, and let's see what comes out.</p>
<div data-language="haskell"><pre><code>
<span>codata</span> <span>Foo</span> <span>where</span>
  <span>Foo1</span> <span>::</span> <span>(</span><span>Int</span><span>,</span> <span>String</span><span>)</span> <span>&lt;-</span> <span>Foo</span>
  <span>Foo2</span> <span>::</span> <span>Bool</span> <span>&lt;-</span> <span>Foo</span></code></pre></div>
<p>I happily renamed <code>data</code> to <code>codata</code>, and flipped the single arrow in each line. Let's massage it a little bit more by flipping the order of the arguments so that the arrow points to the right, because we are accustomed to see the arrow functions that way:</p>
<div data-language="haskell"><pre><code><span>codata</span> <span>Foo</span> <span>where</span>
  <span>Foo1</span> <span>::</span> <span>Foo</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>(</span><span>Int</span><span>,</span> <span>String</span><span>)</span>
  <span>Foo2</span> <span>::</span> <span>Foo</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Bool</span></code></pre></div>
<p>What does this mean? Well, a lot of things at the same time, but let's go one by one.</p>
<p>We have two functions related to the <code>codata Foo</code>. The first, called <code>Foo1</code> takes a <code>Foo</code> and manufactures a pair of Int and String. The second, called <code>Foo2</code> takes a <code>Foo</code> and manufactures a <code>Bool</code>. We have two functions that take what seems to be a composite value <code>Foo</code> and extract simple values from it of types <code>Int</code>, <code>String</code> and <code>Bool</code>.</p>
<p>The same way that we could call any of the two functions in the <code>data Foo</code> declaration, we can call any of the two functions in the <code>codata Foo</code>, and get an <code>(Int, String)</code> for the first case, and a <code>Bool</code> for the second. Nothing forces us to call both, and we can just call any one of them.</p>
<p>If we have a <code>Foo</code>, and by calling <code>Foo1</code> we get simple values from it, this looks a lot like a eliminator. But we can also call <code>Foo2</code>, which looks like another eliminator.</p>
<p>Trying to make sense of all of this, we reach a deep insight:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>data</code> is about how we can call any of the many different constructors of a composite value.</li>
<li><code>codata</code> is about how we can call any of the many different eliminators of a composite value.</li>
</ul>
<p>From it, we can derive further insights:</p>
<ul>
<li>Codata looks a lot like objects and methods, where the codata value is the object, and the eliminators are the methods. There is probably some theorem out there that maps codata as a category to objects in OO programs.</li>
<li>It's not that Functional Programming is superior to Object Oriented Programming. But, the usual Functional Programmer has been an Object Oriented Programmer before. Because of this, he is likely to know <code>codata</code> from OO, and now is starting to understand <code>data</code> from FP. As a result of this, he is better armed than an Object Oriented Programmer because an Object Oriented Programmer only knows <code>codata</code>.</li>
</ul>
<p>Further philosophical details can be extracted from the duality data-codata:</p>
<ul>
<li>If we were to find a pure FP programmer, and a pure OO programmer, they would probably have a similar level of skill, but in totally different dimensions. This would make very hard to actually figure out who is the most skilled, because their skill-sets wouldn't be comparable! How do you compare skill-set in <code>data</code> with skill-set in <code>codata</code>?</li>
<li>Data (and Functional Programming) deals on how we can construct complex datatypes from simple ones by using constructors. Codata (and Object Oriented Programming) deals on how we can extract the components from an object by calling its methods.</li>
<li>
<p>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Expression_problem">Expression Problem</a> states that you should be able to add new cases and new functions to a datatype without losing type safety and without having to recompile.</p>
<ul>
<li>In an OO language, you can add a new case by creating another subclass and implementing the methods. But, if you want to add a new function to a datatype, you have to add it to the superclass and implement it on all the existing subclasses, which means modifying a lot of files and recompiling most of the program.</li>
<li>In a FP language you can add a new function to an existing datatype just by adding a function. But, if you want to add a new case, you have to add the constructor and modify all the functions that use the datatype, which means modifying a lot of files and recompiling most of the program.</li>
</ul>
<p>Turns out, with our new data-codata knowledge, that we have a deeper insight into the Expression Problem, and …</p></li></ul></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.javiercasas.com/articles/codata-in-action/">https://www.javiercasas.com/articles/codata-in-action/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.javiercasas.com/articles/codata-in-action/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24105755</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 05:09:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Revolution in Belarus People are demanding Lukashenko to go home]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 50 | Comments 30 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24104104">thread link</a>) | @monetizeinfo
<br/>
August 9, 2020 | https://dailytrust.info/revolution-in-belarus/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dailytrust.info/revolution-in-belarus/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
				<!-- .entry-header-wrapper -->

				<div>
					<p>Violent scenes are taking place this evening in Minsk, Belarus, where law enforcement officials, with President Aleksandr Lukashenko, are battling the contestants.</p>
<p>The protests began after the official exit poll released on Sunday evening at the end of the presidential election, which credits the eternal Aleksandr Lukashenko with nearly 80% of the vote, according to <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-53717834">BBC News</a> and <a href="https://tass.com/world/1187449">Tass</a>.</p>
<figure id="attachment_106" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-106"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-106">Belarus Riots</figcaption></figure>
<p>The images posted on Facebook, <a href="https://monetize.info/telegram-bots/">Telegram groups</a> and Twitter by independent journalists in Belarus show huge crowds of people in Minsk, but also in other cities of the country – Gomel, Brest or Baranovichi. In the latter two reportedly, police withdrew from the central area in front of thousands of protesters.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WARNING?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#WARNING</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SHOCKCONTENT?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#SHOCKCONTENT</a> scenes from earlier this night, a police van runs over a protestor in Minsk and leaves. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Belarus?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Belarus</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Minsk?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Minsk</a> <a href="https://t.co/XQwpmhIXQe">pic.twitter.com/XQwpmhIXQe</a></p>
<p>— Belarus Free Theatre (@BFreeTheatre) <a href="https://twitter.com/BFreeTheatre/status/1292597515414536192?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 9, 2020</a></p></blockquote>

<p>On the same evening, according to exit polls, <strong>Aleksandr Lukashenko</strong> would have won the election again by 79.7%, while opposition candidate <strong>Svetlana Tihanovskaia</strong> would have won only 6.8% of the suffrages.</p>
<p>The country’s authoritarian leader has previously said that everything will remain “under control”. However, independent journalists in Belarus say that citizens are angry and convinced that the elections have been rigged.</p>
<p>Opposition candidate Svetlana Tihanovskaia’s spokeswoman claimed her victory based on “real” results from 20 polling stations. The official asked the Central Election Commission to declare the correct results on Monday. Tihanovskaia herself urged police not to forget “that it is part of the nation.” “I know that citizens will wake up tomorrow in a new country and I hope that tomorrow will bring good news. Stop the violence. officers, I know you can do it,” the opposition candidate said. Several polling station presidents came out in front of citizens to announce what they call the “real” results of the vote. In the clip below, Tihanovskaia is announced winning by 90%.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A moment when head of one of local election commissions in Minsk announced announced real results in front of the gathered crowd with Tikhanovskaya getting 90% <a href="https://t.co/SgeotipQLL">pic.twitter.com/SgeotipQLL</a></p>
<p>— Tadeusz Giczan (@TadeuszGiczan) <a href="https://twitter.com/TadeuszGiczan/status/1292560483959156742?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 9, 2020</a></p></blockquote>

<p><strong>Aleksandr Lukashenko is in his sixth term as president of Soviet-state Belarus and has ruled the country since 1994.</strong> He is in office for the longest time of all European heads of state (except monarchs). In Belarusian society, the “Old Man” is unofficially called.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Minsk?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Minsk</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Belarus?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Belarus</a>, tonight:<a href="https://t.co/8smxMov6IE">pic.twitter.com/8smxMov6IE</a></p>
<p>— Alex Kokcharov (@AlexKokcharov) <a href="https://twitter.com/AlexKokcharov/status/1292599516567343105?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 9, 2020</a></p></blockquote>

<p>President Aleksandr Lukashenko’s forces are making arrests, while demonstrators are wounded.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Minsk?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Minsk</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Belarus?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Belarus</a>:</p>
<p>Probably a “non lethal” stun grenade… ripped away part of the heel.<br>
Again: all these so-called “non lethal” weapons ARE lethal at close range. <a href="https://t.co/qCgAbd9xVI">pic.twitter.com/qCgAbd9xVI</a></p>
<p>— Thomas C. Theiner (@noclador) <a href="https://twitter.com/noclador/status/1292592464247894016?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 9, 2020</a></p></blockquote>

<p>Unfortunately, the internet is now blocked in Belarus so we will update the article when we will have more details about the current situation.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, feel free to add your own opinion about this situation and the outcome in the comments section.</p>
</div><!-- .entry-content -->

				<!-- .entry-meta -->
			</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dailytrust.info/revolution-in-belarus/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24104104</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:12:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
