<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 08:41:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 08:41:30 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[We Crush, Poison, and Destroy Insects at Our Own Peril]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 65 | Comments 11 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25901384">thread link</a>) | @CapitalistCartr
<br/>
January 25, 2021 | http://m.nautil.us/issue/95/escape/we-crush-poison-and-destroy-insects-at-our-own-peril | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://m.nautil.us/issue/95/escape/we-crush-poison-and-destroy-insects-at-our-own-peril">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
			<p><span>T</span>his past summer, my wife and I ventured to an area near Mount Adams in southwestern Washington state to census bumblebees. We camped there over the weekend as we took part in the Pacific Northwest Bumblebee Atlas survey. Scientists want to fill gaps in their knowledge about the bees. Learning about the relative number of different species, and their floral resources over a broad area, provides invaluable information, particularly when some species are in decline. I was helping to determine where conservation efforts may be needed. Survey participants choose a territory where they capture and photograph bumblebees on two occasions. I still marvel at the variety in the photos we took—bees with coloration incorporating rusty bands of hair, black stubby hairs, white patches, orange bands, and a brilliant, lemon-yellow covering of long hairs. <a href="https://nautil.us/issue/90/something-green/the-fungal-evangelist-who-would-save-the-bees" target="_blank">Bumblebees</a> are really quite beautiful when observed more closely.</p><figure data-alt="Hainze_BREAKER"><img src="http://static.nautil.us/18113_ca9eac0c76de0cab71d5b50951fe4c5f.png" width="733" alt=""><figcaption><span><strong>FIGHT OF THE BUMBLEBEE:</strong> A 2017 global study found that one-third of assessed bumblebee species were in decline. The U.S. is studying whether to place the western bumblebee on the endangered species list.</span><span>Stephen Ausmus, USDA ARS / Wikimedia</span></figcaption></figure><p>There is some risk involved, of course. Bumblebees have a painful sting and, unlike the honeybee, with its barbed stinger, the sharp, smooth bumblebee stinger can sting multiple times. Insect stings may serve two purposes. The first is to incapacitate prey. The second is to ward off predators. Bumblebees feed solely on pollen and flower nectar. So they would not sting to subdue prey. A bumblebee nest full of honey and nearly immobile larvae, though, is highly attractive to predators. The bumblebee sting is a weapon used for defense—a mechanism to escape predation from animals that may be 50,000 to 100,000 times their size.<sup>1</sup> And judging by the way most people respond, it works pretty well. The sting of the honeybee has been used as a reference point by sting pain connoisseur, Justin Schmidt. He rates the bumblebee and <a href="https://nautil.us/issue/3/in-transit/tracking-honeybees-to-save-them" target="_blank">honeybee</a> stings as a pedestrian 2 on his scale of 1-4.<sup>2</sup> But that’s a sufficient wallop for people to keep their distance from these bees—and that’s the way the bees like it.<br></p><p>The unparalleled success of insects as a group of organisms results from their ability to escape existential threats. They’re escape artists. They’ve evolved multiple means of eluding the larger animals that endanger them—by stinging, biting, flying, jumping, running, startling, hiding in crevices, and using camouflage as well as chemical defenses. Yet these masters at evading far larger animals face a threat more pernicious than predation today. The resulting decline in the number of insects and in the number of insect species is increasingly well documented. Why should this be alarming? Insects play significant roles as food or in the growth of food for many organisms, including human beings. Insects are also recyclers, decomposing plant matter and animal dung and contributing to the organic content of soils.</p><blockquote><p>It’s not all honey and butterflies in our relationship with insects.</p> </blockquote><p>It’s been said that if human beings disappeared, we would not be missed. Insects and other organisms would thrive. Yet we and many other animals <a href="https://nautil.us/issue/73/play/we-need-insects-more-than-they-need-us" target="_blank">would not survive were insects to disappear</a>. The plight of the island marble butterfly (<i>Euchloe ausonides insulanis</i>) and the western bumblebee (<i>Bombus occidentalis</i>) exemplify the multiple stressors on insect survival in the <a href="https://nautil.us/issue/90/something-green/dawn-of-the-heliocene" target="_blank">Anthropocene</a>, the proposed name for a new epoch in which human-generated change outstrips the effect of natural forces on the Earth. What responsibilities, if any, do we bear toward these insects? And what can each of us do to stem the tide of global insect decline?<br></p><p>In my recent book, <i>Nature Underfoot</i>, I argue that we crush, poison, and destroy insects and their habitat at our own peril. Yet reasons for acting to prevent insect decline run much deeper than self-interest. Humans cause habitat loss, produce pesticides, and import non-native species. We bear, according to certain strands of philosophical and religious thought, responsibility for the catastrophic losses insects experience today. Some say that insects have moral value since they strive to achieve their ends, just as we and other animals do. Others argue that insects have <a href="https://nautil.us/issue/72/quandary/human-exceptionalism-stifles-progress" target="_blank">moral value as a part of God’s creation</a>. Scientists point to the value of insects in global ecosystems, or the value implied by tens or hundreds of thousands of years involved in the evolution of an insect species.</p><p><span>T</span>he insect apocalypse has captured headlines, but the situation is more nuanced than that. Scientists find an increase in the overall numbers of arthropods in the Arctic, but a decline in diversity. Certain habitats in the Arctic are also affected more than others.<sup>3</sup> In Puerto Rico, insect declines initially attributed to climate change may have resulted instead from hurricanes.<sup>4</sup> Some insect species have even increased in numbers—mainly those that are tolerant of human activities or that benefit from associating with humans or from <a href="https://nautil.us/issue/78/atmospheres/is-net-zero-emissions-an-impossible-goal" target="_blank">climate change</a>.</p><p>Despite that, the general trend is negative as climate change, habitat destruction (in the form of deforestation, urbanization, and <a href="https://nautil.us/issue/66/clockwork/herbicide-is-whats-for-dinner" target="_blank">intensification of agriculture</a>), and pesticides take their toll. These forces are overtaking the insects. They are coming so quickly that even these spectacularly successful evolutionary improvisers do not have time to escape. It’s often difficult for scientists to identify a single contributing factor. A new paper, introducing a special issue on the plight of insects, published in the <i>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</i>, referred to the decline of these tiny creatures as “death by a thousand cuts.”<sup>5</sup></p><figure data-alt="Hainze_BREAKER-2"><img src="http://static.nautil.us/18112_d05c25e6e6c5d4898161e0aaf700d9c7.png" width="733" alt=""><figcaption><strong>EDGE OF EXTINCTION:</strong> The Lazarus-like return of the island marble butterfly is remarkable, but the pressures that endanger its prairie habitats remain.</figcaption></figure><p>There is a paucity of long-term records for insect populations. The best historical records are for moths and butterflies in Europe and North America. The story of the island marble butterfly, a grassland species, illustrates the myriad forces arrayed against insects. It was declared endangered in the United States in May of 2020. It is charmingly small—mostly white on the tops of the wings and mottled green, yellow, and white on the undersides. Perhaps its colorful camouflage is a way of escaping predation. This little butterfly was thought to be extinct since 1908, when it was last collected on Gabriola Island, British Columbia. Quite by accident 90 years later, while conducting a survey of butterflies in Puget Sound prairie habitats, a Washington state biologist, John Fleckenstein, collected two of these butterflies on San Juan Island. Neither Fleckenstein, nor his colleague, Ann Potter, could identify the butterflies as they reviewed his collection. So, Potter took the butterflies to a butterfly conference in Corvallis, Oregon, where experts were ecstatic to see the butterfly once thought extinct!<sup>6</sup><br></p><p>The Lazarus-like return of the island marble butterfly is remarkable, but the pressures that endanger it remain. The prairie habitats where the butterfly is found have been farmed, used for pasture, and developed for housing, destroying much of its original habitat. The butterfly caterpillars feed and develop on plants in the mustard family. The native mustard, Menzies’ pepperweed (<i>Lepidium virginicum</i> var. <i>menziesii</i>), that must have originally supported the butterfly, is often found surrounding lagoons on San Juan Island. These plants and the island marble butterfly are damaged by winter storm surges, which will become more serious as climate change causes sea levels to rise. Fortunately, the butterfly has adapted to feeding on two non-native plants, field mustard (<i>Brassica rapa</i>) and tumble mustard (<i>Sisymbrium altissimum</i>) that grow elsewhere on the island.</p><blockquote><p>We and many animals wouldn’t survive if insects disappeared.</p> </blockquote><p>Other invasive species have had a more deleterious effect on the island marble butterfly. The brown garden snail (<i>Cornu aspersum</i>), brought from Europe to the west coast as a source of escargot, competes with the island marble butterfly in consuming field mustard and tumble mustard. The European rabbit (<i>Oryctolagus cuniculus</i>) develops large populations in the San Juan Islands and also feeds on butterfly host plants. Deer, though native in the San Juans, are destructive of prairie habitat. Deer numbers are very high there because their predators, such as wolves, cougars, and bears, were eliminated by European settlers. Deer not only destroy island marble butterfly habitat, but they may ingest eggs and caterpillars in the process. Island marble butterflies also suffer from predation by native spiders and by a European paper wasp (<i>Polistes dominula</i>).<sup>7</sup><br></p><p>A vigorous and widely distributed population of butterflies could withstand the <a href="https://nautil.us/blog/fear-is-good-for-the-forest" target="_blank">pressure of predation</a>, but it poses a significant risk for the tiny, localized population of island marble butterflies. Death by a thousand cuts. Habitat destruction, loss of food plants, invasive species, climate change, and predation are primarily human-driven problems. Fortunately, what is believed to be the last island marble butterfly population falls within the boundaries of the San Juan National Historic Park. Here, the park service is actively rearing and releasing butterflies and making a significant effort to preserve their habitat. The island marble butterfly is in a fragile state but hopefully its new endangered status will yield another amazing recovery.</p><div>
<article>
<p><a href="http://m.nautil.us/issue/85/Reopening/welcome-back-animals" data-trval="welcome-back-animals" data-trlbl="foc_rec" data-tract="internal_art">
<img src="http://static.nautil.us/17238_b2faac65f33845b3dd70f9fa9e9aa7e3.png" alt="Sapolsky_TH-F1" width="314" height="177">
</a>
</p>
<div>
<p><span>
<span>

<span><a href="http://m.nautil.us/term/f/Environment">Also in Environment</a></span>&nbsp;&nbsp;</span>
</span></p><h4><a href="http://m.nautil.us/issue/85/Reopening/welcome-back-animals" data-trval="welcome-back-animals" data-trlbl="foc_rec" data-tract="internal_art">Welcome Back, Animals!</a></h4>
<p>By  Pamela Yeh &amp; Ian MacGregor-Fors</p>
<p>
The shelter-in-place orders and the massive drop in human activity in our cities, designed to slow the spread of COVID-19, have given us surprising and unexpected sightings of wildlife species across cities around the world. But beyond general awe—and a...<strong><a href="http://m.nautil.us/issue/85/Reopening/welcome-back-animals" data-trval="welcome-back-animals" data-trlbl="foc_rec" data-tract="internal_art">READ MORE</a></strong>
</p>

</div>

</article>
</div><p>Bumblebees experience similar problems, and the citizen-science survey I described endeavored to generate information about wild …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://m.nautil.us/issue/95/escape/we-crush-poison-and-destroy-insects-at-our-own-peril">http://m.nautil.us/issue/95/escape/we-crush-poison-and-destroy-insects-at-our-own-peril</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://m.nautil.us/issue/95/escape/we-crush-poison-and-destroy-insects-at-our-own-peril</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25901384</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 09:52:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Papercraft Models of Computers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 177 | Comments 26 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25898063">thread link</a>) | @laurex
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | http://rockybergen.com/papercraft | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://rockybergen.com/papercraft">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section id="page" role="main" data-content-field="main-content">
      <!-- CATEGORY NAV -->
      
      <div data-type="page" data-updated-on="1592534389753" id="page-5c40ced8575d1f4191811561"><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-0348a58188a4ef2cb7ff"><div><p>Construct the computer from your childhood or build an entire computer museum at home with these paper models, free to download and share.<br>Print, Cut, Score, Fold and Glue.</p></div></div></div></div><div><div><div data-aspect-ratio="75" data-block-type="5" id="block-7348027484c80743e6ed"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547751317778-HWMYNDK2JW0LTOB6EBZP/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kN_ZoNdj1kv_gIvm4zjH76N7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0n54Bn8e90W9qBf-smZxzROWPWatu8N4myd8qBOjLXoKr7eLilP27nxMq5hFavDR2g/IMG_3082.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547751317778-HWMYNDK2JW0LTOB6EBZP/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kN_ZoNdj1kv_gIvm4zjH76N7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0n54Bn8e90W9qBf-smZxzROWPWatu8N4myd8qBOjLXoKr7eLilP27nxMq5hFavDR2g/IMG_3082.png" data-image-dimensions="2500x1786" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="IMG_3082.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c40cf83352f5396d76f7ac3" data-type="image" src="http://rockybergen.com/IMG_3082.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-3fa377625522c866e7f3"><div><h3>AMIGA 500</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="https://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/1/15/amiga-500-papercraft-design">here</a>.                                                              German New Art Edition <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/8/8/amiga-500-new-art-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1547751162669_11811"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547751729623-C59CLX1IAXB7W7VT5Y32/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/front-oregon-trail-alt.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547751729623-C59CLX1IAXB7W7VT5Y32/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/front-oregon-trail-alt.png" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="front-oregon-trail-alt.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c40d12442bfc12f9674aa5a" data-type="image" src="http://rockybergen.com/front-oregon-trail-alt.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1590324703951_24581"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1590325638875-4KWH1QV0IOF6T55KOG17/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kGJPosOZKJ_5bTt_aoKLXvV7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmNO4gLeMELCxgbq9ZwIFBqyNnwMzbLyu6EqVFxy448Ac96U4dydQe93OYlnDwKBkA/Apple+Macintosh+128K+Model" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1590325638875-4KWH1QV0IOF6T55KOG17/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kGJPosOZKJ_5bTt_aoKLXvV7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmNO4gLeMELCxgbq9ZwIFBqyNnwMzbLyu6EqVFxy448Ac96U4dydQe93OYlnDwKBkA/Apple+Macintosh+128K+Model" data-image-dimensions="1126x1126" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Apple Macintosh 128K Model" data-load="false" data-image-id="5eca7180250a6a0b1a797f88" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1590324703951_28199"><div><h3>Apple Macintosh 128K</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2020/5/22/apple-macintosh-128k-papercraft-design">here</a>.                                                                             </p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1592415789136_26033"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1592415990253-RN2H94KYOJUE65PPBML4/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKAIkQk1kT2ThXQe37c2Cyd7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1Ub-K2BP0W1-5FW-m4FzjPBuXfWKGAAA0gU_rp4yEhj2SOpYghpI-Ha_TwZsqqmJXng/BBC+Microcomputer+Papercraft+Model" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1592415990253-RN2H94KYOJUE65PPBML4/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKAIkQk1kT2ThXQe37c2Cyd7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1Ub-K2BP0W1-5FW-m4FzjPBuXfWKGAAA0gU_rp4yEhj2SOpYghpI-Ha_TwZsqqmJXng/BBC+Microcomputer+Papercraft+Model" data-image-dimensions="2332x2332" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="BBC Microcomputer Papercraft Model" data-load="false" data-image-id="5eea56aac4488718b636214d" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1592416156070_26814"><div><h3>BBC MicrocompUteR</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2020/6/17/bbc-microcomputer-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1588440149019_23238"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1588440199899-VSNOEOMJTK66IJ6W9RB4/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kGYKcJaEz4vNz2pgt2fQSqlZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpzBgejzEWRPSQ4sX_EGpmnNOvTH6DYc2wKq80NTw9ecR6Vk-vvLi9jwd_7VQTLTqao/Commodore+VIC-20" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1588440199899-VSNOEOMJTK66IJ6W9RB4/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kGYKcJaEz4vNz2pgt2fQSqlZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpzBgejzEWRPSQ4sX_EGpmnNOvTH6DYc2wKq80NTw9ecR6Vk-vvLi9jwd_7VQTLTqao/Commodore+VIC-20" data-image-dimensions="695x695" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Commodore VIC-20" data-load="false" data-image-id="5eadac7d0ef55d3237cb1ad4" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1588440149019_29173"><div><h3>CoMMODORE VIC-20</h3><p>Link to the latest model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2020/5/2/commodore-vic-20-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1547775615568_46583"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547777663528-ODP80GVLTUA3SJ8S6CD2/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/IBM-5100-Front-v003.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547777663528-ODP80GVLTUA3SJ8S6CD2/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/IBM-5100-Front-v003.png" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="IBM-5100-Front-v003.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c4136514ae237dd786a3b4e" data-type="image" src="http://rockybergen.com/IBM-5100-Front-v003.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1563325615886_43244"><div><h3>IBM 5100 Portable computer</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/12/19/ibm-5100-portable-computer">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1553908991580_15079"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1553909419711-DLINHA95G40WJTJ6B94E/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIuDfvWaFR2Iqed7asMOKyt7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmT9vpqXpgR-5jHl5KNyQ_vOUsaE--K8qAsnBiQUVvocXgZXG9SlBsDZM_BtsjcH9x/IMSAI+8080-+Model" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1553909419711-DLINHA95G40WJTJ6B94E/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIuDfvWaFR2Iqed7asMOKyt7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmT9vpqXpgR-5jHl5KNyQ_vOUsaE--K8qAsnBiQUVvocXgZXG9SlBsDZM_BtsjcH9x/IMSAI+8080-+Model" data-image-dimensions="1483x1483" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="IMSAI 8080- Model" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c9ec6990d92972348b97907" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1571765454448_164008"><div><h3>IMSAI 8080 (PCS-80 SYSTEM)</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="https://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/3/27/imsai-8080">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1547775615568_30953"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547777301331-LA12J4F2DIEBFGMU9166/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/IMG_2254.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547777301331-LA12J4F2DIEBFGMU9166/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/IMG_2254.png" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="IMG_2254.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c4134f1352f53176e89c64d" data-type="image" src="http://rockybergen.com/IMG_2254.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1571765454448_179064"><div><h3>Nintendo GAMECUBE</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/7/21/nintendo-gamecube-papercraft">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1558838880993_46488"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1558839026356-XPE1RQDGOLE6PZAL1UAC/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/Sharp+X68000+Papercraft+Model+Pattern" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1558839026356-XPE1RQDGOLE6PZAL1UAC/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/Sharp+X68000+Papercraft+Model+Pattern" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Sharp X68000 Papercraft Model Pattern" data-load="false" data-image-id="5ce9fecce79c7041acbdfad7" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1574732675505_142131"><div><h3>SHARP X68000</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/5/25/sharp-x68000-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1574732675505_151289"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1574733683491-TX601XVQ4LT92TVKUWTO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/TRS-80+Model+III+Papercraft+Model" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1574733683491-TX601XVQ4LT92TVKUWTO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/TRS-80+Model+III+Papercraft+Model" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="TRS-80 Model III Papercraft Model" data-load="false" data-image-id="5ddc872ee9c9ef3d618bdab0" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1590324703951_73296"><div><h3>TRS-80 Model III</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/11/12/trs-80-model-iii-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div></div><div><div data-aspect-ratio="75" data-block-type="5" id="block-8b4182343a2e489b8831"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547751560304-UUUZ08G6JUN0O58IM2G7/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/front-1.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547751560304-UUUZ08G6JUN0O58IM2G7/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/front-1.png" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="front-1.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c40d0751ae6cf0259ec0e75" data-type="image" src="http://rockybergen.com/front-1.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-3aba1e0c24085fad1534"><div><h3>AmSTRAD CPC 464</h3><p>Link to the latest model <a href="https://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/11/30/amstrad-cpc-464-papercraft-20">here</a>.                                                                                 Prev: <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2017/1/21/amstradcpc">v1</a></p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1571765454448_147172"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1571765716167-0UFNI66U7DBDC1LIEGNS/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/Apple+-+Lisa+1" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1571765716167-0UFNI66U7DBDC1LIEGNS/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/Apple+-+Lisa+1" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Apple - Lisa 1" data-load="false" data-image-id="5daf3dc5a50ae018ef6f1f2f" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1571765454448_149636"><div><h3>APPLE - LISA 1</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="https://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/10/17/apple-lisa-1-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1549746001726_22861"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1549746395018-JW1I4T79NKIQLXYGD2SP/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0s0XaMNjCqAzRibjnE_wBlkZ2axuMlPfqFLWy-3Tjp4nKScCHg1XF4aLsQJlo6oYbA/Atari+520+ST" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1549746395018-JW1I4T79NKIQLXYGD2SP/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0s0XaMNjCqAzRibjnE_wBlkZ2axuMlPfqFLWy-3Tjp4nKScCHg1XF4aLsQJlo6oYbA/Atari+520+ST" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Atari 520 ST" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c5f40bf8165f527b770bddb" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1590324703951_68471"><div><h3>ATARI 520ST</h3><p>Link to the latest model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/2/9/atari-520-st-papercraft-design">here</a>.    </p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1547775615568_7710"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547775762408-DNREFI406UJMGRBUDYAZ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kH7bcx_p807l_7aJvGUB_uN7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0moOD8BDhkEvmr_flZVBtwIChsuiQhyTIkjVQ5JuE40aqe9Md01nIM06lR7f9JJmiQ/C64_Mini_Computer_Papercraft-Basic-2.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547775762408-DNREFI406UJMGRBUDYAZ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kH7bcx_p807l_7aJvGUB_uN7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0moOD8BDhkEvmr_flZVBtwIChsuiQhyTIkjVQ5JuE40aqe9Md01nIM06lR7f9JJmiQ/C64_Mini_Computer_Papercraft-Basic-2.png" data-image-dimensions="2500x2499" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="C64_Mini_Computer_Papercraft-Basic-2.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c412ecf4ae237dd7869e612" data-type="image" src="http://rockybergen.com/C64_Mini_Computer_Papercraft-Basic-2.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1549746001726_26611"><div><h3>COMMODORE 64</h3><p>Link to the latest model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/6/28/commodore-64-papercraft-v3">here</a>.                                                                             Prev: <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/3/30/c64minimonitor">v1</a>, <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/4/5/commodore-64-paper-craft">v2</a>, <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/6/14/commodore-1541-disk-drive-papercraft">v3</a> </p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1563325615886_42967"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1563325867306-T0QGQTZZW2IN3FPM5NH6/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/IBM+5150+Personal+Computer" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1563325867306-T0QGQTZZW2IN3FPM5NH6/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/IBM+5150+Personal+Computer" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="IBM 5150 Personal Computer" data-load="false" data-image-id="5d2e754e8f2287000141be63" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1571765454448_182957"><div><h3>IBM 5150 PERSONAL Computer</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/7/16/ibm-5150-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1553262122748_51565"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1553262699056-FOSE3WO4IMXPUM9GEBK0/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kJNqsDNR92Zm0lZEzPpS63h7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UaQfK7iYtFaG3VRabrZaB72zP5b12zwkFkkazYM2Ml-E3WUfc_ZsVm9Mi1E6FasEnQ/Nintendo+Advanced+Video+System" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1553262699056-FOSE3WO4IMXPUM9GEBK0/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kJNqsDNR92Zm0lZEzPpS63h7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UaQfK7iYtFaG3VRabrZaB72zP5b12zwkFkkazYM2Ml-E3WUfc_ZsVm9Mi1E6FasEnQ/Nintendo+Advanced+Video+System" data-image-dimensions="2375x2375" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Nintendo Advanced Video System" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c94e85b085229d4d73c7e67" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1563325615886_54104"><div><h3>Nintendo ADVANCED VIDEO SYSTEM (PROTOTYPE)</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="https://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/3/2/nintendo-avs-prototype-1983">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1574732675505_143092"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1574733462182-PO1EQFO7VFZMCXO4TERQ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/Sega+Master+System+Papercraft+Model" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1574733462182-PO1EQFO7VFZMCXO4TERQ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/Sega+Master+System+Papercraft+Model" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Sega Master System Papercraft Model" data-load="false" data-image-id="5ddc864af95aa874645141f9" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1574732675505_145992"><div><h3>SEGA MASTER SYSTEM</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/11/14/sega-master-system-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1568075226922_49660"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1568075967367-ZG7V8Q7F3YITXZPQ2TJG/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0s0XaMNjCqAzRibjnE_wBlkZ2axuMlPfqFLWy-3Tjp4nKScCHg1XF4aLsQJlo6oYbA/Sinclair+ZX+Spectrum" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1568075967367-ZG7V8Q7F3YITXZPQ2TJG/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0s0XaMNjCqAzRibjnE_wBlkZ2axuMlPfqFLWy-3Tjp4nKScCHg1XF4aLsQJlo6oYbA/Sinclair+ZX+Spectrum" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Sinclair ZX Spectrum" data-load="false" data-image-id="5d76f0ab4daeac2b978c3f92" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1574732675505_134908"><div><h3>Sinclair ZX Spectrum</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/8/17/sinclair-zx-spectrum-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1547775615568_28037"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547776357981-CB2AMVR04ZPDOBNLYJPM/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/front-2.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547776357981-CB2AMVR04ZPDOBNLYJPM/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/front-2.png" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="front-2.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c41313e03ce6448e4275b88" data-type="image" src="http://rockybergen.com/front-2.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1574732675505_149608"><div><h3>CONION C-100F</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/8/11/conion-c-100f-papercraft">here</a>.</p></div></div></div></div></div>
    </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://rockybergen.com/papercraft</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25898063</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 01:33:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The RustyHermit Unikernel]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 101 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25897117">thread link</a>) | @adamnemecek
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://rust-osdev.com/showcase/rusty-hermit/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rust-osdev.com/showcase/rusty-hermit/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <main>
    

    

    <p><a href="https://github.com/hermitcore/rusty-hermit">RustyHermit</a> is a unikernel, which is completely written Rust. <a href="http://unikernel.org/">Unikernels</a> are application images that directly contain the kernel as a library, so they do not require an installed operating system (OS).&nbsp;They are typical used in virtualized environments, which build the backbone of typical cloud / edge infrastructures.</p>
<span id="continue-reading"></span>


<h2 id="virtualization-designs">Virtualization Designs</h2>
<p>Common virtualized environments are based on classical <strong><em>virtual machines</em></strong>. In this case, complete machines are emulated or virtualized and common operating systems are running on both host and guest site:</p>
<p><img src="https://rust-osdev.com/showcase/rusty-hermit/common_vm.png" alt="Structure of a common virtualitation environment"></p>
<p>This technique is established (VMware, Hyper-V, etc.) and widely used. However, it introduces additional overhead especially regarding memory consumption and performance.</p>
<p>An alternative approach to common virtual machines is <strong><em>OS-level
virtualization</em></strong>, where the&nbsp;kernel&nbsp;allows the existence of multiple
isolated&nbsp;user space&nbsp;instances. These isolated instances are also known
as container. A typical representative is LXC or Docker and promise less
overhead in comparison to common virtual machines. However, the
isolation between the processes is weaker and may provide less security.</p>
<h2 id="unikernels">Unikernels</h2>
<p>Often only one application (e.g. a web server) is running in the container or the virtual machine. In this case, a <em>unikernel</em> is an attractive solution. The kernel is provided as static library and linked to the application. As the images directly contain the OS kernel, unikernels can directly be booted inside a virtual machine and do not require the typical software stack containing a Linux kernel and its userland within the VM.</p>
<p>Unikernels do not provide system calls in the classical sense, as everything is running with the privilege level of a kernel and what is typically done via system calls is provided via a common function call. At first glance, this sounds more insecure than previous approaches. However, these kernels are expected to run within a virtual machine, which isolates the application from the real system. In addition, common compiler analysis is used to check the complete software stack and unneeded components can even be removed, which can reduce the attack surface of the application.</p>
<p><img src="https://rust-osdev.com/showcase/rusty-hermit/libos.png" alt="Structure of a library operating system"></p>
<p>Well known unikernels are kernels such as <a href="https://mirage.io/">MirageOS</a>
and <a href="http://www.unikraft.org/">Unikraft</a>. MirageOS is written in OCaml,
while Unikraft still uses C as programming language. In contrast to these
kernels, RustyHermit is completely written in Rust to benefit from
Rust's performance and security behavior.</p>
<h2 id="rustyhermit">RustyHermit</h2>
<p>In principle, every existing
Rust application can be built on top of RustyHermit. However, unikernels
are a single tasking operating system. Consequently, the support of the
system call <code>fork</code> and inter-process communication are missing. In
addition, a classical C library is missing, which is typical used as
interface to the operating system. Every crate, which bypasses the
standard runtime and tries to communicate directly to operating system
does not work without modifications. However, many applications do not
depend on these features and work on RustyHermit.</p>
<h3 id="performance">Performance</h3>
<p>Unikernels can be highly optimized. For instance, we optimized the
network stack of RustyHermit. RustyHermit uses
<a href="https://github.com/smoltcp-rs/smoltcp">smoltcp</a> as network stack, which
is completely written in Rust. As interface between guest and host
operating system, we use
<a href="https://www.linux-kvm.org/page/Virtio">Virtio</a>, which is in a
para-virtualized driver for KVM and widely used in virtualized Linux
environments.</p>
<p>The following figure compares Linux with RustyHermit,
where both are running as guests inside a virtual machine running on top
of a Linux-based host system:</p>
<p><img src="https://rust-osdev.com/showcase/rusty-hermit/bandwidth.png" alt="Bandwidth of the RustyHermit's exerimental network interface"></p>
<p>Especially for small messages RustHermit
is faster in than Linux.</p>
<h3 id="research">Research</h3>
<p>RustyHermit is also a research project to evaluate new operating
system designs, which improves the scalability and the security of operating systems in cloud environments. For instance, RustyHermit provides classical
techniques to improve the security behavior like stack guards and
separating the application stack from the libOS stack. However, a
library operating system typically uses a common function call to enter
the kernel. A classical separation of user- and kernel space by
entering a higher privilege level is missing.</p>
<p>We presented in a
<a href="https://www.ssrg.ece.vt.edu/papers/vee20-mpk.pdf">paper</a> a modified
version of RustyHermit, which provides an intra-unikernel isolation with
<em>Intel Memory Protection Keys</em> (MPK). MPK is a relatively new hardware
primitive that provides per-thread permission control over groups of
pages in a single address space with <a href="https://www.usenix.org/conference/atc19/presentation/park-soyeon">negligible switching overhead</a>,
making it a compelling candidate for use in unikernels.</p>
<p>MPK is requiring modification of page tables at a small performance cost. Four previously-unused bits of each page table entry (the 62nd to the 59th on x86-64) are exploited by MPK. Since MPK exploits four bits of the page table entry, it supports up to 15 protection keys.
MPK controls per-thread permission on groups of pages. Each core has a PKRU register (32 bits) containing a permission value. The value of the PKRU register defines the permission of the thread currently running on that core for each group of pages containing a protection key in their page table entries. Unlike page-table-level permission, MPK provides thread-local memory permission.</p>
<p>We provide user / kernel separation so we simply see the entire application as an untrusted component, independently of application-specific characteristics such as the language it is written in or the level of skill of the application’s programmer. In addition, we divide the kernel code into trusted and untrusted components. Trusted kernel components represent pieces of code written with a memory-safe language, i.e., offering strong security guarantees. Untrusted kernel components correspond to code written either in memory-unsafe languages or in unsafe Rust code blocks.</p>
<p>By entering the library operating system through the application binary interface the protection keys will be automatically changed, which allows access to the kernel stack and the kernel heap. Unauthorized access from within the application will trigger a pagefault, which will be handled by the library operating system.</p>
<h3 id="example-project">Example Project</h3>
<p>To give you an example on how to build an RustyHermit application, lets create a new cargo project:</p>
<pre><code><span>cargo</span><span> new hello_world
</span><span>cd</span><span> hello_world
</span></code></pre>
<p>RustyHermit currently requires the nightly versions of the Rust toolchain.
To simplify the workflow, we recommend to create the configuration
<em>rust-toolchain</em> as follows to define the required components and to
tested version of nightly compiler:</p>
<pre><code><span>[toolchain]
</span><span>channel </span><span>= "</span><span>nightly-2020-12-23</span><span>"
</span><span>components </span><span>= [ "</span><span>rustfmt</span><span>", "</span><span>rust-src</span><span>", "</span><span>llvm-tools-preview</span><span>"]
</span><span>targets </span><span>= [ "</span><span>x86_64-unknown-hermit</span><span>" ]
</span></code></pre>
<p>The configuration file specifies the required components and the version of the nightly compiler to use.</p>
<p>The RustyHermit's target <code>x86_64-unknown-hermit</code> is part of Rust
supported platforms, but doesn't belong to the <em>tier 1</em> platforms,
which means that official binary releases aren't available and the
standard runtime must be build from scratch.
To simplify this build process, we recommend to create the configuration
file <code>.cargo/config</code> as follows:</p>
<pre><code><span>[unstable]
</span><span>build-std </span><span>= ["</span><span>std</span><span>", "</span><span>core</span><span>", "</span><span>alloc</span><span>", "</span><span>panic_abort</span><span>"]

[build]
</span><span>target </span><span>= "</span><span>x86_64-unknown-hermit</span><span>"
</span></code></pre>
<p>To bind the library operating system to the application, we have to add the crate <a href="https://crates.io/crates/hermit-sys"><code>hermit-sys</code></a> to the dependencies in the file <code>Cargo.toml</code>:</p>
<pre><code><span># Cargo.toml

</span><span>[target.'</span><span>cfg(target_os = "hermit")</span><span>'.dependencies]
</span><span>hermit-sys </span><span>= "</span><span>0.1.*</span><span>"
</span><span>features </span><span>= ["</span><span>smoltcp</span><span>"]
</span></code></pre>
<p>The feature <code>smoltcp</code> is required if your application tries
to establish a TCP connection. In this case, the library operating systems
includes the TCP/stack <a href="https://github.com/smoltcp-rs/smoltcp">smoltcp</a>.
In addition <em>hermit-sys</em> depends on the tool <a href="https://crates.io/crates/cargo-download">cargo-download</a> to download required components and must be installed with the command <code>cargo install cargo-download</code>.
Finally, the application can be build with the common command <code>cargo build</code>.</p>
<p>The result is a 64-bit excutable in the <a href="https://refspecs.linuxfoundation.org/elf/elf.pdf">executable link format</a> (ELF).
To start the application within a common virtual machine, a loader is required, which initialize the processor and start the applications.
We provide a simple loader on <a href="https://github.com/hermitcore/rusty-loader">GitHub</a>.
A makefile to build the loader is part of the project.
After that, Qemu can be used to start RustyHermit in a VM as follows:</p>
<pre><code><span>qemu-system-x86_64 -display</span><span> none</span><span> -smp</span><span> 1</span><span> -m</span><span> 64M</span><span> -serial</span><span> stdio</span><span>  -kernel</span><span> path_to_loader/rusty-loader</span><span> -initrd</span><span> path_to_app/app</span><span> -cpu</span><span> qemu64,apic,fsgsbase,rdtscp,xsave,fxsr
</span></code></pre>
<p>To improve the performance, KVM can be used to use the virtualization extension of modern processors.</p>
<pre><code><span>qemu-system-x86_64 -display</span><span> none</span><span> -smp</span><span> 1</span><span> -m</span><span> 64M</span><span> -serial</span><span> stdio</span><span>  -kernel</span><span> path_to_loader/rusty-loader</span><span> -initrd</span><span> path_to_hello_world/hello_world</span><span> -enable-kvm -cpu</span><span> host
</span></code></pre><h3 id="roadmap">Roadmap</h3>
<p>For the near future, we plan to stabilize the interface to the hardware.
For instance, the support of <a href="https://virtio-fs.gitlab.io/">Virtio-fs</a>
is in an early stage. In addition, the integration into Rust standard
library isn't finalized yet and the current version runs only on x86. In the
future, we want to also support aarch64 as processor architecture.</p>


    

    
</main>

            
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rust-osdev.com/showcase/rusty-hermit/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25897117</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 23:01:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Proof of X]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 159 | Comments 59 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25895996">thread link</a>) | @dguo
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://julian.digital/2020/08/06/proof-of-x/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://julian.digital/2020/08/06/proof-of-x/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
 		
<p><span>01</span> Intro</p>



<p>Sparked by <a href="https://twitter.com/dwr/status/1273307320911450112">an interesting Twitter discussion</a>, I’ve spent a lot of time recently thinking about different proof-of-work mechanisms. </p>



<p>When I say proof-of-work, I’m not talking about consensus algorithms like the ones that some crypto currencies use. I’m talking about social networks.</p>



<p>At their core, social networks are primarily about one thing: Building social capital through signaling. As I wrote in <a href="http://julian.digital/2020/03/28/signaling-as-a-service/">Signaling as a Service</a>, signaling can be broken down into three different components:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Signaling Message</strong><br>A hidden status subtext you’re trying to convey about yourself</li><li><strong>Signaling Distribution</strong><br>The channel through which you’re communicating your signaling message</li><li><strong>Signaling Amplification</strong><br>Ways to boost your signaling message to compete against status rivals</li></ul>



<p>For example: A Patagonia vest signals both a prosocial attitude (<em>“I care about the environment</em>“) as well as wealth (“<em>I can afford to spend $500 on a jacket</em>“). Depending on where you live, it might also signal something about <a href="https://vcstarterkit.com/">your occupation</a>.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/patagucci.png"></p><p>In order to signal these messages to others and build actual social capital you need a signaling distribution channel. One option would be to wear the vest in public where others can see it – but there are obvious physical constraints to the size of the audience you’d be able to reach.</p>



<p>This is where social networks come in.</p>



<p>Their primary role is to distribute signaling messages at scale and transform them into quantifiable social capital (in the form of likes and followers).</p>



<p>As social networks grow, they increase the potential reach of your signaling messages – but they also get crowded with status rivals. This is why social networks typically provide you with a set of signaling amplification tools. These tools help you boost your signaling messages and stand out from the crowd.</p>



<p>In <a href="http://julian.digital/2020/03/28/signaling-as-a-service/">Signaling as a Service</a> I compared signaling amplification to <a href="https://www.eugenewei.com/blog/2019/2/19/status-as-a-service">Eugene Wei’s idea of proof-of-work hurdles</a>, which he describes as follows:</p>



<p><i>Almost every social network of note had an early signature proof of work hurdle. For Facebook it was posting some witty text-based status update. For Instagram, it was posting an interesting square photo. For Vine, an entertaining 6-second video. For Twitter, it was writing an amusing bit of text of 140 characters or fewer. Pinterest? Pinning a compelling photo. You can likely derive the proof of work for other networks like Quora and Reddit and Twitch and so on. Successful social networks don’t pose trick questions at the start, it’s usually clear what they want from you.</i></p>



<p>But the more I think about it, the less I like the comparison. I actually think that Eugene’s proof-of-work theory only scratches the surface of what social networks actually do.</p>



<p>Let me explain.</p>



<p><span>02</span> A closer look at proof mechanisms</p>



<p>Take a look at this very cliché Instagram picture. The photographer clearly put a lot of thought and effort into its composition and applied different filters and editing tools to make it look nicer.</p>



<figure>
<img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/creativework.png">
<figcaption><span>Full disclosure: I actually took this picture from Unsplash. No influencers were harmed during the production of this blog post.<br></span>
</figcaption></figure>



<p>It’s a perfect example of Eugene’s definition of proof-of-work. <br>Proof-of-<strong><em>creative</em></strong>-work, to be more exact. </p>



<p>Editing your photo helps to amplify your signaling message and sets you apart within Instagram’s status arena (aka the newsfeed). It also adds additional signaling messages to your post: <em>“Look how great a photographer I am”</em> or <em>“I’m a creative person”</em>.</p>



<p>But those are not the main signaling messages you are communicating here. What you really want to tell your followers with this photo is something along the lines of <em>“I’m a world-traveler”</em> and <em>“I’m in a happy relationship”</em> <span>(which in turn are also just signaling proxies for wealth and mating worthiness)</span>. </p>



<p>The photo and the location tag are your proof points.</p>



<figure><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/igexample02-1.png">
<figcaption><span>If you look closely, you’ll notice additional hidden signaling messages in the form of Allbirds sneakers and what’s most likely a Patagonia vest → proof-of-ownership<br></span>
</figcaption></figure>



<p>Social networks are therefore not only signaling distribution (and amplification) networks – they also allow users to prove their signaling messages. </p>



<p>The creative proof-of-work is just pretext and helps to boost your post. What’s more important are the additional proof mechanisms that social networks provide. In the case of Instagram those are photos and location tags.</p>



<p>Instagram is essentially “pics or it didn’t happen”-as-a-service.</p>



<p><span>03</span> Implications for new social networks</p>



<p>When new social networks emerge they have to introduce new proof mechanisms to differentiate themselves from existing incumbents. These can either be novel proof-of-creative-work hurdles or completely new proof-of-x mechanisms.</p>



<p>TikTok is a good example for proof-of-<em>creative</em>-work innovation. The app provides creators with a powerful set of video editing tools that have opened a whole new level of creativity. </p>



<p>The cost to participate in TikTok’s status game is a lot higher than Instagram’s <span>(compare a well-made dance choreography on TikTok to your median Instagram travel post)</span> – but its powerful feed algorithms also make discovery easier and thus reward users faster and with more social capital. </p>



<p>TikTok doesn’t add any new proof points beyond its novel creative work hurdle though. You can signal and prove your creativity but you could achieve the same by uploading your video to Instagram.</p>



<p>Strava, on the other hand, introduced an entirely new proof mechanism: Proof-of-physical-activity. By using your phone’s GPS sensor (or a 3rd-party fitness tracker), users can actually prove how much and fast they ran or cycled. In contrast to <a href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2017/10/20/grounded-private-jet-hire-helps-russians-fake-lavish-lifestyles/">Instagram</a> <a href="https://www.vice.com/da/article/wdaqgw/instagrams-ballers-discount-private-jets-324">photos</a>, Strava’s proof mechanism is a lot harder to fake <span>(though there are <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=fake+strava+5k+downhill&amp;oq=fake+strava+5k+downhill">exceptions</a>)</span>.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/stravaproof.png"></p><p>What’s great about Strava is that it reinforces a behavior that’s actually good for you: While the status game that initially got you into the app might be zero sum, the actual physical exercise you have to put in to compete has a very positive, compounding effect.</p>



<p>The question is: What other social networks should we build that could have similar positive feedback loops? And what are their proof mechanisms?</p>



<p><span>04</span> Strava for X</p>



<p>Let’s start with the two examples in <a href="https://twitter.com/dwr/status/1273307320911450112">this tweet</a>.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/tweetstrava.png"></p><p>I love the idea of a <strong>Strava for Cooking</strong> – but I’m very skeptical that it can be built. Why? Because the necessary proof mechanisms don’t exist.</p>



<p>The primary metric you optimize on when cooking is taste. But how would you measure or quantify taste? The closest proxy to taste that we have is optics: How good does the meal that you cooked look? This can easily be proved with a photo .. but that’s a proof-of-work mechanism that Instagram already offers (including filters to make your food look nicer). As long as no one comes up with a better proof mechanism for cooking, I think it’s unlikely that we will see a successful social network in the space.</p>



<p>I’m more optimistic about <strong>Strava for Learning</strong>.</p>



<p>While the activity of learning itself might be hard to quantify, you can measure the outcome of learning: knowledge. Has anyone built a multiplayer version of <a href="https://apps.ankiweb.net/">Anki</a> yet? Flash cards would be a perfect proof-of-knowledge mechanism and could easily be turned into a game where you compete against friends.</p>



<p>Similar to physical activity in the Strava example, learning is not something that most people enjoy doing. As TikTok founder <a href="https://youtu.be/wTyg2E44pBA?t=245">Alex Zhu points out</a>, education goes a little against human nature. In combination with a strong enough signaling mechanism however, you can get users to participate. It’s kind of the opposite of <a href="https://cdixon.org/2015/01/31/come-for-the-tool-stay-for-the-network">Chris Dixon’s famous “Come for the tool, stay for the network” strategy</a>. Come for the status, stay for the tool.</p>



<p>A related product I’d love to see is <strong>Strava for Reading</strong>. Imagine an eBook reader that not only tracks how much time you spend reading but also *what* you are reading. Based on these proof-of-(reading)-work mechanisms you could build streaks or GitHub-contributions-like visualizations that incentivize users to read more (and more regularly).</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/githubforreading.png"></p><p>You could even build leaderboards for different topics based on the content of the books and articles you read. Or think about a score that indicated how balanced your reading behavior per topic was (to incentivize users to read takes on political topics from different perspectives).</p>



<p>Unfortunately, I think it’s unlikely that we will see a product like I described anytime soon. <a href="https://twitter.com/lehrjulian/status/1086659965719404544">The world’s largest bookstore, most popular eBook reader, and biggest social network for books</a> are all owned by a company that has very little competency in design and user-facing product innovation.</p>



<p>(Side note: Amazon’s monopoly on books might be the most underrated sub-optimal equilibrium in tech.)</p>



<p>Another app that would be interesting is a social investing app. Think “Robinhood but as a social network”. It seems like investing is already quite a social activity – just look at <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-02-26/reddit-s-profane-greedy-traders-are-shaking-up-the-stock-market">communities like r/wallstreetbets</a>. As <a href="https://twitter.com/patio11/status/1250703738634829824">patio11 pointed out</a>, Robinhood already feels more like a game than a finance app.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/robinhood.png"></p><p>So why not build an investing app that opens with a feed of all your friends’ investments and their returns over time? Instead of sharing screenshots on Reddit and Instagram you could prove your investments right in the app.</p>



<p><strong>Note that an app like this would not be about signaling wealth. It’s about signaling <em>being right</em> and the ability to prove it</strong>. This is probably an even stronger and more engaging mechanism than signaling wealth – and the reason why I’m still bullish on prediction markets.</p>



<p>Perhaps a well-designed, consumer-friendly prediction market app would be the ultimate proof-of-x social network. <strong>Strava for being right.</strong></p>



<p><span>05</span> A Closing Ask</p>



<p>While we are on the topic of being right: Do you agree with my thoughts in this post? What other social networks and proof-of-x mechanisms would you like to see?</p>



<p>Please leave <a href="https://twitter.com/lehrjulian/status/1291397928788135942">your comments here</a>.</p>







<p><em>Thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/dwr">Dan Romero</a>, <em><a href="https://twitter.com/destraynor">Des Traynor</a>,</em></em> <em><a href="https://twitter.com/einkoenig">Jan König</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/cutler_max">Max …</a></em></p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://julian.digital/2020/08/06/proof-of-x/">https://julian.digital/2020/08/06/proof-of-x/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://julian.digital/2020/08/06/proof-of-x/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25895996</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 21:02:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Our experience with the Fediverse, and why we left]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 202 | Comments 193 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25894414">thread link</a>) | @dsego
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-12-05-leaving-the-fediverse/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-12-05-leaving-the-fediverse/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>The “Fediverse” is a loose aggregation of federated servers that mainly speak the ActivityPub protocol. One of the most famous services in the Fediverse is “Mastodon.” We joined the Fediverse in the early days of Mastodon to share short-lived information that didn’t fit into a separate article on our website.</p><h2 id="the-issues-that-we-discussed-earlier-this-year">The issues that we discussed earlier this year</h2><p>In May, <a href="https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-05-31-monthly-review/#fediverse">we reconsidered our presence in the Fediverse</a>. Back then, the main issues for us were:</p><ol><li>You can’t migrate your posts if you need to migrate to another Mastodon server.</li><li>You can’t update your posts without losing shares and comments.</li><li>All posts have a character limit, so we can’t say everything we want in a single post.</li><li>Many Fediverse users claim to be the “better and open-minded alternative to Twitter.” We think that this doesn’t reflect reality, as explained below.</li></ol><p>In June, we addressed issues 1 to 3 by introducing a “News” section on our website.</p><h2 id="further-issues-in-the-fediverse-and-other-social-networks">Further issues in the Fediverse and other social networks</h2><p>We also participated in discussions and tried to encourage dialogs in the Fediverse and other forums instead of only posting information. However, these discussions revealed consistent issues:</p><h3 id="the-toxic-us-vs-them-ideology">The toxic “us vs. them” ideology</h3><p>For some groups, it is vital to make a bogeyman out of opposing parties. In the Fediverse, some individuals and groups continuously spread misinformation about “the others” to gain likes and followers. While most of the toxic behavior targets the big tech companies in the USA, some individuals targetting us.</p><h3 id="the-reverse-burden-of-proof">The “reverse burden of proof”</h3><p>When discussing with others, we often encountered the “reverse burden of proof.” Somebody posts negative claims about a product or service. Instead of providing (technical) proof for the claim, the only supporting “fact” is, “everybody knows that this is true.” On the contrary, this person doesn’t accept any (technical) proof that debunks their initial claim. For us, it looks like you don’t need to provide any real facts as long as you satisfy the ideology of some people.</p><h3 id="the-i-read-headlines-only-problem">The “I read headlines only” problem</h3><p>Many people read the headlines of a post and then guess what is written in the remaining article. Such behavior results in misinterpreted information and persistent myths. On the other hand, it became a standard tool for some blogs to gain more readers: Writing, “Critical security vulnerability could leak all of your data” results in more clicks and shares than, “Company fixed potential security vulnerability months ago, which could have leaked some of your data if ever exploited.” This problem kills meaningful discussions instantly.</p><h3 id="the-security-and-privacy-by-assumption-problem">The “security and privacy by assumption” problem</h3><p>Most of you know “security by obscurity,” when security relies on keeping the implementation secret. We see another common issue: “security and privacy by assumption.” Many people share security and privacy tips without ever checking whether these tips work. They just assume that somebody else checked it before.</p><h3 id="and-finally-comparing-apples-to-oranges">And finally, “comparing apples to oranges”</h3><p>For instance, some people claim the Signal messenger became insecure after introducing the Signal PIN because a server-side attacker could now access your data. The base for this claim is the assumption that a server-side party extracts encrypted information from the volatile main memory of a server, exploits an unpatched security vulnerability in Intel CPUs to extract a key, and successfully guesses a user-provided password.</p><p>While the attack looks anything but trivial as these people describe it, they then argue that their favorite messenger is far more secure due to being decentralized. They compare the encryption mechanism of instant messenger A with something else. Suppose you look at the same feature of their favorite messenger. In that case, you see that their messenger doesn’t offer any server-side protection. In their case, a server-side party can directly access your data in cleartext—this is trivial.</p><h3 id="im-privacy-friendly-please-donate">“I’m privacy-friendly; please donate”</h3><p>The issues mentioned above are also prevalent on other social networks like Twitter. Just like on Twitter, you see “privacy-friendly” companies trying to gain more paying customers or some bloggers heavily involved in influencer marketing. While most of them claim that this is for a “good cause,” it is ultimately all about money.</p><h3 id="decentralization-still-isnt-a-privacy-feature">Decentralization still isn’t a privacy feature</h3><p>Now, some people may insist that at least security and privacy are far better “due to the decentralized nature” of the Fediverse. As we wrote several times before, “decentralization” isn’t a privacy feature.</p><p>Search engines like Google can discover and index all of your public posts in the Fediverse. By default, you can see the social graphs of all accounts, as followers are public. Especially Mastodon servers come with privacy policies that don’t meet the European GDPR requirements. Many (Mastodon) servers seem to run an outdated version, indicating inadequate security practices.</p><h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2><p>Should you become part of the Fediverse by creating an account? It isn’t up to us to decide this, of course.</p><p>If you only want to read the content of others, we recommend subscribing to their RSS feeds. Your RSS subscriptions are private and more decentralized than any Fediverse account. And you need to manage one account less on the internet.</p><p>If you want to be an active part of the Fediverse, be prepared for the same problems as on any other social network. We decided to leave the Fediverse for now.</p><h2>Read also</h2><ul><li><a href="https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-12-20-contact-and-feed/">On contacting us, and subscribing to our RSS feed</a></li><li><a href="https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-11-08-rss-update/">Update of our RSS/Atom feed</a></li><li><a href="https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-08-02-tls-insights/">TLS usage of InfoSec Handbook readers</a></li><li><a href="https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-08-01-introducing-the-news-section/">Introducing the 'News' section</a></li></ul></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-12-05-leaving-the-fediverse/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25894414</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 18:33:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A 10B Pixel Scan of Vermeer’s Masterpiece]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 112 | Comments 44 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25892840">thread link</a>) | @parisianka
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://www.micro-pano.com/pearl/index.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.micro-pano.com/pearl/index.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.micro-pano.com/pearl/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25892840</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 15:35:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Jeff Bezos and Amazon do not want their workers voting by mail on unionization]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 51 | Comments 40 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25889838">thread link</a>) | @jimmy2020
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://www.outkick.com/jeff-bezos-amazon-mail-in-votes/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.outkick.com/jeff-bezos-amazon-mail-in-votes/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
		

		
		<div itemprop="articleBody">
			



<p>Jeff Bezos — a strong Democratic supporter — and Amazon are aiming to postpone a unionization vote at one of its warehouses in Alabama, the <em>Wall Street Journal</em> <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/amazon-seeks-to-postpone-alabama-unionization-vote-11611339250?mod=e2tw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reports</a>. Interestingly, Amazon has requested that the National Labor Relations Board reconsider allowing mail-in voting, claiming that the mail-in voting process has “serious and systemic flaws.”</p>
<p>Got that? Bezos and Amazon are doing all they can to prevent any shady activity when workers cast their ballots for unionization, and they are particularly concerned about the integrity of mail-in ballots.</p>
<p>You are likely trying to figure out how that adds up, right? The <em>Washington Post</em>, owned by Bezos, called any claims of mail-in voter fraud by Donald Trump and his supporters dangerous and inexcusable. Amazon even banned Parler from its servers, in part to ensure no one could claim voter fraud occurred from mail-in ballots back in November.</p>
<p>But stop trying to make it make sense. It is not supposed to add up.</p>
<p>In this case, mail-in voting is disadvantageous for Bezos and his e-commerce behemoth. Therefore, they now consider mail-in voting seriously flawed.</p>
<p>An Amazon spokesperson <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/01/22/tech/amazon-nlrb-union-election/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tells</a> CNN the company is seeking a “valid, fair and successful election” and suggests that only in-person voting can ensure that. Hmm, interesting perspective.</p>
<p>Amazon has, thus far, fended off unions in the United States. If a majority of ballots vote in favor of unionization, hourly Amazon workers would send an L right up to Bezos’ office.</p>
<p>Bamazonunion.com explains that a union at Amazon would “give us the right to collectively bargain over our working conditions including items such as safety standards, training, breaks, pay, benefits, and other important issues that would make our workplace better.”</p>
<p>The NLRB says, “A mail ballot election will enfranchise employees who cannot enter the voting location for health reasons or due to positive COVID tests.” Fearing an unfavorable outcome, however, Amazon now insists that current COVID outbreaks aren’t dangerous enough to warrant this NLRB decision.</p>
<p>Amazon says that Lisa Henderson, NLRB’s Acting Regional Director “reached the remarkable conclusion that any level of infection or potential infection among employees counts as an ‘outbreak.'” <em>O</em><em>nly</em> 218 people employees, 2.88%, at its Bessemer facility tested positive during the 14-day period ending on January 7, which Amazon does not consider an “outbreak” apparently. This is quite the change of perspective. Imagine the coverage from the <em>Washington Post</em> if similar questions had been asked before November.</p>
<p>Mail-in voting has never been about the health of Americans or ensuring that each voice counts. As always, our country’s most powerful figures in both Washington and Silicon Valley base their opinions solely on the outcomes that increase their own power, finances, and flexibility.</p>
<p>Hypocritical, but sadly, all too predictable.</p>
		</div>
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.outkick.com/jeff-bezos-amazon-mail-in-votes/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25889838</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 06:30:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pip has dropped support for Python 2]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 755 | Comments 644 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25888249">thread link</a>) | @groodt
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://pip.pypa.io/en/stable/news/#id1 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://pip.pypa.io/en/stable/news/#id1">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<li><p><strong>PROCESS</strong> Version numbers are now simply <code><span>X.Y</span></code> where the leading <code><span>1</span></code>
has been dropped.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>BACKWARD INCOMPATIBLE</strong> Dropped support for Python 3.1.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>BACKWARD INCOMPATIBLE</strong> Removed the bundle support which was deprecated in
1.4. (#1806)</p></li>
<li><p><strong>BACKWARD INCOMPATIBLE</strong> File lists generated by <cite>pip show -f</cite> are now
rooted at the location reported by show, rather than one (unstated)
directory lower. (#1933)</p></li>
<li><p><strong>BACKWARD INCOMPATIBLE</strong> The ability to install files over the FTP protocol
was accidentally lost in pip 1.5 and it has now been decided to not restore
that ability.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>BACKWARD INCOMPATIBLE</strong> PEP 440 is now fully implemented, this means that
in some cases versions will sort differently or version specifiers will be
interpreted differently than previously. The common cases should all function
similarly to before.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>DEPRECATION</strong> <code><span>pip</span> <span>install</span> <span>--download-cache</span></code> and
<code><span>pip</span> <span>wheel</span> <span>--download-cache</span></code> command line flags have been deprecated and
the functionality removed. Since pip now automatically configures and uses
it’s internal HTTP cache which supplants the <code><span>--download-cache</span></code> the
existing options have been made non functional but will still be accepted
until their removal in pip v8.0. For more information please see
<a href="https://pip.pypa.io/en/stable/reference/pip_install.html#caching">https://pip.pypa.io/en/stable/reference/pip_install.html#caching</a></p></li>
<li><p><strong>DEPRECATION</strong> <code><span>pip</span> <span>install</span> <span>--build</span></code> and <code><span>pip</span> <span>install</span> <span>--no-clean</span></code> are now
<em>NOT</em> deprecated.  This reverses the deprecation that occurred in v1.5.3.
(#906)</p></li>
<li><p><strong>DEPRECATION</strong> Implicitly accessing URLs which point to an origin which is
not a secure origin, instead requiring an opt-in for each host using the new
<code><span>--trusted-host</span></code> flag (<code><span>pip</span> <span>install</span> <span>--trusted-host</span> <span>example.com</span> <span>foo</span></code>).</p></li>
<li><p>Allow the new <code><span>--trusted-host</span></code> flag to also disable TLS verification for
a particular hostname.</p></li>
<li><p>Added a <code><span>--user</span></code> flag to <code><span>pip</span> <span>freeze</span></code> and <code><span>pip</span> <span>list</span></code> to check the
user site directory only.</p></li>
<li><p>Silence byte compile errors when installation succeed. (#1873)</p></li>
<li><p>Added a virtualenv-specific configuration file. (#1364)</p></li>
<li><p>Added site-wide configuration files. (1978)</p></li>
<li><p>Added an automatic check to warn if there is an updated version of pip
available. (#2049)</p></li>
<li><p><cite>wsgiref</cite> and <cite>argparse</cite> (for &gt;py26) are now excluded from <cite>pip list</cite> and
<cite>pip freeze</cite>. (#1606, #1369)</p></li>
<li><p>Add <code><span>--client-cert</span></code> option for SSL client certificates. (#1424)</p></li>
<li><p><cite>pip show --files</cite> was broken for wheel installs. (#1635, #1484)</p></li>
<li><p>install_lib should take precedence when reading distutils config.
(#1642, #1641)</p></li>
<li><p>Send <cite>Accept-Encoding: identity</cite> when downloading files in an attempt to
convince some servers who double compress the downloaded file to stop doing
so. (#1688)</p></li>
<li><p>Stop breaking when given pip commands in uppercase (#1559, #1725)</p></li>
<li><p>pip no longer adds duplicate logging consumers, so it won’t create duplicate
output when being called multiple times. (#1618, #1723)</p></li>
<li><p><cite>pip wheel</cite> now returns an error code if any wheels fail to build. (#1769)</p></li>
<li><p><cite>pip wheel</cite> wasn’t building wheels for dependencies of editable requirements.
(#1775)</p></li>
<li><p>Allow the use of <code><span>--no-use-wheel</span></code> within a requirements file. (#1859)</p></li>
<li><p>Attempt to locate system TLS certificates to use instead of the included
CA Bundle if possible. (#1680, #1866)</p></li>
<li><p>Allow use of Zip64 extension in Wheels and other zip files. (#1319, #1868)</p></li>
<li><p>Properly handle an index or --find-links target which has a &lt;base&gt; without a
href attribute. (#1101, #1869)</p></li>
<li><p>Properly handle extras when a project is installed via Wheel. (#1885, #1896)</p></li>
<li><p>Added support to respect proxies in <code><span>pip</span> <span>search</span></code>.
(#1180, #932, #1104, #1902)</p></li>
<li><p><cite>pip install --download</cite> works with vcs links. (#798, #1060, #1926)</p></li>
<li><p>Disabled warning about insecure index host when using localhost. Based off of
Guy Rozendorn’s work in #1718. (#1456, #1967)</p></li>
<li><p>Allow the use of OS standard user configuration files instead of ones simply
based around <code><span>$HOME</span></code>. (#2021)</p></li>
<li><p>When installing directly from wheel paths or urls, previous versions were not
uninstalled. (#1825, #804, #1838)</p></li>
<li><p>Detect the location of the <code><span>.egg-info</span></code> directory by looking for any file
located inside of it instead of relying on the record file listing a
directory. (#2075, #2076)</p></li>
<li><p>Use a randomized and secure default build directory when possible.
(#1964, #1935, #676, #2122, CVE-2014-8991)</p></li>
<li><p>Support environment markers in requirements.txt files. (#1433, #2134)</p></li>
<li><p>Automatically retry failed HTTP requests by default. (#1444, #2147)</p></li>
<li><p>Handle HTML Encoding better using a method that is more similar to how
browsers handle it. (#1100, #1874)</p></li>
<li><p>Reduce the verbosity of the pip command by default. (#2175, #2177, #2178)</p></li>
<li><p>Fixed <a href="https://github.com/pypa/pip/issues/2031">#2031</a> - Respect sys.executable on OSX when installing from
Wheels.</p></li>
<li><p>Display the entire URL of the file that is being downloaded when downloading
from a non PyPI repository. (#2183)</p></li>
<li><p>Support setuptools style environment markers in a source distribution. (#2153)</p></li>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://pip.pypa.io/en/stable/news/#id1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25888249</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 02:01:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Software engineering topics I changed my mind on]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 1093 | Comments 657 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25887373">thread link</a>) | @goostavos
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://chriskiehl.com/article/thoughts-after-6-years | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://chriskiehl.com/article/thoughts-after-6-years">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div><article><p><img alt="image" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/awsblogstore/articles/162da1cd/5cfd8e9f-image-1440px.jpeg" srcset="https://s3.amazonaws.com/awsblogstore/articles/162da1cd/5cfd8e9f-image-1440px.jpeg 1440w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/awsblogstore/articles/162da1cd/5cfd8e9f-image-1200px.jpeg 1200w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/awsblogstore/articles/162da1cd/5cfd8e9f-image-960px.jpeg 960w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/awsblogstore/articles/162da1cd/5cfd8e9f-image-720px.jpeg 720w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/awsblogstore/articles/162da1cd/5cfd8e9f-image-480px.jpeg 480w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/awsblogstore/articles/162da1cd/5cfd8e9f-image-240px.jpeg 240w"></p><p><sup>Published: 2021-01-23</sup></p><h2>Things I've changed my mind on:</h2><p>Things I now believe, which past me would've squabbled with:</p><ul><li>Typed languages are better when you're working on a team of people with various experience levels</li><li>Standups are actually useful for keeping an eye on the newbies.</li><li>Sprint retrospectives have their place so long as they're for actual course correction (i.e. "holy shit, <i>that</i> went poorly!") and not some god awful&nbsp; 'agile' / 'scum master' driven waste of everyone's time</li><li>Software architecture probably matters more than anything else. A shitty implementation of a good abstraction causes no net harm to the code base. A bad abstraction or missing layer causes everything to rot. &nbsp;</li><li>Java isn't that terrible of a language.</li><li>Clever code isn't usually good code. Clarity trumps all other concerns.</li><li>Bad code can be written in any paradigm</li><li>So called "best practices" are contextual and not broadly applicable. Blindly following them makes you an idiot</li><li>Designing scalable systems when you don't need to makes you a <i>bad engineer</i>.</li><li>Static analysis is useful</li><li>DRY is about avoiding a specific problem, not an end goal unto itself.</li><li>In general, RDBMS &gt; NoSql</li><li>Functional programming is another tool, not a panacea.</li></ul><h2>Opinions I've picked up along the way</h2><ul><li>YAGNI, SOLID, DRY. In that order.</li><li>Pencil and paper are the best programming tools and vastly under used</li><li>Trading purity in exchange for practicality is usually a good call</li><li>Adding more technology is rarely a good call</li><li>Talking directly to the customer always reveals more about the problem, in less time, and with higher accuracy</li><li>The word "scalable" has a mystical and stupefying power over the mind of the software engineer. Its mere utterance can whip them into a depraved frenzy. Grim actions have been justified using this word</li><li>Despite being called "engineers," most decision are pure cargo-cult with no backing analysis, data, or numbers</li><li>90% – <i>maybe</i> 93% – of project managers, could probably disappear tomorrow to either no effect or a net gain in efficiency.</li><li>After performing over 100 interviews: interviewing is thoroughly broken. I also have no idea how to actually make it better.</li></ul><h2>Old opinions unchanged:</h2><ul><li>People who stress over code style, linting rules, or other minutia are insane weirdos</li><li>Code coverage has absolutely nothing to do with code quality</li><li>Monoliths are pretty good in most circumstances</li><li>TDD purists are just <i>the worst</i>. Their frail little minds can't process the existence of different workflows.</li></ul><p>&nbsp; We'll see which of these have flipped or changed at year 10.</p></article></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://chriskiehl.com/article/thoughts-after-6-years</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25887373</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:02:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
