<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 09:06:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 09:06:43 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why isn't differential dataflow more popular?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 87 | Comments 32 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25867693">thread link</a>) | @jamii
<br/>
January 21, 2021 | https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/why-isnt-differential-dataflow-more-popular/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/why-isnt-differential-dataflow-more-popular/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
  <p><a href="https://github.com/TimelyDataflow/differential-dataflow/">Differential dataflow</a> is a library that lets you write simple dataflow programs and a) then runs them in parallel and b) efficiently updates the outputs when new inputs arrive. Compared to competition like <a href="https://spark.apache.org/">spark</a> and <a href="https://kafka.apache.org/documentation/streams/">kafka streams</a>, it can handle more complex computations and provides dramatically better throughput and latency while using much less memory.</p>
<p>But I'm only aware of a few companies that use it in production, even though it's been around for 5 years. </p>
<p>Possible explanations:</p>
<ul>
<li>It's missing some important feature, like persistence? </li>
<li>It's had very little advertising?</li>
<li>The api is too hard to use?</li>
<li>The docs / tutorials are not good enough?</li>
<li>Rust is intimidating?</li>
<li>No company to provide paid support?</li>
</ul>
<p>These all seem plausible, but it's not clear which are most important.</p>
<p>Even more surprising is that noone has copied the ideas into some enterprise friendly java monstrosity - despite the fact that differential dataflow is open source and is explained in depth in many papers and blog posts.</p>
<p>I'm interested because <a href="https://materialize.com/">materialize</a> is expending a huge amount of effort adding a SQL layer on top of differential dataflow. That's all very well for people who like SQL, but I'm curious whether there are also potential users who would have been perfectly happy with javascript/python/R bindings and a good tutorial? There are probably multiple niches to be served here.</p>
<p>If you considered using differential dataflow and decided against, please <a href="mailto:jamie@scattered-thoughts.net">let me know</a> why.</p>
<hr>
<p>I got feedback in the form of ~20 emails and ~100 comments on <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25867693">hn</a> and <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/7zeb3x/why_isn_t_differential_dataflow_more">lobsters</a>. Thanks to everyone who took the time to reach out - it was very helpful.</p>
<p>(To clarify for many fine but confused commenters - I did not make differential dataflow. I'm just trying to find out what more needs to be done to be useful in that niche.)</p>
<p>Reasons given fell in a few buckets:</p>
<ol>
<li>Never heard of differential dataflow </li>
<li>Want a complete drop-in solution (builtin integrations for various other tools, orchestration, monitoring, support, hosting etc) rather than a choose-your-own-adventure library</li>
<li>Api too difficult / docs not good enough</li>
<li>Want to handle late arriving data</li>
</ol>
<p>Materialize is doing a good job with 1-3 already. </p>
<p>I think differential dataflow actually can handle 4, since it can handle bitemporal timestamps, but this isn't something that has been well tested or advertised. That might be worth experimenting with.</p>
<p>All of the people in group 2 talked about typical data processing tasks, but people in group 3 had a much wider range of tasks including large-scale code analysis and monitoring systems with strong latency/consistency requirements. </p>
<p>Group 3 includes many people who seriously evaluated DD but couldn't get past the hello world stage, but also several people who <em>are</em> using DD because nothing else can handle their requirements, but still complain that the api is difficult to use.</p>
<p>Api complaints included:</p>
<ul>
<li>where is all the state? where do all these map/reduce calls actually end up living?</li>
<li>which operators are internally stateful? how much memory will this use? how can I monitor how much memory each operator is using?</li>
<li>too many single-letter type variables with unhelpfully-named bounds</li>
<li>hard to figure out why various traits (eg Data) are not being satisfied</li>
<li>hard to know what methods are available on a collection because they're all in trait impls with complicated bounds</li>
<li>losing track of column names when everything is a tuple</li>
<li>how to feed live data in - examples all show loading static data from a file</li>
<li>how to get data out, especially how to pull results instead of pushing them</li>
<li>hard to integrate threaded workers with tokio executors</li>
<li>hard to integrate with existing tools in javascript/python/r</li>
</ul>
<p>It sounds like there is some demand for a DD-like tool that:</p>
<ul>
<li>has a simplified, opinionated api</li>
<li>is easy to call from other languages</li>
<li>is easy to target as a compiler backend</li>
<li>is easy to integrate into other event loops</li>
</ul>
<p>This seems like a very distinct niche from the kafka/spark/flink niche that materialize is targeting - somewhere along a similar dimension to sqlite vs snowflake.</p>

</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/why-isnt-differential-dataflow-more-popular/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25867693</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 02:45:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I schedule my friendships like I schedule my meetings]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 58 | Comments 54 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25864090">thread link</a>) | @mcrittenden
<br/>
January 21, 2021 | https://critter.blog/2021/01/21/i-schedule-my-friendships-like-i-schedule-my-meetings/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://critter.blog/2021/01/21/i-schedule-my-friendships-like-i-schedule-my-meetings/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="page">
	<p><a href="#content">Skip to content</a></p><!-- #masthead -->

	
	<div id="content">

	<div id="primary">
		<main id="main">

		

<article id="post-6281">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>
		
<p>It’s hard to stay in touch with friends. The only thing that has <a href="https://critter.blog/2020/10/05/guerrilla-productivity-tactics/">worked for me</a> is <strong>scheduled, recurring calendar events</strong>.</p>



<ul><li>Every other Thursday night, <a href="https://critter.blog/2020/12/25/my-wifes-holiday-costume-makeup/">my wife</a> and I hop on a Zoom with <a href="https://anchor.fm/jace-and-critter/">a friend</a> in Portland and chat for an hour or two. </li><li>Every Tuesday, I have a coffee chat scheduled with a former coworker of mine. </li><li>Every Saturday, my mom comes over for dinner.</li><li>Once a month, I catch up with an old friend who moved away.</li></ul>



<p>We remember because our <a href="https://critter.blog/2020/08/03/your-calendar-should-be-an-allowlist-not-a-blocklist/">calendars</a> remind us. We don’t have to think about <a href="https://critter.blog/2020/11/04/what-we-have-left/">when we’ll hang out again</a>. There’s no <a href="https://critter.blog/2020/08/13/clear-is-kind-unclear-is-unkind/">awkward</a> “we should do this again!” or “let me know when you’re available for lunch next week!” involved. <a href="https://critter.blog/2021/01/07/a-simple-process-beats-a-perfect-process/">It’s automatic</a>. I schedule it once and we are guaranteed to stay in touch.</p>



<p>If you’re thinking it’s weird to treat a friendship like a <a href="https://critter.blog/2020/10/20/a-tiny-guide-to-sprint-planning-in-scrum/">sprint planning</a> meeting, then maybe you’re right. But it works. It’s worth a little weirdness to stay in touch with the people who matter to me. </p>



<p><a href="https://critter.blog/2020/11/24/intense-intervention-or-acceptance-pick-one/">Try it</a> if you’re <a href="https://critter.blog/2020/12/16/if-everyone-else-on-earth-disappeared-how-would-you-spend-your-time/">sad about losing touch</a> with people.</p>




	</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->
</article><!-- #post-6281 -->
			<!-- .post-nav-wrapper -->
		
		</main><!-- #main -->
	</div><!-- #primary -->


<!-- #secondary -->

	</div><!-- #content -->

	
	<!-- #colophon -->
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://critter.blog/2021/01/21/i-schedule-my-friendships-like-i-schedule-my-meetings/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25864090</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 20:53:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[DeLorean considering all-electric reboot]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 366 | Comments 225 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25864078">thread link</a>) | @evo_9
<br/>
January 21, 2021 | https://www.newdelorean.com/nhtsa-releases-final-low-volume-manufacturing-rules/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.newdelorean.com/nhtsa-releases-final-low-volume-manufacturing-rules/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<div>		
        	
                        
            <div id="primary">
    
                            
                
	          		
   
   
    <!-- post -->    
    <article id="post-282">
    
    	<!-- entry-meta -->
    	<!-- close entry-meta -->
        
                    <p><span>January 20, 2021</span>
                <span>                
                     <span>DMC</span>
                </span>     
            </p>
            
    <div>
    
    <!-- entry-header -->    
    <!-- close entry-header -->   
    
         
        
            
	    
    <!-- entry-content -->
    <div>
        <p>National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) has completed a regulation permitting low volume motor vehicle manufacturers to begin selling replica cars that resemble vehicles produced at least 25 years ago. Congress enacted a DeLorean Motor Company-backed bill backed by the Specialty Equipment Market Association (SEMA) DeLorean Motor Company, and others into law in 2015, which streamlined requirements for small automakers, but implementation was delayed while awaiting the NHTSA regulations. Companies like DeLorean will now be able to apply for authorization to produce and sell vehicles under this program.</p>
<p>The recent release of the final rule document was unexpected, and we’re very pleased to see it finally happen. Still, four years overdue with no clear idea of when (or if!) these would ever be released did certainly keep us from putting too many eggs in that stainless steel basket, so to speak.</p>
<p>Some previous suppliers that we had lined up have gone out of business during the pandemic, others have been absorbed by larger companies that have made it clear low volume component production is not something they’re interested in pursuing. In that regard there will be a fair amount of work to be re-done. Perhaps worse, some “champions” we had at various suppliers have retired or moved on. In some cases this has left a void, where before there was a DeLorean fan, who rallied for us within their company and management.</p>
<p>Additionally, certain staffing candidates that were on our short-list have long since moved on in and while unemployment has increased during 2020, many of the specialized roles that we require are still hard to fill.</p>
<p>As mentioned before, in 2015 our planned engine had a life-cycle of emissions compliance through 2022. We had hoped to get into production by 2017 and get 3-4 years out of it before having to take on the engineering for a new powertrain. It’s believed that this engine has been extended through perhaps 2024 now, but it doesn’t seem like a good idea to plan around an engine so near its end-of-life.</p>
<p>That said, with EV’s becoming more mainstream, we’ve been considering switching to an all-electric as the future. It certainly makes for an easier path through emissions maze which still looms large over any internal combustion engine. While an electric Cobra or Morgan may be a little extreme for their potential market, we’ve already seen that an EV DeLorean – as we displayed at the 2012 New York International Auto Show – is not such an “out there” idea.</p>
<p>Most critically, financial markets have changed, and will change even more as the world navigates the continuing COVID crisis during the Biden administration. Will the financial support that we had lined up a few years ago to carry us through the final development and into production still be available?</p>
<p>As the automotive brand with likely the highest name recognition across all demographics in spite of not having a new product in 40 years, we still believe that none of the above is insurmountable and believe that others will see value in it, as well.</p>
<p>Stay tuned…</p>
                
                            </div><!-- close entry-content -->
    
                 
    </div>     
    
    </article><!-- close post --> 

        
                    
                        
            </div>
        
        	
    
    
    
            
		</div>
		
        
        
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.newdelorean.com/nhtsa-releases-final-low-volume-manufacturing-rules/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25864078</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 20:52:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Basic Scripting with Awk and Gnuplot]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 78 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25863846">thread link</a>) | @thevirtuoso1973
<br/>
January 21, 2021 | https://cyberchris.xyz/posts/awk-and-gnuplot/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://cyberchris.xyz/posts/awk-and-gnuplot/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      
      
<p>
<em>Posted to <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25863846">HN</a>. Comments and discussion highly encouraged.</em></p>
<div id="outline-container-headline-1">
<h2 id="headline-1">
Introduction
</h2>
<div id="outline-text-headline-1">
<p>This will be a short example-based guide to (a) awk (b) gnuplot and (c) using
them in a script.</p>
<p>
I needed to graph some data based on the output of a command run a couple times.
So what better way to solve that five minute task than to spend an hour learning
awk &amp; gnuplot to automate it?</p>
</div>
</div>
<div id="outline-container-headline-2">
<h2 id="headline-2">
The Problem
</h2>
<div id="outline-text-headline-2">
<p>I needed to compare how long a program says it takes with how long it <em>actually</em>
takes to execute. So I wanted to run it a couple times and produce a graph
of real vs reported times.</p>
<p>
To do this, we could use the <code>time</code> command to retrieve its 'real' time. My program
already prints (to stdout) the time it says it takes to complete. The output looks like
"Time = x", where x is some decimal number. I'll describe the <code>time</code> output later.
The final table that I want the script to produce should look something like this
(these are just random numbers):</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Trial</th>
<th>Real Time</th>
<th>Printed Time</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>1</td>
<td>12</td>
<td>2</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2</td>
<td>44</td>
<td>5</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3</td>
<td>21</td>
<td>3.6</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>…</td>
<td>…</td>
<td>…</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
</div>
<div id="outline-container-headline-3">
<h2 id="headline-3">
Awk
</h2>
<div id="outline-text-headline-3">
<div id="outline-container-headline-4">
<h3 id="headline-4">
Awk 101
</h3>
<div id="outline-text-headline-4">
<p>A good introduction is <a href="https://ferd.ca/awk-in-20-minutes.html">Awk in 20 minutes</a>, I'd recommend skimming through it.</p>
<p>
Awk is a text-processing language that revolves around <em>patterns</em> and <em>actions</em>.
Patterns are like regular expressions (e.g. <code>hello</code>, or <code>hello+</code> if you want one
or more 'o' characters), actions are just a list of statements (e.g. <code>{ print 1; }</code>).
All patterns are checked against every line, and there corresponding action
will be executed if there is a match.</p>
<p>
Here's an example of using awk to print 1 if some line of the input contains hello:</p>
<div>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">echo hello | awk <span>'/hello/ {print 1;}'</span></code></pre></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="outline-container-headline-5">
<h3 id="headline-5">
Note on zsh's time
</h3>
<p>I use zsh's <code>time</code> which has a slightly different format to bash. Also, both output
to stderr so you'll notice <code>2&gt;&amp;1</code> which redirects stderr to stdout.</p>
</div>
<div id="outline-container-headline-6">
<h3 id="headline-6">
Building The Table With Awk
</h3>
<div id="outline-text-headline-6">
<p>We're going to need variables, like an index to a for loop, to print
the 'trial number'. No problem, we can initialize one with the <code>-v</code>
option like so <code>awk -v j=1 [script]</code> (set j to 1).</p>
<p>
We can also ask awk to give us the nth word in the current line with
<code>$n</code>, where n is some integer.</p>
<p>
And that's basically all we need! Here is the script:</p>
<div>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash"><span># "Time" will appear before "java" in my output (e.g. "Time ...\n java ...\n Time ...\n ...").</span>
<span># Also, substr used to remove the 's' character from time's output</span>
awk -v j<span>=</span><span>1</span> <span>'/Time/{printf("%d %s ", j++, $3)} /java/{printf("%s\n", substr($5, 1, length($5)-1))}'</span></code></pre></div>
</div>
<p>I shall elaborate a little more.
My program could be run like <code>time ./java arg1 arg2 2&gt;&amp;1</code> which would produce 2 lines
of output, the first containing "Time = [integer]", the second containing the output
of <code>time</code>. So my awk script will either see "Time", where it will
print the index and integer, or it will print the real time after seeing "java".
Notice that I don't print a newline with the "Time" action (which will come first
in my output). So I can build a row from data that spans multiple lines (2 lines in
this case.) Also, my output doesn't have any lines that contain both "Time" and "java".</p>
<p>
When my program is run five times and the output is piped to that awk command, it produces
data like this:</p>
<div>
<div><pre><code data-lang="text">1 12.11 2.547
2 11.294 3.07
3 14.375 3.102
4 12.407 3.208
5 10.147 3.212</code></pre></div>
</div>
<p>
Which is what we want for gnuplot.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="outline-container-headline-7">
<h2 id="headline-7">
Gnuplot
</h2>
<div id="outline-text-headline-7">
<p>To plot our data, we could have two lines. One would use the second column for the y-axis, and the other
would use the third. Both use the first column (the trial number) for their x-axis<sup><a id="footnote-reference-1" href="#footnote-1">1</a></sup>.</p>
<p>
To tell gnuplot to use two columns: <code>using 1:2</code> or <code>u 1:2</code> specifies column 1 to be on the x-axis
and column 2 on y. To plot one line, you'd use <code>p "data.dat" u 1:2 title "My Plot" w lp</code> (<code>w lp</code> means
make it a line plot), but we want two lines, and also to use this without gnuplot's interactive mode, so
here's the full command:</p>
<div>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash"><span># data.dat is my file name, convention seems to end it with *.dat.</span>
SETUP_OUTPUT<span>=</span><span>"set terminal png size 500,500; set output 'blogplot.png';"</span>
PLOT_DATA<span>=</span><span>"p 'data.dat' u 1:2 title 'Real Time' w lp, 'data.dat' u 1:3 title 'Printed Time' w lp"</span>
gnuplot -e <span>"</span>$SETUP_OUTPUT<span> </span>$PLOT_DATA<span>"</span></code></pre></div>
</div>
<p>
Which outputs to a png called <code>blogplot.png</code> when executed:
<img src="https://cyberchris.xyz/img/blogplot.png" alt="/img/blogplot.png" title="/img/blogplot.png"></p>
</div>
</div>


    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://cyberchris.xyz/posts/awk-and-gnuplot/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25863846</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 20:33:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Fastmail was down]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 119 | Comments 111 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25863731">thread link</a>) | @open-paren
<br/>
January 21, 2021 | https://www.fastmailstatus.com/services/general/2021-01-21 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.fastmailstatus.com/services/general/2021-01-21">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">
        


<h2>General availability</h2>
<div>
  <p><a href="https://www.fastmailstatus.com/feed/services/general" title="Service RSS feed"><i></i> Feed</a>
</p></div>
<p id="service-description"> General access to FastMail (network etc)</p>


<h3>
  21 Jan 2021
</h3>



<table id="events">
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Time</th>
      <th>Status</th>
      <th>Message</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    
    <tr>
      <td>
        <a href="http://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?year=2021&amp;month=01&amp;day=21&amp;hour=20&amp;min=55&amp;p1=0">
          21 Jan 2021 20:55:26 UTC
        </a><br>
        (2 days ago)
      </td>
      <td title="Up"><i></i></td>
      <td>The issue accessing our web services is now resolved. No mail has been lost.</td>
    </tr>
    
    <tr>
      <td>
        <a href="http://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?year=2021&amp;month=01&amp;day=21&amp;hour=20&amp;min=19&amp;p1=0">
          21 Jan 2021 20:19:07 UTC
        </a><br>
        (2 days ago)
      </td>
      <td title="Warning"><i></i></td>
      <td>Users may see interruptions when accessing Fastmail services. We’re currently investigating.</td>
    </tr>
    
  </tbody>
</table>


<div id="legend">
  <h4> Status Legend </h4>
  <ul>
    
    <li>
      <p title="Up"><i></i> The service is operating normally
    </p></li>
    
    <li>
      <p title="Down"><i></i> The service is unavailable
    </p></li>
    
    <li>
      <p title="Warning"><i></i> The service is operating in a degraded capacity
    </p></li>
    
  </ul>
</div>


      </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.fastmailstatus.com/services/general/2021-01-21</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25863731</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 20:23:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Hiding messages in images: steganography with Python and Repl.it]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 59 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25859891">thread link</a>) | @sixhobbits
<br/>
January 21, 2021 | https://docs.repl.it/tutorials/13-steganography | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://docs.repl.it/tutorials/13-steganography">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    

    <div>
      
<p>In this tutorial, we'll build a steganography tool in Python. Steganography is the practice of hiding information within other data. Unlike encryption, where the goal is to secure <em>the contents</em> of communication between two parties, steganography aims to obscure the fact that the parties are communicating at all.</p>
<p>Our tool will enable the user to hide secret text within a normal-looking <code>.png</code> image file. The receiver of the image will use the same tool to reveal the hidden message.</p>
<p>We'll use Python to build the tool. The most popular Python image processing libraries are <a href="https://pypi.org/project/Pillow/">Pillow</a> and <a href="https://pypi.org/project/opencv-python/">OpenCV</a>, but these are heavy libraries with many dependencies. We'll avoid these and instead use the lightweight <a href="https://pypi.org/project/pypng/">PyPNG</a> library which is written in pure Python, and therefore easier to run on various platforms.</p>
<h2 id="a-quick-background-on-steganography">A quick background on steganography</h2>
<p>Let's imagine three people: Alice, Bob and Eve. Alice wants to send a private message to Bob, while Eve wants to intercept this message. While modern-day encryption can help Alice and Bob ensure that Eve doesn't know the <em>contents</em> of their message, Eve can possibly still deduce interesting information just from knowing that Alice and Bob are communicating at all, and how frequently they communicate.</p>
<p>To obscure the communication channel completely, Alice and Bob can exploit the fact that hundreds of millions of photos are uploaded and shared across the internet daily. Instead of communicating directly, Alice can leave her message hidden in an image at a pre-agreed location and Bob can access this message. From Eve's perspective, there is now no direct communication between the two.</p>
<p>A single image is made up of millions of pixels. While many formats exist, a pixel is most simply represented by a group of three numbers between 0 and 255, one number each for the red, blue, and green values of that pixel. Using this Red-Green-Blue scheme we can represent any colour in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RGB_color_model">RGB color model</a>.</p>
<p>Digital text, like images, is also represented internally by numbers, so the differences between a text file and an image file are not as large as you might assume. Any digital data can be represented as a <a href="https://thehelloworldprogram.com/computer-science/what-is-binary/">binary string</a>, a bunch of 1s and 0s, and we can make tiny modifications to an image to encode a binary string within it. As an example, consider the following:</p>
<pre><code>image = [, , ]</code></pre>
<p>This is a representation of an image with three pixels: one red, one green, and one blue. If we encode this as an image and open it in an image viewer, we'll see the three pixel image, but if we read this data with Python, it is simply a list of tuples, each containing three integers.</p>
<p>We could also look at each value making up each pixel and calculate whether it is <em>odd</em> or <em>even</em>. We could encode odd numbers as <code>1</code> and even values as <code>0</code>. This would give us the binary string "100 010 001" (as the 255 values are odd and the 0s are even).</p>
<p>If we made a small modification to the image as follows:</p>
<pre><code>image = [, , ]</code></pre>
<p>The image would look almost identical in any image viewer (we have just added or subtracted a minuscule amount of color from some values), but the binary string -- using our odd/even method -- would look completely different: "011 111 100". </p>
<p>Using this technique but extending it over an entire image (millions of pixels), we can hide a large amount of text data in any image.</p>
<h2 id="creating-the-project-on-replit">Creating the project on Repl.it</h2>
<p>If you were serious about keeping your messages as secret as possible, you'd want to do all of these steps on an offline computer that you fully control. As a learning exercise though, we'll set the project up on <a href="https://repl.it/">repl.it</a>. Navigate to their site and sign up for an account if you don't have one.</p>
<p>Create a new project, choosing "Python" as the language, and give your project a name.</p>
<p><img src="https://docs.repl.it/images/tutorials/13-steganography/04-create-repl.png" alt="Creating a new repl"></p>
<p>The first piece we need to build is a function to encode any text message as a binary string.</p>
<h2 id="encoding-a-text-message-as-a-binary-string">Encoding a text message as a binary string</h2>
<p>Open the <code>main.py</code> file and add the following code</p>
<pre><code>import base64

def encode_message_as_bytestring(<span>message</span>):
    b64 = <span>message</span>.encode(<span>"utf8"</span>)
    bytes_ = base64.encodebytes(b64)
    bytestring = <span>""</span>.jo<span>in(</span>[<span>"{:08b}"</span>.<span>format</span>(<span>x</span>) for <span>x</span> <span>in</span> bytes_])
    <span>return</span> bytestring</code></pre>
<p>This first encodes our text as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Base64">base64</a> and then as a binary string. You can add some print statements to see how the message is transformed in the different steps, as shown below.</p>
<p><img src="https://docs.repl.it/images/tutorials/13-steganography/13-01-encode-binstring.png" alt="Encoding a message as a binary string"></p>
<p>The base64 step is not strictly necessary, but it is useful as any file or data can be encoded as base64. This opens our project up to future extensions such as hiding other kinds of files within image files instead of just text strings.</p>
<h2 id="adding-an-end-of-message-delimeter">Adding an 'end of message' delimeter</h2>
<p>We'll assume that our message will always 'fit' in our image. We can fit three binary digits per pixel (one for each of the RGB values), so our resulting binary string should be shorter than the the number of pixels in the image multiplied by three.</p>
<p>We'll also need to know when the message <em>ends</em>. The message will only be encoded in the beginning of the image file, but if we don't know how long the message is, we'll keep looking at normal pixels and trying to encode them as text data. Let's add an "end of string" delimiter to the end of our message: this should be something that wouldn't appear half way through our actual message by chance. We'll use the binary representation of '!ENDOFMESSAGE!' for this.</p>
<p>Modify your function to look as follows, which adds this delimeter at the end.</p>
<pre><code>import <span>base64
</span>
ENDOFMESSAGE = <span>"0100100101010101010101100100111101010010010001010011100101000111010101000101010101010110010101000101010100110000010001100100100001010010010100110100010100111101"</span>

def encode_message_as_bytestring(message):
    <span>b64 </span>= message.encode(<span>"utf8"</span>)
    <span>bytes_ </span>= <span>base64.encodebytes(b64)
</span>    <span>bytestring </span>= <span>""</span>.<span>join(["{:08b}".format(x) </span>for x in <span>bytes_])
</span>    <span>bytestring </span>+= ENDOFMESSAGE
    return <span>bytestring</span></code></pre>
<p>Now that we can handle some basic text encoding, let's look at images.</p>
<h2 id="getting-pixels-from-an-image">Getting pixels from an image</h2>
<p>Find a PNG image somewhere - either one you've taken yourself or from a site like unsplash. You can use any online JPG to PNG converter if you only have <code>.jpg</code> files available.</p>
<p>Upload your PNG file by clicking on the three dot menu in the repl sidebar, in the top right corner of the files pane to the left, and selecting <code>upload file</code> or by simply dragging and dropping your file within the files pane.</p>
<p><img src="https://docs.repl.it/images/tutorials/13-steganography/05-upload-file.png" alt="Image showing file upload"></p>
<p>We're going to write a function that extracts the raw pixel data from this image file. Add an import to the top of the file.</p>
<pre><code><span>import</span> png</code></pre>
<p>And then add a new function to the bottom of <code>main.py</code>:</p>
<pre><code><span><span>def</span> <span>get_pixels_from_image</span><span>(fname)</span></span>:
    img = png.Reader(fname).read()
    pixels = img[<span>2</span>]
    <span>return</span> pixels</code></pre>
<p>The <code>read()</code> method returns a 4‑tuple consisting of:</p>
<ul>
<li>width: Width of PNG image in pixels</li>
<li>height: Height of PNG image in pixels</li>
<li>rows: A sequence or iterator for the row data</li>
<li>info: An info dictionary containing some meta data</li>
</ul>
<p>We are primarily interested in the third item, "rows", which is an iterator containing all the pixels of the image, row by row. If you're not familiar with Python generators take a look at <a href="https://realpython.com/introduction-to-python-generators/">this guide</a>, but they are essentially memory-efficient lists.</p>
<h2 id="encoding-the-image-with-the-message">Encoding the image with the message</h2>
<p>Now that we have the encoded message and pixels of the image ready we can combine them to form our secret encoded image.</p>
<p>Add the following function to the bottom of the <code>main.py</code> file. This function takes in the outputs from the previous functions (our raw pixels and our message encoded as a binary string), and combines them.</p>
<pre><code><span><span>def</span> <span>encode_pixels_with_message</span>(<span>pixels, bytestring</span>):</span>
    <span>'''modifies pixels to encode the contents from bytestring'''</span>

    enc_pixels = []
    string_i = <span>0</span>
    <span>for</span> row <span>in</span> pixels:
        enc_row = []
        <span>for</span> i, char <span>in</span> <span>enumerate</span>(row):
            <span>if</span> string_i &gt;= <span>len</span>(bytestring):
                pixel = row[i]
            <span>else</span>:
                <span>if</span> row[i] % <span>2</span> != <span>int</span>(bytestring[string_i]):
                    <span>if</span> row[i] == <span>0</span>:
                        pixel = <span>1</span>
                    <span>else</span>:
                        pixel = row[i] - <span>1</span>
                <span>else</span>:
                    pixel = row[i]
            enc_row.append(pixel)
            string_i += <span>1</span>

        enc_pixels.append(enc_row)
    <span>return</span> enc_pixels</code></pre>
<p>This is the most complicated part of our project, but most of the code is there to handle edge cases. The important insight is that we want to control whether each pixel has an odd value (representing a 1 in our binary string) or an even one (to represent a 0). By chance, half of the pixel values will already have the correct value.</p>
<p>We simply loop through the binary string and the pixel and 'bump' each value that isn't correct by one. That is, we subtract 1 from the value if we need to change it from odd to even or vice versa. We don't want any negative numbers, so if we need to change any of the <code>0</code> values, we add 1 instead.</p>
<h3 id="writing-our-modified-pixels-back-to-an-image">Writing our modified pixels back to an image</h3>
<p>We now have all the image data, including the encoded message but it is still just a list of pixels. Let's add a function that will compile our pixels back into a PNG image.</p>
<p>Add the following function to the bottom of the <code>main.py</code> file.</p>
<pre><code>def write<span>_pixels_to_image(<span>pixels</span>, <span>fname</span>)</span>:
    png.from<span>_array(<span>pixels</span>, 'RGB')</span>.save(fname)</code></pre>
<p>The above function takes the array <code>pixels</code> and uses the <code>png</code> module to write these to a brand new <code>.png</code> file.</p>
<p>Play around with these functions to make sure you understand how they work. Before we write some wrapper code to actually use these, we're going to do everything backwards so that we can also extract hidden messages from previously encoded PNG files.</p>
<h2 id="decoding-messages-from-image-files">Decoding messages from image files</h2>
<p>First we need a function that can turn a binary string back into readable text. As before, we'll go via base64 for better compatability. Add the following function to the bottom of the <code>main.py</code> file.</p>
<pre><code>def decode<span>_message_from_bytestring(<span>bytestring</span>)</span>:
    bytestring = bytestring.split(ENDOFMESSAGE)<span>[<span>0</span>]</span>
    message = <span>int</span>(bytestring, <span>2</span>).<span>to</span><span>_bytes(<span>len</span>(<span>bytestring</span>)</span> 
    message = base64.decodebytes(message).decode(<span>"utf8"</span>)
    return message</code></pre>
<p>Remember how we added a special <code>E…</code></p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://docs.repl.it/tutorials/13-steganography">https://docs.repl.it/tutorials/13-steganography</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://docs.repl.it/tutorials/13-steganography</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25859891</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 15:32:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Build an Escrow Product]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 122 | Comments 28 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25859638">thread link</a>) | @qin
<br/>
January 21, 2021 | https://www.moderntreasury.com/journal/how-to-build-an-escrow-product | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.moderntreasury.com/journal/how-to-build-an-escrow-product">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><h4>Introduction</h4><p>Escrow is a payment setup where the payer sends funds to a third party rather than directly to the payee. If certain conditions are met, the third party routes the funds to the recipient; if not, the funds get returned to the sender. Escrow is particularly useful for high value payments because the payer is guaranteed their money back if the payee doesn’t meet the conditions.</p><p>Many Americans encounter escrow when they buy or sell a home. In the US, the final step in buying a home is referred to as the “closing process.” While it can vary from state to state, the basic premise is that the buyer delivers the funds to a third party, the seller signs over the deed (or title) to the property, and that third party then transfers the funds to the seller once all the documents are complete. The third party is often referred to as a “title and escrow agent.”</p><p>This post takes the sale of a residential home and walks through how to build the flow of funds associated with the escrow process. We hope this guide is useful in demystifying how an escrow company might automate its payment operations using Modern Treasury.</p><h4>The User Experience</h4><p>Let’s say you’re building a title and escrow company in the US that helps clients sell their homes online. The user experience steps might look something like this:<br></p><ol role="list"><li>Billie Buyer commits to buying a house. Billie will make a 20% down payment in cash and will take out a mortgage for the remaining 80%. </li><li>You assign an escrow bank account to the transaction, collect the two incoming wire transfers from Billie Buyer and the lender, and inform the seller when the funds are in your possession.</li><li>At that point, Sandy Seller signs over the property.</li><li>Once you’ve determined all the documentation is completed correctly, you disburse the full purchase amount to Sandy Seller via wire transfer. </li></ol><p>The flow of funds is straightforward: two incoming wire transfers, and one outgoing wire transfer. This can get significantly more complicated if there are multiple sources of funds, or if there are other parties to be paid, such as tax authorities or other settlement agents. But for the sake of clarity, we’ll start with this simple scenario.</p><h4>Payment Ops Architecture<br></h4><p>To start, you should decide on the account structure itself. Escrow accounts have specific legal designations at banks and not all banks offer them. In addition, you should decide whether to use a single bank account for multiple transactions or to use virtual accounts.<br></p><p><a href="https://docs.moderntreasury.com/docs/virtual-accounts" target="_blank">Virtual accounts</a> are accounts with unique account numbers within a physical bank account. They are much faster to provision than real bank accounts and guarantee one-to-one reconciliation. For our architecture, using virtual accounts as escrow accounts is ideal because we can create one account per house sale. This helps us segregate funds in our reconciliation, as opposed to mixing the funds of multiple house sales in a single account. Also, single transactions per virtual account create a more manageable audit trail.<br></p><figure id="w-node-18dd9f1739d7-b8df1e0f"><p><img src="https://assets.website-files.com/5d7e7bbbcad517dd46cb55d3/6009051bee1c4e7860a4289f_Escrow%20Journal%20Post%20Diagram.jpg" loading="lazy" alt=""></p></figure><p>‍<br></p><h4>API Calls and Timings</h4><p>With our payment ops architecture in hand, we’re ready to build. <br></p><h5>Step 1: Assign a Virtual Account to a sale and share numbers with Buyer and Lender</h5><p>As soon as you learn of an impending house sale, you create a virtual account and share its details with Billie Buyer. You might also generate an invoice for Billie Buyer to share with their mortgage lender, along with specific instructions as to the amount and breakdown to be included in the wires.<br></p><p>To do so, you’d make an Modern Treasury API request like the following:<br></p><h6>curl --request POST \<br> &nbsp;-u ORGANIZATION_ID:API_KEY \<br> &nbsp;--url https://app.moderntreasury.com/api/virtual_accounts \<br> &nbsp;-H 'Content-Type: application/json' \<br> &nbsp;-d '{<br> &nbsp; &nbsp;"name": "Sale of 123 Main Street",<br> &nbsp; &nbsp;"internal_account_id": "c743edb7-4059-496a-94b8-06fc081156fd",<br> &nbsp; &nbsp;"account_details": [<br> &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;{<br> &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;"account_number": "2000001",<br> &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;"account_number_type": "other"<br> &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;}<br> &nbsp; &nbsp;]<br> &nbsp;}'</h6><p><em>‍</em>The response includes the unique routing details for the newly created account. &nbsp;You might also want to add additional information about the sale in the account’s metadata, for example: details about the buyer, seller, property in question, expected close date, any unique arrangements, and other information.</p><h5>Step 2: Create Expected Payments to monitor the wires you expect to receive<br></h5><p>Though not required, it’s useful to create Expected Payments for the two incoming wires you expect to receive. This way, Modern Treasury will notify your system via webhook whether a given payment succeeds within your specified time range, or if it is overdue:<br></p><h6>curl --request POST \<br> &nbsp;-u ORGANIZATION_ID:API_KEY \<br> &nbsp;--url https://app.moderntreasury.com/api/expected_payments \<br> &nbsp;-H 'Content-Type: application/json' \<br> &nbsp;-d '{<br> &nbsp; &nbsp;"description": "Sale of 123 Main Street (Billie’s Portion)",<br> &nbsp; &nbsp;"internal_account_id": "c743edb7-4059-496a-94b8-06fc081156fd",<br> &nbsp; &nbsp;"virtual_account_id": "virtual-account-id",<br> &nbsp; &nbsp;"direction": "credit",<br> &nbsp; &nbsp;"amount_upper_bound": 6000000,<br> &nbsp; &nbsp;"amount_lower_bound": 6000000,<br> &nbsp; &nbsp;"date_upper_bound": "2021-01-15"<br> &nbsp;}'</h6><p><em>‍</em>Some banks will notify you in advance of a payment settling in an account. Modern Treasury captures that notification in the form of an Incoming Payment Detail object. Subscribing to Incoming Payment Detail <a href="https://docs.moderntreasury.com/reference#incoming-payment-details" target="_blank">webhooks</a> will be the first indication from the bank that the wires will settle soon.</p><h5>Step 3: Disburse funds </h5><p>Once the funds have arrived and the documents have been signed, you can disburse the total amount due to Sandy Seller. Let’s say Sandy Seller is getting $300,000 in net proceeds, which will go out via a single wire. Note that the amount is in cents, not dollars, so it is presented as 30000000:</p><h6>‍<br>curl --request POST \<br> &nbsp;-u ORGANIZATION_ID:API_KEY \<br> &nbsp;--url https://app.moderntreasury.com/api/payment_orders \<br> &nbsp;-H 'Content-Type: application/json' \<br> &nbsp;-d '{<br> &nbsp; &nbsp;"description": "Sale of 123 Main Street (Sandy’s Payout)",<br> &nbsp; &nbsp;"type": "wire",<br> &nbsp; &nbsp;"amount": 30000000,<br> &nbsp; &nbsp;"direction": "credit",<br> &nbsp; &nbsp;"currency": "USD",<br> &nbsp; &nbsp;"originating_account": "virtual-account-id",<br> &nbsp; &nbsp;"receiving_account_id": "sandy-external-account-id",<br> &nbsp; &nbsp;"counterparty_id": "sandy-counterparty-id"<br> &nbsp;}'</h6><p><em>‍</em>Once the payment goes through, the account will be debited $300,000 and the transaction will be complete.</p><p>Lastly, you want to add <a href="https://docs.moderntreasury.com/reference#metadata" target="_blank">metadata</a> to the payment for future reference. In addition to metadata tags (eg. key value pairs such as Type: Residential or State: Colorado) you might also attach the PDF for the legal docs, or the CSV calculating the amounts. This will be useful for finance teams that might have questions about this payment in the future.</p><p>That’s it. You have just built a sophisticated payment ops architecture for a house sale with a few API calls.</p><div><p>In reality, of course, things can be more elaborate. Billie Buyer could have multiple sources of funds for the down payment, as they may be receiving funds from family or from a service like <a href="http://haus.com/" target="_blank">Haus</a>. They may also be working with multiple lenders if they have a second mortgage. And depending on the state and county the house is located in, the escrow company may have to disburse funds for sales tax or other fees.</p></div><h4>What Can Go Wrong?</h4><p>Payment operations software, such as <a href="https://www.moderntreasury.com/" target="_blank">Modern Treasury</a>, can manage not only the happy path as described above but also edge cases when things go wrong. A common issue could be that a seller could mistype their bank account details, causing the payment to be returned. Modern Treasury supports account verification with providers like <a href="https://docs.moderntreasury.com/docs/plaid-integration-guide" target="_blank">Plaid</a>, so both you and the seller can be confident that funds are routed to the right destination.</p><p>Customer service issues are another type of problem that can arise, such as when a lender sends the incorrect amount. In that case, there might be an additional transaction necessary or an explanatory note for future audits. Modern Treasury supports tracking funds using double-entry <a href="https://docs.moderntreasury.com/docs/ledgers-overview" target="_blank">Ledgers</a>. This way, ops teams can refer to an immutable history of the transaction data, since all money movements are captured and displayed. In the future, accountants and auditors won’t be left wondering about a wire, since contextual information will be tied to the bank statement transaction in question.<br></p><h4>More?</h4><p>This post laid out a simple yet robust foundation for payment ops at an escrow company, leaving plenty of room for future functionality. </p><p>For any specific questions, or to see how Modern Treasury can help make your company’s payment ops simple, scalable, and secure, <a href="https://app.moderntreasury.com/sign_up" target="_blank">sign up today</a>.<br><em>Note: Modern Treasury empowers teams to make payment operations simple, scalable, and secure. The “Guides” series walks through representative businesses or payment processes and explains step by step how best to go about building them from scratch. ‍</em><br></p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.moderntreasury.com/journal/how-to-build-an-escrow-product</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25859638</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 15:15:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Predicting Hard Drive Failure with Machine Learning]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 221 | Comments 53 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25859128">thread link</a>) | @binwiederhier
<br/>
January 21, 2021 | https://datto.engineering/post/predicting-hard-drive-failure-with-machine-learning | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://datto.engineering/post/predicting-hard-drive-failure-with-machine-learning">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<h4><strong>Drive prediction @ Datto</strong></h4>
<p>	We’ve all had a hard drive fail on us, and often it’s as sudden as booting your machine and realizing you can’t access a bunch of your files. It’s not a fun experience. It’s especially not fun when you have an entire data center full of drives that are all important to keeping your business running. What if we could predict when one of those drives would fail, and get ahead of it by preemptively replacing the hardware before the data is lost? This is where the history of predictive drive failure at Datto begins.</p>
<p>	First and foremost, to make a prediction you need data. Hard drives have a built-in utility called SMART<em> (</em><strong><em>S</em></strong><em>elf-</em><strong><em>M</em></strong><em>onitoring, </em><strong><em>A</em></strong><em>nalysis and </em><strong><em>R</em></strong><em>eporting </em><strong><em>T</em></strong><em>echnology)</em> that reports an array of statistics about how the drive is functioning. Here’s an abbreviated view of what that looks like:<br></p>
<figure><img src="https://datto.engineering/DBImg/smart_file_sample.png" alt=""></figure><p>	Datto collects a report like this from each hard drive in its storage servers once per day. Each attribute in the report has three important numbers associated with it: value, thresh, and worst. Each attribute also has a feature named raw_value, but this is discarded due to inconsistent reporting standards between drive manufacturers. </p>
<p>	<strong>Value:</strong> A number between 1 and 253, inclusive. The value reflects how well the drive is operating with respect to the attribute, with 1 being the worst and 253 being the best. The initial value is arbitrarily determined by the manufacturer, and can vary by drive model. </p>
<p>	<strong>Thresh: </strong>A threshold below which the value should not fall in normal operation. If the value falls below the threshold, there is likely something wrong with the drive.</p>
<p>	<strong>Worst: </strong>A record of the lowest value ever recorded for the attribute.</p>
<p>	A quick approach to using these values to make useful predictions is to pick a couple of attributes that seem important and make an alert if any of their values pass below the associated threshold. This is how the first iteration of predictive drive failure at Datto worked. It wasn’t perfect, but it was definitely better than nothing!</p>
<figure><img src="https://datto.engineering/DBImg/code_snippet_1.png" alt=""></figure><p>The next iteration of drive failure prediction was assigning a weighted health score to each drive. This score was defined by assigning weight to several different attributes based on how severe they appeared to be, then adding them together. This prediction method was better than its predecessor, but could potentially be improved even further.</p>
<figure><img src="https://datto.engineering/DBImg/code_snippet_2.png" alt=""></figure><p>This brings us to the most recent iteration of drive failure prediction at Datto and the topic of this article: <strong>smarterCTL</strong>, a machine learning model using most attributes reported by SMART to make the most informed prediction possible. <code>Smartctl</code> is the command line utility used to collect SMART reports. SmarterCTL is a machine learning model making use of <code>smartctl</code>, so it’s the smart-ER version of it. Yeah, it’s a bad pun, but I’m an engineer not a comedian.</p>
<h4><strong>Machine learning &amp;&amp; SMART</strong></h4>
<p>Before we get into the details of smarterCTL, let’s briefly go over machine learning. At its core, machine learning is the process of applying statistics to a dataset to find patterns in it. Once the patterns are found, they can be applied to new data to make assumptions about what that new data means. The defining feature of machine learning is that the programmer doesn’t have any input in figuring out the patterns in the data; the algorithm does that on its own through trial and error. For a great high level introduction to how machine learning works, check out <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f_uwKZIAeM0">this</a> two minute video. </p>
<p>	To get a feel for workflow and terminology, let’s walk through a simplified application of machine learning on drive failure prediction. This example glosses over details and makes some leaps of logic to keep the scope broad. For a more accurate look under the hood of decision tree-based machine learning models, check out this <a href="https://e2eml.school/how_decision_trees_work.html">article</a> and the other resources linked throughout this section.</p>
<p>To make predictions, we need a dataset to train the model on. In this case, the data points are hard drives and the features of those data points are the attributes SMART provides.</p>
<figure><img src="https://datto.engineering/DBImg/datapoint_example.png" alt=""></figure><p>	These data points are labelled as members of the negative or positive class, which in this case means “hard drive operates normally” or “hard drive has failed.” Note that the “positive” in “positive class” doesn’t mean “good.” Instead, it means “this sample exhibits the behavior we’re looking out for.” A machine learning model would read this dataset, then look for patterns in the features that determine why each hard drive ended up in its class.</p>
<p>Normally there would be enough data points and features that a human couldn’t read the whole dataset—let alone spot a pattern in it! This example is simplified enough for us to step through the process that a model might follow. Let’s look for a pattern in each feature:</p>
<figure><img src="https://datto.engineering/DBImg/seek_error_rate.png" alt=""></figure>
<p>Nothing to see here, neither class is homogeneous when it comes to seek_error_rate.<br></p>

<figure><img src="https://datto.engineering/DBImg/spin_up_time.png" alt=""></figure><p>Again, we can’t make a determination based on this attribute alone. There isn’t an obvious split, like high numbers being good and low numbers being bad.</p>

<figure><img src="https://datto.engineering/DBImg/power_on_hours.png" alt=""></figure><p>This time it looks like there is a pattern! Drives with high power-on hours are healthy and drives with low power-on hours will fail. This doesn’t make logical sense though—a drive with low power-on hours should be the healthiest, since it’s the closest to mint condition. Let’s look a little deeper, and see if we can find a correlation between this feature and another that tells us something more logical. </p>

<figure><img src="https://datto.engineering/DBImg/spin_up_over_poh.png" alt=""></figure><p>A-ha! There’s still a difference in magnitude between the two classes, but this time there’s an explanation for it that makes sense: an older drive with a high spin-up time is aging and degrading normally, while a very young drive with a high spin-up time indicates that there might be something like a factory defect.</p>

<p>Now that we’ve figured out the pattern, let’s see how our theoretical model would classify these new SMART reports:</p>
<figure><img src="https://datto.engineering/DBImg/unclassified.png" alt=""></figure><p>	The ratio of spin-up time over power-on hours for drive X is 0.0002, which indicates that it will remain healthy. The ratio for drive Y is 0.045, pointing toward failure.<br>	So how do we know if the model made correct predictions? Well, we just have to wait and see. One of the trickier parts of this problem space is verifying results, because the whole point is to allow us to take action before the thing we’re predicting ever happens. Keep this in mind, it’ll come back to bite us later.</p>
<p>SmarterCTL’s job is to classify hard drives as “failing” or “not failing” so Datto can avoid being blindsided by lost drives and preemptively swap them for healthy ones. If there are patterns in SMART stats that indicate drive failure, smarterCTL will learn those patterns from SMART data Datto has collected over the past 3 years. Then smarterCTL can monitor new daily SMART reports and produce an alert when a drive is exhibiting a pattern that indicates failure.</p>

<h2><strong>Act 2 - Data preparation</strong></h2>
<p>We have several hundred gigabytes of SMART files spanning 3 years and a relatively beefy server to train a machine learning model on—the next step is to set it up and let it churn through the data, right? Unfortunately the work has just begun. Even though machine learning models have a reputation for taking days, or even weeks to train, preparing the data is often the most time consuming part of the process! </p>
<p>	Software folks know that computers are “dumb” and will only do exactly what they’re instructed to. Therefore, the data fed into a machine learning model needs to be very carefully curated. The model has no intuition about whether the conclusions it’s coming to are logical or not, so data that doesn’t accurately describe the whole problem space will lead to a model that confidently spouts nonsense.</p>
<p>In machine learning, the job of the programmer isn’t to spot the patterns in the data: it’s to spot the antipatterns that the model might fall into along the way. Good data treatment and preparation are the first steps in avoiding those antipatterns. </p>
<h4><strong>Shaping the data</strong></h4>
<p>The first step is turning the human readable SMART reports into something more machine readable.</p>
<figure><img src="https://datto.engineering/DBImg/sample_smart_data_1.png" alt=""></figure><p>	I condensed all of the data in each day of smart reports into its own csv file, but some key information was still missing. Since this data will be used to train a model, every data point needs to have a class label associated with it—the model needs to know whether these are healthy or failed drives so it can start to learn about potential patterns. </p>
<p>Producing the class labels ended up being a little tricky—if a drive is in poor enough health to be a member of the failing class, it might already be failing badly enough to not report SMART stats. To get a clearer idea of how drives were behaving and when they were failing out, I wrote a script that walked through every day of SMART reports and tracked how and when each drive failed. </p>
<p>Our servers use the filesystem ZFS, which pools together storage devices into groups called “zpools”. The zpool reports a health status for each drive in the pool. When my script comes across a failing zpool status for a drive, it notes on which day the failure occurred then goes through every daily csv and adds the following features to that drive’s row:</p>
<ol><li>Whether this drive ever fails (class label)</li><li>If so, in how many days from this csv’s date the failure would occur, and</li><li>The zpool status associated with the failure</li></ol><p>With the addition of those features, our data now looks like this:</p>
<figure><img src="https://datto.engineering/DBImg/sample_smart_data_2.png" alt=""></figure><p>	At this point the dataset is a collection of csv files, one per day, that contain:</p>
<ul><li>One row per drive</li><li>The SMART data reported by each drive on that day</li><li>Whether each drive is currently failed</li><li>Whether each drive ever failed while we tracked it</li></ul><p>	Seems like enough data to start making predictions, right? Well, kind of! At this point, the data is well-formed enough that a model could understand it and start producing predictions. The quality of those predictions would be poor, though; the data needs a lot more treatment to remove the pitfalls lurking within.&nbsp;</p>
<h4><strong>Cleaning the data</strong></h4>
<p>	Right now, the data is well formed but messy. It’s in the right shape, …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://datto.engineering/post/predicting-hard-drive-failure-with-machine-learning">https://datto.engineering/post/predicting-hard-drive-failure-with-machine-learning</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://datto.engineering/post/predicting-hard-drive-failure-with-machine-learning</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25859128</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 14:28:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Most surgeries are ineffective]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 57 | Comments 32 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25857435">thread link</a>) | @pvsukale3
<br/>
January 21, 2021 | https://invertedpassion.com/most-surgeries-are-ineffective/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://invertedpassion.com/most-surgeries-are-ineffective/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-1496">
		<!-- .entry-header -->
	<div>
		
		
<p>Do surgeries work? Most of us assume they do, but is there any scientific evidence that they do?</p>

<p>In this episode, I talk to <a href="https://twitter.com/drianharris">Dr Ian Harris</a> who is a Professor of Orthopaedic Surgery at the University of New South Wales in Australia. He is a practicing orthopedic surgeon specializing in trauma surgery. Outside his practice, his research interests broadly cover the topic of surgical effectiveness and clinical research.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<iframe title="#2 Ian Harris - Most surgeries are ineffective" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jCG3tzgGV2A?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p>
</figure>

<h3>What we talk about</h3>

<p><strong>1:38</strong> – Science as a way of knowing things<br><strong>9:15</strong> –&nbsp;Why medical professionals refuse to believe scientific evidence?<br><strong>15:05 </strong>– What is a<strong> </strong>placebo?<br><strong>19:16</strong> – How strong is the placebo effect in surgeries?<br><strong>22:05</strong> – History of bloodletting in medicine and how we stopped this practice<br><strong>24:31</strong> – The myths of knee surgery<br><strong>28:26</strong> – Why doctors need to be held accountable<br><strong>32:26</strong> – Why are there no regulatory authorities in surgery like there are in new medicine?<br><strong>35:14</strong> – Latest studies on why half of the surgeries are ineffective<br><strong>41:00</strong> – Need for randomized trials for discovering which surgeries actually work<br><strong>44:48</strong> – Why is surgery the ultimate placebo?<br><strong>47:12</strong> – How much effort does it take to do a meta-analysis or a systematic review?<br><strong>47:29</strong> – How to improve meta-reviews via living systematic reviews<br><strong>49:54</strong> – What should you be asking your doctor if you are recommended a surgery?</p>

<h3>Dive into Dr Ian Harris’ research</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28592661-surgery-the-ultimate-placebo">Book</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IzueFu1cq5U">Lecture</a></li>
<li><a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=HSd2K4IAAAAJ&amp;hl=en&amp;oi=ao">Papers</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.bmj.com/content/348/bmj.g3253">Relevant paper</a> backing the claim that most surgeries are ineffective</li>
</ul>

<h3>Notes and key insights</h3>

<p>1/ <strong>What is a placebo surgery?</strong> It’s where you make an incision but not do anything. </p>

<p>It’s analogous to traditional placebo in medicine, where a sugar or salt pill is given instead of an active chemical to see whether the intended medicine has an actual impact.</p>

<p>2/ <strong>Majority of surgeries that Dr Ian Harris and other researchers have studied in fact are not more effective than placebos</strong>. This is shocking because even when we have no proof that they work, many of these surgeries are happening even today.</p>

<p>3/ <strong>Examples of such ineffective surgeries include back pain surgeries and knee pain surgeries.</strong> For such surgeries, randomized control trials have found that if you make an incision in the knee but don’t do anything, it’s as effective as actually conducting the surgery of the knee.</p>

<p>4/ Why do patients get better if the surgery doesn’t work? It’s because<strong> many diseases or pain have a natural progression</strong>, and we generally seek surgical/medicinal intervention when we’re in the worst condition. If the body heals / condition becomes better after that, we attribute improvement to the intervention rather than thinking it could have happened anyway (due to the natural course of the condition).</p>

<p>5/ As Dr Ian Harris said, the unsaid attitude could be stated like: “<strong>you have to operate on patients quickly before they get better</strong>“.</p>

<p>Remember: in many cases, if you get sick, you get better after that. And that is why placebos seem to work.</p>

<p>6/ It’s shocking to hear that randomized controlled trials (RCT) for many surgical interventions end up finding that they’re ineffective.</p>

<p>But what’s most shocking is that <strong>many other interventions have never been subjected to an RCT against a placebo</strong>. For many of the common procedures traditionally practiced, we don’t know whether they work at all or not.</p>

<p>7/ For sure, there are many studies that study variations of surgical methods. That is, they try to find out whether an incision from the left is better or from the right. </p>

<p>But very few studies try to find out whether the incision does anything at all for the patient. Shocking, but that’s the truth.</p>

<p>8/ In that sense, <strong>surgery is different than medicine</strong>. All new pharmaceutical molecules are subjected to rigorous clinical trials where they’re tested against placebo or doing nothing. In many countries, there’s no such procedure for surgical treatments. If there is a procedure for new surgical procedures, nobody is testing old ones that have been getting performed every day without evidence.</p>

<p>8/ If research indicates many of the currently practiced surgeries don’t work, why are they still practiced?</p>

<p>Well, <strong>if your salary depends on not believing something, you won’t believe it.</strong></p>

<p>9/ And such <strong>denial is not new</strong>. The most common surgical procedure in history was bloodletting. This practice which lasted for thousands of years was only questioned in mid 19th century, and even after randomized trials showed that it hurt the patient, it wasn’t abandoned suddenly. It died a slow death as its practitioners started dying. </p>

<p>10/ Even today, the fact that practices like Homeopathy survive suggests that <strong>seeking evidence of what works isn’t a big priority for society</strong>. Perhaps keeping traditions is a bigger priority.</p>

<p>11/ But because it’s costly and risky to perform surgeries, the urgent question is: <strong>what surgical procedures are today’s equivalent of bloodletting</strong>? And those that we know are bloodletting, how do we get rid of them as a society?</p>

<p>12/ As a patient, what should you do? Dr Ian Harris recommends that every time your doctor recommends a medical procedure, <strong>ALWAYS ask for risks and benefits</strong>. </p>

<p>Risks are a given and doctors generally are happy to talk about them. But nobody asks for benefits because they’re assumed to be there. </p>

<p>Ask and confirm about benefits explicitly.</p>

<p>13/ What if the pain isn’t going away at all? Should you then get surgery?</p>

<p>Golden advice by Dr Ian -&gt;  “<strong>the severity of your symptoms does not change the effectiveness of the operation</strong>“</p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/paraschopra" data-show-count="true">Follow @paraschopra</a></p>
<p><span><strong>Have an opinion on this essay?</strong></span> You can send your feedback on <a href="https://invertedpassion.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#4d3d2c3f2c3e7c74757a66243d2b2828292f2c2e260d2a202c2421632e2220">email</a> to me.</p>





			</div><!-- .entry-content -->
						<!-- .entry-footer -->
		</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://invertedpassion.com/most-surgeries-are-ineffective/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25857435</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 10:26:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Management by metrics leads us astray]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 287 | Comments 232 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25856257">thread link</a>) | @jakobgreenfeld
<br/>
January 20, 2021 | https://jakobgreenfeld.com/metrics | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jakobgreenfeld.com/metrics">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p>Let’s say my goal this year is to get to 10k monthly recurring revenue (MRR).</p>

<p>MRR first, everything else second. I would ruthlessly cut out all activities that don’t lead to a measurable MRR increase. For example, I would stop writing blog posts like the one you’re currently reading. I certainly wouldn’t create fun projects like What to Tweet or take the time for non-transactional Zoom calls.</p>

<p>I would focus on my revenue generating projects, crank up the advertising machinery and do everything I can think of that potentially increases my MRR.
I’m fairly confident that I would reach 10k MRR by the end of the year. But at what price?</p>

<p>Let’s take a step back for a second.</p>

<p>You know who manages by metrics? Big companies like Google, Amazon and LinkedIn.</p>

<p>And what do they have in common?</p>

<p>Their core product got notably worse over time.</p>

<p>Google’s search results are dominated by ads and many users now use workarounds to find what they’re looking for (“Best headphone reddit”). LinkedIn looks like Minesweeper. Facebook was a fun place to meet friends. And if you search for an electronics product on Amazon, you immediately feel like you’re at a flea market in the middle of Shenzhen.
This is the result of hundreds of decisions that were motivated by a short-term focus on specific metrics like revenue and click rates. And while these decisions most likely optimized the metrics, they made the user experience worse.</p>

<p>The problem is that we don’t have the technology to measure the right thing. Or maybe the “right thing” is inherently immeasurable.</p>

<p>Or, and that’s my personal favorite, we’re dealing with a Schrödinger’s cat like situation. The “right thing” is only the right thing as long as we’re not trying to optimize it.
This is known as Goodhart’s law. “When a measure becomes a target, it ceases to be a good measure.“</p>

<p>Let’s consider another example.</p>

<p>Who else manages by metrics? Politicians!</p>

<p>Instead of some boring historic example (there are plenty, just read “Seeing like a State”), I’m going to spice things up by talking about something that’s happening right now.
It’s not hard to anticipate what I want to talk about since there’s precisely one thing that’s currently happening: Covid-19.</p>

<p>Politicians try to manage the situation by focusing on metrics like the “R number”. At least here in Germany the motto is: let’s lower the R number at all costs.
Turns out the cost of this strategy is incredibly high. It’s just not immediately measurable.</p>

<p>For example, everyone’s getting fatter since all gyms and sport clubs are closed. Most people are developing unhealthy eating habits because there’s simply nothing else to do. Social connections are rapidly degregating even though everyone knows how important they’re for the human wellbeing.</p>

<p>I’m not a doctor and don’t play one on the internet, but I can easily imagine that there are lots of further unintended consequences of the current lockdown policy. For example, since most people now spend most of their time indoors alone and wear masks when they leave their homes, their immune system isn’t stressed regularly like it usual is. Hence I wouldn’t be surprised if many people will get sick of other diseases once the lockdown ends as a result of weakened immune systems.</p>

<p>Just to clarify, I’m all for taking Covid seriously. In fact, I’ve been hoarding masks since 2009. I spent the summer of 2009 with a bunch of friends in Lloret de Mar (a party hotspot in Spain) just when news of the swine flu started to emerge. Long story short, everyone in our group got sick (20+ people) except for my girlfriend and me because we’ve been wearing masks.
Now the most famous example how focusing on metrics can have unhealthy consequences is the cobra effect. I’ll just quote from Wikipedia:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“The term cobra effect originated in an anecdote that describes an occurrence during India under British rule. The British government was concerned about the number of venomous cobras in Delhi. The government therefore offered a bounty for every dead cobra. Initially, this was a successful strategy; large numbers of snakes were killed for the reward. Eventually, however, enterprising people began to breed cobras for the income. When the government became aware of this, the reward program was scrapped. When cobra breeders set their now-worthless snakes free, the wild cobra population further increased.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>There is one more example I always have to talk about when the topic comes up: academia.</p>

<p>Stagnation apologists love to argue that the lack of progress in science is simply a result of the fact that all low-hanging fruit are gone.</p>

<p>That’s complete nonsense. There’s still plenty of low-hanging fruit. It’s just that everyone is so busy chasing meaningless metrics that they can’t see them.</p>

<p>In academia the metric of choice usually has something to do with the number of citations. But just like Google’s backlink-driven algorithm (which was in fact inspired by academia’s citation metrics) was quickly gamed by savvy webmasters, academia’s algorithm is gamed by careerists.</p>

<p>And I’m not talking about some tiny minority here. If you want to survive in academia, you have to play the citation game. And if everyone is cheating, at the very least you have to do the same to stand a chance.</p>

<p>You have to partner up with others because five people can write five times as many papers. You agree to constantly cite each other. Likewise, you focus on incremental additions to established ideas because that’s the safest way to new publications regularly. You work on the stuff everyone else is working on because how else are you going to get citations?</p>

<p>And one thing you absolutely have to avoid like the plague is the risky and deep kind of research that leads to real progress in the field.</p>

<p>The problem isn’t that citations are a bad metric, and we need to come up with smarter ones. Instead, it’s just Goodhart’s law in action.
Every attempt to manage academia makes it worse.</p>

<p>As soon a new metric is introduced it will misdirect the attention of scientists towards playing the game, instead of progressing science.</p>

<p>I talked about three areas, but the same pattern occurs almost everywhere. For example, just remember when everyone started minimizing fat in their diet or how grades are used to measure “learning”.</p>

<p>Crucially the problem is not the specific metric that’s being used. Whatever new metric gets introduced will soon again be made useless by Goodhart’s law. The metrics game will always be akin to Whac-A-Mole.</p>

<p>Now where does this leave us? If management by metrics doesn’t work, what else should we do?</p>

<p>First of all, I think that looking at metrics can be helpful. They just shouldn’t be the sole yardstick decisions are measured against.</p>

<p>And while the map never will be the territory, the picture you’re looking at gets more accurate the more metrics you consider. For example, if politicians would not just consider the R number but hundreds of metrics that take different aspects of a population’s wellbeing into account, the decisions would be better ones.</p>

<p>The obvious problem is that decisions become much harder if you consider more than one metric.</p>

<p>But more importantly there are so many factors we can’t measure that nevertheless should be taken into account.</p>

<p>The more I think about it the more I become convinced that it all boils down to talking to people.</p>

<p>And I’m not talking about surveys that distill thousands of standardized “conversations” into a few numbers or analytics tools that do similar things for behavior. I’m talking about real one-on-one interactions.</p>

<p>Just imagine if Jeff Bezos would talk to hundreds of real (non pre-vetted) Amazon customers each month and take what he hears in these conversations seriously. Or if politicians would have long conversations with regular people from all wakes of life. Or if academic committees would actually talk to applicants before filtering them out based on citation metrics.</p>

<p>In our hyper rational world it’s extremely hard to justify decisions based on the mere gut feeling you got from a few conversations. But this is exactly what people should be doing.</p>

<p>Engagement metrics will never tell you if users are genuinely happy when they use your product. But a few genuine conversations will.</p>

<p>A resume will never tell you if a person is genuinely interested in uncovering unknown truths about nature. But a 30-minute conversation will.</p>

<p>Yes, it’s so much easier to reach a consensus if you just hire the candidate with the highest citation metrics or implement the feature that will lead to the largest revenue increase in the next quarter. But while it’s the easiest decision it’s usually not the best one.</p>

<p>And I think the same applies not just to managing organizations but also to managing ourselves.</p>

<p>Just by listening to my own body I’ll always know better than any fitness tracker if I slept well, better than any blood test if my diet is healthy, and better than my bank account if I’m happy.
That doesn’t mean that I’ll not use a fitness tracker, make regular blood tests, or check my bank account. But I certainly won’t allow them to dictate my decisions.</p>

<p>I’ll look at all the facts and take everything in, even the stuff that can’t be measured, and then I’ll just go with my gut.</p>


  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jakobgreenfeld.com/metrics</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25856257</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 06:52:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Twitter locks account of Chinese Embassy in U.S.]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 53 | Comments 29 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25855653">thread link</a>) | @empressplay
<br/>
January 20, 2021 | https://www.cbc.ca/news/world/twitter-china-trump-xinjiang-uighur-1.5881613 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/news/world/twitter-china-trump-xinjiang-uighur-1.5881613">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Twitter has locked the account of the Chinese Embassy in the U.S. for a tweet that defended China's policies in the Xinjiang region, which the U.S. social media platform said violated the firm's policy against "dehumanization" of a group of people.</p><div><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5881627.1611194382!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/usa-trump-twitter.JPG"></p></div><figcaption>A Twitter logo is seen outside the company headquarters on Jan. 11. The social media platform on Wednesday confirmed it had blocked the account of the Chinese Embassy in the U.S. because of a violation of its policy against the dehumanization of a group of people.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Stephen Lam/Reuters/File photo)</figcaption></figure><p><span><p>Twitter has locked the account of the Chinese Embassy in the U.S. for a tweet that defended China's policies in the Xinjiang region, which the U.S. social media platform said violated the firm's policy against "dehumanization."</p>  <p>The Chinese Embassy account, @ChineseEmbinUS, tweeted this month&nbsp;that Uighur women were no longer "baby making machines," citing a study reported by state-backed newspaper China Daily.</p>  <p>The tweet was removed by Twitter and replaced with a label stating that it was no longer available. Although Twitter hides tweets that violate its policies, it requires account owners to manually delete such posts. The Chinese embassy's account has not posted any new tweets since Jan. 9.</p>  <p>"We've taken action on the Tweet you referenced for violating our policy against dehumanization, where it states: We prohibit the dehumanization of a group of people based on their religion, caste, age, disability, serious disease, national origin, race, or ethnicity," a Twitter spokesperson said on Thursday.</p>  <p>The Chinese embassy in Washington did not immediately reply to an e-mailed request for comment. Twitter is blocked in China.</p>  <p>The Biden administration did not immediately respond to a request for comment on Twitter's move.&nbsp;</p>  <h2>Allegations of genocide</h2>  <p>In one of his final acts in office, now-former secretary of state Mike Pompeo declared Tuesday that China's policies against Muslims in its Xinjiang region constitute "crimes against humanity" and "genocide."&nbsp; President Joe&nbsp;Biden's chosen successor to Pompeo, Antony Blinken, said he shared the same view.</p>  <p><span><blockquote lang="en"><p>I have determined that the People’s Republic of China is committing genocide and crimes against humanity in Xinjiang, China, targeting Uyghur Muslims and members of other ethnic and religious minority groups.</p>&amp;mdash;<a href="https://twitter.com/SecPompeo/status/1351580135464558593">@SecPompeo</a></blockquote></span></p>  <p>Xinjiang, a far western region that borders Central Asia, is home to the predominantly Muslim Uighur ethnic group. China denies human rights violations and says its actions in Xinjiang are necessary to counter a separatist and terrorist threat.</p>  <p>In a striking repudiation of its relationship with Washington under Trump, the Chinese Foreign Ministry announced sanctions against&nbsp;"lying and cheating"&nbsp;Pompeo and 27 other top Trump administration officials&nbsp;in a statement that appeared on its website around the time that Biden was taking the presidential oath.</p>  <p>Pompeo and the others had "planned, promoted and executed a series of crazy moves, gravely interfered in China's internal affairs, undermined China's interests, offended the Chinese people, and seriously disrupted China-U.S. relations," it said.</p>    <p>The 28 individuals and immediate family members would be banned from entering mainland China, Hong Kong or Macao, and companies and institutions associated with them restricted from doing business with China.</p>  <p><em><strong>WATCH |&nbsp;Aspects of Chinese treatment of Uighurs fits genocide definition: Bob Rae</strong></em></p>  <p><span><span><div><div title="Aspects of Chinese treatment of Uighurs fits genocide definition: Bob Rae" role="button" tabindex="0"><div><div aria-labelledby="1819938883873-metadata-" title="Aspects of Chinese treatment of Uighurs fits genocide definition: Bob Rae"><div><p><img src="https://thumbnails.cbc.ca/maven_legacy/thumbnails/973/995/bob-rae-rblive.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p></div></div></div></div></div><span>Canada's ambassador to the United Nations says he's asked the international organization to gather evidence and investigate whether China's persecution of Uighurs in Xinjiang province constitutes a genocide.<!-- --> <!-- -->10:03</span></span></span></p>  <p>China has repeatedly rejected accusations of abuse in its Xinjiang region, where a United Nations panel has said at least one&nbsp;million Uighurs and other Muslims had been detained in camps.</p>  <p>Last year, a report by German researcher Adrian Zenz published by the Washington-based Jamestown Foundation think-tank accused China of using forced sterilization, forced abortion and coercive family planning against minority Muslims. The Chinese foreign ministry said the allegations were groundless and false.</p>    <p>China's foreign ministry is lashing out at Canada after a House of Commons subcommittee concluded that the state's mistreatment of Uighurs living in Xinjiang province amounts to a policy of&nbsp;genocide.</p>  <p>Zhao Lijian, a spokesperson for the Chinese foreign ministry, <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/parliamentary-committee-uighur-genocide-1.5772757">said in Novembe</a>r that this&nbsp;"so-called genocide" is "a rumour and a farce fabricated by some anti-Chinese forces to slander China."</p>  <h2>Suspension of embassy's account follows removal of&nbsp;Trump's&nbsp;</h2>  <p>The embassy's account suspension comes shortly after Twitter removed the account of former U.S. president Donald Trump, which had 88 million followers, citing the risk of violence after some of his supporters stormed the U.S. Capitol this month.</p>  <p>Twitter had locked Trump's account, asking for deletion of some tweets, before restoring it and then removing it altogether after the former president violated the platform's policies again.</p>  <p><em><strong>WATCH | Twitter permanently suspends Trump's account:</strong></em></p>  <p><span><span><div><div title="Twitter permanently suspends Trump" role="button" tabindex="0"><div><div aria-labelledby="1842324035823-metadata-" title="Twitter permanently suspends Trump"><div><p><img src="https://thumbnails.cbc.ca/maven_legacy/thumbnails/818/119/trump-twitter.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p></div></div></div></div></div><span>Twitter has permanently suspended U.S. President Donald Trump's account over concerns his tweets could incite violence. Twitter's decision followed two tweets posted by Trump on Friday afternoon. It says the tweets violated the company's policy against glorifying violence.<!-- --> <!-- -->3:58</span></span></span></p></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/world/twitter-china-trump-xinjiang-uighur-1.5881613</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25855653</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 05:07:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
