<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 12:29:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 12:29:31 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Sony basically removed 25 years of history from PlayStation.com]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 95 | Comments 66 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25134263">thread link</a>) | @petepete
<br/>
November 18, 2020 | https://delistedgames.com/sony-basically-removed-25-years-of-history-from-playstation-com/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://delistedgames.com/sony-basically-removed-25-years-of-history-from-playstation-com/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <!-- .entry-header -->


            <div>
                
<p>The heartbreak continues for those of us that relied on Sony’s websites to find and buy games or to research what was available. After <a href="https://delistedgames.com/sony-makes-it-official-playstation-3-psp-vita-removed-from-psn-website-between-october-21-and-26/">cutting out</a> older PlayStation content from the PlayStation Store over the past month, Sony’s eye has seemingly fallen on PlayStation.com and I find myself feeling gutted this morning. For those who didn’t use it regularly, PlayStation.com housed a gargantuan history of pages for North American PlayStation releases going all the way back to the original console from 1995. Up until this week you could easily find titles using the search box on the site but now anything before the PlayStation 4 returns a disappointing “<em>0 results found</em>“.</p>



<p>The older pages weren’t overflowing with info but they did offer some product details that I couldn’t easily find elsewhere. For newer games these pages also frequently retained links to the PlayStation Store which helped in my research. Even when they <em>were</em> on sale some games were just hard to find on the PlayStation Store while their PlayStation.com pages linked directly to them. Sometimes these pages were among the scant bits of evidence that I could find to confirm these games even existed digitally. Now, like with the changes to the PlayStation Store, all that’s gone too. Well, mostly gone.</p>



<p>Thankfully, like our “<a href="https://delistedgames.com/get-the-old-playstation-store-back-for-now/">old PS Store</a>” workaround, there’s still a way to search PlayStation.com but it might also eventually go away. Google’s “search within a site” function has been around for nearly a decade at this point but I’m sure lots of people don’t even know it exists. For our purposes just head to <em>the Google</em>, type ‘site:playstation.com’ and then whatever game you’re looking for. You can use Google’s other search operators to refine the results as well. Put it all together and it looks something like this: <strong>site:playstation.com “age of booty”</strong></p>



<p>You’ll get search results across the playstation.com domain including PlayStation Blog posts and PlayStation Store pages but look for the ones that specifically state ‘www.playstation.com’. In the case of Age of Booty the page gives us a description and even some screenshots as well as a ‘Buy Download’ link. Of course, the download page has been hidden by Sony’s recent changes to their sites but the URL remains accessible so you can check other territories or check it out using the “<a href="https://delistedgames.com/get-the-old-playstation-store-back-for-now/">old</a>” method. Yes, <a href="https://delistedgames.com/age-of-booty/">Age of Booty</a> is still delisted on PlayStation 3.</p>



<p>Maybe it was just a feature that only <strong><em>I</em></strong> benefited from but it’s really sad to see Sony ostensibly kill 25 years of PlayStation content on the web. It makes the nostalgia trip of Astro’s Playroom feel a little more hollow.</p>

                            </div>
            <!-- .entry-content -->



                    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://delistedgames.com/sony-basically-removed-25-years-of-history-from-playstation-com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25134263</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 08:10:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Math of Password Hashing Algorithms and Entropy (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 54 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25133061">thread link</a>) | @mooreds
<br/>
November 17, 2020 | https://fusionauth.io/learn/expert-advice/security/math-of-password-hashing-algorithms-entropy/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://fusionauth.io/learn/expert-advice/security/math-of-password-hashing-algorithms-entropy/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            
              <p>Here’s the reality, billions of credentials have been leaked or stolen and are now easily downloaded online by anyone. Many of these databases of identities include passwords in plain text, while others are one-way hashed. One-way hashing is better (we’ll get to why in a second), but it is only as secure as is mathematically feasible. Let’s take a look at one-way hashing algorithms and how computers handle them.</p>

<h2 id="hashing">Hashing</h2>

<p>A hash by definition is a function that can map data of an arbitrary size to data of a fixed size. SHA2 is a hashing algorithm that uses various bit-wise operations on any number of bytes to produce a fixed sized hash. For example, the SHA-256 algorithm produces a 256 bit result. The algorithm was designed specifically so that going from a hash back to the original bytes is infeasible. Developers use an SHA2 hash so that instead of storing a plain text password, they instead only store the hash. When a user is authenticated, the plain text password they type into the login form is hashed, and because the algorithm will always produce the same hash result given the same input, comparing this hash to the hash in the database tells us the password is correct.</p>

<h2 id="cracking-passwords">Cracking Passwords</h2>

<p>While one-way hashing means we aren’t storing plain text passwords, it is still possible to determine the original plain text password from a hash. Next, we’ll outline the two most common approaches of reversing a hash.</p>

<h3 id="lookup-tables">Lookup Tables</h3>

<p>The first is called a lookup table, or sometimes referred to as a rainbow table. This method builds a massive lookup table that maps hashes to plain text passwords. The table is built by simply hashing every possible password combination and storing it in some type of database or data-structure that allows for quick lookups.</p>

<p>Here’s an example of a lookup table for SHA2 hashed passwords:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>sha2_hash                                                          password</span>
<span>-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------</span>
<span>e150a1ec81e8e93e1eae2c3a77e66ec6dbd6a3b460f89c1d08aecf422ee401a0   </span><span>123456</span>
<span>e5d316bfd85b606e728017e9b6532e400f5f03e49a61bc9ef59ec2233e41015a   broncosfan123</span>
<span>561acac680e997e22634a224df2c0931cf80b9f7c60102a4e12e059f87558232   Letmein</span>
<span>bdc511ea9b88c90b75c3ebeeb990e4e7c813ee0d5716ab0431aa94e9d2b018d6   newenglandclamchowder</span>
<span>9515e65f46cb737cd8c191db2fd80bbd05686e5992b241e8ad7727510b7142e6   opensesame</span>
<span>6b3a55e0261b0304143f805a24924d0c1c44524821305f31d9277843b8a10f4e   password</span>
<span>c194ead20ad91d30c927a34e8c800cb9a13a7e445a3ffc77fed14176edc3c08f   xboxjunkie42</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Using a lookup table, all the attacker needs to know is the SHA2 hash of the password and they can see if it exists in the table. For example, let’s assume for a moment that Netflix stores your password using an SHA2 hash. If Netflix is breached, their user database is likely now available to anyone with a good internet connection and a torrent client. Even a mediocre hacker now only needs to lookup the SHA2 hash associated with your Netflix account to see if it exists in their lookup table. This will reveal nearly instantly what your plain text password is for Netflix. Now, this hacker can log in to your Netflix account and binge watch all four seasons of Fuller House (“how rude!”). And he can also try this password on Hulu and HBO Go to see if you used the same email address and password for those accounts as well.</p>

<p><img src="https://fusionauth.io/assets/img/blogs/salt.png" alt="Salt"></p>

<p>The best way to protect against this type of attack is to use what is called a <strong>salt</strong>. A salt is simply a bunch of random characters that you prepend to the password before it is hashed. Each password should have a different salt, which means that a lookup table is unlikely to have an entry for the combination of the salt and the password. This makes salts an ideal defense against lookup tables.</p>

<p>Here’s an example of a salt and the resulting combination of the password and the salt which is then hashed:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>// Bad, no salt. Very bland.</span>
<span>sha2</span><span>(</span><span>"password"</span><span>)</span> <span>// 6b3a55e0261b0304143f805a24924d0c1c44524821305f31d9277843b8a10f4e</span>

<span>// Better, add a salt.</span>
<span>salt</span> <span>=</span> <span>";L'-2!;+=#/5B)40/o-okOw8//3a"</span>
<span>toHash</span> <span>=</span> <span>";L'-2!;+=#/5B)40/o-okOw8//3apassword"</span>
<span>sha2</span><span>(</span><span>toHash</span><span>)</span> <span>// f534e6bf84a638112e07e69861927ab624c0217c0655e4d3be07659bcf6c1c07</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Now that we have added the salt, the “password” that we actually generated the hash from was the String <code>;L'-2!;+=#/5B)40/o-okOw8//3apassword</code>. This String is long, complex and contains a lot of random characters. Therefore, it is nearly impossible that the hacker that created the lookup table would have generated the hash for the String <code>;L'-2!;+=#/5B)40/o-okOw8//3apassword</code>.</p>

<h3 id="brute-force">Brute Force</h3>

<p><img src="https://fusionauth.io/assets/img/blogs/hulk.png" alt="Brute Force"></p>

<p>The second method that attackers use to crack passwords is called brute force cracking. This means that the attacker writes a computer program that can generate all possible combinations of characters that can be used for a password and then computes the hash for each combination. This program can also take a salt if the password was hashed with a salt. The attacker then runs the program until it generates a hash that is the same as the hash from the database. Here’s a simple Java program for cracking passwords. We left out some detail to keep the code short (such as all the possible password characters), but you get the idea.</p>



<div><div><pre><code><span>import</span> <span>org.apache.commons.codec.digest.DigestUtils</span><span>;</span>

<span>public</span> <span>class</span> <span>PasswordCrack</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>public</span> <span>static</span> <span>final</span> <span>char</span><span>[]</span> <span>PASSWORD_CHARACTERS</span> <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>char</span><span>[]</span> <span>{</span><span>'a'</span><span>,</span> <span>'b'</span><span>,</span> <span>'c'</span><span>,</span> <span>'d'</span><span>};</span>

  <span>public</span> <span>static</span> <span>void</span> <span>main</span><span>(</span><span>String</span><span>...</span> <span>args</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>String</span> <span>salt</span> <span>=</span> <span>args</span><span>[</span><span>0</span><span>];</span>
    <span>String</span> <span>hashFromDatabase</span> <span>=</span> <span>args</span><span>[</span><span>1</span><span>].</span><span>toUpperCase</span><span>();</span>

    <span>for</span> <span>(</span><span>int</span> <span>i</span> <span>=</span> <span>6</span><span>;</span> <span>i</span> <span>&lt;=</span> <span>8</span><span>;</span> <span>i</span><span>++)</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>char</span><span>[]</span> <span>ca</span> <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>char</span><span>[</span><span>i</span><span>];</span>

      <span>fillArrayHashAndCheck</span><span>(</span><span>ca</span><span>,</span> <span>0</span><span>,</span> <span>salt</span><span>,</span> <span>hashFromDatabase</span><span>);</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span>

  <span>private</span> <span>static</span> <span>void</span> <span>fillArrayHashAndCheck</span><span>(</span><span>char</span><span>[]</span> <span>ca</span><span>,</span> <span>int</span> <span>index</span><span>,</span> <span>String</span> <span>salt</span><span>,</span> <span>String</span> <span>hashFromDatabase</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>for</span> <span>(</span><span>int</span> <span>i</span> <span>=</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span> <span>i</span> <span>&lt;</span> <span>PASSWORD_CHARACTERS</span><span>.</span><span>length</span><span>;</span> <span>i</span><span>++)</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>ca</span><span>[</span><span>index</span><span>]</span> <span>=</span> <span>PASSWORD_CHARACTERS</span><span>[</span><span>i</span><span>];</span>

      <span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>index</span> <span>&lt;</span> <span>ca</span><span>.</span><span>length</span> <span>-</span> <span>1</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>fillArrayHashAndCheck</span><span>(</span><span>ca</span><span>,</span> <span>index</span> <span>+</span> <span>1</span><span>,</span> <span>salt</span><span>,</span> <span>hashFromDatabase</span><span>);</span>
      <span>}</span> <span>else</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>String</span> <span>password</span> <span>=</span> <span>salt</span> <span>+</span> <span>new</span> <span>String</span><span>(</span><span>ca</span><span>);</span>
        <span>String</span> <span>sha2Hex</span> <span>=</span> <span>DigestUtils</span><span>.</span><span>sha2Hex</span><span>(</span><span>password</span><span>).</span><span>toUpperCase</span><span>();</span>
        <span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>sha2Hex</span><span>.</span><span>equals</span><span>(</span><span>hashFromDatabase</span><span>))</span> <span>{</span>
          <span>System</span><span>.</span><span>out</span><span>.</span><span>println</span><span>(</span><span>"plain text password is ["</span> <span>+</span> <span>password</span> <span>+</span> <span>"]"</span><span>);</span>
          <span>System</span><span>.</span><span>exit</span><span>(</span><span>0</span><span>);</span>
        <span>}</span>
      <span>}</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This program will generate all the possible passwords with lengths between 6 and 8 characters and then hash each one until it finds a match. This type of brute-force hacking takes time because of the number of possible combinations.</p>

<h2 id="password-complexity-vs-computational-power">Password complexity vs. computational power</h2>

<p>Let’s bust out our TI-85 calculators and see if we can figure out how long this program will take to run. For this example we will assume the passwords can only contain ASCII characters (uppercase, lowercase, digits, punctuation). This set is roughly 100 characters (this is rounded up to make the math easier to read). If we know that there are at least 6 characters and at most 8 characters in a password, then all the possible combinations can be represented by this expression:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>possiblePasswords = 100^8 + 100^7 + 100^6
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The result of this expression is equal to <code>10,101,000,000,000,000</code>. This is quite a large number, North of 10 quadrillion to be a little more precise, but what does it actually mean when it comes to our cracking program? This depends on the speed of the computer the cracking program is running on and how long it takes the computer to execute the SHA2 algorithm. The algorithm is the key component here because the rest of the program is extremely fast at creating the passwords.</p>

<p>Here’s where things get dicey. If you run a quick Google search for <a href="http://lmgtfy.com/?q=fastest+bitcoin+rig">“fastest bitcoin rig”</a> you’ll see that these machines are rated in terms of the number of hashes they can perform per second. The bigger ones can be rated as high as <code>44 TH/s</code>. That means it can generate 44 tera-hashes per second or <code>44,000,000,000,000</code>.</p>

<p>Now, if we divide the total number of passwords by the number of hashes we can generate per second, we are left with the total time it takes a Bitcoin rig to generate the hashes for all possible passwords. In our example above, this equates to:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>bitcoinRig = 4.4e13
possiblePasswords = 100^8 + 100^7 + 100^6 = 1.0101e16

numberOfSeconds = possiblePasswords / bitcoinRig = ~230
numberOfMinutes = numberOfSeconds / 60 = ~4
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This means that using this example Bitcoin rig, we could generate all the hashes for a password between 6 and 8 characters in length in roughly 4 minutes. Feeling nervous yet? Let’s add one additional character and see long it takes to hash all possible passwords between 6 and 9 characters.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>bitcoinRig = 4.4e13
possiblePasswords = 100^9 + 100^8 + 100^7 + 100^6 = 1.010101E18

numberOfSeconds = possiblePasswords / bitcoinRig = 22,956
numberOfMinutes = numberOfSeconds / 60 = ~383
numberOfHours = numberOfMinutes / 60 = ~6
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>By adding one additional character to the potential length of the password we increased the total compute time from 4 minutes to 6 hours. This is nearing a 100x increase in computational time to use the brute force strategy. You probably can see where this is going. To defeat the brute force strategy, you simply need to make it improbable to calculate all possible password combinations.</p>

<p>Let’s get crazy and make a jump to 16 characters:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>bitcoinRig = 4.4e13
possiblePasswords = 100^16 + 100^15 ... 100^7 + 100^6 = 1e32

numberOfSeconds = possiblePasswords / bitcoinRig = 2.27e18
numberOfMinutes = numberOfSeconds / 60 = 3.78e16
numberOfHours = numberOfMinutes / 60 = 630,000,000,000,000 or 630 trillion
numberOfDays = numberOfHours / 24 = 26,250,000,000,000 or 26.25 trillion days
numberOfYears = numberOfDays / 365 = 71,917,808,219 or 71.9 billion years
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>To boil down our results, if we take these expressions and simplify them, we can build an equation that solves for any length password.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>numberOfSeconds = 100^lengthOfPassword / computeSpeed
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This equation shows that as the password length increases, …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://fusionauth.io/learn/expert-advice/security/math-of-password-hashing-algorithms-entropy/">https://fusionauth.io/learn/expert-advice/security/math-of-password-hashing-algorithms-entropy/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://fusionauth.io/learn/expert-advice/security/math-of-password-hashing-algorithms-entropy/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25133061</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 04:00:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Write Code Like You Write a Recipe]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 69 | Comments 46 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25133041">thread link</a>) | @ahungry
<br/>
November 17, 2020 | https://ahungry.com/blog/2020-11-17-Write-Code-Like-You-Write-a-Recipe.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ahungry.com/blog/2020-11-17-Write-Code-Like-You-Write-a-Recipe.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="text-orgdb8398b">
<p>
As it tends to do, time continues to move on.  The project and code in
it eventually becomes legacy code (aka, someone else's problem to
maintain).
</p>

<p>
One day, the business drudges up that old automated cookie creation
idea and requests that it handles a new task - "instead of just cooking
peanut butter cookies, it'd be great if the cookie system could handle
oatmeal raisin as well!".
</p>

<p>
Hah!  You remember that old system, but you're onto newer and better
things.  This is a perfect task for the intern to sink their teeth
into - afterall, it's legacy and not high profile, it's been stable,
and it was so simple to implement the first time around.
</p>

<p>
The new set of requirements/recipe the intern works off of looks very
similar to the initial ones:
</p>

<ul>
<li>Step 1: Preheat oven to 325F, grease cookie sheet</li>
<li>Step 2: In bowl, stir oats, pumpkin puree and sugar until smooth.</li>
<li>Step 3: Beat in one egg white, then stir in baking soda, salt, and cinnamon.</li>
<li>Step 4: Roll dough into 1 inch balls and place 2 inches apart on the sheet.</li>
<li>Step 5: Bake for 8 minutes, cool for 5, enjoy!</li>
</ul>

<p>
He eagerly begins to expand the original code to handle the new case:
</p>

<div>
<pre><span>function</span> <span>makeCookies</span> <span>(</span><span>type</span> = <span>'peanut-butter'</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>if</span> <span>(</span>type === <span>'peanut-butter'</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    oven.setTemperature<span>(</span>350<span>)</span>
  <span>}</span>

  <span>if</span> <span>(</span>type === <span>'oatmeal-raisin'</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    oven.setTemperature<span>(</span>325<span>)</span>
  <span>}</span>

  sheet.grease<span>()</span>

  <span>if</span> <span>(</span>type === <span>'peanut-butter'</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    bowl.add<span>(</span>peanutButter<span>)</span>
    bowl.add<span>(</span>sugar<span>)</span>
  <span>}</span>

  <span>if</span> <span>(</span>type === <span>'oatmeal-raisin'</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    bowl.add<span>(</span>oats<span>)</span>
    bowl.add<span>(</span>pumpkinPuree<span>)</span>
    bowl.add<span>(</span>sugar<span>)</span>
  <span>}</span>

  bowl.stir<span>()</span>

  <span>if</span> <span>(</span>type === <span>'peanut-butter'</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    bowl.beat<span>(</span>egg<span>)</span>
    bowl.beat<span>(</span>egg<span>)</span>
    bowl.stirIn<span>(</span><span>[</span>bakingSoda, salt, vanilla<span>]</span><span>)</span>
  <span>}</span>

  <span>if</span> <span>(</span>type === <span>'oatmeal-raisin'</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    bowl.beat<span>(</span>eggWhite<span>)</span>
    bowl.stirIn<span>(</span><span>[</span>bakingSoda, salt, cinnamon<span>]</span><span>)</span>
  <span>}</span>

  <span>const</span> <span>dough</span> = bowl.makeDough<span>()</span>
  sheet.add<span>(</span>dough.balls<span>()</span><span>)</span>
  oven.add<span>(</span>sheet<span>)</span>

  <span>if</span> <span>(</span>type === <span>'peanut-butter'</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    oven.setTimer<span>(</span>10<span>)</span>
  <span>}</span>

  <span>if</span> <span>(</span>type === <span>'oatmeal-raisin'</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    oven.setTimer<span>(</span>8<span>)</span>
  <span>}</span>

  <span>const</span> <span>cookies</span> = oven.remove<span>(</span>sheet<span>)</span>
  sheet.cool<span>(</span>5<span>)</span>

  <span>return</span> cookies
<span>}</span>
</pre>
</div>

<p>
The code comes in, the peer reviews pass it as it meets the
requirements and nothing is obviously wrong.  Still, it has become a
bit harder to understand and you're left with a nagging feeling.
</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ahungry.com/blog/2020-11-17-Write-Code-Like-You-Write-a-Recipe.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25133041</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 03:56:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Run x86 Apps (including homebrew) in the Terminal on Apple Silicon]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 149 | Comments 84 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25132217">thread link</a>) | @JoshuaMulliken
<br/>
November 17, 2020 | https://www.notion.so/Run-x86-Apps-including-homebrew-in-the-Terminal-on-Apple-Silicon-8350b43d97de4ce690f283277e958602 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.notion.so/Run-x86-Apps-including-homebrew-in-the-Terminal-on-Apple-Silicon-8350b43d97de4ce690f283277e958602">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.notion.so/Run-x86-Apps-including-homebrew-in-the-Terminal-on-Apple-Silicon-8350b43d97de4ce690f283277e958602</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25132217</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 01:41:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[US Postal Service data suggests significant population decline in San Francisco]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 157 | Comments 182 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25128348">thread link</a>) | @edward
<br/>
November 17, 2020 | https://www.publiccommentsf.com/post/u-s-postal-service-data-suggests-significant-population-decline-in-san-francisco | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.publiccommentsf.com/post/u-s-postal-service-data-suggests-significant-population-decline-in-san-francisco">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-hook="post-description"><article><div><div data-rce-version="8.5.0"><div dir="ltr"><div><ul><li id="viewer-foo"><p><span><em>The United States Postal Service received 124,131 change of address requests originating in San Francisco zip codes between March and November 2020</em></span></p></li><li id="viewer-cc340"><p><span><em>94109 (</em><em>Polk Gulch/Nob Hill), </em><em>94110 (Inner Mission), 94107 (Mission Bay), and 94103 (South of Market) recorded the greatest number of households moving out</em></span></p></li><li id="viewer-6ebgn"><p><span><em>Among those that moved, a large majority relocated outside of the City with Las Vegas, Florida and Denver among the most common out-of-state destinations</em></span></p></li></ul><div id="viewer-c0m6l"><div><div data-hook="imageViewer" role="button" tabindex="0"><div role="img"><p><img data-pin-url="https://www.publiccommentsf.com/post/u-s-postal-service-data-suggests-significant-population-decline-in-san-francisco" data-pin-media="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/4c8f50_6fab1259d0e3431da6fffb71ea5be5bc~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000%2Ch_1000%2Cal_c%2Cq_80/file.png" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/4c8f50_6fab1259d0e3431da6fffb71ea5be5bc~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_300,h_300,al_c,q_5/file.jpg"></p></div></div></div></div><p id="viewer-e7g5"><span><span>Las Vegas is the number one out-of-state destination for residents leaving San Francisco, followed respectively by Palm Beach County, Fla., Seminole County, Fla., Denver metropolitan area and Beaverton, Ore., based on data provided by the United States Postal Service for the period from March 1, 2020 to Nov. 1, 2020. </span></span></p><p id="viewer-ea75i"><span><span>The USPS received a total of 124,131 change of address requests originating in San Francisco zip codes between March and November, and a large majority of those requests were directed to new addresses outside of the City. </span></span></p><div id="viewer-8ano2"><div><div data-hook="imageViewer" role="button" tabindex="0"><div role="img"><p><img data-pin-url="https://www.publiccommentsf.com/post/u-s-postal-service-data-suggests-significant-population-decline-in-san-francisco" data-pin-media="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/4c8f50_7baa9c7e1fc74172a2c392987b3388a8~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000%2Ch_1000%2Cal_c%2Cq_80/file.png" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/4c8f50_7baa9c7e1fc74172a2c392987b3388a8~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_300,h_300,al_c,q_5/file.png"></p></div></div></div></div><p id="viewer-f7b3r"><span><span>At least 34,803 of the address change requests, or 28%, were to new addresses within San Francisco, and the data shows a tremendous amount of movement in and out of specific neighborhoods. The USPS data showing moves within San Francisco zip codes did not include instances with 10 or fewer requests, so although not totally comprehensive, it nonetheless sheds light on where many of those moving trucks are headed. </span></span></p><p id="viewer-cll6n"><span><span>The zip code 94109, or <!-- -->Polk Gulch/Nob Hill<!-- -->, recorded the greatest number of households* moving out, followed by zip codes 94110 (Inner Mission), 94107 (Mission Bay), and 94103 (South of Market).</span></span></p><p id="viewer-90ujh"><span><span>In SF, housing inventory has risen 96% with a flood of new listings, according to a <em>Zillow 2020 Urban-Suburban Market Report </em>released </span><a href="https://www.zillow.com/research/2020-urb-suburb-market-report-27712/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span><u>in August</u></span></a><span>. That might explain the influx of folks heading to different areas within the City. The top three most popular destination neighborhoods were <!-- -->Polk Gulch<!-- -->/Nob Hill (<!-- -->3,276 households), Haight-Ashbury (2,729 households) and Lower Pacific Heights (2,399 households).</span></span></p><p id="viewer-cbo8c"><span><span>Looking at neighboring counties, 456 San Francisco households relocated to Marin County between March and November. Mill Valley (94941) was the most popular destination, with an estimated 65.8% of Marin-bound households relocating there, followed by Belvedere-Tiburon, with 13.6% of households.  </span></span></p><p id="viewer-a6bb6"><span><span>Still within the Bay Area, there were 608 change requests to San Mateo County, 453 to Alameda County, and a mere 44 households relocating to Contra Costa County. </span></span></p><p id="viewer-4nars"><span><span>Heading further north, 36 households relocated to zip codes in Truckee (Nevada County, Calif.); 14 to Sacramento and 11 households relocated to Sonoma County. </span></span></p><div id="viewer-7o4bp"><div><div data-hook="imageViewer" role="button" tabindex="0"><div role="img"><p><img data-pin-url="https://www.publiccommentsf.com/post/u-s-postal-service-data-suggests-significant-population-decline-in-san-francisco" data-pin-media="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/4c8f50_797292695c544f53bd93fc2da1645fc5~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000%2Ch_1000%2Cal_c%2Cq_80/file.png" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/4c8f50_797292695c544f53bd93fc2da1645fc5~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_300,h_300,al_c,q_5/file.png"></p></div></div></div></div><p id="viewer-cuhi8"><span><span><em>*Defined as a USPS customer receiving mail; in other words, a request could indicate an individual, a couple or a family. </em></span></span></p></div></div></div></div></article></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.publiccommentsf.com/post/u-s-postal-service-data-suggests-significant-population-decline-in-san-francisco</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25128348</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 19:20:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Emojis paved the way for UTF-8 everywhere]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 211 | Comments 141 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25124988">thread link</a>) | @velmu
<br/>
November 17, 2020 | https://developers.ibexa.co/blog/emojis-paved-the-way-for-utf-8-everywhere | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://developers.ibexa.co/blog/emojis-paved-the-way-for-utf-8-everywhere">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>When I was growing up using computers I was clueless about character sets. Mostly there were just US characters, and everyone converted the umlauts (Ä and Ö) and the A with the overring (Å) used in Finnish to their A, O and A equivalents. I guess you could call that transliteration, and we all did it&nbsp;because we had to. Technology evolved and we got more and more Äs, Ös and Ås in our digital lives. Everyone I knew was using Windows. Life was good. Then came the web and trouble started brewing.</p><div><p>I started my webmaster amateur career sometime in 1996. I still didn't know (or care) much about character sets, and the most common mistakes I made while learning was with images;&nbsp;I accidentally referred to them from my local C: drive or they were so large it would take a fortnight to load with my somewhat outdated 9.6k <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_Valley_Products" title="">GVC</a> modem.</p><p>It wasn't until my first "real job" in early 2000 when I got a glimpse of&nbsp;the horrors of character sets. At work <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Art_director" title="">Art Directors</a>&nbsp;were using colorful <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Power_Macintosh_G3" title="">Macintosh G3 tower computers</a> with&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mac_OS_9" title="">Mac OS 9</a> that didn't seem to run straight for more than a day. Even worse, sometimes they couldn't even display contemporary words like <a href="https://urbaanisanakirja.com/word/larvilautanen/" title="">lärvilautanen</a> or names like <a href="https://www.mikrobitti.fi/uutiset/jaakko-rytsola-oli-lamborghininsa-kanssa-it-kuplan-kasvot-menetti-miljoonat-ja-haluaa-nyt-opettaa-rahan-arvon-uudella-sovelluksella/dc23a929-db4d-4302-ab7d-3b5a8127d0ff" title="">Rytsölä</a> right. I&nbsp;snickered and crouched over the keyboard of my rock-solid <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windows_NT" title="">Windows NT</a> workstation to&nbsp;craft some fine artesan HTML with notepad.exe.</p><p>The early 2000s were an intense learning experience for me. I switched over from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_Notepad" title="">Microsoft Notepad</a> to <a href="https://medium.com/@velmu/is-it-time-to-reconsider-dreamweaver-34d442e5c278" title="">Macromedia DreamWeaver</a> to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macromedia_HomeSite" title="">Allaire HomeSite</a>. My career peaked when I worked on&nbsp;<a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20001019003024/http://www.bomfunk.net/main_first.html" title="">the homepage for Bomfunk MCs</a>.&nbsp;I felt invincible. I ran into trouble with characters occasionally, but the "real developers" working with ASP or Java were always willing to help the front end developer greenhorn&nbsp;navigate the seas of broken <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Verdana" title="">Verdana</a> on a manager's&nbsp;screen. Every so often I also had issues with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Newline" title="">line breaks</a> too, but the bearded guy always helped me out. I think he used <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Solaris_(operating_system)" title="">Solaris</a>.</p><p>I didn't really start my hate-hate relationship with characters until around 2003. At twenty-three I was now a <em>Senior Developer</em>, and had stretched my wings to the server-side as well with mad LAMP&nbsp;skillz and setting up vhosts on Apache. I was, what you would now call&nbsp;a <em>Senior Fullstack Ninja</em>. Or that's how I saw myself. I was&nbsp;the person people came to get advice from, knee-deep in JavaScript, having innovated an <a href="https://janit.iki.fi/pdf/tarvainen_thesis-040428.pdf" title="">amazing client-side bug tracker</a>&nbsp;that would change how we work. Little did I know.</p><p>At this point I was also working on some projects for a well-known (at the time) Finnish mobile phone manufacturer in foreign languages like Hebrew&nbsp;and Hungarian. This is when it all started falling apart. In the past I had been able to solve issues with weird characters by poking them with a stick or the magical&nbsp;<em>charset=iso-8859-1</em>&nbsp;metatag. But things were gradually getting worse. I was increasingly unable to use HomeSite because the characters were garbled. After too many <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YYv4yadRexY" title="">Jallu</a> shots, I&nbsp;opened up to a guru about this and he mumbled something about no support for UTF-8.&nbsp;</p><p>Now I was a man on a mission. I would find out all about this UTF-8 and conquer this land of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Standard_Generalized_Markup_Language" title="">SGML</a>-like markup once again. I armed myself with all the information on the interwebs and even bought a hard copy of the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/unicode-explained/059610121X/" title="">O'Reilly mini reference on UTF-8</a>. Then I kind of got it, but things were complicated in the real world. Some things were <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UTF-8" title="">UTF-8</a>, some <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ISO/IEC_8859-1" title="">ISO-8859-1</a> and occasionally there was some random <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macintosh_Latin_encoding" title="">Macintosh Latin</a> from a unicorn who could do design and HTML. I read deeper and started seeing nightmares about monsters like the the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Byte_order_mark" title="">Byte Order Mark</a> and&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Endianness" title="">Endianness</a>. Cumulatively I spent weeks on&nbsp;figuring out character sets from files&nbsp;and parsing out something not fÃ©d.</p><p>I was still quite confused&nbsp;with the prospect of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UTF-16" title="">UTF-16</a> and what it would mean for me. Gladly that seemed to have been a whole lot of nothing, and with a steady&nbsp;diet of Linux, OS X and Windows on the desktop it seemed the worst was over. There were some cases where I needed to figure out strange issues with broken characters (usually because of using <a href="https://janit.iki.fi/shit/PHP-the-good-parts.png" title="">non-multibyte safe functions</a> on the server), but this was much more of my own fault than random wonky encodings from input data.</p><p>Still, there were some systems not using UTF-8 by default.&nbsp;There was little incentive for that as it wasn't like there were new letters being added to the English alphabet&nbsp;or anything. This changed gradually with the mainstream adoption of smartphones and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emoji" title="">Emojis</a>. Those cute little&nbsp;🖼️s are essentially new letters to the alphabet. To stay relevant in the age of social media you had to support emoji&nbsp;or you were&nbsp;💀 in the 💧. Fast forward to today and I can't remember the time I wrestled broken characters.</p><p>There are still enterprise&nbsp;systems that can suffer a death by a thousand candy-bar emojis&nbsp;and <a href="https://dev.mysql.com/doc/refman/8.0/en/charset-unicode-utf8mb4.html" title="">UTF-8 quirks in MySQL</a>, but overall I am now in a much happier&nbsp;place. I still don't really know how all this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plane_(Unicode)" title="">character set black magic</a>&nbsp;works deep down, but I don't need to know. For most part it's now a non-issue in my life. And it's amusing to see <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017-10-31-apple-ios-11-1-new-emojis-security-updates.html" title="">Apple using new emojis as a carrot</a> to get people to install the latest security patches. This was a fun nostalgia trip, but I certainly wouldn't want to go back in time to work on multilingual web development. Or implement designs with rounded corners.</p><p>I'd like to extend a&nbsp;big thank you to everyone for using emoji! You saved my&nbsp;🍑!</p><p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@christiannkoepke?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Christiann Koepke</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/peaches-tree?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Unsplash</a></p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://developers.ibexa.co/blog/emojis-paved-the-way-for-utf-8-everywhere</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25124988</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 15:39:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Best aspects of C]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 159 | Comments 226 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25124012">thread link</a>) | @Jorengarenar
<br/>
November 17, 2020 | https://blog.joren.ga/programming/best-of-c | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.joren.ga/programming/best-of-c">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
    <blockquote>
  <p>"Is C good as first language?" "Is&nbsp;there still future with C?"
"Why should I even bother with C?" "C is old!" …</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Have you heard such words? Well, I have. Countless of times, be it
in direct conversation or on a forum. The response is, as always, "it depends",
but in my humble opinion learning C is really valuable experience.</p>

<p>In this not too long text I hope to show you what I think makes C great.</p>

<h3 id="spirit-of-c">Spirit of C</h3>

<p>Let's start with a quote from document <a href="http://www.open-std.org/jtc1/sc22/wg14/www/C99RationaleV5.10.pdf">C99RationaleV5.10</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The C89 Committee kept as a major goal to preserve the traditional spiritof C.
There are many facets of the spirit of C, but the essence is a community
sentiment of the underlying principles upon which the C language is based.
Some of the facets of the spirit of C can be summarized in phrases like:</p>
  <ul>
    <li><em>Trust the programmer.</em></li>
    <li><em>Don’t prevent the programmer from doing what needs to be done.</em></li>
    <li><em>Keep the language small and simple.</em></li>
    <li><em>Provide only one way to do an operation.</em></li>
    <li><em>Make it fast, even if it is not guaranteed to be portable.</em></li>
  </ul>
</blockquote>

<p>Above points directly relate to what I will talk further in the article.</p>

<h3 id="mid-level">"Mid-level"</h3>

<p>In regards of level, there are two types of languages: low and high.</p>

<p>Low-level languages are close to the hardware, the only closer thing to CPU
would be electricity itself. Those languages are divided into machine code and
Assembly. The former is a stream of raw, usually binary, data. If somebody is
required to work with it, usually does it using more "readable" hexadecimal form.</p>

<p>Second-generation languages - Assembly - provide one abstraction level on top
of the machine code. Those languages are mostly only a mapping of human-readable
symbols, including symbolic addresses, to opcodes, addresses, numeric constants,
strings and so on. Also are different for each processor.</p>

<p>How do high-level languages, providing more abstraction, compare? Quoting Wikipedia:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>In contrast to low-level programming languages, it may use natural language
elements, be easier to use, or may automate (or even hide entirely) significant
areas of computing systems (e.g. memory management), making the process of
developing a program simpler and more understandable than when using a
lower-level language. The amount of abstraction provided defines how
"high-level" a programming language is.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>In short: low = more machine friendly, high = more human friendly.</p>

<p>C is high-level, but back when it was created, most of the work was still being
done in low-level Assembly. As a result, C has lower level of abstraction than
other (still) widely used languages, hence I like to call it "mid-level".</p>

<p>You can also easily (with less language bloat) compile C code to Assembly
instead to binary and examine what instructions CPU will execute.</p>

<p>And if it there is a need, popular C compilers offers you the option in C level
down and use inline Assembly to squeeze everything out of CPU. Not really many
other languages implement such a thing.</p>

<h3 id="fairly-simple">Fairly simple</h3>

<p>Low-level languages are harder to program in. Not because they are more complicated,
but because they are more error prone and thus require way more commitment,
memorizing and fiddling.</p>

<p>C is mid-level, so "by definition" it's easier. But there comes the surprise,
learning it is easier compared to higher level languages. Why? Because of really
simple syntax and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Structured_programming">structured paradigm</a>
(don't confuse with <code>struct</code>!). It doesn't take so much to learn the basics.
Loops, functions, structures, pointers, variables, types - the core of language.
Intense week to get the general idea. The rest is "just" maths and CS theorem.</p>

<p>But, but, but, but! Don't get me wrong! To master anything you will
need a lot more practice! <strong>A lot!</strong> And it's truth for anything out there!</p>

<h3 id="fast-and-lightweight">Fast and lightweight</h3>

<p>Standard C library is small compared to other languages (e.g Java). It's small
enough for you to try to memorize all functions successfully (not that it would
be a huge benefit). Yeah, many things should be deprecated long ago, there
obviously is some bloat (try to maintains something without bloat for few years,
let alone few decades), but there is not much enough of it to hinder the performance.</p>

<p>And what if libc is still too much? Nothing stands in the way of not using it
at all. Just don't include any of its headers - not even simple <code>printf()</code> will
be present. Replace it with any other library of your choice.</p>

<p>Maturity, emphasis on proper memory management, inline Assembly, small abstraction
and little bloat gives programmer really good control over the program.</p>

<p>This makes C an ideal choice for OS kernels (Linux, Windows NT or macOS's XNU to
name a few) or other languages (e.g. Python). That's also why C is so popular
on embedded systems, where you cannot afford to waste resources.</p>

<h3 id="ubiquity--portability">Ubiquity = portability</h3>

<p>Does there exist any (still) significant platform with no C compiler available?
Except for those which run only Assembly, I've never heard about one.
C programs are present on your high-end gaming PC, on NASA spacecrafts and
in ticket machines. Literally everywhere. C software runs the world.</p>

<p>In accordance to previous paragraphs, C is peculiarly strong choice for
microcontrollers and other forms of embedded systems, which surround us every day.</p>

<p>And have you heard about <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Foreign_function_interface">FFI</a>?
Turns out many other languages like to have some kind of compatibility with C.</p>

<p>You don't need to worry if you will be able to use this language somewhere as
for 99% you can! (Although it doesn't mean you should…) It means, that while
code may not be 100% portable, you will be a portable programmer.</p>

<h3 id="the-influencer">The influencer</h3>

<p>C has both directly and indirectly influenced innumerous amount of languages.
C++, Java, Go, D, Rust, Perl, even PHP and Python - those are but few examples.</p>

<p>Obviously, knowledge of C isn't needed to learn any of them and sometimes
may even push you to use not the best practices.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, I think it's important to remember the roots. And if you are
cautious, familiarity with C might give you some foothold. It's especially the
case with C++.</p>

<h3 id="rich-collection-of-libraries">Rich collection of libraries</h3>

<p>I suspect all this talk about fastness, lightness, mid-level, Assembly etc. might
have give you an idea, you will need to implement everything yourself. There may
be not any <a href="https://docs.oracle.com/javase/8/docs/api/java/util/LinkedHashMap.html"><code>LinkedHashMap</code></a>
like in Java or other or other functionality like garbage collector…
True, true, except…  not entirely.</p>

<p>C is mature and popular language. Name a thing and believe me, somebody somewhere
already created library for it (although if think about something too obscure,
you won't find it for all the world, but it does exists).</p>

<p>You want garbage collector? <a href="https://www.hboehm.info/gc/">Boehm GC</a> has you covered.
TUI? Nothing like timeless <a href="https://invisible-island.net/ncurses/">ncurses</a>.
Examples can be listed almost infinitely:
<a href="https://gtk.org/">GTK</a>,
<a href="https://pdcurses.org/">PDCurses</a>,
<a href="https://curl.haxx.se/libcurl/">libcurl</a>,
<a href="https://www.alsa-project.org/">ALSA</a>,
<a href="https://codeplea.com/genann">Genann</a>,
<a href="http://libsound.io/">libsoundio</a>,
<a href="https://libsdl.org/">SDL</a>,
<a href="https://www.sqlite.org/index.html">SQLite</a>,
<a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/libc/manual/html_node/Getopt.html">getopt</a>,
<a href="https://www.opengl.org/">OpenGL</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/benhoyt/inih">inih</a>,
<a href="https://gmplib.org/">GMP</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/DaveGamble/cJSON">cJSON</a>,
<a href="https://mupdf.com/">MuPDF</a>,
<a href="https://www.openssl.org/">OpenSSL</a>…</p>

<p>It's very universal language - you can program basically anything: web server,
video game (e.g. <a href="https://github.com/id-Software">classics from <em>id Software</em></a>),
operating system, other programming language or wrapper forcing Firefox to obey
<a href="https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/XDG_Base_Directory">XDG Base Directory specification</a>,
because when I'm an administrator, the programs will do exacly what I told them to!</p>

<p>However, please, remember - the fact you can, doesn't mean you should. For example,
if you want to create a video game, you really ought to turn your eyes to C++.
And you should know, that…</p>

<h3 id="c-is-highly-backward-compatible">C++ is highly backward compatible</h3>

<p>Why do I even make the whole point out of C++ here? Because it's one of most
widely used languages today and you encountering it is more than certain.</p>

<p>In contrary to other languages embracing C compatibility, C++ was created as its
direct descendant and committee goes to great lengths to keep the "copy-paste"
compatibility with it - in most cases you can compile C code as C++ just fine.</p>

<p>Don't be mistaken, C++ isn't by any means a superset of C - the code isn't always
going to work with C++ and a good C code isn't necessary good C++ code. Consider example:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>int</span><span>*</span> <span>x</span> <span>=</span> <span>malloc</span><span>(</span><span>10</span> <span>*</span> <span>sizeof</span><span>(</span><span>*</span><span>x</span><span>));</span>
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>Proper way in C, but in C++ there ought to be <code>(int*)</code> before <code>malloc()</code>,
for it to work, not to mention you should use <code>new int[10]</code> instead.</p>

<p>Although in most cases you can use C library safely in your C++ project.</p>

<p>All examples from the previous point not only <strong>can be</strong>, but <strong>often are</strong>
used in such way. E.g. I myself used <em>ncurses</em> in my C++ code for hex editor
<a href="https://joren.ga/bym/">Bym</a>.</p>

<p>Even libraries already compiled with C compiler can be made compatible with C++,
thanks to <a href="https://en.cppreference.com/w/cpp/language/language_linkage"><code>extern "C"</code></a>
linkage specifier.</p>

<h3 id="program-in-c-song"><em>Program in C</em> song</h3>

<p>
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tas0O586t80" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p>

<hr>

<h3 id="a-blot-on-the-landscape">A blot on the landscape…</h3>

<p>C was created in year 1972 on the foundation of B language, so over the years
it acquired some quirks (<code>memcpy()</code> is defined in string header!), some things
became obsolete, some useless and are kept only for compatibility with old code.</p>

<p>A beginner is likely to burn a lot of time chasing down strange behavior caused
by memory corruption with no idea how to reason about, what may lead actually
big discouraged to programming in general. There is little to none mechanism
to prevent programmer from shooting themselves in the foot.</p>

<p>It's also important to take into account that C is not the introduction to
Computer Science. Learning none of languages is. You need to study it properly
to get a true understanding of this vast field. If not formal education in
university, then online one will be good too. The Internet is full of resources,
some can be found on my <a href="https://joren.ga/urlsList/">list of URLs</a>.</p>

<hr>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>Learning C is valuable experience and it's worth it. If not as your first
language, then as second, third, fourth or whatever. There are a lot of advantages,
but also some disadvantages. At least trying won't hurt. Give it a chance, who
knows, you may truly get to like it, just like me.</p>

<p>And don't believe people saying "C is dead" or "It will soon be replaced"
(I'm looking at you Rust fans). C is fine and will be relevant for few next decades too.
Heck! COBOL, nearly forgotten, yet there are still job openings! How is C supposed
to become obscure when, in the moment I write those words, there is planned new
standard …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.joren.ga/programming/best-of-c">https://blog.joren.ga/programming/best-of-c</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.joren.ga/programming/best-of-c</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25124012</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 14:23:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Rust Performance Book]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 143 | Comments 15 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25122178">thread link</a>) | @walterbell
<br/>
November 17, 2020 | https://nnethercote.github.io/perf-book/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nnethercote.github.io/perf-book/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
        <!-- Provide site root to javascript -->
        

        <!-- Work around some values being stored in localStorage wrapped in quotes -->
        

        <!-- Set the theme before any content is loaded, prevents flash -->
        

        <!-- Hide / unhide sidebar before it is displayed -->
        

        <nav id="sidebar" aria-label="Table of contents">
            
            
        </nav>

        <div id="page-wrapper">

            <div class="page">
                
                
                

                
                
                

                <!-- Apply ARIA attributes after the sidebar and the sidebar toggle button are added to the DOM -->
                

                <div id="content">
                    <main>
                        
<p>Performance is important for many Rust programs. </p>
<p>This book contains many techniques that can improve the performance—speed and
memory usage—of Rust programs. The <a href="https://nnethercote.github.io/perf-book/compile-times.html">Compile Times</a> section also contains some
techniques that will improve the compile times of Rust programs. Some of the
book’s techniques only require changing build configurations, but many require
changing code.</p>
<p>Some of the techniques within are entirely Rust-specific, and some involve
ideas that can be applied (often with modifications) to programs written in
other languages. The <a href="https://nnethercote.github.io/perf-book/general-tips.html">General Tips</a> section also includes some general
principles that apply to any programming language. Nonetheless, this book is
mostly about the performance of Rust programs and is no substitute for a
general purpose guide to profiling and optimization.</p>
<p>The book also focuses on techniques that are practical and proven: many are
accompanied by links to pull requests or other resources that show how the
technique was used on a real-world Rust program.</p>
<p>This book is aimed at intermediate and advanced Rust users. Beginner Rust users
have more than enough to learn and these techniques are likely to be an
unhelpful distraction to them.</p>

                    </main>

                    <nav aria-label="Page navigation">
                        <!-- Mobile navigation buttons -->
                        

                        
                            <a rel="next" href="https://nnethercote.github.io/perf-book/benchmarking.html" title="Next chapter" aria-label="Next chapter" aria-keyshortcuts="Right">
                                <i></i>
                            </a>
                        

                        
                    </nav>
                </div>
            </div>

            <nav aria-label="Page navigation">
                

                
                    <a rel="next" href="https://nnethercote.github.io/perf-book/benchmarking.html" title="Next chapter" aria-label="Next chapter" aria-keyshortcuts="Right">
                        <i></i>
                    </a>
                
            </nav>

        </div>

        

        

        

        
        
        

        

        
        
        
        
        

        
        
        

        <!-- Custom JS scripts -->
        

        

    

</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nnethercote.github.io/perf-book/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25122178</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 10:40:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Getting Started with Ansible]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 97 | Comments 96 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25122103">thread link</a>) | @mmanja
<br/>
November 17, 2020 | https://steampunk.si/blog/getting-started-with-ansible/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://steampunk.si/blog/getting-started-with-ansible/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                <p>In our <a href="https://steampunk.si/blog/introduction-to-configuration-management-tools/" title="Introduction to tonfiguration management tools post">previous blog post</a>, we looked at what configuration management
tools bring to the table. And in this post, we will take a closer look at
Ansible, our configuration management tool of choice. So if you want to learn
what Ansible is, what it does, and how it works, this is the post for you.</p>
<p>We will start by introducing <a href="https://www.ansible.com/" title="Ansible's home page">Ansible</a> and some of the benefits we gain when
using it. Next, we will describe the differences between three different
Ansible packages and give some advice on picking the right one for our use
case. We will continue with the installation instructions and finally wrap up
with an interactive walkthrough of Ansible’s basic functionality like running
Ansible playbooks and installing extra Ansible content.</p>
<h2 id="what-is-ansible">What is Ansible</h2>
<p>We all probably heard about automation systems that suffer from <em>managing the
management</em> and <em>automating your automation</em> issues. Ansible not only brings
order to our infrastructure, but it also does it sustainably.</p>
<p>Because Ansible is <strong>agentless</strong>, dealing with daemons being down,
upgrading agents, and patching agent security vulnerabilities are a thing of
the past.  All we need to do is keep our control node (the computer where the
Ansible runs) updated, and we should be safe.</p>
<p>But what does Ansible do exactly? <strong>Ansible’s primary responsibility is to
reliably enforce the desired state on a set of targets.</strong></p>
<p>We usually keep the state description in a relatively human-friendly and
machine-executable file called an Ansible playbook. We have a bit more
flexibility when it comes to storing information about targets. We can use:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Static inventory files</strong> that contain login information for our targets.</li>
<li><strong>Inventory plugins</strong> that fetch connection information from some
canonical sources like IaaS API.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Enforcing the desired state</strong> in the Ansible world can mean almost anything:
writing a configuration file, creating a virtual machine in the cloud, adding
a VLAN to a network switch, etc. All we need is an Ansible module for
performing the task at hand. And there are a lot of them available out there.
We will talk more about how to obtain them in the last part of this post.</p>
<p><strong>Target</strong> (or <strong>host</strong>) is also quite a broad term in the Ansible world.
Historically, the primary target type was a virtual machine that Ansible
managed via the Secure Shell (SSH) protocol. But today, Ansible can control
many other things like containers, networking equipment, and various
Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) platforms. And because Ansible is
agentless, getting it to work with a specific piece of software or hardware is
usually much easier compared to other configuration management tools.</p>
<p>Now we are ready to start talking about Ansible versions.</p>
<h2 id="what-ansible-package-to-use">What Ansible package to use</h2>
<p>Today, there are three Ansible packages that we can use for our day-to-day
automatization tasks: <code>ansible-2.9</code>, <code>ansible-2.10</code>, and <code>ansible-base-2.10</code>.
Why? Because the monolithic Ansible package was split into a core engine and a
few bundles of Ansible content called Ansible Collections for the 2.10
release.</p>
<p>But fortunately for us, selecting the correct package is relatively simple.
Just answer the following questions in order and stop when you answer “yes”
for the first time:</p>
<ol>
<li>Are you a Red Hat subscriber or want to purchase support? Use
<strong>ansible-2.9</strong>.</li>
<li>Do you have existing playbooks and no time to learn about Ansible
Collections? Use <strong>ansible-2.10</strong>.</li>
<li>Use <strong>ansible-base-2.10</strong>.</li>
</ol>
<p>We made sure examples from this blog post work with all of the versions
mentioned above, so you should have no trouble following along.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-install-ansible">How to install Ansible</h2>
<p>We only need to install Ansible onto the control node (the computer or virtual
machine you will run Ansible commands on). The most flexible way of installing
Ansible is using <code>pip</code>:</p>
<pre><code>$ pip install --user "ansible==2.9.*"  # For ansible 2.9
$ pip install --user ansible           # For ansible 2.10 and newer
$ pip install --user ansible-base      # For ansible-base
</code></pre>
<p>This will install Ansible only for our user account and not mess up the system
if anything goes wrong.</p>
<p>We can also install Ansible using our distribution’s package manager (for
example, <code>dnf</code> on RHEL 8 or <code>apt</code> on Debian-derived distributions).</p>
<pre><code>$ yum install ansible  # RHEL and CentOS 7
$ dnf install ansible  # RHEL and CentOS 8
$ apt install ansible  # Debian and Ubuntu
</code></pre>
<p>But bear in mind that most distributions do not package <code>ansible-base</code> and
<code>ansible</code> 2.10 yet, so you might need to resort to the <code>pip</code> method for the
time being. Official <a href="https://docs.ansible.com/ansible/latest/installation_guide/intro_installation.html" title="Official installation instructions">installation instructions</a> contain even more
installation-related details.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, we cannot use a Windows machine as an Ansible control node.
Matt Davis, one of the core Ansible developers, wrote a
<a href="http://blog.rolpdog.com/2020/03/why-no-ansible-controller-for-windows.html" title="Why no Ansible controller for Windows?">blog post</a> about the reasons. Matt also gives some hints about
what Windows users can do to remedy the situation, so make sure you check his
post out.</p>
<p>Once the installation is behind us, we should be able to run the following
command without errors:</p>
<pre><code>$ ansible --version
ansible 2.9.14
  config file = /etc/ansible/ansible.cfg
  configured module search path = ['/usr/share/ansible/plugins/modules']
  ansible python module location = /usr/lib/python3.8/site-packages/ansible
  executable location = /usr/bin/ansible
  python version = 3.8.6 (default, Sep 25 2020, 00:00:00) [GCC 10.2.1 20200723]
</code></pre>
<p>If nothing went awry, we are ready to start playing with Ansible.</p>
<h2 id="taking-ansible-for-a-spin">Taking Ansible for a spin</h2>
<p>In this last section, we will play around a bit with Ansible. We will start by
analyzing a small Ansible playbook and explaining the purpose of its
components, continue with discussing the Ansible inventory, and conclude
our escapade with some custom Ansible content installation.</p>
<p>If you would like to follow along with us, you will need a Linux computer with
Ansible and Docker installed.</p>
<h3 id="ansible-playbook">Ansible playbook</h3>
<p>Let us start with something relatively simple:</p>
<pre><code>---
- name: Configure local computer
  hosts: localhost

  tasks:
    - name: Create config file
      ansible.builtin.copy:
        dest: /tmp/my.cfg
        content: Hello, World!
</code></pre>
<p>Even if you never heard about Ansible playbook or YAML before, you probably
guessed that we want to create the <code>/tmp/my.cfg</code> file with the <code>Hello, World!</code>
inside it on our local computer. Let us test this. When we run the
<code>ansible-playbook</code> command (we assumed that the playbook is stored in the
<code>play.yaml</code> file), we will see something like this:</p>
<pre><code>$ ansible-playbook play.yaml
[WARNING]: provided hosts list is empty, only localhost is available. Note
  that the implicit localhost does not match 'all'

PLAY [Configure local computer] ******************************************

TASK [Gathering Facts] ***************************************************
ok: [localhost]

TASK [Create config file] ************************************************
changed: [localhost]

PLAY RECAP ***************************************************************
localhost              : ok=2    changed=1    unreachable=0    failed=0
                         skipped=0    rescued=0    ignored=0
</code></pre>
<p>And sure enough, if we open the <code>/tmp/my-cfg.txt</code> file, the hello is there ;)
But how did Ansible know what to do? Explanation time ;)</p>
<p>Ansible playbook is nothing more than a list of plays that Ansible executes
one after another. For the sake of simplicity, our example contains a single
Configure local computer play. The <code>hosts: localhost</code> line informed Ansible
that we will be messing with our local computer. This is the target that we
talked about previously.</p>
<p>All real action happened in the <code>tasks</code> section of the play. The
<code>ansible.builtin.copy:</code> line told Ansible that we want to use the built-in
copy module to create a file. And the <code>dest: /tmp/my-cfg.txt</code> and <code>content: Hello</code> parameter lines provided information to the copy module about our
file’s location and what to place inside it, respectively. The line that
starts with <code>- name</code> serves as documentation for us and is printed to the
output when Ansible starts executing the task at hand.</p>
<p>Technically speaking, Ansible did not create a file. It would be more accurate
to say that Ansible made sure our text file exists and has the correct
content. We can see this technical nitpick in action if we run the same
<code>ansible-playbook</code> command again:</p>
<pre><code>$ ansible-playbook play.yaml
[WARNING]: provided hosts list is empty, only localhost is available. Note
  that the implicit localhost does not match 'all'

PLAY [Configure local computer] ******************************************

TASK [Gathering Facts] ***************************************************
ok: [localhost]

TASK [Create config file] ************************************************
ok: [localhost]

PLAY RECAP ***************************************************************
localhost              : ok=2    changed=0    unreachable=0    failed=0
                         skipped=0    rescued=0    ignored=0
</code></pre>
<p>Notice how in the previous run, Ansible reported our file creation task as
changed, and in this last run, the output changed to ok. This happened because
Ansible determined that the file’s current and desired state are precisely the
same, and there is nothing to do.</p>
<p>But our configuration files are rarely entirely static, meaning that we often
need to customize their content based on some external information. And this
is where variables and <code>ansible.builtin.template</code> module come into play - pun
intended ;).</p>
<p>Using variables in templates is reasonably straightforward: we just need to
place the variable name inside double curly braces, and the template module
will replace it with the variable’s value. For example, this is how our
parameterized configuration file could look:</p>
<pre><code>{{ greeting }} from {{ ansible_distribution }}, World!
</code></pre>
<p>But before we can use the variable, we need to define it somewhere. There are
<a href="https://docs.ansible.com/ansible/latest/user_guide/playbooks_variables.html" title="Official Ansible documentation in variables">many places</a> where Ansible will look for variable definitions, but we
will keep it simple and provide them as part of the playbook (the <code>vars</code>
section in the listing below).</p>
<pre><code>---
- name: Configure local computer
  hosts: localhost

  vars:
    greeting: Welcome

  tasks:
    - name: Create config file
      …</code></pre></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://steampunk.si/blog/getting-started-with-ansible/">https://steampunk.si/blog/getting-started-with-ansible/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://steampunk.si/blog/getting-started-with-ansible/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25122103</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 10:29:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Indian developer jailed for making unauthorized train ticket booking app]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 160 | Comments 73 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25121465">thread link</a>) | @jaikant77
<br/>
November 17, 2020 | https://www.huffingtonpost.in/entry/s-yuvarajaa-super-tatkal-pro-irctc-train-ticket-booking_in_5fb25d5cc5b6d8781808f6ab | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.huffingtonpost.in/entry/s-yuvarajaa-super-tatkal-pro-irctc-train-ticket-booking_in_5fb25d5cc5b6d8781808f6ab">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure>
        <p><figcaption>S. Yuvarajaa</figcaption></p></figure><div><p><em>Editor’s note: IRCTC’s response on Twitter has been added to the story.&nbsp;</em></p><p>Kozhikode, KERALA — On the afternoon of October 23, S. Yuvarajaa was at his home in Tirupur, writing software, when the Railway Police Force came knocking on his door.&nbsp;</p><p>“Did you develop this app?” the policemen asked, pointing to a phone screen displaying Super Tatkal, a phone app developed by Yuvarajaa that books tatkal rail tickets much faster than Indian Railway Catering and Tourism Corporation (<a href="https://www.huffingtonpost.in/news/irctc/">IRCTC</a>), the Indian Railways’ famously cumbersome website.</p><p>When he said ‘yes’, Yuvarajaa, a 32-year-old alumnus of IIT-Kharagpur, was arrested under the Indian Railways Act 1989 for the “unauthorized business of procuring and supplying railway tickets”.</p><p><em><strong><a href="https://www.huffingtonpost.in/entry/lsr-student-suicide-lockdown-poverty-hostel-policy_in_5fa8ab81c5b6f21920dd705e" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lockdown Poverty And Hostel Policy Push LSR Scholarship Student To Suicide</a></strong></em></p><p>Soon after his arrest, the railway authorities deactivated Super Tatkal and Super Tatkal Pro, which were available on Google Playstore until then. Yuvarajaa spent about a week in jail.</p><p>Now out on bail and faced with mounting legal fees, Yuvarajaa says he just wants the railways to understand that far from “swindling” users — as the railways have alleged — he just wanted to help rail passengers book their tickets with ease.</p><p>“I want them to talk to me and find out how the apps can help IRCTC’s ticket-booking operations. I might have been naïve and unaware of consequences when I developed the apps but I had the best of intentions,” Yuvarajaa told <em>HuffPost India</em>. “I have a solution that can effectively address the current issues on the IRCTC website<strong>.</strong> I would like to help them make their website better so that end users, the passengers, can book tickets easily.”</p><p>For now, Yuvarajaa and Super Tatkal have become unfortunate case studies of what happens when the software industry’s ethos of digital disruption crashes into India’s famously prickly bureaucracy as epitomised by the 167-year-old Indian Railways.&nbsp;</p><p>A young coder from a small town who gave up a comfortable job in an aeronautics firm to set up his own business, Yuvarajaa is a poster child for the Indian government’s mission to support digital entrepreneurs of the sort that Prime Minister <a href="https://www.huffingtonpost.in/news/narendra-modi/">Narendra Modi</a> exhorts to “take risks” and embark on adventures.</p><p>Yet, as Yuvarajaa’s arrest shows, the biggest impediment to innovation are his government’s many departments. Yuvarajaa saw himself as an entrepreneur’ but the Railways press release announcing his arrest described him as a “tout”.</p><p>&nbsp;“Regulatory frameworks, be that of IRCTC or that of any other government institution, should not be bypassed,” said S. Arunachalam, Academic Director of Centre for Innovation and Entrepreneurship, Indian School of Business. “But I think that he should have been warned first to reach an amicable solution.”&nbsp;</p><p>IRCTC responded to <em>HuffPost India</em> on Twitter, saying that the use of “illegal software” is prohibited under the Railways Act.</p></div><div><blockquote data-dnt="true" data-conversation="none"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The software developed was used illegally to book tkts through the tickets denying genuine users.Use of illegal software is prohibited under Rly act. No faster app as these features were  available with IRCTC which were disabled to ensure level playing field .</p>— IRCTC (@IRCTCofficial) <a href="https://twitter.com/IRCTCofficial/status/1328668272032583683?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank">November 17, 2020</a></blockquote></div><div><h3><strong>From Tirupur to Super Tatkal</strong></h3><p>The story of Super Tatkal has its roots in Yuvarajaa’s journey from a small town in Tamil Nadu to Bengaluru, India’s self-described Silicon Valley.</p><p>Yuvarajaa comes from a family of farmers—&nbsp;his father worked as one until he died in 2008 and his mother, Eswari, still cultivates the family’s 30 acres of land.</p><p>Yuvarajaa recalls that he first started programming in BASIC as an 11-year-old. Soon, he developed a love for coding and started considering engineering as a career option when he was introduced to Java in Class XI.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>In 2007, Yuvarajaa signed up for an aeronautical engineering degree at the Madras Institute of Technology, Tamil Nadu’s premier tech school. Since he had topped Class XII in his district, he had a three-year scholarship of Rs 3,000 per month from the Indian government’s Defence Research and Development Organisation (DRDO).</p><p>At MIT-Chennai, Yuvarajaa met others like him who loved coding.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>“We were a group of people who liked programming. When some of us went on to take up jobs, Yuvarajaa went for higher studies as he was passionate about engineering,” said Akilan, a friend and fellow aeronautical engineer who is currently working in New Jersey.&nbsp;</p><p>After graduating in 2010 from MIT Chennai, Yuvarajaa joined IIT-Kharagpur for an M. Tech in aeronautical engineering. Again, he had a scholarship, this time for topping the GATE (Graduate Aptitude Test in Engineering).&nbsp;</p><p>Once he finished his IIT course, he joined a firm in Bengaluru.&nbsp;</p><p>“In aeronautical engineering there are very few private firms which offer jobs. But he got one of the good jobs available in India,” Akilan said.&nbsp;</p><p>While working in Bengaluru, Yuvarajaa frequently booked tickets to travel home to Tirupur.&nbsp;</p><p>“It was then that I realised that the IRCTC app is terribly slow. Besides, I always wanted to develop apps and this felt like the right time,” Yuvarajaa told <em>HuffPost India</em>. “So Super Tatkal took shape.”</p><p>Super Tatkal, launched in 2016, allowed users to prefill their journey details and paste these onto the IRCTC website. This sped up the booking process by about five times the usual time it takes to book tickets on IRCTC website, said Yuvarajaa.&nbsp;</p><p>The app was buggy at first, he said, but a steady group of users kept sharing their experience.&nbsp;</p><p>“I went about correcting the bugs and realised that the app was gaining traction,” he said.&nbsp;</p><p>Super Tatkal was free for the first year. Later, as the maintenance cost of servers increased to Rs 10,000 per month, Yuvarajaa asked for user contributions — but this didn’t help much. He then decided to finance the app through in-app purchases where users were asked to buy a stack of 10 virtual coins for Rs 20. After the first three free bookings, the app charged five coins per transaction —&nbsp;ie, a nominal fee of Rs 10 per booking.</p><p>The Railway Police claims Yuvarajaa earned Rs 20 lakh through Super Tatkal between 2016 and 2020. This may sound like a big number, but it works out to about Rs 40,000 per month.</p><p>Yuvarajaa said all his users were aware of the payment model and that he had not cheated anyone into paying.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p></div><figure>
        <p><figcaption>A screengrab of the Super Tatkal Pro app before it was deactivated.</figcaption></p></figure><div><h3><strong>‘Didn’t take permission’</strong></h3><p>While Super Tatkal was taking off, Yuvarajaa soon became comfortable in the startup bubble. He quit his job in 2017 and started a truck aggregator app, Speedbird trucks, along with two of his friends.&nbsp;</p><p>“It was like an Ola or Uber for trucks. It took off well in the beginning,” Yuvarajaa said. But before the app could get traction, trouble started. It was difficult to convince people to use the trucks available on the app because existing contracts from known services seemed simpler for users.&nbsp;</p><p>“We took on lease two trucks to run the app but that ended in losses,” said Yuvarajaa. The company was built on the life savings of the three young men and it lacked a business model.&nbsp;</p><p>“To arrive at the business model one has to experiment with various models and this costs money,” said Yuvarajaa. The company also lacked a mentor, an industry insider, who could have offered steady advice and feedback.&nbsp;</p><p>“It is difficult to network and find help when you are a beginner,” he said.&nbsp;</p><p>It also didn’t have an investor. “We were at the experimental stage and could not win the confidence of an investor,” he said. In the experimental stage, startups built on little resources are mostly on their own and can only dream of reaching the patent filing stage which gets support from the Union government.&nbsp;</p><p>Meanwhile, Super Tatkal was doing relatively well. “The users kept growing and I launched a second app—Super Tatkal Pro—which allowed booking on IRCTC’s rail connect app in 2019,” he said.&nbsp;</p><p>To keep his startup alive and to support his family, Yuvarajaa also worked as a freelance programmer. The income was small but steady. However, unbeknownst to Yuvarajaa, his app was on the Railway police’s radar.&nbsp;</p><p>“RPF Cyber Cell at Southern Railway Headquarters Chennai had played a key role in analysis of data and identification of the fake app developer’s location and also collected digital evidences i.e server source code, application source code, end-users list and bank statements of the offender,” the Railway police said in their press release.</p><p>Yuvarajaa’s mistake, an officer at the security command centre of RPF told <em>HuffPost India</em>, was that “he did not obtain the needed permission from IRCTC and was working like a ticketing agent”.&nbsp;</p><p>Under the Railways Act, all those who help passengers with ticketing are expected to register with the IRCTC as an agent. Does this apply for app creators? The officer reserved his comment.&nbsp;</p><p>Yuvarajaa, however, said that he was “trying to create something of value for people” and that he “was not aware that the app would be considered illegal”. IRCTC could have sent him a warning or a cease-and-desist order before swooping in, he rued.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Arunachalam, of the Indian School of Business, said Yuvarajaa’s case points to the need for more mentorship in India’s start-up space.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>“He does not seem to have understood the process well,” Arunachalam said.</p><p>Back in Tirupur, Yuvarajaa said that he hopes to work with the Railways once his legal troubles end.</p><p>Will he revive his apps if he gets the required permission from IRCTC?&nbsp;</p><p>“I would like to,” he said.</p><p><em>This story was corrected to say that Yuvarajaa was arrested on October 23 and spent about a week in jail, not a month-and-a-half.</em></p></div>                
                                
                <!-- start relEntries --><!-- end relEntries --><section></section>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.huffingtonpost.in/entry/s-yuvarajaa-super-tatkal-pro-irctc-train-ticket-booking_in_5fb25d5cc5b6d8781808f6ab</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25121465</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 08:53:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Being Glue]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 180 | Comments 43 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25120504">thread link</a>) | @monsieurpng
<br/>
November 16, 2020 | https://noidea.dog/glue | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://noidea.dog/glue">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="canvas">

      
  
  



    

    

    

    <section id="page" role="main" data-content-field="main-content">
      <!-- CATEGORY NAV -->
      
      <div data-type="page" data-updated-on="1592981380911" id="page-5cc7644e852586000128e46b"><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1556734196837_9137"><div><p>Your job title says "software engineer", but you seem to spend most of your time in meetings. You'd like to have time to code, but nobody else is onboarding the junior engineers, updating the roadmap, talking to the users, noticing the things that got dropped, asking questions on design documents, and making sure that everyone's going roughly in the same direction. If you stop doing those things, the team won't be as successful. But now someone's suggesting that you might be happier in a less technical role. If this describes you, congratulations: you're the glue. If it's not, have you thought about who is filling this role on your team?</p><p>Every senior person in an organisation should be aware of the less glamorous - and often less-promotable - work that needs to happen to make a team successful. Managed deliberately, glue work demonstrates and builds strong technical leadership skills. Left unconscious, it can be career limiting. It can push people into less technical roles and even out of the industry.</p><p>Let's talk about how to allocate glue work deliberately, frame it usefully and make sure that everyone is choosing a career path they actually want to be on.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1556739775888_8389"><p>(💖💖💖Thank so much to the organisers of the amazing <a href="https://theleaddeveloper.com/" target="_blank">Lead Developer conference</a> where I presented this version of these slides. Thank you also to the organizers of the equally amazing<a href="https://www.writespeakcode.com/" target="_blank"> Write/Speak/Code conference </a>who accepted the first iteration of this talk. You are wonderful folks and I so appreciate the work you do. 💖💖💖)</p></div></div><div><div data-block-type="51" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1592980352948_19617"><div>


<div>
  <form data-form-id="5ef2f43280c2046beb659fc7" autocomplete="on" method="POST" onsubmit="return (function (form) {
    Y.use('squarespace-form-submit', 'node', function usingFormSubmit(Y) {
      (new Y.Squarespace.FormSubmit(form)).submit({
        formId: '5ef2f43280c2046beb659fc7',
        collectionId: '5cc7644e852586000128e46b',
        objectName: 'page-5cc7644e852586000128e46b'
      });
    });
    return false;
  })(this);">
    
    
    <p>No spam, I promise.</p>
    <p>Thank you!</p>
    
  </form>
</div>
</div></div><div data-aspect-ratio="90.83333333333333" data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1556734196837_13841"><div>








  

    

      <figure data-scrolled="" data-test="image-block-v2-outer-wrapper">

        <div>
          
            <a href="https://twitter.com/deniseyu21/status/1123313394113753088" data-animation-role="image" data-description="">
            
            <img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a05ececd55b4165f250f032/1556734772289-TZ8L8K9LCIPEQGXSM8LO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKwP5wc_189XiWLTNbaYn7EUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8GRo6ASst2s6pLvNAu_PZdJQr8gHdfuVEBZ6fGgEWibFK9OSZJCsAjo5_hH76asz9_aMLW6xIlFKyCazI6z63-Q/image-asset.jpeg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a05ececd55b4165f250f032/1556734772289-TZ8L8K9LCIPEQGXSM8LO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKwP5wc_189XiWLTNbaYn7EUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8GRo6ASst2s6pLvNAu_PZdJQr8gHdfuVEBZ6fGgEWibFK9OSZJCsAjo5_hH76asz9_aMLW6xIlFKyCazI6z63-Q/image-asset.jpeg" data-image-dimensions="601x1024" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a05ececd55b4165f250f032/1556734772289-TZ8L8K9LCIPEQGXSM8LO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKwP5wc_189XiWLTNbaYn7EUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8GRo6ASst2s6pLvNAu_PZdJQr8gHdfuVEBZ6fGgEWibFK9OSZJCsAjo5_hH76asz9_aMLW6xIlFKyCazI6z63-Q/image-asset.jpeg">
            
          
            </a>
          

        </div>

        
          
          <figcaption data-width-ratio="">
            <div>

              

              
                <div><p>https://twitter.com/deniseyu21/status/1123313394113753088</p></div>
              

              

            </div>
          </figcaption>
        

      </figure>

    

  


</div></div></div></div></div>
    </section>

    

    

    

  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://noidea.dog/glue</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25120504</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 05:18:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[To find great remote employees, prioritize candidates with strong writing skills]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 389 | Comments 181 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25120207">thread link</a>) | @Riphyak
<br/>
November 16, 2020 | https://youteam.io/blog/3-remote-productivity-hacks-we-wish-we-knew-from-day-one/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://youteam.io/blog/3-remote-productivity-hacks-we-wish-we-knew-from-day-one/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article><div><p>When Mattermost first started, it didn’t make sense for us to have an office; it was just myself and one other person. They were writing code the whole time, and I was on the phone the whole time, and being in the office we ended up interrupting each other. So eventually we started working from our homes and only got together when we needed to catch up.</p><p>As the company grew, we were hiring lots of artists and freelancers based everywhere from Los Angeles to Toronto. Even though there were more of us, it didn’t make sense for us to have an office space when most of the team was somewhere else anyway. We could simply hop on Skype, have our conversation, and get back to work. We became addicted to our ability to source really great talent from anywhere in the world, and addicted to the productivity of not having to worry about the overhead of an office, the time wasted commuting every day, or the frustration of having to find a space to meet up.</p><figure id="attachment_11249" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-11249"><a href="https://youteam.io/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/LIBanner2-scaled.jpg" data-size="{&quot;w&quot;:1920,&quot;h&quot;:1280}"><img loading="lazy" src="https://youteam.io/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/LIBanner2-scaled.jpg" alt="The Mattermost team" width="2560" height="640" srcset="https://youteam.io/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/LIBanner2-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://youteam.io/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/LIBanner2-300x75.jpg 300w, https://youteam.io/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/LIBanner2-1024x256.jpg 1024w, https://youteam.io/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/LIBanner2-768x192.jpg 768w, https://youteam.io/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/LIBanner2-1536x384.jpg 1536w, https://youteam.io/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/LIBanner2-2048x512.jpg 2048w, https://youteam.io/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/LIBanner2-716x179.jpg 716w, https://youteam.io/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/LIBanner2-820x205.jpg 820w" sizes="(max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-11249">The Mattermost team</figcaption></figure><p>That isn’t to say scaling a remote team has been easy. We’ve learned a lot about what makes for a great remote experience. Here are a few of the lessons learned about the challenges of remote work, and how we make it work for our team.</p><h2><strong>Pair design helps remote collaboration run smoothly</strong></h2><p>One of the superpowers of a remote team is <a href="https://about.gitlab.com/company/culture/all-remote/asynchronous/">embracing the ability to work asynchronously</a>. Unfortunately, this can also make large group collaboration more challenging. There are certain problems you might want a relatively large group to work together — for example, planning our annual onsite. In an office setting, you’d just get those four or five or seven people together camped out in a conference room for a whole week, knocking out the problem. But it can be particularly challenging to wrangle a large group of people to carve out a long chunk of time to work together remotely. Everyone has other priorities they’re trying to juggle.</p><p>We’ve found what works best for remote collaboration is keeping the collaboration smaller. We try to apply <a href="https://uxdesign.cc/benefits-of-design-pairing-2a3ceb0bdfac?gi=df46f7c04818">pair design</a> practices wherever we can; if you can break down and prioritize bigger problems into smaller problems two people can tackle, they can work through the problem, talk through it, and agree on it. Then, when they come back to a broader group, they come in with a much more polished solution and it’s easier to get an idea implemented.</p><h2><strong>Documentation is the secret to great onboarding and culture building</strong></h2><p>There’s a bit of a misconception that companies can only build stronger cultures in-person versus remote. I would say culture is stronger when everything is written down because everyone who joins the company has the same baseline: a consistent onboarding experience and documentation as the shared source of truth.</p><p>Remote onboarding done right can be far more scalable, efficient, and impactful. We get a good deal of positive feedback for our onboarding process at Mattermost because <a href="https://handbook.mattermost.com/operations/workplace/people/working-at-mattermost/onboarding">everything is documented</a>. In-office onboarding experiences are usually a series of person-to-person interactions that mete out information bit by bit — you might talk to 18 different people throughout the day, each with a different piece of the organizational puzzle. When you’re a remote company, onboarding is a lot more focused on reading through information.</p><p>Don’t get me wrong — new hires at Mattermost still talk to a lot of people in their first few weeks —&nbsp;but the interactions they have are more meaningful because they’ve gotten all the administrative stuff out of the way. New hires can get up to speed on the history and context of ongoing projects and initiatives when they join and can start asking much higher quality, deep questions during those first interactions.</p><h2><strong>To find great remote employees, prioritize candidates with strong writing skills</strong></h2><p>One thing that’s become even more clear during the pandemic: there are people who really like working remote and thrive in a remote work environment, but it’s not for everyone. Right now everyone needs to work remotely. While many people have realized working from home is amazing — they love not having to commute, they love the independence, the flexibility — there are others who really miss the office environment.</p><p>One of the biggest indicators that we’ve found around who thrives in a remote environment is strong written communication skills. If you’re a strong writer and you can consume information in written formats really well, you’ll probably have an easier time transitioning to a remote team than someone who prefers face-to-face communication.</p><h2><strong>Want to join Mattermost’s remote-first team?</strong></h2><p>Mattermost is on a mission to connect the world with what matters most, and we’re continually looking for people to help us achieve that goal —&nbsp;no matter where in the world they live.&nbsp;To learn more about what it’s like to work at Mattermost and to see our current open roles, check out our <a href="https://mattermost.com/careers/">Careers page</a>.</p></div></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://youteam.io/blog/3-remote-productivity-hacks-we-wish-we-knew-from-day-one/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25120207</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 04:16:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Headlamp: a new UI for Kubernetes]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 125 | Comments 43 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25118870">thread link</a>) | @aberoham
<br/>
November 16, 2020 | https://kinvolk.io/blog/2020/11/shining-a-light-on-the-kubernetes-user-experience-with-headlamp/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://kinvolk.io/blog/2020/11/shining-a-light-on-the-kubernetes-user-experience-with-headlamp/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <p>If you’ve ever seen a Kubernetes demo, it probably involved a terminal and someone typing commands using kubectl and arcane yaml configuration files. This might be a powerful workflow for experts, but in an age when everything has a slick web interface, it is not the most accessible user experience. It <strong>steepens the learning curve</strong> for those new to Kubernetes, and <strong>presents a barrier</strong> to occasional users.</p>
<p>Of course, there are several graphical user interfaces available for Kubernetes, including the <em>Kubernetes Dashboard</em> project that is part of upstream Kubernetes itself. However, when we researched the landscape, we couldn’t find a solution that covered everything we were looking for. Specifically, our criteria were:</p>
<ul>
<li>100% open source</li>
<li>Actively maintained</li>
<li>Generic, in the sense of not being tied to a specific vendor’s Kubernetes distro</li>
<li>Modular and extensible</li>
<li>Clean, modern user interface</li>
<li>Implemented using a stack that was familiar to our development team (Go, Javascript/Typescript, React)</li>
<li>An interactive UI that allows read-write operations, not just a read-only dashboard</li>
<li>Multi-cluster.</li>
</ul>
<p>Despite the good number of alternatives, the reality is that none of the solutions we tested at the time really matched all the points in our criteria or was a good base to start from. So, in the time-honored tradition, we decided to build one ourselves…</p>

<p>Today, I am <strong>proud to announce the general availability of a new UI for Kubernetes</strong>: <a href="https://github.com/kinvolk/headlamp">Headlamp</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://kinvolk.io/media/headlamp_cluster_overview.png" alt="Headlamp"></p>
<p>Headlamp is a generic and extensible Kubernetes UI that meets the criteria mentioned above. Of course, coming from Kinvolk, it is 100% open source. We hope many Kubernetes community members will not just enjoy using Headlamp, but also contribute back to the project.</p>
<p>Let’s take a quick spin through some of its core features.</p>
<h2 id="extensible-ui">Extensible UI</h2>
<p>We want Headlamp to be used for as many different use-cases as possible. That includes not only novice Kubernetes users, but also experienced operators, as well as Kubernetes vendors with very different needs. Often, particularly for UI projects, such a breadth of use cases can only be addressed by downstream users maintaining their own fork. But keeping forks up to date becomes more challenging the deeper the changes are.</p>
<p>A solution to this problem is to have a plugin system. So Headlamp supports out-of-tree UI plugins: Javascript files that are loaded by Headlamp’s backend and passed to the client which dynamically loads them.</p>
<p>This opens up Headlamp to innovation, <strong>fostering a wealth of new functionality</strong>. For example, if you want to add a button to the Pod details view that will redirect the user to a service showing how much the Pod is costing to operate, that should be easy to implement.</p>
<p>We see Headlamp’s plug-in capabilities as a great opportunity for the community. We are eager to collaborate with others who want to develop new Headlamp plugins, or enhance the plugin system itself to support other use-cases.</p>
<h3 id="traceloop">Traceloop</h3>
<p>As an <strong>example of the power of the plug-in system</strong>, and an incredibly useful tool in its own right, we have developed a <a href="https://github.com/kinvolk/lokomotive-web-ui/tree/master/plugins/ig-traces">Headlamp plugin for the traceloop gadget</a> of our <a href="https://github.com/kinvolk/inspektor-gadget">Inspektor Gadget</a> project.</p>
<p>When Inspektor Gadget is installed in a cluster and the traceloop gadget is enabled, it <strong>records all syscalls from a pod</strong> into a ring buffer. This buffer can be seen in real-time as the pod is running, allowing a lens into what the pod is doing right now, but is also saved for terminated pods. This allows operators to see what caused a crash, after it happens – like a “flight data recorder” for your Kubernetes apps.</p>
<p><img src="https://kinvolk.io/media/traces.gif" alt="Traces plugin for Headlamp"></p>
<h2 id="role-aware-ui">Role-aware UI</h2>
<p>One problem with many read-write (CRUD) user interfaces is that they are not aware of underlying access controls. For example, displaying the update/delete buttons is misleading if the user has actually no permissions to modify the resource. So Headlamp checks Kubernetes RBAC settings and displays only those controls whose actions can be performed. So, if the user does not have permission to edit a resource, the edit button will not be displayed.</p>
<p>This results in a much better UX, because it is obvious to the operator what actions are available based on their permissions at the time. In particular, this is great for situations where time-limited credentials are granted to operators (e.g. temporary deletion permissions on a resource).</p>
<p><img src="https://kinvolk.io/media/headlamp_permissions.png" alt="Pod when the user has update/delete permissions" title="Pod when the user has update/delete permissions">
<sub>Pod when the user has update/delete permissions</sub></p>
<p><img src="https://kinvolk.io/media/headlamp_no_permissions.png" alt="Pod when the user has no update/delete permissions" title="Pod when the user has no update/delete permissions">
<sub>Pod when the user has no update/delete permissions</sub></p>
<h2 id="design--user-interface">Design / User Interface</h2>
<p>We wanted Headlamp’s design to be as <strong>clean and modern</strong> as possible, yet without breaking with a more “traditional” Kubernetes UI or dashboard style. For example, we think that showing a familiar table-based view is very helpful, and we hope other visualizations, such as a graph-based representation of the cluster, can be implemented through plugins.</p>
<p>To implement Headlamp’s frontend, we chose to use React with the <a href="https://material-ui.com/">Material UI</a> library, because it is modern, clean, and is well maintained with a large user community. It also has the advantage that it is the same technology stack that we use in our <a href="https://github.com/kinvolk/nebraska">Nebraska</a> project, enabling sharing of expertise and resources, and supporting a consistent UI across all our products.</p>
<h2 id="desktop-vs-in-cluster">Desktop vs In-cluster</h2>
<p>Most Kubernetes UIs can be categorized as either a hosted (often in-cluster) backend, such as the original Kubernetes Dashboard, or a local desktop application, such as VMware’s <a href="https://github.com/vmware-tanzu/octant">Octant</a> project.</p>
<p>Both approaches have their advantages and disadvantages. For example, when run as a hosted application, it’s very simple to just share a URL with users, and have them log in through OIDC. It’s available “everywhere”, and it’s easy to keep it up-to-date with the cluster version. Conversely, with a desktop application, there’s no need to host the UI application, keeping things more isolated, but the burden of keeping the app up to date falls on the user.</p>
<p>With Headlamp, you <strong>don’t have to choose</strong> between these two approaches, as we support both. It can be easily <strong>hosted in-cluster</strong> by using/adapting the YAML files we provide, or <strong>installed locally</strong> on Linux, Mac, and Windows.</p>
<h2 id="multi-cluster-support">Multi-cluster support</h2>
<p>Most Kubernetes deployments involve multiple clusters, even if that’s just to separate a development from a production environment. Thus, Headlamp <strong>allows you to access all your clusters</strong> - with the exact method depending on whether you’re running as a hosted, or a local (desktop), application.</p>
<p>When run locally, Headlamp will read the kube config and display the contexts available there, allowing the user to change when needed just by setting the local environment variable to the appropriate cluster.</p>
<p>The way the multi-cluster support works is straightforward: it creates a proxy for each configured cluster, and redirects requests from the UI (with the Kubernetes API calls) to the right cluster address. Shout-out here to the <a href="https://github.com/indeedeng/k8dash">K8dash</a> project, whose request/API management modules we reused in the development of Headlamp.</p>
<p>It’s also possible to mix this with running in-cluster, though this does require the cluster running the application to have API access to the other configured clusters.</p>
<p><img src="https://kinvolk.io/media/headlamp_cluster_chooser.png" alt="Cluster Chooser" title="Cluster chooser dialog"></p>

<p>You may be aware that Kinvolk also has a Kubernetes distribution, <a href="https://kinvolk.io/lokomotive">Lokomotive</a>. While Headlamp is of course used within Lokomotive as the basis for its web user interface, it is important to note that these are separate and independent projects. True to our goal of being independent of any particular distro, <strong>Headlamp is designed to support any conformant Kubernetes cluster</strong>.</p>

<p>It’s <strong>easy to try out Headlamp</strong>: just apply the deployment manifest to your cluster and point your browser to the Headlamp service, or download and install the desktop application for Windows, Mac, or Linux. For details, see the <a href="https://kinvolk.io/docs/headlamp/latest/installation">documentation</a>.</p>
<p>Headlamp is fully open source, released under the Apache 2.0 terms and, as mentioned above, we created it to be a generic and vendor-independent Kubernetes UI that we hope can suit many use-cases. So we encourage anyone interested to take part.</p>
<p>If you want to participate, please check out our <a href="https://kinvolk.io/docs/headlamp/latest/contributing">contribution guidelines</a>.</p>
<p><strong>We hope you enjoy Headlamp!</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://kinvolk.io/images/headlamp-logo.svg">
</p>

          </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://kinvolk.io/blog/2020/11/shining-a-light-on-the-kubernetes-user-experience-with-headlamp/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25118870</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:16:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[High Performance Individuals and Teams]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 90 | Comments 69 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25118762">thread link</a>) | @pablasso
<br/>
November 16, 2020 | https://pablasso.com/high-performance-individuals-and-teams/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://pablasso.com/high-performance-individuals-and-teams/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Growing up, the only thing that put me off while learning software development, was the common occurrence of people who cared more about one upping others with their trivia knowledge rather than actually building things.</p>
<p>At the start of my career I had a difficult time differentiating between them and actual top performers because the industry still thought there was a strong correlation between jerks and highly productive people. Employers used to be afraid something will go wrong if they fired a mythical 10x engineer and no one else understood how to fix their systems.</p>
<p>After 15 years what I've learned is that engineers that produce orders of magnitude more than others exist<sup id="fnref-1"><a href="#fn-1">1</a></sup>, but the way they are talked about is overly exaggerated. They’re usually not jerks either, at least not more than the rest of the population.</p>
<p>If you find a project where only one person know what is going on, chances are that person is not good at writing code for humans, not that is a coding god.</p>
<p>One thing we don’t often consider is that you don’t have to hire the very top of the field to find people that are orders better than the industry average. Even more important than finding great engineers is to avoid bad ones<sup id="fnref-2"><a href="#fn-2">2</a></sup>.</p>
<p>Being obsessed with finding a 10x engineer, is to be obsessed with shortcuts and Hail Marys. It will hurt you in the long run if you’re focusing on that instead of building solid fundamentals.</p>
<p>Ultimately I am convinced that focusing on building teams is more important than finding individual outliers. Of course the John Carmacks, the Jeff Deans, the Fabrice Bellards, of the industry exist, but your startup isn’t going to die if you don’t find one. It will die if you don’t build a good team.</p>
<h2>Good reads on individual and team performance</h2>
<ul>
<li>Steve McConnell, has a great summary of existing studies that support the 10x theory in <a href="https://www.construx.com/blog/productivity-variations-among-software-developers-and-teams-the-origin-of-10x/">“Individual Productivity Variation in Software Development”</a>. </li>
<li>McConnell also recognizes the aforementioned studies are not perfect in <a href="https://www.construx.com/blog/the-origins-of-10x-how-valid-is-the-underlying-research/">“Origins of 10X – How Valid is the Underlying Research?”</a>. But the lack of studies contradicting the current findings and the abundance of anecdotal stories signals towards confirmation.</li>
<li>In <a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/10429247.2002.11415178">“Leadership, Team Building, and Team Member Characteristics in High Performance Project Teams”</a> the authors identify 9 themes<sup id="fnref-3"><a href="#fn-3">3</a></sup> as potential predictors of team performance.</li>
<li>In <a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/10429247.2002.11415147">“Linking Project Team Performance with Team Health”</a> the authors emphasize that team building is a long term strategy that does not happen overnight by itself. Organizations must invest if they want to build healthy, high performing teams.</li>
<li>In <a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/10429247.1999.11415013">“An Empirical Study of the Relationship Between Team Performance and Team Maturity”</a> the authors measure the impact of changes in team dynamics, and make a correlation of team maturity with high performance teams. They mention how persistance is required to move to higher performance.</li>
<li>In <a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/10429247.1990.11414554">“Innovative Performance in Research, Development, and Engineering”</a> the authors identify 12 factors<sup id="fnref-4"><a href="#fn-4">4</a></sup> that strongly influence innovative work environments:</li>
</ul>

      </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://pablasso.com/high-performance-individuals-and-teams/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25118762</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:04:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
