<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 20]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 20. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 08:22:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-20.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 08:22:34 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[This is how I git]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 80 | Comments 28 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25043731">thread link</a>) | @ingve
<br/>
November 10, 2020 | https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/11/09/this-is-how-i-git/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/11/09/this-is-how-i-git/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Every now and then I get questions on how to work with git in a smooth way when developing, bug-fixing or extending curl – or how I do it. After all, I <a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/10/26/working-open-source/" data-type="post" data-id="14901">work on open source full time</a> which means I have very frequent interactions with git (and GitHub). Simply put, I work with git all day long. Ordinary days, I issue git commands several hundred times.</p>



<p>I have a very simple approach and way of working with git in curl. This is how it works.</p>



<h2>command line</h2>



<p>I use git almost exclusively from the command line in a terminal. To help me see which branch I’m working in, I have this little bash helper script.</p>



<pre>brname () {
  a=$(<code>git rev-parse --abbrev-ref HEAD 2&gt;/dev/null</code>)
  if [ -n "$a" ]; then
    echo " [$a]"
  else
    echo ""
  fi
}
PS1="\u@\h:\w\$(brname)$ "</pre>



<p>That gives me a prompt that shows username, host name, the current working directory and the current checked out git branch.</p>



<p>In addition: I use Debian’s <a href="https://salsa.debian.org/debian/bash-completion/-/blob/master/README.md">bash command line completion</a> for git which is also really handy. It allows me to use tab to complete things like git commands and branch names. </p>



<h2>git config</h2>



<p>I of course also have my customized <code>~/.gitconfig</code> file to provide me with some convenient aliases and settings. My most commonly used git aliases are:</p>


<pre title="">st = status --short -uno
ci = commit
ca = commit --amend
caa = commit -a --amend
br = branch
co = checkout
df = diff
lg = log -p --pretty=fuller --abbrev-commit
lgg = log --pretty=fuller --abbrev-commit --stat
up = pull --rebase
latest = log @^{/RELEASE-NOTES:.synced}..
</pre>


<p>The ‘latest’ one is for listing all changes done to curl since the most recent RELEASE-NOTES “sync”. The others should hopefully be rather self-explanatory.</p>



<p>The config also sets <code>gpgsign = true</code>, enables mailmap and a few other things.</p>



<h2>master is clean and working</h2>



<p>The main curl development is done in the single <a href="https://github.com/curl/curl">curl/curl</a> git repository (primarily hosted on GitHub). We keep the master branch the bleeding edge development tree and we work hard to always keep that working and functional. We do our releases off the master branch when that day comes (every eight weeks) and we provide “<a href="https://curl.haxx.se/snapshots/">daily snapshots</a>” from that branch, put together – yeah – daily.</p>



<p>When merging fixes and features into master, we avoid merge commits and use rebases and fast-forward as much as possible. This makes the branch very easy to browse, understand and work with – as it is 100% linear.</p>



<h2>Work on a fix or feature</h2>



<p>When I start something new, like work on a bug or trying out someone’s patch or similar, I first create a local branch off master and work in that. That is, I don’t work directly in the master branch. Branches are easy and quick to do and there’s no reason to shy away from having loads of them!</p>



<p>I typically name the branch prefixed with my GitHub user name, so that when I push them to the server it is noticeable who is the creator (and I can use the same branch name locally as I do remotely).</p>



<pre>$ git checkout -b bagder/my-new-stuff-or-bugfix</pre>



<p>Once I’ve reached somewhere, I commit to the branch. It can then end up one or more commits before I consider myself “done for now” with what I was set out to do.</p>



<p>I try not to leave the tree with any uncommitted changes – like if I take off for the day or even just leave for food or an extended break. This puts the repository in a state that allows me to easily switch over to another branch  when I get back – should I feel the need to. Plus, it’s better to commit and explain the change <em>before</em> the break rather than having to recall the details again when coming back.</p>



<h2>Never stash</h2>



<p>“git stash” is therefore not a command I ever use. I rather create a new branch and commit the (temporary?) work in there as a potential new line of work.</p>



<h2>Show it off and get reviews</h2>



<p>Yes I am the lead developer of the project but I still maintain the same work flow as everyone else. All changes, except the most minuscule ones, are done as pull requests on GitHub.</p>



<p>When I’m happy with the functionality in my local branch. When the bug seems to be fixed or the feature seems to be doing what it’s supposed to do and the test suite runs fine locally.</p>



<p>I then clean up the commit series with “<code>git rebase -i</code>” (or if it is a single commit I can instead use just “<code>git commit --amend</code>“).</p>



<p>The commit series should be a set of logical changes that are related to this change and not any more than necessary, but kept separate if they are separate. Each commit also gets its own proper commit message. Unrelated changes should be split out into its own separate branch and subsequent separate pull request.</p>



<pre>git push origin bagder/my-new-stuff-or-bugfix</pre>



<h2>Make the push a pull request</h2>



<p>On GitHub, I then make the newly pushed branch into a <a href="https://github.com/curl/curl/pulls">pull request</a> (aka “a PR”). It will then become visible in the list of pull requests on the site for the curl source repository, it will be announced in the #curl IRC channel and everyone who follows the repository on GitHub will be notified accordingly.</p>



<p>Perhaps most importantly, a pull request kicks of a flood of CI jobs that will build and test the code in numerous different combinations and on several platforms, and the results of those tests will trickle in over the coming hours. When I write this, we have around 90 different CI jobs – per pull request – and something like 8 different code analyzers will scrutinize the change to see if there’s any obvious flaws in there.</p>



<figure><a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot_2020-11-05-curl-Project-status-dashboard.png"><img loading="lazy" width="2686" height="1510" src="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot_2020-11-05-curl-Project-status-dashboard.png" alt=""></a><figcaption>CI jobs per platform over time. Graph snapped on November 5, 2020</figcaption></figure>



<h2>A branch in the actual curl/curl repo</h2>



<p>Most contributors who would work on curl would not do like me and make the branch in the curl repository itself, but would rather do them in their own forked version instead. The difference isn’t that big and I <em>could</em> of course also do it that way.</p>



<h2>After push, switch branch</h2>



<p>As it will take some time to get the full CI results from the PR to come in (generally a few hours), I switch over to the next branch with work on my agenda. On a normal work-day I can easily move over ten different branches, polish them and submit updates in their respective pull-requests.</p>



<p>I can go back to the&nbsp;master branch again with ‘<code>git checkout master</code>‘ and there I can “<code>git pull</code>” to get everything from upstream – like when my fellow developers have pushed stuff in the mean time.</p>



<h2>PR comments or CI alerts</h2>



<p>If a reviewer or a CI job find a mistake in one of my PRs, that becomes visible on GitHub and I get to work to handle it. To either fix the bug or discuss with the reviewer what the better approach might be.</p>



<p>Unfortunately, flaky CI jobs is a part of life so very often there ends up one or two red markers in the list of CI jobs that can be ignored as the test failures in them are there due to problems in the setup and not because of actual mistakes in the PR…</p>



<p>To get back to my branch for that PR again, I “<code>git checkout bagder/my-new-stuff-or-bugfix</code>“, and fix the issues.</p>



<p>I normally start out by doing follow-up commits that repair the immediate mistake and push them on the branch:</p>



<pre>git push origin <code>bagder/my-new-stuff-or-bugfix</code></pre>



<p>If the number of fixup commits gets large, or if the follow-up fixes aren’t small, I usually end up doing a squash to reduce the number of commits into a smaller, simpler set, and then force-push them to the branch.</p>



<p>The reason for that is to make the patch series easy to review, read and understand. When a commit series has too many commits that changes the previous commits, it becomes hard to review.</p>



<h2>Ripe to merge?</h2>



<p>When the pull request is ripe for merging (independently of who authored it), I switch over to the master branch again and I merge the pull request’s commits into it. In special cases I cherry-pick specific commits from the branch instead. When all the stuff has been yanked into master properly that should be there, I push the changes to the remote.</p>



<p>Usually, and especially if the pull request wasn’t done by me, I also go over the commit messages and polish them somewhat before I push everything. Commit messages should follow our style and mention not only which PR that it closes but also which issue it fixes and properly give credit to the bug reporter and all the helpers – using the right syntax so that our automatic tools can pick them up correctly!</p>



<p>As already mentioned above, I merge fast-forward or rebased into master. No merge commits.</p>



<h2>Never merge with GitHub!</h2>



<p>There’s a button GitHub that says “rebase and merge” that could theoretically be used for merging pull requests. I <em>never</em> use that (and if I could, I’d disable/hide it). The reasons are simply:</p>



<ol><li>I don’t feel that I have the proper control of the commit message(s)</li><li>I can’t select to squash a subset of the commits, only all or nothing</li><li>I often want to cleanup the author parts too before push, which the UI doesn’t allow</li></ol>



<p>The downside with not using the merge button is that the message in the  PR says “closed by [hash]” instead of “merged in…” which causes confusion to a fair amount of users who don’t realize it means that it actually means the same thing! I consider this is a (long-standing) GitHub UX flaw.</p>



<h2>Post merge</h2>



<p>If the branch has nothing to be kept around more, I delete the local branch again with “<code>git branch -d [name]</code>” and I remove it remotely too since it was completely merged there’s no reason to keep the work version left.</p>



<p>At any given point in time, I have some 20-30 different local branches alive using this approach so things I work on over time all live in their own branches and also submissions from various people that haven’t been merged into master yet exist in branches of various maturity levels. Out of those local branches, the number of concurrent pull requests I have in progress can be somewhere between just a few up to ten, twelve something.</p>



<h2>RELEASE-NOTES</h2>



<p>Not strictly related, but in order to keep interested people informed about what’s happening in the tree, we sync the <a href="https://github.com/curl/curl/blob/master/RELEASE-NOTES">RELEASE-NOTES</a> file every once in a while. Maybe every 5-7 days or so. It …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/11/09/this-is-how-i-git/">https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/11/09/this-is-how-i-git/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/11/09/this-is-how-i-git/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25043731</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 08:08:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[AppleCrate II: A New Apple II-Based Parallel Computer (2015)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 79 | Comments 9 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25042551">thread link</a>) | @aresant
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | http://michaeljmahon.com/AppleCrateII.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://michaeljmahon.com/AppleCrateII.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">

<b><span face="Arial, helvetica" size="4"><p>AppleCrate II:  A New Apple II-Based Parallel Computer</p>
</span><span face="Arial, helvetica" size="2"><p>
Michael J. Mahon – July 26, 2008<br>
Revised – September 23, 2015</p>

<p><img src="http://michaeljmahon.com/CrateII.jpg" width="500" height="612"></p>

</span><span face="Arial, helvetica"><p>Introduction</p>
</span></b><span face="Arial, helvetica" size="2"><p>
In 2004 I built the first <a href="http://michaeljmahon.com/Applecrate.html">AppleCrate</a>, an 8-board system, as an inexpensive, easy to program
vehicle for experiments in parallel programming—a kind of "blade server" for the Apple II, if
you will!  AppleCrate I (at the time I didn't realize that it was number "I" ;-) was great fun, and it
enabled some very interesting experiments, but over time I discovered some of its shortcomings.</p>

<p>First and foremost, since the boards were supported by only two edges and not clamped in place, it
was relatively fragile and hard to transport.  Second, I had come across situations in which more
than 8 slave processors would have been useful.  Third, my arrangement for collecting audio signals
synthesized by the slaves was quite makeshift and delivered sound with lots of digital "hash"
as background noise.  And finally, the original AppleCrate made no provision for plugging I/O cards
into any of its boards, so it had to be hosted by a separate Apple II, adding to the problem of
transporting it for demonstrations.</p>

<p>The AppleCrate II is designed to be significantly improved in all of the areas that were
problems for the AppleCrate I.</p>

<b></b></span><b><span face="Arial, helvetica"><p>Description</p>
</span></b><span face="Arial, helvetica" size="2">

<p>The AppleCrate II is made from 17 Enhanced Apple //e main boards.  (Fifteen of these boards were
obtained in the same eBay auction that netted the eight unenhanced boards for the original AppleCrate.)
Because they are enhanced ROMs, the original NadaNet boot ROM code would not fit and a new
boot protocol had to be developed, as described below.</p>

<p>Instead of mounting the cards vertically in a frame, as in the original, I decided to mount them
horizontally in a stack secured with standoffs—3/4" long hexagonal rods, each with a screw protruding from
one end and a tapped hole in the other.  The AppleCrate II has nine "columns" of these standoffs—six
metal columns at the back and corners of the boards and three nylon columns interior to the boards
to add stiffness, as shown in the photo below at the 2-board construction stage:</p>

<p><img src="http://michaeljmahon.com/TwoBoards.jpg" width="800" height="554"></p>

<p>This "hi-rise" construction makes the "stack" quite rigid and sturdy, while eliminating the need
for a space-consuming exoskeleton.  It also has the advantage of leaving the top board unobstructed
so that I/O cards can be plugged in, allowing it to serve as the host machine for the AppleCrate.  (In fact,
I used 17 boards so that the top board can serve as master and leave 16 slave machines for parallel
programs.)</p>

<p>The Pushbutton 1 input and Annunciator 1 output bus wires and the AN2-to-PB2 GETID daisy chain wires are connected to
machined-pin sockets inserted into the 16-pin game port connector.  These connections support <a href="http://michaeljmahon.com/NadaNet.html">NadaNet</a>,
which is the only signal connection between the boards.  The network adapter (described below) is shown
with its mounting bracket under what will be the third board.  The power bus card is supported by a
similar angle bracket, and the standoffs immediately beneath them are filed down to accomodate the
bracket thickness.</p>

<p>The boards are powered by a PC AT power supply.  The average power consumed by an Apple //e
board is about 4.2 watts, so the whole 17-board crate consumes only about 70 watts in total,
and both the AppleCrate and the power supply run only a few degrees above ambient temperature.</p>

<p>I decided to use #12 copper bus wires
to distribute power to all boards (visible on the right side of the first photo).  I would have preferred
a connectorized approach, but I could not come up with a connector scheme with a
reasonable mating/unmating force.  As a result, I decided to go with soldered power connections.
(It's a good thing that Apple //e's are so reliable, since replacing one in the middle of the
stack would be relatively difficult!)</p>

<p>The top board is used as the "master" machine with I/O cards and an external keyboard plugged into it.
The Master boots the 16 slave Apples in the AppleCrate II and uses them to run parallel programs.
Once they have been booted and started, they can run independently of the master—though they are clearly
I/O-constrained!</p>

<b></b></span><b><span face="Arial, helvetica"><p>Indicators</p>
</span></b><span face="Arial, helvetica" size="2">

<p>It has proven useful to have some real-time indication of each board's activity.  The stock board contains a
red "power" LED (at the right) and a red "speaker" LED at the left.  Both are easily visible from the back of the
boards (the "front" of the AppleCrate).  The function of the power LED is fixed, but the speaker LED is usable
as an indicator that software running on the board can operate, just by toggling the speaker.  For example,
printing a "beep"—CHR$(07)—causes the speaker LED to flash for 0.1 second, and can be used to indicate some
condition in the software.  (The speaker LED will not light when a speaker is installed, but AppleCrate
boards have no speakers attached.)</p>

<p>Although the Applecrate network interface described below incorporates an LED to show global network activity,
it is very useful to be able to see when any particular board is sending on the network.  This need is met by
using the PDL 3 timer to "stretch" each packet send operation into a visible flash of a green rectangular LED.</p>

<p><img src="http://michaeljmahon.com/SendLED.jpg" width="762" height="263"></p>

<p>These photos show the modification made to the 558 timer chip, in which a 267-ohm resistor (just what I
had handy—any value between 220 and 560 ohms is fine) is connected
between pins 5 and 8, and the "send" signalling LED is connected between pin 8 and ground, with pin 8 going to the
anode.  The rectangular LED is carefully pressed between the cassette input and output jacks.  On some boards,
the jacks were so close together that it was necessary to "shave" the upper plastic swage on the side of the input
jack with an Exacto knife to make room for the LED to press fit between them.  (Note that in these photos the red
wire connected to the anode of the LED has not yet been soldered.)</p>

</span><b><span face="Arial, helvetica"><p>Network Boot in NadaNet 3.x</p>
</span></b><span face="Arial, helvetica" size="2">

<p>Since AppleCrate machines have no I/O capabilities other than
the network, they must be booted from the network.  This requires that the ROMs on the boards be replaced with
EPROMs containing modified RESET code to perform the network boot.</p>

<p>As with the AppleCrate I, replacement of the self-test code was the easiest path, since it is self-contained,
contiguous, and is executed upon power-on reset if no keyboard is connected.  However, the Enhanced //e ROM contains
only $200 bytes of self-test code, just half the size of the unenhanced //e self-test, requiring a new
design for the network boot.</p>

<p>The AppleCrate I used an "active" boot protocol, in which each board enabled by the "GETID daisy chain" (connected from
AN2 of the previous machine to PB2 of the current machine) continuously sent GETID requests to ID 1, until it was assigned
a permanent ID and received a NadaNet boot image.  The complexity of this protocol, requiring both sending and receiving
packets over the network, resulted in a boot ROM requirement of almost $400 bytes—which fit in an <b>Unenhanced</b> //e ROM.</p>

<p>Since the <b>Enhanced</b> //e ROM has only $200 bytes available, a new "passive" boot protocol had to be devised.
The <a href="http://michaeljmahon.com/PASSIVEBOOT.ROM.pdf">new ROM code</a> continuously monitors the network for a broadcast BOOTREQ control packet
containing  the load address and length of the immediately following boot code data.  When the boot image has been correctly
read from the network, control is passed to its starting address.  This passive boot code only needs to <b>read</b> packets from the
net, and so occupies just $190 bytes, which comfortably fits in place of the Enhanced //e ROM self-test code at $C600.</p>

<p>The new boot protocol capitalizes on the fact that boot code is sent as a broadcast transaction, so the
machines being booted do not need IDs to receive boot code.  A page of "second-stage boot" code is added at the
front of the slave machine boot image.  This code is given control immediately after the boot image is received, and,
when enabled by the "GETID daisy chain", it sends a GETID request to the machine that &amp;BOOTed it, making use of the
code in the full NadaNet boot image to do so (see the BOOT2 code in the <a href="http://michaeljmahon.com/NADA.CRATE.pdf">NADA.CRATE</a>
listing for details).</p>

<p>The GETID daisy chain functions just as it did in the AppleCrate I.  The "first" machine is permanently enabled
by connecting its PB2 to ground.  AN2 of each machine is connected
to PB2 of the "next" machine.  The second-stage boot code running in each machine initially sets its AN2.
Then it waits until it sees its PB2 go low, enabling it to send its GETID request.  When its GETID is successful
it drops its AN2, enabling the next machine.  Then it clears its video display, writes a banner showing the
machine ID, and enters its server loop.</p>

<p>This results in permanent
IDs being assigned in the fixed order of the physical daisy chain, while allowing all ROMs to be identical.
An LED on the AppleCrate II NadaNet adapter board is wired to the last machine's AN2, so that when the last
machine drops its AN2, the red LED extinguishes, signalling that all machines have booted successfully.</p>

<p>When a network-booting machine is reset, it first checks the network state.  If the network is low (ZERO),
it performs a cold start.  If the network is being held high (ONE), it checks page 3 to see if it is being cold started or warm reset.  If it is
a warm reset, it re-enters its Server loop.  If it is a cold start, it initializes and enters the ROM boot code, again waiting
for a BOOTREQ packet.  (This approach has the advantage of reliably forcing a reboot on a power cycle, while
still permitting boards to be warm reset while holding the network high.)</p>

<p>As of NadaNet 3.1, all AppleCrate boot ROMs must be <a href="http://michaeljmahon.com/PASSIVEBOOT.ROM.pdf">NadaNet 3.x capable</a>.</p>

</span><b><span face="Arial, helvetica"><p>AppleCrate II NadaNet Interface</p>
</span></b><span face="Arial, helvetica" size="2">
<p><a href="http://michaeljmahon.com/NadaNet.html">NadaNet</a> is a TTL-level serial network in which logic high is represented by a voltage greater than +2 volts
and logic low is represented by a voltage less than +0.7 volts.  The fanout capability of a TTL annunciator output
is sufficient to  drive a dozen or so TTL pushbutton inputs if they are not otherwise …</p></span></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://michaeljmahon.com/AppleCrateII.html">http://michaeljmahon.com/AppleCrateII.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://michaeljmahon.com/AppleCrateII.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25042551</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 03:23:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Best Practices for Writing Clean Interfaces in Go]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 42 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25042085">thread link</a>) | @lanecwagner
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | https://qvault.io/2020/03/15/best-practices-for-writing-clean-interfaces-in-go/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://qvault.io/2020/03/15/best-practices-for-writing-clean-interfaces-in-go/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
<p>Interfaces in Go allow us to treat different types as the same data type temporarily. They are central to a Go programmers toolbelt and are often used improperly by new Go developers… leading to hard to read and buggy code. Let’s take a look at some of the best practices for Golang interfaces.</p>



<h2>Recap on Interfaces</h2>



<p>I often look to the standard library as an example of the way to write clean Go. The standard error interface is simple:</p>



<pre><code lang="go">type error interface {
    Error() string
}</code></pre>



<p>The error interface encapsulates any type that has an <code>Error()</code> method defined on it. That method accepts no parameters, and returns a <em>string</em>. For example, let’s define a struct that represents a network problem:</p>



<pre><code lang="go">type networkProblem struct {
	message string
	code    int
}</code></pre>



<p>Then we define an <code>Error()</code> method:</p>



<pre><code lang="go">func (np networkProblem) Error() string {
	return fmt.Sprintf("network error! message: %s, code: %v", np.message, np.code)
}</code></pre>



<p>Now, we can use an instance of the <code>networkProblem</code> struct wherever an error is accepted.</p>



<pre><code lang="go">func handleErr(err error) {
	fmt.Println(err.Error())
}

np := networkProblem{
	message: "we received a problem",
	code:    404,
}

handleErr(np)

// prints "network error! message: we received a problem, code: 404"</code></pre>



<h2>Keep Interfaces Small</h2>



<p>If there is only one piece of advice that you take away from this article, make it this: <strong>keep interfaces small!</strong> Interfaces are meant to define the <em>minimal</em> behavior necessary to accurately represent an idea or concept. </p>



<p>Here is an example from the standard <a aria-label="HTTP package (opens in a new tab)" href="https://golang.org/pkg/net/http/#pkg-overview" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">HTTP package</a> of a larger interface that’s a good example of defining minimal behavior:</p>



<pre><code lang="go">type File interface {
    io.Closer
    io.Reader
    io.Seeker
    Readdir(count int) ([]os.FileInfo, error)
    Stat() (os.FileInfo, error)
}</code></pre>



<p>Any type that satisfies the interface’s behaviors can be considered by the HTTP package as a <em>File</em>. This is convenient because the HTTP package doesn’t need to know if it’s dealing with a file on disk, a network buffer, or a simple <code>[]byte</code>. </p>



<h2>Interfaces Should Have No Knowledge of Satisfying Types </h2>



<p>An interface should define what is necessary for other types to classify as a member of that interface. They shouldn’t be aware of any types that happen to satisfy the interface at design time.</p>



<p>For example, let’s assume we are building an interface to describe the components necessary to define a car.</p>



<pre><code lang="go">type car interface {
	GetColor() string
	GetSpeed() int
	IsFiretruck() bool
}</code></pre>



<p><code>GetColor()</code> and <code>GetSpeed()</code> make perfect sense, they are methods confined to the scope of a car. <code>IsFiretruck()</code> is an anti-pattern. We are forcing all cars to declare whether or not they are firetrucks. In order for this pattern to make any amount of sense, we would need a whole list of possible subtypes. <code>IsPickup()</code>, <code>IsSedan()</code>, <code>IsTank()</code>… where does it end??</p>



<p>Instead, the developer should have relied on the native functionality of <a href="https://yourbasic.org/golang/type-assertion-switch/" target="_blank" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">type assertion</a> to derive the underlying type when given an instance of the <strong>car</strong> interface. Or, if a sub-interface is needed, it can be defined as:</p>



<pre><code lang="go">type firetruck interface {
	car
	HoseLength() int
}</code></pre>



<p>Which inherits the required methods from <code>car</code> and adds one additional required method to make the car a <code>firetruck</code>.</p>



<h2>Interfaces Are Not Classes</h2>



<ul><li>Interfaces are not classes, they are slimmer.</li><li>Interfaces don’t have constructors or deconstructors that require that data is created or destroyed.</li><li>Interfaces aren’t hierarchical by nature, though there is syntactic sugar to create interfaces that happen to be supersets of other interfaces.</li><li>Interfaces define function signatures, but not underlying behavior. Making an interface often won’t <a aria-label="DRY (opens in a new tab)" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_repeat_yourself" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">DRY</a> up your code in regards to struct methods. For example, if five types satisfy the error interface, they all need their own version of the <code>Error()</code> function.</li></ul>







<h2>Related Work</h2>



<ul><li><a href="https://qvault.io/2020/03/29/how-to-separate-library-packages-in-go/">How To Separate Library Packages in Go</a></li><li><a href="https://qvault.io/2020/03/19/golang-mutexes-what-is-rwmutex-for/">Golang Mutexes – What Is RWMutex For?</a></li><li><a href="https://qvault.io/2020/02/20/how-to-build-jwts-in-go-golang/">How To Build JWT’s in Go (Golang)</a></li></ul>
		</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://qvault.io/2020/03/15/best-practices-for-writing-clean-interfaces-in-go/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25042085</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 01:53:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Debunking an election fraud claim using open data and Dolt]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 32 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25041998">thread link</a>) | @proverbialbunny
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2020-11-09-debunking-election-fraud/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2020-11-09-debunking-election-fraud/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2020-11-09-debunking-election-fraud/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25041998</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 01:34:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Try Design Thinking]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 44 | Comments 6 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25041961">thread link</a>) | @gbasin
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | https://garybasin.com/try-design-thinking/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://garybasin.com/try-design-thinking/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://garybasin.com/try-design-thinking/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25041961</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 01:27:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Recalculate a Spreadsheet]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 272 | Comments 64 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25039393">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | https://lord.io/blog/2020/spreadsheets/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://lord.io/blog/2020/spreadsheets/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>Let’s say I’m ordering burritos for my two friends while they quar up in Jersey City, and want to calculate the total price of my order:</p>
<p><img alt="screenshot of spreadsheet; burrito price is listed as $7, burrito price w ship as burrito price plus $3, num burritos is 2, and total is num burritos times burrito price w ship, for a total of $20" src="https://lord.io/images/2020/anchors_0.png"></p>
<p>It’s a little confusing to follow the flow of data in a spreadsheet when it’s written like that, so I hope you don’t mind this equivalent diagram that represents it as a graph:</p>
<p><img alt="the previous spreadsheet represented as a graph, with arrows from one cell to another replacing the spreadsheet cell references" src="https://lord.io/images/2020/anchors_1.png"></p>
<p>We’re rounding the cost of an El Farolito super vegi burrito to $8, so assuming the per-burrito delivery toll remains at just $2 per burrito, it looks like the total for our two burritos will be $20.</p>
<p>Oh no, I completely forgot! One of my friends loves to wolf down multiple burritos at a time, so I actually want to place an order for three burritos. If I update <code>Num Burritos</code>, a naïve spreadsheet engine might recompute the entire document, recalculating first the cells with no inputs, and then recalculating any cell whose inputs are ready until we’ve finished every cell. In this case, we’d first calculate <code>Burrito Price</code> and <code>Num Burritos</code>, then <code>Burrito Price w Ship</code>, and then a new final <code>Total</code> of $30.</p>
<p><img alt="same as previous graph, but num burritos is updated to 3, and every cell is tagged as &quot;recalc&quot;" src="https://lord.io/images/2020/anchors_2.png"></p>
<p>This simple strategy of recalculating the whole document may sound wasteful, but it’s actually already <em>better</em> than VisiCalc, the first spreadsheet software ever made, and the first so-called “killer app”, responsible for popularizing the Apple II. VisiCalc would repeatedly recalculate cells from left-to-right and top-to-bottom, sweeping over them again and again until none of them changed. Despite this “interesting” algorithm, VisiCalc remained the dominant spreadsheet software for four years. Its reign ended in 1983, when Lotus 1-2-3 swept the market with “natural-order recalculation”, <a href="https://aresluna.org/attached/computerhistory/articles/spreadsheets/tenyearsofrowsandcolumns">as described by Tracy Robnett Licklider in Byte Magazine</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Lotus 1-2-3 exploited natural-order recalculation, although it also supported VisiCalc’s row- and column-order modes. Natural-order recalculation maintained a cell dependency list and recalculated a cell before recalculating cells that depended on it.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Lotus 1-2-3 implemented the “recalculate everything” strategy we’ve shown above, and for the first decade of spreadsheets, that was as good as it got. Yes, we recalculate every cell in the document, but at least we only recalculate every cell once.</p>
<h2>but what about “burrito price w ship”</h2>
<p>Great point, header 2. In my three burrito example there’s no reason to recompute <code>Burrito Price w Ship</code>, because changing the number of burritos we order can’t possibly influence the per-burrito price. In 1989, one of Lotus’ competitors realized this, and created SuperCalc5, presumably naming it after the theory of super burritos at the core of this algorithm. SuperCalc5 recalculated “only cells dependent on changed cells”, which would make updating the burrito count look more like this:</p>
<p><img alt="same as prior graph, with burrito count updated from 2 to 3, but now only the two affected cells &quot;num burritos&quot; and &quot;total&quot; are tagged as recalc" src="https://lord.io/images/2020/anchors_3.png"></p>
<p>By only updating a cell when one of its inputs changes, we can avoid recalculating <code>Burrito Price w Ship</code>. In this case, it saves just a single addition, but on larger spreadsheets it can save quite a bit of time! Unfortunately, we now have another problem. Let’s say my friends now want meat burritos, which cost a dollar more, and simultaneously El Farolito adds a $2 fee paid per-order, regardless of how many burritos you order. Before any formula outputs are recalculated, our graph might look like this:</p>
<p><img alt="same as prior graph (after burrito count update finished calculation), but now burrito price is being updated from $8 to $9, and simultaneously total is updated from &quot;burrito price w ship * num burritos&quot; to &quot;burrito price w ship * num burritos + $2 fee&quot;" src="https://lord.io/images/2020/anchors_4.png"></p>
<p>Since there are two updated cells here, we have a problem. Should we recalculate <code>Burrito Price</code> first, or <code>Total</code>? Ideally, we first calculate <code>Burrito Price</code>, notice that its output has changed, then recalculate <code>Burrito Price w Ship</code>, and finally recalculate <code>Total</code>. However, if we instead recalculate <code>Total</code> first, we’ll have to recalculate it a second time once the new $9 burrito price propagates down. If we don’t calculate cells in the right order, this algorithm isn’t better than recalculating the whole document. In some cases, it’s as slow as VisiCalc!</p>
<p>Clearly, it’s important for us to figure out the right order to update our cells. Broadly, there are two solutions to this problem: dirty marking and topological sorting.</p>
<p>This first solution involves marking all cells downstream from an edit as dirty. For instance, when we update <code>Burrito Price</code>, we would mark the downstream cells <code>Burrito Price w Ship</code> and <code>Total</code> as dirty, even before doing any recalculations:</p>
<p><img alt="same as prior graph with the two updates, but now three nodes are tagged as dirty: &quot;burrito price&quot;, &quot;burrito price w ship&quot;, and &quot;total&quot;. would also like to apologize for the rather confusing image alt text so far; it's really hard to write these for graph diagrams!! if you are a screen reader user and have advice on better ways to do this, would love to hear from you." src="https://lord.io/images/2020/anchors_5.png"></p>
<p>Then, in a loop, we find a dirty cell that has no dirty inputs, and recalculate it. When there are no dirty cells left, we’re done! This solves our ordering problem. There’s one downside though — if a cell is recalculated and we find its new output to be the same as its previous output, we’ll still recalculate downstream cells! A little bit of extra logic can avoid actually running the formula trouble in this case, but we unfortunately still waste time marking and unmarking a lot of cells as dirty.</p>
<p>The second solution is topological sorting. If a cell has no inputs, we mark its height as 0. If a cell has inputs, we mark its height as the maximum of the heights of its inputs, plus one. This guarantees all cells have a greater height than any of their inputs, so we just keep track of all cells with a changed input, always choosing the cell with the lowest height to recalculate first:</p>
<p><img alt="same as prior graph with the two updates, but instead of dirty tags, now every node has a height tag. &quot;burrito price&quot; and &quot;num burritos&quot;, the two cells with no in-nodes, have height 0. &quot;burrito price w ship&quot; has height 1. &quot;total&quot; has height 2." src="https://lord.io/images/2020/anchors_6.png"></p>
<p>In our double-update example, <code>Burrito Price</code> and <code>Total</code> would be initially added to the recalculation heap. <code>Burrito Price</code> has lesser height, and would be recalculated first. Since its output changes, we then would add <code>Burrito Price w Ship</code> to the recalculation heap, and since it too has less height than <code>Total</code>, it would be recalculated before we finally recalculate <code>Total</code>.</p>
<p>This has a big advantage over the first solution: no cell is ever marked dirty unless one of its inputs actually change. However, it requires we keep all cells pending recalculation in sorted order. If we use a heap, this results in an <code>O(n log n)</code> slowdown, so in the worst case, asymptotically slower than Lotus 1-2-3’s strategy of recalculating everything.</p>
<p>Modern-day Excel uses <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/office/client-developer/excel/excel-recalculation">a combination of dirty marking and topological sorting</a>, which you can read more about in their docs.</p>
<h2>demand-driven complications</h2>
<p>We’ve now more or less reached the algorithms used in modern-day spreadsheet recalculation. Unfortunately, I suspect there is basically no business case to be made for ever improving it further. The few people with the problem “my Excel spreadsheet is too slow” have already written enough Excel formulas that migration to any other platform is impossible. Fortunately, I have no understanding of business, and so we’re going to look at further improvements anyway.</p>
<p>Beyond caching, one of the cool aspects of a spreadsheet-style computation graph is we can only calculate the cells that we’re interested in. This is sometimes called lazy computation, or demand-driven computation. As a more concrete example, here’s a slightly expanded burrito spreadsheet graph. This example is the same as before, but we’ve added what is best described as “salsa calculations”. Each burrito contains 40 grams of salsa, and we perform a quick multiplication to know how much salsa is in our entire order. In this case, since our order has three burritos, there’s a total of 120 grams of salsa in our entire order.</p>
<p><img alt="a new graph. similar structure to the old graph, but there are two new nodes: &quot;salsa per burrito&quot;, which is set to the constant &quot;40 grams&quot;, and &quot;salsa in order&quot;, which is &quot;salsa per burrito&quot; times &quot;num burritos&quot;" src="https://lord.io/images/2020/anchors_7.png"></p>
<p>Of course, astute readers will have spotted the problem here already: knowing the total weight of salsa in an order is a pretty useless measurement. Who cares that it’s 120 grams? What am I supposed to do with this information?? Unfortunately, a regular spreadsheet would waste cycles calculating <code>Salsa In Order</code>, even if we don’t want it recalculated most of the time.</p>
<p>This is where demand-driven recalculation can help. If we could somehow specify that we’re only interested in the output of <code>Total</code>, we could only recompute that cell and its dependencies, and skip touching <code>Salsa In Order</code> and <code>Salsa Per Burrito</code>. Let’s call <code>Total</code> an <em>observed</em> cell, since we’re trying to look at its output. We can also call both <code>Total</code> and its three dependencies <em>necessary</em> cells, since they’re necessary to compute some observed cell. <code>Salsa In Order</code> and <code>Salsa Per Burrito</code> would be aptly described as <em>unnecessary</em>.</p>
<p>Some folks on the Rust team created the <a href="https://github.com/salsa-rs/salsa">Salsa</a> framework to solve this problem, clearly naming it after the unnecessary salsa calculations their computers were wasting cycles on. Salsa is really cool, and I’m sure <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i_IhACacPRY">they can explain</a> how it works better than I can. Very roughly, they use revision numbers to track whether a cell needs recalculation. Any mutation to a formula or input increments the global revision number, and every cell tracks two revisions: <code>verified_at</code> to track the revision its output was last brought up-to-date, and <code>changed_at</code> to track the revision its output last actually changed.</p>
<p><img alt="our new graph, but now there's a title of &quot;current revision: R6&quot;. each cell is tagged with a change revision and verified at revision. all change revisions are R1, except &quot;salsa per burrito&quot;, which is R6. all verified at revisions are R6, except &quot;salsa in order&quot;, which is R1." src="https://lord.io/images/2020/anchors_8.png"></p>
<p>When the user indicates they’d like a fresh value for <code>Total</code>, we’d first recursively recalculate any cell necessary to <code>Total</code>, skipping cells if their <code>last_updated</code> revision is equal to the global revision. Once the dependencies of <code>Total</code> are up-to-date, we only rerun the actual formula in <code>Total</code> if either <code>Burrito Price w Ship</code> or <code>Num Burrito</code> have a <code>changed_at</code> revision greater than the <code>verified_at</code> revision of <code>Total</code>. This is great for Salsa’s purposes in the rust-analyzer, where simplicity is important and each cell takes a significant amount of time to compute. However, we can see the disadvantages in our burrito graph above — if <code>Salsa Per Burrito</code> constantly changes, our global revision number will frequently tick up. This will make each observation of <code>Total</code> walk the three cells necessary to it, even though none of those cells have actually changed. No formulas will be recalculated, but if the graph is large, repeatedly walking all of a cell’s dependencies could get expensive.</p>
<h2>faster demand-driven solutions</h2>
<p>Instead of inventing new algorithms for demand-driven spreadsheets, what if we instead draw from the two classical spreadsheet algorithms mentioned earlier: dirty marking and topological sorting? As you might imagine, a demand-driven model complicates both of these, but both are still viable.</p>
<p>Let’s first look at dirty marking. As before, when we change a cell’s formula, we mark all downstream cells as …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://lord.io/blog/2020/spreadsheets/">https://lord.io/blog/2020/spreadsheets/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://lord.io/blog/2020/spreadsheets/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25039393</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 20:19:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How does consciousness even make sense?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 22 | Comments 26 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25039045">thread link</a>) | @algoholix
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | http://niklasbuehler.com/blog/consciousness.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://niklasbuehler.com/blog/consciousness.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">

<header>

<span><a href="http://niklasbuehler.com/">Home</a> / <a href="http://niklasbuehler.com/rss.xml">RSS</a> / <a href="http://niklasbuehler.com/contact.html">Contact me</a></span>
</header>
<p><em>08.11.2020</em></p>
<!--
## How does consciousness even make sense?
<a id='1604845992' href='/log/#1604845992'>#1604845992 2020 Nov 08, 15:33</a>
-->
<p>I don’t think the current state of “artificial intelligence” really has proven that it earns the great title of <em>intelligence</em>, as I believe it’s all still just a sophisticated application of statistics on large amounts of data. I prefer the title “machine learning”, as in my opinion that describes the process of adjusting the parameters of statistical methods based on the given data adequately.</p>
<p>I’m not even sure if intelligence and consciousness can be simulated by a computer. Because if they could, then the speed of execution surely wouldn’t matter to that fact, right? And if speed didn’t matter, one could just as well represent the (deterministic!) calculations of a finite computer on a piece of paper or by arranging some stones on a large field. Granted, it’d be somewhat slower than a modern computer and the paper would have to be sufficiently large, but in the end flipping bits, drawing on paper, and moving rocks in a systematic way is just the same when it comes to representing computation. So that’d mean if we arranged a bunch of stones on a large field in a certain pattern and then used some fancy (but deterministic) rules to move them around, we’d create consciousness?! I can’t really believe that’s true.</p>
<p><em>But how is a human brain any different??</em> In the end it’s also just biological wires exchanging electricity (+ some chemistry added to the process)…<br>
I can’t really grasp that. Do my thoughts make sense? Where’s the flaw?</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="join-the-discussion-on-hacker-news">Join the discussion on Hacker News</h3>
<p>There’s an interesting discussion about this text on <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25039045">Hacker News</a>.</p>

<hr>

<h3>Want to leave a comment?</h3>
<p>
If you want to give me some feedback or share your opinion, please contact me via <a href="mailto:hi@niklasbuehler.com?subject=Comment%20on%20Blog:%20consciousness" target="_blank">email</a>.
</p>

<hr>

<p>
<span>© Niklas Bühler, 2020</span>
<span><a href="http://niklasbuehler.com/rss.xml">RSS</a> / <a href="http://niklasbuehler.com/contact.html">Contact me</a></span>
</p>



</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://niklasbuehler.com/blog/consciousness.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25039045</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 19:48:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[AWS Security Maturity Roadmap [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 74 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25038422">thread link</a>) | @sciurus
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | https://summitroute.com/downloads/aws_security_maturity_roadmap-Summit_Route.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://summitroute.com/downloads/aws_security_maturity_roadmap-Summit_Route.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://summitroute.com/downloads/aws_security_maturity_roadmap-Summit_Route.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25038422</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 19:07:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A hidden gem in sound symmetry]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 176 | Comments 43 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25037784">thread link</a>) | @gbh444g
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | https://soundshader.github.io/hn/acf/index.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://soundshader.github.io/hn/acf/index.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      
      
      

      

<blockquote>
  <p><em><a href="https://pages.mtu.edu/~suits/autocorrelation.html">Autocorrelation</a> is used to compare a signal with a time-delayed version of itself. If a signal is periodic, then the signal will be perfectly correlated with a version of itself if the time-delay is an integer number of periods. That fact, along with related experiments, has implicated autocorrelation as a potentially important part of signal processing in human hearing.</em></p>
</blockquote>

<p>ACF is a simple method to visualize music that produces surprisingly good results. Perhaps the most unexpected property of ACF is that it accurately transfers the subjective “harmony level” from music to images. It’s almost an unreasonable property, if you think about it. Images below are ACF height maps in polar coordinates.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Female vocal</th>
      <th>David Parsons</th>
      <th>Piano</th>
      <th>Bird</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td><img src="https://soundshader.github.io/pics/song-2.jpg" alt=""></td>
      <td><img src="https://soundshader.github.io/pics/bowl-3.jpg" alt=""></td>
      <td><img src="https://soundshader.github.io/pics/piano-p.jpg" alt=""></td>
      <td><img src="https://soundshader.github.io/pics/bird-2.jpg" alt=""></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>More examples: <a href="https://soundshader.github.io/gallery/">soundshader.github.io/gallery</a> (beware of large images).</p>

<p>Live demo: <a href="https://soundshader.github.io/">soundshader.github.io</a></p>



<p>Contrary to what you might think, our ears don’t seem to rely on an FFT-like process to extract isolated frequencies. Instead, our ears detect periodic parts in the signal, although in most cases those periodic parts closely match the FFT frequencies. There is a simple <a href="https://auditoryneuroscience.com/pitch/missing-fundamental-stimuli">experiment</a> that proves this point:</p>

<p><img src="https://auditoryneuroscience.com/sites/default/files/missingFundamental2.png" alt=""></p>

<p>As can be clearly seen on the FFT image, the A signal is a pure sinusoidal tone, while B is a mix of tones. Despite each tone in B is higher than A, our ears perceive B as a lower tone. If we plot both waveforms, we’ll see that A has about 9 peaks in a 20 ms window, while B has only 5. The definition of “peak” is moot, but it doesn’t stop our ears from counting them and using the “number of peaks per second” as a proxy to the tone height.</p>

<p>ACF detects those peaks. ACF sees that there are 5 equally spaced time shifts where <code>B[t] * B[t + shift]</code> reaches the maximum, so on the ACF output we’ll see those 5 peaks.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Given that I’ve shamelessly stolen the experiment’s illustration above, I feel obligated to recommend the book where the illustration came from: <a href="https://auditoryneuroscience.com/book-preview">Auditory Neuroscience</a>.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>One downside of ACF is that it drops the phase component of the input signal, and thus ACF is not reversible. This means that images that only render ACF, lose about 50% of the information from the sound and those 50% are important, e.g. dropping the phase from recorded speech makes that speech indiscernible. Real world sounds, such as voice, heavily use nuanced amplitude and phase modulation. ACF captures the former, but ignores the latter.</p>



<p>ACF of a sound sample <code>X[0..N-1]</code> can be computed with two FFTs:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>S = |FFT[X]|^2
ACF[X] = FFT[S]
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And thus ACF contains exactly the same information as the spectral density <code>S</code> (the well known spectrogram).</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>If you’re familiar with the ACF definition, you’ll notice that I should’ve used the inverse FFT in the last step. There is no mistake. The inverse FFT can be computed as <code>FFT[X*]*</code>, where <code>X*</code> is complex conjugate, but since <code>S[i]</code> is real-valued (and positive, in fact), the conjugate has no effect on it, and since ACF is also real valued in this case, the second conjugate has no effect either.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>ACF is a periodic and even function and so it can be naturally rendered in polar coordinates. In most cases, ACF has a very elaborate structure. Below are some examples, where red = ACF &gt; 0 and blue = ACF &lt; 0.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>conventional music</th>
      <th>a bird song</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td><img src="https://soundshader.github.io/pics/acf-c-1.jpg" alt=""></td>
      <td><img src="https://soundshader.github.io/pics/acf-c-3.jpg" alt=""></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>Looking at the first example, we can tell that there are 5 prominent peaks in a 20 ms sound sample, which corresponds to 250 Hz. This means that our ears would necesserarily perceive this sound as a 250 Hz tone, regardless of what its spectrogram says. If it was a pure 250 Hz tone, we’d see perfectly round shapes of the <code>r = cos(250Hz * t)</code> line, but it’s not the case here: we see that the 5 peaks are modulated with small wavelets: there is one big wavelet in the middle (which consists of 3 smaller wavelets) and 4 smaller wavelets. Our ears would hear the big wavelet as the 2nd harmonic of the 250 Hz tone (i.e. it would be a 500 Hz tone with a smaller amplitude) and the 4 small wavelets as the 5th harmonic (1000 Hz) at barely discernible volume. In addition to that, the 500 Hz harmonic is also modulated by the 3 tiny wavelets, which means we’d hear a 1500 Hz tone, almost inaudible. We can say all this without even looking at the spectrogram or hearing the sound.</p>



<p>Music is a temporal ornament. There are many types of ornaments, e.g. the 17 types of wallpaper tesselations, but few of them look like music. However there is one particular type of ornament that resembles music a lot - I mean those “mandala” images. I don’t know how and why those are produced, but I noticed a connection between those images and music:</p>

<ul>
  <li>The 1st obvious observation is that a mandala is drawn in polar coordinates and is <code>2*PI</code> periodic. Sound is periodic too, so I thought the two facts are related.</li>
  <li>The 2nd observation is that patterns on those images evolve over the radial axis. Ans so is music is a sequence of evolving sound patterns.</li>
  <li>The 3rd observation is that a <code>2*PI</code> periodic function trivially corresponds to a set of frequencies. We usually use FFT to extract the frequencies and another FFT to restore the <code>2*PI</code> periodic function. Thus, a single radial slice of a mandala could encode a set of frequencies. If this is correct, a mandala is effectively an old school vinyl disk.</li>
</ul>

<p>Putting these observations together we naturally arrive with the ACF idea.</p>



<p>Open an issue on github or shoot me a email at ssgh@aikh.org</p>



<p>AGPLv3</p>


      
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://soundshader.github.io/hn/acf/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25037784</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 18:19:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why Rust Is the Future of Game Development]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 152 | Comments 224 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25037147">thread link</a>) | @adamnemecek
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | https://thefuntastic.com/blog/why-rust-is-the-future-game-dev? | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thefuntastic.com/blog/why-rust-is-the-future-game-dev?">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-v-10b1bd0a="" data-v-2ae295f5=""><p><em>Rust, not related to the video game also called Rust, is a promising systems programming language with novel features ideally suited for game development. Exposure and awareness within the game developer community, however, remains limited. In this post, I provide a gentle introduction to Rust and attempt to justify its place on your radar.</em></p>
<h2 id="a-short-history-lesson">A Short History Lesson</h2>
<p>What is Rust, and where did it come from? In <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HiWkMFE8uRE" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">this fantastic talk</a>, James Munns gives us a detailed oral history. Way back around 2010, Mozilla was frustrated by the state of development in Firefox, a massive software project  written mostly in C++. Despite best practices and an abundance of engineering talent, writing high-performance, parallelised, and memory-safe code, at that scale of complexity, remained fraught and error-prone.</p>
<p>Bear in mind, this predates the advent of C++11 (aka the 2011 edition) which heralded efforts to somewhat modernise the language. Even so, manual memory manipulation is easy to get wrong, and <a href="https://msrc-blog.microsoft.com/2019/07/18/we-need-a-safer-systems-programming-language/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">research</a> from <a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/chrome-70-of-all-security-bugs-are-memory-safety-issues/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">multiple vendors</a> describes this category of error as responsible for 70% of security vulnerabilities. </p>
<p>Into this context steps Graydon Hoare, a Mozilla employee, introducing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rust_(programming_language)#History" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">a potential solution</a> to the roadblock: Rust, the hobby language he'd been tinkering with since 2006. In 2012, Mozilla would formally announce Servo, an experimental research project to re-imagine a browser engine built with memory safety and concurrency as first principles. And alongside it, Rust, the companion language to make it all possible.</p>
<p>These early days of Rust are described as a Cambrian explosion of ideas and wild experimentation. Concepts were liberally stolen from other languages, from C++ to OCaml, Haskell, Erlang, ML, C#, Ruby and more, reflecting the diverse pool of engineers working on the language at the time. Still, most in the industry, while admiring the optimism in taking such an ambitious moon shot, <a href="http://dtrace.org/blogs/bmc/2018/09/18/falling-in-love-with-rust/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">remained pessimistic</a> about the prospects of success. </p>
<p>2015 saw a major milestone, with the release of Rust v1.0. Perhaps as significant as the feature list, was the number of failed experiments left behind on the cutting room floor, the team unafraid to pare down the language to its quintessential elements. This was also the first time stability guarantees would be offered, a quality notoriously absent before. </p>
<p>Soon after, in 2016, Firefox <a href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2016/07/shipping-rust-in-firefox/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">shipped its first production Rust code</a>. The industry and community started to take notice, and Rust began its impressive, and as yet unbroken, <del>four</del> <a href="https://stackoverflow.blog/2020/01/20/what-is-rust-and-why-is-it-so-popular/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">five year streak</a> as Stack Overflow's most beloved language. [<em>Thank you James Munns for pointing out it's now actually five years</em>]. </p>
<p>Right from the outset, Rust set out with a clear focus on   building an inclusive community. They, in turn, have contributed to Rust's impressive technical aptitude, but have also fostered a sense of reverence and fondness not often witnessed in other languages. Are they crazy zealots or onto something?</p>
<h2 id="why-rust">Why Rust?</h2>
<blockquote>
<p><em>The performance of C++ with the convenience of C#</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>This was the first time Rust hijacked my attention. C++ enjoys a long-standing ubiquity, in part, due to its ability to express zero cost abstractions. As explained by Bjarne Stroustrup, the creator of C++:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>What you don't use, you don't pay for. And further: What you do use, you couldn't hand code any better.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>It's easy to spot the relevancy to games. Making frame-rate while simulating entire worlds is a daunting performance challenge. Indeed, C++ underpins the bulk of game engines. There simply is <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ltCgzYcpFUI" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">no other industrial language</a> that offers the same speed and low-level control, whilst writing programs in the large. </p>
<p>C++, however, suffers from the weight of its legacy. The accumulation of features over 40 years makes for a complex and intricate language. In the last decade modernisation of the standard has done well to uplift it from its C roots, but the experienced programmer must build up an arcane lore of which features are blessed, and which machinery is dangerous. As Stroustrup again describes:  </p>
<blockquote>
<p>Within C++, there is a much smaller and cleaner language struggling to get out.   </p>
</blockquote>
<p>This makes the language daunting and difficult to approach for beginners. In <a href="https://boats.gitlab.io/blog/post/zero-cost-abstractions/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">this blog post</a>, Rust contributor <em>withoutboats</em> defines an import quality about abstraction:  </p>
<blockquote>
<p>A zero cost abstraction, like all abstractions, must actually offer a better experience than the alternative.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So yes, of course, C++ offers a better time than your own hand wrought assembly. However, this is making the subtle point that it's competing against a secondary force: a more expensive abstraction that justifies its cost by being more comfortable and convenient.</p>
<p>We see this writ large in the rise of popular game engines that eschew the complexity of C++, the most notable being Unity. End users write code in C#, a more forgiving and ergonomic language, creating a boon in developer productivity and a reduction in iteration time.  </p>
<p><img src="https://thefuntastic.com/blog/2020-10-Unity-Interest.png" title="Unity interest over time in search trends"></p>
<p>In large codebases though, near the edge of the performance envelope, this trade-off begins to bite. The garbage collector eliminates an entire category of errors by removing responsibility for memory management from the end-user. However as its workload grows, so do periodic performance spikes antithetical to smooth gameplay.  </p>
<p><img src="https://thefuntastic.com/blog/2020-11-GC-spikes.png" title="Unity interest over time in search trends"></p>
<p>The experienced developer can still create a performant experience, however, this demands plugging the leaks in the abstraction. They must build a mental model of the machinery behind the curtain, a collection of arcane wisdom that bans many of the original conveniences, lest they disturb the garbage collector. </p>
<p>So development teams face a choice. Better resourced AAA studios generally choose Unreal or in-house engine tech built on C++, able to absorb the overhead for long term gain. Less resourced studios optimise for time to market, choosing Unity, or one of the many other accessible game making tools (Godot, Haxe, Game Maker, etc.). They often postpone performance concerns until after business eligibility is secured.   </p>
<p>Rust, however, for the first time, promises a third way. A world where it's possible to write zero cost abstractions without sacrificing higher-order elegance. </p>
<h3 id="ownership-based-memory">Ownership based memory</h3>
<p>To understand Rust's special sauce, we're going have to talk about ownership and how it handles memory. This is only a simple sketch, but <a href="http://intorust.com/tutorial/ownership/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">in-depth resources</a> exist for the curious. </p>
<p>Writing optimised code is often about taking the way we, as humans, naturally think of an idea or algorithm, and instead expressing it in terms that favour the computer. This act often harms the legibility and understanding of a program, which makes it much harder for us, the humans, to reason about its correctness. </p>
<p>In a manually managed language, like C, the hapless programmer is left responsible for the machinations of the machine. They must take great care to ensure data is appropriately loaded into memory before operation, and then responsibly disposed of afterwards. A difficult dance in which missteps either cause dramatic crashes or else subtle and hard to detect vulnerabilities. But these are the very same tools that allow careful users to tune performance.  </p>
<p>At the other end of the spectrum, garbage collection promises the programmer it will automatically deal with the problem on their behalf. They are now free to express code naturally, but in doing so, it ties hands behind their back. They no longer have, at least not without indirection, the levers needed to wring out maximal performance.</p>
<p>Rust begins from a different premise. Rather than hiding this complexity, it accepts that computers are hard for humans, and instead tries to save us from the dangerous bits. Users can still tune the machine, but with less rope to wrap around their necks. </p>
<p>In the same way that static typing exists, very clever people have figured out how to make the compiler eliminate a whole category of memory and concurrency errors. To achieve this, Rust makes a bargain with the developer: </p>
<blockquote>
<p>"I'm going to keep track of the lifetime of every piece of memory in your program for you. This way, I can detect the moment you're no longer using it and safely free it on your behalf. But in return, I'm going to need you to follow <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/book/ch04-01-what-is-ownership.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">strict rules</a> about the ownership of that memory. If you try to use it outside of the scope that owns it, my humourless friend here, the borrow checker, is going to make sure you don't hurt yourself."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>However, like static typing, this lunch isn't free. Rust is known to have a steep learning curve, "fighting the borrow checker" becomes a right of passage. It takes time to learn this new paradigm. Ownership makes some familiar patterns difficult or impossible and demands new ones be learnt in their place. Perhaps we should revise our earlier statement as: "The performance of C++ with the <del>convenience</del> safety of C#"</p>
<h2 id="unpacking-rusts-popularity">Unpacking Rust's Popularity</h2>
<p>Early adopters have a selfish reason to extol the virtues of their chosen technology, as widespread adoption enhances the return on their risky investment. In this respect, while interest is high but opportunities for real-world exposure are limited, is it possible that Rust is cresting a wave of unearned hype? <a href="https://matklad.github.io/2020/09/20/why-not-rust.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Not every javascript or python developer</a> interested in the language, for example, has a use case that merits the additional complexity.</p>
<p>To a developer standing on the shores of 2010, <code>git</code>, a new version control system with a steep learning curve, may have seemed like a risky investment. But, in the ensuing world of Github, it's hard to argue the effort was wasted, even if some workloads (i.e. large games) still require alternatives.</p>
<p>In a similar vein, how can we qualify Rust's popularity as a meaningful signal? Ultimately, we will only know by the volume of mud we've dug through in the trenches, and admittedly, it is far too early to collect this data for games. </p>
<p>In other industries, though, early reports of Rust are effusive. <a href="https://medium.com/the-innovation/how-microsoft-is-adopting-rust-e0f8816566ba" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Mircosoft</a>, <a href="https://developers.libra.org/docs/community/coding-guidelines" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Facebook</a>, <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/opensource/aws-sponsorship-of-the-rust-project/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Amazon</a>, <a href="https://www.wired.com/2016/03/epic-story-dropboxs-exodus-amazon-cloud-empire/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Dropbox</a>, <a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/tag/rust/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Cloudflare</a> all have Rust deployed in production. The <a href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-Kernel-Rust-Path-LPC2020" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Linux Kernel</a> and <a href="https://www.chromium.org/Home/chromium-security/memory-safety/rust-and-c-interoperability" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Chrom…</a></p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://thefuntastic.com/blog/why-rust-is-the-future-game-dev?">https://thefuntastic.com/blog/why-rust-is-the-future-game-dev?</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thefuntastic.com/blog/why-rust-is-the-future-game-dev?</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25037147</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 17:27:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Canadian government pledges to connect 98% of Canadians via High-Speed Internet]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 96 | Comments 80 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25037074">thread link</a>) | @aDfbrtVt
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/broadband-internet-1.5794901 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/broadband-internet-1.5794901">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>The Liberal government is promising to spend more than a billion dollars to connect most Canadian to high-speed internet by 2026.</p><div><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.4962390.1546282434!/cpImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/broadband-expansion.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>The Liberal government has been promising to do something to approve broadband internet service in rural areas.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Toby Talbot/Associated Press)</figcaption></figure><p><span><p>After some pandemic-related delays, the Liberal government says it's now&nbsp;on track to connect 98 per cent of Canadians to high-speed internet by 2026.</p>  <p>The announcement comes as more Canadians find themselves living online while stuck at home due to COVID-19 restrictions.</p>  <p>Prime Minister Justin Trudeau and a handful of cabinet ministers&nbsp;held a news conference in Ottawa to launch the $1.75 billion universal broadband fund — a program unveiled in the federal government's 2019 budget and highlighted on the campaign trail and in&nbsp;September's throne speech. Most of the money&nbsp;was&nbsp;announced in last year's budget.</p>  <p>"We were ready to go&nbsp;in March&nbsp;with the new Universal Broadband Fund and then the pandemic hit,"&nbsp;Rural Economic Development Minister Maryam Monsef told reporters.</p>  <p>The prime minister said the government is now on track to connect&nbsp;98 per cent of Canadians&nbsp;to high-speed&nbsp;by 2026 — an increase over&nbsp;the previously promised 95 per cent benchmark — and to link up&nbsp;the rest by 2030.</p>  <p>"These are ambitious targets&nbsp;and we're ready to meet them,"&nbsp;Trudeau said.</p>  <p><em><strong>WATCH |&nbsp;Trudeau announces a large investment in broadband services for rural Canadians</strong></em></p>  <p><span><span><div><div role="button" tabindex="0" title="Trudeau announces a large investment in broadband services for rural Canadians"><div><p><img src="https://thumbnails.cbc.ca/maven_legacy/thumbnails/573/747/ftr%20TRUDEAU%20broadband_frame_0.jpg" alt=""></p></div></div></div><span>Prime Minister Justin Trudeau spoke with reporters during a media briefing in Ottawa on Monday.<!-- --> <!-- -->2:47</span></span></span></p>  <p>About&nbsp;$150 million from the fund will be freed up to fund projects aimed at getting communities connected by next fall.</p>  <p>Senior officials with the department of&nbsp;Innovation, Science and Economic Development&nbsp;said applications will be reviewed on an ongoing basis until Jan. 15, 2021, with a goal of having projects completed by mid-November, 2021.</p>  <p>Deciding who gets upgraded connectivity first will depend on the service providers applying, they said.</p>  <p>Josh Tabish is&nbsp;corporate communications manager at the Canadian Internet Registration Authority, the not-for-profit agency that manages the .ca internet domain. He said he's hoping&nbsp;that a&nbsp;rapid build will bring relief to many Canadians over the next year.</p>    <p>"In terms of action, I think&nbsp;this is great news for Canadians who are stuck at home suffering from slow, crappy internet," he said.&nbsp;</p>  <p>But Tabish also said he hopes the government will look at need when deciding which projects should get approval first.&nbsp;His group has been working to identify the&nbsp;communities that&nbsp;have the slowest&nbsp;rates in Canada.</p>  <p>"What we really want to see happen is communities who are suffering with slow, sluggish connectivity get those upgrades first," he said.</p>  <p>The prime minister said the government also&nbsp;has reached a $600 million agreement with Telesat for satellite capacity to improve broadband service in remote areas and in the North.</p>    <p>"Good reliable internet isn't a luxury. It's a basic service," he said.</p>  <p>"Now more than ever, a video chat cutting out during a meeting or a connection that's too slow to upload a school assignment — that's not just a hassle, that's a barrier."</p>  <h2>Tories call out timelines</h2>  <p>The Opposition Conservatives criticized the government's timelines, arguing Canadians need better access now more than ever.</p>  <p>"This is absolutely unacceptable and a slap in the face to the nearly one million Canadians who don't have internet access at home, much less a reliable cell phone signal," said MP John Nater, Conservative critic&nbsp;for rural economic development.</p>  <p>"For months, Canada's Conservatives have been demanding concrete action to connect Canadians.&nbsp;We will continue to advocate for lower cell phone prices and for real improvements to broadband internet services, so that Canadians living in rural and remote areas have consistent access to these essential services."</p>  <p>The&nbsp;CRTC <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/crtc-internet-essential-service-1.3906664">declared</a> broadband internet a basic telecommunications service in 2016.&nbsp;But its data suggest&nbsp;just&nbsp;<a href="https://crtc.gc.ca/eng/internet/internet.htm">40.8 per cent of rural Canadian households have access to </a>download speeds of&nbsp;at least 50 megabits per second (Mbps) and upload speeds of&nbsp;10 Mbps.</p>  <p>The government said those speeds will allow Canadians to work and learn online and access telehealth services.</p>  <p><em><strong>WATCH | Rural Canadians react to today's announcement</strong></em></p>  <p><span><span><div><div role="button" tabindex="0" title="Liberals promise to connect 98% of Canadians by 2030"><div><p><img src="https://thumbnails.cbc.ca/maven_legacy/thumbnails/732/431/politics_THURTON_broadband_money_7000kbps_1280x720_1817544259879.jpg" alt=""></p></div></div></div><span>After some pandemic-related delays, the Liberal government says it's now on track to connect 98 per cent of Canadians to high-speed internet by 2026. The announcement comes as more Canadians find themselves living online while stuck at home due to COVID-19 restrictions.<!-- --> <!-- -->1:47</span></span></span></p>  </span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/broadband-internet-1.5794901</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25037074</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 17:21:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Converting Utzoo-Wiseman Usenet Tapes to PostgreSQL Back End Using Python]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 40 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25036780">thread link</a>) | @kxrm
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | https://www.joe0.com/2020/10/07/converting-utzoo-wiseman-netnews-archive-to-postgresql-using-python-3-8/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.joe0.com/2020/10/07/converting-utzoo-wiseman-netnews-archive-to-postgresql-using-python-3-8/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><main id="content" role="main" itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="http://schema.org/Blog"> <article id="post-4678" itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting" itemprop="blogPost"><div> <!-- .entry-header --><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>Recently, I came across a resource that allowed me to download the entire collection of UTZOO NetNews Archive of the earliest USENET posts. These were essentially the earliest available discussions posted to the Internet by people working at various Universities who were already connected to the Internet. There were approximately 2.1 million posts in these archives created between Feb 1981 and June of 1991. This article describes the journey of converting those tapes into fully searchable PostgreSQL database and later also into the <a href="https://usenetarchives.com/groups.php?c=utzoo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">usenetarchives.com</a> website.</p><p>Until 2001, these early Usenet discussions were considered being lost, but miraculously <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Henry_Spencer" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Henry Spencer</a> from the University of Toronto, Department of Zoology was backing it up onto magnetic tapes and kept them stored for all these years (apparently at a great cost).</p><p><a href="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/2019-02-17_9-14-15.png"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/2019-02-17_9-14-15.png" alt="" width="325" height="259" srcset="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/2019-02-17_9-14-15.png 1282w, https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/2019-02-17_9-14-15-300x239.png 300w, https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/2019-02-17_9-14-15-768x613.png 768w, https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/2019-02-17_9-14-15-1024x817.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 325px) 100vw, 325px"></a>H. Spencer had altogether 141 of these magnetic tapes, but there were of no use, so eventually, him and a couple of motivated people such as David Wiseman (who dragged 141 tapes back and forth in his a pickup truck), Lance Bailey, Bruce Jones, Bob Webber, Brewster Kahle, and Sue Thielen; embarked on a process of converting all of these tapes into the regular format, accessible to everyone.</p><p>And that’s the copy I downloaded. What a treasure, right?</p><p>Well, not so fast, once I unzipped the data, I realized that the TGZ format contains literally millions of small text files (each post in its own file). While it was certainly nice to have, it wasn’t something that I or anyone else could read. Certainly not in a forum like discussion format. It wasn’t obvious which post is the one that starts the discussion or which ones are the replies to the thread. And forget about searching through these files, that was utterly not possible. Just to put things into perspective, it took me over 5 hours to un-tar the archives.</p><p>That said, it didn’t take long for me to decide to develop a Python-based converter that would allow me to convert the entire collection from millions of flat files into a fully searchable PostgreSQL database. The following post talks about the process and also includes the Python code of the solution released as open source.</p><p>The UTZOO Usenet archive can be downloaded here:</p><ul><li>http://www.skrenta.com/rt/utzoo-usenet/</li><li>http://shiftleft.com/mirrors/utzoo-usenet/</li><li>https://ipfs.io/ipfs/QmTo7fRxpXwxv6Uw4TAAtyLWEmvugKaggrHSKNBTRHzWcA/</li><li>Or using this torrent: <a href="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/utzoo-wiseman-usenet-archive_archive.zip">utzoo-wiseman-usenet-archive_archive</a></li></ul><p>Once downloaded you’ll see that archive contains 161 x TAR Archive files. It looks like this:</p><p><a href="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/img_5c69574363b87.png"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/img_5c69574363b87.png" alt="" width="596" height="531" srcset="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/img_5c69574363b87.png 832w, https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/img_5c69574363b87-300x268.png 300w, https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/img_5c69574363b87-768x685.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 596px) 100vw, 596px"></a></p><p>So, I grabbed a copy of the 7-Zip archiver from <a href="https://www.7-zip.org/">https://www.7-zip.org</a> and started decompressing the files.</p><p>I ended up with over <strong>2,104,828</strong>&nbsp;flat text files in <strong>56,988</strong> folders, which was the entire copy of Henry Spencer’s Usenet archive.</p><p>For those who like numbers, here is each Utzoo tape along with its size, number of files and folders:</p><p id="MLqhONH"><img loading="lazy" width="602" height="2294" src="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e6e422f3ee.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e6e422f3ee.png 602w, https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e6e422f3ee-79x300.png 79w, https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e6e422f3ee-269x1024.png 269w, https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e6e422f3ee-403x1536.png 403w" sizes="(max-width: 602px) 100vw, 602px"></p><h3>File Issues</h3><p>While examining the extract, I realized that Magnetic Tape 118 is uncompressed in \utzoo-wiseman-usenet-archive\news118f1 folder, named tape118, so I had rename it to tape118.tar and extracted it manually, only to realize it’s a copy of files which I already have. Someone creating the original archive forgotten to remove that file. There are 3 files in these folders that need to have.tar extension added and decompressed as well:</p><ul><li>\utzoo-wiseman-usenet-archive\news118f1\tape118</li><li>\utzoo-wiseman-usenet-archive\news120f1\tape120</li><li>\utzoo-wiseman-usenet-archive\news121f1\tape121</li></ul><p>If you opened one of the folders and navigated down to one of the many subfolders, you’d find a file that contained the message. For example, going into&nbsp;\utzoo-wiseman-usenet-archive\news006f1\b15\net\aviation folder, I was now apparently in the <strong>net.aviation</strong> Usenet group. But the only way to find out was to open one of the files and look at the content. Here I highlighted what it looked like.&nbsp;As you can see, each file seems to consist of a header, then a single empty line and the body of the message:</p><p id="RYYsysr"><a href="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/img_5c6967453ae2c.png"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/img_5c6967453ae2c.png" alt="" width="1110" height="759" srcset="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/img_5c6967453ae2c.png 1110w, https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/img_5c6967453ae2c-300x205.png 300w, https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/img_5c6967453ae2c-768x525.png 768w, https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/img_5c6967453ae2c-1024x700.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1110px) 100vw, 1110px"></a></p><p>So, I decided to build a Python parser, that went through all these files reading the header portion of each message and grouping all unique results together, giving me all the possible headers such as (From, Subject, Newsgroup, etc.). I found that there were about 79 x different types of headers. So it appeared that not all messages adhered to the same basic structure. Going through the headers, all had the standard set that was common across all posts.</p><p>Once I had the common field, I’ve created a Postgres database called ‘utzoo’</p><pre>create database utzoo;</pre><p>And a new schema called all_messages</p><pre>create schema all_messages;


</pre><p>The above database and schema were the pre-requisites. Everything else, like table creation, inserting the posts, etc. is part of the Python script and fully automated.</p><p>In terms of table creation, the script automatically creates 5 tables for each detected newsgroup:</p><ul><li>headers – parsed headers</li><li>references – references for each message</li><li>body – text of the message</li><li>from – who posted the message</li><li>subjects – list of unique subject lines</li></ul><p>This is what the script auto-creates for each unique Group name:</p><pre>create table all_messages.<strong>GroupName_headers</strong>
(
    id         bigserial not null
        constraint GroupName_headers_pk primary key,
    dateparsed timestamp,
    subj_id    bigint,
    ref        smallint,
    msg_id     text,
    msg_from   bigint,
    enc        text,
    contype    text,
    processed  timestamp default CURRENT_TIMESTAMP
);
alter table all_messages.GroupName_headers
    owner to postgres;


create table all_messages.<strong>GroupName_refs</strong>
(
    id      bigint,
    ref_msg text default null
);
alter table all_messages.GroupName_refs
    owner to postgres;

create table all_messages.<strong>GroupName_body</strong>
(
    id   bigint primary key,
    data text default null
);
alter table all_messages.GroupName_body
    owner to postgres;

create table all_messages.<strong>GroupName_from</strong>
(
    id   serial not null
        constraint GroupName_from_pk primary key,
    data text
);
alter table all_messages.GroupName_from
    owner to postgres;

create table all_messages.<strong>GroupName_subjects</strong>
(
    id      serial not null
        constraint GroupName_subjects_pk primary key,
    subject text
);
alter table all_messages.GroupName_subjects
    owner to postgres;</pre><p>Those will be the tables where the Python parser will dump all the data and make sure posts are properly lined up between tables.</p><p>The python script also creates indexes to make the inserting and later reading of the posts faster:</p><pre>create unique index GroupName_headers_uiidx on all_messages.GroupName_headers(id);
create unique index GroupName_headers_umidx on all_messages.GroupName_headers(msg_id);
create unique index GroupName_body_idx on all_messages.GroupName_body(id);; 
create unique index GroupName_from_idx on all_messages.GroupName_from(data);
create unique index GroupName_subjects_idx on all_messages.GroupName_subjects(subject);

</pre><p>Once created, the structure per group looks like this:</p><p id="kdsmyQE"><img loading="lazy" width="362" height="703" src="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e3e7d98df4.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e3e7d98df4.png 362w, https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e3e7d98df4-154x300.png 154w" sizes="(max-width: 362px) 100vw, 362px"></p><p>The following screenshot explains how it’s all wired up. I didn’t do any hardcoded relationships, but you can change the script if you want that.</p><p id="THgecCD"><img loading="lazy" width="601" height="496" src="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e40111a6ef.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e40111a6ef.png 601w, https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e40111a6ef-300x248.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 601px) 100vw, 601px"></p><p>The date is an integral part of each message and I had to do some data conversion massaging in Python to get the proper date, as dates were coming in a variety of formats. I’ve tried various libraries but dateutil.parser.parse standard date and time library for Python did the best job.</p><p>However, I still needed to account for various labelling of data fields in the headers, so if data wasn’t found in the ‘date’ header, I had to look into other header parts such as ‘NNTP-Posting-Date’, ‘X-Article-Creation-Date’,&nbsp;‘Posted’,&nbsp;or ‘Received’ fields.</p><p>Well and then it was all about creating a Python parser, start the PostgreSQL, point it to an archive directory, and wait :)</p><p>At the bottom of this article is the code of the Python solution. It’s about 1,000 lines, and it took altogether about 1 day to create and test it. The script is smart enough to keep the track of where it started, so if it needs to be interrupted, it’ll know where to continue from to get the job done.</p><p>The source code is available on GitHub as open-source under MIT license:</p><p><a href="https://github.com/JozefJarosciak/python_mbox_parser/blob/master/utzoo2postgres.py" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/JozefJarosciak/python_mbox_parser/blob/master/utzoo2postgres.py</a></p><p>The final solution artifact is called ‘<strong>utzoo2postgres.py</strong>‘ , and it was tested on Python 3.8.</p><p>Open the script and define the path to un-tared Utzoo archive directories.</p><p>Examples:</p><pre># for Windows
positionFilePath = "E:\\Usenet\\Utzoo\\"
# for linux:
# positionFilePath = "/Usenet/Utzoo/"</pre><p>Also, define the particulars of your PostgreSQL database:</p><pre>db_connection = psycopg2.connect(host="localhost", user="", password="", port="5432", database="utzoo")</pre><p>And then just execute the script!</p><pre>python 3 utzoo2postgres.py</pre><p><em>Note: In case you need to stop the program and run it later, the script is smart to resume from the last spot it was processing.</em></p><p>The script will process all Utzoo Archive messages in about 6 hours (depending on the speed of your machine).</p><p>Screenshot from processing:</p><p id="UwdOjId"><img loading="lazy" width="713" height="585" src="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7dc52b05827.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7dc52b05827.png 713w, https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7dc52b05827-300x246.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 713px) 100vw, 713px"></p><p>Here is a screenshot of the database after only a couple of minutes of conversion:</p><p id="JQYnVLo"><img loading="lazy" width="432" height="642" src="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e3dc6ce1c7.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e3dc6ce1c7.png 432w, https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e3dc6ce1c7-202x300.png 202w" sizes="(max-width: 432px) 100vw, 432px"></p><p>As you can see, the conversion utility produces a database with 5 tables per group where messages are linked to each other through auto-created indexes.</p><p id="kdsmyQE">Let’s say we want to look up all discussions in the<strong> net.physics</strong> discussions; and sort them out by the number of replies.</p><p>This is how you can do that:</p><p id="ymEaJie"><a href="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e48cfddb5b.png"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e48cfddb5b.png" alt="" width="1198" height="625" srcset="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e48cfddb5b.png 1198w, https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e48cfddb5b-300x157.png 300w, https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e48cfddb5b-1024x534.png 1024w, https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e48cfddb5b-768x401.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1198px) 100vw, 1198px"></a></p><p>Now, we can look up a particular discussion by the ID. For example, we want the ID: 1648 from the screenshot above, the discussion with the subject: “<strong>Question on FTL and quantum mechanics</strong>“. That’s not so hard either:</p><p id="rcwUUqq"><a href="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e49dfdfd6d.png"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e49dfdfd6d.png" alt="" width="1697" height="847" srcset="https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e49dfdfd6d.png 1697w, https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e49dfdfd6d-300x150.png 300w, https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e49dfdfd6d-1024x511.png 1024w, https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e49dfdfd6d-768x383.png 768w, https://www.joe0.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/img_5f7e49dfdfd6d-1536x767.png 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1697px) 100vw, 1697px"></a></p><p>It’s nice to have a database full of posts, but it’s hardly usable that way. I needed something that would allow me to easily access these posts.</p><p>So, once everything was done, I built a PHP script around this code and registered <a href="http://usenetarchives.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://usenetarchives.com</a> to make all these archives available online, in an easy to read and search (forum-like) web site.</p><p>The PHP code is not part of this article, but you can head over to <a href="https://usenetarchives.com/groups.php?c=utzoo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>https://usenetarchives.…</strong></a></p></div></div></article></main></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.joe0.com/2020/10/07/converting-utzoo-wiseman-netnews-archive-to-postgresql-using-python-3-8/">https://www.joe0.com/2020/10/07/converting-utzoo-wiseman-netnews-archive-to-postgresql-using-python-3-8/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.joe0.com/2020/10/07/converting-utzoo-wiseman-netnews-archive-to-postgresql-using-python-3-8/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25036780</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 16:56:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Architecture Playbook]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 237 | Comments 46 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25035752">thread link</a>) | @yarapavan
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | https://nocomplexity.com/documents/arplaybook/index.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nocomplexity.com/documents/arplaybook/index.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p>
        
          By Maikel Mardjan<br>
        
            © Copyright 2018,2019, 2020 BM-Support.org. Created by Maikel Mardjan. This work is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License (cc-by-sa).<br>
      </p>
  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nocomplexity.com/documents/arplaybook/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25035752</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 15:31:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I don't care what Elon Musk thinks anymore]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 58 | Comments 66 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25035658">thread link</a>) | @avthar
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | https://avthar.com/blog/dont-outsource-thinking | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://avthar.com/blog/dont-outsource-thinking">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-block-type="2" id="block-f18334b57a4385ee2a76"><div><p><em>This blog originally appeared in my </em><a href="https://avthar.substack.com/"><em>weekly newsletter</em></a><em>, where I share ideas I’m reflecting upon, experiments I’m trying and lessons I’ve learned, all to help you level up your own life. To get posts like this straight to your inbox, </em><a href="https://avthar.substack.com/"><em>subscribe here</em></a><em>.</em></p><p>—</p><p>Youtube recommended to me&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vVnDE8wSrVo">what Elon Musk would work on if he was 22 years old today</a>. The video has almost 3 million views. In the past, I would’ve immediately watched the whole video, gotten inspired by what Elon thought were industries important to the future of humanity and then spent a ton of time working on that and telling everyone about it. All because Elon Musk thought it was important.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>This is outsourcing your thinking</strong>. This trick served me well in highschool and throughout college, but it’s not sustainable for long term success and happiness.&nbsp;</p><p>There are two problems with outsourcing your thinking. Continuing with the example of past me, there are things I’m already interested in, have&nbsp;<a href="https://nav.al/specific-knowledge">specific knowledge</a>&nbsp;about or possess a competitive advantage in, that won’t be mentioned on Elon’s list. Consequently, the first problem is that I will look down on those things as less meaningful and important and not pursue them, despite my better suitability and chances of success in those areas.</p><p>The second problem with outsourcing your thinking is that once the novelty of the problem fades away, I’d be faced with navigating difficulty, naysayers and the friction of creating something new, without an internal compass to guide me toward the correct paths to take. Put simply, Elon Musk isn’t there to talk me through what he thinks the path forward to be. This all stems from the issue that I pursued something, not because I had interest in that thing, actually enjoyed it or thought it was important, but because Elon Musk (or whoever else) thought it was important to work on. And I followed his thinking, rather than thinking for myself.</p><p>The reason this is important is because most success in business is having&nbsp;<strong>product-market-founder fit</strong>, not just about working on what’s world changing or hot. It’s about building a product that solves a burning problem for the right market and&nbsp;<strong>being the right person, with the right intuition</strong>&nbsp;to bring that product to market, operate that company and delight those customers. Even if you’re working on an important problem, if you don’t have conviction that comes from your own mental models, you’ll get burned when chaos hits. Just ask all the crypto ‘experts’ of 2016/17.&nbsp;<strong>It’s better to build something that’s an expression of yourself, rather than something others think is smart.</strong></p><p>Outsourcing your thinking is a manifestation of the error of trusting others more than we trust ourselves.&nbsp;<a href="https://avthar.com/blog/jw-curation">Josh Waitzkin</a>&nbsp;talks about how this phenomenon of outsourcing your thinking happens all the time in the investing world:</p><blockquote><p>“<em>If you take investors, there might be an investment, which one from the outside we think is objectively good. But it really isn't objectively good. It has to fit into one's portfolio of investments in a way that emerges from one's own mental models. Otherwise, it is not a form of self expression. Then, when you enter volatility, you're not gonna know what to do with it.</em>” -&nbsp;<a href="https://avthar.com/blog/jw-curation">Josh Waitzkin</a></p></blockquote><p>Elon Musk is a placeholder for anyone telling you what you should do or think. That could be entrepreneurs or VCs you idolize or maybe your parents (especially true if you’re brown). The reality is that you should not care what Elon Musk or anyone else says is important, you should decide for yourself what you should work on, based on following your own curiosity and interest.&nbsp;<strong>Do the hard work of experimenting, exploring and thinking for yourself. Don’t outsource your thinking.</strong></p><p><a href="https://avthar.substack.com/"><em>Subscribe here</em></a><em> to get posts like this straight to your inbox, </em></p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://avthar.com/blog/dont-outsource-thinking</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25035658</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 15:21:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A US Visa in 937 Days]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 286 | Comments 142 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25035307">thread link</a>) | @caution
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/11/09/a-us-visa-in-937-days/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/11/09/a-us-visa-in-937-days/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Here’s the complete timeline of events. From my first denial to travel to the US until I eventually received a tourist visa. And then I can’t go anyway.</p>



<h2>December 5-11, 2016</h2>



<p>I spent a week on Hawaii with Mozilla – my employer at the time. This was my 12th visit to the US over a period of 19 years. I went there on ESTA, the visa waiver program Swedish citizens can use. I’ve used it many times, there was nothing special this time. The typical procedure with ESTA is that we apply online: fill in a form, pay a 14 USD fee and get a confirmation within a few days that we’re good to go.</p>



<figure><a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/hawaii-2016.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/hawaii-2016.jpg" alt="" width="558" height="414"></a><figcaption>I took this photo at the hotel we stayed at during the Mozilla all-hands on Hawaii 2016.</figcaption></figure>



<h2>June 26, 2017</h2>



<p>In the early morning one day by the check-in counter at Arlanda airport in Sweden, I was refused to board my flight. Completely unexpected and out of the blue! I thought I was going to San Francisco via London with British Airways, but instead I had to turn around and go back home – slightly shocked. According to the lady behind the counter there was “something wrong with my ESTA”. I used the same ESTA and passport as I used just fine back in December 2016. They’re made to last two years and it had not expired.</p>



<figure><a href="https://twitter.com/bagder/status/879198063998513152"><img loading="lazy" src="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot_2020-11-06-Twitter-Publish.png" alt="" width="553" height="199"></a><figcaption>Tweeted by me, minutes after being stopped at Arlanda.</figcaption></figure>



<p>People engaged by Mozilla to help us out could not figure out or get answers about what the problem was (questions and investigations were attempted both in the US and in Sweden), so we put our hopes on that it was a human mistake somewhere and decided to just try again next time.</p>



<h2>April 3, 2018</h2>



<p>I missed the following meeting (in December 2017) for other reasons but in the summer of 2018 another Mozilla all-hands meeting was coming up (in Texas, USA this time) so I went ahead and applied for a new ESTA in good time before the event – as I was a bit afraid there was going to be problems. I was right and I got denied ESTA very quickly. “Travel Not Authorized”.</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://daniel.haxx.se/media/ESTA-travel-not-authorized.png" alt="" width="642" height="458"><figcaption>Rejected from the ESTA program.</figcaption></figure>



<h2>Day 0 – April 17, 2018</h2>



<p><strong>Gaaah</strong>. It meant it was no mistake last year, they actually mean this. I switched approach and instead applied for a tourist visa. I paid 160 USD, filled in a ridiculous amount of information about me and my past travels over the last 15 years and I visited the US embassy for an in-person interview and fingerprinting.</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://daniel.haxx.se/media/Administrative-Processing.png" alt="" width="577" height="289"></figure>



<p>This is day 0 in the <a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2018/07/28/administrative-purgatory/" data-type="post" data-id="11076">visa process</a>, 296 days after I was first stopped at Arlanda.</p>



<h2>Day 90 – July 2018</h2>



<p>I missed the all-hands meeting in San Francisco when I didn’t get the visa in time.</p>



<h2>Day 240 – December 2018</h2>



<p>I <a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2018/11/18/im-leaving-mozilla/">quit Mozilla</a>, so I then had no more reasons to go to their company all-hands…</p>



<h2>Day 365 – April 2019</h2>



<p><a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2019/04/17/one-year-in-still-no-visa/" data-type="post" data-id="12216">A year passed</a>. “someone is working on it” the embassy email person claimed when I asked about progress.</p>



<h2>Day 651- January 28, 2020</h2>



<p>I emailed the embassy to query about the process</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://daniel.haxx.se/media/651-days-email.png" alt="" width="611" height="166"><figcaption>Screenshotted email</figcaption></figure>



<p>The reply came back quickly:</p>



<blockquote><p>Dear Sir, </p><p>All applications are processed in the most expeditious manner possible. While we understand your frustration, we are required to follow immigration law regarding visa issuances. This process cannot be expedited or circumvented. Rest assured that we will contact you as soon as the administrative processing is concluded.</p></blockquote>



<h2>Day 730 – April 2020</h2>



<p><a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/04/17/two-years-in/" data-type="post" data-id="13456">Another year had passed</a> and I had given up all hope. Now it turned into a betting game and science project. How long can they actually drag out this process without saying either yes or no?</p>



<h2>Day 871 – September 3, 2020</h2>



<p>A friend of mine, a US citizen, contacted his Congressman – <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gerry_Connolly">Gerry Connolly</a> – about my situation and asked for help. His office then subsequently sent a question to the US embassy in Stockholm asking about my case. While the response that arrived on September 17 was rather negative…</p>



<pre>your case is currently undergoing necessary administrative processing and regrettably it is not possible to predict when this processing will be completed.</pre>



<p>… I think the following turn of events indicates it had an effect. It unclogged something.</p>



<h2>Day 889 – September 22, 2020</h2>



<p>After 889 days since my interview on the embassy (only five days after the answer to the congressman), the embassy contacted me over email. <em> For the first time since that April day in 2018.</em></p>



<pre>Your visa application is still in administrative processing. However, we regret to inform you that because you have missed your travel plans, we will require updated travel plans from you.</pre>



<p>My travel plans – that had been out of date for the last 800 days or so – suddenly needed to be updated! As I was already so long into this process and since I feared that giving up now would force me back to square one if I would stop now and re-attempt this again at a later time, I decided to arrange myself some updated travel plans. After all, I work for an American company and I have a friend or two there.</p>



<h2>Day 900 – October 2, 2020</h2>



<p>I replied to the call for travel plan details with an official invitation letter attached, inviting me to go visit my colleagues at <a href="https://www.wolfssl.com/">wolfSSL</a> signed by our CEO, Larry. I really want to do this at some point, as I’ve never met most of them so it wasn’t a made up reason. I could possibly even get some other friends to invite me to get the process going but I figured this invite should be enough to keep the ball rolling.</p>



<h2>Day 910 – October 13, 2020</h2>



<p>I got another email. Now at 910 days since the interview. The embassy asked for my passport “for further processing”.</p>



<h2>Day 913 – October 16, 2020</h2>



<p>I posted my passport to the US embassy in Stockholm. I also ordered and paid for “return postage” as instructed so that they would ship it back to me in a safe way.</p>



<h2>Day 934 – November 6, 2020</h2>



<p>At 10:30 in the morning my phone lit up and showed me a text telling me that there’s an incoming parcel being delivered to me, shipped from “the Embassy of the United State” (bonus points for the typo).</p>



<figure><a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/embassy-text.png"><img loading="lazy" src="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/embassy-text.png" alt="" width="496" height="211"></a></figure>



<h2>Day 937 – November 9, 2020</h2>



<p>I received my passport. Inside, there’s a US visa that is valid for ten years, until November 2030.</p>



<div><figure><a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/VISA.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/VISA.jpg" alt="" width="441" height="221"></a><figcaption>The upper left corner of the visa page in my passport…</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>As a bonus, the visa also comes with a NIE (National Interest<br>Exception) that allows me a single entry to the US during the PP (Presidential Proclamations) – which is restricting travels to the US from the European Schengen zone. In other words: I am actually allowed to travel right away!</p>



<p>The timing is fascinating. The last time I was in the US, Trump hadn’t taken office yet and I get the approved visa in my hands just days after Biden has been announced as the next president of the US.</p>



<h2>Will I travel?</h2>



<p>Covid-19 is still over us and there’s no end in sight of the pandemic. I will of course not travel to the US or any other country until it can be deemed safe and sensible.</p>



<p>When the pandemic is under control and traveling becomes viable, I am sure there will be opportunities. Hopefully the situation will improve before the visa expires.</p>



<h2>Thanks to</h2>



<p>All my family and friends, in the US and elsewhere who have supported me and cheered me up through this entire process. Thanks for keeping inviting me to fun things in the US even though I’ve not been able to participate. Thanks for pushing for events to get organized outside of the US! I’m sorry I’ve missed social gatherings, a friend’s marriage and several conference speaking opportunities. Thanks for all the moral support throughout this long journey of madness.</p>



<p>A special thanks go to David (you know who you are) for contacting Gerry Connolly’s office. I honestly think this was the key event that finally made things move in this process.</p>
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/11/09/a-us-visa-in-937-days/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25035307</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 14:47:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[No Free Features]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 72 | Comments 83 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25034809">thread link</a>) | @alangibson
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | https://landshark.io/2020/11/09/no-free-features.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://landshark.io/2020/11/09/no-free-features.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
	<p><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25032105">This thread recently hit the top of Hacker news</a>.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>No More Free Work from Marak: Pay Me or Fork This</p>

  <p>Respectfully, I am no longer going to support Fortune 500s
( and other smaller sized companies ) with my free work.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The gist is that Marak, who’s on the brink of homelessness after his apartment building caught fire, is no longer interested in doing unpaid work for businesses using his <a href="https://github.com/Marak/faker.js">faker.js</a> project. He seems to be getting a lot of support from the open source developer community.</p>

<h2 id="unpaid-interns">Unpaid Interns</h2>

<p>The foundational principle of open source is “fix your problem, then give the world a copy of the solution.” So let’s get one thing straight: <em>open source developers are not volunteering to fix your problem.</em> They are fixing their own problems, then letting you use the solution too because it costs them nothing. That near-zero cost of replicating software is why open source works.</p>

<p>Because of this, I don’t think developers claiming to do open source should expect compensation for features that they need for themselves. But developing a new feature that they don’t need is something different entirely. In IT we call that a Change Request, and CRs come with a fee to cover them. ‘Near-zero cost’ doesn’t apply anymore because now they’re taking on a lot of work they otherwise wouldn’t have done.</p>

<p>Not recognizing this difference has led to a situation where for-profit entities are using open-source devs as unpaid interns. Well it’s worse really: at least interns get resume filler.</p>

<h2 id="no-more-free-features">No More Free Features</h2>

<p>I look forward to a day when asking anyone to do unpaid labor is considered unethical by our industry. That goes for feature requests on open source projects, on unpaid internships, and on unpaid ‘take home’ interview assignments.</p>

<p>Requesting work in an economic context without offering compensation in some form is morally indefensible. It’s wrong because unpaid labor is wrong. It’s wrong because presuming on anyone’s helpful nature is wrong. We shouldn’t be using bounties to move our change requests to the head of the line because we shouldn’t even be making requests without a bounty attached.</p>

<p>(<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25034809">Official Hacker News discussion thread</a>)</p>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://landshark.io/2020/11/09/no-free-features.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25034809</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 13:55:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[When remote work doesn't cut it]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 63 | Comments 47 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25034037">thread link</a>) | @FlyingSnake
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | https://samkhawase.com/blog/remote-work/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://samkhawase.com/blog/remote-work/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                <p>The COVID-19 crisis, while disrupting the global world unlike anything before, has opened up an unexpected window to remote work. Nearly all major<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>tech<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> giants<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup> have<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup> allowed their workers to do home office. Many people are considering this as a sign of the advent of <strong>Work 2.0</strong>, where physical offices spaces will be irrelevant, and people can work from their cozy dens. There are however significant challenges in adoption of generalized remote work and things will be back as usual once the COVID-19 ends.</p>
<p>The <strong>challenges surrounding remote work outweigh it’s promises</strong>. Not every company is a FAANG, and companies will struggle to transition given their limited resources.</p>
<h2 id="regulations">Regulations</h2>
<p>The most significant hurdle in hiring a global remote team is <strong>regulation</strong>. Labor regulations are wildly different amongst countries, and could be cumbersome for some companies. Some major hurdles include:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Payroll taxes</strong>, retirement bonuses: Germany has rentenversicherung, sozialversicherung whereas USA has 401k contributions. Can a German company afford to <strong>setup payroll</strong> taxes for a remote workers hired from India, Chile or US? Or will it lead to worker abuse through <strong>laissez-faire abuse</strong> through freelance contracts?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Notice periods</strong>: Europeans (on average) have 3 months notice period while US Americans have 2 weeks. How would a US company deal with it? On top of that, several countries have <strong>protection against unlawful termination</strong>, and how can a Slovakian employee avail that benefit against a German company?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>IP protection</strong>: It’s hard to <strong>protect IP</strong> if employees are not in the same jurisdiction. A company operation from Czechia would find it hard to settle trade disputes with a remote worker from South Africa. Another example is of <strong>TISAX compliance</strong> that is required for specialized hardware projects for Automotive industries. Remote work fails to make a dent in this situation.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="hardware-cant-remote">Hardware can’t remote</h2>
<p>Patio11’s law<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup> states that the <strong>economy is much bigger than you think</strong>. There are companies which have widely different business models and they often have a hardware related product. My <a href="https://www.salonlab-server.de/en-GB/">current project</a> is an IoT device that talks to an iPad app. The <strong>hardware team</strong> needs <strong>specialized tools</strong> to work on the IoT device, and these tools can’t be moved to home office. Remote work is a strict no-no for such products.</p>
<h2 id="swim-against-the-tide">Swim against the tide</h2>
<p>The biggest hurdle employees face in remote/home offices is <strong>lack of focus and direction</strong>. Humans have evolved over thousands of years to collaborate based on interpersonal cues, and a video call simply does not have the same effect. Humans need <strong>feedback</strong> and <strong>constructive communication</strong> whereas isolation kills the spirit. People who are new to remote work often feel <strong>rudderless</strong> because <strong>self discipline is hard</strong> when there’s no structure. I’m doing remote work on-and-off since 2018, and it took me a lot of discipline to get productive. The simple fact is that remote work is not natural, and not suited for all work streams in a typical company. Add to it the fact that many <strong>families</strong> simply don’t have space to work from home, and on top of that there might be kids around.</p>
<p>Remote work might be one of the few positive outcomes of the COVID-19 crisis but unless we tend to it carefully, we’ll end up creating a unhappy and unproductive workspace.</p>
<section role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
<p><a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-to-shift-permanently-toward-more-remote-work-after-coronavirus-11590081300">https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-to-shift-permanently-toward-more-remote-work-after-coronavirus-11590081300</a> <a href="#fnref:1" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
<p><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/08/07/atlassian-tells-employees-they-can-work-from-home-indefinitely.html">https://www.cnbc.com/2020/08/07/atlassian-tells-employees-they-can-work-from-home-indefinitely.html</a> <a href="#fnref:2" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote">
<p><a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/google-to-keep-employees-home-until-summer-2021-amid-coronavirus-pandemic-11595854201">https://www.wsj.com/articles/google-to-keep-employees-home-until-summer-2021-amid-coronavirus-pandemic-11595854201</a> <a href="#fnref:3" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:4" role="doc-endnote">
<p><a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/alexkantrowitz/twitter-will-allow-employees-to-work-at-home-forever">https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/alexkantrowitz/twitter-will-allow-employees-to-work-at-home-forever</a> <a href="#fnref:4" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:5" role="doc-endnote">
<p><a href="https://secondbreakfast.co/patio11-s-law">https://secondbreakfast.co/patio11-s-law</a> <a href="#fnref:5" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>

            </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://samkhawase.com/blog/remote-work/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25034037</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 12:28:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The power of HTTP headers and examples]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 53 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25033398">thread link</a>) | @loweisz
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | https://www.lorenzweiss.de/the_power_of_http_headers_with_four_examples/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.lorenzweiss.de/the_power_of_http_headers_with_four_examples/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>Almost everything in the web is sent with <strong>http</strong> and even non-developers have seen it when using the internet as keyword
inside urls or links.</p>
<p>Http stands for <strong>Hypertext Transfer Protocol</strong> and gives us the ability to transfer hypertext between a browser and a server.
This is a great technology that has been around almost since the invention of the web and is constantly evolving and
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP/2">offering more and more great features</a></p>

<p>As a developer you probably heard of http headers, at least in the moment you heard about the CORS policy.
This is a problem you must have heard about when developing websites.
But what exactly are http headers and what other ways are there to use them?</p>
<p>Let us first find out what they do and how you could use them. </p>
<p>When a browser requests a resource, for example a page of this blog, it asks the server with a request.
This request looks something like this: </p>
<div data-language="js"><pre><code><span>fetch</span><span>(</span><span>"https://www.lorenzweiss.de/race_conditions_explained/"</span><span>,</span> <span>{</span>
  credentials<span>:</span> <span>"include"</span><span>,</span>
  headers<span>:</span> <span>{</span>
    accept<span>:</span>
      <span>"text/html,application/xhtml+xml,application/xml;q=0.9,image/webp,image/apng,*/*;q=0.8,application/signed-exchange;v=b3"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"accept-language"</span><span>:</span> <span>"en,en-US;q=0.9,de-DE;q=0.8,de;q=0.7"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"cache-control"</span><span>:</span> <span>"max-age=0"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"sec-fetch-mode"</span><span>:</span> <span>"navigate"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"sec-fetch-site"</span><span>:</span> <span>"same-origin"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"sec-fetch-user"</span><span>:</span> <span>"?1"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"upgrade-insecure-requests"</span><span>:</span> <span>"1"</span><span>,</span>
  <span>}</span><span>,</span>
  referrerPolicy<span>:</span> <span>"no-referrer-when-downgrade"</span><span>,</span>
  body<span>:</span> <span>null</span><span>,</span>
  method<span>:</span> <span>"GET"</span><span>,</span>
  mode<span>:</span> <span>"cors"</span><span>,</span>
<span>}</span><span>)</span><span>;</span></code></pre></div>
<p>So you can see the URL or location of the resource, some information about the request and also a lot of headers with some information about the request.
This is how your browser tells the server some more information about the request. For example what kind of data type it accepts or
how the client is handling the cache.</p>
<p>After sending the request, the server replies, and it also sets some headers in the reply, which could look like this: </p>
<div data-language="text"><pre><code>:authority: www.lorenzweiss.de
:method: GET
:path: /race_conditions_explained/
:scheme: https
accept: text/html,application/xhtml+xml,application/xml;q=0.9,image/webp,image/apng,*/*;q=0.8,application/signed-exchange;v=b3
accept-encoding: gzip, deflate, br
accept-language: en,en-US;q=0.9,de-DE;q=0.8,de;q=0.7
cache-control: max-age=0
cookie: _ga=GA1.2.1173972759.1584812492; _gid=GA1.2.2076192721.1594044231
sec-fetch-mode: navigate
sec-fetch-site: same-origin
sec-fetch-user: ?1
upgrade-insecure-requests: 1
user-agent: Mozilla/5.0 (Macintosh; Intel Mac OS X 10_15_1) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/78.0.3904.70 Safari/537.36</code></pre></div>
<p>There is also some information that the server wants to tell the browser what to do with the resource, for example
if there are cookies, it must be determined which encoding was used, etc</p>
<p>Basically, in the http-context the headers for the communication of the browser and the server are used to extend the simple
Requests for resources. You could see it as the sheet of paper that is added on top of a package that you oder from an online store,
giving you more information about the context and the resource that you ordered.
Most of the headers have quite good defaults which you don't need to think of, but there are some headers that
can get quite important, like CORS headers. But there are so much more headers that you might never heard of which are very useful
and good to know how to use. </p>

<p>Do not worry, this article will not deal with CORS headers. The following http headers are those that are rarely used, but
can be really powerful and helpful to significantly improve the communication between a server and the browser. </p>
<p>So let's dig into it. Here are some headers that you can set and that are very useful and practical.</p>
<h2 id="if-range"><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/de/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/If-Range">If-Range</a><a href="#if-range" aria-label="if range permalink"></a></h2>
<h3>What and why?</h3>
<p>Imagine you start downloading a large resource, such as a video, an image, etc., and stop in between because of connection problems.
With <code>If-Range</code> you can tell the server if the representation is unchanged, to send the part(s) that are requested in Range.
Which means only the parts that were missing and not again the whole thing.</p>
<p>This can be very helpful when dealing with large resources and often bad connections as with mobile devices.
Because the resource can be downloaded in parts even if the connection is interrupted in between. </p>
<h4>How to use</h4>
<p>It can either be used with a date when the resources were last modified, or with an <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/ETag">ETag</a>, which is a key to help if the resources was invalidated</p>
<div data-language="text"><pre><code>If-Range: &lt;day-name&gt;, &lt;day&gt; &lt;month&gt; &lt;year&gt; &lt;hour&gt;:&lt;minute&gt;:&lt;second&gt; GMT
If-Range: &lt;etag&gt;</code></pre></div>
<h4>Example</h4>
<div data-language="text"><pre><code>If-Range: Wed, 21 Oct 2015 07:28:00 GMT </code></pre></div>
<h2 id="vary"><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/de/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Vary">Vary</a><a href="#vary" aria-label="vary permalink"></a></h2>
<p><code>Vary</code> Comes from a time when the web or http was used for a variety of things and not just for web pages.<br>
It is based on the idea of using http to exchange information in many different formats.
How does it do that? Well, it tells the server in which header to find the information, how to present the information. </p>
<p>Nowadays it can be really helpful if you have different resources for different customers, for example
mobile, tablet or desktop.
Imagine three different images for the same resource are stored on the server, depending on the device.
Then you can simply use the <code>Vary</code> header to tell the server to check the device and then decide which image size to send. </p>
<h4>Example</h4>
<p>For the example with the device dependent images, you can simply pass the 'user agent' to tell the server
that it should check the user-agent for device information. </p>

<h4>How to use</h4>

<p>Just enter the header, the server must check before deciding which resource to send.</p>
<h2 id="content-disposition"><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/de/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Content-Disposition">Content-Disposition</a><a href="#content-disposition" aria-label="content disposition permalink"></a></h2>
<p>If we go back to the example of a request to a server, for example to load this website, it is clear to the browser,
that it must <strong>display</strong> the resource of the answer.
But it can also be the case that the server sends a resource that the browser should automatically download to the user's computer,
like a picture or pdf etc.
A server can tell the browser what the browser should do with the attached resource via the <code>Content Disposition</code> header.</p>
<h4>Example</h4>
<p>With defining the <code>Content-disposition</code> to <code>attachment</code> the browser knows that this is a resource to download instead of just
show. </p>
<div data-language="text"><pre><code>Content-Disposition: attachment; filename="data.pdf"</code></pre></div>
<h4>How to use</h4>
<p>You can define the header as <code>inline</code> or <code>attachment</code>, where `inline is always the default.  </p>
<div data-language="text"><pre><code>Content-Disposition: &lt;inline | attachment&gt;</code></pre></div>
<h2 id="feature-policy"><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/de/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Feature-Policy">Feature-Policy</a><a href="#feature-policy" aria-label="feature policy permalink"></a></h2>
<p>This is a fairly new header and therefore only supported by modern browsers (sorry to all IE users). However
I want to mention this anyway because I think it can be really helpful for some use cases.<br>
Basically, the <code>feature-policy tells the browser which features or apis the browser should provide to the document and its</code>iframes` to be used. </p>
<p>For example, it can ban all scripts or iframes etc. within this website to allow sensitive apis like the camera or microphone.</p>
<h4>How to use</h4>
<div data-language="text"><pre><code>Feature-Policy: &lt;directive&gt; &lt;allowlist&gt;</code></pre></div>
<p>The <code>directive</code> is the name of the feature. You can see the full <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/de/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Feature-Policy#Directives">list of features here</a>
The <code>allowlist</code> defines the origins which are allowed to use the directive.</p>
<h3>Example</h3>
<p>Suppose we want our website to use neither the microphone nor the camera. With this header the
document or a contained iframe cannot access these functions.</p>
<div data-language="text"><pre><code>Feature-Policy: microphone 'none'; camera 'none'</code></pre></div>
<h3>More Headers:</h3>
<p>Here are some more headers that are worth mentioning: </p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/de/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Upgrade-Insecure-Requests">Upgrade-Insecure-Requests</a></li>
<li><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/de/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Age">Age</a></li>
<li><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/de/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Trailer">Trailer</a></li>
<li><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/de/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Location">Location</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="#conclusion" aria-label="conclusion permalink"></a></h2>
<p>Https headers are great and also very useful! But sometimes they can be quite complex, and it's really hard to get an overview of what headers are available and what benefits they bring.
Also when developing a website, especially in the frontend, you don't come in contact with them too often, except maybe with the CORS headers.
But I think that this missed some possibilities. http headers represent the communication between the server and the
customers much better, and we all know that communication is the key to a good relationship.</p>
<p>I hope I could shed some light on the darkness of http headers for you. In case I missed a good and helpful header,
please do not hesitate to send me a mail or contact me in any way.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.lorenzweiss.de/the_power_of_http_headers_with_four_examples/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25033398</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 10:44:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Zero-Days in Desktop Web Browsers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 119 | Comments 73 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25033290">thread link</a>) | @svenfaw
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | https://www.radsix.com/dashboard1/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.radsix.com/dashboard1/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.radsix.com/dashboard1/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25033290</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 10:24:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pijul: Towards 1.0]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 159 | Comments 102 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25032956">thread link</a>) | @lelf
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | https://pijul.org/posts/2020-11-07-towards-1.0/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://pijul.org/posts/2020-11-07-towards-1.0/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <p>
                We are looking for <strong>VC funding</strong>. If you are interested in helping us build the future of collaboration (for code and other documents), shoot us an email at <a href="mailto:contact@pijul.org">contact@pijul.org</a>.
                
            </p>


<p>Saturday, November 7, 2020</p>
<p>After fixing the performance and scalability problems, we’re on our way to getting a stable Pijul. In this post, I explain what I’ve been up to in the recent months.</p>
<h2 id="context">Context</h2>
<p>Pijul has always been advertised as a research project, trying to implement a theory of patches that would be sound and fast. This is an ambitious goal, and became even more ambitious than initially envisioned.</p>
<p>One of the hardest challenges is that source code is by essence stateful, which makes it much harder to iterate over algorithm designs, like normal research projecst need to. For example, in order to get from our last published version to our current design, we have gone through many different variants, and there wasn’t much to publish.</p>
<p>Moreover, the UX aspect is what matters most in the end, and testing it on a real world project is the only way to get it there. However, unlike in a compiler, where bootstrapping is done one step at a time, and previous versions are always available to compile your current one, a version control system has the additional problem that the previous versions might not always be easily accessible if there is a bug.</p>
<p>One of the criticisms I’ve heard since I realised that better datastructures were possible is that I was “working secretely”. I certainly understand this feeling, but this is based on a misunderstanding of how research works. When I first had the idea that I’m explaining in this post, I realised that a complete rewrite would be needed. But for a very long time, almost nothing other than unusable, unreadable prototypes happened.</p>
<p>Back then, there wasn’t much to show, since it wasn’t even clear that the basic datastructure would work. And even when they started working at a large enough scale, it took me quite a bit of testing on large repositories before they started actually working.</p>
<p>This also implies that there wasn’t much to show for quite a while, since the new algorithm wasn’t usable until very recently, and any repository started before now would have become obsolete in a matter of days.</p>
<p>There were also <a href="#a-personal-note">persoprofessional reasons</a> for this silence, described at the end of this post.</p>

<p>Pijul depends on two other projects I’ve started.</p>
<h3 id="sanakirja">Sanakirja</h3>
<p>One of these projects is Sanakirja, which is “just” a key-value store, but has the extra feature that databases can be cloned efficiently. I would have loved to just use an existing library, but there just isn’t any that has this cloning feature. However, the scope of Sanakirja is still quite modest, it does one thing and does it well. Obviously, it took some time to find the memory-management bugs, but I have good confidence that this is now done.</p>
<p>In previous releases of Pijul, databases were implemented with a single mmapped file containing the binary representation of B Trees. Despite their lower writing performance (compared to alternatives such as <em>Log-structured merge-trees</em>), and the complexity of the code for deletions, B Trees are very well suited to this use case: indeed, since they are trees, reference-counting the nodes is enough to implement efficient clones.</p>
<p>One of the remaining issues was that in order to grow the database, we needed to un-mmapped the file, grow it, and mmap it again. Since applying a single change in Pijul must be an atomic operation, we needed to cancel the transaction when that happened, and restart it with a bigger file.</p>
<p>Another issue is that I wanted the next libpijul to compile on platforms that don’t have mmap, such as WASM. However, if reallocating an mmapped file has a very low complexity (even though it does have a non-zero cost in terms of system calls), reallocating a chunk of memory often requires copying everything. This completely defeats the point of the algorithms in Pijul, which rely on a particular representation of the datastructures on the disk.</p>
<p>The main innovation in Sanakirja 0.13 is to use a vector of memory blocks (either in memory or mmapped from a file), of exponentially-increasing size. The overhead is just one extra indirection, the complexity of adding items is the same (since the operation of creating an extra block is $O(1)$). The exponentially-increasing sizes mean that the allocated memory is always at least half-full.</p>
<h3 id="thrussh">Thrussh</h3>
<p>The other one is Thrussh. That library implements the SSH protocol, and tries to handle a number of key formats. The former is a surprisingly easy goal, and keeping up with Tokio versions has historically been the hardest bit, while the latter is the most horrendous hydra-like task, with new heads and legacy formats showing up every time you think you’re done.</p>
<h2 id="how-repositories-used-to-work-and-still-do-to-some-extent">How repositories used to work (and still do, to some extent)</h2>
<p>Old-style repositories represented a single file by a directed graph $G = (V, E)$ of lines, where each vertex $v\in V$ represented a line, and an edge from $u \in V$ to $v\in V$, labelled by some change (also called patch) number $c$, could be read as “according to change $c$, line $u$ comes before $v$”.</p>
<p>This means that changes could introduce vertices and lines, as in the following example, where a line $D$ is introduced between $A$ and $B$:</p>
<p><img src="https://pijul.org/img/repos-line-add.svg">
</p>
<p>Here, the thick line represents the change from the file containing the lines $A$, $B$, $C$ to the file with the new line $D$.
An important feature to note is that <strong>vertices are uniquely identified</strong>, by the hash of the change that introduced them, along with a position in that change. This means that two lines with the same content, introduced by different changes, will be different. It also means that a lines keeps its identity, even if the change is applied in a totally different context.</p>
<p>Moreover, this system is append-only, in the sense that <em>deletions</em> are handled by a more sophisticated labelling of the edges. In the example above, if we want to delete line $D$, we just need to make a change mapping the edge introduced by $c_0$ to a deleted edge, which we label by the name $c_1$ of the change that introduces it:</p>
<p><img src="https://pijul.org/img/repos-line-del.svg">
</p>
<p>From now on, we call the full edges <strong>alive</strong>, and the dashed ones <strong>dead</strong>.</p>
<p>We have just described the two basic kinds of actions in Pijul. There are no other. One kind adds vertices to the graph, along with “alive” edges around them, and the other kind maps an existing edge label onto a different one.
In order to fully described the system, I also need to mention that the edge labels are given by two parameters: their status (alive, deleted, and a few others related to multiple files and technical details explained below) and the change that introduced them.</p>
<h3 id="dependencies">Dependencies</h3>
<p>This scheme allows to defines dependencies between changes:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>If a change $c$ adds a vertex, we must have its <em>“context”</em>, i.e. the lines before and after it, hence the changes that introduced these lines are in the dependencies of $c$.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If a change $c$ deletes a vertex, or in other words maps an existing edge introduced by a change $d$, then $c$ must depend on $d$.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Of course, this is just the minimal set of dependencies needed to make sense of the text edits. Hooks and scripts may add extra language-dependent dependencies based on semantics.</p>
<h3 id="are-edge-labels-minimal">Are edge labels minimal?</h3>
<p>Our goals is to find the smallest possible system, both for reasons of mathematical aesthetics (why store useless stuff?) and the other one for performance. Therefore, one immediate question comes to mind: why even keep the change number on the edges?</p>
<p>In order to answer that question, suppose we don’t keep the labels, meaning that the maps happen between statuses only. Then, consider the following two situations:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Change inverses</strong></p>
<p>The first issue happens when two authors delete a line in parallel, and one of the authors reverts their change. Applying these changes yields the following diagram, where the two deletions get merged into one, and the inverse applies to both:</p>
 <p><img src="https://pijul.org/img/inverse2.svg">
 </p>
<p>However, this is not what we expect, since one of the authors explicitly reverted the deletion, while the other performed the same deletion in parallel.
By keeping the labels, this is what we get instead:</p>
 <p><img src="https://pijul.org/img/inverse3.svg">
 </p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Missing contexts</strong></p>
<p>For the sake of clarity, in the rest of this post, we name two users Alice (with pronouns “she/her”) and Bob (with pronouns “he/his”).</p>
<p>This situation, where Alice writes something in the middle of a paragraph $p$, while Bob deletes $p$ in parallel.
One issue here, is that the situation is not symmetric: when Bob applies Alice’s change, he can tell immediately that something is wrong, because the context of Alice’s edits is labelled as deleted in his repository.</p>
 <p><img src="https://pijul.org/img/known-vertices1.svg">
 </p>
<p>However, Alice’s situation is different: indeed, consider the case where instead of deleting $p$ <em>in parallel</em> of her changes, Bob deleted $p$ after applying Alice’s change. The edges deleted are exactly the same, but this is not a conflict, as shown in the following diagram:</p>
 <p><img src="https://pijul.org/img/known-vertices2.svg">
 </p>
<p>The situation is further complicated by the fact that this system doesn’t behave symmetrically with the contexts above and below the new line. Indeed, if Bob deleted the <em>down context</em> of the line (i.e. if he deleted line $C$) instead of the <em>up context</em> (line $B$), Alice could detect the conflict, since in that case, $C$ would have both an alive and a dead edge pointing to it ($C$ is called a “zombie vertex” internally), as shown in the following diagram:</p>
 <p><img src="https://pijul.org/img/known-vertices0.svg">
 </p>
<p>Keeping the change identifiers on each edge allows us to solve this. In Pijul 0.12, Bob would add the labels of all the edges around the deleted lines to the dependencies of his change. Then, Alice can tell whether Bob knows of her change before applying it. The changes are conflict if and only if Bob doesn’t know of the new lines.</p>
<p>However, this behaviour was counter-intuitive, <a href="https://discourse.pijul.org/t/why-these-patches-dont-commute/449">as noted by @tae</a>.</p>
<p>A finer analysis of what dependencies are led to a different behaviour in the new Pijul. Changes now have two different sets of …</p></li></ul></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://pijul.org/posts/2020-11-07-towards-1.0/">https://pijul.org/posts/2020-11-07-towards-1.0/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://pijul.org/posts/2020-11-07-towards-1.0/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25032956</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 09:24:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[On the Beauty of Python's ExitStack (2015)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 124 | Comments 29 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25032924">thread link</a>) | @polm23
<br/>
November 9, 2020 | https://www.rath.org/on-the-beauty-of-pythons-exitstack.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.rath.org/on-the-beauty-of-pythons-exitstack.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I believe Python's <a href="http://docs.python.org/3/library/contextlib.html#contextlib.ExitStack">ExitStack</a> feature does not get the recognition
it deserves. I think part of the reason for this is that its
documentation is somewhere deep down in the (already obscure)
<a href="http://docs.python.org/3/library/contextlib.html">contextlib</a> module because formally ExitStack is just one of many
available context managers for Python's <a href="http://docs.python.org/3/reference/compound_stmts.html#the-with-statement">with statement</a>. But
ExitStack deserves far more prominent notice than that. This post will
hopefully help with that.</p>
<p>So what makes ExitStack so important? In short, it's the best way to
handle allocation and release of external resources in Python.</p>
<div id="the-problem">
<h2>The Problem</h2>
<p>The main challenge with external resources is that you have to release
them when you don't need them anymore -- and in particular you must
not forget to do so in all the alternate execution paths that may be
entered in case of error conditions.</p>
<p>Most languages implement error conditions as "exceptions" that can be
"caught" and handled (Python, Java, C++), or as special return values
that you need to check to determine if an error occured (C, Rust,
Go). Typically, code that needs to acquire and release external
resources then looks like this:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>res1</span> <span>=</span> <span>acquire_resource_one</span><span>()</span>
<span>try</span><span>:</span>
    <span># do stuff with res1</span>
    <span>res2</span> <span>=</span> <span>acquire_resource_two</span><span>()</span>
    <span>try</span><span>:</span>
        <span># do stuff with res1 and res2</span>
    <span>finally</span><span>:</span>
        <span>release_resource</span><span>(</span><span>res2</span><span>)</span>
<span>finally</span><span>:</span>
   <span>release_resource</span><span>(</span><span>res1</span><span>)</span>
</pre></div>
<p>or, if the language doesn't have exceptions:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>res1</span> <span>=</span> <span>acquire_resource_one</span><span>();</span>
<span>if</span><span>(</span><span>res</span> <span>==</span> <span>-</span><span>1</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
   <span>retval</span> <span>=</span> <span>-</span><span>1</span><span>;</span>
   <span>goto</span> <span>error_out1</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
<span>// do stuff with res1</span>
<span>res2</span> <span>=</span> <span>acquire_resource_two</span><span>();</span>
<span>if</span><span>(</span><span>res</span> <span>==</span> <span>-</span><span>1</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
   <span>retval</span> <span>=</span> <span>-</span><span>2</span><span>;</span>
   <span>goto</span> <span>error_out2</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
<span>// do stuff with res1 and res2</span>
<span>retval</span> <span>=</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span> <span>// ok</span>

<span>error_out2</span><span>:</span>
  <span>release_resource</span><span>(</span><span>res2</span><span>);</span>
<span>error_out1</span><span>:</span>
  <span>release_resource</span><span>(</span><span>res1</span><span>);</span>
<span>return</span> <span>retval</span><span>;</span>
</pre></div>
<p>This approach has three big problems:</p>
<ol>
<li>The cleanup code is far away from the allocation code.</li>
<li>When the number of resources increases, indentation levels (or jump
labels) accumulate, making things hard to read.</li>
<li>Managing a dynamic number of resources this way is impossible.</li>
</ol>
<p>In Python, some of these issues can be alleviated by using the
<tt>with</tt> statement:</p>
<div><pre><span></span> <span>@contextlib.contextmanager</span>
 <span>def</span> <span>my_resource</span><span>(</span><span>id_</span><span>):</span>
     <span>res</span> <span>=</span> <span>acquire_resource</span><span>(</span><span>id_</span><span>)</span>
     <span>try</span><span>:</span>
         <span>yield</span> <span>res</span>
     <span>finally</span><span>:</span>
         <span>release_source</span><span>(</span><span>res</span><span>)</span>

<span>with</span> <span>my_resource</span><span>(</span><span>RES_ONE</span><span>)</span> <span>as</span> <span>res1</span><span>,</span> \
   <span>my_resource</span><span>(</span><span>RES_TWO</span><span>)</span> <span>as</span> <span>res2</span><span>:</span>
    <span># do stuff with res1</span>
    <span># do stuff with res1 and res2</span>
</pre></div>
<p>However, this solution is far from optimal: you need to implement
resource-specific context managers (note that in the above example we
silently assumed that both resources can be acquired by the same
function), you can get rid of extra indentation only if you allocate
all the resources at the same time and live with an ugly continuation
line (no parenthesis allowed in this context), and you still need to
know the number of required resources ahead of time.</p>
<p>Over in the world of exception-less programming languages (no pun
intended), <a href="http://www.golang.org/">Go</a> has developed a different remedy: the <a href="http://golang.org/ref/spec#Defer_statement">defer statement</a>
defers execution of an expression until the enclosing
function returns. Using <tt>defer</tt>, the above example can be written
as:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>res1</span> <span>=</span> <span>acquire_resource_one</span><span>()</span>
<span>if</span><span>(</span><span>res</span> <span>==</span> <span>NULL</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>-</span><span>1</span>
<span>}</span>
<span>defer</span> <span>release_resource</span><span>(</span><span>res1</span><span>)</span>
<span>// do stuff with res1</span>
<span>res2</span> <span>=</span> <span>acquire_resource_two</span><span>()</span>
<span>if</span><span>(</span><span>res</span> <span>==</span> <span>NULL</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>-</span><span>2</span>
<span>}</span>
<span>defer</span> <span>release_resource</span><span>(</span><span>res2</span><span>)</span>
<span>// do stuff with res1 and res2</span>
<span>return</span> <span>0</span>
</pre></div>
<p>This is pretty nice: allocation and cleanup are kept close together,
no extra indentation or jump labels are required, and converting this
to a loop that dynamically acquires multiple resources would be
straightforward. But there are still some drawbacks:</p>
<ul>
<li>To control when exactly a group of resources is getting released you
have to factor out into separate functions all parts of code that
access the respective resources.</li>
<li>You cannot "cancel" a deferred expression, so there is no way to
e.g. return a resource to the caller if no error occured.</li>
<li>There is no way to handle errors from the cleanup functions.</li>
<li><tt>defer</tt> is available in Go, but not in Python.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div id="exitstack-to-the-rescue">
<h2>ExitStack to the rescue</h2>
<p><a href="http://docs.python.org/3/library/contextlib.html#contextlib.ExitStack">ExitStack</a> fixes all of the above issues, and adds some benefits on
top of it. An ExitStack is (as the name suggests) a stack of clean-up
functions. Adding a callback to the stack is the equivalent of calling
Go's <tt>defer</tt> statement. However, clean-up functions are not executed
when the function returns, but when execution leaves the <tt>with</tt>
block - and until then, the stack can also be emptied again.</p>
<p>Finally, clean-up functions itself may raise exceptions without
affecting execution of other clean-up functions. Even if multiple
clean-ups raise exceptions, you are will get a usable stacktrace.</p>
<p>Here's how to acquire multiple resources:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>with</span> <span>ExitStack</span><span>()</span> <span>as</span> <span>cm</span><span>:</span>
    <span>res1</span> <span>=</span> <span>acquire_resource_one</span><span>()</span>
    <span>cm</span><span>.</span><span>callback</span><span>(</span><span>release_resource</span><span>,</span> <span>res1</span><span>)</span>
    <span># do stuff with res1</span>
    <span>res2</span> <span>=</span> <span>acquire_resource_two</span><span>()</span>
    <span>cm</span><span>.</span><span>callback</span><span>(</span><span>release_resource</span><span>,</span> <span>res2</span><span>)</span>
    <span># do stuff with res1 and res2</span>
</pre></div>
<p>Note that</p>
<ul>
<li>acquisition and release are close to each other</li>
<li>there's no extra indentation,</li>
<li>the pattern and it easily scales up to many resources (including a
dynamic number that's acquired in a loop)</li>
</ul>
<p>If there already is a context manager for your resource, there's also
a shortcut function:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>with</span> <span>ExitStack</span><span>()</span> <span>as</span> <span>cm</span><span>:</span>
    <span>res1</span> <span>=</span> <span>cm</span><span>.</span><span>enter</span><span>(</span><span>open</span><span>(</span><span>'first_file'</span><span>,</span> <span>'r'</span><span>))</span>
    <span># do stuff with res1</span>
    <span>res2</span> <span>=</span> <span>cm</span><span>.</span><span>enter</span><span>(</span><span>open</span><span>(</span><span>'second_file'</span><span>,</span> <span>'r'</span><span>))</span>
    <span># do stuff with res1 and res2</span>
</pre></div>
<p>To open a bunch of files and return them to the caller (without
leaking already opened files if a subsequent open fails):</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>def</span> <span>open_files</span><span>(</span><span>filelist</span><span>):</span>
    <span>fhs</span> <span>=</span> <span>[]</span>
    <span>with</span> <span>ExitStack</span><span>()</span> <span>as</span> <span>cm</span><span>:</span>
        <span>for</span> <span>name</span> <span>in</span> <span>filelist</span><span>:</span>
            <span>fhs</span><span>.</span><span>append</span><span>(</span><span>cm</span><span>.</span><span>enter</span><span>(</span><span>open</span><span>(</span><span>name</span><span>,</span> <span>'r'</span><span>)))</span>
        <span>cm</span><span>.</span><span>pop_all</span><span>()</span>
        <span>return</span> <span>fhs</span>
</pre></div>
<p>Disclaimer: the <a href="https://bugs.python.org/issue13585">original idea for ExitStack</a> came from me.</p>
</div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.rath.org/on-the-beauty-of-pythons-exitstack.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25032924</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 09:19:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Structured Concurrency]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 44 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25032133">thread link</a>) | @ingve
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://ericniebler.com/2020/11/08/structured-concurrency/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ericniebler.com/2020/11/08/structured-concurrency/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<p>TL;DR: <strong>“Structured concurrency” refers to a way to structure async computations so that child operations are guaranteed to complete before their parents, just the way a function is guaranteed to complete before its caller.</strong> This sounds simple and boring, but in C++ it’s anything but. Structured concurrency — most notably, C++20 coroutines — has profound implications for the correctness and the simplicity of async architecture. It brings the <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/cpp/cpp/welcome-back-to-cpp-modern-cpp?view=msvc-160">Modern C++ style</a> to our async programs by making async lifetimes correspond to ordinary C++ lexical scopes, eliminating the need for reference counting to manage object lifetime.</p>
<h2>Structured Programming and C++</h2>
<p>Back in the 1950’s, the nascent computing industry discovered structured programming: that high-level programming languages with lexical scopes, control structures, and subroutines resulted in programs that were far easier to read, write, and maintain than programming at the assembly level with test-and-jump instructions and <code>goto</code>. The advance was such a quantum leap that nobody talks about structured programming anymore; it’s just “programming”.</p>
<p>C++, more so than any other language, leverages structured programming to the hilt. The semantics of object lifetime mirror — and are tied to — the strict nesting of scopes; i.e., the <em>structure</em> of your code. Function activations nest, scopes nest, and object lifetimes nest. Objects’ lifetimes end with a scope’s closing curly brace, and objects are destroyed in the reverse order of their construction to preserve the strict nesting.</p>
<p>The Modern C++ programming style is built on this structured foundation. Objects have <em>value semantics</em> — they behave like the ints — and resources are cleaned up in destructors deterministically, which guarantees structurally that resources aren’t used after their lifetimes have ended. This is <em>very</em> important.</p>
<p>When we abandon this strict nesting of scopes and lifetimes — say, when we reference count an object on the heap, or when we use the singleton pattern — we are fighting against the strengths of the language rather than working with them.</p>
<h2>The Trouble With Threads</h2>
<p>Writing correct programs in the presence of concurrency is far more difficult than in single-threaded code. There are lots of reasons for this. One reason is that threads, like singletons and dynamically allocated objects, scoff at your puny nested scopes. Although you can use the Modern C++ style <em>within</em> a thread, when logic and lifetimes are scattered across threads, the hierarchical structure of your program is lost. The tools we use to manage complexity in single-threaded code — in particular, nested lifetimes tied to nested scopes — simply don’t translate to async code.</p>
<p>To see what I mean, let’s look at what happens when we take a simple synchronous function and make it asynchronous.</p>
<pre>void computeResult(State &amp; s);

int doThing() {
  State s;
  computeResult(s);
  return s.result;
}
</pre>
<p><code>doThing()</code> is simple enough. It declares some local state, calls a helper, then returns some result. Now imagine that we want to make both functions async, maybe because they take too long. No problem, let’s use Boost futures, which support continuation chaining:</p>
<pre>boost::future&lt;void&gt; computeResult(State &amp; s);

boost::future&lt;int&gt; doThing() {
  State s;
  auto fut = computeResult(s);
  return fut.then(
    [&amp;](auto&amp;&amp;) { return s.result; }); // OOPS
}
</pre>
<p>If you’ve programmed with futures before, you’re probably screaming, <em>“Nooooo!”</em> The <code>.then()</code> on the last line queues up some work to run after <code>computeResult()</code> completes. <code>doThing()</code> then returns the resulting future. The trouble is, when <code>doThing()</code> returns, the lifetime of the <code>State</code> object ends, <em>and the continuation is still referencing it</em>. That is now a dangling reference, and will likely cause a crash.</p>
<p>What has gone wrong? Futures let us compute with results that aren’t available yet, and the Boost flavor lets us chain continuations. But the continuation is a separate function with a separate scope. We often need to share data across those separate scopes. No more tidy nested scopes, no more nested lifetimes. We have to manage the lifetime of the state manually, something like this:</p>
<pre>boost::future&lt;void&gt;
computeResult(shared_ptr&lt;State&gt; s); // addref
                                    // the state

boost::future&lt;int&gt; doThing() {
  auto s = std::make_shared&lt;State&gt;();
  auto fut = computeResult(s);
  return fut.then(
    [s](auto&amp;&amp;) { return s.result; }); // addref
                                       // the state
}
</pre>
<p>Since both async operations refer to the state, they both need to share responsibility to keep it alive.</p>
<p>Another way to think about this is: <em>what is the lifetime of this asynchronous computation?</em> It starts when <code>doThing()</code> is called, but it doesn’t end until the continuation — the lambda passed to <code>future.then()</code> — returns. <em>There is no lexical scope that corresponds to that lifetime.</em> And that is the source of our woes.</p>
<h2>Unstructured Concurrency</h2>
<p>The story gets more complicated yet when we consider executors. Executors are handles to executions contexts that let you schedule work onto, say, a thread or thread pool. Many codebases have some notion of an executor, and some let you schedule things with a delay or with some other policy. This lets us do cool things, like move a computation from an IO thread pool to a CPU thread pool, or retry an async operation with a delay. Handy, but like <code>goto</code> it is a very low-level control structure that tends to obfuscate rather than clarify.</p>
<p>For instance, I recently came across an algorithm that uses executors and callbacks (called Listeners here) that retries the async allocation of some resource. Below is a greatly abridged version. It is described after the break.</p>
<pre>// This is a continuation that gets invoked when
// the async operation completes:
struct Manager::Listener : ListenerInterface {
  shared_ptr&lt;Manager&gt; manager_;
  executor executor_;
  size_t retriesCount_;

  void onSucceeded() override {
    /* ...yay, allocation succeeded... */
  }
  void onFailed() override {
    // When the allocation fails, post a retry
    // to the executor with a delay
    auto alloc = [manager = manager_]() {
      manager-&gt;allocate();
    };
    // Run "alloc" at some point in the future:
    executor_.execute_after(
      alloc, 10ms * (1 &lt;&lt; retriesCount_));
  }
};

// Try asynchronously allocating some resource
// with the above class as a continuation
void Manager::allocate() {
  // Have we already tried too many times?
  if (retriesCount_ &gt; kMaxRetries) {
    /* ...notify any observers that we failed */
    return;
  }

  // Try once more:
  ++retriesCount_;
  allocator_.doAllocate(
    make_shared&lt;Listener&gt;(
      shared_from_this(),
      executor_,
      retriesCount_));
}
</pre>
<p>The <code>allocate()</code> member function first checks to see if the operation has already been retried too many times. If not it calls a helper <code>doAllocate()</code> function, passing in a callback to be notified on either success or failure. On failure, the handler posts deferred work to the executor, which will call <code>allocate()</code> back, thus retrying the allocation with a delay.</p>
<p>This is a heavily stateful and rather circuitous async algorithm. The logic spans many functions and several objects, and the control and data flow is not obvious. Note the intricate ref-counting dance necessary to keep the objects alive. Posting the work to an executor makes it even harder. Executors in this code have no notion of continuations, so errors that happen during task execution have nowhere to go. The <code>allocate()</code> function can’t signal an error by throwing an exception if it wants any part of the program to be able to recover from the error. Error handling must be done manually and out-of-band. Ditto if we wanted to support cancellation.</p>
<p>This is <strong>unstructured concurrency</strong>: we queue up async operations in an <em>ad hoc</em> fashion; we chain dependent work, use continuations or “strand” executors to enforce sequential consistency; and we use strong and weak reference counts to keep data alive until we are certain it’s no longer needed. There is no formal notion of task A being a child of task B, no way to enforce that child tasks complete before their parents, and no one place in the code that we can point to and say, “Here is the algorithm.”</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>If you don’t mind the analogy, the hops through the executor are a bit like <code>goto</code> statements that are non-local in both time and space: “Jump to this point in the program, <em>X</em> milliseconds from now, on this particular thread.”</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>That non-local discontinuity makes it hard to reason about correctness and efficiency. Scale unstructured concurrency up to whole programs handling lots of concurrent real-time events, and the incidental complexity of manually handling out-of-band asynchronous control and data flow, controlling concurrent access to shared state, and managing object lifetime becomes overwhelming.</p>
<h2>Structured Concurrency</h2>
<p>Recall that in the early days of computing, unstructured programming styles rapidly gave way to structured styles. With the addition of coroutines to C++, we are seeing a similar phase shift happening today to our asynchronous code. If we were to rewrite the above retry algorithm in terms of coroutines (using Lewis Baker’s popular <a href="https://github.com/lewissbaker/cppcoro">cppcoro</a> library), it might look something like this:</p>
<pre>// Try asynchronously allocating some resource
// with retry:
cppcoro::task&lt;&gt; Manager::allocate() {
  // Retry the allocation up to kMaxRetries
  // times:
  for (int retriesCount = 1;
       retriesCount &lt;= kMaxRetries;
       ++retriesCount) {
    try {
      co_await allocator_.doAllocate();
      co_return; // success!
    } catch (...) {}

    // Oops, it failed. Yield the thread for a
    // bit and then retry:
    co_await scheduler_.schedule_after(
      10ms * (1 &lt;&lt; retriesCount));
  }

  // Error, too many retries
  throw std::runtime_error(
    "Resource allocation retry count exceeded.");
}
</pre>
<blockquote>
<p>Aside: This replaces the <code>executor_</code> with a <code>scheduler_</code> that implements cppcoro’s <a href="https://github.com/lewissbaker/cppcoro#delayedscheduler-concept">DelayedScheduler</a> concept.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Let’s …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://ericniebler.com/2020/11/08/structured-concurrency/">https://ericniebler.com/2020/11/08/structured-concurrency/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ericniebler.com/2020/11/08/structured-concurrency/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25032133</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 07:15:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I'm going to experiment by being Blind and Alone for 24 Hours]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 82 | Comments 75 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25031774">thread link</a>) | @Osiris30
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://dormin.org/2020/11/08/the-blind-alone-and-confused-for-24-hours-challenge/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dormin.org/2020/11/08/the-blind-alone-and-confused-for-24-hours-challenge/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-896">

	
	<!-- .entry-header -->


			<div>

			
<figure><img data-attachment-id="901" data-permalink="https://dormin.org/bird-box/" data-orig-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/bird-box.jpg" data-orig-size="2000,1050" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="bird-box" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/bird-box.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/bird-box.jpg?w=760" src="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/bird-box.jpg?w=1024" alt="" srcset="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/bird-box.jpg?w=1024 1024w, https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/bird-box.jpg?w=150 150w, https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/bird-box.jpg?w=300 300w, https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/bird-box.jpg?w=768 768w, https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/bird-box.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"></figure>



<p>For 24 hours I will be blind and alone in my apartment. I eventually want to try being blind for a week, but I’ll need seven days with no other obligations, and I won’t have that for a while. For now, I’ll suffice with a smaller-scale experiments with a few extra provisions for added difficulty.</p>







<ol type="1"><li>I must leave my blindfold on for 24 hours.<ul><li>If I remove the blindfold, I have failed the experiment</li><li>If the blindfold falls off or I can get partial sight, I have failed the experiment.</li><li>I am only allowed to readjust my blindfold if I can see light.</li></ul></li><li>I must not be in contact with any other people for 24 hours.<ul><li>I cannot answer my phone or any other messaging system.</li><li>I cannot receive in-person visitors.</li><li>If someone knocks at the door, I cannot answer verbally or physically.</li></ul></li><li>I will set an alarm for 24 hours. I cannot set any other alarms or use any other means to ascertain the time.<ul><li>It is up to me to keep my phone charged so the alarm goes off.</li></ul></li><li>I cannot leave my apartment.</li></ol>











<p>I have no good reason. I just want to see if I am capable of doing it and what will happen. Some things I’m curious about:</p>



<ul><li>Do I have the willpower to get through the experiment?</li><li>Will I become disoriented from losing all sense of time?</li><li>Will I be able to stave off boredom with podcasts, audiobooks, and music on my phone?</li><li>Will I enter some sort of meditative state due to a lack of sensory input?</li><li><a href="https://www.discovermagazine.com/the-sciences/scientists-made-people-wear-blindfolds-for-4-days-the-resulting-hallucinations-were-incredible">Will I hallucinate</a>?</li><li>Will my non-sight senses heighten?</li><li>Will I hurt myself by falling or banging into something?</li><li>Will I sleep?</li><li>Will I eat? Is consuming caffeine a good idea (for entertainment) or a bad idea (energy with no direction)?</li><li>Will this experience make me more interested in being blind for a week? Or less?</li></ul>



<figure><img src="https://digitalimpact.io/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Blind.png" alt="Modern CEOs Are Blindfolded - Digital Impact"></figure>







<p>Attempt One started at 10:30 AM and failed at 1:13 PM. I purposefully took off my blindfold because I was worried that my multiple failures to input my Iphone’s password had resulted in a permanent lock or data wipe. But the password screen was just locked for a minute and all was well.</p>



<p>Given that I failed in the early afternoon, I considered restarting the experiment on another day in the morning. But I had already carved out a 24 hour period when I wouldn’t do any work or be disturbed, and it might have been a week or two longer before I got that opportunity again.</p>



<p>So I checked my messages, briefly went on Reddit, and then restarted.</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="903" data-permalink="https://dormin.org/t86752/" data-orig-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blindfold-2.jpg" data-orig-size="521,610" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;CSA Images \/ CSA Images&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;Blindfolded Woman&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;\u00a9 CSA Images \/ CSA Images&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;T86752&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="T86752" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blindfold-2.jpg?w=256" data-large-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blindfold-2.jpg?w=521" src="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blindfold-2.jpg?w=521" alt="" srcset="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blindfold-2.jpg 521w, https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blindfold-2.jpg?w=128 128w, https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blindfold-2.jpg?w=256 256w" sizes="(max-width: 521px) 100vw, 521px"></figure></div>







<p>Attempt Two was successful. I put on my blindfold at 1:23 PM on Thursday, November 5, 2020. I removed it at 1:28 PM on Friday, November 6.</p>



<p>It was an… interesting experience. I don’t recommend it, but I’m glad I did it. I’m not sure where to begin in describing it, especially since I couldn’t take notes, and part of the challenge was being confused. But I’ll do my best to break down the experience.</p>



<div><figure><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0818/3417/products/Les_Sublimes_Cashmere_Scarf_Dark_Blue_packshot_2048x.jpg?v=1539973736" alt="Large Cashmere Scarf in Dark Blue | Les Sublimes" width="427" height="427"></figure></div>



<h2><strong><span>Blindfold</span></strong></h2>



<p>To simulate blindness, I used a dark blue scarf as a blindfold. One layer wasn’t quite dark enough, so I folded it in half for extra light defense.</p>



<p>With the blindfold securely on, my vision was the same whether my eyes were open or closed. I kept my eyes closed 99.9% of the time since it was usually more comfortable and helped limit light. I occasionally opened my eyes to check the brightness level and to… I guess you could call it <em>stretch my eyelids.</em> They don’t feel good if you leave them closed for too long.</p>



<p>I couldn’t get a perfect scarf seal around my eyes, so sometimes when I tilted my head back while sitting I noticed a little light come into the bottom of my vision. To limit this, I often pinched the scarf around my nose in that position. But many/most blind people can see some light anyway, so I don’t think this was a significant violation of the experiment.</p>



<p>My eyes got quite dry under the scarf, so I applied moisturizer to this lids and sockets four or five times. I wanted to use eyedrops too, but there was no way to do so without failing the experiment.</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="906" data-permalink="https://dormin.org/image/" data-orig-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/image.jpeg" data-orig-size="225,225" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="image" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/image.jpeg?w=225" data-large-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/image.jpeg?w=225" src="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/image.jpeg?w=225" alt="BLACK N BLACK - #blackouttuesday ✊🏻✊🏼✊🏽✊🏾✊🏿 | Facebook" width="786" height="786" srcset="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/image.jpeg 225w, https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/image.jpeg?w=150 150w" sizes="(max-width: 786px) 100vw, 786px"></figure>



<h2><strong><span>Blindness</span></strong></h2>



<p>Initially, everything was black, but as the day went on and the sun went down, I could tell it was nighttime even through two layers of scarf and my eyelids. I’m not sure if I could tell because my eyes had adjusted to become extremely sensitive to light, or if there were other subtle signals (ie. noises, air temperature, circadian rhythms, etc.) which my body picked up on. As evidence of the latter, I could not see any difference between the tv being on or off, nor the refrigerator being opened or closed, even when I was sitting right in front of either.</p>



<p>What I saw depended on how I applied my focus. If I did focus on my vision, I’d see the typical blackness you get from closing your eyes, but it was never perfectly black nor uniform; there was always some odd movement and occasional coloring (whiteness, pale blue, or sometimes red). The most common distortions were a swirling or flowing whiteness, sort of like cream in coffee. I hoped that being blindfolded for so long would make the distortions more extreme, but for the most part it looked no different than what you’d see if you closed your eyes right now for ten minutes.</p>



<p>There was one exception. It must have been about 20+ hours into the experiment, and my eyes were itching, so I rubbed both of them at the same time over the scarf. If you rub your closed eyes and focus on your sight any time you can see some weird stuff, but this was far more extreme than usual. I remember my entire vision filling up with white bubbles which then broke and briefly returned to black. Then white lightning bolt shapes stretched across my sight, expanded to make my vision purely white, and then slowly faded back to black. The strangest thing about it was the <em>brightness</em>. I literally felt like I was staring into lights despite being blindfolded in a dark room. Unfortunately, it only lasted about 30 seconds, but my heart was racing.</p>



<p>More notable than what I saw was what I didn’t see. By default, I was lost in thought and I focused on nothing. In such a state, I didn’t even register my vision or notice the darkness. I <em>think</em> this made my imagination and mental visualization more acute. On occasion, I’d be deep in thought and I’d get the <em>brightness</em> sensation again because I’d be mentally picturing something so vividly that the inevitable return to darkness felt like shutting off the lights in my brain. I’ll explain more about this in the <strong>Three Phases</strong> section.</p>



<p>Sadly, I did not hallucinate, or at least not as far as I could tell.</p>



<figure><img src="https://i1.wp.com/www.intelligentliving.co/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/sloth-sleeping.jpg?fit=1024%2C698&amp;ssl=1" alt="Fighting Bacteria With Sloth Fur"></figure>



<h2><strong><span>Energy</span></strong></h2>



<p>This was the most surprising aspect of the experiment.</p>



<p>I read that <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Health/story?id=117902&amp;page=1#:~:text=Without%20light%20cues%20that%20the,as%20a%20result%2C%20researchers%20say.">blind people have trouble getting to sleep</a> because they don’t access any/enough light for their circadian rhythms. I seem to have the exact opposite problem. Without light, my body always thinks it’s time to sleep and has trouble doing anything else. Throughout most of the experiment, I felt extremely lethargic, lazy, and had to fight to stay awake.</p>



<p>I started my first failed experiment attempt at 10:30 AM. I had gotten 7.5 solid hours of sleep, I hadn’t done anything tiring the previous day, and I generally felt fine. Then I put on my blindfold, and within thirty minutes I was nodding off. I semi-slept for two hours before deciding to get an energy drink to get myself out of the funk. That worked, but as soon as it wore off, I was back in semi-sleep mode.</p>



<p>Even when I was firmly awake, I generally felt weak and lethargic. Movement around the apartment was annoying of course, but made so much more difficult by my energy levels. I ended up lying perfectly still in my comfy computer chair with my feet on a table 95% of the time. That is, when I wasn’t lying in bed.</p>



<p>On the other hand, when I removed my blindfold after 24 hours, I experienced a <em>burst</em> of energy. Seriously, it was like I had downed a double shot of espresso. It was like a switch had been flicked. The haziness and cobwebs were gone in an instant, and I felt the energy coursing through my body. I guess light has a big impact on me.</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="908" data-permalink="https://dormin.org/blind-man-2/" data-orig-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blind-man-2.jpg" data-orig-size="615,479" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1604789422&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="blind-man-2" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blind-man-2.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blind-man-2.jpg?w=615" src="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blind-man-2.jpg?w=615" alt="" srcset="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blind-man-2.jpg 615w, https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blind-man-2.jpg?w=150 150w, https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blind-man-2.jpg?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 615px) 100vw, 615px"></figure></div>



<h2><strong><span>Movement</span></strong></h2>



<p>I moved exactly how you’d expect… clumsily.</p>



<p>For the most part, I slowly walked around my apartment with a hand out to feel for walls and edges. Sometimes I’d get lazy and crawl just so it was easier. I know my apartment well enough that it wasn’t hard to get around, but every once in awhile I’d lose track of where I was and would be left slowly swinging my arm around searching for anything. It’s not a pleasant sensation.</p>



<p>Before the experiment, I had planned to pace around for fun, or maybe even do some exercise with the free time. But the confusion and especially the lethargy stopped all that. I just sat in my chair and didn’t move unless I needed to get a drink, go to the bathroom, or sleep.</p>



<p>I kind of wish I had done the experiment in an unfamiliar environment to add to the movement challenge, but oh well.</p>



<div><figure><img src="https://secure.img1-fg.wfcdn.com/im/99629273/compr-r85/1167/116715839/dual-flush-elongated-one-piece-toilet-seat-included.jpg" alt="DeerValley Dual-Flush Elongated One-Piece Toilet (Seat Included) &amp; Reviews  | Wayfair" width="729" height="729"></figure></div>



<h2><strong><span>Necessities</span></strong></h2>



<p>For food, I ate a big lunch at 10 AM before the experiment and then munched on dark chocolate throughout the night. I felt the heavy lethargy well before the lack of calories was an issue. I probably should have put some prepackaged meals in my fridge to eat, but I was worried about making a mess and not being able to clean up. Do I want ants? Because that’s how I get ants.</p>



<p>For drinks, I could manage to get to the kitchen and fill a cup with water when I needed to. I never took a full cup back to my chair just in case I knocked it over (clean up would be a nightmare). I also had some diet coke to serve as entertainment and put a little caffeine in me.</p>



<p>For the bathroom, I (a man) peed sitting down. I’m not ashamed to admit it.</p>



<div><figure><img src="https://imgaz2.staticbg.com/thumb/large/oaupload/banggood/images/F2/09/b934b522-e3e3-491d-b758-d0b92c259f0c.jpg" alt="Novel surreal melting distorted wall clock surrealist salvador dali style  wall clock amazing home decoration gift Sale - Banggood.com" width="802" height="801"></figure></div>



<h2><strong><span>Time</span></strong></h2>



<p>As part of the experiment, I never knew what time it was. This was intended to confuse me throughout the 24 hours, and it did, but it may have helped too. With no sense of time, it was easy to sit back and not think about it. Time drifted by and I existed. That was that.</p>



<p>I actually did ask Siri for the time once… it was late in the experiment, and it felt like I had put on the blindfold forever ago. As you’d expect, …</p></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://dormin.org/2020/11/08/the-blind-alone-and-confused-for-24-hours-challenge/">https://dormin.org/2020/11/08/the-blind-alone-and-confused-for-24-hours-challenge/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dormin.org/2020/11/08/the-blind-alone-and-confused-for-24-hours-challenge/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25031774</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 05:39:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Start with pen and paper]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 159 | Comments 86 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25031483">thread link</a>) | @sethetter
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://sethetter.com/posts/start-with-pen-and-paper/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://sethetter.com/posts/start-with-pen-and-paper/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">
            


<article>
    
    <section>
        <p>tl;dr — If you feel unfocused, grab a pen and paper and start writing your thoughts down.</p>
<p>Is there a question you are stuck on? A ambiguous goal you're trying to accomplish? Maybe a task you know you need to do but from which you keep getting distracted?</p>
<p><strong>Nothing will provide focus like pen and paper.</strong></p>
<p>It's all too easy these days to have a clear intention only to be sidetracked by the whirlpool of apps and services clawing for our attention on our devices.</p>
<p>It helps to take the time to groom our notification settings for importance and timeliness, but a digital device that we can use to complete nearly any task will never stand up to pen and paper in terms of it's ability to provide focus.</p>
<p>My thoughts are a constant whirlwind, I'm certainly more distractible than most, and interacting with nearly any online service only fuels that fire. So how can I get anything done if I'm unable to control my focus?</p>
<p><strong>Pen and paper.</strong> Whenever I catch myself stuck in the whirlpool, feeling not-great because I <em>know</em> I'm not doing what I want to be doing, or what I should be doing, I step away, grab pen and paper, and start writing.</p>
<p>The simple act of writing can focus my thoughts and attention in a way that nothing else can. Free from distractions, just a canvas to pour my thoughts into, and turn them into something with a sense of direction and purpose.</p>
<p>Writing is like a superpower to me. If there's any task I want to accomplish, the first step is always to write it down. Anytime I need to recenter myself on that task, I simply return to paper.</p>
<p>Throughout my life I've found that the simplest solutions are often the most powerful. So far I've found no simpler solution to start tackling any problem than to simply write it down, and then keep on writing.</p>

    </section>
</article>


        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://sethetter.com/posts/start-with-pen-and-paper/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25031483</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 04:33:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Cool Machine Learning Books]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 238 | Comments 15 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25031455">thread link</a>) | @ridddle
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | http://matpalm.com/blog/cool_machine_learning_books/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://matpalm.com/blog/cool_machine_learning_books/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    
  <p>awhile ago i posted
   <a href="http://matpalm.com/blog/2010/08/06/my-list-of-cool-machine-learning-books/">my list of cool machine learning books</a>,
   but it's been awhile so it's probably time to update it...
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/mml.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://mml-book.github.io/">Mathematics for Machine Learning</a>
   by Marc Peter Deisenroth, A. Aldo Faisal &amp; Cheng Soon Ong.</b>
</p>
<p>this is my personal favorite book on the general math required for machine learning,
   the way things are described really resonate with me.
   available as a free pdf but i got a paper copy to support the authors after reading the
   first half.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/laalfd.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="http://math.mit.edu/~gs/learningfromdata/">Linear Algebra and Learning from Data</a>
   by Gilbert Strang.</b>
</p>
<p>this is gilbert's most recent work. it's really great, he's such a good teacher, and
   <a href="https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/mathematics/18-065-matrix-methods-in-data-analysis-signal-processing-and-machine-learning-spring-2018/">his freely available lectures</a>
   are even better. it's a shorter text than his other classic intro below with
   more of a focus on how things are connected to modern machine learning techniques.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/itla.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://math.mit.edu/~gs/linearalgebra/">Introduction to Linear Algebra</a>
   by Gilbert Strang.</b>
</p>
<p>this was my favorite linear algebra book for a long time before his 'learning from
   data' came out. this is a larger book with a more comprehensive view of linear algebra.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/ts.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://greenteapress.com/wp/think-stats-2e/">Think Stats: Probability and Statistics for Programmers</a> by Allen Downey.</b>
</p>
<p>this book focuses on practical computation methods for probability and statistics.
   i got a lot out of working through this one.
   it's all in python and available for free.
   ( exciting update! as part of writing this post i've discovered there's a new edition
   to read!)
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/dbda.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://sites.google.com/site/doingbayesiandataanalysis/">Doing Bayesian Data Analysis</a>
   by John Kruscgke</b>
</p>
<p>on the bayesian side of things this is the book i've most enjoyed working through.
   i've only got the first edition which was R and
   <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OpenBUGS">BUGS</a> but i see
   the second edition is R,
   <a href="http://mcmc-jags.sourceforge.net/">JAGS</a> and
   <a href="https://mc-stan.org/">Stan</a>.
   it'd be fun i'm sure to work through it doing
   everything in <a href="https://github.com/pyro-ppl/numpyro">numpyro</a>. i might do that in all
   my free time. haha. "free time" hahaha. sob.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/eosl.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://web.stanford.edu/~hastie/ElemStatLearn/">The Elements of Statistical Learning</a>
   by Hastie, Tibshirani and Friedman</b>
</p>
<p>this is still one of the most amazing fundamental machine learning books i've ever had.
   in fact i've purchased this book <em>twice</em> and given it away both times :/ i might buy another
   copy some time soon, even though it's been freely available to download for ages. an
   amazing piece of work.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/pgm.jpg"></p>
<p><b>
   <a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/probabilistic-graphical-models">Probabilistic Graphical Models</a>
   by Daphne Koller &amp; Nir Friedman</b>
</p>
<p>this is an epic textbook that i'd love to understand better. i've read a couple of sections in
   detail but not the entire tome yet.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/praml.jpg"></p>
<p><b>
   <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/people/cmbishop/prml-book/">Pattern Recognition and Machine Learning</a>
   by Christopher Bishop</b>
</p>
<p>this is probably the best overall machine learning text book i've ever read. such a beautiful book
   and <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/uploads/prod/2006/01/Bishop-Pattern-Recognition-and-Machine-Learning-2006.pdf">the pdf is FREE FOR DOWNLOAD!!!</a>
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/mlapp.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/machine-learning-1">Machine Learning: A Probabilistic Perspective</a> by Kevin Murphy</b>
</p>
<p>this is my second favorite general theory text on machine learning.
   i got kevin to sign my copy when he was passing my desk once but
   someone borrowed it and never gave it back :(
   so if you see a copy with my name on the spine let me know!
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/homl.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/hands-on-machine-learning/9781492032632/">Hands-On Machine Learning with Scikit-Learn, Keras, and TensorFlow</a> by Aurélien Géron</b>
</p>
<p>this is the book i point most people to when they are interested in getting up
   to speed with modern applied machine learning without too much concern for the
   theory. it's very up to date (as much as a book can be) with the latest libraries
   and, most importantly, provides a good overview of not just neural stuff but fundamental
   <a href="https://scikit-learn.org/stable/">scikit-learn</a> as well.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/mle.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="http://www.mlebook.com/wiki/doku.php">Machine Learning Engineering</a> by Andriy Burkov</b>
</p>
<p>a great book focussing on the operations side of running a machine learning system. i'm a bit
   under half way through the free online version and very likely to buy a physical copy to finish
   it and support the author. great stuff and, in many ways, a more impactful book than any of
   the theory books here.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/itdm.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://www-users.cs.umn.edu/~kumar001/dmbook/index.php">Introduction to Data Mining</a>
   by Pang-Ning Tan, Michael Steinbach &amp; Vipin Kumar</b>
</p>
<p>this is another one that was also on my list from ten years ago and though it's section
   on neural networks is a bit of chuckle these days there is still a bunch of really
   great fundamental stuff in this book. very practical and easy to digest. i also see there's
   a second edition now. i reckon this would compliment the "hands on" book above very well.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/salp.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://web.stanford.edu/~jurafsky/slp3/">Speech and Language Processing</a>
   by Dan Jurafsky &amp; James Martin</b>
</p>
<p>still the best overview of NLP there is (IMHO). can't wait to read the 3rd edition which
   apparently will cover more modern stuff (e.g. transformers) but until then, for the
   love of god though, please don't be one of those "this entire book is
   irrelevant now! just fine tune BERT" people :/
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/no.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://link.springer.com/book/10.1007/978-0-387-40065-5">Numerical Optimization</a>
   by Jorge NocedalStephen J. Wright</b>
</p>
<p>this book is super hard core and maybe more an operations
   research book than machine learning. though i've not read it cover to cover the
   couple of bits i've worked through really taught me a lot. i'd love to understand
   the stuff in this text better; it's so so fundamental to machine learning (and more)
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/dl.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://www.deeplearningbook.org/">Deep Learning</a>
   by Ian Goodfellow</b>
</p>
<p>writing a book specifically on deep learning is very dangerous since things move so fast but
   if anyone can do it, ian can... i think ian's approach to explaining neural networks
   from the ground up is one of my favorites. i got the first edition hardback but it's free to
   download from the website.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/pr.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/probabilistic-robotics">Probabilistic Robotics</a>
   by Sebastian Thrun, Wolfram Burgard and Dieter Fox</b>
</p>
<p>when i first joined a robotics group i bought a stack of ML/robotics books and this
   was by far the best. it's good intro stuff, and maybe already dated in places given
   it's age (the 2006 edition i have) but i still got a bunch from it.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/tml.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/tinyml/9781492052036/">TinyML</a>
   by Pete Warden &amp; Daniel Situnayake</b>
</p>
<p>this was a super super fun book to tech review! neural networks on microcontrollers?!?
   yes please!
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/ec.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://www.wiley.com/en-us/Evolutionary+Computation%3A+Toward+a+New+Philosophy+of+Machine+Intelligence%2C+3rd+Edition-p-9780471669517">Evolutionary Computation</a> by David Fogel</b>
</p>
<p>this is still by favorite book on evolutionary algorithms; i've had this for a loooong
   time now. i still feel like evolutionary approaches are due for a big big comeback
   any time soon....
</p>
<hr>


<h2>in the mail...</h2>
<p>the good thing about writing a list is you get people telling you cool ones you've missed :)
</p>
<p>the top three i've chosen (that are in the mail) are...
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/ciis.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="http://bayes.cs.ucla.edu/PRIMER/">Causal Inference in Statistics</a> by
   Judea Pearl, Madelyn Glymour &amp; Nicholas P. Jewell</b>
</p>
<p>recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/animesh_garg">animesh</a> who quite rightly points out
   the lack of causality in machine learning books in the books above.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/itiala.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://www.cambridge.org/au/academic/subjects/computer-science/pattern-recognition-and-machine-learning/information-theory-inference-and-learning-algorithms?format=HB&amp;isbn=9780521642989">Information Theory, Inference and Learning Algorithms</a> by David MacKay</b>
</p>
<p>i've seen this book mentioned a number of times and was most recently recommended by
   my colleague <a href="https://twitter.com/danesherbs">dane</a> so it's time to get it.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/bmlpa.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/building-machine-learning/9781492045106/">Building Machine Learning Powered Applications</a> by Emmanuel Ameisen</b>
</p>
<p>a number of people i worked with have enjoyed this. first recommended by another
   colleague <a href="https://twitter.com/davidcolls">dave</a>.
   looks to be on the practical side rather than the theory but that's ok some times :)
</p>

  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://matpalm.com/blog/cool_machine_learning_books/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25031455</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 04:26:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How does the event loop work in JavaScript? [video]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 35 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25031384">thread link</a>) | @krayonatan
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://yonatankra.com/how-does-the-event-loop-work/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://yonatankra.com/how-does-the-event-loop-work/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="primary"><main id="main" role="main"><article id="post-599"><div><!-- .entry-meta --><div> <p><span><span>Estimated Reading Time: </span> <span>&lt; 1</span> <span>minute</span></span></p><figure><p><span><iframe width="640" height="360" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Nqx3rtv_dko?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;fs=1&amp;hl=en-US&amp;autohide=2&amp;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></span></p><figcaption>The event loop and your code talk from WarsawJS</figcaption></figure><p>On august 2020 I spoke at <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://warsawjs.com/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://warsawjs.com/" target="_blank">WarsawJS</a>, explaining about the event loop and how it works.  I hope you will enjoy this talk.</p><p>If you prefer to read – <a href="https://yonatankra.com/the-event-loop-and-your-code/" data-type="post" data-id="299">here’s the blog post this talk is based on</a>.</p><p id="jp-relatedposts"><h3><em>Related</em></h3></p></div><!-- .entry-content --><!-- .entry-footer --></div></article><!-- #post-## --><p><h3>Enjoyed the article?</h3><h4>Sign up to my newsletter to enjoy more content:</h4></p>  <nav role="navigation" aria-label="Posts"><h2>Post navigation</h2></nav><!-- #comments --></main><!-- #main --></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://yonatankra.com/how-does-the-event-loop-work/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25031384</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 04:12:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A fun website that simulates fluid]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 302 | Comments 47 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25031304">thread link</a>) | @svikashk
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://paveldogreat.github.io/WebGL-Fluid-Simulation/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://paveldogreat.github.io/WebGL-Fluid-Simulation/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                        <p>Try Fluid Simulation app!</p>
                        <p><a id="apple_link" target="_blank">
                                <img alt="Download on the App Store" src="https://paveldogreat.github.io/WebGL-Fluid-Simulation/app_badge.png">
                            </a>
                            <a id="google_link" target="_blank">
                                <img alt="Get it on Google Play" src="https://paveldogreat.github.io/WebGL-Fluid-Simulation/gp_badge.png">
                            </a>
                        </p>
                    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://paveldogreat.github.io/WebGL-Fluid-Simulation/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25031304</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 03:54:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Attention Is My Most Valuable Asset for Productivity as a Software Developer]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 602 | Comments 237 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25030938">thread link</a>) | @zwbetz
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://zwbetz.com/attention-is-my-most-valuable-asset-for-productivity-as-a-software-developer/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://zwbetz.com/attention-is-my-most-valuable-asset-for-productivity-as-a-software-developer/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main-content">
      <div>
        <div>
          <div>
            
  
  
  <p>
    
    
    
    <strong>Published: </strong>2020-11-08

    
    
      
      
        • <strong>Lastmod: </strong>2020-11-09

      
    
    
    
    
      <br>
      <span>
        <strong>Tags: </strong>
        
          
          
          
        
          
          
          
        
          
          
          
        
        <a href="https://zwbetz.com/tags/life/">life</a> • <a href="https://zwbetz.com/tags/attention/">attention</a> • <a href="https://zwbetz.com/tags/productivity/">productivity</a>
      
    </span>
  </p>
  
  
  
  

<p>Like a tightly written function, I prefer to exit early if no work should be done. So, if you disagree with these definitions and assumptions, now’s a good time to stop reading.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sustainable productivity:</strong> The maximum rate of quality work output, without loss to the wellbeing of the developer</li>
<li><strong>Quality work:</strong> Software that meets requirements, is valuable to users, is maintainable, and is as bug free as possible</li>
<li><strong>Attention:</strong> The limited mental capacity to focus on a task</li>
<li>Sustainable productivity is desired</li>
<li>Attention is essential to sustainable productivity</li>
</ul>
<p>My high-level workflow looks something like this: identify the problem to solve; think on the problem and let ideas percolate; research, discuss, and experiment with these ideas; implement and test the solution; deliver and maintain the solution.</p>
<p>This cycle could repeat many times in a day. Or I could spend days stuck on a single cycle step. Every step in this cycle requires attention. The more attention I can devote, the more cycles I can complete, and the more productive I am.</p>
<p>How long you can focus on a task varies by person. Some people are very good at it out of the box, some people, not so much. Regardless of the hand you were dealt, I believe that focus (the act of devoting your attention) is a skill, and like any skill, can be improved with practice.</p>
<p>So, how can you increase your attention reserves? The most bang for your buck is to organize your outside world in such a way that it’s distraction free as possible. Once you do that, you’ll have more time to practice, and therefore more time to get better.</p>
<p><strong>Build physical strength.</strong> The damage done by sitting 8+ hours a day is underrated. You need a way to offset this damage, especially if you plan to work in this field for decades. Opinions abound on this topic, but I personally prefer deadlifts. There are few movements more primal than picking a heavy object off the ground and standing up with it. You can <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wYREQkVtvEc">learn correct technique in little time</a>. I most like deadlifts because you can do them safely, at high weights, into old age. I also like the hand, back, and hip strength they give, to make it that much harder for sitting damage to have its way with you.</p>
<p><strong>Make your place of work boring and tidy.</strong> My office is a spare bedroom. The walls are blank. There’s no tv. There’s a desk, chair, laptop, laptop stand, keyboard, mouse, and mouse pad. There’s a window, which lets enough light in so that I don’t feel like I’m missing a beautiful day, but not too much light to cause screen glare. If I need to work with paper, it’s immediately filed somewhere when done. Like I said, boring and tidy.</p>
<p><strong>Make your smart phone dumb.</strong> My phone has all notifications disabled, except for calls and text messages. Well, and National Hurricane Center alerts, since I live in Louisiana. Unless you’re my wife, you know that I don’t respond to text messages immediately, that’s just how it is. I disabled my social media accounts some time ago. But if you have them, turning off notifications should help curve the urge to compulsively check them.</p>
<p><strong>Be an OS minimalist.</strong> Apps I use less commonly are a keypress combo away. Given this, my dock has only the apps I use on a daily basis:</p>
<ul>
<li>File system explorer</li>
<li>Internet browser</li>
<li>Terminal</li>
<li>Text editor for front-end code and notes</li>
<li>IDE for back-end code</li>
<li>IDE for database</li>
<li>Visual file differ for version control</li>
<li>Email client</li>
<li>Instant message client</li>
</ul>
<p>My desktop alternates between clean and dirty states. Files I’m currently working with live on the desktop. Then they’re filed away into sensible folders when done.</p>
<p><strong>Organize your browser bookmarks.</strong> When I read something useful that I may need to reference later, I file it under a general archive folder. Then more specific items get their own folders. Frequently accessed links are visible on my bookmarks bar under their own folder.</p>
<p><strong>Minimize meetings.</strong> Look, I know some things make sense to discuss face to face, or voice to voice. But if they don’t, then you don’t need a meeting. An email or instant message will suffice.</p>
<p><strong>Finally, use the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_management#The_Eisenhower_Method">The Eisenhower Method</a> to categorize your tasks.</strong> Imagine a grid of 4 quadrants:</p>
<ul>
<li>Important and Urgent</li>
<li>Important and Not Urgent</li>
<li>Not Important and Urgent</li>
<li>Not Important and Not Urgent</li>
</ul>
<p>Important and Urgent tasks have to be dealt with. For me, these are usually major production issues.</p>
<p>Important and Not Urgent tasks should absorb the bulk of your time. For me, this is the plain old development work of implementing features, fixing bugs, and making existing code more maintainable and performant. Also included are building relationships with others and planning ahead.</p>
<p>Not Important and Urgent tasks are nasty attention thieves. They shout out to you in immediacy, but offer little value in return. You know what these are for you. For me, these are most often lazily asked questions, where the asker did not do their due diligence, and expects a top-notch answer immediately. Also included are last-minute meetings, and over-talkative coworkers.</p>
<p>Not Important and Not Urgent tasks are usually not known to your users. Take internal documentation updates as an example. Thing is, they’re an investment in yourself, which means a more productive future “you”. So don’t forget to show them some love in your spare moments.</p>
<p><strong>Further reading.</strong> If you don’t know who Cal Newport is, you’re missing out. He has a whole blog dedicated to this type of thing, and has written books such as <em>Deep Work</em> and <em>Digital Minimalism</em>. Here are some of my favorite articles by him:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.calnewport.com/blog/2009/02/04/have-we-lost-our-tolerance-for-a-little-boredom/">Have We Lost Our Tolerance For a Little Boredom?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.calnewport.com/blog/2010/06/10/is-allowing-your-child-to-study-while-on-facebook-morally-equivalent-to-drinking-while-pregnant/">Is Allowing Your Child to Study While on Facebook Morally Irresponsible?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.calnewport.com/blog/2008/04/07/monday-master-class-how-to-reduce-stress-and-get-more-done-by-building-an-autopilot-schedule/">Monday Master Class: How to Reduce Stress and Get More Done By Building an Autopilot Schedule</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.calnewport.com/blog/2009/11/24/are-passions-serendipitously-discovered-or-painstakingly-constructed/">Are Passions Serendipitously Discovered or Painstakingly Constructed?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.calnewport.com/blog/2018/06/08/jerry-seinfelds-closed-door/">Jerry Seinfeld’s Closed Door</a></li>
</ul>



  
  
  

  
  




          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://zwbetz.com/attention-is-my-most-valuable-asset-for-productivity-as-a-software-developer/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25030938</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 02:39:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
