<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 08:26:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 08:26:01 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Firefox usage is down 85% despite Mozilla's top exec pay going up 400%]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 556 | Comments 487 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24563698">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
September 22, 2020 | http://calpaterson.com/mozilla.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://calpaterson.com/mozilla.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <article>
            
            <p>September 2020</p>
            <p id="article-description">Mozilla is in an absolute state: high
            overheads, falling usage of Firefox, questionable sources of revenue and
            now making big cuts to engineering as their income falls.</p>
            <hr>
            <figure>
                <img src="http://calpaterson.com/assets/mozilla-boss-pay.svg" alt="a graph showing that executive pay has grown fast while Firefox's market share has fallen">
                <figcaption>
                    Mozilla's top exec pay has gone up hugely even as usage has
                    crashed.
                </figcaption>
            </figure>
            <p>Mozilla recently announced that they would be dismissing 250 people.
            That's a quarter of their workforce so there are some deep cuts to their
            work too. The victims include: the MDN docs (those are the web standards
            docs everyone likes better than w3schools), the Rust compiler and even some
            cuts to Firefox development. Like most people I want to see Mozilla do well
            but those three projects comprise pretty much what I think of as the whole
            point of Mozilla, so this news is a big let down.</p>
            <p>The stated reason for the cuts is falling income. Mozilla largely relies
            on "royalties" for funding. In return for payment, Mozilla allows big
            technology companies to choose the default search engine in Firefox - the
            technology companies are ultimately paying to increase the number of
            searches Firefox users make with them. Mozilla haven't been particularly
            transparent about why these royalties are being reduced, except to blame
            the coronavirus.</p>
            <p>I'm sure the coronavirus is not a great help but I suspect the bigger
            problem is that Firefox's market share is now a tiny fraction of its
            previous size and so the royalties will be smaller too - fewer users, so
            fewer searches and therefore less money for Mozilla.</p>
            <p>The real problem is not the royalty cuts, though. Mozilla has already
            received more than enough money to set themselves up for financial
            independence. Mozilla received up to half a billion dollars a year (each
            year!) for many years. The <em>real problem</em> is that Mozilla didn't use
            that money to achieve financial independence and instead just spent it each
            year, doing the organisational equivalent of living hand-to-mouth.</p>
            <p>Despite their slightly contrived legal structure as a non-profit that
            owns a for-profit, Mozilla are an NGO just like any other. In this article
            I want to apply the traditional measures that are applied to other NGOs to
            Mozilla in order to show what's wrong.</p>
            <p>These three measures are: overheads, ethics and results.</p>
            <h2>Overheads</h2>
            <p>One of the most popular and most intuitive ways to evaluate an NGO is to
            judge how much of their spending is on their programme of works (or
            "mission") and how much is on other things, like administration and
            fundraising. If you give money to a charity for feeding people in the third
            world you hope that most of the money you give them goes on food - and not,
            for example, on company cars for head office staff.</p>
            <p>Mozilla looks bad when considered in this light. Fully 30% of all
            expenditure goes on administration. Charity Navigator, an organisation that
            measures NGO effectiveness, would give them <a href="https://www.charitynavigator.org/index.cfm?bay=content.view&amp;cpid=48#PerformanceMetricTwo">
            zero out of ten</a> on the relevant metric. For context, to achieve 5/10 on
            that measure Mozilla admin would need to be under 25% of spending and, for
            10/10, under 15%.</p>
            <p>Senior executives have also done very well for themselves. Mitchell
            Baker, Mozilla's top executive, was paid $2.4m in 2018, a sum I personally
            think of as instant inter-generational wealth. Payments to Baker have more
            than doubled in the last five years.</p>
            <p>As far as I can find, there is no UK-based NGO whose top executive makes
            more than £1m ($1.3m) a year. The UK certainly has its fair share of big
            international NGOs - many much bigger and more significant than
            Mozilla.</p>
            <p>I'm aware that <a href="https://concepts.effectivealtruism.org/concepts/relationship-between-overheads-and-effectiveness/">
            some people dislike overheads as a measure</a> and argue that it's possible
            for administration spending to increase effectiveness. I think it's hard to
            argue that Mozilla's overheads are correlated with any improvement in
            effectiveness.</p>
            <h2>Ethics</h2>
            <p>Mozilla now thinks of itself less as a custodian of the old Netscape
            suite and more as a 'privacy NGO'. One slogan inside Mozilla is: "Beyond
            the Browser".</p>
            <p>Regardless of how they view themselves, most of their income comes from
            helping to direct traffic to Google by making that search engine the
            default in Firefox. Google make money off that traffic via a big targeted
            advertising system that tracks people across the web and largely without
            their consent. Indeed, one of the reasons this income is falling is because
            as Firefox's usage falls less traffic is being directed Google's way and so
            Google will pay less.</p>
            <p>There is, as yet, no outbreak of agreement among the moral philosophers
            as to a universal code of ethics. However I think most people would
            recognise hypocrisy in Mozilla's relationship with Google. Beyond the
            ethical problems, the relationship certainly seems to create conflicts of
            interest. Anyone would think that a privacy NGO would build anti-tracking
            countermeasures into their browser right from the start. In fact, this was
            only added relatively recently (<a href="https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/06/04/firefox-now-available-with-enhanced-tracking-protection-by-default/">in
            2019</a>), after both Apple (<a href="https://webkit.org/blog/7675/intelligent-tracking-prevention/">in
            2017</a>) and Brave (since release) paved the way. It certainly seems like
            Mozilla's status as a Google vassal has played a role in the absence of
            anti-tracking features in Firefox for so long.</p>
            <p>Another ethical issue is Mozilla's big new initiative to <a href="https://vpn.mozilla.org/">move into VPNs</a>. This doesn't make a lot of
            sense from a privacy point of view. Broadly speaking: VPNs are not a useful
            privacy tool for people browsing the web. A VPN lets you access the
            internet through a proxy - so your requests superficially appear to come
            from somewhere other than they really do. This does nothing to address the
            main privacy problem for web users: that they are being passively tracked
            and de-anonymised on a massive scale by the baddies at Google and
            elsewhere. This tracking happens regardless of IP address.</p>
            <p>When I tested Firefox through <a href="https://vpn.mozilla.org/">Mozilla
            VPN</a> (a rebrand of <a href="https://mullvad.net/">Mullvad VPN</a>) I
            found that I could be de-anonymised by browser fingerprinting - already a
            fairly widespread technique by which various elements of your browser are
            examined to create a "fingerprint" which can then be used to re-identify
            you later. Firefox does not include as many countermeasures against this as
            some other browsers (<strong>this is a correction</strong> - I previously
            said Firefox contained none but it's been pointed out to me that <a href="https://blog.mozilla.org/security/2020/01/07/firefox-72-fingerprinting/">since
            earlier this year</a> it does block some kinds of fingerprinting).</p>
            <figure>
                <img src="http://calpaterson.com/assets/panopticlick-firefox.png" alt="firefox's results on panopticlick - my browser has a unique fingerprint">
                <figcaption>
                    Even when using Mozilla's "secure and private" VPN, Firefox is
                    trackable by browser fingerprinting, as demonstrated by the
                    <a href="https://panopticlick.eff.org/">EFF's Panopticlick
                    tool</a>. Other browsers use randomised fingerprints as a
                    countermeasure against this tracking.
                </figcaption>
            </figure>
            <p>Another worry is that many of these privacy focused VPN services have a
            nasty habit of turning out to keep copious logs on user behaviour. A few
            months ago several "no log" VPN services inadvertently released terabytes
            of private user data that they had promised not to collect <a href="https://www.vpnmentor.com/blog/report-free-vpns-leak/">in a massive
            breach</a>. VPN services are in a great position to eavesdrop - and even if
            they promise not to, your only option is to take them at their word.</p>
            <h2>Results</h2>
            <p>I've discussed the Mozilla chair's impressive pay: $2.4m/year. Surely
            such impressive pay is justified by the equally impressive results Mozilla
            has achieved? Sadly on almost every measure of results both quantitative
            and qualitative, Mozilla is a dog.</p>
            <p>Firefox is now so niche it is in danger of garnering a cult following:
            it has just 4% market share, down from 30% a decade ago. Mobile browsing
            numbers are bleak: Firefox barely exists on phones, with a market share of
            less than half a percent. This is baffling given that mobile Firefox has a
            rare feature for a mobile browser: it's able to install extensions and so
            can block ads.</p>
            <p>Yet despite the problems within their core business, Mozilla, instead of
            retrenching, has diversified rapidly. In recent years Mozilla has
            created:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>a mobile app for making websites</li>
                <li>a federated identity system</li>
                <li>a large file transfer service</li>
                <li>a password manager</li>
                <li>an internet-of-things framework/standard</li>
                <li>an email relay service</li>
                <li>a completely new phone operating system</li>
                <li>an AI division (but of course)</li>
                <li>and spent $25 million buying the reading list management startup,
                Pocket</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Many of the above are now abandoned.</p>
            <p>Sadly <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/foundation/annualreport/2018/">Mozilla's
            annual report</a> doesn't break down expenses on a per-project basis so
            it's impossible to know how much of the spending that <em>is</em> on
            Mozilla's programme is being spent on Firefox and how …</p></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://calpaterson.com/mozilla.html">http://calpaterson.com/mozilla.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://calpaterson.com/mozilla.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24563698</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 06:38:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A look at /e/OS on the FairPhone 3 – a FOSS OS for phones [video]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 60 | Comments 37 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24563576">thread link</a>) | @indidea
<br/>
September 22, 2020 | https://share.tube/videos/watch/ef3e5eec-27aa-45c8-b87b-64a57fc6e176 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://share.tube/videos/watch/ef3e5eec-27aa-45c8-b87b-64a57fc6e176">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://share.tube/videos/watch/ef3e5eec-27aa-45c8-b87b-64a57fc6e176</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24563576</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 06:17:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Catch Breaking Changes by Diffing API Traffic]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 85 | Comments 23 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24561119">thread link</a>) | @jeanyang
<br/>
September 22, 2020 | https://www.akitasoftware.com/blog/2020/9/22/faster-better-earlier-catch-breaking-changes-by-diffing-api-behavior | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.akitasoftware.com/blog/2020/9/22/faster-better-earlier-catch-breaking-changes-by-diffing-api-behavior">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          

          <main>
            
              <section data-content-field="main-content">
                <article id="post-5f6a6536fa06431194e74792" data-item-id="5f6a6536fa06431194e74792">

    
      
    

    <div data-layout-label="Post Body" data-type="item" data-updated-on="1600808326368" id="item-5f6a6536fa06431194e74792"><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-b94a17a4246df542ccf7"><div><p>If you work on web apps, you may sometimes feel that your tools have forsaken you. And you’re not wrong. Because of the way modern tech stacks are set up, it’s getting harder and harder to make sure your code is doing what it’s supposed to.</p><p>In this blog post, we’ll show you a bug that slips through the cracks today, explain why it’s nobody’s fault, and show you how we diff API behaviors to catch bugs (while generating API specs along the way!!).</p><h2>😱 The Bug That (Almost) Ruined A Friendship</h2><p>You work on a web app. Your co-worker and #bff, Aki, opened a pull request to remove a property from a commonly used API. You two are tight, so you jump in to review the PR. Aki’s PR includes a link showing that this property’s usage has been removed from the website, once again proving why Aki is your #bff. You +1 the PR enthusiastically, with both of you believing that Aki has taken into account all of the dependencies.</p><p>The change gets merged. Then: BETRAYAL! There are now outages in the mobile clients, and it’s late nights for you and Aki. (Good thing you started out liking Aki so much.) It turns out that Aki’s API had been so good that the mobile APIs had started depending on the removed property, unbeknownst to both you and Aki.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1600807765736_28487"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b6f6c558ab722caa37858bf/1600808423195-A8MEAE1ZSLUSRTJU27ZN/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPpDoBIqNy1gGho9uyT02YZZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWEtT5uBSRWt4vQZAgTJucoTqqXjS3CfNDSuuf31e0tVFMU71HPrJlrka-k3KdzI_LQkclrYoo_JyQT2V0r-tdNKQvevUbj177dmcMs1F0H-0/been_here_all_along.gif" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b6f6c558ab722caa37858bf/1600808423195-A8MEAE1ZSLUSRTJU27ZN/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPpDoBIqNy1gGho9uyT02YZZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWEtT5uBSRWt4vQZAgTJucoTqqXjS3CfNDSuuf31e0tVFMU71HPrJlrka-k3KdzI_LQkclrYoo_JyQT2V0r-tdNKQvevUbj177dmcMs1F0H-0/been_here_all_along.gif" data-image-dimensions="474x264" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="been_here_all_along.gif" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f6a65d7f2a96f4111ce87f9" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1600807765736_28787"><div><p>If this has happened to you, you are not to blame! These bugs are nasty little things: they have to do with dependencies on the code you wrote rather than the code itself, making it hard to catch them through source diffs. In fact, as soon as bugs cross API boundaries, they become extremely hard to catch because they elude common testing and software analysis (think static and dynamic analysis) solutions. Developers are left to rely on documentation, word of mouth, and crossing their fingers really hard.<br></p><h2>⚡️ Find Bugs by Diffing API Behavior</h2><p>To catch these kinds of bugs, you can simply install Akita to analyze API-impacting changes whenever you make a pull request. Here is an example of a comment that Akita leaves on your pull request:</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1600807765736_41128"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b6f6c558ab722caa37858bf/1600808581307-IQU2P2L5CSD49CHWB6S5/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kBSisbFCmLfsWG8TQUrClwdZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpw0ownQnmw6tXIbWXwOqlr6LyiEFX92T0WhozlucCNM3TxLzdvFHSK_CwcKuIV17xo/Screen+Shot+2020-09-21+at+9.38.25+PM.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b6f6c558ab722caa37858bf/1600808581307-IQU2P2L5CSD49CHWB6S5/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kBSisbFCmLfsWG8TQUrClwdZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpw0ownQnmw6tXIbWXwOqlr6LyiEFX92T0WhozlucCNM3TxLzdvFHSK_CwcKuIV17xo/Screen+Shot+2020-09-21+at+9.38.25+PM.png" data-image-dimensions="720x395" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Screen Shot 2020-09-21 at 9.38.25 PM.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f6a668349ec6e5af6d59390" data-type="image" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b6f6c558ab722caa37858bf/1600808581307-IQU2P2L5CSD49CHWB6S5/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kBSisbFCmLfsWG8TQUrClwdZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpw0ownQnmw6tXIbWXwOqlr6LyiEFX92T0WhozlucCNM3TxLzdvFHSK_CwcKuIV17xo/Screen+Shot+2020-09-21+at+9.38.25+PM.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1600809689527_10094"><div><p>Akita enables you to compare API behavior across pull requests, multiple environments (ex production vs. test), and even pre-existing specs. If Aki had used Akita to compare the API behavior between their production and test environments, they surely would have caught the bug and saved you some late-night debugging!</p><p>By diffing on <em>behaviors</em> rather than code, Akita summarizes how a pull request changes your API, including: </p><ul data-rte-list="default"><li><p>Endpoints added that expose new functionality</p></li><li><p>Removed/changed parameters that may break existing clients</p></li><li><p>Simple type changes (ex string to int) that can pollute data pipelines</p></li><li><p>Complex type changes (ex phone number to datetime) that can break dependencies</p></li><li><p>👷🏻‍♀️ Coming soon: Impacted Clients, telling you exactly which mobile and web clients are affected</p></li></ul><p>Just this week, we released our GitHub integration to deliver insight on every pull request. You can now use Akita without changing any code or config files, without having to proxy—and as part of your normal developer workflow.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1600807765736_62396"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b6f6c558ab722caa37858bf/1600808791165-T8ZNZ149RXNZXQIEMEZB/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kBPgYHUT9ThyHW4rLCUoJ0lZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWhcwhEtWJXoshNdA9f1qD7Tj1Xq8fmJm7kR3YKhl46-gnroPAwW8vDSy_xFKJA22nuObuMlYXtIhhFNrGCmVLcw/taylor_swift_magic.gif" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b6f6c558ab722caa37858bf/1600808791165-T8ZNZ149RXNZXQIEMEZB/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kBPgYHUT9ThyHW4rLCUoJ0lZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWhcwhEtWJXoshNdA9f1qD7Tj1Xq8fmJm7kR3YKhl46-gnroPAwW8vDSy_xFKJA22nuObuMlYXtIhhFNrGCmVLcw/taylor_swift_magic.gif" data-image-dimensions="268x300" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="taylor_swift_magic.gif" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f6a6753a4d7ab439775c1b5" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1600807765736_62695"><div><p>Akita does this by showing you <em>semantic diffs</em> between <em>implicit API contracts</em>. In other words, this means Akita does some magic to figure out what your API normally does and then diffs on that, instead of diffing syntactically on the source code. Diffing on observed behaviors, rather than the code itself or a static graph of what APIs could call each other, allows Akita’s reports to pinpoint potential issues much more precisely. Akita is flexible enough to run in both CI, as shown here, and in production environments!<br></p><h2>⚒ Under the Hood: Advanced API Analysis</h2><p>You may be wondering how we do this, since no existing linter, static analysis, or dynamic analysis gets anywhere close. Under the hood, Akita analyzes API traffic to build a model of your API from scratch. As a foundation, Akita builds an API spec for your API. Here we show an OpenAPI spec that Akita automatically generated:</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1600807765736_66982"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b6f6c558ab722caa37858bf/1600808826794-Z8US2E3IAXUHH1IPLX75/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kEE5BRPVFdSFNJ9EWVjnQtJZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpzBAkhzHXcTUkbSFC51ULQzwiZaehtpr50pAWHTpVqK6r115xOpNXu01MbofqMIiwU/ezgif.com-gif-maker.gif" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b6f6c558ab722caa37858bf/1600808826794-Z8US2E3IAXUHH1IPLX75/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kEE5BRPVFdSFNJ9EWVjnQtJZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpzBAkhzHXcTUkbSFC51ULQzwiZaehtpr50pAWHTpVqK6r115xOpNXu01MbofqMIiwU/ezgif.com-gif-maker.gif" data-image-dimensions="600x393" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="ezgif.com-gif-maker.gif" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f6a6778d23bb34052efba66" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1600807765736_67281"><p>The next step is where the magic comes from. Akita uses advanced programming languages technology to detect not just the basic spec properties, but also <em>implicit API contracts</em>, for instance, specific types like datetime, email, phone number, and more:</p></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1600807765736_71700"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b6f6c558ab722caa37858bf/1600808865413-FUBU45W5T149VXEPJIJN/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kBB-NYNLcJUiltQ1hCaI3rZZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpwA8pzCiywVt9LP9piA_ClOHaEOe2M-jmaR_vLVWBls2AqnUAfoiU4gMfB4Brxcm5Y/ezgif.com-video-to-gif+%283%29.gif" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b6f6c558ab722caa37858bf/1600808865413-FUBU45W5T149VXEPJIJN/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kBB-NYNLcJUiltQ1hCaI3rZZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpwA8pzCiywVt9LP9piA_ClOHaEOe2M-jmaR_vLVWBls2AqnUAfoiU4gMfB4Brxcm5Y/ezgif.com-video-to-gif+%283%29.gif" data-image-dimensions="600x454" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="ezgif.com-video-to-gif (3).gif" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f6a679ca354713d8a568518" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1600807765736_71999"><p>All you have to do is set up Akita to watch your API traffic. No code changes and no proxying necessary:</p></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1600807765736_76619"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b6f6c558ab722caa37858bf/1600809028362-FJSJ12A8EEIKI2PM9EEB/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kMCbG34QsIB0ipg6r18MvYZZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpyi5tdW1COKT9Y4DK_rBTv9Q6FtHNTZjOfSYj3sGOmcYpFc0Nb-CneOPLcghlQYm6U/ezgif.com-video-to-gif+%281%29+%281%29.gif" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b6f6c558ab722caa37858bf/1600809028362-FJSJ12A8EEIKI2PM9EEB/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kMCbG34QsIB0ipg6r18MvYZZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpyi5tdW1COKT9Y4DK_rBTv9Q6FtHNTZjOfSYj3sGOmcYpFc0Nb-CneOPLcghlQYm6U/ezgif.com-video-to-gif+%281%29+%281%29.gif" data-image-dimensions="600x476" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="ezgif.com-video-to-gif (1) (1).gif" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f6a684260fe9502d3149c18" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1600807765736_76918"><div><h2>👀 What’s Next?&nbsp;</h2><p>We’ve just released the spec viewer and GitHub integration in our private beta and would love to have you try out our spec generation and/or semantic API behavior diffs. Here’s how you can help:</p><ul data-rte-list="default"><li><p><a href="https://www.akitasoftware.com/get-invite?utm_campaign=2020_pre_launch&amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;utm_source=2020_09_22_product_update"><strong>Sign up for our private beta</strong></a><strong> if you’re interested in trying things out!</strong></p></li><li><p>You may also be interested in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?utm_campaign=2020_pre_launch&amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;v=uYA4DsuMrg8%3Futm_source%3D2020_09_22_product_update">this talk and demo</a> we gave at the API Specs Conference last week.</p></li><li><p>We’re also constantly trying to make our tool better! If change analysis is an issue for you, please fill out <a href="https://akitasoftware.typeform.com/to/iAbs1tB5?utm_campaign=2020_pre_launch&amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;utm_source=2020_09_22_product_update">this survey</a>—with an opportunity to win a $50 Amazon gift card.</p></li><li><p>Spread the word about us! We’d love all the feedback we can get!</p></li></ul></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1600807765736_188572"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b6f6c558ab722caa37858bf/1600809657904-GN3J9FTFCFFTRWQ9D4I2/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kEVUGKfLWnr3FrBNrBvkNl1Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWEtT5uBSRWt4vQZAgTJucoTqqXjS3CfNDSuuf31e0tVHHv_BoFYeKfPNyfF1FiKR-vDFZ_sNHqsWdE5x3HFER1Bur-lC0WofN0YB1wFg-ZW0/next_chapter.gif" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b6f6c558ab722caa37858bf/1600809657904-GN3J9FTFCFFTRWQ9D4I2/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kEVUGKfLWnr3FrBNrBvkNl1Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWEtT5uBSRWt4vQZAgTJucoTqqXjS3CfNDSuuf31e0tVHHv_BoFYeKfPNyfF1FiKR-vDFZ_sNHqsWdE5x3HFER1Bur-lC0WofN0YB1wFg-ZW0/next_chapter.gif" data-image-dimensions="478x266" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="next_chapter.gif" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f6a6aa4f2a96f4111cf7183" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div></div></div></div>

    

    

    <section id="comments-5f6a6536fa06431194e74792">
      
  


    </section>

  </article>





  <nav>

    

    
      <a href="https://www.akitasoftware.com/blog/2020/7/29/the-secret-to-building-better-software-get-in-control-of-your-apis">
        <div>
          <p>Next</p>
          <h4>The secret to building better software? Get in control of your APIs</h4>
          <div>
            <!--

            Categories

            --><p><span>Updates, Approach</span></p><!--

            Author

            --><p><span>Jean Yang</span></p><!--

            Date

            --><p><time datetime="2020-07-30">July 30, 2020</time>
          </p></div>
        </div><!--
        --><svg viewBox="0 0 23 48">
          <g>
            <polyline fill="none" stroke-miterlimit="10" points="1.5,45.7 20.4,23.5 1.5,1.3 "></polyline>
          </g>
        </svg>
      </a>
    

  </nav>
              </section>
            
          </main>

        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.akitasoftware.com/blog/2020/9/22/faster-better-earlier-catch-breaking-changes-by-diffing-api-behavior</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24561119</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 23:13:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Older people have become younger]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 137 | Comments 112 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24560595">thread link</a>) | @betocmn
<br/>
September 22, 2020 | https://www.jyu.fi/en/current/archive/2020/09/older-people-have-become-younger-physical-and-cognitive-function-have-improved-meaningfully-in-30-years | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.jyu.fi/en/current/archive/2020/09/older-people-have-become-younger-physical-and-cognitive-function-have-improved-meaningfully-in-30-years">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content-core">
  <div>

    <div id="parent-fieldname-text"><p><span lang="EN-GB" xml:lang="EN-GB">“Performance-based measurements describe how older people manage in their daily life, and at the same time, the measurements reflect one’s functional age,” says the principal investigator of the study, Professor <strong>Taina Rantanen.</strong></span></p>
<p><span lang="EN-GB" xml:lang="EN-GB">Among men and women between the ages of 75 and 80, muscle strength, walking speed, reaction speed, verbal fluency, reasoning and working memory are nowadays significantly better than they were in people at the same age born earlier. In lung function tests, however, differences between cohorts were not observed. </span></p>
<p><span lang="EN-GB" xml:lang="EN-GB">“Higher physical activity and increased body size explained the better walking speed and muscle strength among the later-born cohort,” says doctoral student <strong>Kaisa Koivunen</strong>, “whereas the most important underlying factor behind the cohort differences in cognitive performance was longer education.” </span></p>
<p><span lang="EN-GB" xml:lang="EN-GB">Postdoctoral researcher <strong>Matti Munukka</strong> continues: “The cohort of 75- and 80-year-olds born later has grown up and lived in a different world than did their counterparts born three decades ago. There have been many favourable changes. These include better nutrition and hygiene, improvements in health care and the school system, better accessibility to education and improved working life.”</span></p>
<p><span lang="EN-GB" xml:lang="EN-GB">The results suggest that increased life expectancy is accompanied by an increased number of years lived with good functional ability in later life. The observation can be explained by slower rate-of-change with increasing age, a higher lifetime maximum in physical performance, or a combination of the two.</span></p>
<p><span lang="EN-GB" xml:lang="EN-GB">“This research is unique because there are only a few studies in the world that have compared performance-based maximum measures between people of the same age in different historical times,” says Rantanen.</span></p>
<p><span lang="EN-GB" xml:lang="EN-GB">“The results suggest that our understanding of older age is old-fashioned. From an aging researcher’s point of view, more years are added to midlife, and not so much to the utmost end of life. Increased life expectancy provides us with more non-disabled years, but at the same time, the last years of life comes at higher and higher ages, increasing the need for care. Among the ageing population, two simultaneous changes are happening: continuation of healthy years to higher ages and an increased number of very old people who need external care.”</span></p>
<p><span lang="EN-GB" xml:lang="EN-GB">The study was conducted at the Faculty of Sport and Health Sciences and Gerontology Research Center at University of Jyväskylä, Finland. The first cohort data were collected between 1989 and 1990 and consisted of 500 people born between 1910 and 1914. The second cohort data were collected from 2017 to 2018 and comprised 726 people born in 1938 or 1939 and 1942 or 1943. In both cohorts, the participants were assessed at the age 75 or 80 years. Participants were recruited from the Digital and Population Data Services Agency. The study was funded by the Academy of Finland and the European Research Council.</span></p>
<h4><span lang="EN-GB" xml:lang="EN-GB">Original publications:</span></h4>
<p><span lang="EN-GB" xml:lang="EN-GB">Koivunen, K, Sillanpää, E, Munukka, M, Portegijs, E, Rantanen, T. Cohort differences in maximal physical performance: a comparison of 75- and 80-year-old men and women born 28 years apart. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2020. <a href="https://academic.oup.com/biomedgerontology/advance-article/doi/10.1093/gerona/glaa224/5901594" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-linktype="external" data-val="https://academic.oup.com/biomedgerontology/advance-article/doi/10.1093/gerona/glaa224/5901594">https://doi.org/10.1093/gerona/glaa224.</a></span></p>
<p><span lang="EN-GB" xml:lang="EN-GB">Munukka M, Koivunen K, von Bonsdorff M, Sipilä S, Portegijs, E, Ruoppila I, Rantanen T. Birth cohort differences in cognitive performance in 75- and 80-Year-Olds - A comparison of two cohorts over 28 years. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2020. <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s40520-020-01702-0" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-linktype="external" data-val="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s40520-020-01702-0">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40520-020-01702-0</a>.</span></p>
<h4><span lang="EN-GB" xml:lang="EN-GB">Contact information: </span></h4>
<ul>
<li><span lang="EN-GB" xml:lang="EN-GB">Doctoral student Kaisa Koivunen, kaisa.m.koivunen@jyu.fi , +358503608818</span></li>
<li><span lang="EN-GB" xml:lang="EN-GB">Post doctoral researcher Matti Munukka, matti.munukka@jyu.fi, +358408053606</span></li>
<li>Professor Taina Rantanen, taina.rantanen@jyu.fi, +358408053590</li>
</ul></div>

    
  


  </div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.jyu.fi/en/current/archive/2020/09/older-people-have-become-younger-physical-and-cognitive-function-have-improved-meaningfully-in-30-years</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24560595</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 22:12:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Absent aid, few US cities will be able to avoid austerity]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 59 | Comments 60 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24559756">thread link</a>) | @walterbell
<br/>
September 22, 2020 | https://citymonitor.ai/government/absent-aid-few-us-cities-will-be-able-to-avoid-austerity | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://citymonitor.ai/government/absent-aid-few-us-cities-will-be-able-to-avoid-austerity">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			<p><span>Austin City Council member Jimmy Flannigan knows his city is lucky.&nbsp;</span>
</p><p><span>The fourth-largest city in Texas suffered a nasty shock at the beginning of the Covid-19 pandemic when Mayor Steve Adler canceled its signature event, South by Southwest.&nbsp; </span><span>The annual ten-day extravaganza draws luminaries from the entertainment, tech and media industries and </span><a href="https://explore.sxsw.com/hubfs/2019%20SXSW%20Economic%20Impact%20Analysis%20-%2011.18.19%20OPT.pdf"><span>brings over $350 million</span></a><span> to Austin’s economy.</span>
</p><figure id="attachment_638" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-638"><img src="https://citymonitor.ai/wp-content/uploads/sites/18/2020/09/GettyImages-1226093815-1.jpg" alt="A view of downtown Austin, Texas. " width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://citymonitor.ai/wp-content/uploads/sites/18/2020/09/GettyImages-1226093815-1.jpg 1024w, https://citymonitor.ai/wp-content/uploads/sites/18/2020/09/GettyImages-1226093815-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://citymonitor.ai/wp-content/uploads/sites/18/2020/09/GettyImages-1226093815-1-600x400.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-638"><span>Austin’s economy is doing better than most US cities since the outbreak of Covid-19. (Photo by Tom Pennington/Getty Images)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><span>Flannigan is the former head of the city’s LGBT Chamber of Commerce, and he immediately rallied venue and bar owners to discuss the economic fallout. But the loss of the conference, and its tens of thousands of attendees, was quickly eclipsed by, well, everything else.&nbsp;</span>											</p>
									 
			
<p><span>“There was the cancel South by stage, where we all thought, ‘This is going to suck, but it’s not coming here,’” says Flannigan. “Then very quickly, you realize that this is a globally interconnected city and Southy by is not the problem. In a short period of time, it became clear that this was going to be shutting down a lot more than music venues.”</span>
</p><p><span>The cancellation of South By Southwest was one of those moments, like the National Basketball Association’s decision to pause its season, when Americans started realizing the pandemic wasn’t just happening somewhere else. But in the months since, Austin is looking like one of the luckiest urban areas in the United States. Unemployment in the city <a href="https://www.statesman.com/business/20200918/austin-jobless-rate-keeps-improving-down-to-55">fell to 5.5% in August</a> – far lower even than other wealthy US cities such as San Francisco or New York. After a 20% year-over-year dive, sales tax revenues are recovering (although they have not yet returned to pre-pandemic levels). Austin is one of the only major cities in Texas that hasn’t furloughed or laid off public-sector workers thanks, in part, to the city’s approach to addressing another crisis roiling the US: Black Lives Matter and the demand for police reform.&nbsp;</span>
</p><p><span>But despite the relatively sunny outlook, Austin faces the same daunting dilemmas as do other cities across the United States.</span>
</p><p><span>“I think most cities are basically going to be broke for the foreseeable future,” says Bill Fulton, director of the Kinder Institute for Urban Research at Rice University in Houston. “I’ve been the mayor of a city, and if you lose 10 to 15 percent of revenue, it is impossible to maneuver or do anything. In a situation like this, you see a rapid drop in revenue and very slow restoration. And it’s impossible to know what business travel and the tourist economy is going to do in the years ahead.”</span>
</p><p><span>To make matters worse, for many cities the fallout from the Great Recession never ended. Although the Obama administration’s stimulus package in 2009 provided aid to state and local governments, it ran dry in 2011. Revenues continued falling for years, only bottoming out in 2014.</span>
</p><p><span>Economists such as Amanda Page-Hoongrajok, an assistant professor of economics and finance at Saint Peter’s University, argue that austerity at the local and state level fully offset the federal stimulus during the Great Recession. That’s part of why the recovery took so long and was so uneven: In cities and regions that weren’t doing as well, those public sector jobs never fully came back. That meant a lot of private sector jobs that relied on them died too.&nbsp;</span>
</p><p><span>“Pretty much any spending cuts at the state and local level are going to be a huge drag on the overall economic recovery,” says Page-Hoongrajok. “If state and local governments are condensing their balance sheets, they’re laying people off. They’re cutting spending on equipment. Capital spending is cut early during downturns. All of that is sucking demand right out of the economy.”</span>
</p><figure id="attachment_642" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-642"><img src="https://ind-dev-newstatesman-b2b.pantheonsite.io/citymonitor/wp-content/uploads/sites/18/2020/09/GettyImages-112145276.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://citymonitor.ai/wp-content/uploads/sites/18/2020/09/GettyImages-112145276.jpg 1024w, https://citymonitor.ai/wp-content/uploads/sites/18/2020/09/GettyImages-112145276-768x512.jpg 768w, https://citymonitor.ai/wp-content/uploads/sites/18/2020/09/GettyImages-112145276-600x400.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-642"><span>Thousands of union members from around Michigan rally at the State Capitol to protest Governor Rick Snyder’s proposed budget cuts in April 13, 2011. (Photo by Bill Pugliano/Getty Images)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><span>Compared to many other rich nations, America governs itself with a relatively messy form of federalism. The powers of federal, state and local government all overlap somewhat, which means the higher branches can sometimes leave the lower ones to fend for themselves. Unless Congress steps in, it’s up to state and local governments to balance their own ledgers. This time, despite the massive stimulus efforts put forward in Washington, the only lifeline was a $150 billion cut of the $2.2 trillion CARES Act, which then had to be split between states, cities, and tribal governments. The funds could only be spent on efforts to ameliorate the pandemic.&nbsp;</span>
</p><p><span>That did nothing for the Covid-sized hole blown in municipal budgets by skyrocketing unemployment, declining sales taxes, and the overnight evisceration of revenue derived from pandemic-vulnerable sources like hotel and liquor taxes. As the pandemic rages, some governmental duties require less input, but public responsibilities like social services grow more costly.</span>
</p><p><span>Without further federal aid, this will pose a problem for many localities. Left to their own devices, the layers of American government below the federal level have a limited toolkit. States cannot print their own money and many have balanced budget requirements. Even those that don’t have explicit strictures about the need for current revenues to cover expenditures are afraid to get too creative with their financing for fear of making the costs of borrowing more expensive.&nbsp;</span>
</p><p><span>Cities governments, meanwhile, live at the whim of their states and face even tighter restrictions. In cases like Austin, where state governments are of a different ideological persuasion than municipal politicians, the ability of liberal local leaders to raise taxes can be limited by conservative elected officials in the statehouse. Their borrowing capabilities are even more tightly constrained than the states, because their tax bases are much smaller and predecessor city governments have </span><a href="https://www.citymetric.com/politics/pandemic-economy-could-revive-one-america-s-ugliest-fights-over-local-control-5147"><span>suffered fiscal crises</span></a><span> after being disciplined by the bond markets.&nbsp;</span>
</p><p><span>That just leaves current revenues on the table, which are looking precarious. The mainstay of municipal finance, property taxes, mostly haven’t been paid yet this year. But the National Association of Counties reports that 27% of respondents to their membership polling have already experienced a lag in collection or a decline in revenue from this usually reliable source. Experts fear that property taxes won’t bring in what they once did in the medium term either. What owner of a mostly empty commercial office building won’t be challenging their assessment?&nbsp;</span>
</p><p><span>In </span><a href="https://www.nlc.org/sites/default/files/users/user57221/City_Fiscal_Conditions_2020_FINAL.pdf"><span>a mid-August report</span></a><span>, the National League of Cities outlined the dire reality facing its membership. Almost 90% of cities anticipated being less able to meet their needs in fiscal year 2021, while the hundreds surveyed anticipated an average 13% decline in general fund revenues. </span><a href="https://covid19.nlc.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/What-Covid-19-Means-For-City-Finances_Report-Final.pdf"><span>A third of the nation’s</span></a><span> three million city workers are expected to be furloughed, laid off, or required to serve on reduced pay. In April alone, almost 800,000 jobs in local governments were lost. Employment in the sector has been growing again since June, but it lags overall job growth.&nbsp;</span>
</p><p><span>All of this has been a nasty shock for a sector that only just recovered from the last (supposedly) once-in-a-generation crisis a little over a decade ago. Page-Hoongrajok says inflation adjusted state and local government spending did not return to pre-Great Recession levels until 2019. Public sector employment has fallen back to the same level it was in the 1990s, when the US population was roughly 60 million people fewer than it is today. Many key services were never restored to pre-Great Recession levels: infrastructure spending is at </span><a href="https://www.cbpp.org/research/state-budget-and-tax/its-time-for-states-to-invest-in-infrastructure"><span>a 70-year low point</span></a><span> while capital spending on schools is </span><a href="https://www.cbpp.org/blog/with-federal-funding-unreliable-states-must-invest-in-school-buildings"><span>below what it was in 2008. </span></a><span>&nbsp;</span>
</p><figure id="attachment_644" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-644"><img src="https://ind-dev-newstatesman-b2b.pantheonsite.io/citymonitor/wp-content/uploads/sites/18/2020/09/GettyImages-80923121.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://citymonitor.ai/wp-content/uploads/sites/18/2020/09/GettyImages-80923121.jpg 1024w, https://citymonitor.ai/wp-content/uploads/sites/18/2020/09/GettyImages-80923121-768x512.jpg 768w, https://citymonitor.ai/wp-content/uploads/sites/18/2020/09/GettyImages-80923121-600x400.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-644"><span>A foreclosure sign sits in front of a home for sale April 29, 2008 in Stockton, California. (Photo by Justin Sullivan/Getty Images)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><span>Fulton remembers the pain of the Great Recession well. In the late 2000s, he served as mayor of Ventura, California, a city of just over 100,000 people midway between Santa Barbara and Los Angeles.</span>
</p><p><span>Ventura’s experience during the Great Recession was harrowing: Fulton recalls the city’s tax revenues plunging almost 15% overnight. It took years to restore, despite the city’s relative affluence – today Ventura’s median income is almost $13,000 higher than the national average.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span>
</p><p><span>The downturn turned the position of mayor into a depressing bookkeeping exercise. Instead of cutting ribbons at new parks and infrastructure projects, Fulton spent his days cutting budgets and, more painfully, staff. Austerity proved even more painful elsewhere in the state. Cities across California’s Central Valley, which has not prospered alongside the coastal regions, eliminated their planning departments and never replaced them.</span>
</p><p><span>In Fulton’s estimation, there is an order to how local politicians implement austerity measures. First, they put a halt to capital projects and, then, services. The </span><a href="https://www.naco.org/sites/default/files/documents/Analysis-of-COVID-19s-Impact-on-County-Finances-and-Implications-for-the-US-Economy.pdf"><span>National Association of Counties found</span></a><span> that 71% of its members have already cut back on capital spending and 68% on services. Then non-personnel spending goes. After that, staff is cut through attrition, as job vacancies open up but go unfilled.&nbsp;</span>
</p><p><span>“The second to last resort is that they cut staff, they lay people off,” says Fulton, “and then the last resort, when everything else falls, they actually start to rethink what they do.”&nbsp;</span>
</p><p><span>Fulton says that an emergency of this magnitude will force cities to make hard decisions. But it can also provide an opportunity to change long established ways of operating that have proven resistant to crusading council members or activist campaigns.&nbsp;</span>
</p><p><span>In Austin, easily the most left-wing city in Texas, the city government patched holes in municipal finances and funded needed city services by redistributing some of the police department’s budget. In the midst of the Black Lives Matter protests this summer, activists demanded moving funds – and responsibilities …</span></p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://citymonitor.ai/government/absent-aid-few-us-cities-will-be-able-to-avoid-austerity">https://citymonitor.ai/government/absent-aid-few-us-cities-will-be-able-to-avoid-austerity</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://citymonitor.ai/government/absent-aid-few-us-cities-will-be-able-to-avoid-austerity</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24559756</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 20:53:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Crab – an interpreter for a tiny subset of Logo]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 53 | Comments 13 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24559333">thread link</a>) | @beagle3
<br/>
September 22, 2020 | http://beyondloom.com/crab | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://beyondloom.com/crab">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://beyondloom.com/crab</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24559333</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 20:17:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Era of Visual Studio Code]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 510 | Comments 556 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24558788">thread link</a>) | @robenkleene
<br/>
September 22, 2020 | https://blog.robenkleene.com/2020/09/21/the-era-of-visual-studio-code/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.robenkleene.com/2020/09/21/the-era-of-visual-studio-code/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <section id="post">
          <article>
            <header>
              <time datetime="">Monday, Sep 21, 2020</time>
              
            </header>

<p><img src="https://blog.robenkleene.com/assets/2020-09-20-vs-code-hero.png" alt="VS Code Hero"></p>

<p>The most important thing I look for when choosing which tools to use is longevity. Learning software is an investment, and if you have to switch to another application later, you lose some of that investment.</p>

<p>In most software categories, choosing the software with longevity is easy, the most popular tools <a href="https://blog.robenkleene.com/2020/04/27/software-to-die-for/">are usually the ones that have been around the longest</a>. <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-365/excel">Microsoft Excel</a> and <a href="https://www.adobe.com/products/illustrator.html">Adobe Illustrator</a> were both released in 1987 and, for the most part, they’ve remained the most popular software in their categories since then.</p>

<p>Text editors, on the other hand, are a software category where the most popular options are not the oldest. According to the <a href="https://insights.stackoverflow.com/survey/">Stack Overflow Annual Developer Survey</a>, <a href="https://www.sublimetext.com/">Sublime Text</a> was the most popular text editor available on the Mac from 2015–2017. Sublime Text was released in 2008, a sprightly youth compared to Excel and Illustrator. Text editors have been a category with a lot of movement: In the last 20 years, TextMate, Sublime Text, and Atom have all been the text editor with the most momentum<sup id="fnref:whytexteditorshavechurn" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:whytexteditorshavechurn">1</a></sup>. For big complicated desktop software, has any other category ever had so much movement?</p>

<p>I believe the era of new text editors emerging and quickly becoming popular has now ended with <a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/">Visual Studio Code</a>. VS Code has reached unprecedented levels of popularity and refinement, laying a foundation that could mean decades of market dominance. If, like me, one of your priorities for your tools is longevity<sup id="fnref:whynotemacsandvim" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:whynotemacsandvim">2</a></sup>, than that means VS Code might be a great text editor to invest in learning today.</p>

<p>The case for VS Code’s longevity comes from several points we’ll cover in this piece:</p>

<ol>
  <li><a href="#popularity"><strong>Popularity</strong></a>: It’s crossed a popularity threshold that no earlier text editor in recent history has crossed.</li>
  <li><a href="#the-text-editor-as-platform"><strong>The Text Editor as Platform</strong></a>: It’s the endgame of a revolution that saw text editors be remade around extensions.</li>
  <li><a href="https://blog.robenkleene.com/2020/09/21/the-era-of-visual-studio-code/paradigm-transcendence"><strong>Paradigm Transcendence</strong></a>: It’s transcended its paradigm as a desktop app by becoming a hosted web app, and even a reference implementation.</li>
  <li><a href="https://blog.robenkleene.com/2020/09/21/the-era-of-visual-studio-code/company-management"><strong>Company Management</strong></a>: It’s managed by a powerful tech company, and it’s being developed <em>aggressively</em>.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="popularity">Popularity</h2>

<p>VS Code is the most popular text editor today. It’s so popular, that it could be the most popular <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graphical_user_interface">GUI</a> programming tool of all time. <a href="https://insights.stackoverflow.com/survey/2015#tech-editor">Since 2015</a>, Stack Overflow has included questions about text editors in their survey<sup id="fnref:stackoverflowremovedthetexteditorquestions" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:stackoverflowremovedthetexteditorquestions">3</a></sup>. Back then <a href="https://notepad-plus-plus.org/">Notepad++</a> was the most popular text editor, with 34.7% of respondents saying they were “likely to use it”. In the following years, the popularities of different text editors moved around a bit, but nothing ever broke the 40% mark. That is, until its <a href="https://insights.stackoverflow.com/survey/2019#development-environments-and-tools">most recent poll in 2019</a>, when VS Code jumped to 50.7%. This was the second year in a row that VS Code increased by ~45%, this time jumping from <a href="https://insights.stackoverflow.com/survey/2019#development-environments-and-tools">34.9% in 2018</a>, where <em>it had already been the most popular</em>.</p>

<h3 id="text-editor-popularity-20152019">Text Editor Popularity 2015–2019</h3>

<p><img src="https://blog.robenkleene.com/assets/2020-09-20-text-editor-popularity.png" alt="Text Editor Popularity"></p>

<p>(Note that Stackoverflow started allowing multiple answers between 2015 and 2016, so I’d take the changes between those two years in particular with a grain of salt.)</p>

<h2 id="the-text-editor-as-platform">The Text Editor as Platform</h2>

<p>So VS Code is objectively wildly popular; the next point we’re going to look at is more qualitative. For the past couple of decades, text editors have been on a trajectory that I believe VS Code is the final representation of. This is the progression of text editors becoming platforms in their own right by increasing the role and capabilities of extensions. What follows is the history of this progression<sup id="fnref:texteditorprogessionpreviously" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:texteditorprogessionpreviously">4</a></sup>.</p>

<h3 id="pre-2004-bbedit-emacs-and-vim">Pre-2004: BBEdit, Emacs, and Vim</h3>

<p><a href="https://www.barebones.com/products/bbedit/index.html">BBEdit</a>, <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/">Emacs</a>, and <a href="https://www.vim.org/">Vim</a> are all great text editors in their own right, but they all have idiosyncrasies that (while beloved by people like me) prevent them from ever being the <em>most popular</em> text editor.</p>

<p>Emacs, and Vim’s predecessor Vi, were both first released in 1976, before many of todays user-interface conventions were solidified. Predating conventions like using a modifier key with <code>Z</code>, <code>X</code>, <code>C</code>, and <code>V</code> for undo, cut, copy, and paste (keyboard shortcuts that were popularized by the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macintosh#1978%E2%80%9384:_Development_and_introduction">original Macintosh</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windows_1.0">Windows 1.0</a>, released in 1984 and 1985 respectively). Neither Emacs<sup id="fnref:cuamodeinemacs" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:cuamodeinemacs">5</a></sup> or Vim use these keys, and instead use their own terminology. They both use the term “yank” for example (although to mean different things, it’s copy in Vim, and paste in Emacs).</p>

<p>BBEdit was released in 1992, around the time that some of the first GUI tools emerged that would become dynasties. Note the proximity to Excel (1987), Illustrator (1987), and Photoshop (1990). And just like those apps, BBEdit is still relevant today. But unlike those apps, it’s not the most popular in its category, by a wide margin. The reason seems to be at least partially that it never fully adapted to a world where text editors put so much emphasis on package-driven ecosystems.</p>

<h3 id="2004-textmate">2004: TextMate</h3>

<p>TextMate, released in 2004, is arguably the most influential text editor ever. Among the numerous features it popularized are <a href="https://macromates.com/manual/en/snippets">abbreviation-based snippets</a>, <a href="https://macromates.com/manual/en/working_with_text#auto-paired_characters_quotes_etc">automatic paired characters</a>, and <a href="https://macromates.com/manual/en/working_with_multiple_files#moving_between_files_with_grace">fuzzy finding by file name</a>. All of these features became staples in every popular text editor that followed. The implementations of <a href="https://macromates.com/manual/en/scope_selectors">Scope Selectors</a> and <a href="https://macromates.com/manual/en/themes">theming</a> that TextMate pioneered have also formed the basis for themes and syntax highlighting in every subsequent popular text editor.</p>

<p>That’s already a lot to originate from a single app, but it still doesn’t even include TextMate’s most significant innovation; the one that would go on to re-shape text editors, solidify niche status for every text editor that came before it, and pave the way for VS Code to become the most popular text editor in history a decade later. TextMate’s most important innovation was that it was the first popular text editor that was primarily built around <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plug-in_%28computing%29">extensions</a>.</p>

<p>While TextMate popularized the concept of a text editor built around extensions, in hindsight, it didn’t go far enough. TextMate’s extensions had limitations that later text editors would thrive by removing.</p>

<h3 id="2008-sublime-text">2008: Sublime Text</h3>

<p><a href="https://www.sublimetext.com/">Sublime Text</a>, released in 2008, popularized the minimap and multiple cursors. And unlike TextMate and BBEdit, it’s cross-platform, running on Linux, MacOS, and Windows, which helped it reach a wider audience than those editors. But Sublime Text’s biggest impact was greatly expanding the capabilities of extensions.</p>

<p>Sublime Text’s extensions run in an embedded <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Python_(programming_language)">Python</a> runtime with an <a href="https://www.sublimetext.com/docs/3/api_reference.html">extensive API</a>, unlike TextMate which <a href="https://github.com/textmate/bundle-support.tmbundle/blob/13169c6209ebb02564009c4ce573d62452c9b3ae/Support/shared/bin/ruby18">uses the scripting languages built-in to macOS</a>, and <a href="https://macromates.com/manual/en/appendix#plug-in_api">rather than having a proper extension API</a>, mainly centers on processing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Standard_streams">standard out</a>.</p>

<p>Sublime Text greatly expanded what extensions could do, allowing more sophisticated integrations such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lint_(software)">linters</a> that included GUI components. And <a href="https://packagecontrol.io/news">Package Control</a>, the enormously popular package manager for Sublime Text built by <a href="https://twitter.com/wbond/">Will Bond</a><sup id="fnref:sublimehqhire" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:sublimehqhire">6</a></sup>, features a centralized source for package management, reducing the friction to browse, install, and update packages; a model that all subsequent popular text editors would also adopt.</p>

<p>Even with Sublime Text’s expanded extensions, it still didn’t go far enough. Package Control wasn’t built-in, and, while Sublime Text does have an API, its use of Python with custom calls for GUI components still left room for future text editors to make extensions more accessible to build.</p>

<h3 id="2014-atom">2014: Atom</h3>

<p><a href="https://atom.io/">Atom</a>, released by <a href="https://github.com/">GitHub</a> in 2014, finally brings extensions to their final form. Atom’s package manager is built in<sup id="fnref:textmate2hasabuiltinbundlebrowser" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:textmate2hasabuiltinbundlebrowser">7</a></sup>, displays extension <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/README">READMEs</a> complete with inline images (and early extensions made by GitHub themselves popularized the convention of using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GIF">animated GIFs</a> to illustrate functionality), creating an extension experience reminiscent of an <a href="https://www.apple.com/ios/app-store/">app store</a>.</p>

<p>Then there’s the matter of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTML">HTML</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cascading_Style_Sheets">CSS</a>. Atom is built on <a href="https://www.electronjs.org/">Electron</a><sup id="fnref:electronwasmadeforatom" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:electronwasmadeforatom">8</a></sup>, which means the editor itself is written in JavaScript and runs on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Node.js">Node</a><sup id="fnref:atomwaswrittenincoffeescript" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:atomwaswrittenincoffeescript">9</a></sup>. Compared to Sublime Text’s Python API; HTML, CSS, and JavaScript are some of most widely-known languages in existence, which greatly lowers the barrier of entry for creating extensions.</p>

<p>Atom had essentially perfected the extension-based editor, there was just one problem: It’s slow. Performance complaints have plagued Atom since its release, and market ended up split with Sublime Text, which is lightning fast by comparison.</p>

<h3 id="2015-visual-studio-code">2015: Visual Studio Code</h3>

<p>VS Code was released in 2015, based on the <a href="https://microsoft.github.io/monaco-editor/">Monaco Editor</a> that Microsoft had <a href="https://weblogs.asp.net/jongalloway/a-quick-look-at-the-new-visual-studio-online-quot-monaco-quot-code-editor">first released in 2013</a> that could be embedded into websites. When GitHub released Electron along with Atom. Microsoft used it to create a desktop version of the Monaco Editor called Visual Studio Code.</p>

<p>VS Code takes the same formula as Atom<sup id="fnref:vscodeislesshackable" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:vscodeislesshackable">10</a></sup>—a local web-based text editor written in Electron with an emphasis on extensions—and makes it more performant. VS Code makes extensions even more visible, by putting them in the sidebar, raising to the same level as file browsing, searching, source control, and debugging. VS Code extensions can have rich user-interfaces, being written in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, and with full-access to <a href="https://nodejs.org/en/">Node</a>, they can essentially do anything any other application can do. And indeed, <a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=GrapeCity.gc-excelviewer">some</a> <a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=hediet.vscode-drawio">extensions</a> start to look like apps in and of themselves.</p>

<p>With VS Code, the extension-based text editor has seemingly reached its final form. Ever since TextMate, extensions have increased in prominence and capabilities, and with VS Code, that progression appears to have culminated. There just isn’t anywhere else to go. Correspondingly, there isn’t a way a new text editor can leapfrog VS Code the same way previous text editors have been leapfrogging each other by improving extensions.</p>

<h2 id="paradigm-transcendence">Paradigm Transcendence</h2>

<p>So far we’ve looked at VS Code’s popularity, and its extensions implementation, as indicators of longevity. The third indicator we’ll look at is how VS Code has moved beyond the confines of the desktop. The <a href="https://github.com/cdr/code-server"><code>code-server</code></a> project runs VS Code as a regular web app, in other words, hosted on a server and accessed through the browser. GitHub’s <a href="https://github.com/features/codespaces/">Codespaces</a> also run VS Code as a web app, this time by spinning up an ad hoc development environment.</p>

<p>Transcending a …</p></article></section></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.robenkleene.com/2020/09/21/the-era-of-visual-studio-code/">https://blog.robenkleene.com/2020/09/21/the-era-of-visual-studio-code/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.robenkleene.com/2020/09/21/the-era-of-visual-studio-code/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24558788</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 19:30:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The case for comments in code]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 96 | Comments 58 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24556782">thread link</a>) | @pcr910303
<br/>
September 22, 2020 | https://notes.eatonphil.com/the-case-for-comments-in-code.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://notes.eatonphil.com/the-case-for-comments-in-code.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <div>
        <p>When I first started programming, especially when asked for code
samples, my comments lacked purpose and would often duplicate in
English what the code clearly indicated. I knew that "commenting is
good" but as a beginner I had no further insight.</p>
<p>Over time with the help of books like Clean Code, I grew disdainful of
comments. Good code should be self-documenting. Whenever I needed to
write a comment to explain something, I'd realize I could easily
rename some key variable or function. I grew more comfortable with
variables and functions with a few words in the title. Better to spend
time on good code structure and naming.</p>
<p>
  I have always left TODOs though, since TODOs can't so easily be
  expressed in variable names. But even these TODOs concerned me
  because they existed in my issue tracker, or maybe should have.
</p><p>As I watched mature open source projects and mature engineers, I came
to value well-documented pull requests. Solid pull requests include or
link to all necessary background, opportunities failed or ignored, how
to use, links to external bugs requiring workarounds and the results
of performance evaluation.</p>
<p>Beyond pull request descriptions, when I really wanted to grease a
pull request I'd use the pull request UI to add comments calling
reviewer attention to key changes in lines of the diff.</p>
<p>Both kinds of guidance are a massive aid to reviewers, saving a lot of
time.</p>
<p>But when I'd find a bug in code -- and I knew there was good pull
request documentation, even for pull requests as recent as six months
ago -- I've been repeatedly failed by the pull request and <em>pull
request comment</em> search exposed by Github and Gitlab.</p>
<p>I <em>knew</em> there were links to documented oddities or bug reports in
pull request threads. But practically speaking, for historic pull
requests, pull request comments are useless.</p>
<p>This is the single biggest reason I've started to push for more
comments in code. More so than all other tools (issue tracker, code
management system, etc.) comments in code have the greatest chance of
still being around and <em>easily searchable</em> if they haven't been
deleted.</p>
<p>
  Don't get me started on pull request documentation in an external
  medium like Slack. It's so rewarding to get or give instant feedback
  on changes on instant messengers, but good luck finding that
  discussion 3 months later.
</p><p>Every time I have to call out a line of code in a pull request, that's
immediate cause for that code to be modified with comments.</p>
<p>Maybe I wouldn't do this if Github/Gitlab exposed a Google Docs-like
interface for browsing code line by line with links to all pull
request comment threads.</p>
<p>Please reply on Twitter with questions or comments.</p>
<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The biggest reason to add comments in code (often linking to documented oddities or bug reports) is because it's impossible to search pull request threads historically in every source control management UI I've used.<a href="https://t.co/JlHWfbUH5z">https://t.co/JlHWfbUH5z</a></p>— Phil Eaton (@phil_eaton) <a href="https://twitter.com/phil_eaton/status/1303130504993136642?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 8, 2020</a></blockquote> 

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://notes.eatonphil.com/the-case-for-comments-in-code.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24556782</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 16:47:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[No script is too simple]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 257 | Comments 149 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24556022">thread link</a>) | @nicbou
<br/>
September 22, 2020 | https://nicolasbouliane.com/blog/no-script-is-too-simple | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nicolasbouliane.com/blog/no-script-is-too-simple">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                            <div>
        <article>
            <p>
                Posted on <time datetime="2020-09-18 13:43:00">September 18, 2020</time>
            </p>
                        <p>Most of the projects I work on have a <code>scripts</code> directory. For examples, here's are the scripts I use for <a href="https://allaboutberlin.com/">All About Berlin</a>:</p>

<pre>backup-db.sh
clear-static-cache.sh
copy-production-db.sh
restore-db.sh
save-composer-dependencies.sh
</pre>
<p>Those scripts are all very simple. They're under 10 lines long, and take no arguments. Some just call a single command, so why bother creating them?<br></p>
<p><em>What</em> must be done ("start the project", "run the tests" etc.) won't change. <em>How</em> it must be done ("yarn ...", "docker-compose ...") can change multiple time in a project's lifespan. <strong>It's a lot easier to update a single script than to propagate a new set of commands</strong>.</p><p>This script contains the only valid instructions for starting the project. <strong>It's the single source of truth for how to perform that task</strong>. Your colleagues, your CI/CD pipeline, your commit hooks, your cronjobs, your other scripts and your documentation can just refer to <code>start.sh</code>. If you change the script, the new instructions propagate instantly. You don't need to inform your colleagues, update a bunch of Jenkins jobs or update the README. All of it is still up to date. There will be no discrepancies.</p><p>With all those people and machines working off the same scripts, it pays to improve them. You can add usability improvements that will benefit the whole team. You can check the python/node/docker versions, add error handling, remove noise from the output, add colours and headers to build steps, and even interactivity.<br></p><p><strong>Script calls are also more explicit than commands</strong>. A Jenkins job that calls <code></code><code>lint-source.sh &amp;&amp; start.sh &amp;&amp; run-tests.sh &amp;&amp; ...</code> is pretty self-explanatory. A script called <code>create-user.sh</code> is easier to remember than <code>docker-compose exec backend python3 manage.py createsuperuser</code>. This is especially nice when you frequently switch between projects, and constantly need to recall how each one works.<br></p>
                    </article>

                            </div>
            
                        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nicolasbouliane.com/blog/no-script-is-too-simple</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24556022</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 15:55:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Americans don't feel they can get justice when wronged by their ISP – survey]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 246 | Comments 84 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24555525">thread link</a>) | @KaiserSanchez
<br/>
September 22, 2020 | https://fairshake.com/consumer-news/survey-americans-no-justice-against-isps/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://fairshake.com/consumer-news/survey-americans-no-justice-against-isps/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
        <div>
            <section>
                <div>
                    <p><span><img src="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/00-Header-1.jpg" alt="" width="2022" height="1155" srcset="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/00-Header-1.jpg 2022w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/00-Header-1-300x171.jpg 300w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/00-Header-1-1024x585.jpg 1024w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/00-Header-1-768x439.jpg 768w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/00-Header-1-1536x877.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 2022px) 100vw, 2022px" data-srcset="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/00-Header-1.jpg 2022w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/00-Header-1-300x171.jpg 300w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/00-Header-1-1024x585.jpg 1024w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/00-Header-1-768x439.jpg 768w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/00-Header-1-1536x877.jpg 1536w" data-src="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/00-Header-1.jpg" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==">It’s no secret that internet service providers (ISPs) cause plenty of frustration for their customers.</span></p>
<p><span>We recently set out to discover </span><a href="https://fairshake.com/consumer-guides/mapped-the-most-hated-internet-service-providers-in-every-u-s-state/"><span>which ISP was the most-hated in every U.S. state</span></a><span>, and in doing so, we learned more about the types of complaints many people have about their ISPs: billing problems, deceptive pricing, misleading sales tactics, poor service, slow speeds, and more.</span></p>
<p><span>We also got a glimpse of how many people have struggled with these types of problems —&nbsp;our research led us to thousands and thousands of one-star reviews left for ISPs online. It made us start to wonder: Just how widespread </span><i><span>are</span></i><span> these problems? How many people have disputes against their ISP, how many of those disputes go unresolved, and what avenues do consumers pursue to find help?</span></p>
<p><span>And so, we surveyed consumers, and the results were eye-opening. From our survey, we found that it’s possible that more than 20 million American households have unresolved complaints against their ISPs, and that while many of them look to legal action for help, most ultimately don’t end up moving forward —&nbsp;because the process is too expensive, it’s too complicated, or they just don’t know how.</span></p>
<p><span>Our survey results paint a picture of a country where consumers are almost held hostage by their ISPs — many of them experience serious problems, but when they do, they struggle to find avenues to resolution. Here’s everything we found.</span></p>
<h2><span>More Than 1/3 of Households Had a Dispute Against Their ISP in the Last Year</span></h2>
<p><span><img src="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/01-ImageV2.jpg" alt="" width="2022" height="1519" srcset="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/01-ImageV2.jpg 2022w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/01-ImageV2-300x225.jpg 300w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/01-ImageV2-1024x769.jpg 1024w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/01-ImageV2-768x577.jpg 768w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/01-ImageV2-1536x1154.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 2022px) 100vw, 2022px" data-srcset="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/01-ImageV2.jpg 2022w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/01-ImageV2-300x225.jpg 300w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/01-ImageV2-1024x769.jpg 1024w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/01-ImageV2-768x577.jpg 768w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/01-ImageV2-1536x1154.jpg 1536w" data-src="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/01-ImageV2.jpg" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==">In our survey, 37 percent of respondents said that they had had an experience with an ISP in the last year in which they were unfairly charged for service, or otherwise treated unfairly.</span></p>
<p><span>That’s more than one-third of respondents. And when you extrapolate that finding to the 110.57 million U.S. households that </span><a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/183614/us-households-with-broadband-internet-access-since-2009/#:~:text=This%20timeline%20shows%20the%20number,to%2080%20million%20in%202009."><span>had fixed broadband access in 2018</span></a><span>, that’s more than 40 million households with a complaint against their ISP in </span><i><span>just one year</span></i><span> — 40,446,500 of them, to be exact.</span></p>
<h3><span>More Than Half of Those Disputes Went Unresolved</span></h3>
<p><span><img src="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02-ImageV2.jpg" alt="" width="2022" height="1411" srcset="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02-ImageV2.jpg 2022w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02-ImageV2-300x209.jpg 300w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02-ImageV2-1024x715.jpg 1024w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02-ImageV2-768x536.jpg 768w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02-ImageV2-1536x1072.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 2022px) 100vw, 2022px" data-srcset="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02-ImageV2.jpg 2022w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02-ImageV2-300x209.jpg 300w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02-ImageV2-1024x715.jpg 1024w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02-ImageV2-768x536.jpg 768w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02-ImageV2-1536x1072.jpg 1536w" data-src="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/02-ImageV2.jpg" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==">What’s even more shocking is what we found when we asked respondents how their disputes against their ISPs had been handled. More than half of them —&nbsp;50 percent —&nbsp;answered no when asked if the issue was “resolved to their satisfaction.”</span></p>
<p><span>Extrapolate </span><i><span>that</span></i><span> result to all the internet-connected households in the U.S., and this survey finding indicates that as many as 20,371,000 — more than 20 million — U.S. households had an unresolved complaint against their ISP in the last year alone.</span></p>
<p><span>That’s a shocking number, so we wanted more details. We wanted to know how people consider fighting against unfair charges and other complaints, so we dug a little deeper. Here’s what we found.</span></p>
<h3><span>Many People Consider Legal Action, but Most Don’t</span></h3>
<p><span><img src="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/03-ImageV2.jpg" alt="" width="2022" height="1005" srcset="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/03-ImageV2.jpg 2022w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/03-ImageV2-300x149.jpg 300w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/03-ImageV2-1024x509.jpg 1024w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/03-ImageV2-768x382.jpg 768w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/03-ImageV2-1536x763.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 2022px) 100vw, 2022px" data-srcset="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/03-ImageV2.jpg 2022w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/03-ImageV2-300x149.jpg 300w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/03-ImageV2-1024x509.jpg 1024w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/03-ImageV2-768x382.jpg 768w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/03-ImageV2-1536x763.jpg 1536w" data-src="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/03-ImageV2.jpg" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==">According to our survey, a large number of people consider legal action as an avenue for resolving their complaint with an ISP —&nbsp;35 percent of them, or around 7 million households last year.</span></p>
<p><span>But we were shocked to learn that most people just don’t consider taking legal action against their ISP in the event of an unresolved issue.</span></p>
<p><span>Of our survey respondents who said they had unresolved complaints, 65 percent said they didn’t feel the need to pursue legal action — including a lawsuit, a small claims court case, a class action suit, or arbitration —&nbsp;or monetary compensation. Only just over a third, 35 percent, said they did consider legal action.</span></p>
<h3><span>Most People Who Do Consider Legal Action Don’t Go Through With It</span></h3>
<p><span>But most people with complaints against their ISP don’t even reach that point. Of the respondents in our survey who considered legal action:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span>67 percent decided not to move forward with legal action</span></li>
<li><span>21 percent attempted to pursue legal action but were unsuccessful</span></li>
<li><span>13 percent were successful in pursuing legal action against their ISP</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><span><img src="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/04-ImageV2.jpg" alt="" width="2022" height="1575" srcset="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/04-ImageV2.jpg 2022w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/04-ImageV2-300x234.jpg 300w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/04-ImageV2-1024x798.jpg 1024w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/04-ImageV2-768x598.jpg 768w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/04-ImageV2-1536x1196.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 2022px) 100vw, 2022px" data-srcset="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/04-ImageV2.jpg 2022w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/04-ImageV2-300x234.jpg 300w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/04-ImageV2-1024x798.jpg 1024w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/04-ImageV2-768x598.jpg 768w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/04-ImageV2-1536x1196.jpg 1536w" data-src="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/04-ImageV2.jpg" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==">Most People Find Legal Action Too Expensive to Pursue</span></h3>
<p><span>With so many people looking into legal action and then deciding not to pursue it, we wanted to know what made them stop. Here’s what we found.<img src="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/05-ImageV2.jpg" alt="" width="2022" height="1937" srcset="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/05-ImageV2.jpg 2022w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/05-ImageV2-300x287.jpg 300w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/05-ImageV2-1024x981.jpg 1024w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/05-ImageV2-768x736.jpg 768w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/05-ImageV2-1536x1471.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 2022px) 100vw, 2022px" data-srcset="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/05-ImageV2.jpg 2022w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/05-ImageV2-300x287.jpg 300w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/05-ImageV2-1024x981.jpg 1024w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/05-ImageV2-768x736.jpg 768w, https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/05-ImageV2-1536x1471.jpg 1536w" data-src="https://4bvihq1vzfw92gpacq41usu0-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/05-ImageV2.jpg" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></span></p>
<ul>
<li><span>31 percent of respondents said they stopped pursuing legal action when they found the process to be too expensive.</span></li>
<li><span>31 percent stopped because they simply weren’t sure how to proceed.</span></li>
<li><span>22 percent of respondents said they wanted to pursue legal action, but the process was too complicated.</span></li>
<li><span>16 percent of respondents said they needed help pursuing legal action, but couldn’t find the help they needed.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span>That last statistic really stood out for us. More than 16 percent of people were wronged by their ISP and wanted help getting justice, but they couldn’t find the help they needed. That help is out there —&nbsp;or, right here.</span></p>
<h2><span>FairShake Is the Best Way to Get the Justice Your Deserve</span></h2>
<p><span>Getting the justice you deserve against ISPs —&nbsp;and all kinds of other companies —&nbsp;doesn’t have to be long, drawn out, complicated, or expensive. And most importantly, you don’t have to do it alone.</span></p>
<p><span>At </span><a href="https://fairshake.com/"><span>FairShake</span></a><span>, we help consumers avoid expensive and time-consuming court cases, and instead help them pursue arbitration, a process similar to mediation that employs a professional, neutral third party to help reach resolution in a dispute. You just tell us about your complaint, and we’ll create an official legal demand on your behalf. Then, we’ll help guide you through the next legal steps so you’re never left alone or in the dark.</span></p>
<p><span>Ready to get your fair shake against an ISP that let you down? Check out FairShake today.</span></p>
<h2><span>Methodology</span></h2>
<p><span>We surveyed 1,200 American consumers over the age of 18 using PollFish.com between June 15-16, 2020. We asked six total questions about whether they’d had a dispute with their ISP in the last year, whether it was ever resolved, and what they did to try to get justice.</span></p>
<p><span>11 percent of respondents were ages 18 to 24. 17 percent were ages 25 to 34. 22 percent were ages 35 to 44. 19 percent were ages 45 to 54, and 32 percent were 55 and up.</span></p>
<p><span>58 percent identified as female, and 42 percent identified as male.</span></p>
<p><span>To get a bigger-picture view of the scope of some of our survey results, we extrapolated out sample size to the population of the entire U.S., and the number of U.S. households that have fixed broadband home internet access. Our sample size allowed us to apply results to a group the size of the U.S. population with 95 percent confidence and a 5 percent margin of error.</span></p>
                    
                </div>

                
                                
                            </section>

                                                        <section>
                    
                    
                </section>
                                    </div>
    </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://fairshake.com/consumer-news/survey-americans-no-justice-against-isps/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24555525</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 15:21:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[2020 General Election Early Vote Statistics]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 51 | Comments 44 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24553908">thread link</a>) | @blacksqr
<br/>
September 22, 2020 | https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/index.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/index.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>




<!--/.navbar -->




<p>Last updated: 09/25/2020 01:41 AM Eastern Time</p>
<p>Michael McDonald • Professor, University of Florida<br>
Web: <a href="http://www.electproject.org/">United States Elections Project</a> • Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/ElectProject">@ElectProject</a></p>
<p>Detailed state statistics and analyses for reporting states<br>
<a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/CA.html">CA</a> | <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/CO.html">CO</a> | <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/DC.html">DC</a> | <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/FL.html">FL</a> | <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/GA.html">GA</a> | <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/HI.html">HI</a> | <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/IA.html">IA</a> | <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/IL.html">IL</a> | <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/ME.html">ME</a> | <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/MI.html">MI</a> | <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/MN.html">MN</a> | <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/MT.html">MT</a> | <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/NC.html">NC</a> | <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/NJ.html">NJ</a> | <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/NV.html">NV</a> | <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/OH.html">OH</a> | <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/OR.html">OR</a> | <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/PA.html">PA</a> | <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/SC.html">SC</a> | <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/UT.html">UT</a> | <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/VA.html">VA</a> | <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/VT.html">VT</a> | <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/WA.html">WA</a> | <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/WI.html">WI</a></p>
<p>These states are those where I have current data on mail ballot activity. More states will be added as state reports become available.</p>
<div id="summary-statistics-for-reporting-states">
<h2>Summary Statistics for Reporting States</h2>
<div id="mail-ballots-returned-or-in-person-early-votes">
<h3>Mail Ballots Returned or In-Person Early Votes</h3>
<p>Voters have cast a total of <strong>527,502</strong> ballots in the reporting states.</p>


<div id="voted-by-party-registration">
<h4>Voted by Party Registration</h4>
<p>Reporting states with party registration data: FL, IA, NC</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>
Party
</th>
<th>
Count
</th>
<th>
Percent
</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>
Democrats
</td>
<td>
109,903
</td>
<td>
54.5
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
Republicans
</td>
<td>
32,342
</td>
<td>
16.0
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
Minor
</td>
<td>
599
</td>
<td>
0.3
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
No Party Affiliation
</td>
<td>
58,774
</td>
<td>
29.2
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
TOTAL
</td>
<td>
201,618
</td>
<td>
100.0
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
</div>
<div id="mail-ballots-requested">
<h3>Mail Ballots Requested</h3>
<p>Voters have requested a total of <strong>62,621,733</strong> ballots in the reporting states.</p>


<div id="mail-ballots-requested-by-party-registration">
<h4>Mail Ballots Requested by Party Registration</h4>
<p>Reporting states with party registration data: CA, CO, DC, FL, IA, ME, NC, NJ, NV, OR, PA, UT</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>
Party
</th>
<th>
Count
</th>
<th>
Percent
</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>
Democrats
</td>
<td>
20,086,491
</td>
<td>
43.4
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
Republicans
</td>
<td>
12,075,059
</td>
<td>
26.1
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
Minor
</td>
<td>
1,775,868
</td>
<td>
3.8
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
No Party Affiliation
</td>
<td>
12,364,622
</td>
<td>
26.7
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
TOTAL
</td>
<td>
46,302,040
</td>
<td>
100.0
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Registered Democrats have a <strong>8,011,432</strong> ballot request lead over registered Republicans.</p>
<p><em>Note:</em> Party registration statistics are for states that have party registration. These statistics are not actual votes. By federal law, election officials do not begin counting ballots until Election Day, although they may start the process of preparing ballots for counting in advance.</p>
</div>
<div id="mail-ballots-requested-by-race-and-ethnicity">
<h4>Mail Ballots Requested by Race and Ethnicity</h4>
<p>Reporting states with race or ethnicity data: NC, SC</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>
Race
</th>
<th>
Count
</th>
<th>
Percent
</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>
Non-Hispanic White
</td>
<td>
1,595,312
</td>
<td>
61.4
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
Non-Hispanic Black
</td>
<td>
657,913
</td>
<td>
25.3
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
Hispanic
</td>
<td>
54,812
</td>
<td>
2.1
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
Non-Hispanic Asian American
</td>
<td>
69,868
</td>
<td>
2.7
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
Non-Hispanic Native American
</td>
<td>
6,454
</td>
<td>
0.2
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
Other/Multiple/Unknown
</td>
<td>
214,783
</td>
<td>
8.3
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
TOTAL
</td>
<td>
2,599,142
</td>
<td>
100.0
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><em>Note:</em> Race and ethnicity statistics are for states that ask registered voters to provide their race and ethnicity.</p>
</div>
<div id="mail-ballots-requested-by-age">
<h4>Mail Ballots Requested by Age</h4>
<p>Reporting states with age data: CO, OH (partial), PA</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>
Age
</th>
<th>
Count
</th>
<th>
Percent
</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>
18 to 24
</td>
<td>
745,656
</td>
<td>
7.0
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
25 to 34
</td>
<td>
1,425,253
</td>
<td>
13.5
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
35 to 44
</td>
<td>
1,377,856
</td>
<td>
13.0
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
45 to 54
</td>
<td>
1,378,836
</td>
<td>
13.0
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
55 to 64
</td>
<td>
1,898,105
</td>
<td>
17.9
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
65 and up
</td>
<td>
3,763,748
</td>
<td>
35.5
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
TOTAL
</td>
<td>
10,589,454
</td>
<td>
100.0
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
<div id="mail-ballots-requested-by-gender">
<h4>Mail Ballots Requested by Gender</h4>
<p>Reporting states with gender data: CO, NC</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>
Gender
</th>
<th>
Count
</th>
<th>
Percent
</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>
Female
</td>
<td>
837,129
</td>
<td>
52.8
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
Male
</td>
<td>
642,765
</td>
<td>
40.6
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
Unknown
</td>
<td>
104,188
</td>
<td>
6.6
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
TOTAL
</td>
<td>
1,584,082
</td>
<td>
100.0
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
</div>
</div>




</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24553908</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 13:01:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Small Tech]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 206 | Comments 26 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24553085">thread link</a>) | @luu
<br/>
September 22, 2020 | https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/small-tech/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/small-tech/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
  <p>Should you join a big company or start a startup?</p>
<p>This frequently debated question paints a picture of a world where the only choice is between being a cog at a giant semi-monopoly, or taking investment money in the hopes of one day growing to be head cog at a giant semi-monopoly.</p>
<p>Role models matter. So I made a list of small companies that I admire. Neither giants nor startups - just people making a living writing software on their own terms.</p>
<h2 id="sqlite"><a href="https://www.sqlite.org/index.html">sqlite</a></h2>
<p>Sqlite is an existence proof that you don't need a thousand engineers to have an impact. It's been around since the early 90s, is one of the <a href="https://www.sqlite.org/mostdeployed.html">most shipped</a> pieces of software in existence and is widely respected for its <a href="https://www.sqlite.org/testing.html">exceptional testing methodology</a>. Yet it was written almost entirely by a few people:</p>
<pre><span>jamie@machine:~/sqlite$ git shortlog -s -n | head -n 5
 14012	drh
  4297	dan
  1663	danielk1977
  1099	mistachkin
   175	shane
</span></pre>
<p>Their growth plans:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Hwaci is a small company but it is also closely held and debt-free and has low fixed costs, which means that it is largely immune to buy-outs, take-overs, and market down-turns. Hwaci intends to continue operating in its current form, and at roughly its current size until at least the year 2050. We expect to be here when you need us, even if that need is many years in the future.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Sqlite is also interesting because although the code is open source they operate on a cathedral model, generally <a href="https://www.sqlite.org/copyright.html">refusing or rewriting</a> outside contributions.</p>
<h2 id="pinboard"><a href="https://pinboard.in/">pinboard</a></h2>
<p>Pinboard is a single-person operation that has been making a solid income year on year <a href="https://blog.pinboard.in/2019/07/i_cant_stop_winning/">since 2010</a>. It somehow still leaves Maciej enough free time to go around <a href="https://idlewords.com/2019/5/">teaching politicians how to not get hacked</a> and <a href="https://idlewords.com/talks/senate_testimony.2019.5.htm">explaining privacy to the senate</a>. All the while <a href="https://blog.pinboard.in/2017/06/pinboard_acquires_delicious/">destroying his competition</a> using highly advanced tactics such as <a href="http://idlewords.com/talks/fan_is_a_tool_using_animal.htm">listening to his customers</a> and not operating at a loss.</p>
<p>But if Maciej had done nothing else he would still be on this list for his beautiful talk <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5Vt8zqhHe_c">Barely Succeed! It's Easier!</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>We live in a remarkable time when small teams (or even lone programmers) can successfully compete against internet giants. But while the last few years have seen an explosion of product ideas, there has been far less innovation in how to actually build a business. Silicon Valley is stuck in an outdated 'grow or die' mentality that overvalues risk, while investors dismiss sustainable, interesting projects for being too practical. So who needs investors anyway?</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>I'll talk about some alternative definitions of success that are more achievable (and more fun!) than the Silicon Valley casino. It turns out that staying small offers some surprising advantages, not just in the day-to-day experience of work, but in marketing and getting customers to love your project. Best of all, there's plenty more room at the bottom.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>If your goal is to do meaningful work you love, you may be much closer to realizing your dreams than you think.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="tarsnap"><a href="https://www.tarsnap.com/">tarsnap</a></h2>
<p>Another single-person operation, tarsnap has reported been profitable <a href="https://www.tarsnap.com/about.html">since 2009</a> and shows no sign of going anywhere, even lowering it's prices over the years as storage became cheaper. It's saved me on multiple occasions and it's so simple, reliable and cheap that I think of it almost like a utility - tarsnap having an outage would be more surprising to me than water not coming out of my taps.</p>
<p>One of the most interesting things about tarsnap is that it could <a href="https://www.kalzumeus.com/2014/04/03/fantasy-tarsnap/">easily be making more money</a>. If tarsnap had investors or shareholders, they would have <strong>already forced Colin to do so</strong>. In other words, the only reason that Colin gets to continue running the kind of business that he <strong>wants</strong> to run is that he owns it entirely and noone can force him to maximize profit instead.</p>
<h2 id="sublime"><a href="https://www.sublimetext.com/">sublime</a></h2>
<p>Version 1.0 came out in <a href="https://www.sublimetext.com/blog/articles/one-point-oh">2008</a> and they're still going strong today, making enough to <a href="https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/small-tech/">hire an extra developer</a> and <a href="https://www.sublimetext.com/blog/articles/sublime-merge">launch a separate product</a>.</p>
<p>Sublime is notable for surviving despite massive open-source competition in a field where people hate to pay for tools. As <a href="https://thume.ca/2017/03/04/my-text-editor-journey-vim-spacemacs-atom-and-sublime-text/">Tristan Hume points out</a>, it's really the only editor that has managed to remain both fast and consistent while still supporting a large plugin ecosystem. These kind of end-to-end qualities are perhaps one of the main advantages for small teams with a long time horizon.</p>
<h2 id="zig"><a href="https://ziglang.org/">zig</a></h2>
<p>Zig has been around <a href="https://andrewkelley.me/post/full-time-zig.html">only a few years</a> but I'm already wildly impressed by the quality of thought and engineering that has gone into it.</p>
<p>The Zig Software Foundation is a non-profit, currently funded entirely by donations and working towards being able to employ a second full-time developer. They explicitly chose to be a non-profit out of concern over how profit incentives creep into daily decision making:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In You Weren’t Meant to Have a Boss, Paul Graham makes an analogy between animals in the zoo (employees) and animals in the wild (startup founders). I think he’s on to something, but when you start a startup, you still have a boss. In fact, you have the same boss. At the end of the day, it is an inescapable fact that you must do what makes a profit, for the shareholders.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>The difference in incentives makes a structural difference that permeates every part of an organization. Windows users wake up one day and find ads in their start menu. Will Debian Linux ever try to put ads into any of its software? The concept is absurd.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Zig was explicitly designed to be a <a href="https://ziglang.org/#Small-simple-language">small, simple language</a>, allowing it to be maintained indefinitely by a small, committed team.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>ZSF is a small organization and makes efficient use of monetary resources.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>I don’t see the need for ZSF to grow beyond a handful of people.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>As Maciej <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5Vt8zqhHe_c&amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;t=2144">puts it</a>, one of the advantages of being small is that you can speak with a human voice. This comes across clearly from the zig team, who are <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e8f48iYKxgg">resolutely human</a> instead of projecting some impassive facade of professionalism.</p>

</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/small-tech/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24553085</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 11:04:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Bypassing ESP32 Encrypted Secure Boot]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 160 | Comments 58 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24552482">thread link</a>) | @mleonhard
<br/>
September 22, 2020 | https://raelize.com/posts/espressif-esp32-bypassing-encrypted-secure-boot-cve-2020-13629/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://raelize.com/posts/espressif-esp32-bypassing-encrypted-secure-boot-cve-2020-13629/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article><p>We arrived at the last post about our <strong>Fault Injection</strong> research on the <strong>ESP32</strong>. Please read our previous posts as it provides context to the results described in this post.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://raelize.com/posts/espressif-systems-esp32-bypassing-sb-using-emfi/">Espressif ESP32: Bypassing Secure Boot using EMFI</a></li>
<li><a href="https://raelize.com/posts/espressif-systems-esp32-controlling-pc-during-sb/">Espressif ESP32: Controlling PC during Secure Boot</a></li>
<li><a href="https://raelize.com/posts/espressif-systems-esp32-bypassing-flash-encryption/">Espressif ESP32: Bypassing Flash Encryption (CVE-2020-15048)</a></li>
</ul>
<p>During our <strong>Fault Injection</strong> research on the <strong>ESP32</strong>, we gradually took steps forward in order to identify the required vulnerabilities that allowed us to bypass <strong>Secure Boot</strong> and <strong>Flash Encryption</strong> with a single <strong>EM</strong> glitch. Moreover, we did not only achieve <strong>code execution</strong>, we also extracted the <strong>plain-text flash</strong> data from the chip.</p>
<p><strong>Espressif</strong> requested a <strong>CVE</strong>  for the attack described in this post: <a href="https://www.espressif.com/sites/default/files/advisory_downloads/Security%20Advisory%20CVE-2020-15048%2C%2013629%20EN%26CN.pdf" target="_blank">CVE-2020-13629</a>. Please note, that the attack as described in this post, is only applicable to <strong>ESP32</strong> silicon revision 0 and 1. The newer <strong>ESP32 V3</strong> silicon supports functionality to disable the <strong>UART bootloader</strong> that we leveraged for the attack.</p>

<p>The <strong>ESP32</strong> implements an <strong>UART bootloader</strong> in its <strong>ROM code</strong>. This feature allows, among other functionality, to program the external flash. It's not uncommon that such functionality is implemented in the <strong>ROM code</strong> as it's quite robust as the code cannot get corrupt easily. If this functionality would be implemented by code stored in the external flash, any corruption of the flash may result in a bricked device.</p>
<p>Typically, this type of functionality is accessed by booting the chip in a special <strong>boot mode</strong>. The <strong>boot mode</strong> selection is often done using one or more external strap pin(s) which are set before resetting the chip. On the <strong>ESP32</strong> it works exactly like this pin <code>G0</code> which is exposed externally.</p>
<p>The <strong>UART bootloader</strong> supports many interesting <a href="https://github.com/espressif/esptool/wiki/Serial-Protocol#command-opcodes" target="_blank">commands</a> that can be used to read/write memory, read/write registers and even execute a stub from <strong>SRAM</strong>.</p>
<h4 id="executing-arbitrary-code">Executing arbitrary code</h4>
<p>The <strong>UART bootloader</strong> supports loading and executing arbitrary code using the <code>load_ram</code> command. The <strong>ESP32</strong>'s SDK includes all the tooling required to compile the code that can be executed from <strong>SRAM</strong>. For example, the following code snippet will print <code>SRAM CODE\n</code> on the serial interface.</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="C"><span>void</span> <span>__attribute__</span><span>((</span><span>noreturn</span><span>))</span> <span>call_start_cpu0</span><span>()</span>
<span>{</span>
    <span>ets_printf</span><span>(</span><span>"SRAM CODE</span><span>\n</span><span>"</span><span>);</span>
    <span>while</span> <span>(</span><span>1</span><span>);</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div><p>The <code>esptool.py</code> tool, which is part of the <strong>ESP32</strong>'s SDK, can be used to load the compiled binary into the <strong>SRAM</strong> after which it will be executed.</p>
<pre><code>esptool.py --chip esp32 --no-stub --port COM3 load_ram code.bin
</code></pre><p>Interestingly, the <strong>UART bootloader</strong> cannot disabled and therefore always accessible, even when <strong>Secure Boot</strong> and <strong>Flash Encryption</strong> are enabled.</p>
<h4 id="additional-measures">Additional measures</h4>
<p>Obviously, if no additional security measures would be taken, leaving the <strong>UART bootloader</strong> always accessible would render <strong>Secure Boot</strong> and <strong>Flash Encryption</strong> likely useless. Therefore, <strong>Espressif</strong> implemented additional security measures which are enabled using dedicated <strong>eFuses</strong>.</p>
<p>These are security configuration bits implemented in special memory, often referred to as <strong>OTP memory</strong>, which can typically only change from 0 to 1. This guarantees, that once enabled, is enabled forever. The following <strong>OTP memory</strong> bits are used to disable specific functionality when the <strong>ESP32</strong> is in the <strong>UART bootloader</strong> boot mode.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>DISABLE_DL_ENCRYPT</strong>: disables flash encryption operation</li>
<li><strong>DISABLE_DL_DECRYPT</strong>: disables transparent flash decryption</li>
<li><strong>DISABLE_DL_CACHE</strong>: disables the entire MMU flash cache</li>
</ul>
<p>The most relevant <strong>OTP memory</strong> bit is <strong>DISABLE_DL_DECRYPT</strong> as it disables the transparent decryption of the flash data.</p>
<p>If not set, it would be possible to simply access the plain-text flash data while the <strong>ESP32</strong> is in its <strong>UART bootloader</strong> boot mode.</p>
<p>If set, any access to the flash, when the chip is in <strong>UART bootloader</strong> boot mode, will yield just the encrypted data. The <strong>Flash Encryption</strong> feature, which is fully implemented in hardware and transparent to the processor,  is only enabled in when the <strong>ESP32</strong> is in <strong>Normal</strong> boot mode.</p>
<p>The attacks described in this post have all these bits set to 1.</p>

<p>The <strong>SRAM</strong> memory that's used by the <strong>ESP32</strong> is typical technology that's used by many chips. It's commonly used to the <strong>ROM</strong>'s stack and executing the first bootloader from flash. It's convenient to use at early boot as it typically require no configuration before it can be used.</p>
<p>We know from previous experience that the data stored in <strong>SRAM</strong> memory is persistent until it's overwritten or the required power is removed from the physical cells. After a <strong>cold reset</strong> (i.e. power-cycle) of the chip, the <strong>SRAM</strong> will be reset to its default state. This often semi-random and unique per chip as the default value for each bit (i.e. 0 or 1) is different.</p>
<p>However, after a <strong>warm reset</strong>, where the entire chip is reset without removing the power, it may happen that the data stored in <strong>SRAM</strong> remains unaffected. This persistence of the data is visualized in the picture below.</p>
<p>
    <a href="https://raelize.com/img/esp32/esp32-sram-persistence.png">
        <img src="https://raelize.com/img/esp32/esp32-sram-persistence.png" width="700px">
    </a>
</p>
<p>We decided to figure out if this behavior holds up for the <strong>ESP32</strong> as well. We identified that the hardware <a href="https://docs.espressif.com/projects/esp-idf/en/latest/esp32/api-reference/system/wdts.html" target="_blank">watchdog</a> can be used to issue a <strong>warm reset</strong> from software. This <strong>watchdog</strong> can also be issued when the chip is in <strong>UART bootloader</strong> boot mode and therefore we can use it to reset the <strong>ESP32</strong> back into <strong>Normal</strong> boot mode.</p>
<p>Using some test code, loaded and executed in <strong>SRAM</strong> using the <strong>UART bootloader</strong>, we determined that the data in <strong>SRAM</strong> is indeed persistent after issuing a <strong>warm reset</strong> using the <strong>watchdog</strong>. Effectively this means we can boot the <strong>ESP32</strong> in <strong>Normal</strong> boot mode with the <strong>SRAM</strong> filled with controlled data.</p>
<p>But… how can we (ab)use this?</p>

<p>We envisioned that we may be able to leverage the persistence of data in <strong>SRAM</strong> across <strong>warm resets</strong> for an attack. The first attack we came up with is to fill the <strong>SRAM</strong> with code using the <strong>UART bootloader</strong> and issue a <strong>warm reset</strong> using the <strong>watchdog</strong>. Then, we inject a glitch while the <strong>ROM code</strong> is overwriting this code with the <strong>flash bootloader</strong> during a normal boot.</p>
<p>We got this ideas as during our previous experiments, where we <a href="">turned data transfers into code execution</a>, we noticed that for some experiments the chip started executing from the entry address before the bootloader was finished copying.</p>
<p>Sometimes you just need to try it…</p>
<h4 id="attack-code">Attack code</h4>
<p>The code that we load into the <strong>SRAM</strong> using the <strong>UART bootloader</strong> is shown below.</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="C"><span>#define a "addi a6, a6, 1;"
</span><span>#define t a a a a a a a a a a
</span><span>#define h t t t t t t t t t t
</span><span>#define d h h h h h h h h h h
</span><span></span>
<span>void</span> <span>__attribute__</span><span>((</span><span>noreturn</span><span>))</span> <span>call_start_cpu0</span><span>()</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>uint8_t</span> <span>cmd</span><span>;</span>

    <span>ets_printf</span><span>(</span><span>"SRAM CODE</span><span>\n</span><span>"</span><span>);</span>

    <span>while</span> <span>(</span><span>1</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>

        <span>cmd</span> <span>=</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span>
        <span>uart_rx_one_char</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>cmd</span><span>);</span>

        <span>if</span><span>(</span><span>cmd</span> <span>==</span> <span>'A'</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>                                    <span>// 1
</span><span></span>            <span>*</span><span>(</span><span>unsigned</span> <span>int</span> <span>*</span><span>)(</span><span>0x3ff4808c</span><span>)</span> <span>=</span> <span>0x4001f880</span><span>;</span>
            <span>*</span><span>(</span><span>unsigned</span> <span>int</span> <span>*</span><span>)(</span><span>0x3ff48090</span><span>)</span> <span>=</span> <span>0x00003a98</span><span>;</span>
            <span>*</span><span>(</span><span>unsigned</span> <span>int</span> <span>*</span><span>)(</span><span>0x3ff4808c</span><span>)</span> <span>=</span> <span>0xc001f880</span><span>;</span>
        <span>}</span>
    <span>}</span>

    <span>asm</span> <span>volatile</span> <span>(</span> <span>d</span> <span>);</span>                                     <span>// 2
</span><span></span>
    <span>"movi a6, 0x40; slli a6, a6, 24;"</span>                       <span>// 3
</span><span></span>    <span>"movi a7, 0x00; slli a7, a7, 16;"</span>
    <span>"xor a6, a6, a7;"</span>
    <span>"movi a7, 0x7c; slli a7, a7, 8;"</span>
    <span>"xor a6, a6, a7;"</span>
    <span>"movi a7, 0xf8;"</span>
    <span>"xor a6, a6, a7;"</span>

    <span>"movi a10, 0x52; callx8  a6;"</span> <span>// R
</span><span></span>    <span>"movi a10, 0x61; callx8  a6;"</span> <span>// a            
</span><span></span>    <span>"movi a10, 0x65; callx8  a6;"</span> <span>// e               
</span><span></span>    <span>"movi a10, 0x6C; callx8  a6;"</span> <span>// l               
</span><span></span>    <span>"movi a10, 0x69; callx8  a6;"</span> <span>// i               
</span><span></span>    <span>"movi a10, 0x7A; callx8  a6;"</span> <span>// z               
</span><span></span>    <span>"movi a10, 0x65; callx8  a6;"</span> <span>// e               
</span><span></span>    <span>"movi a10, 0x21; callx8  a6;"</span> <span>// !               
</span><span></span>    <span>"movi a10, 0x0a; callx8  a6;"</span> <span>// \n               
</span><span></span>
    <span>while</span><span>(</span><span>1</span><span>);</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div><p>To summarize, the above code implements the following:</p>
<ol>
<li>Command handler with a single command to perform a <strong>watchdog</strong> reset</li>
<li>NOP-like padding using <code>addi</code> instructions</li>
<li>Assembly for printing <code>Raelize!</code> on the serial interface</li>
</ol>
<p>Please note, the listing's numbers match the numbers in the code.</p>
<h4 id="timing">Timing</h4>
<p>We target a reasonably small attack window at the start of <strong>F</strong> which is shown in the picture below. We know from previous experiments that during this moment the <strong>flash bootloader</strong> is copied.</p>
<p>
    <a href="https://raelize.com/img/esp32/esp32-spi-pin1-during-boot.png">
        <img src="https://raelize.com/img/esp32/esp32-spi-pin1-during-boot.png" width="600px">
    </a>
</p>
<p>The glitch must be injected before our code in <strong>SRAM</strong> is entirely overwritten by the valid <strong>flash bootloader</strong>.</p>
<h4 id="attack-cycle">Attack cycle</h4>
<p>We took the following steps for each experiment to determine if the attack idea actually works. A successful glitch will print <code>Raelize!</code> on the serial interface.</p>
<ol>
<li>Set pin <strong>G0</strong> to low and perform a <strong>cold reset</strong> to enter <strong>UART bootloader</strong> boot mode</li>
<li>Use the <code>load_ram</code> command to execute our <strong>attack code</strong> from <strong>SRAM</strong></li>
<li>Send an <code>A</code> to the program to issue a <strong>warm reset</strong> into <strong>normal</strong> boot mode</li>
<li>Inject a glitch while the <strong>flash bootloader</strong> is being copied by the <strong>ROM code</strong></li>
</ol>
<h4 id="results">Results</h4>
<p>After running these experiments for more than a day, resulting in more than 1 million experiments, we did not observe any successful glitch…</p>
<h4 id="an-unexpected-result">An unexpected result</h4>
<p>Nonetheless, while analyzing the results, we noticed something unexpected.</p>
<p>The <strong>serial interface</strong> output for one of the experiments, which is shown below, indicated that the glitch caused an <strong>illegal instruction</strong> exception.</p>
<pre><code>ets Jun  8 2016 00:22:57
rst:0x10 (RTCWDT_RTC_RESET),boot:0x13 (SPI_FAST_FLASH_BOOT)
configsip: 0, SPIWP:0xee
clk_drv:0x00,q_drv:0x00,d_drv:0x00,cs0_drv:0x00,hd_drv:0x00,wp_drv:0x00
mode:DIO, clock div:2
load:0x3fff0008,len:4
load:0x3fff000c,len:3220
load:0x40078000,len:4816
load:0x40080400,len:18640
entry 0x40080740
Fatal exception (0): IllegalInstruction
epc1=0x661b661b, epc2=0x00000000, epc3=0x00000000, 
excvaddr=0x00000000, depc=0x00000000
</code></pre><p>These type of exceptions happened quite often when glitches are injected in a chip. This was not different for the <strong>ESP32</strong>. For most the exceptions the <code>PC</code> register is set to a value that's expected (i.e. a valid address). It does not happen often the <code>PC</code> register is set to such an interesting value.</p>
<p>The <code>Illegal Instruction</code> exception is caused as there is no valid instruction stored at the <code>0x661b661b</code> address. We conclude this value must come from somewhere and that is cannot magically end up in the <code>PC</code> register.</p>
<p>We analyzed the code that we load into the <strong>SRAM</strong> in order to find an explanation. The …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://raelize.com/posts/espressif-esp32-bypassing-encrypted-secure-boot-cve-2020-13629/">https://raelize.com/posts/espressif-esp32-bypassing-encrypted-secure-boot-cve-2020-13629/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://raelize.com/posts/espressif-esp32-bypassing-encrypted-secure-boot-cve-2020-13629/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24552482</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 09:16:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Designing Up Banking]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 107 | Comments 40 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24552043">thread link</a>) | @merricksb
<br/>
September 22, 2020 | https://up.com.au/blog/the-evolutionary-design-of-up/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://up.com.au/blog/the-evolutionary-design-of-up/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section><p>When we launched nearly 2 years ago, we declared our first principles approach to banking:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Challenge the assumptions and limitations in banking and re-evaluate them from a more current point of view."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This statement did not come out of a contrived workshop, or committee, or a board of investors. It was the resonating sentiment of a team that had spent years in the weeds of banking software and its bureaucracy. Existing banks have too much baggage to be able to see the future of banking for what it could be. They lacked the courage to really re-invent themselves. Some questions that emerged from that period:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Why doesn’t every transaction have a timestamp, a merchant logo?</em></li>
<li><em>Why are all my payments to a particular person not grouped?</em></li>
<li><em>Why isn’t it easier to pay someone I’ve paid before?</em></li>
<li><em>Why am I sitting on hold on my phone to resolve an issue?</em></li>
<li><em>How can saving money be fun and engaging?</em></li>
</ul>
<p>We knew that if we followed our noses and solved these user-centric problems, and many others of course, that winning customers would take care of itself. We now have over 280,000 Upsiders and counting.</p>
<h2>Making Feedback Easy</h2>
<p>Up does not do traditional user testing. There, I said it. That’s our dirty secret.</p>
<p>We think there are other techniques that are faster and better indicators of real-world behaviour. We also believe we have two advantages:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>An innovation mindset</strong></li>
<li><strong>A deeper relationship with our customers than any financial institution in Australia</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Much of banking is a known problem space. We feel like we're taking a more creative approach to the problem, but that's not to say we don't rely on user feedback. Our <em>Talk to Us</em> section encourages Upsiders to give us feedback or suggest ideas. To date, we have received over 6,000 ideas via this channel, making it one of the most crucial conduits into the minds of our customers. We also have other highly-engaged channels such as our socials and the newsletter where we hear, almost instantly, what customers think of what we’ve delivered.</p>
<figure>
  <img loading="lazy" src="https://up.com.au/449d9fa0873011802b194d6b669ffe9e/feedback-categories.gif" alt="Initiating a 'Talk to Us' chat with our team">
  <figcaption>
    Our <em>Talk to Us</em> trinity; ask for help, give feedback and report a bug
  </figcaption>
</figure>
<h2>Engagement Is the Name of the Game</h2>
<p>So where do we get our inspiration? It's rarely in the banking or fintech space. These are the apps that exist on billions of devices and set the bar for mobile digital experiences:</p>
<figure>
  <span>
      <a href="https://up.com.au/static/2e11befb2645e3c45227a91f56aed310/c6b2e/inspire_apps.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="World leaders for designing mobile experiences" title="World leaders for designing mobile experiences" src="https://up.com.au/static/2e11befb2645e3c45227a91f56aed310/40619/inspire_apps.jpg" srcset="https://up.com.au/static/2e11befb2645e3c45227a91f56aed310/b0fd2/inspire_apps.jpg 175w,
https://up.com.au/static/2e11befb2645e3c45227a91f56aed310/aaaf9/inspire_apps.jpg 350w,
https://up.com.au/static/2e11befb2645e3c45227a91f56aed310/40619/inspire_apps.jpg 700w,
https://up.com.au/static/2e11befb2645e3c45227a91f56aed310/e8c9e/inspire_apps.jpg 1050w,
https://up.com.au/static/2e11befb2645e3c45227a91f56aed310/5814a/inspire_apps.jpg 1400w,
https://up.com.au/static/2e11befb2645e3c45227a91f56aed310/c6b2e/inspire_apps.jpg 2175w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span>
  <figcaption>
    The leaders in mobile experience design
  </figcaption>
</figure>
<p>While they vary in purpose, their collective dominance in the landscape means they teach and familiarise patterns to expect when using our phones.</p>
<ul>
<li><em>How does TikTok allow you to react to content quickly and effortlessly?</em></li>
<li><em>What similarities are there between Whatsapp, Messenger and Instagram when conversing with friends?</em></li>
<li><em>When explaining new features what language do these platforms use? When do they use visualisations? When do they use words?</em></li>
<li><em>When is Snapchat playful and when is it serious?</em></li>
<li><em>Do I identify with my real name or username for Instagram? What about Facebook?</em></li>
</ul>
<p>As users we immerse ourselves in the apps that have nailed engagement. While acknowledging the patterns they establish, we also appreciate the balance between knowing when to follow them and when to do our own thing. Up has a handful of atypical patterns, but as long as they are usable and intuitive they can become distinct moments used to engage and delight.</p>
<p>Why is it so important that Upsiders engage with the Up app? Aside from the opportunity to nurture a relationship through frequent interactions, we also think that being more engaged with your money encourages better financial literacy. It’s common that people fall into credit trouble by continuing to use their plastic cards without checking their balance regularly. By making Up an engaging experience, we’re making Upsiders more confident and connected to their finances.</p>
<h2>Becoming an Upsider</h2>
<p>We’ve previously deep-dived on our <a href="https://up.com.au/blog/designing-a-super-powered-welcome-pack-experience/">card delivery experience</a>. Before we could even get that far, we had to solve the huge problem of enabling people to sign up for a bank account without leaving the comfort of a mobile app — something that had not been done before in Australia.</p>
<p>We knew that the sheer amount of information we needed from the user was going to be a challenge. Banking is highly regulated in Australia, so we had to cater for many types of identity data (passport, license etc). Most apps can get away with just asking for a username, email and password.</p>
<p>Mobile flows tend to be atomic with a single input per screen, so with identity verification we were anticipating quite a long flow. Our focus was to trim the fat wherever possible, not just by reducing the total number of screens but also by making it easy for people to understand what was being asked of them as they progressed.</p>
<figure>
  <span>
      <a href="https://up.com.au/static/e381b2e19148dfb3bd4e3475c1d71c01/c6b2e/signup-flow.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="Large and complicated data capture flow" title="Large and complicated data capture flow" src="https://up.com.au/static/e381b2e19148dfb3bd4e3475c1d71c01/40619/signup-flow.jpg" srcset="https://up.com.au/static/e381b2e19148dfb3bd4e3475c1d71c01/b0fd2/signup-flow.jpg 175w,
https://up.com.au/static/e381b2e19148dfb3bd4e3475c1d71c01/aaaf9/signup-flow.jpg 350w,
https://up.com.au/static/e381b2e19148dfb3bd4e3475c1d71c01/40619/signup-flow.jpg 700w,
https://up.com.au/static/e381b2e19148dfb3bd4e3475c1d71c01/e8c9e/signup-flow.jpg 1050w,
https://up.com.au/static/e381b2e19148dfb3bd4e3475c1d71c01/5814a/signup-flow.jpg 1400w,
https://up.com.au/static/e381b2e19148dfb3bd4e3475c1d71c01/c6b2e/signup-flow.jpg 2175w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span>
  <figcaption>
    A portion of the Sign-up flow
  </figcaption>
</figure>
<p>We fought to reduce the amount of data we needed to collect. Why does banking need to know your gender? We cut it. Do you need your card sent to a PO Box? We’ll give you a contextual experience based on answers you’ve already provided rather than a scrolling form full of fields. As we tested the new flow amongst ourselves and with beta users from our waitlist, we made a few changes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Anchoring buttons to the bottom of the viewport, and making them full-width. Close to your thumb and easy to hit.</li>
<li>Removing anything extra like images, so you could move faster without distractions.</li>
<li>Using conversational instructions (eg “What is your mobile number?” Instead of “Enter mobile number”). And only using secondary body text when it was really necessary.</li>
<li>Using example text for the input placeholder, so you'd know what the right info looks like.</li>
</ul>
<figure>
  <video autoplay="true" loop="true" muted="true" playsinline="true" alt="Signup flow, before and after">  
    <source type="video/mp4" src="https://up.com.au/85d89ef5fc1450db9c15cb25ceed64d1/signup-flow-tweaks.mp4">
  </video>
  <figcaption>    
    Tweaks made to the signup flow
  </figcaption>
</figure>
<p>All of these small iterations reduced the cognitive load for users and made it feel easy and fast, despite the number of screens. This granularity was important as there isn’t actually a single sign up flow, but several which vary depending on your circumstances and the information we are required to collect.</p>
<h2>Up Yeah!</h2>
<p>Once we became more confident in our onboarding flow and how streamlined it was becoming, you could feel the team were ready to ship it and move onto the next bit of work.</p>
<p>It’s easy to have the blinkers on when you have such a measurable and objective goal — get users into the app in under x time — but stepping back, we made the observation that although we’d nailed sign up speed, something was missing the first time you landed on your activity feed. A moment that should feel significant and celebratory — you’ve literally just opened a bank account in under 3 minutes through your phone — feels clinical and unimpressive. We appreciate great brand moments in digital experiences, most notably MailChimp’s use of emotive design throughout their email software.</p>
<figure>
  <img loading="lazy" src="https://up.com.au/b5b11a8931d184e937662bc553657582/mailchimp.gif" alt="Mailchimp animations">
  <figcaption>  
    Great emotive design through animations by MailChimp
  </figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Email campaigns are stressful exercises — you can’t unsend them once they go out. It’s the nature of the beast. Interestingly, it was the arm of their mascot beast Freddie that was used in these cute but situationally-aware animations. The red button before launch, the high five once your campaign is live, and the rock fist for scheduled campaigns.</p>
<p>Our creative director Pete was eager to create a moment post-signup that made you go “f*ck yeah” in celebration.</p>
<figure>
  <img loading="lazy" src="https://up.com.au/1c642ec78c4396636c3b1bc150d48a29/upyeahmoment-signup.gif" alt="Up Yeah! account created">
  <figcaption>  
    The first of many ‘Up Yeah!’ moments
  </figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Almost immediately after this launched it was being shared by new Upsiders and acknowledged through our feedback channels. Of course you only give yourself an opportunity for these moments if you are nailing the fundamentals. But this reinforcement encouraged us to lean into these seemingly frivolous treatments as a way to delight Upsiders while building a stronger brand.</p>
<h2>Logging in Sucks</h2>
<p>Sometimes the design process involves considering what you don’t see as much as what you do see. For Up, removing the login screen is a great example of this. Banking apps tend to have heavy authentication flows before you see your feed or landing screen. It’s easy to see how this came to be; mobile apps came after desktop banking sites, and so inherited their secure lockdown context. And perhaps it goes back even further back to the mindset of “money belongs in a vault, behind a locked door”.</p>
<p>With all the technological advances in mobile device security, from the humble PIN code to sophisticated biometric recognition, it’s worth questioning some of the assumptions and trade-offs made in the name of security.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Logging in is a big friction point. Especially if we’re trying to help inform you about your finances.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>There’s an interesting distinction that’s prominent in tech — the difference between security and privacy. If we break out of the world of banking apps and look at some of the apps we use each and every day – imagine if you had to enter a passcode every time you opened your email, or your messages? Yet if someone had access to either, they could reset every password you have and really cause you some headaches. We found a helpful albeit simplified distinction when approaching this aspect of the user-experience:</p>
<br>
<table>
    <tbody><tr>
        <td><img loading="lazy" src="https://up.com.au/251bbe56c807fe4657239958a04f14e6/zap-coat.gif" alt="Mailchimp animations">
        </td>
        <td>
          <h3>Privacy</h3>
          Protecting information that is sensitive
          <em> "Read Only"</em>
        </td>
    </tr>
</tbody></table>
<table>
    <tbody><tr>
        <td><img loading="lazy" src="https://up.com.au/6e9f440aae0b397bd198cc1182838ed9/zap-lock.gif" alt="Mailchimp animations">
        </td>
        <td>
          <h3>Security</h3>
          Protecting against being compromised financially
          <em>"Write Access"</em>
        </td>
    </tr>
</tbody></table>

<p>A design decision we’ve made with this framework is removing the need to enter a passcode by default (which can be re-enabled in settings), and also when moving money where there isn’t any risk. Transfering between Savers doesn’t require you to use your phone’s authentication flow (e.g. passcode, Apple’s FaceID or Android’s BioAuth), but moving money into your spending account or sending money outside of your account (e.g. to another bank or via BPay) does.</p>
<p>Our philosophy is to ask for authentication where appropriate to maximise security, while also letting Upsiders enjoy the benefits of being more informed and connected with their money in a low-friction way.  Our push …</p></section></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://up.com.au/blog/the-evolutionary-design-of-up/">https://up.com.au/blog/the-evolutionary-design-of-up/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://up.com.au/blog/the-evolutionary-design-of-up/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24552043</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 07:59:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Mainline Linux on the MikroTik RB3011]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 95 | Comments 40 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24550846">thread link</a>) | @pabs3
<br/>
September 21, 2020 | https://www.earth.li/~noodles/blog/2020/09/rb3011-mainline.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.earth.li/~noodles/blog/2020/09/rb3011-mainline.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
  <p>I upgraded my home internet connection to fibre (FTTP) <a href="https://www.earth.li/~noodles/blog/2019/10/native-ipv6-fttp.html">last October</a>. I’m still on an 80M/20M service, so it’s no faster than my old VDSL FTTC connection was, and as a result for a long time I continued to use my HomeHub 5A running <a href="https://openwrt.org/">OpenWRT</a>. However the FTTP ONT meant I was using up an additional ethernet port on the router, and I was already short, so I ended up with a GigE switch in use as well. Also my wifi is handled by a <a href="https://unifi-network.ui.com/">UniFi</a>, which takes its power via Power-over-Ethernet. That mean I had a router, a switch and a PoE injector all in close proximity. I wanted to reduce the number of devices, and ideally upgrade to something that could scale once I decide to upgrade my FTTP service speed.</p>

<p>Looking around I found the <a href="https://mikrotik.com/product/RB3011UiAS-RM">MikroTik RB3011UiAS-RM</a>, which is a rack mountable device with 10 GigE ports (plus an SFP slot) and a dual core <a href="https://www.qualcomm.com/products/ipq8064">Qualcomm IPQ8064</a> ARM powering it. There’s 1G RAM and 128MB NAND flash, as well as a USB3 port. It also has PoE support. On paper it seemed like an ideal device. I wasn’t particularly interested in running RouterOS on it (the provided software), but that’s based on Linux and there was some work going on within OpenWRT to add support, so it seemed like a worthwhile platform to experiment with (what, you expected this to be about me buying an off the shelf device and using it with only the supplied software?). As an added bonus a friend said he had one he wasn’t using, and was happy to sell it to me for a bargain price.</p>

<p><img alt="RB3011 router in use" src="https://www.earth.li/~noodles/blog/images/2020/rb3011.jpg"></p>

<p>I did try out RouterOS to start with, but I didn’t find it particularly compelling. I’m comfortable configuring firewalling and routing at a Linux command line, and I run some additional services on the router like my <a href="https://www.earth.li/~noodles/blog/2018/05/mqtt-broker.html">MQTT</a> broker, and <a href="https://www.earth.li/~noodles/blog/2018/09/netlink-arp-presence.html">mqtt-arp</a>, my wifi device presence monitor. I could move things around such that they ran on the <a href="https://www.earth.li/~noodles/blog/2019/07/upgrading-the-house-server.html">house server</a>, but I consider them core services and as a result am happier with them on the router.</p>

<p>The first step was to get something booting on the router. Luckily it has an RJ45 serial console port on the back, and a reasonably featured bootloader that can manage to boot via tftp over the network. It wants an ELF binary rather than a plain kernel, but Sergey Sergeev had done the hard work of getting <a href="https://github.com/adron-s/uboot-ipq806x">u-boot working for the IPQ8064</a>, which mean I could just build normal u-boot images to try out.</p>

<p>Linux upstream already had basic support for a lot of the pieces I was interested in. There’s a slight fudge around <code>AUTO_ZRELADDR</code> because the network coprocessors want a chunk of memory at the start of RAM, but there’s ongoing discussions about how to handle this cleanly that I’m hopeful will eventually mean I can drop that hack. Serial, ethernet, the QCA8337 switches (2 sets of 5 ports, tied to different GigE devices on the processor) and the internal NOR all had drivers, so it was a matter of crafting an appropriate DTB to get them working. That left niggles.</p>

<p>First, the second switch is hooked up via SGMII. It turned out the IPQ806x <code>stmmac</code> driver didn’t initialise the clocks in this mode correctly, and neither did the <code>qca8k</code> switch driver. So I need to fix up both of those (Sergey had handled the stmmac driver, so I just had to clean up and submit his patch). Next it turned out the driver for talking to the Qualcomm firmware (SCM) had been updated in a way that broke the old method needed on the IPQ8064. Some git archaeology figured that one out and provided a solution. Ansuel Smith helpfully provided the DWC3 PHY driver for the USB port. That got me to the point I could put a Debian armhf image onto a USB stick and mount that as root, which made debugging much easier.</p>

<p>At this point I started to play with configuring up the device to actually act as a router. I make use of a number of VLANs on my home network, so I wanted to make sure I could support those. Turned out the stmmac driver wasn’t happy reconfiguring its MTU because the IPQ8064 driver doesn’t configure the FIFO sizes. I found what seem to be the correct values and plumbed them in. Then the <code>qca8k</code> driver only supported port bridging. I wanted the ability to have a trunk port to connect to the upstairs switch, while also having ports that only had a single VLAN for local devices. And I wanted the switch to handle this rather than requiring the CPU to bridge the traffic. Thankfully it’s easy to find a copy of the QCA8337 datasheet and the kernel <a href="https://www.kernel.org/doc/html/latest/networking/dsa/index.html">Distributed Switch Architecture</a> is pretty flexible, so I was able to implement the necessary support.</p>

<p>I stuck with Debian on the USB stick for actually putting the device into production. It makes it easier to fix things up if necessary, and the USB stick allows for a full Debian install which would be tricky on the 128M of internal NAND. That means I can use things like <a href="https://wiki.nftables.org/">nftables</a> for my firewalling, and use the standard Debian packages for things like <a href="https://collectd.org/">collectd</a> and <a href="https://mosquitto.org/">mosquitto</a>. Plus for debug I can fire up things like tcpdump or tshark. Which ended up being useful because when I put the device into production I started having weird IPv6 issues that turned out to be a lack of proper Ethernet multicast filter support in the IPQ806x ethernet device. The driver would try and setup the multicast filter for the IPv6 NDP related packets, but it wouldn’t actually work. The fix was to fall back to just receiving all multicast packets - this is what the vendor driver does.</p>

<p>Most of this work will be present once the 5.9 kernel is released - the basics are already in 5.8. Currently not queued up that I can think of are the following:</p>

<ul>
  <li>stmmac IPQ806x FIFO sizes. I sent out an RFC patch for these, but didn’t get any replies. I probably just need to submit this.</li>
  <li>NAND. This is missing support for the QCOM ADM DMA engine. I’ve sent out the patch I found to enable this, and have had some feedback, so I’m hopeful it will get in at some point.</li>
  <li>LCD. AFAICT LCD is an ST7735 device, which has kernel support, but I haven’t spent serious effort getting the SPI configuration to work.</li>
  <li>Touchscreen. Again, this seems to be a zt2046q or similar, which has a kernel driver, but the basic attempts I’ve tried don’t get any response.</li>
  <li>Proper SFP functionality. The IPQ806x has a PCS module, but the stmmac driver doesn’t have an easy way to plumb this in. I have ideas about how to get it working properly (and it can be hacked up with a fixed link config) but it’s not been a high priority.</li>
  <li>Device tree additions. Some of the later bits I’ve enabled aren’t yet in the mainline RB3011 DTB. I’ll submit a patch for that at some point.</li>
</ul>

<p>Overall I consider the device a success, and it’s been entertaining getting it working properly. I’m running a mostly mainline kernel, it’s handling my house traffic without breaking a sweat, and the fact it’s running Debian makes it nice and easy to throw more things on it as I desire. However it turned out the RB3011 isn’t as perfect device as I’d hoped. The PoE support is passive, and the UniFi wants 802.1af. So I was going to end up with 2 devices. As it happened I picked up a cheap <a href="https://eu.dlink.com/uk/en/products/dgs-1210-series-gigabit-smart-plus-switches">D-Link DGS-1210-10P</a> switch, which provides the PoE support as well as some additional switch ports. Plus it runs Linux, so more on that later…</p>

  </article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.earth.li/~noodles/blog/2020/09/rb3011-mainline.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24550846</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 04:27:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[RIP iCloud, Self-Hosting Part 5: Finale]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 53 | Comments 65 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24550197">thread link</a>) | @walterbell
<br/>
September 21, 2020 | https://www.naut.ca/blog/2020/05/05/self-hosting-series-part-5-finale/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.naut.ca/blog/2020/05/05/self-hosting-series-part-5-finale/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><img src="https://www.naut.ca/blog/content/images/2020/05/Screen-Shot-2020-05-05-at-3.30.56-PM.jpeg" width="400px/"></p><p>Just yesterday, I turned off iCloud on <strong>all</strong> my Apple devices. I then took a moment to savour my liberation from Apple's walled garden.</p>
<p>It has been over two years since I first dabbled in hosting my own blog server to finally disabling my iCloud account. There is a good reason as to why it took so long. Apple has cultivated a beautiful hardware+software ecosystem over the years, resulting in an ecosystem filled with magical features such as Apple Pay, Home Sharing, Handoff, and Instant Hotspot. An iCloud account is apparently a requirement for all of those features, which is a shame. I didn't find out until after I logged out and lost those features, but maybe it was for the better. Anyway, here's the proof:<br>
<img src="https://www.naut.ca/blog/content/images/2020/05/Screen-Shot-2020-05-05-at-3.38.39-PM.jpeg" alt="Screen-Shot-2020-05-05-at-3.38.39-PM"><br>
Now this may sound odd, but I feel that the fallbacks and replacements to iCloud features are sometimes easier to understand and give more of a feeling of groundedness, albeit at the cost of convenience. For example, I no longer debate about whether to use Apple Pay or not, and I feel grounded knowing that the physical card is all I need to protect, and that my credit card won't run out of battery. I now plug in a cable to backup my iPhone, and I hear the hard disks on my server grinding away as the files are transferred. I'm confident that something, if anything, is happening. By physically self-hosting emails in the house, I feel secure that a company can't tell me that my account has vanished, a concept that is becoming <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23057365">increasingly common</a>.</p>
<p>As we switched from using physical devices such as floppy disks, CDs, and servers to storing data and logic online, we lost a sense of physicality and tangibility, replaced by an abstract notion of the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8GRPArTor7w">cloud</a>. Most programmers realize that the cloud is not a magical place and are comfortable with the notion, but I've noticed that the cloud instills fear, uncertainty, and doubt in others.</p>
<p>Given that I've been to hell and back setting up a self-hosted cloud (even my programmer friends stare at me quizzically), I sound crazy to mention that this has made things "easier". I'm definitely <strong>not</strong> saying that self-hosting is easier than using iCloud, but it has made me aware of what we are missing. In any interactive system, the true complexity must hide somewhere, and in this case, Apple is offering to manage it for you. In an attempt for trust, security, and ease of use, these services create a greater disconnect between you and your "interactee". To give an example, take transactions between you and a merchant. First there was bartering. Then there was cash. These are both easy to understand, and almost nobody has trouble understanding the end-to-end concepts. However, take Apple Pay. Here's a high-level example of what it actually does:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>NFC Coil in POS Terminal energizes iPhone antenna ⟶ sends data to NFC Chip ⟶ activates iPhone CPU ⟶ requests Face ID unlock ⟶ beams tiny Infrared dots at your face ⟶ Infrared Camera constructs 3D model using Machine Learning model ⟶ decrypts credit card details in Secure Enclave ⟶ creates credit card token ⟶ sends back to iPhone NFC chip ⟶ transmits to POS Terminal ⟶ encrypts with TLS ⟶ sends through internet to the credit card network ⟶ network replies back</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>To reiterate, this is a <em>high-level</em> overview. So yeah, try feeling grounded with that. It's a miracle that it even works.</p>
<h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<p>Overall, my self-hosting series has reduced the FUD surrounding these services for <em>me</em> (and hopefully at least another reader), since I now understand how the software works. I feel it is an accomplishment to be disconnected from Apple, knowing that I'm free to switch hardware whenever I please. Although increased privacy was one of the main reasons I started this series, I haven't really noticed anything different day-to-day. This series has been a very interesting journey, and it will be something that I will continue to explore with future blog posts. As somebody who is now examining iCloud from an outsider perspective for the first time, it is mind-boggling the amount of complexity that Apple manages and exerts power over, such as their COVID-19 Contact Tracing technology. I wonder what the future holds for Apple, and how its values will change over time.</p>
<h3 id="alternativestoicloud">Alternatives to iCloud:</h3>
<p><em>Note: E2EE software with easily exportable data is acceptable, e.g. Firefox Sync</em></p>
<p><strong>Rationale</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.naut.ca/blog/2019/06/19/self-hosting-series-part-1-saying-bye-bye-to-icloud/">Self-Hosting Part 1: Why I'm Ditching iCloud</a></li>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/bugbountywriteup/how-apple-stored-all-your-email-metadata-for-years-on-their-servers-2a61b1a3232d">How Apple store all your email metadata for years on their servers</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>iCloud Mail, Notes</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.naut.ca/blog/2019/10/06/self-hosting-series-part-2-mail-server/">Self-Hosting Part 2: Mail Server</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>iCloud Contacts, Calendar, Reminders</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.naut.ca/blog/2019/11/16/self-hosting-series-part-3-radicale-server/">Self-Hosting Part 3: WebDAV Server</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>iCloud Safari</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2018/11/firefox-sync-privacy/">Firefox Sync</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>iCloud Backup</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.naut.ca/blog/2020/03/20/self-hosting-series-part-4-backup/">Self-Hosting Part 4: iOS + macOS Backup</a></li>
<li><a href="https://support.apple.com/en-ca/HT203977#computer">iTunes Local Backup</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>iCloud Drive</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://9to5mac.com/2019/06/17/ios-13-beta-2-enables-smb-server-connectivity-in-the-files-app/">Samba Server</a></li>
<li><a href="https://nextcloud.com/">NextCloud</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>iCloud Photos</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://nextcloud.com/">NextCloud</a></li>
<li><a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201313">iTunes Photo Sync</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>iCloud Keychain</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://bitwarden.com/">Bitwarden (Self-hosted)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.enpass.io/">Enpass (Self-hosted)</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>iCloud Home</strong><br>
TBD. Currently, HomeKit requires iCloud Keychain to sync with your iOS devices. I am trying to develop a hub that rebroadcasts all HomeKit accessories allowing for multiple devices to connect to the same HomeKit device.</p>
<p><strong>Further Resources</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://roll.urown.net/index.html">Roll Your Own Network</a></li>
</ul>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.naut.ca/blog/2020/05/05/self-hosting-series-part-5-finale/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24550197</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 02:07:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[When feature flags do and don’t make sense (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 96 | Comments 40 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24549917">thread link</a>) | @nomdep
<br/>
September 21, 2020 | https://software.rajivprab.com/2019/12/19/when-feature-flags-do-and-dont-make-sense/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://software.rajivprab.com/2019/12/19/when-feature-flags-do-and-dont-make-sense/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<div><figure><a href="https://www.redbubble.com/i/canvas-print/If-Else-Software-Developer-Joke-Beer-Lover-by-VaSkoy/33140544.5Y5V7" target="_blank"><img data-attachment-id="282" data-permalink="https://software.rajivprab.com/flag/" data-orig-file="https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2019/12/flag.png" data-orig-size="896,1480" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="flag" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2019/12/flag.png?w=182" data-large-file="https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2019/12/flag.png?w=620" src="https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2019/12/flag.png?w=182" alt="" srcset="https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2019/12/flag.png?w=182 182w, https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2019/12/flag.png?w=364 364w, https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2019/12/flag.png?w=91 91w" sizes="(max-width: 182px) 100vw, 182px"></a></figure></div>



<p>Over the past years, I’ve worked in multiple teams adopting very different strategies when it comes to feature flags. I’ve seen the pros and cons of both, and over time, I found myself disagreeing with any fundamentalist position on their use. There is a lot of nuance to this topic, and I think it is worth considering more carefully the various scenarios where feature flags do and do not make sense.</p>



<h2>The Reasons For</h2>



<p>There are a few major scenarios where feature flags make a lot of sense. The first is when it’s used for <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="A/B testing (opens in a new tab)" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A/B_testing" target="_blank">A/B testing</a>, where you absolutely do want different behaviors for different users, based on their randomly assigned treatment. I’ve seen this strategy employed extremely well at Amazon where new features are gated by a “feature flag” that is actually controlled by an internal A/B testing framework. The framework randomly exposes some Amazon customers to the new feature, and then monitors their subsequent behavior in order to estimate the business impact of launching the feature.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I was initially skeptical, but was soon won over by how easy the framework was to use, and the valuable insights it provided on the benefits (or drawbacks) of certain features. “Flavor of the month” decisions were replaced with real data. And none of this is possible without the use of “feature flags” to dynamically toggle new features.</p>



<hr>



<p>Another great use case for feature flags, is when you’re working on a very complex epic that require many different sub-tasks to be completed in different parts of the system. Sub-tasks that are too numerous and invasive to be done in a single pull-request. </p>



<p>In such cases, trying to keep all these disparate changes in side-branches and coordinating a simultaneous merge and deployment, is a recipe for disaster. It’s far more manageable to gate any disruptive changes behind a master flag, merge and deploy all the sub-commits incrementally, and do a flag-flip once all the pieces are in place.</p>



<hr>



<p>One last use case for feature flags, is when you do not have control over your deployments. For example, consider the Facebook Android app, which contains code contributed by hundreds of different teams, all combined and deployed as a single binary. In such scenarios, performing rollbacks can be infeasible. For practical, political, bureaucratic or even marketing reasons. In such cases, feature flags allow your team to toggle new functionality or mitigate risky changes, without having to rollback or deploy any new binaries.</p>



<p><em><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/i5zbvk/when_feature_flags_do_and_dont_make_sense/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Someone on Reddit pointed out</a> a similar use-case for feature flags: targeting a very specific launch date for marketing reasons, while still deploying your code much earlier, in order to ensure stability. You can then have a “dynamic” feature flag that automatically enables itself at a specific time. This is also a great use-case for similar reasons – changing functionality in situations where deploying a new binary is impractical.</em></p>



<h2>Risk Aversion</h2>



<p>The above are all fantastic use cases for feature flags, but I’ve also seen teams get bogged down by policies that overreach in their use. For example, mandating that every single code change should be behind a feature flag, <em>“just in case we made a mistake”</em>.</p>



<p>Risk management should indeed be a priority for all teams. But there are better ways of doing this than relying on feature flags, especially if your team has control over its own deployments. The <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://software.rajivprab.com/2019/04/28/rethinking-software-testing-perspectives-from-the-world-of-hardware/" target="_blank">vast majority of your bugs should be caught by your automated test suite</a> and/or QA process. And the last few stragglers should be handled using <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="incremental deployments, production alarms and rollbacks (opens in a new tab)" href="https://software.rajivprab.com/2019/11/25/the-birth-of-legacy-software-how-change-aversion-feeds-on-itself/" target="_blank">incremental deployments, production alarms and rollbacks</a>.</p>



<p>Besides, as soon as any problem is detected, the recommendation at places like Google is to <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="rollback first and ask questions later (opens in a new tab)" href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/gcp/reliable-releases-and-rollbacks-cre-life-lessons" target="_blank">rollback first and investigate the problem later</a>:</p>



<blockquote><p><em>We have seen this at Google any number of times, where a hastily deployed roll-forward fix either fails to fix the original problem, or indeed makes things worse. Even if it fixes the problem it may then uncover other latent bugs in the system; you’re taking yourself further from a known-good state, into the wilds of a release that hasn’t been subject to the regular strenuous QA testing. At Google, our philosophy is that “rollbacks are normal.” When an error is found or reasonably suspected in a new release, the releasing team rolls back first and investigates the problem second</em></p></blockquote>



<p> When things are on fire, the last thing you want to do is root-cause the bug and figure out which flag-flip will safely fix the problem. And that may not even fix things – there’s no guarantee that even if your teammate tried to put his changes behind a feature flag, he didn’t inadvertently introduce a bug that cannot be solved by a flag-flip.</p>



<p>Feature flags are a poor man’s alternative to binary rollbacks, and they definitely aren’t a substitute for having a great automated test suite and a robust QA process. If you’re relying on feature flags to remedy production bugs, you should stop and evaluate your team’s practices. Risk aversion is often a smell of your team <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="entering into a doom loop which will only get worse and worse with time (opens in a new tab)" href="https://software.rajivprab.com/2019/11/25/the-birth-of-legacy-software-how-change-aversion-feeds-on-itself/" target="_blank">entering into a doom loop which will only get worse and worse with time</a>.</p>



<h2>Death By Feature Flags</h2>



<p>You may be wondering at this point why we shouldn’t use feature flags anyway. After all, <em>“defense in depth” …</em> and it never hurts to have more fine-grain flexibility right?</p>



<p>While feature flags are great in some cases, we should also keep in mind their costs. Software engineering is primarily an exercise in managing complexity. And each feature flag immediately doubles the universe of corner cases that your programmers have to understand, and your code is required to handle. <em>“But what would happen if Foo is enabled, Bar is disabled, and we do independent A/B tests on Baz and Kaz on the same day?”</em> In my experience, this combinatorial explosion in complexity can and <strong>will</strong> lead to bugs. Not to mention slowing down the speed at which your team can make any changes.</p>



<p><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24549917" target="_blank">To quote an amusing anecdote shared online</a>: <em>“A flag that hasn’t been set to off in a year can be masking a major regression. At my last job we had two major outages in as many years from defunct flags defaulting to ‘off’ when the feature flag system failed to return flag states.”</em></p>



<p><em>“But these feature flags are only temporary. You should be removing them as soon as possible!”</em></p>



<p>Sure, and we should also not allow our tech debt to accumulate and we should follow every single best-practice religiously. Unfortunately, this never happens in any corporate environment. Even in great teams, tech debt often gets de-prioritized in the face of new requests. Newcomers to the team or those on their way out, aren’t always disciplined enough to clean up their flags after a successful rollout. And sometimes, these tasks simply slip through the cracks and get forgotten.</p>



<p><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24549917" target="_blank">Someone on HackerNews has pointed out</a> that as of Sept-2020, the release version of Windows <em>“has roughly 2500 feature flags. Some are permanently jammed into the on position, some off position, and the rest are configurable by its experimentation frameworks and hackers”</em>.</p>



<p>There is no better illustration of this than the KCG debacle where a financial firm lost half a billion dollars and almost went bankrupt in 30 minutes, partly due to dead code that was behind a feature flag.</p>



<blockquote><p><a href="https://www.bugsnag.com/blog/bug-day-460m-loss"><em>The cause of the failure</em></a><em> was due to multiple factors. However, one of the most important was that a flag which had previously been used to enable Power Peg… Power Peg had been obsolete since 2003, yet still remained in the codebase some eight years later.</em></p><p><em>In 2005, an alteration was made to the Power Peg code which inadvertently disabled safety-checks which would have prevented such a scenario. However, this update was deployed to a production system at the time, despite no effort having been made to verify that the Power Peg functionality still worked</em></p></blockquote>



<hr>



<p>Feature flags are a powerful tool that can help you experiment with new features, manage the rollout of complex epics, and mitigate the problems associated with not controlling your team’s deployments. </p>



<p>But they come at a significant cost, in the form of code complexity, tech debt, slower development speeds, and inevitably, bugs. </p>



<p>As tempting as it may be, there is no silver bullet here. Weigh the pros against the cons, and use this tool judiciously when it makes sense to do so.</p>



<hr>



<p><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/i5zbvk/when_feature_flags_do_and_dont_make_sense/" target="_blank"><em>Discussion thread on /r/programming</em></a><br><em><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24549917" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Discussion thread on Hacker News</a></em></p>
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://software.rajivprab.com/2019/12/19/when-feature-flags-do-and-dont-make-sense/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24549917</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 01:11:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
