<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 5]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 5. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 12:45:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-5.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 12:45:38 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Case Against Fauci]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 12 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25986443">thread link</a>) | @andrewon
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | https://www.thedriftmag.com/the-case-against-fauci/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.thedriftmag.com/the-case-against-fauci/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                <p><strong>T</strong><span>here is no one in American government — or perhaps any government — quite like Dr. Anthony Fauci. His position, with its mixture of informal power and public visibility, scientific authority and beltway influence, is sui generis. Few other unconfirmed civil servants have access to as many rooms in the executive interagency; no public official commands as much respect in the world of science and medicine. As director of the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID) since 1984, he has advised six presidents (and now a seventh) on domestic and global health issues — HIV/AIDS, SARS, Ebola, Zika, and MERS — and overseen decades of research on infectious disease, pandemics, and virology. Under his stewardship, NIAID’s mission has been reshaped around his personage: its priorities are </span><i><span>his</span></i><span> priorities, its research agenda is </span><i><span>his</span></i><span> research agenda. And that agenda has borne fruit: breakthrough treatments for HIV and other deadly diseases and now, a vaccine for Covid-19. As Stanford microbiologist David Relman told </span><i><span>The</span></i> <i><span>New Yorker</span></i><span> in April, “Tony has essentially become the embodiment of the biomedical and public-health research enterprise in the United States.”</span></p>
<p><span>Although Fauci has no statutory authority to preside over a public health crisis, he has become the nation’s de facto Doctor-in-Chief during this pandemic. His face — elven and expressive — is the face of the medical establishment’s response to the novel coronavirus. I doubt most Americans can name the (</span><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/us-policy/2021/01/20/biden-surgeon-general-resignation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>outgoing</span></a><span>) U.S. Surgeon General, CDC Director, or Fauci’s nominal boss, the director of the National Institutes of Health (Jerome Adams, Robert Redfield, and Francis Collins, respectively), but everyone knows Dr. Fauci. His plaintive but never pessimistic patter and disarming outer-borough rasp are soothing sonic features of our daily dirge of death, doom, and statistics. I was relieved when I first saw Fauci on TV — sometime in March 2020 — thinking dimly to myself, for the millionth time, “Ah, an adult in the room.” Amid a ceaseless current of chaos and grief, Fauci’s egoless display of competence, his grandfatherly warmth and irony, were ports in a storm.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>But a comforting bedside manner has done little to mitigate catastrophe. Over 400,000 Americans are dead, twice as many as any other country. Infections, hospitalizations, and deaths are currently at record highs. And although we have a vaccine, the rollout has already been stymied by a dearth of resources and coordination. As one public health expert told <em>The </em></span><i><span>New York Times </span></i><span>on January 17</span><i><span>,</span></i><span> our pandemic response has been “a colossal failure at every level of government.” And herein lies a paradox. America is suffering from a disease outbreak whose morbid scope is the consequence of world-historic negligence. We are desperately and needlessly sick. And yet, the man known as “America’s Doctor,” the undisputed personification of public health research and pandemic preparedness, faces no reputational consequences. On the contrary, Dr. Fauci remains one of our most beloved public figures.&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>What explains this? Liberals, who otherwise harshly condemn the federal government’s pandemic response, are especially besotted with the diminutive virologist. For fans of the #Resistance, a well-timed </span><a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/dr-anthony-fauci-did-a-facepalm-during-trumps-coronavirus-briefing-2020-3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>facepalm</span></a><span> during one of the Mad King’s early soliloquies guaranteed Fauci’s place on a Mount Rushmore of replacement patriarchs, alongside James Comey and Robert Mueller. (Fauci later insisted the gesture was innocuous; he was merely obscuring his face to dislodge a lozenge from his throat.) Still, Democrats’ devotion has never waned. They see in Fauci a lonely champion of “truth” and “facts” in a White House otherwise hostile to “science.” Brad Pitt earned an Emmy nomination for portraying the 80-year-old physician on Saturday Night Live. One Hamilton-inspired TikTok (“My name is Dr. Anthony Fau-CHEE…”) went viral. Just since the beginning of the “third wave” of Covid infections in October, Fauci has received leadership awards from the National Academy of Medicine, the FBI Agents Association, the Arthur Ashe Institute for Urban Health, and the Boy Scouts of America. Joe Biden has </span><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/12/03/politics/anthony-fauci-biden-transition/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>asked</span></a><span> Fauci to stay on at NIAID and serve in his administration as a chief medical advisor. D.C. Mayor Muriel Bowser proclaimed “Anthony S. Fauci Day” on December 24.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>Fauci’s celebrity, however, cannot obscure empirical reality. As America’s Doctor would surely agree, the numbers don’t lie: 2,824 Americans died of Covid-19 on Anthony S. Fauci Day.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>Anthony Fauci is no doubt a dedicated public servant, respected by his colleagues, beloved by many Americans. But the puzzle remains: why has the man most closely associated with the public health response to the pandemic entirely avoided accountability for its failure?&nbsp;</span></p>

<p><strong>F</strong><span>irst, the most straightforward defense: it wasn’t his fault. He did the best he could, but Fauci’s better instincts were thwarted by Trump and his coterie of idiots. Of course, there’s truth in this. The uneasy peace between Trump and his medical advisors started to unravel almost before it began. By the end of March, Trump was sweating the stocks and tweeting that the “cure” must not be worse “than the problem itself.” He clashed with Fauci throughout the spring — over masks, hydroxychloroquine, school openings, and Easter. By summer, Trump was publicly lambasting the good doctor, leaking anti-Fauci talking points to the press and sidelining him in task force meetings, which were themselves increasingly rare. Scott Atlas, the libertarian radiologist and herd-immunity advocate whom Trump hired based on his Fox News appearances, was calling the shots.</span></p>
<p><span>But Fauci seldom contradicted the president’s lies outright, opting for tact and de-escalation instead. “I can’t jump in front of the microphone and push him down,” Fauci </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/mar/23/dr-fauci-press-conference-white-house-coronavirus" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>said</span></a><span> in late March. “OK, he said it. Let’s try and get it corrected for the next time.” On July 4, Trump said 99 percent of Covid cases were “harmless.” Fauci characterized this as a misinterpretation. (“I’m trying to figure out where the president got that number…” he said.) Though Fauci has a reputation for bluntness, as the </span><i><span>Financial Times</span></i><span>’s Hannah Kuchler </span><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/57834c2c-a078-4736-9173-8fb32cfbbf4e" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>observed</span></a><span>, “he clearly also tries to hold back, believing he will make a bigger difference to the course of the pandemic if he keeps his job.”</span></p>
<p><span>This logic pervades the most common defense of Fauci’s record. “Tony is unique, in that he has such credibility with politicians that he’s been able to insert hard facts into the conversation,” Nobel laureate biologist David Baltimore told </span><i><span>The</span></i> <i><span>New Yorker</span></i><span> in April. “That has been wonderful for our country and the world.” In this view, Fauci was </span><i><span>handling</span></i><span> Trump, just as he handled previous presidents, including a reluctant Ronald Reagan during the AIDS epidemic. When he pulls his punches, it’s always for the greater good; namely, the cause of remaining in the room. Stepping too far out of line, contradicting Trump with too much vigor, would have imperiled his standing. “The argument for Fauci saying more,” </span><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2020/07/16/anthony-fauci-built-truce-trump-is-destroying-it/?arc404=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>wrote</span></a><span> Molly Roberts in <em>The</em> </span><i><span>Washington Post</span></i><span>, “… is also an argument for self-exile.” And then what? Truth and facts would have had no advocate inside the White House. As Fauci himself </span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/24/health/fauci-trump-covid.html?action=click&amp;module=Top%20Stories&amp;pgtype=Homepage" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>told</span></a><span> the </span><i><span>Times</span></i><span> on Sunday, “I felt that if I stepped down, that would leave a void. Someone’s got to not be afraid to speak out the truth.”</span></p>
<p><span>At a briefing in July, Trump </span><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/07/28/politics/donald-trump-anthony-fauci-approval-rating/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>mused</span></a><span>, “It’s interesting: [Fauci’s] got a very good approval rating. And I like that, it’s good. Because remember, he’s working for this administration. He’s working with us.” Winding his way to his point, Trump said, “So why don’t I have a high approval rating… with respect to the virus?” After a pause, he deadpanned, “It can only be my personality, that’s all.”&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>As is often the case with Trump, he had a point, just not the one he meant. The liberal apologia for Fauci </span><i><span>was</span></i><span> internally contradictory. As one scientist said to me, “We can’t deify Fauci’s response to the pandemic as fantastic while simultaneously condemning Trump, when for months, the two were hand in hand.” Indeed, Fauci is only blameless if he was utterly powerless to stop the administration’s disastrous plans. And if he </span><i><span>was</span></i><span> powerless, he should’ve resigned and communicated the truth bluntly to the public long ago. Otherwise, he knowingly lent credibility to an abject failure he couldn’t control.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>To put an even finer point on it, the precise conditions that would maximally exonerate Fauci — i.e., Trump is solely at fault; Fauci had no influence — are conditions under which Fauci </span><i><span>absolutely </span></i><span>should have bolted. The more aberrant Trump’s behavior, the more he diverged from the medically prudent course of action, the greater Fauci’s responsibility to leave and blow the whistle. If Fauci knew better but didn’t say, what use was he inside the room? If he </span><i><span>didn’t</span></i><span> know better, then he shares the blame.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>In recent days, Fauci and Covid task force coordinator Dr. Deborah Birx — another veteran AIDS researcher who’s received slightly </span><a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2020/11/18/biden-coronavirus-team-deborah-birx-437923" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>less deferential</span></a><span> treatment from the media than her male counterpart — have undertaken a goodwill tour. Birx </span><a href="https://twitter.com/FaceTheNation/status/1353332977560735744?s=20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>told</span></a><span> CBS that denialists in the White House “derailed” the pandemic response, putting out information she knew to be false. Fauci joked with Rachel Maddow that Trump had </span><a href="https://www.msnbc.com/rachel-maddow/watch/fauci-to-maddow-i-ve-been-wanting-to-come-on-your-show-for-months-and-months-99905093921" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>forbidden</span></a><span>&nbsp;him from coming on her show and </span><a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/2021/01/21/anthony-fauci-speaking-covid-liberating-under-biden-vs-trump/4244169001/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>told</span></a><span> the White House press corps, “The idea that you can get up here and… let the science speak, it is somewhat of a liberating feeling.” Meanwhile, liberal pundits like Ezra Klein have </span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/18/opinion/biden-covid-19-plan.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>praised</span></a><span> Biden’s “maddeningly obvious” Covid plans, describing their simplicity as a “damning indictment” of Trump’s negligence. But if Biden’s life-saving interventions are so straightforward and crucial, why weren’t Fauci and Birx loudly demanding them months ago?&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>“To keep their jobs” should not be a satisfying answer — not for the living or for the dead.&nbsp;</span></p>

<p><strong>F</strong><span>rank assessments of Fauci’s performance are hard to come by. Those in a position to judge him from an informed public …</span></p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.thedriftmag.com/the-case-against-fauci/">https://www.thedriftmag.com/the-case-against-fauci/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.thedriftmag.com/the-case-against-fauci/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25986443</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 07:30:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[gemini:// Space]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 105 | Comments 56 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25986378">thread link</a>) | @pabs3
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | https://spwhitton.name//blog/entry/geminispace/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://spwhitton.name//blog/entry/geminispace/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div class="page">







<div id="pagebody">

<div id="content">
<p>Recently I have become curious about <a href="https://gemini.circumlunar.space/">the Gemini
Project</a> and the content that people have
made available to be retrieved over the gemini:// protocol.  I’m not convinced
by the arguments for not just using http, and mostly it’s just that I
typically find more things that I am interested in casually reading through on
people’s gemlogs than I would on, say, reddit, and similar aggregators.  But
presumably advocates of gemini:// and the text/gemini format would argue that
it’s various respects in which it differs from the web that makes geminispace
conducive to the production of the sort of content you find there.  So I’m
remaining open minded about the possibility that having a completely separate
protocol is important, and not just an annoyance because rss2email doesn’t
work and I had to spend time writing
<a href="https://manpages.debian.org/gmi2email">gmi2email</a>.</p>

<p>I now have a games console at home for the first time in some years, which I
bought in response to the ongoing pandemic, and one thing that I have noticed
is that using it feels like being offline in a way that playing games on a
regular computer never would.  It has a WiFi connection but it doesn’t have a
web browser, and I am glad that using it provides an opportunity to be
disconnected from the usual streams of information.  And perhaps something
similar ought to be said in favour of how the Gemini project does not just use
http.  There is, perhaps, a positive psychological effect induced by making
the boundary between text/gemini and the web as hard as it is made by using
gemini:// rather than http.</p>

<p>Something about which I find myself much more sceptical is how the
specification for gemini:// and text/gemini is not extensible.  Advocates of
Gemini have this idea that they can’t include, say, a version number in the
protocol, because the extensibility of the web is what has led to the problems
they think it has, so they want to make it impossible.  Now on the one hand
perhaps the people behind Gemini are in the best position that anyone is in to
come up with a spec which they will finalise and render effectively
unchangeable, because a lot of them have been using Gopher for decades, and so
they have enough experience to be able to say exactly what Gopher is missing,
and be confident that they’ve not missed anything.  But on the other hand,
Gemini is one technological piece in attempts to make a version of the
Internet which is healthier for humans – the so-called “small Internet”
movement – and maybe there will be new ideas about how the small Internet
should be which would benefit from a new version of the Gemini specification.
So it seems risky to lock-in to one version.</p>

<p><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25986378">Comments on Hacker News</a>.</p>

</div>









</div>



</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://spwhitton.name//blog/entry/geminispace/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25986378</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 07:14:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Counterfeiting Stock – Explaining illegal naked shorting and stock manipulation]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 183 | Comments 132 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25986320">thread link</a>) | @lelf
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | http://counterfeitingstock.com/CS2.0/CounterfeitingStock.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://counterfeitingstock.com/CS2.0/CounterfeitingStock.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">


<center><b>Counterfeiting Stock 2.0</b></center>

<p>
Illegal naked shorting and stock manipulation are two of Wall Street's deep, dark secrets. These practices have been around for decades and have resulted in trillions of dollars being fleeced from the American public by Wall Street. In the process, many emerging companies have been put out of business. This report will explain the magnitude of this problem, how it happens, why it has been covered up and how short sellers attack a company. It will also show how all of the participants; the short hedge funds, the prime brokers and the Depository Trust Clearing Corp. (DTCC)—make unconscionable profits while the fleecing of the small American investor continues unabated.
</p>
<p>
<span>Why is This Important?</span> This problem affects the investing public. Whether invested directly in the stock market or in mutual funds, IRAs, retirement or pension plans that hold stock — it touches the majority of Americans.
</p>
<p>
The participants in this fraud, which, when fully exposed, will make Enron look like child's play, have been very successful in maintaining a veil of secrecy and impenetrability. Congress and the SEC have unknowingly (?) helped keep the closet door closed. The public rarely knows when its pocket is being picked as unexplained drops in stock price get chalked up to “market forces” when they are often market manipulations.
</p>
<p>
The stocks most frequently targeted are those of emerging companies who went to the stock market to raise start–up capital. Small business brings the vast majority of innovative new ideas and products to market and creates the majority of new jobs in the United States. It is estimated that over 1000 of these emerging companies have been put into bankruptcy or had their stock driven to pennies by predatory short sellers. 
</p>
<p>
It is important to understand that selling a stock short is not an investment in American enterprise. A short seller makes money when the stock price goes down and that money comes solely from investors who have purchased the company's stock. A successful short manipulation takes money from investment in American enterprise and diverts it to feed Wall Street's insatiable greed—the company that was attacked is worse off and the investing public has lost money. Frequently this profit is diverted to off–shore tax havens and no taxes are paid. This national disgrace is a parasite on the greatest capital market in the world.
</p>
<p>
<span>A Glossary of Illogical Terms</span> — The securities industry has its own jargon, laws and practices that may require explaining. Most of these concepts are the creation of the industry, and, while they are promoted as practices that ensure an orderly market, they are also exploited as manipulative tools. This glossary is limited to naked short abuse, or counterfeiting stock as it is more correctly referred to. 
</p>

<ol>
<li><b>Broker Dealer or Prime Broker</b> — The big stockbrokers who clear their own transactions, which is to say they move transacted shares between their customers directly, or with the DTC. Small brokers will clear through a clearing house — also known as a broker's broker.
</li>
<li><b>Hedge Funds</b> — Hedge funds are really unregulated investment pools for rich investors. They have grown exponentially in the past decade and now number over 10,000 and manage over one trillion dollars. They don't register with the SEC, are virtually unregulated and frequently foreign domiciled, yet they are allowed to be market makers with access to all of the naked shorting loopholes. Frequently they operate secretively and collusively. The prime brokers cater to the hedge funds and allegedly receive eight to ten billion dollars annually in fees and charges relating to stock lend to the short hedge funds.
</li>
<li><b>Market Maker</b> — A broker, broker dealer or hedge fund who makes a market in a stock. In order to be a market maker, they must always have shares available to buy and sell. Market makers get certain sweeping exemptions from SEC rules involving naked shorting.
</li>
<li><b>Short Seller</b> — An individual, hedge fund, broker or institution who sells stock short. The group of short sellers is referred to as “the shorts.”
</li>
<li><b>The Securities and Exchange Commission</b> — The SEC is the federal enforcement agency that oversees the securities markets. The top–level management is a five–person Board of Governors who are Presidential appointees. Three of the governors are usually from the securities industry, including the chairman. The SEC adopted Regulation SHO in January 2005 in an attempt to curb naked short abuse.
</li>
<li><b>Depository Trust Clearing Corp</b> — Usually known as the DTCC, this privately held company is owned by the prime brokers and it clears, transacts and holds most stock in this country. It has four subsidiaries, which include the DTC and the NCSS. The operation of this company is described in detail later.
</li>
<li><b>Short Sale</b> — Selling a stock short is a way to make a profit while the stock price declines. For example: If investor S wishes to sell short, he borrows a share from the account of investor L. Investor S immediately sells that share on the open market, so investor S now has the cash from the sale in his account, and investor L has an IOU for the share from investor S. When the stock price drops, investor S takes some of the money from his account and buys a share, called “covering”, which he returns to investor L's account. Investor S books a profit and investor L has his share back.
<p>This relatively simple process is perfectly legal—so far. The investor lending the share most likely doesn't even know the share left his account, since it is all electronic and occurs at the prime broker or DTC level. If shares are in a margin account, they may be loaned to a short without the consent or knowledge of the account owner. If the shares are in a cash account, IRA account or are restricted shares they are not supposed to be borrowed unless there is express consent by the account owner.
</p></li>
<li><b>Disclosed Short</b> — When the share has been borrowed or a suitable share has been located that can be borrowed, it is a disclosed short. Shorts are either naked or disclosed, but, in reality, some disclosed shorts are really naked shorts as a result of fraudulent stock borrowing. 
</li>
<li><b>Naked Short</b> — This is an invention of the securities industry that is a license to create counterfeit shares. In the context of this document, a share created that has the effect of increasing the number of shares that are in the market place beyond the number issued by the company, is considered counterfeit. This is not a legal conclusion, since some shares we consider counterfeit are legal based upon today's rules. The alleged justification for naked shorting is to insure an orderly and smooth market, but all too often it is used to create a virtually unlimited supply of counterfeit shares, which leads to widespread stock manipulation—the lynchpin of this massive fraud. 
<p>
Returning to our example, everything is the same except the part about borrowing the share from someone else's account: There is no borrowed share — instead a new one is created by either the broker dealer or the DTC. Without a borrowed share behind the short sale, a naked short is really a counterfeit share.
</p></li>
<li><b>Fails–to–Deliver</b> — The process of creating shares via naked shorting creates an obvious imbalance in the market as the sell side is artificially increased with naked short shares or more accurately, counterfeit shares. Time limits are imposed that dictate how long the sold share can be naked. For a stock market investor or trader, that time limit is three days. According to SEC rules, if the broker dealer has not located a share to borrow, they are supposed to take cash in the short account and purchase a share in the open market. This is called a “buy–in,” and it is supposed to maintain the total number of shares in the market place equal to the number of shares the company has issued.
<p>
Market makers have special exemptions from the rules: they are allowed to carry a naked short for up to twenty–one trading days before they have to borrow a share. When the share is not borrowed in the allotted time and a buy–in does not occur, and they rarely do, the naked short becomes a fail–to–deliver (of the borrowed share).
</p></li>
<li><b>Options</b> — The stock market also has separate, but related markets that sell options to purchase shares (a “call”) and options to sell shares (a “put”). Options are an integral part of short manipulations, the result of SEC promulgated loopholes in Reg SHO. A call works as follows: Assume investor L has a share in his account that is worth $25. He may sell an option to purchase that share to a third party. That option will be at a specific price, say $30, and expires at a specific future date. Investor L will get some cash from selling this option. If at the expiration date, the market value of the stock is below $30 (the “strike price”), the option expires as worthless and investor L keeps the option payment. This is called “out of the money.” If the market value of the stock is above the strike price, then the buyer of the option “calls” the stock. Assume the stock has risen to $40. The option buyer tenders $30 to investor L and demands delivery of the share, which he may keep or immediately sell for a $10 profit.
</li>
<li><b>Naked call</b> — The same as above except that investor L, who sells the call, has no shares in his account. In other words, he is selling an option on something he does not own. The SEC allows this. SEC rules also allow the seller of a naked short to treat the purchase of a naked call as a borrowed share, thereby keeping their naked short off the SEC's fails–to–deliver list. A share of stock that has a naked call as its borrowed shares is marked as a disclosed short when it is sold, even though nobody in the transaction actually owns a share.
</li>
</ol>




<p>
<span>How The System Transacts Stocks</span> — This explanation has been greatly simplified in the interest of brevity. 
</p>

<img src="http://counterfeitingstock.com/CS2.0/diagram.png">

<ol>
<li><b>Customers</b> — These can be individuals, institutions, hedge funds and prime broker's house accounts.</li></ol></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://counterfeitingstock.com/CS2.0/CounterfeitingStock.html">http://counterfeitingstock.com/CS2.0/CounterfeitingStock.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://counterfeitingstock.com/CS2.0/CounterfeitingStock.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25986320</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 06:59:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What the F#]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 75 | Comments 43 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25986316">thread link</a>) | @sidcool
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | https://onurgumus.github.io/2021/01/31/What-the-F.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://onurgumus.github.io/2021/01/31/What-the-F.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content-wrapper">
      <div>
         <section id="main-content">
            

<p>In a previous <a href="https://onurgumus.github.io/2020/12/26/Functional-Programming.html">post</a> I have explained my motivations for functional programming.
It’s no secret I love F# because F# makes me sleep better. In this post, I would like to discuss some different aspects of F#.</p>

<h2 id="f-is-gaining-independence-from-net">F# is gaining independence from .NET</h2>

<p><img src="https://onurgumus.github.io/assets/posts/2021-01-31-What-the-F/platform.png" alt="F# platforms"></p>

<!--more-->

<p>F# is mostly known to the developer community as the small ignored brother of C# running on the .NET platform. However, what is less known about F# is that it
has come to a level to be .NET independent. Thanks to <a href="https://fable.io/">Fable</a>, today F# can be considered as a complete replacement of TypeScript. Yes,
people do write full-blown SPA, React, Svelte applications by using F# instead of TypeScript. If you think Fable is just a transpiler, think again:  https://github.com/kunjee17/awesome-fable . I would say Fable is on the way being an ecosystem by itself.</p>

<p>There is also a new prototype target for Fable that allows F# code to transpile to Python developed by Dag Brattli.</p>

<p><img src="https://onurgumus.github.io/assets/posts/2021-01-31-What-the-F/python2.gif" alt="Python"></p>

<p>F# also works as on WebAssembly with <a href="https://fsbolero.io/">Bolero</a> which is still based on .NET. And not to forget another F# web platform called <a href="https://websharper.com/">WebSharper</a> from the same people who developed Bolero.</p>

<p>Just like JavaScript people were using NodeJs to bring the front-end devs to the backend zone, F# also can be used to bring the backend-devs to the front-end realm. I am a living example myself. By using F# in the font-end you can practically share the code between your .NET/Node backend and the browser, giving you an isomorphic development experience.</p>

<p>This somewhat puts F# in an interesting position as historically most dotnet has been languages are managed by Microsoft. But Fable simply liberates
F# from Microsoft and .NET.</p>

<h2 id="the-f-fanboys">The F# fanboys</h2>

<p>You might have heard “one of those guys” like me who is talking about how great functional programming and/or F# is. And from that point, it looks like below</p>

<p><img src="https://onurgumus.github.io/assets/posts/2021-01-31-What-the-F/music.png" alt="music"></p>

<p>I know it’s annoying, however, let’s look at it from the side and this is how an F# developer feels when he or she is suggesting you using F#:
<img src="https://onurgumus.github.io/assets/posts/2021-01-31-What-the-F/wheel.png" alt="wheels"></p>

<h2 id="microsofts-and-communitys-stance">Microsoft’s and community’s stance</h2>

<p>From Microsoft’s point of view, F# is actively supported and maintained. There are Microsoft developers actively fixing things and adding new features however as a general Microsoft’s point of view .NET == C# and that is that. From .NET developer community’s
point of view, things are even worse. Since all Microsoft docs and tools geared towards C#, adding up unfamiliarity with the functional paradigm, most people follow C# way and completely ignore its little brother F#. I still think this is a missed 
opportunity for the .NET community. For example, let’s look at the excellent server side F# web framework <a href="https://giraffe.wiki/">Giraffe</a>. 
While C# and asp.net developers are busy memorizing the Microsoft way of handling requests, learning what attributes to decorate their
classes and members, the F# developers who use giraffe, simply rely on functional composition:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>let</span> <span>app</span> <span>=</span>
    <span>route</span> <span>"/"</span>
    <span>&gt;=&gt;</span> <span>setHttpHeader</span> <span>"X-Foo"</span> <span>"Bar"</span>
    <span>&gt;=&gt;</span> <span>setStatusCode</span> <span>200</span>
    <span>&gt;=&gt;</span> <span>setBodyFromString</span> <span>"Hello World"</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>As HTTP processing is usually treated as a pipeline by itself on the server-side, it’s an excellent target for functional programming. Just like lego, plug-in your pipes, and you are good to go.</p>

<p>Furthermore, most developers worry about if they could find an F# job whereas companies who consider making the switch worry if they could find an F# developer.
As of today on linked in there are approximately 700 F# jobs and even most of these are not F# specific rather than they are like “C# or F# developers wanted”.</p>

<p>And most non-.NET people are not willing to touch anything related to Microsoft even with a 10 foot pole. (Of course, the major exceptions to this are TypeScript and Visual Studio Code which both are widely popular). The  Functional programmers’ camp also dismisses F# at sight blaming it’s not like Haskell as in for example F# does not support type classes.</p>

<h2 id="couple-of-unique-features-of-f">Couple of unique features of F#</h2>

<p>I am not going to talk about the features of F# but just wanted to highlight a couple of them.</p>

<p>The first one is the file order. Please look at the below photo:</p>

<p><img src="https://onurgumus.github.io/assets/posts/2021-01-31-What-the-F/files.png" alt="file-order"></p>

<p>In F# the order of the files matter. It is somewhat a disliked feature by the newcomers, but it makes the dependencies immediately visible.
So the code in the top file has no dependency on any others below and the 2nd file from the top only depends on the first. When you open a project which you are not 
familiar, file ordering helps to find your way.</p>

<p>The second one is Type Providers:</p>

<p><img src="https://onurgumus.github.io/assets/posts/2021-01-31-What-the-F/sqlprovider.gif" alt="type-providers"></p>

<p>Type providers are somewhat code generators but they do that non-intrusively. Very roughly similar to LISP style macros they expand at compile time. Type providers make it very easy to discover HTML or JSON documents read database rows, file system, and discover DDL and rows within the coding screen without leaving your editor. And everything becomes so type-safe.</p>

<h2 id="develop-fantastic-ui-apps-with-f-and-elmish">Develop fantastic UI apps with F# and Elmish</h2>

<p>Well they say seeing is believing, so let’s see how well F# handles UI development. While React devs on Facebook trying to solve the state problem over and over again by using hooks and perhaps new experimental
recoil and contexts IMHO, all are horrible options as they encourage rendering code inter-mix with business code reminding me asp.net web forms times where you could write your SQL statements right into the page itself.</p>

<p>F# developers have ported elm architecture to something called elmish and it flourished well among F# community.</p>

<p>Here’s a list of things you can do with Elmish as you can write your business code once and port it to any UI platform below:</p>

<ul>
  <li>React: <a href="https://github.com/elmish/react">Elmish React</a></li>
  <li>Windows Desktop: <a href="https://github.com/elmish/Elmish.WPF">Elmish WPF</a></li>
  <li>Gaming: <a href="https://github.com/ChrisPritchard/Xelmish">Xelmish</a></li>
  <li>Cross platform UI: <a href="https://github.com/AvaloniaCommunity/Avalonia.FuncUI">Avalonia.FuncUI</a></li>
  <li>Mobile development: <a href="https://github.com/fsprojects/Fabulous">Fabulous</a></li>
  <li>Terminal: <a href="https://github.com/DieselMeister/Terminal.Gui.Elmish">Terminal.Gui.Elmish</a></li>
  <li>Web Assembly: <a href="https://fsbolero.io/">Bolero</a></li>
</ul>

<p>They all share the same single architecture: Elmish. So you can write your code for one and port it to another.</p>

<h2 id="getting-started-and-some-resources">Getting started and some resources</h2>

<p>If you want to get started to F#, the first place you should check out is <a href="https://fsharp.org/">F# Software Foundation</a></p>

<p><img src="https://onurgumus.github.io/assets/posts/2021-01-31-What-the-F/fsf2.png" alt="fsharp-foundation"></p>

<p>As you can see FSharp Software Foundation offers mentorship programs periodically, which means you can have a free weekly 1 on 1 session with an experienced F# developer! As of today the program is open for people who want to have an F# mentor or want to be
an F# mentor. You can apply from <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdKgZaAcjf7ZxVqBZzyZcBi609BOc0etBnV5XhR6BMihdyYRw/viewform">here</a>.</p>

<p>If you are sold with F# there is one important point to highlight. Do not treat F#, just another language with different syntax especially if you are familiar
with Python, Ruby, JavaScript, C#, etc. You have to embrace functional programming as a paradigm. F# is a functional-first programming language. In other words,
although F# has OOP syntax as well, it mostly makes sense to use F# when you want to get benefit from functional programming concepts. If you try to program
F# the same way you program other imperative languages you won’t get much benefit.</p>

<p>If you are a C# develeoper and you want to start functional programming with F# this is the go-to book:
<em>Disclaimer: I do not know the author nor I am affiliated with the publisher by any way</em></p>

<p><a href="https://www.manning.com/books/functional-programming-in-c-sharp">Functional programming in C#</a></p>

<p>Although the book is mostly about C#, it will show you how painful to do functional programming with C# and only perhaps then you can develop
some love for F#. Having that said it will also help you to understand some more new coming but confusing features of C# 9 like Records and Pattern matching.
If you think  C# records are for immutability, no they are not. They are for Value semantics and <a href="https://www.sitepoint.com/what-is-referential-transparency/#:~:text=In%20functional%20programming%2C%20referential%20transparency,the%20result%20of%20the%20program.">referential transparency</a>.</p>

<p>To try F# right away you may use the following links:</p>

<p>https://try.fsharp.org/</p>

<p>https://fable.io/repl/</p>

<p>https://tryfsharp.fsbolero.io/</p>

<h2 id="syntax">Syntax</h2>

<p>When you are unfamiliar with F# syntax, it might look a bit cryptic. And I have seen some people complained that it is very verbose. On the contrary, I would make a bold claim that F# beats most other languages when it comes to conciseness. You don’t believe me? see it your self (make sure you check all implementations)</p>

<p><a href="https://rosettacode.org/wiki/Category:F_Sharp">F# problems on Rosetta Code</a></p>

<h2 id="a-couple-of-toy-projects-of-mine">A couple of toy projects of mine</h2>

<p>I have developed commercial applications with F#, but as public stuff here are a couple of projects I have built. One is a full blazor/web assembly project:</p>

<p>https://github.com/OnurGumus/FBlazorShop</p>

<p>And the actual app for the 3D bin packing problem, in which items of different volumes must be packed into a finite number of bins or containers each of a fixed given volume in a way that minimizes the number of bins used.</p>

<p>https://github.com/OnurGumus/BinDrake</p>

<p>http://bindrake.com/</p>

<p>Trying and learning F# really requires you to dismiss your prejudices and be patient. But in the end, once you master the functional paradigm,
it makes you sleep better as a developer.</p>


             
            
            
            
                  
         </section>
         
      </div>
   </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://onurgumus.github.io/2021/01/31/What-the-F.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25986316</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[195 gigapixel 360-degree panorama of Shanghai]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 11 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25986212">thread link</a>) | @lelf
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | http://pf.bigpixel.cn/zh-CN/pano/771906131130847232.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://pf.bigpixel.cn/zh-CN/pano/771906131130847232.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div id="id_pano_ad"><div></div></div><p>大像素看世界第4期：上海</p><p>陆家嘴是上海的经济脉动中心，也是向世界展示中国经济腾飞的窗口。受上海市新闻办的邀请，大像素团队为其创作上海互联网城市名片。</p><div><p> 最热评论</p><a id="social-comment" target="_blank" href="http://pf.bigpixel.cn/zh-CN/downapp.html"><div><p> 暂无评论 </p></div></a><p><a target="_blank" href="http://pf.bigpixel.cn/zh-CN/downapp.html"> 更多 ...</a></p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://pf.bigpixel.cn/zh-CN/pano/771906131130847232.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25986212</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 06:37:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[This is How Google will Collapse (2017)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 43 | Comments 28 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25985843">thread link</a>) | @partingshots
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | https://www.googliath.org/this-is-how-google-will-collapse-by-daniel-colin-james/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.googliath.org/this-is-how-google-will-collapse-by-daniel-colin-james/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
<!-- ARTICAL CONTENT -->
                                                        <h2>Reporting from the very near, post-Google future</h2>
<p>Google made almost all its money from ads. It was a booming business — until it wasn’t. Here’s how things looked right before the most spectacular crash the technology industry had ever seen.<br>
The crumbling of Google’s cornerstone</p>
<p>Search was Google’s only unambiguous win, as well as its primary source of revenue, so when Amazon rapidly surpassed Google as the top product search destination, Google’s foundations began to falter. As many noted at the time, the online advertising industry experienced a major shift from search to discovery in the mid-2010s.</p>
<p>While Google protected its monopoly on the dying search advertising market, Facebook — Google’s biggest competitor in the online advertising space — got on the right side of the trend and dominated online advertising with its in-feed native display advertising.</p>
<p><a href="https://hackernoon.com/how-google-collapsed-b6ffa82198ee" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Read the full article here.</a></p>
                                                    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.googliath.org/this-is-how-google-will-collapse-by-daniel-colin-james/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25985843</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 05:32:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[That’s Big Sir to You]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 39 | Comments 33 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25984970">thread link</a>) | @zdw
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | https://www.shirtpocket.com/blog/index.php/shadedgrey/thats_big_sir_to_you/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.shirtpocket.com/blog/index.php/shadedgrey/thats_big_sir_to_you/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.shirtpocket.com/blog/index.php/shadedgrey/thats_big_sir_to_you/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25984970</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 02:43:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Doctor Do-Little – The Case Against Anthony Fauci]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 8 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25983611">thread link</a>) | @mhb
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | https://www.thedriftmag.com/the-case-against-fauci/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.thedriftmag.com/the-case-against-fauci/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                <p><strong>T</strong><span>here is no one in American government — or perhaps any government — quite like Dr. Anthony Fauci. His position, with its mixture of informal power and public visibility, scientific authority and beltway influence, is sui generis. Few other unconfirmed civil servants have access to as many rooms in the executive interagency; no public official commands as much respect in the world of science and medicine. As director of the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID) since 1984, he has advised six presidents (and now a seventh) on domestic and global health issues — HIV/AIDS, SARS, Ebola, Zika, and MERS — and overseen decades of research on infectious disease, pandemics, and virology. Under his stewardship, NIAID’s mission has been reshaped around his personage: its priorities are </span><i><span>his</span></i><span> priorities, its research agenda is </span><i><span>his</span></i><span> research agenda. And that agenda has borne fruit: breakthrough treatments for HIV and other deadly diseases and now, a vaccine for Covid-19. As Stanford microbiologist David Relman told </span><i><span>The</span></i> <i><span>New Yorker</span></i><span> in April, “Tony has essentially become the embodiment of the biomedical and public-health research enterprise in the United States.”</span></p>
<p><span>Although Fauci has no statutory authority to preside over a public health crisis, he has become the nation’s de facto Doctor-in-Chief during this pandemic. His face — elven and expressive — is the face of the medical establishment’s response to the novel coronavirus. I doubt most Americans can name the (</span><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/us-policy/2021/01/20/biden-surgeon-general-resignation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>outgoing</span></a><span>) U.S. Surgeon General, CDC Director, or Fauci’s nominal boss, the director of the National Institutes of Health (Jerome Adams, Robert Redfield, and Francis Collins, respectively), but everyone knows Dr. Fauci. His plaintive but never pessimistic patter and disarming outer-borough rasp are soothing sonic features of our daily dirge of death, doom, and statistics. I was relieved when I first saw Fauci on TV — sometime in March 2020 — thinking dimly to myself, for the millionth time, “Ah, an adult in the room.” Amid a ceaseless current of chaos and grief, Fauci’s egoless display of competence, his grandfatherly warmth and irony, were ports in a storm.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>But a comforting bedside manner has done little to mitigate catastrophe. Over 400,000 Americans are dead, twice as many as any other country. Infections, hospitalizations, and deaths are currently at record highs. And although we have a vaccine, the rollout has already been stymied by a dearth of resources and coordination. As one public health expert told <em>The </em></span><i><span>New York Times </span></i><span>on January 17</span><i><span>,</span></i><span> our pandemic response has been “a colossal failure at every level of government.” And herein lies a paradox. America is suffering from a disease outbreak whose morbid scope is the consequence of world-historic negligence. We are desperately and needlessly sick. And yet, the man known as “America’s Doctor,” the undisputed personification of public health research and pandemic preparedness, faces no reputational consequences. On the contrary, Dr. Fauci remains one of our most beloved public figures.&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>What explains this? Liberals, who otherwise harshly condemn the federal government’s pandemic response, are especially besotted with the diminutive virologist. For fans of the #Resistance, a well-timed </span><a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/dr-anthony-fauci-did-a-facepalm-during-trumps-coronavirus-briefing-2020-3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>facepalm</span></a><span> during one of the Mad King’s early soliloquies guaranteed Fauci’s place on a Mount Rushmore of replacement patriarchs, alongside James Comey and Robert Mueller. (Fauci later insisted the gesture was innocuous; he was merely obscuring his face to dislodge a lozenge from his throat.) Still, Democrats’ devotion has never waned. They see in Fauci a lonely champion of “truth” and “facts” in a White House otherwise hostile to “science.” Brad Pitt earned an Emmy nomination for portraying the 80-year-old physician on Saturday Night Live. One Hamilton-inspired TikTok (“My name is Dr. Anthony Fau-CHEE…”) went viral. Just since the beginning of the “third wave” of Covid infections in October, Fauci has received leadership awards from the National Academy of Medicine, the FBI Agents Association, the Arthur Ashe Institute for Urban Health, and the Boy Scouts of America. Joe Biden has </span><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/12/03/politics/anthony-fauci-biden-transition/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>asked</span></a><span> Fauci to stay on at NIAID and serve in his administration as a chief medical advisor. D.C. Mayor Muriel Bowser proclaimed “Anthony S. Fauci Day” on December 24.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>Fauci’s celebrity, however, cannot obscure empirical reality. As America’s Doctor would surely agree, the numbers don’t lie: 2,824 Americans died of Covid-19 on Anthony S. Fauci Day.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>Anthony Fauci is no doubt a dedicated public servant, respected by his colleagues, beloved by many Americans. But the puzzle remains: why has the man most closely associated with the public health response to the pandemic entirely avoided accountability for its failure?&nbsp;</span></p>

<p><strong>F</strong><span>irst, the most straightforward defense: it wasn’t his fault. He did the best he could, but Fauci’s better instincts were thwarted by Trump and his coterie of idiots. Of course, there’s truth in this. The uneasy peace between Trump and his medical advisors started to unravel almost before it began. By the end of March, Trump was sweating the stocks and tweeting that the “cure” must not be worse “than the problem itself.” He clashed with Fauci throughout the spring — over masks, hydroxychloroquine, school openings, and Easter. By summer, Trump was publicly lambasting the good doctor, leaking anti-Fauci talking points to the press and sidelining him in task force meetings, which were themselves increasingly rare. Scott Atlas, the libertarian radiologist and herd-immunity advocate whom Trump hired based on his Fox News appearances, was calling the shots.</span></p>
<p><span>But Fauci seldom contradicted the president’s lies outright, opting for tact and de-escalation instead. “I can’t jump in front of the microphone and push him down,” Fauci </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/mar/23/dr-fauci-press-conference-white-house-coronavirus" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>said</span></a><span> in late March. “OK, he said it. Let’s try and get it corrected for the next time.” On July 4, Trump said 99 percent of Covid cases were “harmless.” Fauci characterized this as a misinterpretation. (“I’m trying to figure out where the president got that number…” he said.) Though Fauci has a reputation for bluntness, as the </span><i><span>Financial Times</span></i><span>’s Hannah Kuchler </span><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/57834c2c-a078-4736-9173-8fb32cfbbf4e" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>observed</span></a><span>, “he clearly also tries to hold back, believing he will make a bigger difference to the course of the pandemic if he keeps his job.”</span></p>
<p><span>This logic pervades the most common defense of Fauci’s record. “Tony is unique, in that he has such credibility with politicians that he’s been able to insert hard facts into the conversation,” Nobel laureate biologist David Baltimore told </span><i><span>The</span></i> <i><span>New Yorker</span></i><span> in April. “That has been wonderful for our country and the world.” In this view, Fauci was </span><i><span>handling</span></i><span> Trump, just as he handled previous presidents, including a reluctant Ronald Reagan during the AIDS epidemic. When he pulls his punches, it’s always for the greater good; namely, the cause of remaining in the room. Stepping too far out of line, contradicting Trump with too much vigor, would have imperiled his standing. “The argument for Fauci saying more,” </span><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2020/07/16/anthony-fauci-built-truce-trump-is-destroying-it/?arc404=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>wrote</span></a><span> Molly Roberts in <em>The</em> </span><i><span>Washington Post</span></i><span>, “… is also an argument for self-exile.” And then what? Truth and facts would have had no advocate inside the White House. As Fauci himself </span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/24/health/fauci-trump-covid.html?action=click&amp;module=Top%20Stories&amp;pgtype=Homepage" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>told</span></a><span> the </span><i><span>Times</span></i><span> on Sunday, “I felt that if I stepped down, that would leave a void. Someone’s got to not be afraid to speak out the truth.”</span></p>
<p><span>At a briefing in July, Trump </span><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/07/28/politics/donald-trump-anthony-fauci-approval-rating/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>mused</span></a><span>, “It’s interesting: [Fauci’s] got a very good approval rating. And I like that, it’s good. Because remember, he’s working for this administration. He’s working with us.” Winding his way to his point, Trump said, “So why don’t I have a high approval rating… with respect to the virus?” After a pause, he deadpanned, “It can only be my personality, that’s all.”&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>As is often the case with Trump, he had a point, just not the one he meant. The liberal apologia for Fauci </span><i><span>was</span></i><span> internally contradictory. As one scientist said to me, “We can’t deify Fauci’s response to the pandemic as fantastic while simultaneously condemning Trump, when for months, the two were hand in hand.” Indeed, Fauci is only blameless if he was utterly powerless to stop the administration’s disastrous plans. And if he </span><i><span>was</span></i><span> powerless, he should’ve resigned and communicated the truth bluntly to the public long ago. Otherwise, he knowingly lent credibility to an abject failure he couldn’t control.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>To put an even finer point on it, the precise conditions that would maximally exonerate Fauci — i.e., Trump is solely at fault; Fauci had no influence — are conditions under which Fauci </span><i><span>absolutely </span></i><span>should have bolted. The more aberrant Trump’s behavior, the more he diverged from the medically prudent course of action, the greater Fauci’s responsibility to leave and blow the whistle. If Fauci knew better but didn’t say, what use was he inside the room? If he </span><i><span>didn’t</span></i><span> know better, then he shares the blame.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>In recent days, Fauci and Covid task force coordinator Dr. Deborah Birx — another veteran AIDS researcher who’s received slightly </span><a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2020/11/18/biden-coronavirus-team-deborah-birx-437923" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>less deferential</span></a><span> treatment from the media than her male counterpart — have undertaken a goodwill tour. Birx </span><a href="https://twitter.com/FaceTheNation/status/1353332977560735744?s=20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>told</span></a><span> CBS that denialists in the White House “derailed” the pandemic response, putting out information she knew to be false. Fauci joked with Rachel Maddow that Trump had </span><a href="https://www.msnbc.com/rachel-maddow/watch/fauci-to-maddow-i-ve-been-wanting-to-come-on-your-show-for-months-and-months-99905093921" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>forbidden</span></a><span>&nbsp;him from coming on her show and </span><a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/2021/01/21/anthony-fauci-speaking-covid-liberating-under-biden-vs-trump/4244169001/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>told</span></a><span> the White House press corps, “The idea that you can get up here and… let the science speak, it is somewhat of a liberating feeling.” Meanwhile, liberal pundits like Ezra Klein have </span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/18/opinion/biden-covid-19-plan.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>praised</span></a><span> Biden’s “maddeningly obvious” Covid plans, describing their simplicity as a “damning indictment” of Trump’s negligence. But if Biden’s life-saving interventions are so straightforward and crucial, why weren’t Fauci and Birx loudly demanding them months ago?&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>“To keep their jobs” should not be a satisfying answer — not for the living or for the dead.&nbsp;</span></p>

<p><strong>F</strong><span>rank assessments of Fauci’s performance are hard to come by. Those in a position to judge him from an informed public …</span></p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.thedriftmag.com/the-case-against-fauci/">https://www.thedriftmag.com/the-case-against-fauci/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.thedriftmag.com/the-case-against-fauci/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25983611</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 23:18:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[NES.css – NES-Style CSS Framework]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 553 | Comments 89 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25982999">thread link</a>) | @dsego
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | https://nostalgic-css.github.io/NES.css/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nostalgic-css.github.io/NES.css/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          <a :class="{ active:  scrollPos < 200 }" href="https://github.com/nostalgic-css/NES.css" target="_blank" rel="noopener" @mouseover="startAnimate" @mouseout="stopAnimate">
            <p>Fork me<br>on GitHub</p>
            <i :class="animateOctocat ? 'animate' : ''"></i>
          </a>

          <!-- About -->
          <section>
            <h2 id="about"><a href="#about">#</a>About</h2>
            <p>NES.css is NES-style (8bit-like) CSS Framework.</p>
          </section>


          <!-- Installation -->
          <section>
            <h2 id="installation"><a href="#installation">#</a>Installation</h2>
            <p>NES.css is available via either npm or Yarn, or a CDN.</p>
            <p>Please read <a href="https://github.com/nostalgic-css/NES.css" target="_blank" rel="noopener">README.md</a>.</p>
          </section>

          <!-- Usage -->
          <section>
            <h2 id="usage"><a href="#usage">#</a>Usage</h2>
            <p>NES.css only provides components. You will need to define your own layout.</p>

            <section v-for="sample in collection" :key="sample">
              <section>
                <h3>{{ sample.title | capitalize }}</h3>
                
                <p v-if="sample.description">{{ sample.description }}</p>
                <p v-if="sample.note">{{ sample.note }}</p>
                
              </section>
              <section v-show="sample.showCode">
                
                <pre><code>{{ sample.code }}</code></pre>
              </section>
            </section>
          </section>

          <!-- Members -->
          <section>
            <h2 id="members"><a href="#members">#</a>Members</h2>
            <section>
              <h3><i></i>Core Team Members</h3>
              <p>Here is core team members developing NES.css.</p>

              
            </section>
            <section v-if="emeriti.length > 0">
              <h3><i></i>Core Team Emeriti</h3>
              <p>Here we honor some no-longer-active core team members.</p>

              
            </section>
            <section>
              <h3><i></i>Contributors</h3>
              <template v-for="user in contributors">
                <a class="contributor" :href="'https://github.com/' + user" target="_black">
                  <img class="nes-avatar is-large is-rounded lazy" :data-src="'https://github.com/' + user + '.png?size=64'" :alt="'Contributor ' + user">
                  <p>{{ user }}</p>
                </a>
              </template>
            </section>
          </section>

          <!-- Articles -->
          <section>
              <h2 id="articles"><a href="#articles">#</a>Articles</h2>
              <article>
                <h3>
                  <a href="https://medium.com/@bc_rikko/why-i-created-and-released-nes-css-ee8966bacd09" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i></i><span>Why I created and released NES.css</span></a>
                </h3>
              </article>
              <article>
                <h3>
                  <a href="https://github.blog/2019-01-20-release-radar-december-2018/#nes-css-1-0" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i></i><span>Release Radar·December 2018|The GitHub Blog</span></a>
                </h3>
              </article>
          </section>

        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nostalgic-css.github.io/NES.css/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25982999</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 22:04:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[WhatsApp and the Domestication of Users]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 155 | Comments 94 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25982860">thread link</a>) | @upofadown
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | https://seirdy.one/2021/01/27/whatsapp-and-the-domestication-of-users.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://seirdy.one/2021/01/27/whatsapp-and-the-domestication-of-users.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemscope="" itemtype="https://schema.org/BlogPosting">
	<article itemprop="mainEntityOfPage">
		
		<section itemprop="articlebody">
			<p>I have never used WhatsApp, and never will. Despite this, I still feel the need to write an article about WhatsApp since it’s the perfect case study to help understand a class of businesses models I call “user domestication”. The domestication of users is high on my list of problems plaguing the human race, and is worth a detailed explanation.</p>
<p>WhatsApp wasn’t the first instant messenger of its kind, and probably won’t be the last. I simply chose to focus on WhatsApp since its recent privacy issues have made it a hot topic.</p>
<p>With the meta-explanation out of the way, let us begin.</p>
<h2 id="whatsapps-rise">WhatsApp’s rise</h2>
<p>For those unfamiliar, WhatsApp is a tool that makes it convenient and easy to help Facebook further its core mission: the optimization and auctioning of human behavior (colloquially known as “targeted advertising”). It originally persuaded people to consent to this by allowing them to send text to each other over the Internet, something that was <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_of_instant_messaging_protocols">already possible</a>, and combining an easy-to-learn UI with successful marketing. It then expanded to include features such as free voice and video calls. Free calls helped it grow to become the de-facto communication platform many regions. I’m stunned at its ubiquity every time I visit my extended family in India; I’m frequently greeted by looks of confusion when I remind them that I don’t use WhatsApp.</p>
<p>Having its own proprietary chat system incompatible with other clients allowed WhatsApp to build a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_effect">network effect</a>: WhatsApp’s existing users were held captive by the fact that leaving WhatsApp meant losing the ability to communicate with WhatsApp users. People switching from WhatsApp must convince all their friends to switch, too; this includes less technically inclined friends who had a hard time learning WhatsApp in the first place.</p>
<p>In a WhatsApp world, people who want to keep in touch must abide by the following rules:</p>
<ul>
<li>Everyone can only use the proprietary WhatsApp client to send messages; developing alternative clients isn’t supported.</li>
<li>Everyone’s mobile device must run an operating system supported by said client. Since WhatsApp developers will only write a client for popular operating systems, the Android and iOS duopoly strengthens.</li>
<li>Users fully depend on WhatsApp developers. If WhatsApp developers decide to include user-hostile features in the app, users must go with it. They can’t switch to a different server or client without switching away from WhatsApp and losing the ability to communicate with all their WhatsApp contacts.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="user-domestication">User domestication</h2>
<p>WhatsApp rose by trapping previously-free beings in their corral and changing their habits to create dependence on masters. Over time, this made it difficult or impossible to return to their previous lifestyle. That process should sound familiar: it’s eerily similar to the domestication of animals. I call this type of vendor lock-in <strong>user domestication:</strong> the removal of user autonomy to trap users into serving vendors.</p>
<p>I chose this metaphor because animal domestication is a gradual process that isn’t always deliberate, and typically revolves around one group becoming dependent upon another. For example: there’s evidence that domestication of dogs began with socialization, resulting in not-entirely-artificial selection promoting genes that resulted in more friendliness with and dependence upon humans.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></p>
<p>Whether it happens on purpose or by accident, user domestication almost always follows the same three steps:</p>
<ol>
<li>A high level of dependence given from users to a software vendor</li>
<li>An inability for users to control their software, through at least one of the following methods:
<ol>
<li>Preventing modification of the software</li>
<li>Preventing migration onto a different platform</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>The exploitation of now-captive users who are unable to resist</li>
</ol>
<p>The completion of the first two steps left WhatsApp users vulnerable to user domestication. With investors to answer to, they had every incentive to implement user-hostile features without consequence.</p>
<p>So, of course, they did.</p>
<h2 id="whatsapps-descent">WhatsApp’s descent</h2>
<p>Domestication has a purpose: it enables a master species to exploit the domesticated species for its own gain.</p>
<p>Recently, WhatsApp updated its privacy policy to allow sharing data with its parent, Facebook. Users who agreed to use WhatsApp under its previous privacy policy had two options: agree to the new policy or be unable to use WhatsApp again. The WhatsApp privacy policy update is a classic bait-and-switch: WhatsApp lured users in with a sleek interface and the impression of privacy, domesticated them to remove their autonomy to migrate, and then backtracked on its previous commitment to privacy with minimal consequence. Each step in this process enabled the next; had user domestication not taken place, it would be easy for most users to switch away with minimal friction.</p>
<p>Those of us who were sounding the alarm a few years ago experienced a brief moment of sadistic bliss when our titles were upgraded from “annoying and paranoid conspiracy theorists” to just “annoying”.</p>
<h3 id="an-attempt-at-damage-control">An attempt at damage control</h3>
<p>The bait-and-switch operation incurred backlash significant enough for a noticeable minority of users to actually migrate; this number turned out to be slightly more than the rounding error WhatsApp was likely expecting. In response, WhatsApp delayed the change and published the following ad:</p>
<picture>
	<source srcset="https://seirdy.one/p/whatsapp_ad_dark.3e9ad6a0c2c8c377c4583cf92bddcd47.avif" type="image/avif" media="(prefers-color-scheme: dark)">
	<source srcset="https://seirdy.one/p/whatsapp_ad_dark.09f935219fb9d5ac9fa9bc4acb733d13.webp" type="image/webp" media="(prefers-color-scheme: dark)">
	<source srcset="https://seirdy.one/p/whatsapp_ad_dark.8792c2187d444ebc32bf8c386ea0cda9.png" type="image/png" media="(prefers-color-scheme: dark)">
	<source srcset="https://seirdy.one/p/whatsapp_ad.94ed78578e240dfd57f833807f8167ed.avif" type="image/avif">
	<source srcset="https://seirdy.one/p/whatsapp_ad.9efe174613a8b02274fa62feff7b8374.webp" type="image/webp">
	<source srcset="https://seirdy.one/p/whatsapp_ad.b81802ac13cd4a2540211e05819cd29e.png" type="image/png">
	<img width="600" src="https://seirdy.one/p/whatsapp_ad.png" alt="WhatsApp ad describing data not collected">
</picture>

<p>The ad lists various data that WhatsApp doesn’t collect or share. Allaying data collection concerns by listing data <em>not</em> collected is misleading. WhatsApp doesn’t collect hair samples or retinal scans either; not collecting that information doesn’t mean it respects privacy because it doesn’t change the information WhatsApp <em>does</em> collect.</p>
<p>The ad denies “keep[ing] logs of who everyone is messaging or calling”. Collecting data is not the same as “keeping logs”; it’s possible for metadata to be fed into an algorithm before being discarded. A model can thus learn that two users call each other frequently without keeping logs of the metadata for each call. The fact that they specifically chose to phrase this line around logging implies that WhatsApp either already collects this class of data or has deliberately left the door open to collecting it in the future.</p>
<p>A stroll through WhatsApp’s <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20210124061525/https://www.whatsapp.com/legal/updates/privacy-policy/?lang=en">actual privacy policy</a> at the time reveals that they do collect considerable metadata used for marketing through Facebook.</p>
<h2 id="software-freedom">Software freedom</h2>
<p>With user domestication, providing useful software to users is a means to the end of exploiting them. The alternative is simple: make serving users the end in and of itself.</p>
<p>To prevent being controlled by software, users must be in control. Software that allows users to be in control is called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_software">free software</a>. The word “free” in this context refers to freedom rather than price. Software freedom is similar to the concept of open-source, but the latter is focused on practical benefits rather than ethics. A less ambiguous term that neutrally refers to both free and open-source software is <strong><abbr title="free and open-source software">FOSS</abbr></strong>.</p>
<p>Others have <a href="https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.en.html">explained</a> the concepts underpinning free software better than I can, so I won’t go into detail. It comes down to four essential freedoms:</p>
<ul>
<li>The freedom to run the program as you wish, for any purpose</li>
<li>The freedom to study how the program works, and change it so it does your computing as you wish</li>
<li>The freedom to redistribute copies so you can help others</li>
<li>The freedom to distribute copies of your modified versions to others</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="making-money-with-foss">Making money with FOSS</h3>
<p>The most common objection I hear is that FOSS makes it harder to make money.</p>
<p>The key to making money with FOSS is to make software a <a href="https://www.gwern.net/Complement">commoditized complement</a> of other, more profitable services. Examples of such services include selling support, customization, consulting, training, managed hosting, hardware, and certifications. Plenty of companies use this approach instead of building proprietary software: Red Hat, Collabora, System76, Purism, Canonical, SUSE, Hashicorp, Databricks, and Gradle are some names that come to mind.</p>
<p>Managed hosting isn’t a basket worth all your eggs if giants like AWS can do the same at a lower price. Being the developer can give an edge in areas like customization, support, and training; it doesn’t offer as obvious an advantage when it comes to hosting.</p>
<h2 id="foss-isnt-always-enough">FOSS isn’t always enough</h2>
<p>Free software is a necessary but sometimes insufficient requirement to build domestication immunity. Two more measures include <strong>simplicity</strong> and <strong>open platforms.</strong></p>
<h3 id="simplicity">Simplicity</h3>
<p>When software grows too complex, it needs to be maintained by a large team. Users who disagree with a vendor can’t easily fork and maintain a multi-million-line codebase, especially if the software in question potentially contains security vulnerabilities. Dependence on the vendor can grow quite problematic when complexity causes development costs to skyrocket; the vendor might resort to implementing user-hostile features to stay afloat.</p>
<p>Complex software that can’t be developed by a different group of people creates dependence, step one of user domestication. That alone is enough to open the door to problematic developments.</p>
<h4 id="case-study-mozilla-and-the-web">Case study: Mozilla and the Web</h4>
<p>Mozilla was a ray of hope in the browser wars, a space dominated by adtech, surveillance, and vendor lock-in. Unfortunately, developing a browser engine is a monumental task difficult enough for Opera and Microsoft to give up and re-skin Chromium. Browsers are more than the document readers they were meant to be: they’ve evolved into application runtimes with their own stacks for GPU acceleration, Bluetooth, permissions, device enumeration, bundled media codecs, <abbr title="digital rights management">DRM</abbr><sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup>, extension APIs, developer tools…the list goes on. It takes billions of dollars a year to respond to vulnerabilities in such a massive attack surface and keep up with a standard that grows at such a worrying rate. Those billions have to come from somewhere.</p>
<p>Mozilla ended up having to make major compromises to stay afloat. It cut search deals with blatantly user-hostile companies, and bundled the browser with <a href="https://blog.mozilla.org/advancingcontent/2014/02/11/publisher-transformation-with-users-at-the-center/">ads</a> and bloatware such as a partially …</p></section></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://seirdy.one/2021/01/27/whatsapp-and-the-domestication-of-users.html">https://seirdy.one/2021/01/27/whatsapp-and-the-domestication-of-users.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://seirdy.one/2021/01/27/whatsapp-and-the-domestication-of-users.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25982860</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 21:45:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Fun with an ATTiny85, Liyafy HC-35 with 8 LEDs, & a serial to parallel shifter]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 10 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25982614">thread link</a>) | @nanis
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | https://www.nu42.com/2021/01/attiny85-liyafy-hc-35-8-led-keypad-serial-in-parallel-out-shift-register.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.nu42.com/2021/01/attiny85-liyafy-hc-35-8-led-keypad-serial-in-parallel-out-shift-register.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
<header>
<h3><time datetime="2020-01-31T21:00:00-00:00">January 31, 2020</time></h3>
</header>
</p><div><p>Some months ago, I got curious about ESP32 microcontrollers. The exact reason is not important. I ended up learning about <a href="https://www.nodemcu.com/">NodeMCU</a>, <a href="https://micropython.org/">MicroPython</a>, <a href="https://www.i2c-bus.org/">I<sup>2</sup>C</a>. In the end, I was able to wire up an ESP32 to an OLED screen which showed a small set of rotating fortune cookies.</p>
<p>It turned out to be rather straightforward. I wanted more artificial constraints. After all, I am not doing this for real work. It’s just a different way of having a well defined task that can be accomplished in a short amount of time with a visible outcome. In that sense, it is similar to <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/users/100754/sinan-%c3%9cn%c3%bcr">answering questions on Stackoverlow</a>. I find it helpful in a way others might find meditation helpful.</p>
<p>Before going further, I am know I late to the party. People have been doing this stuf for quite some time now. This gives me the ability to more easily discover how to solve a given problem because others did and wrote blog posts about them years ago.</p>
<p>My search for a <em>reasonably</em> constrained environment led me to <a href="https://www.microchip.com/wwwproducts/en/ATtiny85" title="ATtiny85 datasheet">ATtiny85</a>. I decided I wanted to do something with it, but I did not know what. So, the first thing I tried was to wire up an ATtiny85 to an OLED screen and display a (now much smaller) set of rotating <a href="https://www.nu42.com/2020/12/small-is-beautiful.html">fortune cookies</a>.</p>
<p>ATtiny85 has 8 kilobytes of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flash_memory">programmable flash</a>, 512 bytes of programmable <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/EEPROM">EEPROM</a>, and 512 bytes of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Static_random-access_memory">SRAM</a>. As I said, for a while I did not know what I wanted to do with it. I would occasionally browse Amazon and order things that looked cheap and fun.</p>
<p><em>Note that in what follows, I will be using shortened Amazon affiliate links to the products I actually bought and used in making this blog post. The advantage of shortened links is that just loading the page does not immediately result in tracking images and cookies to be fetched (of course, if your browser does aggressive <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Link_prefetching_FAQ">link prefetching</a>, all bets are off). Linking to those products do not mean I endorse them or even recommend them. I am just writing about my experience using them.</em></p>
<p>Among the things I bought because it looked cheap at the time was <a title="Amazon afiliate link to Liyafy HC-35 product page" href="https://amzn.to/3raaH4b">Liyafy HC-35 8 LED 4x4 push button matrix keyboard</a>. From my perspective, it looked appealing because it came with no documentation, there were no useful comments or Q&amp;A on the product page, and a Google search only revealed <a href="https://forum.arduino.cc/index.php?topic=500018.0">an unanswered question from 2017 on the Arduino forums</a>.</p>
<p>In the package were two keypads on a single board with a slight perforation running through the middle. So, I cracked them apart :-) Now, I had two keypads with no documentation. Here is one of them:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nu42.com/2021/01/liyafy-hc-35-lg.jpg"><img src="https://www.nu42.com/2021/01/liyafy-hc-35-sm.jpg"></a></p>
<p>Documentation or not, the task seemed simple to me: There are three banks of pins on the left side of the board. The bottom bank is for manipulating the LEDs, and the two banks above that are for reading the state of the red buttons and the state of the black buttons, respectively. Eight LEDs, eight bits in a byte, not a huge leap to assume that each LED maps to a bit in a byte. It is not really clear whether the LEDs are ordered MSB first or LSB first. I am not good at reading board traces.</p>
<p>So, we need to have eight wires to drive the LEDs. VCC is clearly marked, but I didn’t know whether the board needed 5V or 3.3V. In fact, at first I guessed wrong and tried 5V. It doesn’t seem to have harmed the board, but after the fact, I thought maybe it would have been better to try the lower voltage first :-)</p>
<p>The ATtiny85 has 8 pins in <em>total</em>. We need a further four wires to read the state of the KEY B bank consisting of the red buttons, and we need an additional eight wires to read state of the KEY A bank consisting of the 4x4 keypad. Note the pins on the KEY A bank are labeled <var>L<sub>i</sub></var> and <var>R<sub>i</sub></var> where I would expect L to stand for “line” and R to stand for “row” which seem like the same thing to me. I decided to anchor on “R is row” and “L is column” as a working assumption, and focus solely on getting some lights to blink first.</p>
<p>Before going further, I should note that by the time I got around the thinking about this, a couple of months had gone by. Luckily, I had picked some other bits and pieces I thought might come in handy if I ever got around to trying this. Here is a list of what I ended up using:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2NNFi97" title="Amazon affiliate link to ATtiny85 10 pack">A ten-pack of ATtiny85 chips</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2NNF1TD" title="Amazon affiliate link to Belker 45W/3A AC/DC adapter">Belker 45W 5V 6V 7.5V 9V 12V 13.5V 15V Universal AC DC Power Supply</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/3tfScgj" title="Amazon affiliate link to REXQualis Electronics Component Fun Kit">REXQualis Electronics Component Fun Kit</a>
<ul>
<li>Breadboard</li>
<li>Jumper wires</li>
<li>Extra LEDs</li>
<li>Power supply module</li>
<li><a href="https://www.ti.com/product/SN74HC595" title="595 8 bit serial to parallel shifter data sheet">74HC595</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/3r5mXmo" title="Amazon affiliate link to Tiny AVR Programmer">Tiny AVR programmer</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Note that stuff you find on Amazon tends to have a markup compared to the unit prices you find when shopping at speciality or overseas suppliers. And, prices on Amazon tend to vary a lot. I was not in a rush, did not have a specific project in mind, and just grabbed a thing or two when I thought the price was right. The Belker adapter is great. I have, of course, a box of wall warts accumulated over time, but with those either the specs turn out not to be what you want (if you can read them) or the tips don’t match etc. Since I bought this, it’s already been useful in multiple other contexts.</p>
<p>Well, I figured the first task was to actually be able to get something on the ATtiny85 to execute. I knew that I needed to install some drivers for the “programmer”, stick the chip in the right way (here’s where the 10-pack comes in handy: If you insert the chip in the wrong way, it burns because you end up swapping VCC and GND and 5V runs through going the wrong way … don’t trust your eyes, triple check before plugging the programmer in to your computer’s USB port). The <a href="https://www.microchip.com/wwwproducts/en/ATtiny85" title="ATtiny85 datasheet">datasheet</a> has the pin out diagram as well as other good information:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nu42.com/2021/01/attiny85-8pin-dip.png"><img title="ATtiny85 8 pin DIP package pinout diagram" alt="[ ATtiny85 8 pin DIP package pinout diagram ]" src="https://www.nu42.com/2021/01/attiny85-8pin-dip-thumb.png"></a></p>
<p>I followed <a href="https://learn.sparkfun.com/tutorials/tiny-avr-programmer-hookup-guide/all">SparkFun’s Tiny AVR programming hookup guide</a> followed by <a href="https://hackaday.com/2018/11/01/drawing-on-an-oled-with-an-attiny85-no-ram-buffers-allowed/">Drawing On An OLED With An ATtiny85</a> to produce some output on a <a href="https://amzn.to/3aiv5JA" title="Amazon affilliate link to SSD1306 128x32 OLED 3-pack">128x32 OLED screen</a> to get warmed up.</p>
<p>The next task was to figure out how to drive the LEDs which require 8 wires using the five pins I had at my disposal. So, I started by staring at the contents of the “Fun Kit”. There are only two ICs included in the pack. I did not know what the 4N35 was for (it turned out to be a <a href="https://www.vishay.com/docs/81181/4n35.pdf">light sensor</a>) but it has only six pins, so clearly it could not do anything with mapping one bit at a time (aka serial) output to eight bits at a time (parallel). So, I searched the web for the only other IC in the package, <a href="https://www.nu42.com/2021/01/sipo">74HC595</a>. TI’s page for the product mentions “<a href="https://www.nu42.com/2021/01/ti-595-snip.png">8-bit shift registers with 3-state output registers</a>” right under the product name. To be honest, that didn’t mean any thing to me and I almost navigated away from the page, but scrolling down a little (is it me, or is everything on the web in huge and huger fonts now?) revealed the description:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The SNx4HC595 devices contain an 8-bit, serial-in, parallel-out shift register that feeds an 8-bit D-type storage register. The storage register has parallel 3-state outputs. Separate clocks are provided for both the shift and storage register. The shift register has a direct overriding clear (SRCLR) input, serial (SER) input, and serial outputs for cascading. When the output-enable (OE) input is high, the outputs are in the high-impedance state.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Yay! It looks like the “fun kit” includes just the part I needed for this! Good.</p>
<p>Time to learn what the gobbledygook means … It sounds like it’s saying it takes serial input, puts bits in eight bins, and, when you give it the all clear, it puts those zeros and ones on some IO pins. Here is the pin-out:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nu42.com/2021/01/SN74HC595-pins.png"><img alt="[ SN74HC595 pin out diagram ]" width="326" src="https://www.nu42.com/2021/01/SN74HC595-pins.png"></a></p>
<p><var>Q<sub>A</sub></var> - <var>Q<sub>H</sub></var> are the eight output pins. VCC is VCC, GND is GND. <u>SER</u> better be serial. O̅E̅ is “output enable” meaning put “put the bits you buffered on the pins”. <var>Q<sub>H</sub><sup>′</sup></var> seems to provide the same output serially.</p>
<p>OK, so I need to connect <var>Q<sub>A</sub></var> - <var>Q<sub>H</sub></var> to the LED inputs … I think I did this the “wrong” way by connecting <var>Q<sub>A</sub></var> to <var>D<sub>1</sub> on the keypad, but at this stage, I didn’t care what lit up … just that something did.</var></p>
<p>The big question is what to do with the five other pins. How do I drive them from the ATtiny85? I was confronted with a choice: I could read the datasheet, draw on my “vast” knowledge from electronics all gained in 8th grade, and translate the information in the datasheet to a program. Or, I could see if anyone else had done something similar. Searching for 74HC595 and Arduino led me to the documentation for the <a href="https://www.arduino.cc/reference/en/language/functions/advanced-io/shiftout/">shiftout</a> function:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Shifts out a byte of data one bit at a time. Starts from either the most (i.e. the leftmost) or least (rightmost) significant bit. Each bit is written in turn to a data pin, after which a clock pin is pulsed (taken high, then low) to indicate that the bit is available.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Nice. It turns out Arduino documentation is really good like Perl documentation (docs on both focus on giving you the information you need to be able to use a specific piece of functionality – For a contrast, see Python’s documentation which tends to obscure the information you need in dense prose). The docs for <code>shiftout</code> came with a complete example as well as a link to a <a href="https://www.arduino.cc/en/Tutorial/Foundations/ShiftOut" title="Serial to Parallel Shifting-Out with a 74HC595">tutorial on controlling the 74HC595 shift register</a>. Of course, the mnemonics used in the pin-out diagram in the tutorial do not fully match the datasheet, but it is really nice to have these resources when you are trying to take the baby steps. It is easier to understand how you ended up blinking those if you can get them to blink in the first place.</p>
<p>Obviously, the tutorial is great. Explains all you need to know really. It is geared towards an Arduino board and those tend to have way more available pins than the ATtiny85. Laying cable on a breadboard is not my strong suit (never touched a soldering iron either), but after spending a moment considering my options, I decided to use the three available pins on the right side of the ATtiny85 (<var>PB<sub>0</sub></var> … <var>PB<sub>2</sub></var>) for interfacing with the 595. While reading the tutorial, I noticed this:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“3 states” refers to the fact that you can set the output pins as either high, low or “high impedance.” … Neither example takes advantage of this feature and you won’t usually need to worry about getting a chip that has it.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Good. One less thing to worry about.</p>
<p>Anyway, I used whatever wires were available within the routing constraints and came up with this wiring:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nu42.com/2021/01/attiny85-SN74HC595-HC-35-breadboard.jpg"><img src="https://www.nu42.com/2021/01/attiny85-SN74HC595-HC-35-breadboard-thumb.jpg" width="400" title="ATtiny85 SN74HC595 Liyafy HC-35 keypad breadboard wiring" alt="[ ATtiny85 SN74HC595 Liyafy HC-35 keypad breadboard wiring ]"></a></p>
<p>The colors of the wires were dictated by available …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.nu42.com/2021/01/attiny85-liyafy-hc-35-8-led-keypad-serial-in-parallel-out-shift-register.html">https://www.nu42.com/2021/01/attiny85-liyafy-hc-35-8-led-keypad-serial-in-parallel-out-shift-register.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.nu42.com/2021/01/attiny85-liyafy-hc-35-8-led-keypad-serial-in-parallel-out-shift-register.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25982614</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 21:12:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The true power of regular expressions]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 22 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25981212">thread link</a>) | @mfbx9da4
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | https://nikic.github.io/2012/06/15/The-true-power-of-regular-expressions.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nikic.github.io/2012/06/15/The-true-power-of-regular-expressions.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
        <p>As someone who frequents the <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/php">PHP tag on StackOverflow</a> I pretty often see questions about how to parse some
particular aspect of HTML using regular expressions. A common reply to such a question is:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>You cannot parse HTML with regular expressions, because HTML isn’t regular. Use an XML parser instead.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This statement - in the context of the question - is somewhere between very misleading and outright wrong. What I’ll try
to demonstrate in this article is how powerful modern regular expressions <em>really</em> are.</p>

<h2 id="what-does-regular-actually-mean">What does “regular” actually mean?</h2>

<p>In the context of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formal_language">formal language theory</a>, something is called “regular” when it has a grammar where all production
rules have one of the following forms:</p>



<p>You can read those <code>-&gt;</code> rules as “The left hand side can be replaced with the right hand side”. So the first rule would
be “B can be replaced with a”, the second one “B can be replaced with aC” and the third one “B can be replaced with the
empty string” (<code>ε</code> is the symbol for the empty string).</p>

<p>So what are <code>B</code>, <code>C</code> and <code>a</code>? By convention, uppercase characters denote so called “non-terminals” - symbols which <em>can</em>
be broken down further - and lowercase characters denote “terminals” - symbols which <em>cannot</em> be broken down any
further.</p>

<p>All that probably sounds a bit abstract, so let’s look at an example: Defining the natural numbers as a grammar.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>N -&gt; 0
N -&gt; 1
N -&gt; 2
N -&gt; 3
N -&gt; 4
N -&gt; 5
N -&gt; 6
N -&gt; 7
N -&gt; 8
N -&gt; 9
N -&gt; 0N
N -&gt; 1N
N -&gt; 2N
N -&gt; 3N
N -&gt; 4N
N -&gt; 5N
N -&gt; 6N
N -&gt; 7N
N -&gt; 8N
N -&gt; 9N
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>What this grammar says is:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>A natural number (N) is
... one of the digits 0 to 9
or
... one of the digits 0 to 9 followed by another natural number (N)
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>In this example the digits 0 to 9 would be terminals (as they can’t be broken down any further) and <code>N</code> would be the
only non-terminal (as it can be and is broken down further).</p>

<p>If you have another look at the rules and compare them to the definition of a regular grammar from above, you’ll see
that they meet the criteria: The first ten rules are of the form <code>B -&gt; a</code> and the second ten rules follow the form
<code>B -&gt; aC</code>. Thus the grammar defining the natural numbers is <em>regular</em>.</p>

<p>Another thing you might notice is that even though the above grammar defines such a simple thing, it is already quite
bloated. Wouldn’t it be better if we could express the same concept in a more concise manner?</p>

<p>And that’s where regular expressions come in: The above grammar is equivalent to the regex <code>[0-9]+</code> (which is a hell lot
simpler). And this kind of transformation can be done with <em>any</em> regular grammar: Every regular grammar has a
corresponding regular expression which defines all its valid strings.</p>

<h2 id="what-can-regular-expressions-match">What can regular expressions match?</h2>

<p>Thus the question arises: Can regular expressions match only regular grammars, or can they also match more? The answer
to this is both yes <em>and</em> no:</p>

<p>Regular expressions in the formal grammar sense can (pretty much by definition) only parse regular grammars and nothing
more.</p>

<p>But when programmers talk about “regular expressions” they aren’t talking about formal grammars. They are talking about
the regular expression <em>derivative</em> which their language implements. And those regex implementations are only very
slightly related to the original notion of regularity.</p>

<p>Any modern regex flavor can match a <em>lot</em> more than just regular languages. How much exactly, that’s what the rest of
the article is about.</p>

<p>To keep things simple, I’ll focus on the PCRE regex implementation in the following, simply because I know it best (as
it’s used by PHP). Most other regex implementations are quite similar though, so most stuff should apply to them too.</p>

<h2 id="the-language-hierarchy">The language hierarchy</h2>

<p>In order to analyze what regular expressions can and cannot match, we first have to look at what other types of
languages there are. A good starting point for this is the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chomsky_hierarchy">Chomsky hierarchy</a>:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Chomsky hierarchy:

/-------------------------------------------\
|                                           |
|     Recursively enumerable languages      | Type 0
|                                           |
|   /-----------------------------------\   |
|   |                                   |   |
|   |    Context-sensitive languages    |   | Type 1
|   |                                   |   |
|   |   /---------------------------\   |   |
|   |   |                           |   |   |
|   |   |  Context-free languages   |   |   | Type 2
|   |   |                           |   |   |
|   |   |   /-------------------\   |   |   |
|   |   |   | Regular languages |   |   |   | Type 3
|   |   |   \-------------------/   |   |   |
|   |   \---------------------------/   |   |
|   \-----------------------------------/   |
\-------------------------------------------/
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>As you can see the Chomsky hierarchy divides formal languages into four types:</p>

<p>Regular languages (Type 3) are the least-powerful, followed by the context-free languages (Type 2), the
context-sensitive languages (Type 1) and at last the all-mighty recursively enumerable languages (Type 0).</p>

<p>The Chomsky hierarchy is a containment hierarchy, so the smaller boxes in the above image are fully contained in the
larger boxes. For example every regular language is also a context-free language (but <em>not</em> the other way around!)</p>

<p>So, let’s move one step up in that hierarchy: We already know that regular expressions can match any regular language.
But can they also match context-free languages?</p>

<p>(Reminder: When I say “regular expression” here I obviously mean it in the programmer sense, not the formal language
theory sense.)</p>

<h2 id="matching-context-free-languages">Matching context-free languages</h2>

<p>The answer to this is <em>yes</em>, they can!</p>

<p>Let’s take the classical example of a context-free language, namely <code>{a^n b^n, n&gt;0}</code>, which means “A number of <code>a</code>
characters followed by the <em>same</em> number of <code>b</code> characters”. The (PCRE) regex for this language is:</p>



<p>The regular expression is very simple: <code>(?1)</code> is a reference to the first subpattern, namely <code>(a(?1)?b)</code>. So basically
you could replace the <code>(?1)</code> by that subpattern, thus forming a recursive dependency:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>/^(a(?1)?b)$/
/^(a(a(?1)?b)?b)$/
/^(a(a(a(?1)?b)?b)?b)$/
/^(a(a(a(a(?1)?b)?b)?b)?b)$/
# and so on
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>From the above expansions it should be clear that this expression can match any string with the same number of <code>a</code>s and
<code>b</code>s.</p>

<p>Thus regular expressions can match at least some non-regular, context-free grammars. But can they match all? To answer
that, we first have to look at how context-free grammars are defined.</p>

<p>In a context-free grammar all production rules take the following form:</p>



<p>Here <code>A</code> once again is a non-terminal symbol and <code>β</code> is an arbitrary string of terminals and non-terminals. Thus every
production rule of a context-free grammar has a non-terminal on the left hand side and an arbitrary symbol string on
the right hand side.</p>

<p>As an example, have a look at the following grammar:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>function_declaration -&gt; T_FUNCTION is_ref T_STRING '(' parameter_list ')' '{' inner_statement_list '}'

is_ref -&gt; '&amp;'
is_ref -&gt; ε

parameter_list -&gt; non_empty_parameter_list
parameter_list -&gt; ε

non_empty_parameter_list -&gt; parameter
non_empty_parameter_list -&gt; non_empty_parameter_list ',' parameter

// ... ... ...
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>What you see there is an excerpt from the PHP grammar (just a few sample rules). The syntax is slightly different from
what we used before, but should be easy to understand. One aspect worth mentioning is that the uppercase <code>T_SOMETHING</code>
names here also are terminal symbols. These symbols which are usually called <em>tokens</em> encode more abstract concepts.
E.g. <code>T_FUNCTION</code> represents the <code>function</code> keyword and <code>T_STRING</code> is a label token (like <code>getUserById</code> or
<code>some_other_name</code>).</p>

<p>I’m using this example to show one thing: Context-free grammars are already powerful enough to encode quite complex
languages. That’s why pretty much all programming languages have a context-free grammar. In particular this also
includes well-formed HTML.</p>

<p>Now, back to the actual question: Can regular expressions match all context-free grammars? Once again, the answer is
<em>yes</em>!</p>

<p>This is pretty easy to prove as regular expressions (at least PCRE and similar) provide a syntax very similar to the
above for constructing grammars:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>/
    (?(DEFINE)
        (?&lt;addr_spec&gt; (?&amp;local_part) @ (?&amp;domain) )
        (?&lt;local_part&gt; (?&amp;dot_atom) | (?&amp;quoted_string) | (?&amp;obs_local_part) )
        (?&lt;domain&gt; (?&amp;dot_atom) | (?&amp;domain_literal) | (?&amp;obs_domain) )
        (?&lt;domain_literal&gt; (?&amp;CFWS)? \[ (?: (?&amp;FWS)? (?&amp;dtext) )* (?&amp;FWS)? \] (?&amp;CFWS)? )
        (?&lt;dtext&gt; [\x21-\x5a] | [\x5e-\x7e] | (?&amp;obs_dtext) )
        (?&lt;quoted_pair&gt; \\ (?: (?&amp;VCHAR) | (?&amp;WSP) ) | (?&amp;obs_qp) )
        (?&lt;dot_atom&gt; (?&amp;CFWS)? (?&amp;dot_atom_text) (?&amp;CFWS)? )
        (?&lt;dot_atom_text&gt; (?&amp;atext) (?: \. (?&amp;atext) )* )
        (?&lt;atext&gt; [a-zA-Z0-9!#$%&amp;'*+/=?^_`{|}~-]+ )
        (?&lt;atom&gt; (?&amp;CFWS)? (?&amp;atext) (?&amp;CFWS)? )
        (?&lt;word&gt; (?&amp;atom) | (?&amp;quoted_string) )
        (?&lt;quoted_string&gt; (?&amp;CFWS)? " (?: (?&amp;FWS)? (?&amp;qcontent) )* (?&amp;FWS)? " (?&amp;CFWS)? )
        (?&lt;qcontent&gt; (?&amp;qtext) | (?&amp;quoted_pair) )
        (?&lt;qtext&gt; \x21 | [\x23-\x5b] | [\x5d-\x7e] | (?&amp;obs_qtext) )

        # comments and whitespace
        (?&lt;FWS&gt; (?: (?&amp;WSP)* \r\n )? (?&amp;WSP)+ | (?&amp;obs_FWS) )
        (?&lt;CFWS&gt; (?: (?&amp;FWS)? (?&amp;comment) )+ (?&amp;FWS)? | (?&amp;FWS) )
        (?&lt;comment&gt; \( (?: (?&amp;FWS)? (?&amp;ccontent) )* (?&amp;FWS)? \) )
        (?&lt;ccontent&gt; (?&amp;ctext) | (?&amp;quoted_pair) | (?&amp;comment) )
        (?&lt;ctext&gt; [\x21-\x27] | [\x2a-\x5b] | [\x5d-\x7e] | (?&amp;obs_ctext) )

        # obsolete tokens
        (?&lt;obs_domain&gt; (?&amp;atom) (?: \. (?&amp;atom) )* )
        (?&lt;obs_local_part&gt; (?&amp;word) (?: \. (?&amp;word) )* )
        (?&lt;obs_dtext&gt; (?&amp;obs_NO_WS_CTL) | (?&amp;quoted_pair) )
        (?&lt;obs_qp&gt; \\ (?: \x00 | (?&amp;obs_NO_WS_CTL) | \n | \r ) )
        (?&lt;obs_FWS&gt; (?&amp;WSP)+ (?: \r\n (?&amp;WSP)+ )* )
        (?&lt;obs_ctext&gt; (?&amp;obs_NO_WS_CTL) )
        (?&lt;obs_qtext&gt; (?&amp;obs_NO_WS_CTL) )
        (?&lt;obs_NO_WS_CTL&gt; [\x01-\x08] | \x0b | \x0c | [\x0e-\x1f] | \x7f )

        # character class definitions
        (?&lt;VCHAR&gt; [\x21-\x7E] )
        (?&lt;WSP&gt; [ \t] )
   …</code></pre></div></div></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://nikic.github.io/2012/06/15/The-true-power-of-regular-expressions.html">https://nikic.github.io/2012/06/15/The-true-power-of-regular-expressions.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nikic.github.io/2012/06/15/The-true-power-of-regular-expressions.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25981212</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 18:31:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: YaHNd – HN Books: The Best Books of Hacker News]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 51 | Comments 15 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25980892">thread link</a>) | @yaj54
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | https://yahnd.com/books/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://yahnd.com/books/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://yahnd.com/books/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25980892</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 18:01:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Google Play bans open source Matrix client Element, citing “abusive content”]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 30 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25980728">thread link</a>) | @guybedo
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | Https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/01/google-play-bans-open-source-matrix-client-element-citing-abusive-content/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/Https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/01/google-play-bans-open-source-matrix-client-element-citing-abusive-content/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <h4>
      We need a "Section 230" for the Play Store    —
</h4>
            
            <h2 itemprop="description">Banning a Matrix client for content is really no different from banning a Web browser. </h2>
            <section>

  



  
</section>        </div><section>
            <div itemprop="articleBody">
                                    
<figure><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/15-1-800x450.jpg" alt="Google Play bans open source Matrix client Element, citing â€œabusive contentâ€� [Updated]"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><!-- cache hit 99:single/related:f5ad687345fb5db54153ecf87a4c7210 --><!-- empty --><p>The latest app to catch an illogical ban from the Google Play Store <a href="https://element.io/blog/element-on-google-play-store/">is Element</a>, an open source, end-to-end encrypted messaging client for the federated Matrix chat protocol. Google banned Element late Friday night, a ban thatÂ&nbsp;<a href="https://twitter.com/element_hq/status/1355465650114846720">Element said</a> "is due to abusive content somewhere on Matrix." Matrix has millions of users, and as a federated chat protocol, Element does not control the content on Matrix, so this is a bit like banning a Web browser for displaying Web content. Element says it is working with Google to "explain how Element works and get the situation resolved."</p>
<p>Google has <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/01/google-bans-parler-from-android-app-store/">been cracking down</a> on apps that display hateful content, but Element says that it shouldn't be part of the crackdown. "We have also explained that the Matrix servers that we <em>do</em> run as Element (including the default Matrix.org homeserver, which we run on behalf of <a href="https://matrix.org/foundation">The Matrix.org Foundation</a>) have <a href="https://matrix.org/legal/terms-and-conditions#6-play-nice-clauses">strict Terms of Use</a> which we actively enforce," Element said. "We abhor abuse, and Element is not an app that caters to abusive content."</p>
<p>Element says it has a full-time team dedicated to handling abuse reports.</p>
<p>Element (which was formerly called Riot.im) is <a href="https://matrix.org/docs/projects/try-matrix-now">often cited</a> as one of the best Matrix clients. It looks a lot likeâ€”and is actually <a href="https://element.io/blog/slack-bridging/">interoperable with</a>â€”Slack and Discord. Element says it is used by "the French, German, UK and US governments, countless universities, thousands of businesses and millions of people across the world." The app has recently seen <a href="https://sifted.eu/articles/element-whatsapp-exodus/">an influx of new users</a> after WhatsApp's announcement about <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/01/whatsapp-users-must-share-their-data-with-facebook-or-stop-using-the-app/">Facebook data sharing</a>, so maybe that triggered deeper scrutiny from Google. At press time, <a href="https://play.google.com/store/search?q=matrix%20chat&amp;c=apps">many other Matrix apps</a>â€”which by definition show the same content as Elementâ€”are still active on the Play Store.</p>                                            
                                                        
<p>Google takes a 30 percent cut of all Play Store transactions, which is supposed to pay for the cost of running the Store, but the company doesn't hire humans to primarily review apps the way Apple does, choosing instead to let the bots handle it. Apple <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2020/11/apple-lowers-its-cut-of-app-store-revenues-for-some-developers/">recently cut</a> its App Store tax from 30 percent to 15 percent, so Apple actually charges developers less than Google while also offering better human support.
</p><p>Element's <a href="https://twitter.com/element_hq/status/1355595359582638080">latest update</a> on the situation as of this writing said it has been waiting more than eight hours for an email response. Element says it was not notified of the takedown, which has now passed the 24-hour mark.</p>
<p>The bots' interpretation of Google's rules often make no sense, and as a result Google regularly bans random small apps from the Play Store because they can display content from the Internet. We've seen <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/androiddev/comments/96kpsf/more_issues_with_google_play_suspended_for_hate/">Reddit apps,</a> <a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2020/05/19/podcast-addict-pulled-play-store-allegedly-violating-coronavirus-policy/">podcast apps</a>, and other apps that display third-party Web content all "win" the Google Play ban-of-the-week lottery, just because they can be made to display third-party content. The same is true of Google Search, Chrome, Gmail, all of Google's chat apps, YouTube, Google Drive, and Google Podcasts, but those apps never get banned. Earlier this week Google <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/01/googles-bots-decide-ass-subtitle-support-is-too-risque-for-the-play-store/">banned a video app</a> because it listed support for the standard ".ass" subtitle filetype in its description.</p>
<p>The one benefit of the Play Store is that you don't have to use it, since Android supports sideloading. Element is also up <a href="https://f-droid.org/en/packages/im.vector.app/">on F-Droid</a>, an all-open source repository of Android apps, though the version offered there is a month out of date. A more up-to-date version is on <a href="https://www.apkmirror.com/apk/vector-creations-limited/riot-im-communicate-your-way/riot-im-communicate-your-way-1-0-14-release/">APKmirror</a>, the Android hacking community's biggest app store.</p>
<p>These bans are almost always temporary mistakes that are rectified after a few hours or days, but that gives little solace to app developers who can suddenly have their businesses ripped out from under them because of an enforcement mistake. Element says, "we can only apologize for the disruption caused by the app disappearing like this."</p>
<p><strong>Update:</strong> Element got in touch with a person at Google and says the app should be back up soon.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Update: we just got a call from a Google VP who explained the suspension was triggered by a report of extremely abusive content accessible on the <a href="https://t.co/g01j4u6O2e">https://t.co/g01j4u6O2e</a> server. Our trust &amp; safety team had already acted on it, and the app should be reinstated shortly.</p>
<p>â€” Element (@element_hq) <a href="https://twitter.com/element_hq/status/1355663753380032512?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 30, 2021</a></p></blockquote>

                                                </div>

            
            
        </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>Https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/01/google-play-bans-open-source-matrix-client-element-citing-abusive-content/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25980728</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 17:45:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What to Expect from Old Windows PC's]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 21 | Comments 9 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25979810">thread link</a>) | @TLM275
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/end-of-life.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/end-of-life.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/end-of-life.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25979810</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 16:13:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[GitHub Should Start an App Store]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 746 | Comments 255 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25979774">thread link</a>) | @quaintdev
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | https://www.ankshilp.com/time_for_github_app_store/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.ankshilp.com/time_for_github_app_store/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content"><header>
    <div>
        <p><a href="https://www.ankshilp.com/">
                <img id="home-image" src="https://www.ankshilp.com/images/avatar.png">
            </a>
        </p>
        
    </div>
    <hr>
</header>
<div>
    <div>
        <h2 id="github-should-start-an-app-store">GitHub Should Start An App Store</h2>
<p>Yesterday, Google suspended Elements - matrix chat app - from play store <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25965443">without any reasonable explanation</a>. I think this was an automated removal triggered by user reports or some other factors. The matrix team tried to reach out to them for explanation to no avail. We have seen this pattern in many cases now. Either it’s getting overwhelming for Google to monitor apps in its store or they don’t want apps like Elements which is decentralized to be on their store. The later mostly seems like a conspiracy theory and I think former is more true. In any case, it doesn’t make any sense for a single entity to govern what gets installed and not on billions of devices. A decentralized app store whould be best to fight this sort of suspensions but it’s far from reality at the moment. The alternative? GitHub App Store.</p>
<h3 id="but-why-github">But Why GitHub?</h3>
<p>Few reasons why I think GitHub is our best bet:</p>
<ol>
<li>They already host source code of millions of apps. Release integration should be trivial to implement.</li>
<li>Unlike Google they actually listen to their users. They were awesome during <a href="https://github.blog/2020-11-16-standing-up-for-developers-youtube-dl-is-back/">youtube-dl</a> debacle.</li>
<li>Backed by Microsoft. Microsoft has been playing good by the developers for years now. I trust them more than Apple and Google.</li>
<li>They could finally give the desktop the app store it deserves</li>
<li>This is a minor but users will be able to raise issues with developers directly instead writing comments over app pages which I think you would agree completely suck.</li>
</ol>
<p>They will have to create app store applications for major platforms along with provision to host closed source applications on their store and they should be good to go. Honestly I can not imagine any other player being more successful in app stores than GitHub.</p>
<p><em>Update: <a href="https://twitter.com/element_hq/status/1355663753380032512">Google has reinstated Elements</a></em></p>

    </div>

            </div>
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.ankshilp.com/time_for_github_app_store/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25979774</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 16:07:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why Robinhood disabled buys but not sells]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 672 | Comments 648 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25979673">thread link</a>) | @stu2b50
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | https://stu2b50.dev/posts/why-robinhood-d3580b | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://stu2b50.dev/posts/why-robinhood-d3580b">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="layout">
      <div id="main">
        

    

    <div>
        <p>There's been enough time for the dust to settle and for Robinhood's actual reason for halting trades to come out. But the question of why only buys and not sells has not really been answered in detail, and that's mainly because it's a pain-in-the-ass and delves deep into how the deposit requirements are calculated by the DTCC for brokers. </p>
<h2>First, what happened</h2>
<p>On that fateful day, Gamestop stock had massive volatility, and given the cries of "Buy!" and "Hold!" from /r/WSBs, I'd assume on Robinhood, a broker targeted at retail investors, it'd be heavily imbalanced towards buy trades.</p>
<p>As volatility increased, the DTCC (Depository Trust &amp; Clearing Corporation) increased the deposit requirements for brokers. Basically, when you submit a trade on a broker, the exchange of money for stock doesn't actually happen until 2 days later, and the firm that handles that exchange is called a clearing firm. Before then, Robinhood just sends records: John bought 2 GME for $600, Mary sold 1 GME for $290. If that's all that happened that day, then Robinhood would need to provide $310 dollars to the clearing firm, and receive 1 stock.</p>
<p>That's a credit risk - what if Robinhood doesn't have the money on settlement? The clearing firm would be on the hook. So the DTCC requires that brokers put up a deposit beforehand. On that day, the DTCC massively increased the deposit requirements for brokers</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A spokesman for the DTCC wouldn’t specify how much it required from specific firms but said that by the end of the day industrywide collateral requirements jumped to $33.5 billion, up from $26 billion.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2021-01-29/reddit-traders-on-robinhood-are-on-both-sides-of-gamestop">Levine</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>The amount required by clearinghouses to cover the settlement period of some securities rose tremendously this week. How much? To put it in perspective, this week alone, our clearinghouse-mandated deposit requirements related to equities increased ten-fold. </p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://blog.robinhood.com/news/2021/1/29/what-happened-this-week">Robinhood</a></p>
<p>So, Robinhood legally could not submit trades on $GME until they could muster the deposits for GME that they needed. And they quickly <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/01/29/investing/robinhood-gamestop-reddit/index.html">scrounged up some capital</a> so they could continue on Friday.</p>
<h3>Robinhood's Clearing Firm</h3>
<p>Robinhood actually has their own clearing firm, Robinhood Securities... for some reason, but it's still a DTCC member and must listen to what the SEC regulates. </p>
<h3>update 12:32 - On margin?</h3>
<p>Some people seem to be mistaking the situation. It is not about margin accounts - while yes, Robinhood "instant transfers" provides the illusion of being instant effectively with margin, it's not really the issue here.</p>
<p>Brokers cannot use client money to satisfy their clearing fund obligation.  So whether or not the accounts had a settled balance didn't matter - as you can see from the other brokers which halted buys and did not have "instant transfers".</p>
<p>Again, this is about what's effectively <em>collateral</em> the brokers must put up so that all parties can mitigate the risk of a broker failing. Of course client money is used when the transaction <em>settles</em>, but, naturally, you can't use their money, which isn't yours, as collateral.</p>
<h2>But why ONLY Buys?</h2>
<p>The deposit requirement is </p>
<p><code>deposit = min( 99% 2d VaR + Gap Risk Measure, Deposit Floor Calc) + Mark-to-Market</code></p>
<p>And the variable to look at is the 99% 2d VaR</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The volatility component is designed to capture the market price risk associated with each Member’s portfolio at a 99th percentile level of confidence. The VaR Charge is the volatility component applicable to most Net Unsettled Positions, and usually comprises the largest portion of a Member’s Required Deposit. Procedure XV of the Rules currently provides that the VaR Charge shall be calculated in accordance with a generally accepted portfolio volatility margin model utilizing assumptions based on reasonable historical data and an appropriate volatility range. As such, NSCC currently calculates a Member’s VaR Charge utilizing the VaR model, which incorporates an EWMA volatility
estimation. </p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://www.sec.gov/rules/sro/nscc-an/2018/34-82631.pdf">SEC</a></p>
<p>Remember when I subtracted John's buys of $600 with Mary's sell of $290 to get $310? That's the broker's net unsettled cash positions. The 99% VaR is basically, "99% of the time the broker's net unsettled will not be higher than X". You might remember if you took statistics about confidence intervals; this is the upper 99% confidence interval.</p>
<h3>Bad Desmos Graphs</h3>
<p>So, let's model our risk as a Normal curve, for simplicity's sake. Here I've graphed a normal distribution with a line representing the 95% percentile</p>
<p><img src="https://stu2b50.dev/images/get/why-robinhood-d3580b/r1.png" alt=""></p>
<p>The Y axis is probability, the X axis is Robinhood's net unsettled positions. The more positive, the more money they'd owe theoretically.</p>
<p>Now, what happens if more people buy than sell? Then it'd shift over to the right</p>
<p><img src="https://stu2b50.dev/images/get/why-robinhood-d3580b/r2" alt=""></p>
<p>Hasn't the 95% percentile moved rightward as well? Now, what happens if the market is super volatile (i.e, the std dev of the distribution increases)</p>
<p><img src="https://stu2b50.dev/images/get/why-robinhood-d3580b/r3" alt=""></p>
<p>Wow, now it's even more to the right! </p>
<p>As you can see, <strong>buys make this worse</strong>, <strong>sells make it better</strong>. Robinhood <em>could not</em> execute buys, because it would increase the deposits they'd need, which they legally must obligate by.  Sells, on the other hand, do not have this problem. They would not push the 95% boundary more to the right.</p>
<h2>The Decision</h2>
<p>So really, it's not a bad decision or good decision that Robinhood halted buys of GME - it wasn't a decision, and it wasn't something they alone did.</p>
<p>These brokers halted buys of GME</p>
<ul>
<li>Robinhood</li>
<li>Webull</li>
<li>M1 Finance</li>
<li>Public</li>
<li>E-Trade</li>
</ul>
<p>While others only halted options</p>
<ul>
<li>Interactive</li>
<li>TDA</li>
<li>Schwab</li>
<li>Tradeing212</li>
</ul>
<p>Hmm, see a pattern? The former group includes companies like Robinhood (2013), WeBull (2017), M1 Finance (2015), while the latter has TDA (1975), Schwab(1971), Trading212 (2004).</p>
<p>(Okay, E-Trade is actually old too, but I guess they're just cash-strapped right now?)</p>
<p>Looks like young brokers with a limited capital resources to me.</p>
<h2>Stay or Switch?</h2>
<p>If there's something to fault Robinhood, it's that they're a young, janky broker (and also you might be getting screwed on the spread by Citadel). If they had more money on-hand they might not have had to stop buys of Gamestop. Perhaps they should have expected this and raised more capital earlier. </p>
<p>And that's a real reason to stay away from Robinhood. But for the love of god do not swap to WeBull or something if that's your concern.</p>
<p>And don't do it because you're abhorred by Robinhood's class warfare or something. Because that didn't happen - it was a mixture of SEC regulations and a cash-strapped startup (well, cash-strapped on big broker scales).</p>
<p>Although if you want to get mad at Hedge Funds anyway, feel free! You should always be mad at Hedge Funds. But please pick a real reason - you have no lack of choice to pick from.</p>

    </div>
  

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://stu2b50.dev/posts/why-robinhood-d3580b</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25979673</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 15:55:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[From catching up to getting ahead: an Emacs wishlist]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 10 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25979530">thread link</a>) | @mpereira
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | https://www.murilopereira.com/emacs-from-catching-up-to-getting-ahead/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.murilopereira.com/emacs-from-catching-up-to-getting-ahead/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>What does Emacs need for us to someday run M-x neuralink-mode and evaluate Lisp in the brain?</p><div><p>I started using <a href="https://github.com/mpereira/.emacs.d/commit/30024f963ed794ec3a4c41229dbd4fab81f9b912">Emacs</a> almost exactly four years ago, after almost a decade
of <a href="https://github.com/mpereira/.vim">Vim</a>. I made the switch cold turkey. I vividly remember being <em>extremely</em>
frustrated by unbearable slowness while editing a Clojure file at work.
With no sane way of debugging it, just moving the cursor up and down would
result in so much lag that I had to step away from the computer to breathe
for a while. When I came back I quit Vim (I knew how at that point), opened
Emacs, and started building my configuration.</p><p>More recently, I’ve been very put off by the performance and stability (or
lack thereof) of building large scale software via Tramp. This has been
sufficient to have me looking out again. On a whim, I installed VSCode for
the first time and tried its “remote development” capabilities and holy
smokes are they good. Getting up and running was trivial and the
performance was great. Saving files was snappy and LSP worked out of the
box. What a different experience from my carefully-put-together,
half-working, slow Emacs setup.</p><p>My common denominator for rage-quitting software seems to be
consistent: <i>bad performance</i>.</p><p>There has recently been more discussion than usual regarding “modernizing”
Emacs, by making keybindings more consistent with other applications and
using more attractive color schemes and visuals, with the end goal of
attracting more users and by extension more contributors.</p><p>In my view improving these aspects of user experience wouldn’t hurt. The
way I see it, though, is that for Emacs to attract more users it needs to
be objectively better than the alternatives. And the way to do it is for
Emacs to become <em>even more</em> like Emacs.</p><p>I see Emacs as being fundamentally two things: a programmable runtime,
and a beacon for free software. I'm talking more about the former.</p><p>It needs to be a <em>more</em> robust, <em>more</em> efficient, and <em>more</em> integrated
platform with a <em>more</em> powerful extension language, to empower its users to
build their own environment.</p><p>Getting LSP integrated <em>pervasively</em> in Emacs in a way that it reliably
<em>just works</em> and performs well out of the box, would go a long way towards
making Emacs more attractive not just to new users, but to existing ones
too. Imagine an experience similar to VSCode’s:</p><ol><li>Open Emacs for the first time</li><li>Open a source code file</li><li>Emacs asks if you want it to configure itself for the programming
language of that source file</li><li>Saying “yes” automatically sets up Emacs to have a modern programming
environment for that programming language with smart code completion,
navigation, and refactoring, rich hover information, highlighting,
automatic formatting, snippets, etc. Maybe even open a side window with
a buffer with a short “getting started” tutorial showing the available
keybindings.</li></ol><p>Given enough users, opinionated community-built Emacs “distributions” like
Spacemacs, Doom, and Prelude will do the job of making it easier for
newcomers to get started with typical contemporary tasks: building software
with popular programming languages, writing documents, managing machines,
etc.</p><p>Building and maintaining these “distributions” also becomes much easier
given a more robust, more efficient, and more integrated platform with a
more powerful extension language.</p><p>Having a <a href="https://blog.polaris64.net/post/could-emacs-have-a-set-up-wizard/">wizard</a> showing up in new Emacs installations might be a great
low-hanging fruit way of making Emacs more accessible. Assuming buy-in from
core maintainers, the wizard could even directly reference popular Emacs
“distributions” like the ones mentioned above, so that new users can
kickstart their lives in Emacs.</p><p>The way to attract contributors can also be <em>stated</em> simply: directly improve
the contribution process.</p><p>Easier said than done.</p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VADudzQGvU8">Many</a> have created their Emacs <a href="https://www.jwz.org/doc/xemacs-wishlist.html">wishlists</a>. This is mine:</p><ol><li>Improved single-core efficiency</li><li>Improved display efficiency and rendering engine</li><li>Leveraging preemptive parallelism</li><li>Emacs Lisp improvements</li><li>Enhanced stability</li><li>Dealing with non-text</li><li>Improved contribution and development process</li></ol><p>Let’s get into it.</p><h2 id="1-dot-improved-single-core-efficiency">1. Improved single-core efficiency</h2><p>There are two dimensions to this:</p><ul><li>garbage collection efficiency</li><li>code execution efficiency</li></ul><p>For the past one and a half years, <a href="https://twitter.com/Koral%5F001">Andrea Corallo</a>, a compiler engineer,
has been <a href="https://akrl.sdf.org/gccemacs.html">working</a> on adding native compilation capabilities to the Emacs
Lisp interpreter. His work is available in a branch in the official Emacs
repository. Folks have been trying it out, and according to the reports
I’m hearing, the results are staggeringly positive. I am <em>very</em> excited
about Andrea’s work, which seems to bring enough improvement to the “code
execution speed” side of the equation to make it a non-issue for now.</p><p>Andrea’s work will also allow for more of Emacs to be implemented in Emacs
Lisp itself (instead of C), which is what most contributors are used to.
This is a great win for maintainability and extensibility: incrementally
having more and more of Emacs be implemented in the language with which
it’s extended.</p><p>The garbage collector is still in much need of improvement. Many resort to
hacks to ameliorate frequent and sometimes long pauses that seem to be
unavoidable while working on large git repositories, fast-scrolling
font-locked Eshell buffers, displaying dynamically updating child frames,
navigating big Org files, and many other tasks.</p><p><span>Also, try this out:</span> <code>(setq garbage-collection-messages t)</code></p><h2 id="2-dot-improved-display-efficiency-and-rendering-engine">2. Improved display efficiency and rendering engine</h2><p>The display implementation in Emacs core is… less than ideal.</p><blockquote><p>GNU Emacs is an old-school C program emulating a 1980s Symbolics Lisp
Machine emulating an old-fashioned Motif-style Xt toolkit emulating a
1970s text terminal emulating a 1960s teletype. Compiling Emacs is a
challenge. Adding modern rendering features to the redisplay engine is a
miracle.</p><p>— <a href="https://www.facebook.com/notes/daniel-colascione/buttery-smooth-emacs/10155313440066102/">Daniel Colascione in “Buttery Smooth Emacs” (2016)</a></p></blockquote><p>It would be great if Emacs did like Neovim and decoupled the editor
runtime from the display engine. This would make it possible for the
community to build powerful <a href="https://neovim.io/news/2020/10/#guis">GUIs</a> without having to change <a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/emacs-mirror/emacs/master/src/xdisp.c">Emacs core</a>,
possibly <a href="https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/CAO2hHWbUmgirn1gJ4OGbRghhCkOPcEsL=moc82Q-6QO+C=189Q@mail.gmail.com/">using technology</a> <a href="https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/E1jPGhC-0003i1-W4@fencepost.gnu.org/">not fully sanctioned</a> by core maintainers.</p><p>Take a look at the screenshots of these Neovim GUIs:</p><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/Kethku/neovide">neovide</a></li><li><a href="https://github.com/smolck/uivonim">uivonim</a></li></ul><p>They’re powerful, look great, perform well, and more importantly, are
based on industry standard, cross-platform graphics APIs (Vulkan and WebGL
respectively) that get lots of personpower contributions from companies
and individuals alike.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/40303878">Onivim</a> and <a href="https://github.com/xi-editor/xi-editor">Xi</a> text editors could also be sources of inspiration:</p><ul><li>Separating the core runtime from the user interface</li><li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rope%5F(data%5Fstructure)">Ropes</a> for faster incremental changes and parallelization of text
operations</li><li>Game-like drawing pipelines</li></ul><h2 id="3-dot-leveraging-preemptive-parallelism">3. Leveraging preemptive parallelism</h2><p>Emacs does not support parallel code execution via multi-core processing.
Code execution happening on any buffer will freeze the whole program,
preventing not only user interaction but other cooperative threads of
execution from making progress as well.</p><p>Adding parallelism to Emacs in a way that automatically makes existing
code run in parallel is about as close to impossible as it can get. What
would be more feasible is including new primitives for parallel execution
that new code could leverage, to build more powerful extensions to Emacs.</p><p><a href="https://github.com/emacs-ng/emacs-ng">Emacs-ng</a> is a recent effort that implements just that: an additive layer
over Emacs that brings not only parallelism, but also asynchronous I/O
capabilities via an embedded <a href="https://deno.land/">Deno</a> runtime, and GPU-based rendering via
<a href="https://github.com/servo/webrender">WebRender</a>. I am <em>super</em> excited about the very fast progress from the folks
working on emacs-ng, and I think the project holds great promise for the
future of Emacs itself.</p><p>There also seems to be advances in the area of immutable data structures
that could be leveraged by the Emacs core, as seen in “<a href="https://public.sinusoid.es/misc/immer/immer-icfp17.pdf">Persistence for the
Masses: RRB-Vectors in a Systems Language</a>”. Persistent data structures
would make building thread-safe parallel code much easier.</p><h2 id="4-dot-enhanced-stability">4. Enhanced stability</h2><p>It is very easy to either freeze Emacs or cause it to run very slowly.
Multiple times a day I have to hit <code>C-g</code> incessantly to bring it back from
being frozen. When that fails, I am sometimes able to get it back with
<code>pkill -SIGUSR2 Emacs</code>. At least once per week I have to <code>pkill -9 Emacs</code>
because it turned completely unresponsive. I suspect doing more work
outside of the main thread might help with this?</p><p>There are many hacks to ameliorate issues caused by long lines, but
they’re still fundamentally there. Advancements in the “display efficiency
and rendering engine” effort would help with this too.</p><p>I recently tried a package that displays pretty icons on completion
prompts, and noticed that it made scrolling through candidates really
slow. Profiling showed that the package was creating thousands of <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/html%5Fnode/elisp/Idle-Timers.html">timers</a>,
which were somehow causing the issue. There are lots of cases like this,
where folks attempt to create something nice, but inevitably have to
resort to <a href="https://github.com/domtronn/all-the-icons.el/issues/113">hacks</a> to either achieve acceptable performance, or to be able to
implement the thing at all. Having a more robust/efficient/integrated core
with a more powerful extension language would help here.</p><p>Impressive efforts from folks like Lars Ingebrigtsen who routinely comes
in and <a href="https://lars.ingebrigtsen.no/2020/10/26/5x10/">obliterates 10% of all reported Emacs bugs</a> also have a sizable
impact. We users should follow the lead and do a better job not only
creating good bug reports but also dipping in our toes and helping out:
fixing bugs, writing tests, and documentation.</p><p>Yuan Fu recently wrote a <a href="https://archive.casouri.cat/note/2020/contributing-to-emacs/">nice guide</a> for contributing to Emacs.</p><h2 id="5-dot-emacs-lisp-improvements">5. Emacs Lisp improvements</h2><p>Emacs Lisp is a much better language than Vimscript. Unfortunately, that’s
not saying much. It’s not a particularly good Lisp and has lots of room
for improvement.</p><blockquote><p>For example, if you want to use a map, you have three choices: you can use
alists, plists or hash maps. There are no namespaces in Emacs Lisp, so for
each of the three data types you get a bunch of functions with weird
names. For alists get is <code>assoc</code> and set is <code>add-to-list</code>, for hash maps get
is <code>gethash</code> and set is <code>puthash</code>, for plists get is <code>plist-get</code> and set is
<code>plist-put.</code> For each of those types it …</p></blockquote></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.murilopereira.com/emacs-from-catching-up-to-getting-ahead/">https://www.murilopereira.com/emacs-from-catching-up-to-getting-ahead/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.murilopereira.com/emacs-from-catching-up-to-getting-ahead/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25979530</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 15:34:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[IoT Network Watches You as You Shop – Without Cameras]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 61 | Comments 43 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25979480">thread link</a>) | @adunk
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/iot-mesh-retail/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/iot-mesh-retail/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          <section><p>Online retailers know a lot about how their customers are navigating their virtual stores. Offline retailers are not so&nbsp;lucky.</p>
<p>Together with consumer behavior experts <a href="https://b-clarity.com/2020/01/08/what-is-the-role-of-touching-in-store/" target="_blank">B:Clarity</a> and a multinational home appliance brand we built a system to help understand customer movement and&nbsp;behavior.</p>
<p>The system consists of wireless sensors that are installed in electronics stores. A few hundred sensors in each&nbsp;store.</p>
<p>There are two types of&nbsp;sensors:</p>
<ul>
<li>Vibration sensors. That trigger when someone is trying out a&nbsp;product.</li>
<li>Light sensors. Trigger when someone is standing in front of a&nbsp;product.</li>
</ul>
<p>With these sensors, we can see what items are most popular, how it correlates to sales data – and how to take action to improve&nbsp;sales.</p>
<p>But without collecting any <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personal_data" target="_blank">personally identifiable information</a>.</p>
<p>This is what the sensors look&nbsp;like:</p>
<div>
<div data-animation="quicksand" data-x-gap="16" data-y-gap="16" data-media-queries="[
{&quot;width&quot;: 1500, &quot;cols&quot;: 2},
{&quot;width&quot;: 1100, &quot;cols&quot;: 2},
{&quot;width&quot;: 800, &quot;cols&quot;: 2},
{&quot;width&quot;: 480, &quot;cols&quot;: 2},
{&quot;width&quot;: 300, &quot;cols&quot;: 2}
]">

<p><a href="https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/iot-mesh-retail/sensor1.jpg" data-title="Laptops with IoT shopping sensors">
<img width="704" height="938" data-src="sensor1.jpg" alt="Laptops with IoT shopping sensors" src="https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/iot-mesh-retail/sensor1.jpg">
<span>
<span>
<span></span>
</span>
</span>
</a>
</p>


<p><a href="https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/iot-mesh-retail/sensor2.jpg" data-title="Cleaning equipment with IoT shopping sensors">
<img width="661" height="881" data-src="sensor2.jpg" alt="Cleaning equipment with IoT shopping sensors" src="https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/iot-mesh-retail/sensor2.jpg">
<span>
<span>
<span></span>
</span>
</span>
</a>
</p>

</div>
</div>


<p>And this is where they are&nbsp;installed:</p>



<h2 id="why-monitor-shoppers-">Why monitor&nbsp;shoppers?</h2>
<p>Online retailers and e-commerce has many ways to gain insight into their customers. Examples include seeing the <a href="https://help.shopify.com/en/manual/reports-and-analytics/shopify-reports/report-types/behaviour-reports#top-online-store-searches" target="_blank">toplist of searched-for items</a>, and the <a href="https://help.shopify.com/en/manual/reports-and-analytics/shopify-reports/report-types/behaviour-reports#top-online-store-searches-with-no-results" target="_blank">toplist of searched-for items with no results</a>.</p>
<p>Physical retailers don’t want to be left&nbsp;behind.</p>
<p>So many different ways to monitor shoppers in physical stores have been&nbsp;developed.</p>
<p>Amazon Go stores extensively <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/21/inside-amazons-surveillance-powered-no-checkout-convenience-store/" target="_blank">use cameras</a> to track everything that happens inside their&nbsp;stores.</p>
<p>Many stores provide free WiFi so that they can <a href="https://www.retaildive.com/spons/wi-fi-tracking-a-data-gold-mine-or-privacy-nightmare/572937/" target="_blank">track their customers</a>.</p>
<p>All these solutions have a big problem:&nbsp;privacy.</p>
<p>Cameras see everything – much more than they need. And this data is collected and stored. Free WiFi hotspots may capture all kinds of&nbsp;traffic.</p>
<p>This is an obvious privacy problem for the&nbsp;shoppers.</p>
<p>But it is not just a problem for the&nbsp;shoppers.</p>
<p>It also creates a major problem for the companies storing the data: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/19/silicon-valley-terrified-california-privacy-law/" target="_blank">personally identifiable data is a liability</a>.</p>
<p>This is why we chose vibration sensors and light sensors. No liability from owning any personally identifiable&nbsp;information.</p>
<p>With only vibration and light, there simply is nothing there to identify individual&nbsp;shoppers.</p>
<div>
<div>
<div data-src="washingmachines.jpg">
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<figure>
<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" x="0px" y="0px" viewBox="0 0 8 8" style="enable-background:new 0 0 8 8;" space="preserve">
<path d="M3,1.3C2,1.7,1.2,2.7,1.2,3.6c0,0.2,0,0.4,0.1,0.5c0.2-0.2,0.5-0.3,0.9-0.3c0.8,0,1.5,0.6,1.5,1.5c0,0.9-0.7,1.5-1.5,1.5
C1.4,6.9,1,6.6,0.7,6.1C0.4,5.6,0.3,4.9,0.3,4.5c0-1.6,0.8-2.9,2.5-3.7L3,1.3z M7.1,1.3c-1,0.4-1.8,1.4-1.8,2.3
c0,0.2,0,0.4,0.1,0.5c0.2-0.2,0.5-0.3,0.9-0.3c0.8,0,1.5,0.6,1.5,1.5c0,0.9-0.7,1.5-1.5,1.5c-0.7,0-1.1-0.3-1.4-0.8
C4.4,5.6,4.4,4.9,4.4,4.5c0-1.6,0.8-2.9,2.5-3.7L7.1,1.3z"></path>
</svg>
</figure>
<blockquote>
Our IoT shopper system uses simple sensors: vibration and light.
</blockquote>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<h2 id="understanding-shopper-behavior">Understanding shopper&nbsp;behavior</h2>
<p>As a shopper, you want to find the best products, and – ideally – pay the lowest possible&nbsp;price.</p>
<p>The retailers and producers have slightly different&nbsp;motivations:</p>
<ul>
<li>Brands want customer to buy their products, and not their&nbsp;competitors’</li>
<li>Retailers want to sell more&nbsp;products</li>
</ul>
<p>And when the motivations of shoppers, retailers, and brands align, business is made. And the more business, the better for&nbsp;all.</p>
<p>Understanding customer behavior is key to improving the experience for&nbsp;everyone.</p>
<p>The sensors detect when people are looking at items. And they report this immediately, so that we can see in real-time where shoppers&nbsp;are.</p>
<div>
<div data-layout="grid" data-controls="#filterControls" data-animation="quicksand" data-x-gap="32" data-y-gap="32" data-media-queries="[
{&quot;width&quot;: 1500, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 1100, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 800, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 480, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 300, &quot;cols&quot;: 1}
]">
<div>
<p><small>
Shopper hotspots: the IoT mesh network collects its data in real-time, so that we can see where shoppers are – right now.
</small>
</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>But the data is also posted to a backend database. This lets us to more <a href="https://b-clarity.com/case/100-000-human-interactions-cant-be-wrong-touch-increases-sales/" target="_blank">in-depth, off-line analysis</a> of the data, see how it changes over time, and how it improves the&nbsp;sales.</p>
<div>
<div data-layout="grid" data-controls="#filterControls" data-animation="quicksand" data-x-gap="32" data-y-gap="32" data-media-queries="[
{&quot;width&quot;: 1500, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 1100, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 800, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 480, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 300, &quot;cols&quot;: 1}
]">
<div>
<p><small>
The data is also stored in a backend database so that we can run powerful off-line analytics on the data.
</small>
</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>To be able to cover large electronics stores, we use a wireless IoT mesh&nbsp;network.</p>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<figure>
<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" x="0px" y="0px" viewBox="0 0 8 8" style="enable-background:new 0 0 8 8;" space="preserve">
<path d="M3,1.3C2,1.7,1.2,2.7,1.2,3.6c0,0.2,0,0.4,0.1,0.5c0.2-0.2,0.5-0.3,0.9-0.3c0.8,0,1.5,0.6,1.5,1.5c0,0.9-0.7,1.5-1.5,1.5
C1.4,6.9,1,6.6,0.7,6.1C0.4,5.6,0.3,4.9,0.3,4.5c0-1.6,0.8-2.9,2.5-3.7L3,1.3z M7.1,1.3c-1,0.4-1.8,1.4-1.8,2.3
c0,0.2,0,0.4,0.1,0.5c0.2-0.2,0.5-0.3,0.9-0.3c0.8,0,1.5,0.6,1.5,1.5c0,0.9-0.7,1.5-1.5,1.5c-0.7,0-1.1-0.3-1.4-0.8
C4.4,5.6,4.4,4.9,4.4,4.5c0-1.6,0.8-2.9,2.5-3.7L7.1,1.3z"></path>
</svg>
</figure>
<blockquote>
Electronics stores are large. But a wireless sub-GHz IoT mesh network can easily cover the entire area.
</blockquote>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<h2 id="why-use-a-wireless-iot-mesh-network-">Why use a wireless IoT mesh&nbsp;network?</h2>
<p>A wireless mesh network is a wireless network that automatically extend its&nbsp;range.</p>
<p>The Thingsquare IoT mesh network solution uses so-called <a href="https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/what-is-subghz-networking/" target="_blank">sub-GHz wireless technology</a> that has way better range than traditional WiFi or&nbsp;Bluetooth.</p>
<p>But even with a longer range, it is not always&nbsp;enough.</p>
<p>Electronics stores can be very large. And there is plenty of metal inside them that hampers the wireless&nbsp;coverage.</p>
<p>A mesh network is the ideal technology in these&nbsp;situations:</p>
<ul>
<li><p><strong>Coverage</strong>. Electronics stores can be huge. With a mesh network, we can cover it&nbsp;all.</p>
</li>
<li><p><strong>It just works</strong>. No network planning is&nbsp;needed.</p>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Easy to install</strong>. Just put each device where it should&nbsp;be.</p>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Easy to maintain</strong>. If there are issues with coverage, just add extenders as&nbsp;needed.</p>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Robustness</strong>. If something changes, the network will automatically adapt and&nbsp;overcome.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>This is what the wireless mesh network typically looks&nbsp;like:</p>
<div>
<div data-layout="grid" data-controls="#filterControls" data-animation="quicksand" data-x-gap="32" data-y-gap="32" data-media-queries="[
{&quot;width&quot;: 1500, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 1100, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 800, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 480, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 300, &quot;cols&quot;: 1}
]">
<div>
<p><small>
The IoT mesh network uses range extenders to cover the entire area of the electronics store.
</small>
</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>In this deployment, the mesh network used one access point and two extenders. Most device are able to reach the access point directly, but some chose to talk to one of the&nbsp;extenders.</p>
<h2 id="battery-life">Battery&nbsp;life</h2>
<p>The sensors are equipped with batteries: one coin-cell battery&nbsp;each.</p>
<p>The Thingsquare IoT mesh system is <a href="https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/sensortag-power/" target="_blank">tailored for extreme low-power operation</a>. Extreme low-power operation in this case means that the sensors can go for several months one a single&nbsp;charge.</p>
<p>For example, the sensors are automatically turned off at night, to conserve their precious&nbsp;power.</p>
<p>But most importantly, the Thingsquare system continuously collects power consumption data from each and every&nbsp;sensor.</p>
<p>This data lets us see the exact behavior at any given time: are there any sensors that behave in a way that require their batteries to be replaced earlier? The Thingsquare system knows the answers to this, and alerts us if this would be the&nbsp;case.</p>
<div>
<div data-layout="grid" data-controls="#filterControls" data-animation="quicksand" data-x-gap="32" data-y-gap="32" data-media-queries="[
{&quot;width&quot;: 1500, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 1100, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 800, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 480, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 300, &quot;cols&quot;: 1}
]">
<div>
<p><small>
Each sensor measures and reports a detailed break-down of their power consumption.
</small>
</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<h2 id="connectivity">Connectivity</h2>
<p>The ioT mesh network is connected to the Internet via a 4G modem. The network maintains a stable encrypted connection to the backend system so that the devices always can be&nbsp;reached.</p>
<p>If the Internet connection would go down at any point during the deployment, the devices hold off from reporting their data until the Internet connection is&nbsp;restored.</p>
<p>With this technique, no data is ever&nbsp;lost.</p>
<div>
<div data-layout="grid" data-controls="#filterControls" data-animation="quicksand" data-x-gap="32" data-y-gap="32" data-media-queries="[
{&quot;width&quot;: 1500, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 1100, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 800, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 480, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 300, &quot;cols&quot;: 1}
]">
<div>
<p><small>
A vibration sensor installed on top of a washing machine.
</small>
</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<h2 id="technical-details">Technical&nbsp;details</h2>
<p>The software used in the project is the <a href="https://www.thingsquare.com/iot-platform/" target="_blank">Thingsquare IoT platform</a>, with its wireless mesh network and the backend controller in the&nbsp;cloud:</p>
<ul>
<li>Thingsquare’s IoT mesh <a href="https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/what-is-subghz-networking/" target="_blank">Sub-GHz</a> radio&nbsp;technology</li>
<li>Thingsquare’s IoT mesh IPv6 networking and the <span>RPL</span> mesh routing&nbsp;protocol</li>
<li><span>TLS</span> end-to-end&nbsp;encryption</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/channel-hopping/" target="_blank">Channel hopping</a> to avoid problematic radio&nbsp;channels</li>
<li>Cloud deployment on&nbsp;<span>AWS</span></li>
</ul>
<p>The project uses the following hardware&nbsp;components:</p>
<ul>
<li>The Texas Instrument <span>CC1350</span> wireless System-on-a-Chip (which is an earlier version of the current <a href="https://www.ti.com/tool/LPSTK-CC1352R" target="_blank"><span>CC1352R</span> SoC</a> that we currently&nbsp;use)</li>
<li>An <a href="https://invensense.tdk.com/products/motion-tracking/9-axis/mpu-9250/" target="_blank"><span>MPU9250</span> accelerometer</a> to detect&nbsp;vibrations</li>
<li>An <a href="https://www.ti.com/product/OPT3001" target="_blank"><span>OPT3001</span> digital ambient light sensor</a> to measure changes in lighting&nbsp;conditions</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="conclusions">Conclusions</h2>
<p>This project is a multi-year collaboration between a Thingsquare customer and a major multinational home appliance brand. Thingsquare is the technology partner, providing our wireless IoT technology and expertise to make the project come&nbsp;true.</p>
<p>Are you looking to build an IoT project with extreme requirements in terms of scale, coverage, or power consumption? <a href="#" data-modal-target="#start">Get in touch with us today</a> to see how we can help you make your project come&nbsp;true!</p>
</section>
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/iot-mesh-retail/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25979480</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 15:28:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Rome in 3D]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 156 | Comments 56 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25979436">thread link</a>) | @GizmoSwan
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | https://relivehistoryin3d.com/projects/rome-in-3d/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://relivehistoryin3d.com/projects/rome-in-3d/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content"><div id="primary"><main id="main" role="main"> <img src="https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Rome-in-3D_opt.jpg" data-src="https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Rome-in-3D_opt.jpg" alt="" width="1600" height="900" data-srcset="https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Rome-in-3D_opt.jpg 1600w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Rome-in-3D_opt-600x338.jpg 600w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Rome-in-3D_opt-768x432.jpg 768w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Rome-in-3D_opt-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Rome-in-3D_opt-400x225.jpg 400w" data-sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" srcset="https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Rome-in-3D_opt.jpg 1600w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Rome-in-3D_opt-600x338.jpg 600w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Rome-in-3D_opt-768x432.jpg 768w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Rome-in-3D_opt-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Rome-in-3D_opt-400x225.jpg 400w"><p>What is our “Rome in 3D” project in general? Broadly speaking, it is an attempt to give you an opportunity to take a look at Rome as it really was, by the eyes of humans who lived there in that time. Due to this, we are already paying much attention (and will proceed) to the level of details, adding realistic materials, colors, visual and weather effects. That’s why we are concentrating just on the center of the Rome for now, just to focus on quality and details.</p><p>Now we are planning to add a little additional territory (such as Circus Maximus, Velabrum area), and release our project as a 3d walkthrough application. I hope we will be able to complete it in a year approximately.</p> <img src="https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Enscape_2019-10-16-22-47-45_opt.jpg" data-src="https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Enscape_2019-10-16-22-47-45_opt.jpg" alt="" width="1600" height="900" data-srcset="https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Enscape_2019-10-16-22-47-45_opt.jpg 1600w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Enscape_2019-10-16-22-47-45_opt-600x338.jpg 600w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Enscape_2019-10-16-22-47-45_opt-768x432.jpg 768w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Enscape_2019-10-16-22-47-45_opt-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Enscape_2019-10-16-22-47-45_opt-400x225.jpg 400w" data-sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" srcset="https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Enscape_2019-10-16-22-47-45_opt.jpg 1600w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Enscape_2019-10-16-22-47-45_opt-600x338.jpg 600w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Enscape_2019-10-16-22-47-45_opt-768x432.jpg 768w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Enscape_2019-10-16-22-47-45_opt-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Enscape_2019-10-16-22-47-45_opt-400x225.jpg 400w"><p>Boasting some impressive in-video lighting features, the animation focuses on the monumental scale that was flaunted by Rome during its apical architectural stage. And furthermore according to&nbsp; the animators of this video – this movie is just a promo, with the entire scope (which took years to animate) to be inducted into a game engine that would be accessible to the interested people.</p><figure id="attachment_92" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-92"><img src="https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/BC_caldarium_opt.jpg" data-src="https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/BC_caldarium_opt.jpg" alt="" width="1600" height="900" data-srcset="https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/BC_caldarium_opt.jpg 1600w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/BC_caldarium_opt-600x338.jpg 600w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/BC_caldarium_opt-768x432.jpg 768w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/BC_caldarium_opt-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/BC_caldarium_opt-400x225.jpg 400w" data-sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" srcset="https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/BC_caldarium_opt.jpg 1600w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/BC_caldarium_opt-600x338.jpg 600w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/BC_caldarium_opt-768x432.jpg 768w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/BC_caldarium_opt-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://relivehistoryin3d.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/BC_caldarium_opt-400x225.jpg 400w"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-92"><strong>Baths of Caracalla</strong></figcaption></figure><p>The « History in 3D » creative team continues working on a virtual reconstruction of ancient Rome. Our goal is to carry out this project at a new qualitative level using modern available data and technical capabilities. Some time ago, three video trailers about Rome in 3D reconstruction have already been released on our YouTube channel, representing the various stages of work on the reconstruction. Since the recent video was released, a lot of work has been done to update and expand the content, and we believe that the project has been transformed crucially and reached a new level of quality.</p><p>Here, our 3rd trailer about Colosseum district:<br></p><center><br> <iframe title="&quot;HISTORY IN 3D&quot; - ANCIENT ROME 320 AD -  3rd trailer &quot;Walking around Colosseum&quot;" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/btKooS7k3nw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe><br></center><br> &nbsp;<hr><h2>Recent project articles</h2><div><p><img src="data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns=%22http://www.w3.org/2000/svg%22%20viewBox=%220%200%20210%20140%22%3E%3C/svg%3E" data-src=""></p>   </div></main></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://relivehistoryin3d.com/projects/rome-in-3d/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25979436</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 15:22:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[First Principles as a Life Strategy]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 10 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25979431">thread link</a>) | @Bluestein
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | https://vineet.bearblog.dev/first-principles/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://vineet.bearblog.dev/first-principles/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <div><p>Pioneered 2000 years ago by Aristotle and popularized most recently by Elon Musk, <em>First Principles</em> is a method of reasoning which involves breaking down a complex problem into its most fundamental parts and reasoning upwards from there.</p>
<p>In his interview with Kevin Rose, Musk says:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“It’s important to reason from first principles rather than by analogy. So the normal way we conduct our lives is, we reason by analogy. We are doing this because it’s like something else that was done, or it is like what other people are doing… with slight iterations on a theme. And it’s … mentally easier to reason by analogy rather than from first principles. First principles is kind of a physics way of looking at the world, and what that really means is, you … boil things down to the most fundamental truths and say, “okay, what are we sure is true?”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Given his ubiquitous popularity in the mainstream culture, it is easy to forget that what Musk is doing is literally <em>unearthly</em>! Take a minute and read <a href="https://www.spacex.com/human-spaceflight/mars/">this page</a> on SpaceX's mission statement. It's hard to fathom how courageous, confident and clear one needs to be in their thinking, to come up with a plan to colonize Mars(!) and saying it publicly without the fear of being ridiculed. How does he do it?</p>
<p>He takes an insanely complicated problem, goes to the bottom of it and comes up with intuitive solutions which people before him never came up with because they reasoned by analogy. Notice how this theme of <em>first principles</em> based problem-solving underlies all of his work:</p>
<ul>
<li><p><strong>SpaceX</strong> — Space flight is crazy expensive. Why? Because we use new rockets for every launch. That sounds dumb. Let's find a way to make reusable rockets. To the layman it sounds obvious. But why didn't people before him question these basics? Lack of <em>first principles</em> based thinking.</p>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Tesla</strong> — Fuel-based automobiles are bad for the planet. Why can't people switch to electric cars? Because they are not battery efficient, lack performance and are often poorly designed. Boom! Tesla now builds some of the most good looking and fastest cars on the planet.</p>
</li>
<li><p><strong>The Boring Company</strong> — There's too much traffic on the road. Why? Human settlements are multiple storeyed. But human transport is still archaic and restricted to one plane. Let's change that by boring underground transportation tunnels.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>All of this sounds so damn obvious and it is hard to believe that people never questioned these basic premises in their fields. It is mind-blowing how restrictive reasoning by analogy can be.</p>
<h2 id="first-principles-approach-to-life">First Principles Approach to Life</h2>
<p>I know. <em>First principles</em> seems overly simplistic in theory. But trust me, it can be quite difficult to implement. Now I don't know how to make rockets like Elon but over time I have learned how to use <em>first principles</em> as a strategy for living life.</p>
<p>Living abroad and building your life from scratch in a new country is a great way to identify with these principles. In retrospect, I realise that the most fundamental elements of my life were often the things which I took for granted while living at home. Which included my physical and mental health, my friends and family, and a sense of belonging which your homeland provides.</p>
<p>Lockdown-induced self-introspection made 2020 a year of tremendous personal growth and I realised that I had made a lot of decisions in my personal and professional life which did not allign with my principles. But that's okay. We all get influenced by culture and the people around us. We try to replicate other people's life strategies because we see them working. Once you identify and build your life around your own principles, you quickly become unapologetic and make decisions without seeking external validation.</p>
<p>Imagine your life is a tree and every decision you make branches you out into the world. Now all trees branch out differently so it is futile to imitate the trees around you. Of course, you can get some idea about what kind of decisions lead you where but it is really stupid to shape yourself in somebody else's reflection. The reason why <em>first principles</em> drastically improves your decision making and life satisfaction is because every decision you take, every new branch you create, is strongly attached to your own core. Even if it doesn't work out, you will love it as your own.</p>
<p>As it often happens with people, your principles may change over time and that's okay. You can rebranch your tree gradually but honestly, I do believe that there are some core, non-negotiable principles to live a good life. These can also be a good starting point to create your own list of <em>first principles</em>. Here are three undeniable ones — taking care of your body, maintaining healthy relationships and doing satisfying work which pays the bills. Everytime I find myself in a rut, I reason upwards from here.</p>
<h2 id="first-principles-as-opposed-to-backwards-induction">First Principles as opposed to <em>Backwards Induction</em></h2>
<p>I have never found it useful to set specific goals. An unpopular opinion, I know. A notoriously flawed concept in self-improvement circles is the concept of S.M.A.R.T. goals. It is an acronym for goals which are specific, measurable, attainable, relevant and time-bound. This life strategy is a derivative of <em>Backwards Induction</em> way-of-reasoning where you take the end goal in mind and reason backwards from there. Personally, I've found this strategy to be too restrictive and given my temparament and personality-type, I have always enjoyed some amount of spontaneity in life. I like to diversify my interests, trying different things and adjusting my sails as I move forward making sure that I don't miss the forest for the trees. In Tim Minchin's words, "the disciplined pursuit of short-term goals."</p>
<p>I would rather aim to build systems which are in allignment with my principles. Instead of setting a goal to run a sub-4 hour marathon in 6 months, it is more sustainable to create a system which allows me to become a better runner. This means I run every other day, focus on recovery and nutrition, and push my self everyday without injuring myself. Since I don't care about the specifics, I am never dissapointed even if I fail to reach these arbitary metrics. You might say that every system inherently has a goal, no matter how vague. That is true. But the important point is not to make these goals <em>too</em> specific.</p>
<p>This way, reasoning by <em>first principles</em> clears your head, getting rid of assumptions, external influences and perceived limitations drastically improving life satisfaction.</p>
</div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://vineet.bearblog.dev/first-principles/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25979431</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 15:21:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Turn an IKEA Coffee Table into a DIY Server Rack]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 400 | Comments 192 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25978013">thread link</a>) | @thejokersthief
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/LackRack | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/LackRack">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="mw-content-text" lang="en" dir="ltr"><div><div><div><p><a href="https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/File:Lackrack_manual_page_1_400x566.png"><img alt="" src="https://wiki.eth0.nl/images/3/33/Lackrack_manual_page_1_400x566.png" decoding="async" width="400" height="566" data-file-width="400" data-file-height="566"></a></p></div></div>



<div><div><p><a href="https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/File:LackRack.jpg"><img alt="" src="https://wiki.eth0.nl/images/7/7a/LackRack.jpg" decoding="async" width="400" height="300" data-file-width="3072" data-file-height="2304"></a></p><div><p>The first implementation: Red LackRack with Ethernet switch and table lamp</p></div></div></div>
<p>First occurrence on <a href="https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/Eth0:2010_Winter" title="Eth0:2010 Winter">eth0:2010 Winterlan</a>, the LackRack is the ultimate, low-cost, high shininess solution for your modular datacenter-in-the-living-room. Featuring the <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ikea.com/us/en/catalog/products/40104270">LACK</a> (side table) from Ikea, the LackRack is an easy-to-implement, exact-fit datacenter building block.
It's a little known fact that we have seen Google engineers tinker with Lack tables since way back in 2009.
</p><p>The LackRack will certainly make its appearance again this summer at <a href="https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/Eth0:2010_Summer" title="Eth0:2010 Summer">eth0:2010 Summer</a>.
</p>

<div><div><p><a href="https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/File:Lack-offline.jpg"><img alt="" src="https://wiki.eth0.nl/images/7/79/Lack-offline.jpg" decoding="async" width="250" height="244" data-file-width="250" data-file-height="244"></a></p><div><p>When temporarily not in use, multiple LackRacks can be stacked in a space-efficient way <i>without disassembly</i>, unlike competing 19" server racks.</p></div></div></div><p>The LackRack was first seen on <a href="https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/Eth0:2010_Winter" title="Eth0:2010 Winter">eth0:2010 Winterlan</a> in the no-shoe Lounge area. Its low-cost and perfect fit are great for mounting up to 8 U of 19" hardware, such as switches (see below), or perhaps other 19" gear. It's very easy to assemble, and thanks to the design, they are stable enough to hold (for example) 19" switches and you can put your bottle of Club-Mate on top! Multi-shiny LackRack can also be painted to your specific preferences and the airflow is unprecedented!
</p>
<p>You can find a howto on buying a LackRack on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://mrngm.com/eth0/LackRack/">this page</a>. This includes the proof that a 19" switch can indeed be placed in the LackRack in its natural habitat!
</p>
<div><div><p><a href="https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/File:Lackrack-w-switch.jpg"><img alt="" src="https://wiki.eth0.nl/images/d/d7/Lackrack-w-switch.jpg" decoding="async" width="250" height="188" data-file-width="2592" data-file-height="1944"></a></p><div><p>Close-up of the LackRack, with a switch, in its natural habitat (the IKEA)</p></div></div></div>

<div><div><p><a href="https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/File:5x_lackrack.jpg"><img alt="" src="https://wiki.eth0.nl/images/9/99/5x_lackrack.jpg" decoding="async" width="250" height="250" data-file-width="800" data-file-height="800"></a></p><div><p>Illustration of the LackRack's modularity</p></div></div></div><p><i>For assembly in terms of a programming language, this is not the page you need.</i>
</p><p>However, in order to assemble the LackRack, there are a few prerequisites or tools that are needed:
</p>
<ul><li>1 (or more) LACK side table from Ikea</li>
<li>Screwdriver (whether muscle-driven or motor-driven, with preference of the latter)</li>
<li>Wood screws (they should fit in the rack mounts on your appliance, and not exceed 1" in length)</li>
<li>Spare time</li></ul>
<p>That's all! First, follow the assembly instructions in the Ikea manual in order to assemble the LACK.
After that, the installation of your 19" hardware can begin. When assembling a larger number of LACKs, <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.instructables.com/id/IKEA_Hack_a_Lack/">this link</a> describes a useful tool for fitting the legs to the tabletop.
</p><p>The LackRack is a stackable modular product. Additional elements can be stacked on top easily. Brackets to secure the top element to the bottom one are not included but available from your local non-computer hardware store.
</p>
<ul><li>If you put several LackRacks side by side, the higher levels can be staggered to form a pyramid. This feature is not present in any other of the commercially available rack products.</li></ul>

<div><div><p><a href="https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/File:Lackrack2.jpg"><img alt="" src="https://wiki.eth0.nl/images/7/76/Lackrack2.jpg" decoding="async" width="300" height="400" data-file-width="1536" data-file-height="2048"></a></p><div><p>Due to their light weight design, Lackracks will grow to any required size without compromise</p></div></div></div>
<p>Installing hardware in your LackRack is easy!
</p>
<ul><li><i>Optional but recommended</i> - Put the table on its side (which one is your decision) or upside down</li>
<li>Mount the hardware between the left and right leg
<ul><li>If you mount the first item, it is recommended to install it against the table top for good fit. This happens automatically if you have the LackRack upside down, except in zero gravity environments.</li></ul></li>
<li>Screw all the screws that fit in the rack mount in the left and right leg (for stability).
<ul><li>With deep units, a Z-shaped bracket may be advisable to secure the rear of the unit against the underside of the tabletop.</li></ul></li>
<li>&nbsp;???</li>
<li>Profit! (note how <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.rackable.com/">lackable.com</a> has been bought by sgi recently)</li></ul>
<h2><span id="Note">Note</span></h2>
<p>Current LACK tables have hollow legs; only the top 5 cm (2") is solid. Fitting equipment below the solid section may require the use of cavity plugs, such as <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.fischer-international.com/en/products/cavity-fixings/board-fixing/metal-cavity-fixing-hm/519772-hm-5-x-37-s">these</a>
</p>
<h2><span id="Goodies">Goodies</span></h2>
<ul><li>You can put food and/or drink on your rack.</li>
<li>You can put a small lamp on top of the rack to see your hardware and/or better find the aforementioned food and drink.</li>
<li>The table can be painted in a color of your preference, or decorated in various ways. The eth0 Design team can advise, for a fee, how to optimally decorate the rack to suit your environment.
<ul><li>That means, no more dull black/gray racks!</li>
<li>Or you can put <a href="https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/File:Lack2.jpg" title="File:Lack2.jpg">stickers of your favorite event</a> on them.</li></ul></li>
<li>It's easy to colour-code your datacentre: e.g. <span>red</span> for critical services, <span>grey</span> for office automation, <span>green</span> for file-servers, <span>black</span> for systems and network management.</li>
<li>Cheap!</li>
<li>Easy!</li>
<li>Looks good!</li></ul>
<h2><span id="Alternative_configuration">Alternative configuration</span></h2>
<div><div><p><a href="https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/File:Lack_alt1.jpg"><img alt="" src="https://wiki.eth0.nl/images/7/74/Lack_alt1.jpg" decoding="async" width="300" height="225" data-file-width="768" data-file-height="576"></a></p><div><p>fitting the equipment to the rear of the front legs</p></div></div></div>
<ul><li>Mounting the equipment to the rear of the front legs is recommended if you plan to fit switches with fiber uplinks; the created tabletop overhang shields the fiber connections from minor mishap</li></ul>
<div><div><p><a href="https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/File:Lack_alt2.jpg"><img alt="" src="https://wiki.eth0.nl/images/5/57/Lack_alt2.jpg" decoding="async" width="300" height="225" data-file-width="768" data-file-height="576"></a></p><div><p>front view: 8 port switch with fiber uplink, and power bar</p></div></div></div>
<div><div><p><a href="https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/File:Lack_alt3.jpg"><img alt="" src="https://wiki.eth0.nl/images/f/f3/Lack_alt3.jpg" decoding="async" width="300" height="225" data-file-width="768" data-file-height="576"></a></p></div></div>

<ul><li>Q: Does the LackRack provide redundant power supply?
<ul><li>A: Only if you add it yourself</li></ul></li>
<li>Q: Can I put my (coffee) mug on top and don't have to worry about it if I spill liquid on the LackRack?
<ul><li>A: You can spill coffee on the LackRack, since it can be cleaned quite easily. However, if you have appliances <b>in</b> the LackRack, there is a chance that these appliances cannot handle the coffee (or any other liquid). You should take precautions in order to protect your appliances</li></ul></li></ul>

<p>As from the Ikea <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ikea.com/us/en/catalog/products/40104270">product page</a>:
</p>
<ul><li>Product information
<ul><li>Easy to assemble.</li>
<li>Low weight; easy to move.</li>
<li>Readily available desktop area holding your laptop during maintenance.</li>
<li>Levenstein distance of "Lack" and "Rack" is 1. Can this still be a coincidence?</li></ul></li></ul>
<ul><li>Designer:
<ul><li>IKEA of Sweden</li></ul></li></ul>
<ul><li>Product dimensions
<ul><li>Length: 55cm (21 5/8 ")</li>
<li>Width: 55cm (21 5/8 ")</li>
<li>Height: 45cm (17 3/4 ")</li>
<li>Almost 9U of rack space</li></ul></li></ul>
<ul><li>Care instructions
<ul><li>Wipe clean using a damp cloth and a mild cleaner.</li>
<li>Wipe dry with a clean cloth</li></ul></li></ul>
<ul><li>Product description
<ul><li>Top: Particleboard, Fiberboard, ABS plastic, Printed and embossed acrylic paint, Clear acrylic lacquer</li>
<li>Filling material: Paper</li>
<li>Leg: Particleboard, Fiberboard, Foil, Foil</li></ul></li></ul>

<h2><span id="Enterprise_Edition">Enterprise Edition</span></h2>
<div><div><p><a href="https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/File:Lackrack_enterprise.jpg"><img alt="" src="https://wiki.eth0.nl/images/4/41/Lackrack_enterprise.jpg" decoding="async" width="400" height="300" data-file-width="1024" data-file-height="768"></a></p><div><p><a rel="nofollow" href="http://revspace.nl/">RevSpace</a> branded LackRack Enterprise Edition</p></div></div></div>
<div><div><p><a href="https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/File:Norco-3216-LackRack.jpg"><img alt="" src="https://wiki.eth0.nl/images/0/0f/Norco-3216-LackRack.jpg" decoding="async" width="400" height="300" data-file-width="720" data-file-height="540"></a></p><div><p><a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.norcotek.com/item_detail.php?categoryid=1&amp;modelno=RPC-3216">Norco RPC-3216</a> mounted in a LackRack Enterprise Edition.<br>Additional brackets used to raise the shelf and support the 45kg+ weight.</p></div></div></div>
<p><a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ikea.com/nl/nl/catalog/products/00095036">Ikea LACK coffee table</a>: almost twice as deep, and comes with a shelf. Its size allows both short ends to be used as rack space simultaneously. It's interesting to note that Ikea photographed it from the side; an uncommon artistic approach to 19" server rack photography.
It provides for 8 U of hardware: 4 on either side of the shelf.
</p><p>Following ICT tradition, the Enterprise Edition is more than three times as expensive, while providing less stability than two of the regular products combined.
</p>
<ul><li>Product information
<ul><li>Easy to assemble.</li>
<li>Low weight; easy to move.</li>
<li>Readily available desktop area holding your laptop during maintenance.</li>
<li>Levenstein distance of "Lack" and "Rack" is 1. Can this still be a coincidence?</li></ul></li></ul>
<ul><li>Designer:
<ul><li>IKEA of Sweden</li></ul></li></ul>
<ul><li>Product dimensions
<ul><li>Length: 90cm</li>
<li>Width: 55cm (21 5/8 ")</li>
<li>Height: 45cm (17 3/4 ")</li></ul></li></ul>
<ul><li>Care instructions
<ul><li>Wipe clean using a damp cloth and a mild cleaner.</li>
<li>Wipe dry with a clean cloth</li></ul></li></ul>
<ul><li>Product description&nbsp;:
<ul><li>Top: Particleboard, Fiberboard, ABS plastic, Printed and embossed acrylic paint, Clear acrylic lacquer</li>
<li>Filling material: Paper</li>
<li>Leg: Particleboard, Fiberboard, Foil, Foil</li></ul></li></ul>

<p>It is clear that Ikea has strived to keep many of their products
rack compatible since so many of them are capable of housing 19"
equipment. See <a href="https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/List_of_IkeaRacks" title="List of IkeaRacks">List_of_IkeaRacks</a>
</p>


<ul><li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=lackrack">Twitter search on <i>lackrack</i></a></li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/LackRack/267773044028">LackRack fans on Facebook</a></li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://fenrir.high5.net/view_album.php?set_albumName=LackRack">Photos of an installed RackLack</a> with (fanless) HP Procurve 2510 <b>(in production)</b></li></ul>
<dl><dt>Danish</dt></dl>
<ul><li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.sunech.com/2010/01/21/serverrack-fra-ikea/"><b>Sunech</b>: Server rack from Ikea?</a></li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.lydmaskinen.dk/viewtopic.php?f=17&amp;p=273452"><b>Lydmaskinen</b>: Forum thread</a></li></ul>
<dl><dt>Dutch</dt></dl>
<ul><li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.webhostingtalk.nl/webhostingtalk-lounge/157237-het-lackrack-van-ikea-3.html"><b>WebHostingTalk</b>: Forum thread</a></li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://rapture.tweakblogs.net/blog/3449/lackrack.html"><b>Rapture's logs</b>: LackRack</a> (Blogger discovers that his 19" gear lacks mounting brackets, after buying a new LackRack...)</li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://blog.webwereld.nl/2010/01/25/een-datacenter-in-je-huiskamer/"><b>Webwereld</b>: Een datacenter in je huiskamer</a></li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.matthijs.org/lackrack_2_0"><b>Matthijs.org</b>: LackRack v2.0</a> (LackRack variation for more practical everyday office use)</li></ul>
<dl><dt>English</dt></dl>
<ul><li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://mrngm.com/eth0/LackRack/"><b>mrngm</b>: LackRack - an odyssee</a> (Buyer's guide)</li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.instructables.com/id/IKEA_Hack_a_Lack/"><b>instructables</b>: IKEA Hack-a-Lack</a> (Not about the LackRack per se, but a method for assembling a large number of them)</li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.datacenterknowledge.com/archives/2010/01/21/the-new-data-center-rack-from-ikea/"><b>Data Center Knowledge</b>: The New Data Center Rack From ... IKEA?</a></li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://blog.makezine.com/archive/2010/01/lackrack_ikea_server_racks_for_livi.html"><b>Make:</b>: Ikea server racks for living room datacenters</a> (<a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.edugeek.net/forums/general-chat/48713-lackrack-ikea-server-racks-living-room-datacenters.html">forum 1</a>, <a rel="nofollow" href="http://forums.hexus.net/general-discussion/179779-lackrack-ikea-server-racks-living-room-datacenters.html">forum 2</a>)</li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://idle.slashdot.org/story/10/01/21/1717224/LackRack-Makes-Home-Colocation-More-Affordable"><b>Slashdot</b>: LackRack Makes Home Colocation More Affordable</a></li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.nordichardware.com/news,10613.html"><b>NordicHardware</b>: The LackRack - €5 server rack, for real!</a> (<a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.nordichardware.com/forum/view-previous-topic-vt13397.html">forum</a>)</li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://dailydiy.com/2010/01/22/lackrack-ikea-server-racks-for-living-room-datacenters/"><b>Daily DIY</b>: LackRack: Ikea server racks for living room datacenters</a></li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://zedomax.com/blog/2010/01/22/server-hack-how-to-build-your-own-ikea-servers/"><b>Zedomax</b>: Server Hack – How to Build Your Own IKEA Servers!</a></li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://ikeahacker.blogspot.com/2010/01/lack-rack-hack.html"><b>Ikea hacker</b>: The Lack rack hack</a></li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.askcharly.net/blog/buzz/lackrack-tech-enabled-furniture/"><b>AskCharly</b>: LackRack: Tech Enabled Furniture</a></li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.unplggd.com/unplggd/inspiration/ikea-lack-tablenetwork-rackthe-lackrack-107711"><b>unplggd</b>: IKEA Lack+Network Rack=The LackRack</a></li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://blog.isabel-drost.de/index.php/archives/tag/lackrack"><b>Inductive Bias</b>: Shopping at Ikea</a></li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://lincgeek.org/blog/?p=940"><b>LincolnBlogs</b>: LackRack</a></li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.lackcluster.org/"><b>LackCluster</b>: LackRack-ed Cluster Computer</a> Practical use of the LackRack</li></ul>
<dl><dt>French</dt></dl>
<ul><li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.artiflo.net/2010/01/ikea-arrive-dans-les-datacenter/"><b>Artiflo</b>: Ikea arrives in the datacentre</a></li></ul>
<dl><dt>German</dt></dl>
<ul><li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogmmix.ch/kategorie/aktuell/happy-birthday-30-jahre-lack-beistelltisch.html"><b>BlogMMix</b>: Happy birthday, 30 year old sidetable!</a></li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.gamestar.de/hardware/news/vermischtes/2312088/lackrack.html"><b>GameStar</b>: IKEA table as server rack</a></li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://tipuraneo.blogspot.com/2010/01/gunstiges-19-rack.html"><b>Tipuraneo</b>: Cheap 19" rack</a></li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.sysadminslife.com/hardware/lackrack-billigstes-19-zoll-serverrack-made-by-ikea/"><b>Sysadminslife</b>: LackRack – billigstes 19 Zoll Serverrack made by IKEA?</a></li></ul>
<dl><dt><span title="Swedish :)">Ikeaspråk</span></dt></dl>
<ul><li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.techworld.idg.se/2.2524/1.287656/serverracket-du-hittar-pa-ikea"><b>Techworld</b>: Server racks at Ikea</a> (<a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.sweclockers.com/forum/showthread.php?threadid=906172">forum</a>)</li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.nordichardware.se/nyhet,17256.html"><b>NordicHardware</b>: The world's cheapest 19-inch rack from IKEA</a> (<a rel="nofollow" href="http://nhw.se/forum/viewtopic.php?topic=182544&amp;forum=17">forum</a>)</li>
<li>Mah lackrack is teh shit - <a rel="nofollow" href="http://mickenordin.se/blog/index.php/2011/01/mah-lackrack-is-teh-shit/">http://mickenordin.se/blog/index.php/2011/01/mah-lackrack-is-teh-shit/</a></li></ul>
<dl><dt>Japanese</dt></dl>
<ul><li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.isisaka.com/blog/archives/2010/01/ikea19.html"><b>石坂</b>: Ikea-made 19" rack</a></li></ul>
<dl><dt>Russian</dt></dl>
<ul><li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://habrahabr.ru/tag/LACKRack/"><b>Хабрахабр</b>: Server rack from Ikea</a></li></ul>
<dl><dt>Spanish</dt></dl>
<ul><li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.internetlab.es/post/857/una-nueva-estructura-para-servidores-de-ikea"><b>internetlab</b>: The New Data Center Rack From ... IKEA?</a></li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.acens.com/blog/ikea-diversifica-y-entra-en-el-sector-de-infraestructura-para-datacenters"><b>acens</b>: Ikea diversifies and enters infrastructure market for datacenters</a></li>
<li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://alsanan.info/5456"><b>alasan</b>: LackRack</a></li></ul>
<dl><dt>Portugese</dt></dl>
<ul><li><a rel="nofollow" href="http://blackhold.nusepas.com/2012/02/lackrack-rack-de-bajo-coste-fase-i/">Lackrack, rack de bajo coste: Fase I</a></li></ul>

<ul>
		<li><div>
			<div><p><a href="https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/File:2x3U_LackRack.jpg"><img alt="" src="https://wiki.eth0.nl/images/2/26/2x3U_LackRack.jpg" decoding="async" width="90" height="120" data-file-width="2304" data-file-height="3072"></a></p></div>
			<p>2 by 3U LackRack.
</p>
		</div></li>
		<li><div>
			<div><p><a href="https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/File:TripleLackRackDeLuxe.jpg"><img alt="" src="https://wiki.eth0.nl/images/7/7f/TripleLackRackDeLuxe.jpg" decoding="async" width="90" height="120" data-file-width="960" data-file-height="1280"></a></p></div>
			<p>Triple LackRack DeLuxe.
</p>
		</div></li>
		<li><div>
			<div><p><a href="https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/File:LackRackAtIKEA_1.JPG"><img alt="" src="https://wiki.eth0.nl/images/e/e6/LackRackAtIKEA_1.JPG" decoding="async" width="90" height="120" data-file-width="2736" data-file-height="3648"></a></p></div>
			<p>LackRack at IKEA
</p>
		</div></li>
		<li><div>
			<div><p><a href="https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/File:Image005.jpg"><img alt="" src="https://wiki.eth0.nl/images/b/b7/Image005.jpg" decoding="async" width="90" height="120" data-file-width="1046" data-file-height="1395"></a></p></div>
			<p>CCNA Lab LackRack 01
</p>
		</div></li>
		<li><div>
			<div><p><a href="https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/File:Image002.jpg"><img alt="" src="https://wiki.eth0.nl/images/f/f5/Image002.jpg" decoding="async" width="90" height="120" data-file-width="1046" data-file-height="1395"></a></p></div>
			<p>CCNA Lab LackRack 02
</p>
		</div></li>
</ul>
<!-- 
NewPP limit report
Cached time: 20210129104829
Cache expiry: 604800
Dynamic content: false
Complications: []
[SMW] In‐text annotation parser time: 0.001 seconds
CPU time usage: 0.097 seconds
Real time usage: 0.102 seconds
Preprocessor visited node count: 80/1000000
Preprocessor generated node count: 0/1000000
Post‐expand include size: 0/2097152 bytes
Template argument size: 0/2097152 bytes
Highest expansion depth: 2/40
Expensive parser function count: 0/100
Unstrip recursion depth: 0/20
Unstrip post‐expand size: 2224/5000000 bytes
-->
<!--
Transclusion expansion time report (%,ms,calls,template)
100.00%    0.000      1 -total
-->

<!-- Saved in parser cache with key eth0_wiki:pcache:idhash:625-0!canonical and timestamp 20210129104829 and revision id 12216
 -->
</div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://wiki.eth0.nl/index.php/LackRack</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25978013</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 11:26:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Building a personal data warehouse in Snowflake for fun and no profit]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 157 | Comments 31 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25978000">thread link</a>) | @thomasdziedzic
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | https://www.thomasdziedzic0.com/blog/building-a-personal-data-warehouse-in-snowflake-for-fun-and-no-profit | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.thomasdziedzic0.com/blog/building-a-personal-data-warehouse-in-snowflake-for-fun-and-no-profit">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="page" role="main">
        
          <article data-page-sections="5fffb1fb083bda4cd2029cf2" id="sections">
  
    <section data-test="page-section" data-section-theme="white" data-section-id="5fffb1fb083bda4cd2029cf4" data-controller="SectionWrapperController, MagicPaddingController" data-current-styles="{
&quot;imageOverlayOpacity&quot;: 0.15,
&quot;backgroundWidth&quot;: &quot;background-width--full-bleed&quot;,
&quot;sectionHeight&quot;: &quot;section-height--medium&quot;,
&quot;customSectionHeight&quot;: 10,
&quot;horizontalAlignment&quot;: &quot;horizontal-alignment--center&quot;,
&quot;verticalAlignment&quot;: &quot;vertical-alignment--middle&quot;,
&quot;contentWidth&quot;: &quot;content-width--wide&quot;,
&quot;customContentWidth&quot;: 50,
&quot;sectionTheme&quot;: &quot;white&quot;,
&quot;sectionAnimation&quot;: &quot;none&quot;,
&quot;backgroundMode&quot;: &quot;image&quot;
}" data-animation="none">
  
  <div>
    <div>
      
      
      
      
      <div data-content-field="main-content" data-item-id="">
  <article id="article-">
  
    <div>
      

      <div>
        <div><div data-layout-label="Post Body" data-type="item" id="item-600f55010fc2501849ebea9b"><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-ee8fde62179b7bb27e53"><div><p>I’ve always wanted to build a personal data warehouse and after watching Simon Willison’s <a href="https://simonwillison.net/2020/Nov/14/personal-data-warehouses/">talk</a>, I got the motivation to finally build it out. In case you aren’t familiar with the term “data warehouse”, it’s basically a database that centralizes your data to be used for analysis. There are many databases you can choose from, for example in Simon Willison’s talk, he uses <a href="https://www.sqlite.org/index.html">SQLite</a>. I chose <a href="https://www.snowflake.com/">Snowflake</a> because I’m familiar with it and so far I have liked what Ive seen. Some features that make it stand out for me are things like <a href="https://docs.snowflake.com/en/user-guide/data-time-travel.html">time travel</a>, <a href="https://docs.snowflake.com/en/sql-reference/sql/undrop-table.html">undrop table</a>, a rich set of <a href="https://docs.snowflake.com/en/sql-reference/intro-summary-operators-functions.html">functions</a>, among many others.</p><p>Ok great, so we now have an empty database to start with. But a database is only useful when there is data in it to query. So we must choose which datasets to pull into our freshly minted database. I’m going to start with bringing in <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/">Hacker News</a> data because I’m a big fan of the site and it has an actual <a href="https://github.com/HackerNews/API">API</a> which means we wont have to be scraping HTML. I’m also going to bring in stock data into the warehouse to see if we can get any stock information out of Hacker News. Finally we’ll analyze the stock market and correlate stocks to the latest GameStop stock craze.</p><p>The first part of the plan will be to get the Hacker News data loaded into Snowflake. Then I’ll use Snowflake’s Data Marketplace to bring in the stock data, which will save me from writing an ELT (Extract, Load, Transform).</p><h2>Getting an initial dump of the Hacker News data.</h2><p>I wanted to write as little code as possible to get this initial historical dump of Hacker News so I decided to use a combination of curl, bash and parallel to get the job done. I first used <a href="https://ec2instances.info/">ec2instances.info</a> to find a relatively cheap CPU per dollar machine. I spun up a c5a.8xlarge on AWS which has 32 vCPUs.<br>I wouldn’t be surprised if there were cheaper options, but I just eyeballed it.</p><p>Let’s get the largest item ID:</p></div></div><div data-block-type="23" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611791428293_3993"><div><pre><code>curl https://hacker-news.firebaseio.com/v0/maxitem.json</code></pre></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611792427454_4138"><div><p>Which returned: 25,806,058</p><p>Sigh, looks like we’re going to have to do 25 million HTTP calls. Let’s get started:</p><p>Let’s generate a file with all of the endpoints we will need to hit. This will be needed for my next one liner:</p></div></div><div data-block-type="23" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611792427454_5677"><div><pre><code>for ((i=1; i&lt;25806059; ++i)); do echo "https://hacker-news.firebaseio.com/v0/item/${i}.json"; done &gt; list-of-item-urls</code></pre></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611793513046_4897"><p>Ok, so we have 25 million URLs that we need to download. Let’s use curl with parallel to download this:</p></div><div data-block-type="23" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611793677899_11393"><div><pre><code>time { parallel --jobs 500 --progress --arg-file ../list-of-item-urls "curl --silent -O {}"; }</code></pre></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611793677899_11459"><p>This fails with an error that we’ve reached a limit regarding the number of open file handles, you will need to add the following line to limits.conf and then reboot the machine:</p></div><div data-block-type="23" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611793677899_14036"><div><pre><code>cat /etc/security/limits.conf 
...
ubuntu           soft    nofile          10000
...</code></pre></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611793677899_14107"><p>Lets try running the download job again and fast forwarding till the end:</p></div><div data-block-type="23" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611793677899_15450"><div><pre><code>~/hackernews/data$ time { parallel --jobs 500 --progress --arg-file ../list-of-item-urls "curl --silent -O {}"; }                                                                               

Computers / CPU cores / Max jobs to run
1:local / 32 / 500

Computer:jobs running/jobs completed/%of started jobs/Average seconds to complete
local:0/25806058/100%/0.0s   

real    1419m19.537s
user    5375m8.349s
sys     3894m15.079s</code></pre></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611793677899_15519"><div><p>The rate at which we were downloading URLs was 25,806,058 / (1,419 * 60 + 19) = 303 URLs per second. </p><p>This was a really slow process, especially given that I used a medium-end machine. My guess is that EBS volumes might not like 25 million files getting created.</p><p>Let’s see how big the data directory is:</p></div></div><div data-block-type="23" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611793677899_17011"><div><pre><code>~/hackernews$ du -hs data
100G    data</code></pre></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611793677899_17077"><p>Ouch, lots of little files definitely take up a lot of space. In addition, I haven’t thought this through. It’s probably going to be painful uploading 25 million files to Snowflake so lets combine all the files into a single file:</p></div><div data-block-type="23" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611793677899_18389"><div><pre><code>~/hackernews/data$ time { find . -name '*.json' -exec cat {} \; -exec echo \; &gt; ../items ; }

real    2120m33.575s
user    740m24.364s
sys     1208m22.212s
</code></pre></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611793677899_18455"><div><p>Well it doesn’t look like my laziness paid off.<br>Combining the 25 million files into 1 file on this ec2 instance using an EBS volume took longer than downloading the files at a rate of 25,806,058  / (2,120 * 60 + 33) = 202 files per second. Maybe using a native storage instance would make this go faster, but still, combining millions of little files is a really slow process.’</p><p>Eighty dollar lesson learned.</p><p>Additionally, when combined into a single file, it takes about 11 gigs.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="23" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611793677899_19766"><div><pre><code>ls -lh items
-rw-rw-r-- 1 ubuntu ubuntu 11G Jan 19 12:48 items</code></pre></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611854158631_9850"><p>And compressed, it's still even lower, 4 gigs:</p></div><div data-block-type="23" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611854158631_11094"><div><pre><code>ls -lh items.gz
-rw-rw-r-- 1 ubuntu ubuntu 4.1G Jan 19 12:48 items.gz</code></pre></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611854158631_12186"><div><p>Copying to AWS S3 takes almost no time. So we finally have the data where Snowflake can access it!</p><p>Let's load it in:</p></div></div><div data-block-type="23" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611854158631_13561"><div><pre><code>use database main_db;

create schema hackernews;

use schema hackernews;

create table raw_items(item variant not null);

copy into raw_items
from s3://hacker-news-dump/items.gz
credentials = (aws_key_id = 'REDACTED' aws_secret_key = 'REDACTED')
file_format = (type = json);

create table items(
  id bigint,
  deleted boolean,
  type string,
  by_ string,
  time timestamp,
  text string,
  dead boolean,
  parent bigint,
  poll bigint,
  kids array,
  url string,
  score bigint,
  title string,
  parts array,
  descendants bigint
);

insert into items(
  id,
  deleted,
  type,
  by_,
  time,
  text,
  dead,
  parent,
  poll,
  kids,
  url,
  score,
  title,
  parts,
  descendants
)
select
  item:id,
  item:deleted,
  item:type,
  item:by,
  item:time,
  item:text,
  item:dead,
  item:parent,
  item:poll,
  item:kids,
  item:url,
  item:score,
  item:title,
  item:parts,
  item:descendants
from raw_items;</code></pre></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611854158631_14726"><div><p>Loading the data takes a couple of minutes but now we have all Hacker News items loaded into Snowflake!</p><h2>Data Quality Checks.</h2><p>Let’s run some sanity checks on our data by looking for gaps between the ids:</p></div></div><div data-block-type="23" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611854158631_16858"><div><pre><code>select lag(id, 1) over (order by id) prev_id, id
from items
qualify id - prev_id &gt; 1
order by 1;</code></pre></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611854158631_20248"><div><p>I have 15k gaps in my data. To quote Dyatlov from Chernobyl, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Mg5HOnq7zD0">“Not great, not terrible”</a>.</p><p>I ended up writing a python <a href="https://github.com/thomasdziedzic/hackernews-fill-gaps/blob/master/main.py">script</a> to calculate and download these missing items. If you know how one would generate the missing ids between the gaps (which could be of variable size), I would sure like to learn how you accomplish that because it might have spared me from writing this python script. Moving on…</p><p>I also found that the API returns some nulls for items. So I ran the following to clean those up:</p></div></div><div data-block-type="23" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611854158631_21920"><div><pre><code>delete from items where id is null;
</code></pre></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611854158631_23295"><div><h2>Review so far and writing an incremental script.</h2><p>I just spent $80 getting the data into Snowflake and I’m not happy with the performance of the extraction.</p><p>In fact, I was thinking how I was going to maintain this data moving forward, and how I was going to load the data incrementally.<br>I was not satisfied enough with the current approach to keep using it. We must do better, for the sake of my wallet.</p><p>I gave up trying to figure out how to do it purely from a shell scripting perspective, and wrote my own <a href="https://github.com/thomasdziedzic/hackernews-etl/blob/master/main.py">Python script</a> to figure out which items it needs to extract, and then load into Snowflake. This script can be run without user intervention and will keep the data up-to-date. Using Python to write the ELT gave me more flexibility to fix some things that I saw as issues. For example, the script starts N * 4 (where N is the number of logical cpus) jobs and only produces N * 4 files instead of 1 file per item. This approach will avoid having to do an expensive file combination step at the end. I also added some awesome progress bars to the script so that I knew how many requests remain thanks to <a href="https://github.com/alphatwirl/atpbar/issues/21#issuecomment-766468695">Tai Sakuma</a>.</p><p>Running this script from my laptop (a Dell 9370 Developer Edition with 8 logical cores) and spotty Wi-Fi, script extracts items from the API at about 130 items/second. This is slower than extracting from a c5a.8xlarge machine, but at least my laptop isn’t charging me $1.232/hour for using it. And my script has the benefit of not having to combine millions of tiny files at the end. Let’s test my incremental loading script out on an ec2 instance to see how it really compares with my naive approach.</p><h2>Downloading incremental data from Hacker News using my script</h2></div></div><div data-block-type="23" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1611883239126_31321"><div><pre><code>$ time { poetry run python main.py ; }
fetching 116738 items
 100.00% :::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: |     1824 /     1824 |:  ForkPoolWorker-22
 100.00% :::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: |     1824 /     1824 |:  ForkPoolWorker-47
 100.00% :::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: |     1824 /     1824 |:  ForkPoolWorker-14
 100.00% :::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: |     1824 /     1824 |:  ForkPoolWorker-36
 100.00% :::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: |     1824 /     1824 |:  ForkPoolWorker-54
 100.00% :::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: |     1824 /     1824 |:  ForkPoolWorker-19
 100.00% :::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: |     1824 /     1824 |:  ForkPoolWorker-58
 100.00% :::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: |     1824 /     1824 |:  ForkPoolWorker-13
 100.00% :::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: |     1824 /     1824 |:  ForkPoolWorker-52
 100.00% :::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: |     1824 /     1824 |:  ForkPoolWorker-56
 100.00% :::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: |     1824 /     1824 |:  ForkPoolWorker-63
 100.00% :::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: |     1824 /     1824 |:  ForkPoolWorker-62
 100.00% :::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: |     1824 /     1824 |:  ForkPoolWorker-29
 100.00% :::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: |     1824 /     1824 |:  ForkPoolWorker-57
 100.00% :::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: |     1824 /     1824 |:  ForkPoolWorker-26
 100.00% :::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: |     1824 /     1824 |:  ForkPoolWorker-12
 100.00% :::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: |     1824 /     1824 |:  ForkPoolWorker-17
 100.00% :::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: |     1824 /     1824 |:  ForkPoolWorker-4
 100.00% …</code></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></article></div></div></div></section></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.thomasdziedzic0.com/blog/building-a-personal-data-warehouse-in-snowflake-for-fun-and-no-profit">https://www.thomasdziedzic0.com/blog/building-a-personal-data-warehouse-in-snowflake-for-fun-and-no-profit</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.thomasdziedzic0.com/blog/building-a-personal-data-warehouse-in-snowflake-for-fun-and-no-profit</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25978000</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 11:24:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Black Bart – The Buried TV Sequel to Blazing Saddles]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 138 | Comments 20 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25977514">thread link</a>) | @rbanffy
<br/>
January 31, 2021 | https://reprobatepress.com/2021/01/30/black-bart-the-buried-tv-sequel-to-blazing-saddles/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://reprobatepress.com/2021/01/30/black-bart-the-buried-tv-sequel-to-blazing-saddles/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">

	<section id="primary">
		<main id="main" role="main">

		
<article id="post-38544">

	
	
	
	<div>

		<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-4.png?resize=840%2C606&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="840" height="606" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-4.png?w=850&amp;ssl=1 850w, https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-4.png?resize=300%2C216&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-4.png?resize=768%2C554&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-4.png?resize=840%2C606&amp;ssl=1 840w" sizes="(max-width: 840px) 100vw, 840px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-4.png?w=850&amp;ssl=1 850w, https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-4.png?resize=300%2C216&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-4.png?resize=768%2C554&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-4.png?resize=840%2C606&amp;ssl=1 840w" data-lazy-src="https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-4.png?resize=840%2C606&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><em><strong>The Mel Brooks classic that became a TV series that ran for four seasons without being broadcast anywhere.</strong></em></p>

<p><em>Update: large parts of this story may, in fact, be fiction. See the addendum at the end for details.</em></p>
<p>Film rights are a strange and complex thing, especially when it comes to existing properties. The contracts for these things can involve a labyrinthine series of clauses and negotiations, where the owners of the original property want to include cut-off clauses that will enable them to claw back the rights and sell them again, possibly for much more money if the adaptation has been a success, the artistic creator wants to hold on to some level of creative control and the film studio wants to ensure that neither of those things happens. We’ve seen assorted shenanigans at work across the board – the <a href="https://reprobatepress.com/2018/08/30/big-bond-themes-and-secret-agent-cover-versions/">James Bond</a> copyright snafu that saw the film rights for <strong>Casino Royale</strong> owned and exploited by another company than the one that made the official series, and perhaps most famously in terms of contractual obligations, the first <strong>Fantastic Four</strong> movie, made as a low-budget throwaway affair simply to ensure that the film rights stayed with Constantin Film, who was not quite ready to make a ‘proper’ version of the story but who saw the potential in the property and didn’t want to let it go.</p>
<p>But perhaps the most absurd of these contractual obligation projects came with <strong>Blazing Saddles</strong>, which was adapted into a TV series that ran for four seasons – which would suggest a major hit show by 1970s television standards, except for the fact that it never aired. Not a single episode beyond the pilot was shown on TV anywhere.</p>
<p><strong>Blazing Saddles</strong> was a major hit in 1974 and remains one of the most beloved Hollywood comedies – well, perhaps not with Millenials and Generation Z, given the film’s rather liberal use of the sort of racist language that is now strictly forbidden, even in context. Mel Brooks’ comedy western mocked American racism brutally – perhaps a little too brutally in the use of one particular word, which is bandied about throughout the film. It was a different time.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-3.png?resize=840%2C605&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="840" height="605" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-3.png?w=850&amp;ssl=1 850w, https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-3.png?resize=300%2C216&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-3.png?resize=768%2C553&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-3.png?resize=840%2C605&amp;ssl=1 840w" sizes="(max-width: 840px) 100vw, 840px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-3.png?w=850&amp;ssl=1 850w, https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-3.png?resize=300%2C216&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-3.png?resize=768%2C553&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-3.png?resize=840%2C605&amp;ssl=1 840w" data-lazy-src="https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-3.png?resize=840%2C605&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></p>
<p>Brooks was on fire as a filmmaker in 1974, and there was every reason to expect <strong>Blazing Saddles</strong> to be a massive hit, as indeed it was. Having dealt with studios enough by this point, Brooks knew that they might want to take the project away from him and produce sequels – the story essentially opened itself up for on-going narratives. And so he came up with a cunning plan. The contracts for the film stated that there could only be film sequels if a TV series follow-up was made within six months. Brooks and his legal team were pretty certain that the film was too profane and vulgar to ever be adapted as a TV series. I mean, what could they do? Strip it back to its most basic elements while throwing out everything that made the film what it was?</p>
<p>Well, that was precisely what happened. In 1977, Warner Brothers announced plans for a sequel film – in fact, a series of sequels – to <strong>Blazing Saddles</strong>, and when Brooks and his lawyers waved the contract at them, they pulled their ace card – a four-season series based on the original film that had gone into production very quickly in 1974. As Brooks explained, <em>“Warner Bros comes to me and says they want to make another Blazing Saddles, and I say, ‘No. You don’t have the right to do that.’ They say, ‘Yes we do, we’ve been making a TV series and still control the rights.’ What TV series? I haven’t seen a TV show. They take me onto the lot, into a projection booth, and show me three episodes. My lawyers never thought to put in language that said they had to air the damn thing, only that they had to make it.”</em></p>
<p>You have to almost admire Warner Brothers’ gall here, and – oddly – their belief in <strong>Blazing Saddles</strong>. Not only did they rush a series into production in 1974, but they kept it in production – because the contract only allowed a new movie within six months of the last <strong>Blazing Saddles</strong> project – for four years until they finally had a movie ready. TV shows might be cheaper than films, but nevertheless, imagine how much they had to spend, making four seasons of a show just to hold onto the film rights.</p>
<p>In fact, the pilot episode of <strong>Black Bart</strong>, as the series is called, was shown once in 1975 on CBS, with no one even noticing. Well, why would they? As well as changing the title (because the contract also failed to state that any TV series be <em>called</em> <strong>Blazing Saddles</strong>), Brooks wasn’t credited, with Andrew Bergman, who originally came up with the <strong>Blazing Saddles</strong> idea listed as creator. The show starred Louis Gossett Jr as Sheriff Bart, continuing his battles against both criminals and racists, while the other film characters were replaced with similar, but not identical characters to avoid crediting Brooks. Both the cast – including Gerrit Graham – and the characters are lightweight versions of the originals, the humour is almost non-existent and the laugh track just hammers home how unfunny the show is. And yet it is a professional work, and arguably no less forced than several other sitcoms of the era. So the question is: why didn’t they just put in a bit more effort and then show the damn thing instead of paying everyone to shoot twenty-four episodes that would sit, unseen, in the Warner Brothers vaults?</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i2.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-2.png?resize=840%2C602&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="840" height="602" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-2.png?w=850&amp;ssl=1 850w, https://i2.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-2.png?resize=300%2C215&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-2.png?resize=768%2C550&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-2.png?resize=840%2C602&amp;ssl=1 840w" sizes="(max-width: 840px) 100vw, 840px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i2.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-2.png?w=850&amp;ssl=1 850w, https://i2.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-2.png?resize=300%2C215&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-2.png?resize=768%2C550&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-2.png?resize=840%2C602&amp;ssl=1 840w" data-lazy-src="https://i2.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/black-bart-blazing-saddles-tv-series-2.png?resize=840%2C602&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></p>
<p>Presumably, the answer is that a TV show – even a good TV show – would have diluted the appeal of another film. The 1970s were a different time (we mentioned that, right?) and there was less crossover of film and TV – sure, some films – like <a href="https://reprobatepress.com/2020/09/27/go-ape-the-planet-of-the-apes-book-and-comics-of-the-1970s/"><strong>Planet of the Apes</strong></a> – were adapted into TV shows, but those shows were rarely successful and were seen as having essentially killed off any chance of audiences then going to the cinema to watch a movie version. If anything, <strong>Black Bart</strong> might have served as a sign of just how bad a Mel Brooks-free version of <strong>Blazing Saddles</strong> could be. So instead of putting any effort into making a decent TV series based on the property (and there’s certainly the potential there), Warner Brothers simply put the least possible effort into making something that would still legally stand up as a TV show that could, in theory, be broadcast – and then buried it.</p>
<p>What the cast and crew thought of all this is hard to gauge – Gossett has talked about the weirdness of it all, but you have to wonder just how anyone managed to drum up any enthusiasm once it became clear that the show would never air. Ironically, the plans for a <strong>Blazing Saddles</strong> sequel ultimately went nowhere – by 1979, it was clear that the moment had passed and audience tastes had changed. The sequel was shelved, and the series was finally cancelled. The pilot episode has since turned up on the <strong>Blazing Saddles</strong> DVD and blu-ray, but the other episodes have yet to be seen. It’s entirely possible that they were never even completed beyond the ones shown to Brooks, and may have been trashed. A pity, as we’ll never know if it accidentally improved.</p>
<p><strong>IMPORTANT UPDATE:</strong> We feel it’s important to point out that some sources are claiming since we originally posted this that the entire story – with the exception of the<strong> Black Bart</strong> pilot, which definitely exists and is perhaps a weird enough thing in itself – is in fact a spoof that has somehow become accepted as reality – ‘fake news’, as I believe it is known. There are several sources online claiming that this story is authentic; others claiming that it is satire (links appear in the comments). Unless Mel Brooks – or perhaps Louis Gossett – wants to come clean on the actual facts, it perhaps remains a mystery. Stranger-than-fiction may, or may not, be actual fiction, and isn’t that depressing when it’s a story as good as this? As Tony Wilson said (or possibly didn’t say, there’s the rub), <em>“when&nbsp;you have to choose between the truth and the legend, choose the legend.”</em></p>
<p>DAVID FLINT</p>
<p><em><strong>Help support The Reprobate:</strong></em></p>
<p><em><strong><a href="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/reprobatepress" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/buy-me-a-beer.png?resize=199%2C59&amp;ssl=1" alt="buy-me-a-beer" width="199" height="59" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-src="https://i0.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/buy-me-a-beer.png?resize=199%2C59&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></a><br>
<a href="https://www.patreon.com/reprobatepress" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Patreon_White_on_Navy.jpg?resize=567%2C283&amp;ssl=1" alt="Patreon" width="567" height="283" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Patreon_White_on_Navy.jpg?w=567&amp;ssl=1 567w, https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Patreon_White_on_Navy.jpg?resize=300%2C150&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 567px) 100vw, 567px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Patreon_White_on_Navy.jpg?w=567&amp;ssl=1 567w, https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Patreon_White_on_Navy.jpg?resize=300%2C150&amp;ssl=1 300w" data-lazy-src="https://i1.wp.com/reprobatepress.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Patreon_White_on_Navy.jpg?resize=567%2C283&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></a></strong></em></p>


		
	</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->

</article>

	<!-- #comments -->


		</main><!-- #main -->
	</section><!-- #primary -->

	
	<!-- #secondary -->



	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://reprobatepress.com/2021/01/30/black-bart-the-buried-tv-sequel-to-blazing-saddles/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25977514</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 09:42:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[WallStreetBets vs. Wall Street and the Populist Rebellion]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25977022">thread link</a>) | @lettergram
<br/>
January 30, 2021 | https://austingwalters.com/wallstreetbets-vs-wall-street-and-the-populist-rebellion/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://austingwalters.com/wallstreetbets-vs-wall-street-and-the-populist-rebellion/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-3831">

<div>
<p>I have been engaging with WSB (<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/wallstreetbets/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">/r/WallStreetBets</a>) since 2014.</p>
<p>Every regular person on WSB understands it’s a game. You can loose it all, make it big, sometimes both in the same day — it’s all a game. The most accurate assessment of WSB culture was clearly:</p>
<blockquote><p>Like 4chan found a Bloomberg Terminal.</p></blockquote>
<p>While the influx of new users may change the community, prior to January 15, 2021 the above was indeed an accurate description.</p>

<p>Honestly, this world feels like we are in a simulation. The company GameStop appears to be poised to bring down the entire financial system — stopping the game.</p>
<p>The infinity squeeze appears to be coming, what is an infinity squeeze you ask? It’s a really massive short squeeze:</p>
<blockquote><p>A short squeeze occurs when a stock or other asset jumps sharply higher, forcing traders who had bet that its price would fall, to buy it in order to forestall even greater losses. Their scramble to buy only adds to the upward pressure on the stock’s price.</p></blockquote>
<p>Short positions can technically lead to infinite losses. Simply put, if I open a short position for $10 and the share price drops 10%, I make $1. However, if the stock price increases say 10,000% I now owe $1,000.</p>
<p>In the case of GameStop, the situation appears dire. At one point the short positions were 140% of available shares of the market. This means that more shares were lent out than were available on float, i.e. shorts were resold / lent several times. At this point, several things are happening[<a href="https://www.investopedia.com/ask/answers/05/shortsaleclosed.asp" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1</a>]:</p>
<ul>
<li>Those holding short positions are paying ridiculously high interest rates</li>
<li>If the short positions were forced to close, it would cause a major loss to multiple hedge funds (tens of billions total &amp; bankrupcies)</li>
<li>Due to the level of shorting, exiting the short positions would be excessively expensive and cause a <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/s/shortsqueeze.asp" target="_blank" rel="noopener">short squeeze</a></li>
<li>There is less GameStop stock available for purchase</li>
<li>The price of GameStop stock is rising</li>
</ul>
<p>As a result, it appears to me that:</p>
<ul>
<li>Short holders cannot exit their positions without going bankrupt</li>
<li>Short holders are being hit by high interest rates</li>
<li>Closing other positions in the stock market should help them cover the interest rates</li>
<li>Best option for short position holders is is to wait &amp; pray the stock price drops</li>
<li>What happens if not enough people are willing to sell?</li>
</ul>
<p>Personally, I believe all of this will suck all the liquidity from the stock market. Either those shorting suffer the loss and close their positions or wait as the stock continues to stay high… in either case hundreds of billions of dollars is leaving the market.</p>
<p>How did we get here?</p>
<h3>Infinity Squeeze – Short Positions</h3>
<p>There’s a lot to this story I’ll come back an fill in, but the gist is this — In mid-January 2021 GameStop was <em>extremely</em> shorted.</p>
<figure id="attachment_3832" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3832"><a href="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-01-17.png"><img loading="lazy" src="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-01-17.png" alt="" width="424" height="417" srcset="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-01-17.png 424w, https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-01-17-300x295.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 424px) 100vw, 424px" data-old-src="//austingwalters.com/wp-content/plugins/a3-lazy-load/assets/images/lazy_placeholder.gif" data-src="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-01-17.png" data-srcset="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-01-17.png 424w, https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-01-17-300x295.png 300w"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3832">Courtesy of <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/GME/key-statistics?p=GME" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Yahoo Finance</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The massive short position and didn’t go unnoticed, WSB had been <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20201222153244/https://old.reddit.com/r/wallstreetbets/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">discussing it for months</a>. That being said, the massive spikes in purchases did not start until January 12:</p>
<p><a href="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-05-15.png"><img loading="lazy" src="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-05-15.png" alt="" width="916" height="411" srcset="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-05-15.png 916w, https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-05-15-300x135.png 300w, https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-05-15-768x345.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 916px) 100vw, 916px" data-old-src="//austingwalters.com/wp-content/plugins/a3-lazy-load/assets/images/lazy_placeholder.gif" data-src="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-05-15.png" data-srcset="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-05-15.png 916w, https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-05-15-300x135.png 300w, https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-05-15-768x345.png 768w"></a></p>
<p>What happened at that time? The <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20210118091858/https://old.reddit.com/r/wallstreetbets/comments/kxeq23/gme_yolo_update_jan_14_2021/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">YOLO updates</a> definitely started at that time and stocks started to rise. Once the stocks started to rise, I believe institutions and WSB itself started piling into GameStop. The stock started to move and if they could get in they could make a boat load. It’s important to remember WSB is often visited by hedge fund mangers, CEOs, day traders big and small, etc. It’s not always the little guy(s). When they piled in, the price started to rise further.</p>
<h3>Infinity Squeeze – Let’s Make Money</h3>
<p>As they purchased, I personally believe some short sellers managed to exit their positions (about 7m shares, per Yahoo Finance data)</p>
<p><a href="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-01-17-highlighted.png"><img loading="lazy" src="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-01-17-highlighted.png" alt="" width="424" height="417" srcset="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-01-17-highlighted.png 424w, https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-01-17-highlighted-300x295.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 424px) 100vw, 424px" data-old-src="//austingwalters.com/wp-content/plugins/a3-lazy-load/assets/images/lazy_placeholder.gif" data-src="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-01-17-highlighted.png" data-srcset="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-01-17-highlighted.png 424w, https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-01-17-highlighted-300x295.png 300w"></a></p>
<p>What this indicates to me is that many of those holding short positions did not realize what was about to happen. They kept holding believing this was a classic pump-and-dump. Even WSB at the time didn’t not necessarily think about much <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20210115023914/https://old.reddit.com/r/wallstreetbets/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">besides making money</a>. I know I even purchased call options during this week, particularly when the new data came out January 15, 2021. To me, it became clear the stock was about to rocket.</p>
<h3>Infinity Squeeze – Let’s Stick it to the Man</h3>
<p>In light of the massive number of short position(s) open in January 15, 2021, WSB realized they could (a) make money and (b) stick it to the hedge funds. Frankly, WSB have been waging a war on short selling for years. With GameStop they had a company with relatively few shares&nbsp; in float (47m), a low market cap, basically something that purchases would have an outsized impact.</p>
<p>I’m not 100% sure this was intentional, but as people started buying and holding waiting for the squeeze the stock started to rise.The rising stock both led to discussions on news outlets and the stock started going viral on social media platforms outside of WSB – further raising the going rate for a share of GameStop.</p>
<p>Those holding short positions did not want to sell as they’d lose money, so they were searching for capital to cover their leveraged positions. Citadel and Point72 partners appears to have <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/citadel-point72-to-invest-2-75-billion-into-melvin-capital-management-11611604340" target="_blank" rel="noopener">come to at least one short sellers aid</a>. This showed they were weak and further emboldened the WSB folks – “Let’s make some money on the hedge funds behalf”</p>
<p>Purchases from Jan 19 to Jan 23, 2021 and the stock price increased exponentially as it went viral:</p>
<p><a href="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-46-17.png"><img loading="lazy" src="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-46-17.png" alt="" width="507" height="423" srcset="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-46-17.png 507w, https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-46-17-300x250.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 507px) 100vw, 507px" data-old-src="//austingwalters.com/wp-content/plugins/a3-lazy-load/assets/images/lazy_placeholder.gif" data-src="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-46-17.png" data-srcset="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-46-17.png 507w, https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-from-2021-01-31-00-46-17-300x250.png 300w"></a></p>
<h3>Infinity Squeeze – The Rebellion</h3>
<p>On January 27, 2021 across the board buying for GameStop was <a href="https://www.clickondetroit.com/money/2021/01/27/robinhood-td-ameritrade-other-brokerages-have-tech-problems-at-market-open/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">restricted (along with multiple other stocks) across various trading platforms</a>. This effectively forced purchase volume lower and as users of these platforms could only sell it drove down the share price. This likely startled many GameStop shareholds and many liquidated their positions, letting the short sellers exit some of their positions. Through January 29, 2021 the ability to purchase in an unrestricted manner has not been restored.</p>
<p>What happened?</p>
<p>Personally, I’m of the opinion that there was not enough shares to go around and likely these platforms colluded to drive down the stock price. What’s more interesting is how few people sold. As of January 29, 2021 the price of a GameStop share was back at $325. This has led to some very VERY strong backlash and I know I’ll be joining a lawsuit at some point (if not filing my own), as this collusion cost me tens to hundreds of thousands of dollars.</p>
<p>One essay that particularly struck me was made on WSB: <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20210130034124/https://www.reddit.com/r/wallstreetbets/comments/l6omry/an_open_letter_to_melvin_capital_cnbc_boomers_and/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">An Open Letter to Melvin Capital, CNBC, Boomers, and WSB</a></p>
<p>I recommend reading the comments on this essay to really get an under standing of what’s happening. Look at the charts. This is personal now. The market manipulation is obvious and people want revenge. For the current events, for 2008, for the entire corrupt system. They want to send a message. This is a protest.</p>
<p><a href="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/vymOZEhH.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/vymOZEhH.jpg" alt="" width="474" height="567" srcset="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/vymOZEhH.jpg 474w, https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/vymOZEhH-251x300.jpg 251w" sizes="(max-width: 474px) 100vw, 474px" data-old-src="//austingwalters.com/wp-content/plugins/a3-lazy-load/assets/images/lazy_placeholder.gif" data-src="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/vymOZEhH.jpg" data-srcset="https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/vymOZEhH.jpg 474w, https://austingwalters.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/vymOZEhH-251x300.jpg 251w"></a>Many retail investors will hold until the bitter end.</p>
<h3>Infinity Squeeze – End Game</h3>
<p>So what happens next?</p>
<ul>
<li>Starting on January 27-29 people were trying to transfer funds off Robinhood and the other platforms which disabled purchasing of GameStop shares.</li>
<li>Come the <span>first week of February</span> these assets will be again available and can be used to purchase GameStop shares.</li>
<li>Everyone saw much fewer shares being traded Friday</li>
<li>Everyone is talking with their families</li>
<li>People are going to purchase more GameStop shares &amp; hold</li>
<li>I expect many are going to pull their assets out of the stock market</li>
</ul>
<p>There are some unknowns, for instance have the short positions been closed? Have there been backroom deals to stave off the infinity squeeze?</p>
<p>If neither of those assumptions above hold, then what happens when the price rises further and there’s not enough shares for sale?</p>
<p>Hedge funds either bleed out as they pay the massive interest rates on holding those short positions or they will close their short positions causing an infinity squeeze (GameStop shares will be priced in the thousands). In either case hundreds of billions would likely leave the market.</p>
<h3>Conclusion – The Black Hole</h3>
<p>It’s a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nash_equilibrium" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nash Equilibrium</a>, essentially the share holders have every reason to ask the maximum amount they can get for a share of GameStop (i.e. make money). If for some reason these GameStop share holders are unwilling to sell at a low rate, then these hedge funds stand to lose hundreds of billions and will go bankrupt (slowly via interest payments or quickly via short squeeze). To try and pay for their debts, they’ll have to sell off market wide and the entire market collapses.</p>
<p>There are three ways to alleviate the issue:</p>
<ul>
<li>GameStop issues a massive number of new shares</li>
<li>Market manipulation (such as Robinood and friends only enabling selling – of course that didn’t work last time)</li>
<li>Government settles the matter by confiscating shares</li>
</ul>
<p>Personally, I view government involvement as inevitable. They could settle everyone accounts fairly by giving everyone the current share price or what they bought it for, which every is higher. That being said, I suspect the more likely course of action is some flat rate $100/share or something to that effect. In either case, if they don’t get involved, I suspect the system really will collapse.</p>
<p>Unless of course, I am wrong. I am not a financial expert and nothing in this article should be taken as advice.</p>
<p>It’s completely possible I’m inaccurately reading the situation and those shorting GameStop have already exited their position(s) and GameStop is currently just in a classic bubble.</p>

</div>

</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://austingwalters.com/wallstreetbets-vs-wall-street-and-the-populist-rebellion/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25977022</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 07:57:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Japan API – Free and Open Data]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 7 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25976575">thread link</a>) | @irevenko
<br/>
January 30, 2021 | https://japan-api.github.io/docs/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://japan-api.github.io/docs/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://japan-api.github.io/docs/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25976575</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 06:26:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why Google needs to build an open chat client like Elemen]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 16 | Comments 15 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25976275">thread link</a>) | @rukshn
<br/>
January 30, 2021 | https://ruky.me/2021/01/31/why-google-needs-to-build-an-open-chat-client-like-element/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ruky.me/2021/01/31/why-google-needs-to-build-an-open-chat-client-like-element/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

<p><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://twitter.com/element_hq/status/1355290296947499013" target="_blank">Google recently blocked the Matrix based chat app Element from the Play Store sighting sexual content on the platform.</a> It’s really hard to define the explanation because WhatsApp, Telegram users of other chat clients also share the same content. <a href="https://www.redpoints.com/blog/telegram-book-piracy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Telegram is also known to host groups sharing pirated content as well.</a></p>
<p>This post is not going to bash Google on the ban of Element. It’s about how Google can win the chat app, but how google can build a chat app based on an open chat protocol and create a winning chat platform for them.</p>
<p>Chat apps have been hot for the past couple of years. When I initially Tweeted that chat apps are the new social network, 6-7 years ago (I wish if I can find that tweet, but I can’t seem to find it, maybe it was lost when I deleted all my tweets sometime ago), I remember how people laughed replying how can that even possible, but now as Facebook is on the decline, chat apps are the goto place to hang out with friends.</p>
<p>Google currently doesn’t have a house in the chat app race. Google tried with several chat applications, like Allo, Hangout, Google Talk, none of them took off. Even though Allo looked promising, and was integrated into Android, people never jumped the ship to Allo. And since Google now allowing several chat/video platforms like Hangout, Meet etc, Google’s direction in communication platform seems big vague.</p>
<p>Google also has had a poor history with social networking, Google does not have social in their DNA, it feels like they are engineering, technology first in their approach, while Facebook feels more social first than anything else.</p>
<p>However, after seeing this ban I feel what Google should have a horse in the chat app race, and it should be a matrix/element based chat client. Allow me to explain,</p>
<p>Google should embrace an open protocol like Matrix and build a chat client on top of it, yes it’s against their pattern of hoarding data, and usage of open protocol.</p>
<p>But Google was able to win the email, the email protocol is an open protocol, anyone can implement it, anyone can use any client they want, but still Google was able to create the most popular email service available out their, and even monetise it. </p>
<p>Before Google started gmail, services like hotmail only allowed 200mb of storage, I remember Yahoo deleting my email account because I didn’t login for 6 months (I was still schooling at that time, and didn’t use email much), and not to mention Yahoo, and hotmail had atrocious ads on their email service. But google changed all that, they gave a better UI, more storage, and even a better ad experience.</p>
<p>So what makes then incapable of using an open chat protocol and build a great experience around it? With engineers and money to back a project like that Google can build a good chat service around an open chat protocol.</p>
<p>Even ads might not be a thing, Google can still provide enterprise chat service to organisations, powered by their data servers. They can even keep their source closed if they want to, like they are doing with Gmail, but an open source client would be great.</p>
<p>And Google’s backing for a open chat platform will make people interested about it, and even more people will use it just because it’s from Google. People will be able to use their own clients like Element, or another Matrix client, still and users can build a network greater than a centralised chat service, like we use gmail in our mail app to chat with someone else with a different email provider. </p>
<p>And the bottom line is Facebook, Telegram, Signal, and other chat platforms are going on a race without Google, all providing a centralised experience, with the exception of Signal, who is providing a semi-centralised experience. So even if you can’t beat them, why not try to destroy them all with an open chat protocol?</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ruky.me/2021/01/31/why-google-needs-to-build-an-open-chat-client-like-element/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25976275</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 05:24:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[This is how Google will collapse]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25975560">thread link</a>) | @partingshots
<br/>
January 30, 2021 | https://empirics.asia/this-is-how-google-will-collapse/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://empirics.asia/this-is-how-google-will-collapse/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p id="473e">Google made almost all its money from ads. It was a booming business — until it wasn’t. Here’s how things looked right before the most spectacular crash the technology industry had ever seen.</p><h3 id="816d">The crumbling of Google’s cornerstone</h3><p id="ce3a">Search was Google’s only unambiguous win, as well as its <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2017/01/26/googlealphabet-reports-fourth-quarter-2016-earnings-q4.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="http://www.cnbc.com/2017/01/26/googlealphabet-reports-fourth-quarter-2016-earnings-q4.html">primary source of revenue</a>, so when Amazon <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2017/amazon-continues-grow-lead-google-starting-point-online-shoppers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="http://www.geekwire.com/2017/amazon-continues-grow-lead-google-starting-point-online-shoppers/">rapidly surpassed Google</a> as the top product search destination, Google’s foundations began to falter. <span data-creator-ids="anon">As <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/08/11/google-isnt-safe-from-yahoos-fate/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/08/11/google-isnt-safe-from-yahoos-fate/">many noted</a> at the time, the online advertising industry experienced a major shift from search to discovery in the mid-2010s.</span></p><p id="652c">While Google protected its monopoly on the dying search advertising market, Facebook — Google’s biggest competitor in the online advertising space — got on the <a href="https://www.emarketer.com/Article/Google-Facebook-Increase-Their-Grip-on-Digital-Ad-Market/1015417" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="https://www.emarketer.com/Article/Google-Facebook-Increase-Their-Grip-on-Digital-Ad-Market/1015417">right side of the trend</a> and dominated online advertising with its in-feed native display advertising.</p><figure id="88e5"><div></div><figcaption>The people who turned to Amazon over Google? <a <a="" href="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Screen-Shot-2017-01-13-at-10.40.08-AM.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Screen-Shot-2017-01-13-at-10.40.08-AM.png">The 18–29 crowd led the&nbsp;way</a>.</figcaption></figure><p id="93c5">In late 2015, Apple — Google’s main competitor in the mobile space — added a feature to their phones and tablets that allowed users to block ads.</p><p id="0ebe">Devices running iOS were responsible for an <a href="http://appleinsider.com/articles/15/05/27/apples-ios-drives-75-of-googles-mobile-advertising-revenue" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="http://appleinsider.com/articles/15/05/27/apples-ios-drives-75-of-googles-mobile-advertising-revenue">estimated 75%</a> of Google’s revenue from mobile search ads, so by making this move, Apple was simultaneously weighing in decisively on the great ad blocking debate of the 2010s and dealing a substantial blow to the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/07/24/apple-lays-the-groundwork-to-kill-online-advertising/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/07/24/apple-lays-the-groundwork-to-kill-online-advertising/">future of online advertising</a>.</p></div><div><p id="4b96">A year later, as the internet went mobile, so too did ad blocking. The number of people blocking ads on a mobile device grew <a href="https://pagefair.com/blog/2016/mobile-adblocking-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="https://pagefair.com/blog/2016/mobile-adblocking-report/">102% from 2015 to 2016</a>; by the end of 2016, an estimated 16% of smartphone users globally were <a href="https://pagefair.com/blog/2016/mobile-adblocking-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="https://pagefair.com/blog/2016/mobile-adblocking-report/">blocking ads</a> when browsing the internet on a mobile device. The number was <a href="https://www.emarketer.com/Article/Why-More-than-Quarter-of-US-Internet-Users-Block-Ads/1014333" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="https://www.emarketer.com/Article/Why-More-than-Quarter-of-US-Internet-Users-Block-Ads/1014333">as high as 25%</a> for desktop and laptop users in the United States, a country that accounted for <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/266250/regional-distribution-of-googles-revenue/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/266250/regional-distribution-of-googles-revenue/">47% of Google’s revenue</a>.</p><p id="9580">The people most likely to block ads were also the most valuable demographic: <a href="http://marketingland.com/ad-blocker-usage-highest-among-key-advertiser-demos-millennials-and-high-earners-143546" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="http://marketingland.com/ad-blocker-usage-highest-among-key-advertiser-demos-millennials-and-high-earners-143546"><em>millennials and high earners</em></a><em>.</em></p></div><div><p id="ab13"><strong>Internet users had spoken, and they hated ads.</strong></p><p id="f036">In early 2017, Google announced its plans to build an ad blocker into its popular Google Chrome browser. Google’s ad blocker would only block ads that were deemed unacceptable by the <a href="http://www.thedrum.com/news/2016/09/16/procter-gamble-unilever-google-facebook-and-more-form-coalition-better-ads" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="http://www.thedrum.com/news/2016/09/16/procter-gamble-unilever-google-facebook-and-more-form-coalition-better-ads">Coalition For Better Ads</a>, effectively allowing the company to use its dominant web browser to strengthen its already dominant advertising business.</p><p id="d68f">Even after making this desperate and <a href="http://fortune.com/2017/04/20/google-ad-blocker/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="http://fortune.com/2017/04/20/google-ad-blocker/">legally questionable</a> move, it would quickly become clear to Google that even though ads were getting better, ad blocking numbers would <a href="http://adage.com/article/digital/ad-blocking-increases-consumers-improving/305978/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="http://adage.com/article/digital/ad-blocking-increases-consumers-improving/305978/">continue to rise</a>. Google had given even more people a small taste of what an ad-free internet experience could look like.</p><p id="5e12"><strong>The company discovered that it wasn’t just annoying ads that people didn’t like; it was ads in general.</strong></p></div><div><p id="5603">A key platform where Google served ads was YouTube, which it bought in 2006 and quickly turned into one of its biggest entities. But even with a <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/youtube-stats_n_2922543.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/youtube-stats_n_2922543.html">sixth of the world</a> visiting this video-sharing behemoth every month, YouTube <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/viewers-dont-add-up-to-profit-for-youtube-1424897967" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/viewers-dont-add-up-to-profit-for-youtube-1424897967">never became profitable</a>. In an attempt to combat the effect of ad blockers, YouTube launched an ad-free subscription model in late 2015, but the subscription numbers were <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/11/2/13498470/youtube-red-subscribers-video-content-music" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="http://www.theverge.com/2016/11/2/13498470/youtube-red-subscribers-video-content-music">underwhelming</a>.</p><p id="7afb">YouTube’s already insurmountable problems multiplied in early 2017 as advertisers <a href="http://www.fiercepharma.com/marketing/google-scrambling-for-solutions-after-advertiser-departures-youtube" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="http://www.fiercepharma.com/marketing/google-scrambling-for-solutions-after-advertiser-departures-youtube">began to pull out amid ad placement controversies</a>, and huge revenue generators began to <a href="http://www.ibtimes.com/pewdiepie-starts-weekly-twitch-show-uploads-youtube-over-party-video-2523797" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="http://www.ibtimes.com/pewdiepie-starts-weekly-twitch-show-uploads-youtube-over-party-video-2523797">leave the site</a>.</p><p id="f0ab">Even those who weren’t blocking ads had trained themselves to ignore them entirely. Researchers dubbed this phenomenon “<a href="http://www.tobiipro.com/fields-of-use/marketing-consumer-research/advertising/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="http://www.tobiipro.com/fields-of-use/marketing-consumer-research/advertising/">banner blindness</a>”. The average banner ad was clicked on by a dismal <a href="https://www.thinkwithgoogle.com/intl/en-gb/planning-tool/display-benchmarks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="https://www.thinkwithgoogle.com/intl/en-gb/planning-tool/display-benchmarks/">0.06% of viewers</a>, and of those clicks, roughly <a href="http://www.goldspotmedia.com/fat-finger-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="http://www.goldspotmedia.com/fat-finger-report/">50% were accidental</a>.</p><p id="c67f">Research showed that <a href="https://www.bannersnack.com/blog/build-trust-display-ads/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="http://www.bannersnack.com/blog/build-trust-display-ads/">54% of users</a> reported a lack of trust as their reason for not clicking banner ads and 33% found them completely <a href="http://downloads.pagefair.com/reports/adblocking_goes_mainstream_2014_report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="http://downloads.pagefair.com/reports/adblocking_goes_mainstream_2014_report.pdf">intolerable</a>. These figures painted a pretty grim picture for the sustainability of online advertising, but especially for Google’s position within the industry.</p><blockquote id="8a50"><p>Google’s mighty engine had started to&nbsp;sputter.</p></blockquote><h3 id="def0">A chance to pivot, and how Google missed&nbsp;it</h3><p id="ec19">If losing a major portion of their audience and annoying the rest wasn’t bad enough, Google also failed to get ahead of one of the biggest shifts in technology’s history. They recognized the importance of artificial intelligence but their approach missed the mark. Since Google’s search pillar had become unstable, a lot was riding on the company’s strategy for artificial intelligence.</p><blockquote id="2408"><p>“We will move from mobile first to an AI first&nbsp;world.”</p></blockquote><p id="814d">Google’s then-CEO Sundar Pichai <a href="https://blog.google/topics/inside-google/this-years-founders-letter/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="https://blog.google/topics/inside-google/this-years-founders-letter/">famously predicted</a> in 2016 that “<em>the next big step will be for the very concept of the ‘device’ to fade away” </em>and that<em> “over time, the computer itself — whatever its form factor — will be an intelligent assistant helping you through your day. We will move from mobile first to an AI first world.”</em></p><p id="6d2f">Google’s ability to acknowledge the coming trend and still fail to land in front of it reminded many observers of its catastrophic failures in the booming industries of social media and instant messaging.</p><figure id="179f"><div></div><figcaption>Sundar Pichai wondering how to monetize a virtual assistant</figcaption></figure><h3 id="deb3">Google vs.&nbsp;Amazon</h3><p id="d2e7">Meanwhile, in 2014, Amazon released a product called Amazon Echo, a small speaker that could sit in your home and answer questions, perform tasks, and buy things online for you. The Echo was a <a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/amazon-echo-success-could-spell-big-trouble-for-google-2017-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="http://www.businessinsider.com/amazon-echo-success-could-spell-big-trouble-for-google-2017-1">smash success</a>. Google released its copycat product, Google Home, two years later, but it was already <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/jan/22/home-battleground-amazon-google-voice-technology" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/jan/22/home-battleground-amazon-google-voice-technology">too late to catch up</a>, and had no clear revenue strategy.</p><p id="a3f9">Alexa — the assistant that lived inside the Echo — on the other hand, was quickly integrated into several products and services, and its monetization model was clear, viable, and most importantly future-friendly. The Echo made it easy to order products through Amazon, and every time someone used an Echo to purchase something, Amazon made money.</p><p id="dde3">Google extended the reach of their virtual assistant by building it into Android, but doing so still didn’t provide an answer for how the technology would generate enough revenue to sustain Google’s expanding repertoire of expensive innovations.</p><p id="c590">Google’s ads relied on screens, yet voice interaction subverted screens entirely. Google briefly tried playing audio ads with the Google Home, but consumers were <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017/03/17/google-home-ads-bad-precedent/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="https://www.engadget.com/2017/03/17/google-home-ads-bad-precedent/">far from receptive</a>. Investors <a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/google-ceo-sundar-pichai-responds-to-concerns-over-monetizing-voice-search-2017-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="http://www.businessinsider.com/google-ceo-sundar-pichai-responds-to-concerns-over-monetizing-voice-search-2017-1">started to voice their concerns in 2017</a>, but Sundar Pichai told them not to worry, leaving them to assume that Google would use their age-old strategy and analyze users’ voice searches so that users could be shown more suitable ads on devices with screens.</p><figure id="388c"><div></div><figcaption>Alexa celebrating its victory over&nbsp;Google</figcaption></figure><p id="f6d7">Headlines in early 2017 <a href="https://www.wired.com/2017/01/ces-alexa-in-everything/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="https://www.wired.com/2017/01/ces-alexa-in-everything/">proclaimed</a> that “Alexa Just Conquered CES. The World is Next.” Amazon then made their technology <a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/amazon-opens-echo-microphone-tech-to-third-party-alexa-devices/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="http://www.zdnet.com/article/amazon-opens-echo-microphone-tech-to-third-party-alexa-devices/">available</a> to third party manufacturers, putting even more distance between the two companies. Amazon <a href="http://www.investors.com/news/technology/amazon-confronts-microsoft-google-ibm-in-cloud-computing-wars/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="http://www.investors.com/news/technology/amazon-confronts-microsoft-google-ibm-in-cloud-computing-wars/">had already beaten Google once before</a>, holding 54% of the cloud computing market (compared to Google’s 3%) in 2016, and they were just getting started.</p><p id="2d79">By early 2017, Amazon <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2017/03/31/competing-with-amazon-is-crushing-retailers.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="http://www.cnbc.com/2017/03/31/competing-with-amazon-is-crushing-retailers.html">had begun closing in</a> on <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/groupthink/2017/02/03/amazon-go-is-the-future-plus-4-reasons-why-amazon-might-just-win-retail" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/groupthink/2017/02/03/amazon-go-is-the-future-plus-4-reasons-why-amazon-might-just-win-retail">the entire</a> <a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/retailers-are-going-bankrupt-at-a-staggering-rate-2017-4" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-href="http://www.businessinsider.com/retailers-are-going-bankrupt-at-a-staggering-rate-2017-4">retail industry</a>.</p><h3 id="a95b">Ads weren’t&nbsp;forever</h3><p id="99b5">At its peak, Google had a massive and loyal user-base across a staggering number of products, but advertising revenue was the glue that held everything together. As the numbers waned, Google’s core began to buckle under the weight of its vast empire.</p><p id="4f07">Google was a driving force in the technology industry ever since its disruptive entry in 1998. But in a world where people despised ads, Google’s business model was not innovation-friendly, and they missed several opportunities to pivot, ultimately rendering their numerous grand and ambitious projects unsustainable. Innovation costs money, and Google’s main stream of revenue had started to dry up.</p><p id="dd33">In a few short years, Google had gone from a fun, commonplace verb to a reminder of how quickly a giant can fall.</p><p>___________________________________________</p><p><strong>About the Author</strong></p><p><em>This article was written by&nbsp;<a dir="auto" href="https://hackernoon.com/@dacoja?source=post_header_lockup" data-action="show-user-card" data-action-source="post_header_lockup" data-action-value="6502e16a569a" data-action-type="hover" data-user-id="6502e16a569a" data-collection-slug="hacker-daily">Daniel Colin James</a>,developer, writer, master’s student. <a href="http://danielcolinjames.com/">See more</a>. <a href="https://empirics.asia/this-is-how-google-will-collapse/danielcolinjames@gmail.com">Contact</a>.&nbsp;</em></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://empirics.asia/this-is-how-google-will-collapse/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25975560</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 03:25:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[An Onion's Genome Has Five Times More DNA Than Humans (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 50 | Comments 28 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25975457">thread link</a>) | @disqard
<br/>
January 30, 2021 | https://geneticsunzipped.com/news/2019/1/31/the-onion-test | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://geneticsunzipped.com/news/2019/1/31/the-onion-test">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1565793939038_266584"><div><p>The human genome is an incredible thing. Six billion letters of DNA – that’s more than two metres of DNA in every single cell – containing all the genes that enable a single cell to grow into a fully-formed, fully functioning person. </p><p>So when the first draft sequence of the human genome was published in 2001, researchers around the world were eager to discover exactly how many genes must be packed into our glorious genome.</p><p>The answer was a big surprise.</p><p>Many people thought that it must take at least a hundred thousand genes to make a human – with a sweepstake on offer to the person who made the closest guess to the final number – yet the human genome turns out to contain only 20,000 or so genes (roughly the same number of genes as a fruit fly or nematode worm).</p><p>This seems remarkably low to make an organism with as much dazzling complexity as a human being.  Even more perplexingly, the genes that we do have make up less than two per cent of all that DNA. So what’s the rest?</p><p>To find out, we need to go back in time to 1972.</p><p>That’s when geneticist Susumu Ohno published a paper entitled “So much ‘junk’ DNA in our genome” in an obscure scientific journal, the Brookhaven Symposia in Biology, in which he mused upon a mathematical problem.</p><p>By that point, scientists had already measured how much DNA was present in bacteria and figured out that these little bugs must contain a few thousand genes. They also knew that a single human cell contained at least 750 times as much DNA.</p><p>Ohno did a quick back-of-the-envelope calculation – if the number of genes in any genome was directly proportional to the amount of DNA, then humans should have….. three million genes, more or less.</p><p>But, as he pointed out in his paper, ‘lowly lungfish and salamanders’ can have 36 times more DNA in their cells than is present in ours, suggesting that they should have…. A hundred million genes.</p><p>He didn’t believe it. What would a slimy salamander need with all those genes? Therefore, Ohno concluded, the vast majority of the human genome must be junk. And, correspondingly, varying proportions of other organisms’ genomes must be junk too. And once the Human Genome project revealed that the vast majority of our genome doesn’t seem to contain actual genes, it looked like he was right.</p><p>The function of this remaining 98% of the human genome - sometimes called ‘junk DNA’ but more accurately referred to as non-coding DNA – is a hotly debated topic in the world of genetics, fought out within the dignified pages of journals and the more febrile atmosphere of scientific conferences.</p><p>An absolutely massive study published in 2012, known as ENCODE, suggested that around 80% of the human genome was functional – namely, that it did something important for the proper functioning of our cells and bodies. Just under 10 per cent is thought to be control switches responsible for turning genes on and off at the right time and in the right place, while the rest does all manner of things, from producing little pieces of RNA that control gene activity to organising the three-dimensional structure of the DNA inside a cell.</p><p>Others were unconvinced. For example, evolutionary geneticist Chris Ponting suggests that less than 10% of the human genome is functional, based on how much has been strongly preserved through evolutionary time and must therefore be very important.</p><p>It’s against this backdrop we bring in the Onion Test, devised by T. Ryan Gregory and posted on his blog in April 2007. It was later formalised as a scientific paper that he published in 2014, together with Alexander Palazzo.</p><p>Put simply, the Onion Test goes like this.</p><p>The onion in your vegetable drawer has five times more DNA than humans. So if you’re a researcher who thinks that non-coding DNA has a particular function in the genome, can you explain why an onion needs about five times more of it than a human to do the same thing?</p><p>Unpeeling this idea a bit further, Gregory points out that some species of onions have around double the amount of DNA as your regular onions, while others have less than half. Yet they’re pretty much the same and have the same number of genes, so why would they need double or half the amount of non-coding DNA?</p><p>This argument works for all kinds of species, from Ohno’s lowly salamanders with their giant genomes containing roughly the same set of genes as other vertebrates, including humans, to the biggest genome discovered to date, which belongs to the Japanese canopy flower, Paris Japonica, with around 150 time more DNA in its genome than a human.</p><p>Then there’s the poisonous Fugu pufferfish – often eaten (very carefully!) as a delicacy in Japan.  They have remarkably compact genomes, roughly an eighth of the size of our own yet containing almost exactly the same repertoire of genes and very little junk.</p><p>Perhaps our obsession with finding function for all the junk in our genome comes from a desire to think that humans are something special in the biological world – certainly more special than an onion.</p><p> But in the words of the grumpy geneticist Dan Graur, who I interviewed for my book Herding Hemingway’s Cats in which I dig into the junk in our genetic trunk,  “Either you have to assume that humans are the pinnacle of creation –that everything is functional and those organisms with more DNA than us have junk DNA but we don’t. Or you have to assume that humans are a regular organism that has junk DNA just like everything else.”</p><p><strong>Further reading:</strong></p><ul data-rte-list="default"><li><p><a href="http://www.genomicron.evolverzone.com/2007/04/onion-test/" target="_blank">T. Ryan Gregory’s original post about the onion test</a></p></li><li><p><a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosgenetics/article?id=10.1371/journal.pgen.1004351" target="_blank">The case for junk DNA, Palazzo &amp; Gregory (2014), PLoS Genetics</a></p></li><li><p><a href="https://www.sciencemag.org/news/2010/10/scienceshot-biggest-genome-ever" target="_blank">The biggest ever genome - Paris Japonica </a></p></li><li><p><a href="http://bit.ly/HerdingHemingwaysCats" target="_blank">Herding Hemingway’s Cats - Kat Arney </a>(aff) Chapters 1 and 2</p></li></ul></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://geneticsunzipped.com/news/2019/1/31/the-onion-test</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25975457</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 03:13:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Element on Google Play Store]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 7 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25975378">thread link</a>) | @keskadale
<br/>
January 30, 2021 | https://element.io/blog/element-on-google-play-store/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://element.io/blog/element-on-google-play-store/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <div>
      
      <div><p>Hi all,</p><p>At 2021-01-29 at 21:35 UTC Google suspended Element from the Play Store without warning or notification. &nbsp;We submitted an appeal asking for clarification at 23:18, and at 05:31 received a generic update from the Google Play Policy team citing that the app has been removed due to content which contravenes their terms of use, and asking us to “make the necessary changes to [our] app” and “upload a new app using a new package name and a new app name”.</p><p>As of 11:44 UTC we’ve submitted a detailed appeal to reiterate that Element is a generic chat app for connecting to the global Matrix communication network, just as Chrome is a generic web browser for connecting to the Web - and just as Google does not control the content on the Web, Element does not control the content on Matrix.</p><p>We have also explained that the Matrix servers that we <em>do</em> run as Element (including the default Matrix.org homeserver, which we run on behalf of <a href="https://matrix.org/foundation">The Matrix.org Foundation</a>) have <a href="https://matrix.org/legal/terms-and-conditions#6-play-nice-clauses">strict Terms of Use</a> which we actively enforce. We abhor abuse, and Element is not an app that caters to abusive content.</p><p>In order to enforce our terms of use on the Matrix servers we run as Element, we have a formal Trust and Safety team hired full-time who are dedicated to investigating and tracking abuse reports sent to <a href="https://element.io/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#fd9c9f888e98bd909c898f9485d3928f9a"><span data-cfemail="25444750564065484451574c5d0b4a5742">[email&nbsp;protected]</span></a> or reported from the app. &nbsp;The team takes appropriate action on a ticket by ticket basis - deactivating abusive accounts and blocking chatrooms from our servers which contravene our terms of use, and building tooling to help enforce the terms of use on the servers we run.</p><p>Managing abuse is an ongoing activity, and <a href="https://sifted.eu/articles/element-whatsapp-exodus/">Matrix is expanding massively at the moment</a>. We are expanding Element’s Trust and Safety team to match that growth, focusing on improving our anti-abuse mechanisms, and we are also constantly expanding the <a href="https://matrix.org/docs/guides/moderation/">moderation tools</a> we provide to the community.</p><p>Meanwhile, we’re also continuing to work on decentralised reputation as a <a href="https://matrix.org/blog/2020/10/19/combating-abuse-in-matrix-without-backdoors/">scalable solution to empower other users to combat abuse</a> for the wider Matrix network - effectively bringing control back to users and empowering communities to remain safe online.</p><p>Element and Matrix are used by the French, German, UK and US governments, <a href="https://matrix.org/blog/2021/01/29/this-week-in-matrix-2021-01-29#dept-of-status-of-matrix-%EF%B8%8F">countless universities</a>, thousands of businesses and millions of people across the world - we can only apologise for the disruption caused by the app disappearing like this.</p><p>We’re currently waiting for an update to Google and will keep this blog post updated as the situation develops. &nbsp;We look forward to resolving the problem and getting the app back in the store shortly.</p><p>-- The Element Team</p><p>Update: reminder that in the interim you can download a (slightly outdated) version of Element Android from F-Droid at <a href="https://f-droid.org/en/packages/im.vector.app/">https://f-droid.org/en/packages/im.vector.app</a>. &nbsp;We're also looking into running our own F-Droid repository going forwards so the most recent build is always available there.</p><p>UPDATE: At 2021-01-30 23:17 UTC we received a call from a VP at Google who apologised for the bad communication from Google and explained the situation, which related to some extremely abusive content which was accessible on the default matrix.org homeserver. &nbsp;Our Trust and Safety team had already identified and acted on this content to enforce the server's terms of use, and so we've explained how Element and Matrix works, established a channel for communication over any future moderation concerns, and expect the app to be restored shortly.</p><p>UPDATE: The app is restored as of 2021-01-31 00:30 UTC. &nbsp;Huge thanks to everyone for your patience and support while we sorted this out, and to the wider Element team who spent their Saturday on this. &nbsp;Thanks also to Google for being transparent and apologetic and the rapid resolution once we'd established contact.</p></div>
      
    </div>
  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://element.io/blog/element-on-google-play-store/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25975378</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 02:59:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[PDP-11/04 – Restoration – Finished]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 16 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25974507">thread link</a>) | @segfaultbuserr
<br/>
January 30, 2021 | http://www.datormuseum.se/computers/digital-equipment-corporation/pdp-11-04 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.datormuseum.se/computers/digital-equipment-corporation/pdp-11-04">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">Of course some nice soul has scanned the&nbsp;</span><a href="http://bitsavers.informatik.uni-stuttgart.de/pdf/dec/unibus/EK-BA11L-TM-001_Oct77.pdf">BA11L maintenance manual</a><span face="verdana, sans-serif">&nbsp;which describes in detail the inner workings of the power supply.&nbsp;<br></span></p><div><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">The big filtering capacitors rated at 50 V 22000uf to filter the raw DC was able to charge through a 10k resistor perfectly well and the leakage was very small. The output capacitor for 5V was in worse shape. A 3900 uF / 6VDC Sprague with impressive connectors never managed to get to the nominal voltage even using a 560 ohm resistor and plenty of time. <br></span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">&nbsp;<p><a href="http://i.imgur.com/O4FWlpH.png" imageanchor="1"><img alt="Capacitor replacement" src="http://i.imgur.com/O4FWlpH.png"></a></p><br><span><img alt="Zooma in (verklig storlek: 800 x 598)" src="http://elektronikforumet.com/forum/images/spacer.gif" title="Zooma in (verklig storlek: 800 x 598)"></span><p>Nowadays there are no such capacitors as 3900 uF / 6VDC with screw connectors so I replaced it with a 6800uF / 40VDC RIFA&nbsp; </p></span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">With a new capacitor the power supply managed well to deliver 3 Amps in my dummy load which after while smelt nicely from hot pertinax<br></span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif"><p><a href="http://i.imgur.com/3v9ATUo.jpg" imageanchor="1"><img alt="test" src="http://i.imgur.com/3v9ATUo.jpg"></a></p><br><span><img alt="Zooma in (verklig storlek: 1000 x 747)" src="http://elektronikforumet.com/forum/images/spacer.gif" title="Zooma in (verklig storlek: 1000 x 747)"></span><p>But does the it work if one connects the power supply to the back plane? Unfortunately it doesn't. Apparently two signals from the power supply was permanently in low state, BUS DC LO L and BUS AC LO L. These are active low signals and in its' low state the inhibits the clock generation of the main CPU.</p></span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">The schematics above describes the 5V regulator of the H777 power supply. The blue marked area is a current source circuit which is fed by incoming raw DC and which charges a 50uF capacitor which thus creates a nice ramp signal. A resistor ladder circuit and a number of comparators generate the BUS DC LO L, BUS AC LO L and an internal signal which causes the clock signal to the main PWM switch. The voltage over the capacitor never exceeded 20.4 V which was not enough to get the two of the comparators to change polarity. It seems like to much current is consumed from the current source. The capacitor was replaced, but no difference. But the current source was not only connected to the capacitor. It was also connected to the red marked area which is a crow bar circuit. If any of the main switch transistors would fail a 38 V raw DC would be the result on the output. Not very good. Therefore there is a zener diode and a couple of thyristors which fires off if the output voltage exceeded 5.6 VDC. This will also short circuit the current source, effectively stopping all activities in&nbsp; power supply. The problem seemed to be that even under normal circumstances 1.5 mA was consumed by leakage in the thyristor even though hasn't fired. Apparently all thyristors have leakages but not this much.<p><a href="http://i.imgur.com/U0GunMu.png" imageanchor="1"><img alt="Thyristor" height="389" src="http://i.imgur.com/U0GunMu.png" width="400"></a></p><p>Change of thyristor to a modern BT145 resulted in a fully functional power supply!</p><p><span>Testing the CPU</span></p><p>All cables were connected and the power was switched on. No smoke leaked anywhere which was a good sign. But the RUN lamp were just flashing briefly. Pressing INIT switch on the console only gave a short blink of the RUN lamp. Not very promising.</p><p>A check with the oscilloscope on the main clock signal of then CPU board showed that is starts up does 8 cycles, the stops for a couple micro seconds then does three more cycles, yet another stop and the three cycles and then nothing.</p><p><span><img alt="Zooma in (verklig storlek: 1200 x 961)" src="http://elektronikforumet.com/forum/images/spacer.gif" title="Zooma in (verklig storlek: 1200 x 961)"></span></p><p><a href="http://i.imgur.com/O3QASBs.png" imageanchor="1"><img alt="8 micro cycles" src="http://i.imgur.com/O3QASBs.png"></a></p><br>From the picture above one can deduce that the cycle time is closer to 250 ns rather than 260 ns&nbsp; specified in "Computer Engineering". However using a delay line in a feedback loop may not be that accurate. 4 MHz is a quite impressive speed at least in the mid seventies. </span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">Further than this is probably not possible using an oscilloscope only. For that purpose I have gotten this little USB connected tool:<br></span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">But to cover the entire machine with address and data bus one would need four of these. Luckily at this point in time I was offered to buy a HP1664A logic analyser at an affordable price!<br></span></p><div><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif"><b>Logic&nbsp;analyser&nbsp;fault tracing</b></span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">After some initial problems which was caused by mixed-up signals and also forgetting that the machine is active low I got some good traces from the analyser:<br></span></p><div><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif"><p><a href="http://i.imgur.com/SPIxi1B.png" imageanchor="1"><img alt="micro code" src="http://i.imgur.com/SPIxi1B.png"></a></p><p>The picture above shows the output of the micro address pipeline register. So it actually shows the second micro step as the first micro-step. But this is actually the correct sequence comparing to this <a href="http://vaxhaven.com/images/1/11/EK-KD11D-TM-PRE.pdf">document</a>. </p><p><a href="http://i.imgur.com/vCoTm8v.png" imageanchor="1"><img alt="Address bus and databus" src="http://i.imgur.com/vCoTm8v.png"></a></p><br>The interesting with this trace is that the CPU output addresses 24 and the 26 on the address bus. On the data bus it then receives 165020 which is the to be PC to start execution at after power fail, this is also the first address of the diagnostics program of the M9312. But looking at the address the CPU subsequently outputs on the address bus it is 167020. For some reason bit 10 has became high! Measuring more closely on a bus receiver chip, DS8641 shows that even though the input is at 3.31 V the output is a 3.78 V! This seems to be wrong!</span></p><p><span><span face="verdana, sans-serif">It is alive</span></span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif"><b><br></b>This is the little evil thing:<p><a href="http://i.imgur.com/XojS9FU.png" imageanchor="1"><img alt="DS8641" height="320" src="http://i.imgur.com/XojS9FU.png" width="319"></a></p><br>Unfortunately DS8641 is not a very common IC. It is especially adapted to Digital open collector buses. I ordered some from a seller on Ebay located in China but since the delivery time is quite long I resorted to desoldered an IC from another board and replaced the faulty chip on the CPU board.<p>This time the result was much better:</p></span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif"><p><a href="http://i.imgur.com/soZUSxo.png" imageanchor="1"><img alt="Waiting for TX ready" src="http://i.imgur.com/soZUSxo.png"></a></p><br>However it ends up spinning waiting for TX ready bit of the console serial port to become ready. Strange. Maybe the M7800 is faulty?</span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif"><b>Another M7800</b><br></span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif"><br>Another M7800 was configured a put into the back plane. A serial port was connected to the my laptop.<p><a href="http://i.imgur.com/0OiZWz0l.png" imageanchor="1"><img src="http://i.imgur.com/0OiZWz0l.png"></a></p></span></p></div><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">Perfect! Now it passed diagnostics step 1 to 4. But pressing DL to make it boot from the (non existent) RL device causes it to halt. <br></span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">It seems that when trying to execute the memory tests it fails and then it gets a double bus fault when handling the first. This very well matches the TRAP handling of the CPU.<br></span></p><div><p><span><span face="verdana, sans-serif">Failing DIP switch!</span></span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">While investigating the memory board and checking the jumpers and switch settings I found that although I changed the DIP switches back and forth regardless of position 6 out of 8 of the switches remained open circuit. Not very promising<span>.<br></span></span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif"><p><a href="http://i.imgur.com/QdUYcEjl.png" imageanchor="1"><img alt="DIP switches" src="http://i.imgur.com/QdUYcEjl.png"></a></p><p>New switch to the left and old to the right.</p><p>Finally it runs!</p><p><a href="http://i.imgur.com/CwHpbFnl.png" imageanchor="1"><img alt="Memory OK!" src="http://i.imgur.com/CwHpbFnl.png"></a></p></span></p><div><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">It is possible Examine and Deposit in the memory!</span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif"><span>PDP11GUI</span></span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif"><a href="http://retrocmp.com/tools/pdp11gui">PDP11GUI</a>&nbsp;is a nice windows tool to control your PDP-11. It can be used to load files into memory, examining memory and starting the CPU to run. <p><span><img alt="Zooma in (verklig storlek: 1279 x 775)" src="http://elektronikforumet.com/forum/images/spacer.gif" title="Zooma in (verklig storlek: 1279 x 775)"></span></p><p><a href="http://i.imgur.com/4UYRAjsl.png" imageanchor="1"><img alt="PDP11GUI" src="http://i.imgur.com/4UYRAjsl.png"></a></p><br></span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif" size="2">There are papertapes of&nbsp;<a href="http://iamvirtual.ca/PDP-11/Basic-11/DEC-11-AJPB-PB.ptap">BASIC</a>&nbsp;to be found on many places on the internet. But it comes in an Absolute Binary Loader format which&nbsp;<a href="http://retrocmp.com/tools/pdp11gui">PDP11GUI</a>&nbsp;currently cannot read. However writing a small C program to convert it is simple and then it can be fee into the machine, but it is not very fast to run over a 9600 bps serial line.</span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif" size="2">The Absolute Loader is a small paper tape that need to be bootstrapped into memory for the machine to be able to load files in Absolute Loader format, like to BASIC interpreter above. The Absolute loader comes on a tape called&nbsp;<span>DEC-11-L2PC-PO.</span></span></p><div><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif"><b>UPDATE</b>: As of v1.38 of&nbsp;<a href="http://retrocmp.com/tools/pdp11gui">PDP11GUI</a>&nbsp;it is not necessary to convert the file before using it with&nbsp;<a href="http://retrocmp.com/tools/pdp11gui">PDP11GUI</a>&nbsp;since this conversion has been included in&nbsp;<a href="http://retrocmp.com/tools/pdp11gui">PDP11GUI</a>.<br></span></p></div><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">Starting the PDP at 016104 gives the BASIC prompt!<br></span></p>
</div><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">It seems that I haven't been around doing any BASIC programming for a long long time :-)</span></p>
<p><b><span face="verdana, sans-serif">Running diagnostics</span></b></p></div><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">To really check that the CPU was working as it should there are two diagnostics to run. These are GKAA and GKAB. There are actually two ways to run them. Either you have an image of the paper tape which you load by PDP11GUI or you run the XXDP environment. I tried both ways.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">Originally these are paper tape software but unfortunately I was unable to find images of these paper tapes. But I did find a XXDP image with the GKAAA0.BIC and GKABC0.BIC on them. It turns out that these binaries in reality has exactly the same format as a paper tape. I used the <a href="http://www.dbit.com/putr/">PUTR</a>&nbsp;tool to extract them from the image. Please make sure to copy them as binary otherwise you end up like me scratching my head for hours... I then used PDP11GUI to load them into memory and starting them at address 200.&nbsp;</span></p><p><b><span face="verdana, sans-serif">Booting XXDP</span></b></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">XXDP needs to be booted from some kind of mass storage. The only thing than would be quite easy to get running on the machine right now is TU58 since it is using a standard serial port to connect to the drive. The drive itself can be emulated using a PC or MAC. I downloaded&nbsp;<a href="http://www.ak6dn.com/PDP-11/TU58/tu58em/index.html">tu58em</a>&nbsp;and compiled it on my Mac. It needed just a few modifications to the serial port code to compile cleanly.</span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">Then I started the work to get a bootable TU58 image for my TU58 emulator. It is far simpler to use an emulator to all this kind of work. I used&nbsp;<a href="http://www.dbit.com/">E11</a>&nbsp;to do all this. First I tried XXDP 2.6 which I found an image for on bitsavers:</span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">Unfortunately it required more memory than my machine had so it won't be possible to run this version. Besides the GKAB diagnostics doesn't run at all on the emulated PDP-11/04 for some reason!</span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">I then spent some time to make a TU58 image for XXDP+, an earlier version of the XXDP suite.</span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">This is how I did that using E11:</span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">Running GKAAA0.BIC under XXDP+ on the real machine works fine. Most of the machine is in perfect order! Here is a link to the <a href="http://storage.datormuseum.se/u/96935524/Datormusuem/dddp2.dsk">image</a> I used.</span></p><div><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif"><p><a href="http://storage.datormuseum.se/u/96935524/Datormusuem/Screenshot%20XXDP%20boot.png" imageanchor="1"><img src="http://storage.datormuseum.se/u/96935524/Datormusuem/Screenshot%20XXDP%20boot.png"></a></p><br></span></p></div><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">But running the GKABC0 unfortunately ends with a halt. It is impossible to find a listing for this diagnostic but the PDP-11/34 version is very similar. Looking through the <a href="http://bitsavers.informatik.uni-stuttgart.de/pdf/dec/pdp11/xxdp/diag_listings/1134/AC-8045D-MC_CFKABD0-1134-Traps-Tst_Apr77.pdf">code</a>&nbsp;gives that the section where it halts is testing the stack overflow logic in the CPU. It does this by setting the stack pointer to 400 and then enable console TX interrupts. This will cause an immediate TX interrupt to occur. This will decrement the stack pointer below 400 and immediately trigger a trap to vector 4/6. My machine on the other hand will trigger new console interrupts until the stack wraps to 177774 (where there are no memory) and then halt with a double bus fault!</span></p><p><b><span face="verdana, sans-serif">Faulty DL11-W!</span></b></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">By swapping cards I found that the using a replacement DL11-W the problem vanished. It seems that the interrupt logic inside the DL11-W has broken down. The interrupt shall be cleared as soon as the CPU responds with an SSYN. This doesn't happen on the faulty board. As soon as the CPU has started serving the interrupt till interrupt again and again.</span></p><p><span face="verdana, sans-serif">This is the unibus interrupt cycle. The device asserts /BRn line and the CPU responds with a BGn when the CPU is ready to serve the interrupt. The device will then respond with the /SACK and then put the vector on to the bus and assert the /INTR signal. The CPU will respond with a …</span></p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://www.datormuseum.se/computers/digital-equipment-corporation/pdp-11-04">http://www.datormuseum.se/computers/digital-equipment-corporation/pdp-11-04</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.datormuseum.se/computers/digital-equipment-corporation/pdp-11-04</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25974507</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:33:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
