<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 20]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 20. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 08:39:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-20.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 08:39:48 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Elderly patients 23% more likely to die if surgery is on the surgeon’s birthday]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 128 | Comments 89 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25440322">thread link</a>) | @whx23
<br/>
December 16, 2020 | https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/elderly-emergency-surgery-patients-23-more-likely-to-die-if-operation-takes-place-on-surgeons-birthday/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/elderly-emergency-surgery-patients-23-more-likely-to-die-if-operation-takes-place-on-surgeons-birthday/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-5563" role="main"><div><div><div><p>A <a href="https://www.bmj.com/content/371/bmj.m4381" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new study has found</a> that elderly patients who underwent emergency surgery on their surgeon’s birthday had significantly higher 30-day mortality rates than patients whose surgery took place on any other day of the year. <span data-ez-name="psychnewsdaily_com-medrectangle-3"></span></p><p>The 30-day mortality rate (defined as death within 30 days after surgery)&nbsp;for the “surgeon’s birthday” group was 6.9%. This was 23% higher than the 5.6% rate for the “other day” group.</p><p>The study, which appears today in the <em>British Medical Journal</em> (<a href="https://www.bmj.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BMJ</a>),&nbsp;looked at 980,876 procedures performed in US hospitals by 47,489 surgeons.&nbsp;Of those procedures, 2,064 (0.2%) took place on a surgeon’s birthday.&nbsp;The patients were all Medicare beneficiaries aged 65 to 99. They had all undergone one of 17 common emergency surgical procedures between 2011 and 2014.</p><h2>Distractions during the most common emergency surgery types</h2><p>Examples of those 17 procedures included cardiovascular surgeries, hip and femur fracture, appendectomy, and small bowel resection. The study focused on&nbsp;emergency surgery, so as to&nbsp;minimize the potential selection bias. For example, surgeons might otherwise choose patients based on their illness severity, or patients might choose their surgeon.</p><p>As the authors write, “The effect size of surgeons’ birthday observed in our analysis (1.3 percentage point increase or a 23% increase in mortality), though substantial, is comparable to the impact of other events, including holidays (e.g., Christmas and New Year) and weekends.” <span data-ez-name="psychnewsdaily_com-medrectangle-4"></span></p><p>In fact, the <a href="https://amzn.to/3m5rimG" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">history of surgery</a> has often demonstrated that external factors can influence surgical outcomes. The authors refer to a 2014 study showing that <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23345314/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">patients admitted to Scottish emergency rooms on&nbsp;public holidays had a 27% increase</a> in 30-day mortality.&nbsp;Other research has found, for example,&nbsp;that doctors are more likely to <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamainternalmedicine/fullarticle/1910546" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">prescribe antibiotics</a> and <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamanetworkopen/fullarticle/2749268" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">opioids</a> — and <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamanetworkopen/fullarticle/2733171" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">less likely to order&nbsp;cancer screening tests</a> — as the workday progresses. This is most likely because the “cumulative cognitive demand” of such decisions gradually takes its toll.&nbsp;</p><p>Research on judges has yielded similar results. It has found, for example, that external factors as diverse as outdoor temperatures and sports results can influence judges’ decisions.&nbsp;</p><h2>A natural experiment: ER surgery on the doctor’s birthday</h2><p>But the authors say the “natural experiment” in the present study is more revealing than, for example, holiday-related mortality rates. That is because “those events not only affect physicians’ performance but also influence patients’ decision to seek care (i.e., patients seeking care on these special days might be sicker than those seeking care on other days), as well as hospital staffing.” Unless, of course, the patients know their surgeon’s birthday, which is unlikely (though that may change if this study becomes widely known).&nbsp;</p><p>The 1.3% effect size was the result after a very through series of controls. These included, for example, excluding those surgeons with the highest patient mortality rates. Other controls included assigning a random “pseudo-birthday” to surgeons to see whether the results still held up, or checking whether the surgeon did an above-average number of procedures on their birthday. <span data-ez-name="psychnewsdaily_com-box-4"></span></p><p>Likewise, the researchers controlled for “milestone” birthdays (such as 40 or 50). They also controlled for whether a birthday fell on a Friday, which might make after-work birthday festivities more likely.&nbsp;Their findings also held up when the analysis was restricted to procedures with the highest average mortality, or to only the most ill patients.&nbsp;In fact, without these adjustments, the 30-day mortality rate difference between the birthday and non-birthday groups (the unadjusted rate) was even higher (7.0% vs. 5.6%, or a 1.4% difference).</p><h2><strong>Why</strong> does emergency surgery suffer on surgeon’s birthday?</h2><p>The authors propose a few potential explanations for this “birthday effect.”&nbsp;</p><p>These include hurrying through an emergency surgery to be on time for after-work birthday events; <a href="https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/study-finds-users-not-notifications-initiate-89-of-smartphone-interactions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">distracting</a> birthday-related phone calls or text messages; more conversations with well-wishing staff members; and a decreased likelihood to go back to the hospital that evening if a patient’s condition deteriorates.</p><p>They also found that some surgeons did not work on their birthdays. While 2,144 surgeons in this study performed procedures one day before their birthday, and 2,027 did so one day after their birthday, only 1,805 surgeons carried out procedures on their actual birthday. This does not affect the results of the study’s analyses. But it does suggest “that birthdays are an important enough factor for some surgeons to choose not to operate on that day, which supports the credibility of our assumption that a birthday could be a distracting factor for those surgeons who choose to operate on that day,” the authors write.&nbsp;</p><h2><strong>Limitations</strong> <strong>and future directions</strong></h2><p>The researchers emphasized that this study focused on common procedures, and on older Medicare patients. This means that the findings may not apply to other types of patients, or to other surgical procedures.</p><p>Still, the authors write, these results may lead to “additional support for surgeons who have potentially distracting events,” such as birthdays, “to make sure that patients receive high quality surgical care regardless of when undergo surgery.”</p><hr><p><strong>Study: </strong>“<a href="https://dx.doi.org/10.1136/bmj.m4381" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Patient mortality after surgery on the surgeon’s birthday: observational study</a>“<br><strong>Authors:</strong> Hirotaka Kato, Anupam B. Jena, and Yusuke Tsugawa<br><strong>Published in:</strong> <a href="https://www.bmj.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>The BMJ</em></a><br><strong>Publication date: </strong>December 10, 2020<br><strong>DOI:</strong> <a href="https://dx.doi.org/10.1136/bmj.m4381" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://dx.doi.org/10.1136/bmj.m4381</a><br><strong>Photo: </strong>by&nbsp;<a href="https://pixabay.com/users/theshiv76-1022681/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=766166">Jason Shivers</a>&nbsp;from&nbsp;<a href="https://pixabay.com/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=766166">Pixabay</a>&nbsp;</p><p>For a weekly summary of the latest psychology news, subscribe to our <a href="https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/the-psych-news-weekly-newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Psych News Weekly newsletter</a>.</p></div></div></div></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/elderly-emergency-surgery-patients-23-more-likely-to-die-if-operation-takes-place-on-surgeons-birthday/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25440322</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 08:38:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Far Cry: How the Fire Burns and Spreads (2012)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 120 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25437800">thread link</a>) | @fctorial
<br/>
December 15, 2020 | https://jflevesque.com/2012/12/06/far-cry-how-the-fire-burns-and-spreads/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jflevesque.com/2012/12/06/far-cry-how-the-fire-burns-and-spreads/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            
			
<h2>INTRO</h2>



<p>A few years ago, I got the opportunity to architect and code the fire propagation system in Far Cry 2. &nbsp;At that time, &nbsp;it was a gigantic task and it scared the hell out of me. Luckily, it turned out well enough.</p>



<p>With the upcoming Far Cry 3, several people recently asked me how the system worked. I realized that I never took the time to write it down. So, before I forget and also because it might be useful to somebody out there, here’s a high level overview of its inner workings. &nbsp;Pretty programmer art included as a bonus.</p>



<p><em>Disclaimer: Although Far Cry 3 uses the same system I wrote, I was not involved in the project. They may or may not have changed / adapted or modified the algorithms. What I describe below is accurate for Far Cry 2.</em></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Far Cry 3 incredible fire demo video" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zcmbWqJjCN4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<h2>BASE STRUCTURE</h2>



<div><figure><img src="http://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/ACell1.jpg" alt="" srcset="https://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/ACell1.jpg 600w, https://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/ACell1-300x206.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px"><figcaption>A 2D Grid good for grass fire. &nbsp;Here, a fire cell has 50 hitpoints</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>At the core, the fire propagation system is quite simple. Since gameplay is what’s important, we&nbsp;sacrifice some of the realism for fun. The fire propagation in&nbsp;Far Cry 2 &nbsp;(and Far Cry 3) has just enough realism to maintain the player’s&nbsp;<a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20160114121147/http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suspension_of_disbelief">suspension of disbelief</a>,&nbsp;but certainly not enough to get published anytime soon. Because I like to&nbsp;<a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20160114121147/http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KISS_principle">keep things simple</a>, it doesn’t involve any complicated mathematics, physics or fluid dynamics. That has the additional advantage to be fast to simulate and easy to understand.</p>



<p>The secret sauce is an&nbsp;equally spaced grid. It is true for grass, for objects as well as for trees. The only difference is that we use a 2D grid for grass and a 3D grid for objects and trees.</p>



<p>Each cell of the grid has a position in the world, a radius and&nbsp;<strong>hitpoints</strong>. The cells have a plethora of&nbsp;properties, but these three are the bare minimum to propagate fire.</p>



<h2>LIGHT MY FIRE! HOW TO START ONE?</h2>



<p>The game engine tracks all damage done in the game, might it be bullet shots, impacts or fire damage. When a game entity is damaged, it is notified by an event. The damage event includes how much damage was done, what kind it was and what caused it.&nbsp;&nbsp;If the kind of damage was fire based and the entity is flammable, then at least two things happen:</p>



<ul><li>Firstly, the fire grid is dynamically created for the damaged entity. We create them dynamically because we don’t want those grids&nbsp;to exist in the wild for no reasons. That would take memory, disk space, etc, so we create them as we go. But, once created, it remains as long as the game entity exists.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Secondly, we figure out which cell in the grid is closest to the damage source. That cell then takes the damage and its hitpoints are reduced accordingly.</li></ul>



<p>That’s where things get interesting – When a cell has been damaged by fire and has lost all its hitpoints;&nbsp;<strong>it catches fire</strong>.</p>



<p>While burning, the cell becomes a damager itself. It deals damage to its neighbour cells on the grid; cells that share an edge with it. By doing so, it reduces their hitpoints and when in turns these cells have lost all their hitpoints, they catch fire. That’s how the propagation is created.<br></p>



<div><figure><img src="http://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/2DGridBiggerFire1.jpg" alt="" srcset="https://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/2DGridBiggerFire1.jpg 700w, https://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/2DGridBiggerFire1-300x220.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px"><figcaption>Fire propagating from left to right. The cells on the fire front are being damaged.</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Lastly, a cell from the grid as a finite lifetime. Otherwise, it would burn forever. It can be seen as the amount of energy given by the material that is burning. &nbsp;For instance,&nbsp;a piece of paper would most likely burn faster than a wood log, so it would be given a shorter lifetime value.</p>



<p>That’s it. A fully functional fire propagation system good enough for a AAA game!</p>



<h2>TECHNICALITIES</h2>



<p><strong>Simulate wet jungle VS dry patch of grass</strong><br>How to simulate a wet jungle versus a dry patch of grass? They behave differently. Quite easily!<br>Increase the fire cell’s hitpoints and it’s difficult to set it on fire and it’s slow to propagate.&nbsp;Decrease its burning lifetime and the fire dies out quickly. There, you just simulated a wet jungle environment.</p>



<p><strong>How to create the propagation grids</strong></p>



<p><strong><em>Grass / Land</em></strong><br>For grass wildfire, &nbsp;an axis-aligned 2D grid is built in realtime and projected on a 3D terrain. For each of the cell, we take care to determine if the cell position is underwater, or under an object such as a rock or a building. In which case, we disable that cell and it can no longer catch fire. We wouldn’t want to have fire propagating under rock, would we?<br></p>



<div><figure><img src="http://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/2DGridDisabled.jpg" alt="" srcset="https://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/2DGridDisabled.jpg 512w, https://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/2DGridDisabled-300x220.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px"><figcaption>2D grid projected on a terrain. The cells under the rock are disabled.</figcaption></figure></div>



<p><strong><em>Objects</em></strong><br>For objects, it’s a little bit more complicated. First, we create an&nbsp;<a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20160114121147/http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bounding_volume">AABB</a>&nbsp;that entirely surrounds the object. &nbsp;Second, we somehow&nbsp;need to detect the shape of that object. After all, it could be a chair, an oil barrel or a whole house for all we know. To accomplish that, the &nbsp;bounding box is divided in equally spaced cubes.&nbsp;The size of each cube depends of the object size, the number of fire emitter we want to have, performance, memory, etc.</p>



<p>An iterative algorithm then go through all those cubes and test their location against the collision shape of the object.&nbsp;If the test return a positive result, this cube is kept, otherwise it is discarded. At the end, we have a collection of cubes that approximately&nbsp;represent the shape of the object to be burned. That’s our propagation grid.<br></p>



<div><figure><img src="http://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/3DGrid.jpg" alt="" srcset="https://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/3DGrid.jpg 800w, https://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/3DGrid-300x183.jpg 300w, https://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/3DGrid-768x469.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px"><figcaption>Detection of the shape of an object</figcaption></figure></div>



<h2><strong>WIND EFFECT</strong></h2>



<p>The wind is an important disruptive factor for a wildfire and it adds a great layer of realism for the player. &nbsp;Here it could be tempting to&nbsp;over-think&nbsp;the design and go with a very complicated system. After all, it’s an active area of research and&nbsp;<a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20160114121147/http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1540748912001988">several</a>&nbsp;<a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20160114121147/http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0378475407002030">papers</a>&nbsp;on the subject are available online.</p>



<div><figure><img src="http://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/1-s2.0-S0378475407002030-gr3-300x235-1.jpg" alt=""></figure></div>



<div><figure><img src="http://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/1-s2.0-S1540748912001988-gr3.jpg" alt=""></figure></div>



<p>Luckily, with what have been explained thus far, it’s quite easy to simulate if we accept to cut corners a bit.</p>



<p>In our system, the fire propagates by damaging the&nbsp;neighbor&nbsp;cells on a grid. And it is generally accepted that a fire should spread faster in the direction of the wind than against&nbsp;the wind? Then, with that in mind, we can create a rule where a burning cell deals more damage to its&nbsp;neighbor&nbsp;cells if that neighbor is in the direction of the wind.</p>



<p>We do that by getting the&nbsp;<a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20160114121147/http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dot_product">dot product</a>&nbsp;between the wind direction&nbsp;vector and the direction of the&nbsp;neighbor&nbsp;cell to damage.&nbsp;If the result is greater than zero, then that node is dealt greater damage. &nbsp;Likewise, if the result is negative, &nbsp;the node is against the wind and should be dealt less damage. To be fancy, the amount of damage is interpolated with the dot product result as shown in the picture below.<br></p>



<div><figure><img src="http://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/ACellWindEffect1.jpg" alt="" srcset="https://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/ACellWindEffect1.jpg 600w, https://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/ACellWindEffect1-300x206.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px"><figcaption>The cell on fire causes more damage to its neighbor cells if they are in the direction of the wind.</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>With that rule alone, you will get a nice bell shaped fire front that propagates in the direction of the wind. Simple, yet believable&nbsp;enough to get the player’s stamp of approval.</p>



<p>It’s worth noting that we simulate gravity the exact same way.</p>



<h2>PROPAGATING TO THINGS AROUND AND CHAIN REACTIONS</h2>



<p>When a cell burns, it sends a “I’m on fire and I burn this much in this radius” message down&nbsp;the game event pipeline. This event is caught by objects, AI and other game systems that are in that area. They react&nbsp;to this message their own specific ways. The AI freaks out, the flammable objects get damaged and eventually catch fire. And, &nbsp;it is also true for dynamic objects. &nbsp;For example, if a burning oil barrel goes flying through the map, every step of the way, &nbsp;it will send that “i’m burning” message and a lot of things around might hear it.<br></p>



<div><figure><img src="http://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/2DGridDmgZone.jpg" alt="" srcset="https://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/2DGridDmgZone.jpg 719w, https://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/2DGridDmgZone-300x284.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 719px) 100vw, 719px"><figcaption>In the absence of wind, a cell on fire damages equally all its neighbors.</figcaption></figure></div>







<p>This causes a chain reaction effect where trees, explosive items, &nbsp;objects and patches of grass set each others on fire. &nbsp;It’s completely&nbsp;systemic and it makes it much more believable. It &nbsp;also scores pretty high on the&nbsp;player’s&nbsp;fun meter because it behaves as one would expect, yet as real fire, it sometimes gets totally out of control.</p>



<h2>OPTIMISATION</h2>



<p><strong>The Hair Transplant Strategy</strong></p>



<p>In an ideal world, we would have access to enough memory to hold&nbsp;an infinite number of particle emitters and we could display an infinite number of particles on screen.&nbsp;Unfortunately, the reality is that those numbers are actually pretty low.</p>



<p>To do more with less, we have to put our emitters where it really counts. Enters the hair transplant strategy! &nbsp;In Far Cry 2, the fire emitters are constantly being teleported around, most importantly, from the back of the camera to the front. The player’s point of view is monitored at all time and emitters that are burning out of sight are moved to a better location where they are also needed.</p>



<p>In addition, the emitters’s density is higher in close proximity of the player and lower as the distance increases. A kind of fire&nbsp;<a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20160114121147/http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Level_of_detail">LOD&nbsp;</a>if you will.&nbsp;If things are getting bad and we still need more emitters but none are available, we increase the particle sizes to give them more volume and fill more space on screen.</p>



<p>With this strategy, and some others, we can simulate a wildfire that is several meters wide with a relatively low number of particle emitters.<br></p>



<div><figure><img src="http://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/farc2.jpg" alt="" srcset="https://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/farc2.jpg 600w, https://jflevesque.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/farc2-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px"><figcaption>Credits: http://www.rockpapershotgun.com</figcaption></figure></div>



<p><strong>Event Pipeline</strong><br>Since the described system tried to avoid all complicated maths, generally speaking we will be GPU bound before being&nbsp;CPU bound.</p>



<p>That being said, the event pipeline could be a bottleneck. It works well when you have just a few cells on fire. But, it’s another story when you have thousands of them burning and&nbsp;advertising&nbsp;their state to the world. That will likely clog your CPU’s arteries.</p>



<p>The trick for me was to regroup the cells that were burning into&nbsp;<a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20160114121147/http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Axis-aligned_bounding_box#Axis-aligned_minimum_bounding_box" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">AABB</a>&nbsp;groups. These groups would constantly merge, split and&nbsp;change shape to follow the evolution of the fire. The events would then be sent per AABB instead of per cell, which saves&nbsp;a significant amount of processing power. Additionally, the events would be spread out across several frames in order to distribute the load and avoid framerate spikes.</p>



<p><strong>Keeping things under control.</strong><br>In your game, if you don’t constrain the propagation somehow, it will either</p>



<ul><li>Burn the entire map and kill all the NPCs</li><li>Fill out the …</li></ul></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://jflevesque.com/2012/12/06/far-cry-how-the-fire-burns-and-spreads/">https://jflevesque.com/2012/12/06/far-cry-how-the-fire-burns-and-spreads/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jflevesque.com/2012/12/06/far-cry-how-the-fire-burns-and-spreads/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25437800</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 01:13:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What I wish someone had told me about tensor computation libraries]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 269 | Comments 75 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25435028">thread link</a>) | @_eigenfoo
<br/>
December 15, 2020 | https://eigenfoo.xyz/tensor-computation-libraries/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://eigenfoo.xyz/tensor-computation-libraries/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<section itemprop="text">

<p>I get confused with tensor computation libraries (or computational graph libraries, or symbolic
algebra libraries, or whatever they’re marketing themselves as these days).</p>
<p>I was first introduced to PyTorch and TensorFlow and, having no other reference, thought they were
prototypical examples of tensor computation libraries. Then I learnt about Theano - an older and
less popular project, but different from PyTorch and TensorFlow and better in some meaningful ways.
This was followed by JAX, which seemed to be basically NumPy with more bells and whistles (although
I couldn’t articulate what exactly they were). Then came <a href="https://pymc-devs.medium.com/the-future-of-pymc3-or-theano-is-dead-long-live-theano-d8005f8a0e9b">the announcement by the PyMC developers
that Theano would have a new JAX
backend</a>.</p>
<p>Anyways, this confusion prompted a lot of research and eventually, this blog post.</p>
<p>Similar to <a href="https://eigenfoo.xyz/prob-prog-frameworks/">my previous post on the anatomy of probabilistic programming
frameworks</a>, I’ll first discuss tensor computation
libraries in general - what they are and how they can differ from one another. Then I’ll discuss
some libraries in detail, and finally offer an observation on the future of Theano in the context of
contemporary tensor computation libraries.</p>
<h2 id="dissecting-tensor-computation-libraries">Dissecting Tensor Computation Libraries</h2>
<p>First, a characterization: what do tensor computation libraries even do?</p>
<ol>
<li>They provide ways of specifying and building computational graphs,</li>
<li>They run the computation itself (duh), but also run “related” computations that either (a) <em>use
the computational graph</em>, or (b) operate <em>directly on the computational graph itself</em>,
<ul>
<li>The most salient example of the former is computing gradients via
<a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1502.05767">autodifferentiation</a>,</li>
<li>A good example of the latter is optimizing the computation itself: think symbolic
simplifications (e.g. <code>xy/x = y</code>) or modifications for numerical stability (e.g. <a href="https://cs.stackexchange.com/q/68411"><code>log(1 + x)</code>
for small values of <code>x</code></a>).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>And they provide “best execution” for the computation: whether it’s changing the execution by JIT
(just-in-time) compiling it, by utilizing special hardware (GPUs/TPUs), by vectorizing the
computation, or in any other way.</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="tensor-computation-library---maybe-not-the-best-name">“Tensor Computation Library” - Maybe Not The Best Name</h3>
<p>As an aside: I realize that the name “tensor computation library” is too broad, and that the
characterization above precludes some libraries that might also justifiably be called “tensor
computation libraries”. Better names might be “graph computation library” (although that might get
mixed up with libraries like <a href="https://networkx.org/"><code>networkx</code></a>) or “computational graph management
library” or even “symbolic tensor algebra libraries”.</p>
<p>So for the avoidance of doubt, here is a list of libraries that this blog post is <em>not</em> about:</p>
<ul>
<li>NumPy and SciPy
<ul>
<li>These libraries don’t have a concept of a computational graph - they’re more like a toolbox of
functions, called from Python and executed in C or Fortran.</li>
<li>However, this might be a controversial distinction - as we’ll see later, JAX also doesn’t build
an explicit computational graph either, and I definitely want to include JAX as a “tensor
computation library”… <code>¯\_(ツ)_/¯</code></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Numba and Cython
<ul>
<li>These libraries provide best execution for code (and in fact some tensor computation libraries,
such as Theano, make good use them), but like NumPy and SciPy, they do not actually manage the
computational graph itself.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Keras, Trax, Flax and PyTorch-Lightning
<ul>
<li>These libraries are high-level wrappers around tensor computation libraries - they basically
provide abstractions and a user-facing API to utilize tensor computation libraries in a
friendlier way.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="some-differences-between-tensor-computation-libraries">(Some) Differences Between Tensor Computation Libraries</h3>
<p>Anyways, back to tensor computation libraries.</p>
<p>All three aforementioned goals are ambitious undertakings with sophisticated solutions, so it
shouldn’t be surprising to learn that decisions in pursuit on goal can have implications for (or
even incur a trade-off with!) other goals. Here’s a list of common differences along all three axes:</p>
<ol>
<li>Tensor computation libraries can differ in how they represent the computational graph, and how it
is built.
<ul>
<li>Static or dynamic graphs: do we first define the graph completely and then inject data to run
(a.k.a. define-and-run), or is the graph defined on-the-fly via the actual forward computation
(a.k.a. define-by-run)?
<ul>
<li>TensorFlow 1.x was (in)famous for its static graphs, which made users feel like they were
“working with their computational graph through a keyhole”, especially when <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=13429355">compared to
PyTorch’s dynamic graphs</a>.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Lazy or eager execution: do we evaluate variables as soon as they are defined, or only when a
dependent variable is evaluated? Usually, tensor computation libraries either choose to support
dynamic graphs with eager execution, or static graphs with lazy execution - for example,
<a href="https://www.tensorflow.org/guide/eager">TensorFlow 2.0 supports both modes</a>.</li>
<li>Interestingly, some tensor computation libraries (e.g. <a href="https://thinc.ai/">Thinc</a>) don’t even
construct an explicit computational graph: they represent it as <a href="https://thinc.ai/docs/concept">chained higher-order
functions</a>.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Tensor computation libraries can also differ in what they want to use the computational graph
<em>for</em> - for example, are we aiming to do things that basically amount to running the
computational graph in a “different mode”, or are we aiming to modify the computational graph
itself?
<ul>
<li>Almost all tensor computation libraries support autodifferentiation in some capacity (either
forward-mode, backward-mode, or both).</li>
<li>Obviously, how you represent the computational graph and what you want to use it for are very
related questions! For example, if you want to be able to represent aribtrary computation as a
graph, you’ll have to handle control flow like if-else statements or for-loops - this leads to
common gotchas with <a href="https://jax.readthedocs.io/en/latest/notebooks/Common_Gotchas_in_JAX.html#%F0%9F%94%AA-Control-Flow">using Python for-loops in
JAX</a>
or needing to use <a href="https://discuss.pytorch.org/t/can-you-have-for-loops-in-the-forward-prop/68295"><code>torch.nn.ModuleList</code> in for-loops with
PyTorch</a>.</li>
<li>Some tensor computation libraries (e.g. <a href="https://github.com/Theano/Theano">Theano</a> and it’s
fork, <a href="https://theano-pymc.readthedocs.io/en/latest/index.html">Theano-PyMC</a>) aim to <a href="https://theano-pymc.readthedocs.io/en/latest/extending/optimization.html">optimize
the computational graph
itself</a>, for which an
<a href="#an-observation-on-static-graphs-and-theano">explicit graph is necessary</a>.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Finally, tensor computation libraries can also differ in how they execute code.
<ul>
<li>All tensor computation libraries run on CPU, but the strength of GPU and TPU support is a major
differentiator among tensor computation libraries.</li>
<li>Another differentiator is how tensor computation libraries compile code to be executed on
hardware. For example, do they use JIT compilation or not? Do they use “vanilla” C or CUDA
compilers, or <a href="https://tensorflow.google.cn/xla">the XLA compiler for machine-learning specific
code</a>?</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="a-zoo-of-tensor-computation-libraries">A Zoo of Tensor Computation Libraries</h2>
<p>Having outlined the basic similarities and differences of tensor computation libraries, I think
it’ll be helpful to go through several of the popular libraries as examples. I’ve tried to link to
the relevant documentation where possible.<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup></p>
<h3 id="pytorch"><a href="https://pytorch.org/">PyTorch</a></h3>
<ol>
<li>How is the computational graph represented and built?
<ul>
<li>PyTorch dynamically builds (and eagerly evaluates) an explicit computational graph. For more
detail on how this is done, check out <a href="https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/notes/autograd.html">the PyTorch docs on autograd
mechanics</a>.</li>
<li>For more on how PyTorch computational graphs, see <a href="https://jdhao.github.io/2017/11/12/pytorch-computation-graph/"><code>jdhao</code>’s introductory blog post on
computational graphs in
PyTorch</a>.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>What is the computational graph used for?
<ul>
<li>To quote the <a href="https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/index.html">PyTorch docs</a>, “PyTorch is an
optimized tensor library for deep learning using GPUs and CPUs” - as such, the main focus is on
<a href="https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/notes/autograd.html">autodifferentiation</a>.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>How does the library ensure “best execution” for computation?
<ul>
<li>PyTorch has <a href="https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/notes/cuda.html">native GPU support</a> via CUDA.</li>
<li>PyTorch also has support for TPU through projects like
<a href="https://github.com/pytorch/xla">PyTorch/XLA</a> and
<a href="https://www.pytorchlightning.ai/">PyTorch-Lightning</a>.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="jax"><a href="https://jax.readthedocs.io/en/latest/">JAX</a></h3>
<ol>
<li>How is the computational graph represented and built?
<ul>
<li>Instead of building an explicit computational graph to compute gradients, JAX simply supplies a
<code>grad()</code> that returns the gradient function of any supplied function. As such, there is
technically no concept of a computational graph - only pure (i.e. stateless and
side-effect-free) functions and their gradients.</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://sjmielke.com/jax-purify.htm">Sabrina Mielke summarizes the situation very well</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>PyTorch builds up a graph as you compute the forward pass, and one call to <code>backward()</code> on
some “result” node then augments each intermediate node in the graph with the gradient of the
result node with respect to that intermediate node. JAX on the other hand makes you express
your computation as a Python function, and by transforming it with <code>grad()</code> gives you a
gradient function that you can evaluate like your computation function — but instead of the
output it gives you the gradient of the output with respect to (by default) the first
parameter that your function took as input.</p>
</blockquote>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>What is the computational graph used for?
<ul>
<li>According to the <a href="https://jax.readthedocs.io/en/latest/notebooks/quickstart.html">JAX quickstart</a>,
JAX bills itself as “NumPy on the CPU, GPU, and TPU, with great automatic differentiation for
high-performance machine learning research”. Hence, its focus is heavily on
autodifferentiation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>How does the library ensure “best execution” for computation?
<ul>
<li>
<p>This is best explained by quoting the <a href="https://jax.readthedocs.io/en/latest/notebooks/quickstart.html">JAX quickstart</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>JAX uses XLA to compile and run your NumPy code on […] GPUs and TPUs. Compilation happens
under the hood by default, with library calls getting just-in-time compiled and executed. But
JAX even lets you just-in-time compile your own Python functions into XLA-optimized kernels
[…] Compilation and automatic differentiation can be composed arbitrarily […]</p>
</blockquote>
</li>
<li>
<p>For more detail on JAX’s four-function API (<code>grad</code>, <code>jit</code>, <code>vmap</code> and <code>pmap</code>), see
<a href="http://alexminnaar.com/2020/08/15/jax-overview.html">Alex Minaar’s overview of how JAX works</a>.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="theano"><a href="https://theano-pymc.readthedocs.io/en/latest/">Theano</a></h3>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> the <a href="https://github.com/Theano/Theano">original Theano</a> (maintained by
<a href="https://mila.quebec/en/">MILA</a>) has been discontinued, and the PyMC developers have forked the
project: <a href="https://github.com/pymc-devs/Theano-PyMC">Theano-PyMC</a> (soon to be renamed Aesara). I’ll
discuss both the original and forked projects below.</p>
</blockquote>
<ol>
<li>How is the computational graph represented and built?
<ul>
<li>Theano statically builds (and lazily evaluates) an explicit computational graph.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>What is the computational graph used for?
<ul>
<li>Theano is unique among tensor computation libraries in that it places more emphasis on
reasoning about the computational graph itself. In other words, while Theano has <a href="https://theano-pymc.readthedocs.io/en/latest/library/gradient.html">strong
support for
autodifferentiation</a>,
running the computation and computing gradients isn’t the be-all and end-all: Theano has an
entire module for <a href="https://theano-pymc.readthedocs.io/en/latest/optimizations.html">optimizing the computational graph
itself</a>, and makes it fairly
straightforward to compile the …</li></ul></li></ol></section></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://eigenfoo.xyz/tensor-computation-libraries/">https://eigenfoo.xyz/tensor-computation-libraries/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://eigenfoo.xyz/tensor-computation-libraries/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25435028</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 20:46:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Publicly share your stock portfolio]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 22 | Comments 6 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25434362">thread link</a>) | @probe
<br/>
December 15, 2020 | https://withlaguna.com/create-your-page | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://withlaguna.com/create-your-page">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div><p>Use Laguna to import your trades automatically, notify followers, and grow your audience</p><div><p><a href="https://access.withlaguna.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Create Your Page</a><a href="https://rob.withlaguna.com/">See Sample Page</a></p></div></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://withlaguna.com/create-your-page</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25434362</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 19:58:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Asset forfeiture is just theft]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 57 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25433867">thread link</a>) | @samizdis
<br/>
December 15, 2020 | https://pluralistic.net/2020/12/15/iowa-vs-16-tons-of-bricks/#stand-and-delivery | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://pluralistic.net/2020/12/15/iowa-vs-16-tons-of-bricks/#stand-and-delivery">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-1710">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	
	
	<div>
		<p><!--
Tags:
dma, dsa, pornhub, gatekeepers, payment processors, porn, sex workers, censorship, csam, civil forfeiture, civil asset forfeiture, highway robbery, eu, competition, trustbusting, voting, electronic voting, blockchain, distributed sudoku

Summary:
Pornhub and payment processors; Asset forfeiture is just theft; EU competition rules have real teeth; Blockchain voting is bullshit

URL:
https://pluralistic.net/2020/12/15/iowa-vs-16-tons-of-bricks/ 

Title:
Pluralistic: 15 Dec 2020 iowa-vs-16-tons-of-bricks

Bullet:
🥵

Separator:
_,.-'~'-.,__,.-'~'-.,__,.-'~'-.,__,.-'~'-.,__,.-'~'-.,_

Top Sources:
Today's top sources: Bruce Schneier (schneier.com/), Naked Capitalism (https://www.nakedcapitalism.com/).

--><br>
<a href="https://pluralistic.net/2020/12/15/iowa-vs-16-tons-of-bricks/"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/craphound.com/images/15Dec2020.jpg?w=840&amp;ssl=1" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-src="https://i2.wp.com/craphound.com/images/15Dec2020.jpg?w=840&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></a></p>

<ul>
<li attrs="{'class': ['xToC']}"><a attrs="{'href': '#xslug'}" href="https://pluralistic.net/2020/12/15/iowa-vs-16-tons-of-bricks/%20#chokepoints">Pornhub and payment processors</a>: No one elected Visa and Mastercard.
</li>
<li attrs="{'class': ['xToC']}"><a attrs="{'href': '#xslug'}" href="https://pluralistic.net/2020/12/15/iowa-vs-16-tons-of-bricks/%20#stand-and-delivery">Asset forfeiture is just theft</a>: Cops steal more than robbers.
</li>
<li attrs="{'class': ['xToC']}"><a attrs="{'href': '#xslug'}" href="https://pluralistic.net/2020/12/15/iowa-vs-16-tons-of-bricks/%20#dsm">EU competition rules have real teeth</a>: The DSA and DMA are unveiled.
</li>
<li attrs="{'class': ['xToC']}"><a attrs="{'href': '#xslug'}" href="https://pluralistic.net/2020/12/15/iowa-vs-16-tons-of-bricks/%20#sudoku-voting">Blockchain voting is bullshit</a>: Yet another problem blockchain doesn't, can't and won't solve.
</li>
<li attrs="{'class': ['xToC']}"><a attrs="{'href': '#xslug'}" href="https://pluralistic.net/2020/12/15/iowa-vs-16-tons-of-bricks/%20#retro">This day in history</a>: 2005, 2010, 2015
</li>
<li attrs="{'class': ['xToC']}"><a attrs="{'href': '#xslug'}" href="https://pluralistic.net/2020/12/15/iowa-vs-16-tons-of-bricks/%20#bragsheet">Colophon</a>: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading
</li>
</ul>

<hr>
<p><a name="chokepoints"></a><br>
<img src="https://i2.wp.com/craphound.com/images/cuAEzvxi.png?w=840&amp;ssl=1" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-src="https://i2.wp.com/craphound.com/images/cuAEzvxi.png?w=840&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></p>

<p>Today, Pornhub took down all videos from unverified accounts after a New York Times report documented instances of nonconsensual pornography and child sexual abuse material on the service.</p>
<p>But the Times editorial isn't what spurred the shutdown: rather, it was the decision by Visa and Mastercard to withdrawn Pornhub's payment processing that prompted Pornhub to take action.</p>
<p>You may count that as a win. No one with any kind of moral center endorses nonconsensual pornography, especially when it involves children, and the less there is out there, the better the world is. I agree.</p>
<p>But we should also be worried about the growing monopolization of payment processing, and the role that payment processors are coming to play as gatekeepers for all kinds of activities.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/12/visa-and-mastercard-are-trying-dictate-what-you-can-watch-pornhub">https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/12/visa-and-mastercard-are-trying-dictate-what-you-can-watch-pornhub</a></p>
<p>Mastercard and Visa are not qualified to make those calls. More importantly, no one elected them to make those calls. No law requires them to make those calls, and any law that tried would likely be unconstitutional.</p>
<p>If you want a sex industry based on consent and dignity, this should doubly worry you. After all, the first group of people shut down by payment processors' arbitrary judgements about what speech should and should exist were independent sex-workers.</p>
<p><a href="https://newrepublic.com/article/160488/nick-kristof-holy-war-pornhub">https://newrepublic.com/article/160488/nick-kristof-holy-war-pornhub</a></p>
<p>It took years for the payment processors to work their way up to the monopolistic, sprawling porn empire behind Pornhub – a Canadian company called Mindgeek that maintains the pretense that it is headquartered in Luxembourg,a notorious tax-evasion jurisdiction.</p>
<p>There's an old saw that the sex industry are early tech adopters. That's not quite true – rather, people with disfavored views are the first people for whom it's worth figuring out new technologies, since the old ones are unavailable to them.</p>
<p>Porn got into home films because most big cinemas wouldn't screen pornography. They got into VHS because it was easier to duplicate than film. They got into the net because it offered access without social costs of being seen in the adult section of the video rental place.</p>
<p>But while pornographers aren't early adopters, they ARE leading indicators. Pornographers' fights with novel censorship tactics are also trial-runs for using those tactics against OTHER people – and payment processors have already been pressed into service.</p>
<p>Visa and Mastercard threats have been used to block or shut down journalism, self-published books, dating services.</p>
<p>Mindgeek and Pornhub don't need our sympathy, but hard cases make bad law.</p>
<p>With only a few payment processors online, our ability to engage in legal conduct will always be at the mercy of Visa, Mastercard and a handful of others.</p>
<hr>
<p><a name="stand-and-delivery"></a><br>
<img src="https://i1.wp.com/craphound.com/images/Highway_Robbery-Clean-6.jpg?w=840&amp;ssl=1" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-src="https://i1.wp.com/craphound.com/images/Highway_Robbery-Clean-6.jpg?w=840&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></p>

<p>If you're charged with a crime, the prosecutor has to prove you did it beyond a reasonable doubt; when it's a civil case, it's up to YOU to prove based on "preponderance of evidence" that you are innocent. A real difference, especially when the accused is an inanimate object.</p>
<p>In civil asset forfeiture, police seize the goods of people they suspect of criminal activity – without the need for a charge or conviction – and sue that property (i.e. "State of Iowa v Six Tons of Bricks") and you pay a lawyer to prove your property's innocence.</p>
<p>If your lawyer loses (or if you can't afford a lawyer), you lose your stuff, and the cops get to keep it or sell it and keep the money as an off-the-books black budget. Cops love this money – it lets them buy military surveillance gear.</p>
<p><a href="https://revealnews.org/article/chicago-and-los-angeles-have-used-dirt-box-surveillance-for-a-decade/">https://revealnews.org/article/chicago-and-los-angeles-have-used-dirt-box-surveillance-for-a-decade/</a></p>
<p>But not just that: one sheriff stole $70k from his townspeople and used the money to buy a muscle car that he only drove to and from work.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.ajc.com/news/local-govt--politics/feds-want-reimbursement-for-gwinnett-sheriff-70k-muscle-car/zkOidGb5oRfCHGO5RlZGsL/">https://www.ajc.com/news/local-govt–politics/feds-want-reimbursement-for-gwinnett-sheriff-70k-muscle-car/zkOidGb5oRfCHGO5RlZGsL/</a></p>
<p>City attorneys have worked with cops in the past to draw up "wish lists" of stuff they'd like to steal. The cops then nose around the owners of that stuff, looking for a pretence to seize it.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2014/11/10/us/police-use-department-wish-list-when-deciding-which-assets-to-seize.html">https://www.nytimes.com/2014/11/10/us/police-use-department-wish-list-when-deciding-which-assets-to-seize.html</a></p>
<p>Indeed, police departments future budgets projected their forfeiture revenues for years to come, effectively setting a quota for how much they had to steal from people each year:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/investigations/dc-police-plan-for-future-seizure-proceeds-years-in-advance-in-city-budget-documents/2014/11/15/7025edd2-6b76-11e4-b053-65cea7903f2e_story.html">https://www.washingtonpost.com/investigations/dc-police-plan-for-future-seizure-proceeds-years-in-advance-in-city-budget-documents/2014/11/15/7025edd2-6b76-11e4-b053-65cea7903f2e_story.html</a></p>
<p>By 2014, US police were stealing more from the people they were sworn to protect than all the nation's burglars combined.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.armstrongeconomics.com/international-news/north_america/americas-current-economy/police-civil-asset-forfeitures-exceed-all-burglaries-in-2014/">https://www.armstrongeconomics.com/international-news/north_america/americas-current-economy/police-civil-asset-forfeitures-exceed-all-burglaries-in-2014/</a></p>
<p>No wonder that by 2015 Congress ended the program (don't worry, Trump reinstated and expanded it):</p>
<p><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2015/12/23/the-feds-just-shut-down-a-huge-program-that-lets-cops-take-your-stuff-and-keep-it/">https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2015/12/23/the-feds-just-shut-down-a-huge-program-that-lets-cops-take-your-stuff-and-keep-it/</a></p>
<p>Long after the program was ended, cops insisted that without forfeiture, they lacked the "incentive" to fight crime:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.greenvilleonline.com/story/news/taken/2019/02/03/sc-civil-forfeiture-police-defend-practice-say-funds-essential-law-enforcement/2746412002/">https://www.greenvilleonline.com/story/news/taken/2019/02/03/sc-civil-forfeiture-police-defend-practice-say-funds-essential-law-enforcement/2746412002/</a></p>
<p>They predicted that without forfeiture, police budgets would be too strained to fight crime, while criminals' coffers would swell. That was the scare-story New Mexico's legislature heard in 2015 when the state ended civil forfeiture.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/police-say-seizing-property-without-trial-helps-keep-crime-down-a-new-study-shows-theyre-wrong">https://www.propublica.org/article/police-say-seizing-property-without-trial-helps-keep-crime-down-a-new-study-shows-theyre-wrong</a></p>
<p>Five years later, the verdict is in, and the cops' predictions were wrong. A new report from The Institute for Justice shows that NM experienced no rise in crime, no drop in arrests, and "arrest/offense rates consistent with trends in two neighboring states, CO and TX."</p>
<p><a href="https://ij.org/report/policing-for-profit-3/">https://ij.org/report/policing-for-profit-3/</a></p>
<p>The study shows that far from being an instrument to return stolen goods or make restitution to crime victims, forfeiture is a way to fatten police budgets and personally enrich police officials. The seizures are mostly small-dollar amounts (not drug dealer money).</p>
<p>The larger seizures tell an even worse story: they include numerous instances in which a family home was seized because an underage offender sold small quantities of drugs from the premises – leaving families to spend fortunes defending their homes, often unsuccessfully.</p>
<hr>
<p><a name="dsm"></a><br>
<img src="https://i2.wp.com/craphound.com/images/flag_yellow_high-7.jpg?w=840&amp;ssl=1" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-src="https://i2.wp.com/craphound.com/images/flag_yellow_high-7.jpg?w=840&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></p>

<p>Back in September, we got a glimpse of upcoming EU tech competition rules, courtesy of a leak from the European Commission; they set out an ambitious set of rules on mergers, self-dealing, surveillance, and interoperability.</p>
<p><a href="https://pluralistic.net/2020/09/30/death-to-all-monopoly/#whither-structural-separation">https://pluralistic.net/2020/09/30/death-to-all-monopoly/#whither-structural-separation</a></p>
<p>The proposal wasn't perfect, but it was still exciting and encouraging, especially the interoperability proposals. Interop, after all, is the judo that every one of today's tech giants used to beat the companies that came before them.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2019/07/samba-versus-smb-adversarial-interoperability-judo-network-effects">https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2019/07/samba-versus-smb-adversarial-interoperability-judo-network-effects</a></p>
<p>Today, the Commission published the first public draft of its rules (these need to get through the EU Parliament and the Council of national governments):</p>
<p><a href="https://ec.europa.eu/info/strategy/priorities-2019-2024/europe-fit-digital-age/digital-markets-act-ensuring-fair-and-open-digital-markets_en">https://ec.europa.eu/info/strategy/priorities-2019-2024/europe-fit-digital-age/digital-markets-act-ensuring-fair-and-open-digital-markets_en</a></p>
<p>The Digital Markets Act and its companion, the Digital Services Act, are the first major update to EU e-commerce rules in nearly two decades. A LOT has changed since the E-Commerce Directive!</p>
<p>For a quick overview, I recommend my EFF colleagues Christoph Schmon and Karen Gullo's analysis:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/12/european-commissions-proposed-regulations-require-platforms-let-users-appeal">https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/12/european-commissions-proposed-regulations-require-platforms-let-users-appeal</a></p>
<p>The good news: the proposal requires due process for content removal – not a system where filters remove your content in an eyeblink and then you spend months or years in autoresponder hell trying to get it back up.</p>
<p>It doesn't require giant companies to police their users' speech, a rule that has led to mass-scale censorship, especially targeted against marginalized people who lack the platform and resources to complain when they get blocked.</p>
<p>It includes <em>very</em> steep penalties for companies that don't comply (up to 6% of annual global revenue), and a means to reach beyond EU borders to sanction companies that do business in the EU – both measures are powerful and potentially dangerous, and both need more specifics.</p>
<p>One disappointment: the interoperability measures have been weakened since September's leaks, though Article 6 of the Digital Markets Act is still a strict and far-reaching set of pro-competition rules with some look-in for interop.</p>
<p>Here's some A6 highlights, rules for the largest tech companies ("gatekeeper companies"):</p>
<ul>
<li>A ban on combining platform data with data from third parties and on automatically logging users from one service on a platform to other ones
</li>
<li>
<p>A requirement to let businesses on the platform offer services and pricing that directly competes with the platform owner</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A requirement to let businesses on the platform do subscription and payment with users on their own terms, without having to use the platform</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A ban on blocking businesses on the platform from complaining about abuses to regulators</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A ban on …</p></li></ul></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://pluralistic.net/2020/12/15/iowa-vs-16-tons-of-bricks/#stand-and-delivery">https://pluralistic.net/2020/12/15/iowa-vs-16-tons-of-bricks/#stand-and-delivery</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://pluralistic.net/2020/12/15/iowa-vs-16-tons-of-bricks/#stand-and-delivery</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25433867</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 19:16:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Estimated 1.56B face masks will have entered oceans in 2020]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 122 | Comments 155 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25433475">thread link</a>) | @Element_
<br/>
December 15, 2020 | https://oceansasia.org/covid-19-facemasks/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://oceansasia.org/covid-19-facemasks/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content-wrap">

		
		<div id="primary">

			
			<div id="content">

				
				
<article>

	
<div itemprop="text">

	
			<div data-elementor-type="wp-page" data-elementor-id="847" data-elementor-settings="[]">
						<div>
							<div>
							<section data-id="3bc37af" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="b3f8c7c" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="11406f6" data-element_type="widget" data-settings="{&quot;aspect_ratio&quot;:&quot;169&quot;}" data-widget_type="video.default">
				<div>
					<p>
			<iframe allowfullscreen="" title="vimeo Video Player" src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/487781778?color&amp;autopause=0&amp;loop=0&amp;muted=0&amp;title=1&amp;portrait=1&amp;byline=1#t="></iframe>		</p>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section data-id="b9da48f" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="0a02902" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="1d6a43b" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<p>
			<h2>Estimated 1.56 billion face masks will have entered oceans in 2020 - OceansAsia Report  
For Immediate Release: December 7, 2020
</h2>		</p>
				</div>
				<div data-id="e99a48e" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div>
					<div><p>Our oceans will be flooded with an estimated 1.56 billion face masks in 2020 says a report released today by Hong-Kong-based marine conservation organization OceansAsia. This will result in an additional 4,680 to 6,240 metric tonnes of marine plastic pollution, says the report, entitled “Masks on the Beach: The Impact of COVID-19 on Marine Plastic Pollution.” These masks will take as long as 450 years to break down, slowly turning into&nbsp; micro plastics while negatively impacting marine wildlife and ecosystems.</p>
<p>The report used a global production estimate of 52 billion masks being manufactured in 2020, a conservative loss rate of 3%, and the average weight of 3 to 4 grams for a single-use polypropylene surgical face mask to arrive at the estimate.&nbsp;</p>
<p>“The 1.56 billion face masks that will likely enter our oceans in 2020 are just the tip of the iceberg,” says Dr. Teale Phelps Bondaroff, Director of Research for OceansAsia, and lead author of the report. “The 4,680 to 6,240 metric tonnes of face masks are just a small fraction of the estimated 8 to 12 million metric tonnes of plastic that enter our oceans each year.”</p></div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div data-id="7f1289a" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div>
					<p><img width="1024" height="384" src="https://oceansasia.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/facemasks2-1024x384.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="https://oceansasia.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/facemasks2-1024x384.jpg 1024w, https://oceansasia.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/facemasks2-300x113.jpg 300w, https://oceansasia.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/facemasks2-768x288.jpg 768w, https://oceansasia.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/facemasks2-1536x576.jpg 1536w, https://oceansasia.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/facemasks2-2048x768.jpg 2048w, https://oceansasia.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/facemasks2-600x225.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px">											</p>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div data-id="793f0a3" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div>
					<div><p>Plastic consumption, which has been steadily rising for years, increased significantly as a result of the COVID-19 pandemic.</p><p>“Hygiene concerns and greater reliance on take-away food has led to increased use of plastics, particularly plastic packaging,” says Gary Stokes, Director of Operations of OceansAsia. “Meanwhile, a number of measures designed to reduce plastic consumption, like single-use plastic bag bans, have been delayed, paused, or rolled back.”</p><p>The use of PPE, in particular face masks, has become a common tool used in preventing the spread of the virus, with many jurisdictions mandating the wearing of masks in public. The production of PPE has expanded in an attempt to meet skyrocketing demand, and PPE waste has also increased dramatically.&nbsp;</p><p>Single-use face masks are made from a variety of meltblown plastics and are difficult to recycle due to both composition and risk of contamination and infection. They enter oceans when they are littered, when waste management systems are inadequate or non-existent, or when these systems become overwhelmed due to increased volumes of waste.</p><p>“Marine plastic pollution is devastating our oceans,” says Gary Stokes, Operations Director of OceansAsia. “Plastic pollution kills an estimated 100,000 marine mammals and turtles, over a million seabirds, and even greater numbers of fish, invertebrates and other animals each year. It also negatively impacts fisheries and the tourism industry, and costs the global economy an estimated $13 billion USD per year.”</p></div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section data-id="0dff72a" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="9ffb5fd" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						
				<div data-id="6dd1cc3" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div>
					<div><p>The report asks people to wear reusable masks whenever possible, dispose of masks responsibly and reduce their overall consumption of single-use plastic. It also calls on governments to:</p><ul><li>Implement policies designed to encourage the use of reusable masks, such as releasing guidelines regarding the proper manufacture and use of reusable masks.</li><li>Foster innovation and the development of sustainable alternatives to single-use plastic masks.</li><li>Discourage littering by increasing fines, and educate the public about responsible ways to dispose of masks.&nbsp;</li><li>Repair and improve waste management systems to reduce losses and spillage.&nbsp;</li></ul><p>“It is critical that we work to reduce our use of single-use plastics, and we all have a role to play,” says Dr. Phelps Bondaroff. “There are reusable and sustainable options for almost every single single-use plastic item. Please wear a reusable mask, unless absolutely necessary, and be sure to dispose of all masks responsibly.</p></div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section data-id="8681e54" data-element_type="section">
						
		</section>
				<section data-id="c420295" data-element_type="section">
						
		</section>
						</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		
	
</div>

</article>

				
			</div><!-- #content -->

			
		</div><!-- #primary -->

		
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://oceansasia.org/covid-19-facemasks/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25433475</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 18:45:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[REST vs. GraphQL – A search for evidence on which is better]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 160 | Comments 204 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25432233">thread link</a>) | @gsvclass
<br/>
December 15, 2020 | https://42papers.com/p/rest-vs-graphql-a-controlled-experiment | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://42papers.com/p/rest-vs-graphql-a-controlled-experiment">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://42papers.com/p/rest-vs-graphql-a-controlled-experiment</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25432233</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 17:08:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Learn Machine Learning and Deep Learning: A Guide for Software Engineers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 56 | Comments 14 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25431821">thread link</a>) | @renanmoura
<br/>
December 15, 2020 | https://renanmf.com/machine-learning-and-deep-learning-software-engineers/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://renanmf.com/machine-learning-and-deep-learning-software-engineers/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2>Introduction</h2><p>The subject of Artificial Intelligence piques my interest and I’m constantly studying and trying new things in this field.</p><p>It is notorious how the technologies related to Natural Language Processing, Computer Vision and such have emerged and evolved into solutions used by millions of users every day.</p><p>Even though people use the term "Artificial Intelligence", we are still far away from something as advanced as a Skynet from the Terminator movies.</p><p>The most common subfield of AI used today is the one called Machine Learning, which, in its turn, has Deep Learning as subfield steeply growing every day for quite some time now.</p><p>In this guide, I aim to describe a path to follow for software engineers to begin understanding how Machine Learning works and how to apply it to your projects.</p><p>Yeah, you can just go to Google API’s or Amazon and pick some magical API to do Speech Recognition for you, but the value of knowing how it works, why it works and even more, how to make your own API as a Service and tune it to your specific needs is incredible.</p><p>Remember, as a developer, every tool is a new power.</p><p>I’ve read, watched and gone through all these resources until the end, even got a paid certification for some, even though it is not necessary to learn, I find myself more engaged to finish when I have some deadline and assessment to prove I actually learned the material.</p><p>Let’s dive into the topics.</p><p>Python is the main language these days when working with Data Science, Machine Learning, and Deep Learning.</p><p>If you need a crash course on Python, here is your guide: <a href="https://renanmf.com/the-python-guide-for-beginners/">The Python Guide for Beginners</a>.</p><h2>The Basics: Math!</h2><p>Maybe you never had the chance to study some college-level math, or you did study it but you can’t remember most of the stuff because JavaScript and CSS took all the memory of those topics away.</p><p>There are 3 topics you must know beforehand, or at least have a decent grasp of to follow any good material on ML and DL: Linear Algebra, Calculus and Statistics.</p><p>If you’d like to go deep in learning the math needed to ML and DL, you can look for MIT OpenCourseWare classes like Professor Strang’s renowned <a href="https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/mathematics/18-06-linear-algebra-spring-2010/">Linear Algebra</a> class.</p><p>I’ve watched it in college in parallel with my regular class and it is very good.</p><p>But, let’s face it, most people have no time for that or the patience.</p><p>So I will give you the crash course for the 3 topics mentioned above.</p><h3>Linear Algebra</h3><p>Just watch the whole series <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fNk_zzaMoSs&amp;list=PLZHQObOWTQDPD3MizzM2xVFitgF8hE_ab">Essence of Linear Algebra</a> from the Youtube channel 3Blue1Brown.</p><p>The guy makes visual explanations of once hard concepts incredibly easy!</p><p>It is very far in terms of content compared to Professor Strang’s, but it’s enough, to begin with, and you can go after other topics as you advance in ML and DL.</p><h3>Calculus</h3><p>Guess what?</p><p>3Blue1Brown also has a whole series on Calculus on Youtube for you to watch for free: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WUvTyaaNkzM&amp;list=PLZHQObOWTQDMsr9K-rj53DwVRMYO3t5Yr">Essence of Calculus</a>.</p><p>Again, he is very good at giving you the intuition of why and how rather than just throw some random equations on your face.</p><h3>Statistics</h3><p>This is a whole field that, in my opinion, you can learn as needed, a good reference is <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Practical-Statistics-Data-Scientists-Essential/dp/1491952962">Practical Statistics for Data Scientists: 50 Essential Concepts</a>.</p><p>An objective book with some good examples for every concept.</p><p>Fast to read too.</p><p>As the title implies, it is more suitable for Data Scientists, but understanding some basics of statistics is always good and this is what this is book is for.</p><p>You won’t become a statistician after reading it, but you will learn some good stuff.</p><h2>The Bypassed: Machine Learning</h2><p>Everybody wants to jump straight into Deep Learning and be the cool guy training a single model for a week on a 12GB GPU.</p><p>But to get Deep Learning right, you need to go through Machine Learning first!</p><h3>Start from the beginning</h3><p>The concepts, the train of thought, the "feeling" of how things work start here and there is no one else more capable of teaching those concepts than Professor Andrew Ng in his course <a href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/machine-learning">Machine Learning</a>.</p><p>You may think this course is old and outdated, well, technology-wise, maybe, but conceptually-wise, it is better than anything else out there.</p><p>Professor Ng makes it easy to understand the math applied in every technique he teaches and gives you a solid understanding of what happens underneath in a very short and concise course.</p><p>All the exercises are made in Octave, a free version of Matlab of sorts, and you finish the course implementing your own Neural Network!</p><p>The syntax in Octave is easy to grasp for any programmer, so don’t let that be a barrier for you.</p><p>Once you finish the course, you will have implemented all the major algorithms and will be able to solve several prediction problems.</p><h3>Random Forests</h3><p>I said all the major algorithms, right?</p><p>Actually, there is but one flaw in Andrew Ng’s course, he doesn’t cover Random Forests.</p><p>An awesome complement to his course is fast.ai’s <a href="http://course18.fast.ai/ml">Introduction to Machine Learning for Coders</a>.</p><p>Jeremy Howard goes super practical on the missing piece in Ng’s course covering a topic that is, for many classical problems, the best solution out there.</p><p>Fast.ai’s approach is what is called Top-Down, meaning they show you how to solve the problem and then explain why it worked, which is the total opposite of what we are used to in school.</p><p>Jeremy also uses real-world tools and libraries, so you learn by coding in industry-tested solutions.</p><h2>Deep Learning</h2><p>Finally!</p><p>The reason why we are all here, Deep Learning!</p><p>Again, the best resource for it is Professor Ng’s course, actually, a series of courses.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.deeplearning.ai/deep-learning-specialization/">Deep Learning Specialization</a> is composed of 5 courses total going from the basics and evolving on specific topics such as language, images, and time-series data.</p><p>One nice thing is that he continues from the very end of his classical Machine Learning course, so it just feels like an extension of the first course.</p><p>The math, the concepts, the notion of how and why it works, he delivers it all very concisely like few I’ve seen.</p><p>The only drawback is that he uses <a href="https://www.tensorflow.org/">Tensorflow</a> 1.x (Google’s DL Framework) in this course, but that’s minimal detail in my opinion since the explanations and exercises are so well delivered.</p><p>You can pick up the most recent version of the framework relatively easy and to do so there is the final piece of this guide, a book.</p><h3>Too much stuff, give me something faster</h3><p>This book might be the only thing you need to start, it is Aurélien Géron’s <a href="https://www.amazon.com.br/Hands-Machine-Learning-Scikit-Learn-TensorFlow-ebook/dp/B07XGF2G87">Hands-On Machine Learning with Scikit-Learn, Keras, and TensorFlow: Concepts, Tools, and Techniques to Build Intelligent Systems</a>.</p><p>It covers a lot, from classical Machine Learning to the most recent Deep Learning topics. Good examples and exercises using industry-grade frameworks and libraries.</p><p>I dare say that, if you are really in a rush, you can skip everything I said before and just go for the book.</p><p>You will miss a good amount of information contained on the other resources mentioned, but the practical and actionable knowledge from Géron’s book is enough to work on many ideas for your next project.</p><p>If you feel limited after only reading the book, go back and study the rest of the material, it will fill in the gaps you might have and give you a more solid understanding.</p><h2>What about Framework X or Y?</h2><p>"Hey, I’ve heard about PyTorch and that other framework or library X everybody talks about".</p><p>As a Software Engineer, you know better than anyone how fast technology evolves.</p><p>Don’t go crazy for that, after you learn the basics in this guide, you can easily go, for instance, on <a href="https://pytorch.org/">PyTorch</a> documentation or any other library or framework of sorts and learn how to use it in a week or two.</p><p>The techniques, the concepts, are all the same, it is only a matter of syntax and application or even tastes that you might have for any given tool.</p><h2>Conclusion</h2><p>To wrap it up, I want to say that, even though it might seem a lot, I tried to remove all the noise and at the end of the process, you will feel confident that you understand what is happening behind the curtains, the jargons and even be able to read some papers published in the field to keep up with the latest advances.</p><p>TL;DR Here is the list of resources mentioned in sequence:</p><ul><li><a href="https://renanmf.com/the-python-guide-for-beginners/">The Python Guide for Beginners</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fNk_zzaMoSs&amp;list=PLZHQObOWTQDPD3MizzM2xVFitgF8hE_ab">Essence of Linear Algebra</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WUvTyaaNkzM&amp;list=PLZHQObOWTQDMsr9K-rj53DwVRMYO3t5Yr">Essence of Calculus</a></li><li><a href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/machine-learning">Machine Learning</a></li><li><a href="http://course18.fast.ai/ml">Introduction to Machine Learning for Coders</a></li><li><a href="https://www.deeplearning.ai/deep-learning-specialization/">Deep Learning Specialization</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com.br/Hands-Machine-Learning-Scikit-Learn-TensorFlow-ebook/dp/B07XGF2G87">Hands-On Machine Learning with Scikit-Learn, Keras, and TensorFlow: Concepts, Tools, and Techniques to Build Intelligent Systems</a></li></ul></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://renanmf.com/machine-learning-and-deep-learning-software-engineers/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25431821</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 16:32:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Lonely people's brains are different due to excess of imaginary social contact]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 386 | Comments 225 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25431817">thread link</a>) | @Bologo
<br/>
December 15, 2020 | https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/lonely-people-have-a-unique-brain-signature-perhaps-due-to-so-much-imagined-social-contact/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/lonely-people-have-a-unique-brain-signature-perhaps-due-to-so-much-imagined-social-contact/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-5697" role="main"><div><div><div><p>A <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41467-020-20039-w" target="_blank">new study of almost 40,000 adults</a> has found that the brains of lonely people differ from those of people who are not lonely, in significant and detectable ways. <span data-ez-name="psychnewsdaily_com-medrectangle-3"></span></p><p>This loneliness “signature” consists of variations in the volume of different brain regions, and the way those brain regions communicate. And these variations may be related to the typical thinking patterns of lonely people, which include for example higher than average amounts of reminiscence and imaginary conversations.</p><p>The study compared the MRI scans of people who said they “often” feel lonely with the scans of people do not report feeling that way. The data comes from the <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.ukbiobank.ac.uk/" target="_blank">UK Biobank</a>, which is an open-source database containing genetic and health information from about half a million people in the UK.</p><p>The 38,701 participants consisted of 47.5% men and 52.5% women. Their ages ranged from 40 – 69, with an average age of 55. About 13% of them answered “yes” to the question “Do you often feel lonely?” Of those who answered yes, about 39% were men, and 61% women.</p><p>The new paper appeared today (December 15) in <em><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.nature.com/ncomms" target="_blank">Nature Communications</a></em>.<span data-ez-name="psychnewsdaily_com-medrectangle-4"></span></p><h2>Lonely people and the default network</h2><p>The researchers behind the study, from McGill University in Montreal, found that the key differences involved the brain’s “<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Default_mode_network" target="_blank">default network</a>.” This network is responsible for a wide range of mental processes that take place when the brain is at rest. These processes are often referred to as the “inner voice”, or the “self.”</p><p>The default network plays a crucial role in memory, social cognition (i.e. thinking about other people), and mental time travel (“What will I do tomorrow?”). It involves the medial prefrontal cortex, and the posterior cingulate cortex, along with a number of other structures. It is also responsible for hallucinations and internal imagery.</p><p>The researchers discovered, unexpectedly, that volumes in several of these default network regions were larger in lonely people. They also found equally unexpected patterns of positive associations between some of these regions.</p><h2>Feeling lonely: the typical thought patterns of lonely people</h2><p>The association between the default network and loneliness may be because of the way lonely people think. Lonely people have been found, for example, to focus more on internal thoughts, perhaps to compensate for their lack of actual social experiences. Their thought patterns tend to include above-average levels of reminiscing and imagined social exchanges. And this increase in thoughts about the self might well influence the relationship between the regions of the default network.<span data-ez-name="psychnewsdaily_com-box-4"></span></p><p>“In the absence of desired social experiences,” the authors write, “lonely individuals may be biased towards internally directed cognitions,” as if “to fill the social void.”</p><p>In that sense, then, the physical effects of loneliness on the brain are not surprising. Paying “greater attention to one’s inner milieu, and a heightened focus on the self and self-reflective thoughts,” the authors write, “would naturally engage memory-based functions of the default network.”</p><p>Indeed, <a href="https://amzn.to/3nnJzNk" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener sponsored nofollow">past research on loneliness</a> has found that lonely people are more likely to engage in <a href="https://doi.org/10.1037%2F0022-3514.85.3.409" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">imaginary social interactions</a>, <a href="https://doi.org/10.1111%2Fj.1467-9280.2008.02194.x" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">nostalgic reminiscences</a>, and <a href="https://doi.org/10.1037%2F0033-295X.114.4.864" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hypothetical conversations</a>, and are also more likely to <a href="https://doi.org/10.1111%2Fj.1467-9280.2008.02056.x" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">treat pets like people</a>.</p><h2>So lonely: why studying loneliness matters</h2><p>Researchers are increasingly recognizing loneliness as a major health problem. A recent study, for example, found that <a href="https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/loneliness-among-older-americans-doubled-during-pandemic-poll-shows/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">loneliness has more than doubled among older people</a> since the Covid-19 pandemic began.</p><p>Past research has also shown that older people who experience loneliness have a higher risk of cognitive decline and dementia. Lonely people get sick more often, and take longer to get over infections. Loneliness also increases blood pressure and levels of stress hormones. Socially isolated people are more likely to be depressed, suffer from memory loss, and use alcohol and drugs. Likewise, evidence suggests that loneliness contributes to ageing in a number of ways, and leads to reduced longevity. In fact, the health risks of loneliness are <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/1745691614568352" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">equivalent to those related to obesity or smoking 15 cigarettes a day</a>.</p><p>Understanding how loneliness works in the brain could one day help prevent neurological disease, and lead to better treatments.</p><p>“We speculate that the associations between the default network and loneliness revealed here,” the researcher write, “reflect increased demands on episodic mental simulation of inner social events in the absence of desired social experience in the external world.”</p><hr><p><strong>Study:</strong> “<a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-20039-w" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The default network of the human brain is associated with perceived social isolation</a>“<br><strong>Authors:</strong> Nathan Spreng et al.<br><strong>Published in:</strong> <em><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.nature.com/ncomms" target="_blank">Nature Communications</a></em><br><strong>Publication date: </strong>December 15, 2020<br><strong>DOI:</strong> http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41467-020-20039-w<br><strong>Photo:</strong> by&nbsp;<a href="https://unsplash.com/@anthonytran?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Anthony Tran</a>&nbsp;via&nbsp;<a href="https://unsplash.com/?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Unsplash</a></p><p>For a weekly summary of the latest psychology news, subscribe to our <a href="https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/the-psych-news-weekly-newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Psych News Weekly newsletter</a>.</p></div></div></div></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/lonely-people-have-a-unique-brain-signature-perhaps-due-to-so-much-imagined-social-contact/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25431817</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 16:32:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[SuperRT – Realtime Raytracing on the SNES]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 320 | Comments 70 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25431203">thread link</a>) | @mkeeter
<br/>
December 15, 2020 | https://www.shironekolabs.com/posts/superrt/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.shironekolabs.com/posts/superrt/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
    <header>
        
        
        <h2>
        December 13, 2020
        <br>
        
        </h2>
    </header>
    <section id="post-body">
        <p><strong>Video links for this article:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://youtu.be/VeFF344NbZ4">Short trailer</a></li>
<li><a href="https://youtu.be/2jee4tlakqo">Walkthrough and technical details</a></li>
</ul>

<p>I’m pleased to finally have some results to show for a project I’ve been working on in my spare time for the last year or so.</p>

<p>The idea originated when I was trying to think of an interesting idea for a project to help me learn Verilog and FPGA design, and the notion of building a simple raytracer came to mind (partly inspired by a scarily smart friend of mine who is building his own GPU). A bit later - because sometimes my brain hates me and delights in coming up with silly things to do - this turned into “wouldn’t it be interesting to try making a SNES do raytracing?”, and thus the SuperRT chip idea was born.</p>

<p>What I wanted to try and do was something akin to the Super FX chip used in titles such as Star Fox, where the SNES runs the game logic and hands off a scene description to a chip in the cartridge to generate the visuals. To that end I’ve deliberately tried to restrict myself to just using a single custom chip for the design, not making use of the ARM core available on the DE10 board or any other external processing resources.</p>

<p>The end results look something like this:</p>

<p>
 <video width="320" height="240" autoplay="" loop="">
  <source src="https://www.shironekolabs.com/posts/superrt/Bubbles2.mp4" type="video/mp4">
  SuperRT scene example video
 </video> 
</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Apologies for the poor screenshot quality, incidentally - for some reason my capture card produces terrible results when capturing from my SNES, so I had to resort to the good old “photograph the screen in a darkened room” approach.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><img src="https://www.shironekolabs.com/posts/superrt/Hardware.jpg" alt="SuperRT development hardware"></p>

<p>The Super Nintendo (technically a Super Famicom) seen here has had the case removed to make room for the cabling, but other than that is totally unmodified. Attached to it is the PCB from a copy of an <em>awful</em> Pachinko game I picked up for 100 yen at a local second-hand store, with the game ROM removed and replaced with a cable breakout. This then passes through a set of level shifters to convert the SNES’s 5v down to 3.3v and then into a DE10-Nano FPGA development board with a Cyclone V FPGA. The level shifter boards are anything but pretty - and assembling them was a nightmare thanks to the necessary ICs only being available in surface-mount packages - but they do the job.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.shironekolabs.com/posts/superrt/Slide3.jpg" alt="Hardware layout diagram"></p>

<p>The SuperRT chip constructs the scene using a specialised command language which is executed by one of three parallel execution units on the chip - essentially specialised CISC processors - to perform ray intersection tests. The scene description allows objects to be constructed using a subset of CSG operations, using spheres and planes as the basic building blocks and then performing OR, AND and subtraction operations using them to build up the desired geometry. AABBs are also supported, although primarily for use in culling tests (they can be rendered if desired, but they have a lower positional accuracy than other primitives and thus this is not generally very useful except for debugging purposes).</p>

<p>
 <video width="320" height="240" autoplay="" loop="">
  <source src="https://www.shironekolabs.com/posts/superrt/Artefact.mp4" type="video/mp4">
  SuperRT scene example video
 </video> 
</p>

<p>The renderer casts up to four rays per screen pixel, calculating direct shadows from a directional light source and a single reflection bounce. Surfaces each have a diffuse colour and reflectivity property, and it’s possible to apply modifiers to these based on CSG results or specialised functions - this is used to generate the checkerboard pattern on the floor.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.shironekolabs.com/posts/superrt/Slide2.jpg" alt="SuperRT screenshot"></p>

<p>The ray colour for each pixel is calculated by a “ray engine”, which handles the overall ray lifecycle and uses an “execution engine” module to run the command program describing the scene as many times as is required to resolve the ray. The command program itself is uploaded from the SNES and stored in a local 4K RAM buffer - animation is performed by writing modified commands into this buffer as required. A disassembled command buffer looks like this:</p>

<pre><code>0000 Start
0001 Plane 0, -1, 0, Dist=-2
0002 SphereSub OH 2, 1, 5, Rad=5
0003 SphereSub OH 4, 1, 4, Rad=4
0004 SphereSub OH 5, 1, 9, Rad=9
0005 SphereSub OH 2, 1, 2, Rad=2
0006 SphereSub OH -0.5, 1, 2, Rad=2
0007 RegisterHitNoReset 0, 248, 0, Reflectiveness=0
0008 Checkerboard ORH 48, 152, 48, Reflectiveness=0
0009 ResetHitState
0010 Plane 0, -1, 0, Dist=-2.150146
0011 RegisterHit 0, 0, 248, Reflectiveness=153
0012 AABB 4, -2.5, 11,    8, 3.5, 13
0013 ResetHitStateAndJump NH 44
0014 Origin 6, 2, 12
0015 Plane -0.2929688, 0, -0.9570313, Dist=0.2497559
0016 PlaneAnd OH 0.2919922, 0, 0.9560547, Dist=0.25
0017 PlaneAnd OH 0, 1, 0, Dist=1
0018 PlaneAnd OH 0, -1, 0, Dist=4
0019 PlaneAnd OH -0.9570313, 0, 0.2919922, Dist=-1
0020 PlaneAnd OH 0.9560547, 0, -0.2929688, Dist=1.499756
0021 RegisterHit 248, 0, 0, Reflectiveness=0
</code></pre>

<p>Each execution engine is a processor module with a 14 cycle pipeline, and in general one instruction is retired per cycle, so each execution unit can calculate about 50 million sphere, plane or AABB intersections per second. The exception to this is that branch operations have to flush the entire pipeline and thus have a  16 cycle overhead (14 cycles to flush the pipeline + 2 cycles instruction fetch delay). To try and avoid this as much as possible a branch prediction system is used - fortunately a lot of the time the spatial coherency of nearby rays means that a high prediction hit rate is achievable.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.shironekolabs.com/posts/superrt/Slide5.jpg" alt="SuperRT screenshot"></p>

<p>Intersections in the execution engine are carried out by two pipelines, one handling AABBs and the other spheres and planes. The system as a whole works exclusively using 32-bit integer maths in 18.14 fixed point format, with 16-bit (2.14) format used where values are known to be in the +-1 range, and the sphere/plane intersection pipeline has two dedicated additional maths units that calculate reciprocal and square root operations.</p>

<p>
 <video width="320" height="240" autoplay="" loop="">
  <source src="https://www.shironekolabs.com/posts/superrt/Light.mp4" type="video/mp4">
  SuperRT scene example video
 </video> 
</p>

<p>Once a frame is rendered, the PPU converter module turns the framebuffer into a format that can be DMAed directly to the SNES VRAM for display, reducing it to 256 colours and swizzling it into character tile bitplanes. The screen resolution is 200x160 - this results in exactly 32000 bytes of image data for a full frame, which is transferred to VRAM in two 16000 bytes chunks over successive frames due to bandwidth constraints. Thus the full image can only be refreshed once every two frames, effectively limiting the maximum framerate to 30FPS - although the test scene runs at closer to 20FPS (primarily due to some bottlenecks with the logic on the SNES side at present).</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Many thanks to the participants in <a href="https://forums.nesdev.com/viewtopic.php?f=12&amp;t=20068">this thread</a> over at SNESdev for a lot of useful ideas on fullscreen expansion chip DMA that inspired the solution used here.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><img src="https://www.shironekolabs.com/posts/superrt/Slide4.jpg" alt="SuperRT screenshot"></p>

<p>The chip also implements a number of other basic functions - there is an interface to the SNES cartridge bus, along with a small program ROM holding 32K of code for the SNES (this is constrained by the fact that the interface board currently only connects up the SNES Address Bus A lines, and thus the effective usable address space is a mere 64K, of which 32K is used for memory-mapped IO registers to communicate with the SuperRT chip). There is also a multiplication accelerator unit that lets the SNES perform 16x16bit multiply operations rapidly.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.shironekolabs.com/posts/superrt/Shot13.jpg" alt="SuperRT screenshot"></p>

<p>For debugging, I used the HDMI interface on the DE10 board to output data to a second monitor, along with a Megadrive joypad connected to the GPIO pins to manipulate the debug system. Resource constraints mean that this has to be disabled if all three ray engine cores are enabled, however.</p>

<p>So that’s a broad overview of the system - I intend to post some articles giving more details of how individual components work in the near future. In the meantime, though, if you have any questions or thoughts then please get in touch and I’ll do my best to answer!</p>

<p>Many thanks to Matt, Jaymin, Rick and everyone else who has helped with advice, inspiration and support!</p>

<p>
 <video width="320" height="240" autoplay="" loop="">
  <source src="https://www.shironekolabs.com/posts/superrt/PanDown.mp4" type="video/mp4">
  SuperRT scene example video
 </video> 
</p>

<p><em>“SNES” and “Super Nintendo” are trademarks of Nintendo Co Ltd. This is a hobby project and completely unassociated with Nintendo.</em></p>

    </section>
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.shironekolabs.com/posts/superrt/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25431203</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 15:36:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Zen of Index.html]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 37 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25431167">thread link</a>) | @HugoDaniel
<br/>
December 15, 2020 | https://hugodaniel.com/posts/using-just-an-index-to-develop-a-web-app/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://hugodaniel.com/posts/using-just-an-index-to-develop-a-web-app/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>

		<header>
			
			<p> Web development has become a very complex field with many branches and tools to master. In this article, I suggest doing the inverse and use just a simple `index.html` file to manage all of the web app development scripts and assets. This might seem radical but does it make life more complex than using all those front-end tools we have become accustomed to? </p>
			<nav>
				<time datetime="2020-12-15">15-Dec-2020</time>
				<span>
					<a id="back" href="https://hugodaniel.com/">About me</a>
					<a href="https://hugodaniel.com/posts">All posts</a>
				</span>
			</nav>
		</header>
		<p>Using an <code>index.html</code> as the single management file for the app.</p>
<p><img src="https://hugodaniel.com/images/html5-hammer.png" alt="HTML5 badge with a hammer, ready to do some damage" title="That is one big hammer!"></p>
<p><em>"It might work for small things, but I wouldn't use it for something big."</em>
Said someone about something.</p>
<p>These are some of the things that an <code>index.html</code> typically does:</p>
<ul>
<li>Sets the title for the current page</li>
<li>Defines the content and assets</li>
<li>Defines content to be used as a template</li>
<li>Loads styles</li>
<li>Runs scripts and resolves modules dependencies</li>
</ul>
<p>Which are already quite good, but there are many more goodies to be found among the things that a simple <code>index.html</code> allows to do such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Set a <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Manifest">manifest file</a> for offline usage of the page items</li>
<li>Using the <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API">Web API</a>'s on the scripts (navigation, web components, 3d, audio, network access, etc...)</li>
<li><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Preloading_content">Preload</a> content and assets</li>
<li>Content <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_syndication">syndication</a></li>
<li>Social networks <a href="https://ogp.me/">meta information</a></li>
</ul>
<p>In fact, everything that any modern complex Web App does can be fit into a single <code>index.html</code> file.</p>
<p>It is mostly a matter of managing the complexity and growth of files, assets, components, etc...</p>
<p>We have developed a wide range of very complex tools to help us with that. Front-end development has become so complex that it is hard for any single person to master it.</p>
<p>How much harder would life be if a single <code>index.html</code> was used to drive all of the development instead of all those Create-React-App/Babel/WebPack/npm/yarn/d/sass/styled-components/optimizers? </p>
<p>I don't know how to answer this but will try to shed some light on a simpler, more "naked" approach for web app development.</p>
<p>To start <strong>there are at least two problems</strong> with using a single <code>index.html</code> as the only management file for the app:</p>
<ul>
<li>No TypeScript support (or any other transpiler language, only JS, GLSL, and WebASM supported)</li>
<li>No way to easily manage 3rd party dependencies dependencies (dependencies)</li>
</ul>
<p>These two will be the subject of my next post. For now, I am going to lay the ground for a simple <code>index.html</code>-only approach.</p>
<h2 id="a-common-structure-for-most-apps">A common structure for most apps</h2>
<p>The common structure I plan to follow is something like this:</p>
<pre><code><span>&lt;</span><span>head</span><span>&gt;
</span><span>&lt;!-- Page meta --&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;link&gt;'s go here after the meta stuff --&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;script type="module"&gt;'s go here --&gt;
</span><span>&lt;/</span><span>head</span><span>&gt;
&lt;</span><span>body</span><span>&gt; </span><span>&lt;!-- Feature flags as class strings in body --&gt;
  &lt;!-- Modals go here --&gt;
  </span><span>&lt;</span><span>main</span><span>&gt;
    </span><span>&lt;!-- The content being shown goes here --&gt;
  </span><span>&lt;/</span><span>main</span><span>&gt;
  </span><span>&lt;!-- &lt;template&gt;'s go here --&gt;
  &lt;!-- &lt;script&gt;'s go here at the end --&gt;
</span><span>&lt;/</span><span>body</span><span>&gt;
</span></code></pre>
<p>This structure makes some compromises but overall is enough for most complex apps. It is not that different from a normal HTML page 🧐.</p>
<p>JavaScript modules are being loaded at the <code>&lt;head&gt;</code>, which is ok because module scripts are deferred by default and do not block the parsing of the rest of the document. They could go anywhere, I prefer to keep the <code>&lt;body&gt;</code> for the main logic and more immediate scripts.</p>
<p>With this in mind, here are 3 common things to a web app that can be done in such a simple structure without much effort:</p>
<ol>
<li>Global loading state (full-screen loading)</li>
<li>Routing (what to show according to the URL being rendered)</li>
<li>Place common HTML parts/assets without repeating them (templating/components)</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="global-loading-page">Global Loading page</h2>
<p>A loading page that fills the whole screen is something that most web apps have, some even distract us with cool animations while loading.</p>
<p>In the above structure, the loading page goes into the modal area. Right before the <code>&lt;main&gt;</code> content. This allows heavy content like <code>&lt;canvas&gt;</code>, <code>&lt;img&gt;</code> to be placed as <code>&lt;main&gt;</code> children and fully load (shaders, image data, etc) behind it, before clearing the loading state and showing them to our friends.</p>
<pre><code><span>...
&lt;</span><span>body</span><span>&gt;
  &lt;</span><span>div </span><span>id</span><span>="</span><span>loading</span><span>"&gt;Loading&lt;/</span><span>div</span><span>&gt;
  &lt;</span><span>main</span><span>&gt;
  ...
</span></code></pre>
<p>The whole visible space gets covered with that loading <code>&lt;div&gt;</code> which is then removed when all the things that the app needs for a good first run are ready.</p>
<p>Having the loading upfront on the <code>index.html</code> without needing any JS to first show it also helps our karma score in the bots&amp;spiders purgatory that purge the web we all love into useful cinder blocks.</p>
<h2 id="routing">Routing</h2>
<p>No lib is going to be used for routing. Routing is going to consist of simple manipulations of the browser history with <code>popstate</code> and <code>pushstate</code>. The basic approach is:</p>
<ol>
<li>Read the current route from the window location</li>
<li>Clone its corresponding <code>&lt;template&gt;</code> into the <code>&lt;main&gt;</code> tag</li>
<li>Inside it adjust the relevant <code>&lt;a&gt;</code>'s and other link navigation tags to perform a <code>pushState</code> instead of their default behavior
<ul>
<li>Filters can be applied to only consider <code>&lt;a&gt;</code>'s that have relative paths, or that do not have the <code>rel=nofollow</code> attribute</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><code>onpopstate</code> clone the correspnoding <code>&lt;template&gt;</code> into the <code>&lt;main&gt;</code> tag</li>
</ol>
<p>This is intended only for web apps as an effort to reduce the amount of JS and leverage the features already at hand. For anything similar to regular pages the browser behavior is more than good enough, no need for JS there.</p>
<p>This approach should work well if the web app uses less than 20 or 15 possible routing patterns. Most web apps likely average at some number under 10. This simple approach should be more than enough. There is no need in my foreseeable use cases to use anything more complex like the DOM or any big library to manage routes.</p>
<p>I will evolve this into a very simple routing/templating library to be announced soon(ish). For reference, here is some code that I did for a template engine in one of the many Grid iterations: <a href="https://hugodaniel.com/scripts/meander.js">old routing code</a>.</p>
<p>I appreciate the browser's approach of associating page state with history, however, for a web app I find it simpler and more manageable to keep these two things separate:</p>
<ul>
<li>Routing seen as pure functions of navigation only transformations</li>
<li>App state in its own separate tarpit.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="html-templating">HTML Templating</h2>
<p>Stamping and repeating a common HTML structure in a couple of places is a frequent routine that most web apps do. Be it for menu entries, list items, or even whole parts like sidebars or modal and toast elements. Finding a common HTML structure and repeat it when needed with small adjustments is a stapled practice.</p>
<p>HTML templating has many technicalities and possibilities. Most JS frameworks commonly solve it in their own way with different degrees of justifiable complexity.</p>
<p>Web browsers already provide a very flexible and complex way to do templating through the Web Components suite of technologies. For most of my cases plain HTML will be prefered and written directly at that <code>index.html</code>. For the other cases where DRY speaks louder a simple static "copy/paste" tag will suffice, a small prototype of this could be something like:</p>
<pre><code><span>customElements</span><span>.</span><span>define</span><span>("</span><span>template-content</span><span>", </span><span>class extends </span><span>HTMLElement </span><span>{
  </span><span>constructor</span><span>() {
    </span><span>super</span><span>();
    </span><span>this</span><span>.</span><span>attachShadow</span><span>({ mode: </span><span>"</span><span>open</span><span>" </span><span>})
        .</span><span>appendChild</span><span>(
          document.</span><span>getElementById</span><span>(
            </span><span>this</span><span>.</span><span>getAttribute</span><span>(</span><span>'</span><span>from-id</span><span>'</span><span>)
          ).content.</span><span>cloneNode</span><span>(</span><span>true</span><span>))
  }
}</span><span>);
</span></code></pre>
<p>This small code defines a new WebComponent tag <code>&lt;template-content&gt;</code>, this tag reads an element id from its <code>from-id</code> attribute, then gets the corresponding element on the DOM for that id, clones it, and replaces itself with it.</p>
<p>This is useful because it provides a quick way to stamp HTML/SVG content on the document. Helpful to replicate SVG elements, lists, and node sub-trees on the client-side.</p>
<pre><code><span>&lt;</span><span>nav</span><span>&gt;
	&lt;</span><span>button </span><span>onclick</span><span>="</span><span>tool</span><span>('</span><span>undo</span><span>')"&gt;
		&lt;</span><span>template-content </span><span>from-id</span><span>="</span><span>tools-button-content</span><span>" /&gt;
		&lt;</span><span>template-content </span><span>from-id</span><span>="</span><span>tools-undo</span><span>" /&gt;
	&lt;/</span><span>button</span><span>&gt;
	&lt;</span><span>button </span><span>onclick</span><span>="</span><span>tool</span><span>('</span><span>draw</span><span>')"&gt;
		&lt;</span><span>template-content </span><span>from-id</span><span>="</span><span>tools-button-content</span><span>" /&gt;
		&lt;</span><span>template-content </span><span>from-id</span><span>="</span><span>tools-draw</span><span>" /&gt;
	&lt;/</span><span>button</span><span>&gt;
&lt;/</span><span>nav</span><span>&gt;

&lt;</span><span>template </span><span>id</span><span>="</span><span>tools-button-content</span><span>"&gt;
</span><span>&lt;!-- Some complex content here --&gt;
</span><span>&lt;/</span><span>template</span><span>&gt;
&lt;</span><span>template </span><span>id</span><span>="</span><span>tools-draw</span><span>"&gt;
</span><span>&lt;!-- Some other complex content here --&gt;
</span><span>&lt;/</span><span>template</span><span>&gt;
</span></code></pre><h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Keeping a single <code>index.html</code> might be just enough for a simpler naked approach to app development. If there is no need for big dependencies, versioning tracking files, transpilers, and all that, this could very well be good enough. It works directly on top of what browsers already provide and hints at a simpler, leaner, style of development.</p>
<p>It does not have TypeScript support and it also does not automatically resolve dependencies and bundles them.</p>
<p>These are two open problems with this approach that I plan to show a possible solution that is on par in simplicity with this one. That will be the subject of my next technical post (likely to come out next week). Stay tuned.</p>

	</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://hugodaniel.com/posts/using-just-an-index-to-develop-a-web-app/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25431167</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 15:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Shitlist Driven Development (2016)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 387 | Comments 128 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25429493">thread link</a>) | @r4um
<br/>
December 15, 2020 | https://sirupsen.com/shitlists/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://sirupsen.com/shitlists/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="article-content">
    

    <p>Recently the team I work with completed a project to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7UyDK2bDjc4">allow Shopify to run in
multiple datacenters</a>. This project
was a refactoring project in disguise. When you undertake large refactoring of a
code-base with 100s of developers and 100,000s of lines of code, you can’t align
by sending an email. The merge-conflicts a single pull request would entail
makes me shiver. When deprecating in a large code-base the only way to reliably
avoid new deprecated behaviour is a failing test that tells you what to do.
Otherwise the pace that new deprecated code is introduced can easily outpace the
speed at which you can remove them, or be a massive source of frustration.</p>
<p>Typically deprecations come in the form of soft warnings: Logging to <code>stderr</code>,
capital letters and exclamation marks in the documentation, or a legacy prefix
to the method or class name. At the end of the day, everyone needs to get work
done, and if they see a code-path already being used from 10 places in the
code-base despite these soft warnings–it doesn’t seem crazy to introduce
another. However, if another project is blocked on these deprecated code-paths,
piling on may have a large cost.</p>
<p>To solve this problem <a href="https://twitter.com/fw1729">Florian Weingarten</a> on our
team introduced what he calls “shitlists”: a whitelist of deprecated behaviour.
Existing deprecated behaviour is OK and whitelisted. New usage of the deprecated
API is banned and fails a test with a well-defined error.</p>
<p>They come in many forms, but could look like this:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="ruby"><span>Shitlist</span> <span>=</span> <span>[</span>
  <span>ClassA</span>,
  <span>ClassB</span>,
  <span>ClassC</span>
<span>]</span>

<span>def</span> <span>push_job_that_does_crazy_things</span>(klass)
  <span>if</span> <span>Shitlist</span><span>.</span>include?(klass)
    <span># Existing deprecated behaviour is called.</span>
  <span>else</span>
    <span>raise</span> <span>Shitlist</span><span>::</span><span>Error</span>, <span>&lt;&lt;-EOS
</span><span></span><span>You</span><span>'</span>re pushing a job that does crazy things<span>.</span> <span>This</span> <span>API</span> has been 
deprecated <span>in</span> this code<span>-</span>base<span>.</span> <span>&lt;</span>team<span>&gt;</span> is actively trying to get
rid of this code<span>-</span>path, because
<span>&lt;</span>reason<span>&gt;.</span> <span>We</span> suggest you instead <span>do</span> <span>&lt;</span>alternative<span>&gt;.</span> <span>If</span> you have questions, please
ping <span>&lt;</span>team<span>&gt;.</span>
  <span>EOS</span>
<span>end</span>
</code></pre></div><p>A shitlist could be something as simple as a <code>git grep</code> for a certain code-path:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="ruby"><span>test</span> <span>"no new introductions of legacy code path"</span> <span>do</span>
  actual <span>=</span> <span>`git grep some_legacy_method_with_a_unique_name`</span>
  assert_equal <span>321</span>, actual
<span>end</span>
</code></pre></div><p>Other times you can reach into another API and get a count or shitlist:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="ruby"><span>RedisShitlist</span> <span>=</span> <span>[</span>
  <span>Session</span>,
  <span>FragmentCache</span>,
  <span>AuthenticationTokens</span>,
<span>]</span>

<span>test</span> <span>"no new redis models introduced"</span> <span>do</span>
  assert_equal <span>RedisShitlist</span>, <span>RedisModel</span><span>.</span>descendants
<span>end</span>
</code></pre></div><p>Other ways we’ve used shitlists in the past:</p>
<ul>
<li>Make sure that a certain datastore is only read from in a certain context (or
not used at all). This would allow for using a read-only slave, or improving
resiliency in a certain area.</li>
<li>Ensure fallbacks for all uses of a secondary data-store. E.g. if you access
sessions in Redis and Redis is down, you should be able to still render the
page (i.e. have an empty session fallback).</li>
<li>Shitlisting joins between tables that have no business being joined. This is
helpful to keep data-models and scope clean, or separating a part of an
application.</li>
</ul>
<p>If you have a linter for a project, you may be able to encode rules. For example
you might use <a href="http://www.foodcritic.io/">Foodcritic</a> for Chef, or
<a href="https://github.com/bbatsov/rubocop">Rubocop</a> for Ruby.</p>
<p>Sometimes the shitlist is quite complicated, and much more domain-specific.</p>
<p>Building the shitlist gives the team responsible for it a number of advantages:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Strong feedback loop.</strong> The goal is to reduce the <code>Shitlist</code> to an empty
Array and always raise or remove the code entirely. Remove a class from the
list, fix the code and the tests, celebrate and move on.</li>
<li><strong>Stopped the bleeding.</strong> New deprecated behaviour is not introduced unless
the team is contacted or some other action defined in the error is taken.</li>
<li><strong>Success metric</strong>. If you have shitlists for everything that needs to be
done for your project, you have metrics that you can track. Every week you
can look at how these lists are shrinking. Refactoring for months at a time
can be exhausting, but if you see that you’re making progress with metrics
moving, it’s much more rewarding.</li>
<li><strong>Enforces a guarantee</strong>. For example, you can have a shitlist that all jobs
have a retry mechanism. In that case, you know that you can kill any worker
gracefully at any time since the job will retry. Because of 1-3 you know how
much work it will take to have this guarantee.</li>
</ol>
<p>It is important that the shitlist errors are actionable. If you hit the shitlist
of another team, you need to know what to do next. Ideally the error explains
exactly what you need to do, and no humans need to talk, but reaching out to the
owner of the shitlist should always be part of the shitlist.</p>
<p>If you own a shitlist, you must empathize with the problems of everyone who’s
running into problems. If you simply deprecate new behaviour and don’t offer an
alternative, you will be the source of frustration. If the value of emptying the
shitlist far outweighs the value of adding to the shitlist, it may be OK to not
offer a direct other solution but ask the person who ran into the error to
revise their solution.</p>
<p>It is important that people run into shitlists as early in development as
possible. If you run into a shitlist after spending hours implementing your
solution, you will be less than popular. Some shitlists may require an entire
re-architecting of some teams’ solutions.</p>
<p>Months, in our case more than a year, of refactoring can be overwhelming and
unrewarding work. With the strong feedback loop that shitlists introduce you can
see the light at the end of the tunnel. You know that nothing is added to the
shitlist without you knowing about it.</p>
<p>Creating shitlists in some cases can be extremely difficult. Some take hours to
create, others weeks, and in our case one took months to come up with. You’ll
have to place the cost of developing the shitlist against the cost of not having
it. In some cases logging when you hit a bad code-path may be enough (simple
soft warning deprecation) if you assert the risk of new behaviour small and the
complexity of introducing the shitlist big.</p>
<p>Delegating with shitlists is great. Due to the tight feedback loop, asking other
teams or onboarding new team members becomes much easier. Remove something on
the shitlist, fix the code and the tests, then move on. Sometimes during large
refactorings you may need other teams with more domain expertise of a certain
area of the code-base to help. The shitlist becomes a great rock to point people
at.</p>
<p>If you are about to embark on a large refactor, I highly recommend adding
shitlists to your toolbox. Your project will look much less daunting when it
goes from an opaque objective to a list of shitlists.</p>


    

    
  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://sirupsen.com/shitlists/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25429493</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 12:05:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Minimal safe Bash script template]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 458 | Comments 240 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25428621">thread link</a>) | @signa11
<br/>
December 15, 2020 | https://betterdev.blog/minimal-safe-bash-script-template/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://betterdev.blog/minimal-safe-bash-script-template/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

<p>Bash scripts. Almost anyone needs to write one sooner or later. Almost no one says “yeah, I love writing them”. And that’s why almost everyone is putting low attention while writing them.</p>



<p>I won’t try to make you a Bash expert (since I’m not a one either), but I will show you a minimal template that will make your scripts safer. You don’t need to thank me, your future self will thank you.</p>



<h2><span id="why_scripting_in_bash"></span>Why scripting in Bash?<span></span></h2>



<p>The best summary of Bash scripting appeared recently on my Twitter feed:</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>The opposite of "it's like riding a bike" is "it's like programming in bash".</p><p>A phrase which means that no matter how many times you do something, you will have to re-learn it every single time.</p></div>— Jake Wharton (@JakeWharton) <a href="https://twitter.com/JakeWharton/status/1334177665356587008?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 2, 2020</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>But Bash has something in common with another widely beloved language. Just like JavaScript, it won’t go away easily. While we can hope that Bash won’t become the main language for literally everything, it’s always somewhere near.</p>



<p>Bash <a href="https://www.quora.com/Is-Bash-considered-the-lingua-franca-of-shells/answer/Paul-Reiber">inherited the shell throne</a> and can be found on almost every Linux, including Docker images. And this is the environment in which most of the backend runs. So if you need to script the server application startup, a CI/CD step, or integration test run, Bash is there for you.</p>



<p>To glue few commands together, pass output from one to another, and just start some executable, Bash is the easiest and most native solution. While it makes perfect sense to write bigger, more complicated scripts in other languages, you can’t expect to have Python, Ruby, fish, or whatever another interpreter you believe is the best, available everywhere. And you probably should think twice and then once more before adding it to some prod server, Docker image, or CI environment.</p>



<p>Yet Bash is far from perfect. The syntax is a nightmare. Error handling is difficult. There are landmines everywhere. And we have to deal with it.</p>



<h2><span id="bash_script_template"></span>Bash script template<span></span></h2>



<p>Without further ado, here it is.</p>



<pre><code>#!/usr/bin/env bash

set -Eeuo pipefail
trap cleanup SIGINT SIGTERM ERR EXIT

script_dir=$(cd "$(dirname "${BASH_SOURCE[0]}")" &amp;&gt;/dev/null &amp;&amp; pwd -P)

usage() {
  cat &lt;&lt;EOF
Usage: $(basename "${BASH_SOURCE[0]}") [-h] [-v] [-f] -p param_value arg1 [arg2...]

Script description here.

Available options:

-h, --help      Print this help and exit
-v, --verbose   Print script debug info
-f, --flag      Some flag description
-p, --param     Some param description
EOF
  exit
}

cleanup() {
  trap - SIGINT SIGTERM ERR EXIT
  # script cleanup here
}

setup_colors() {
  if [[ -t 2 ]] &amp;&amp; [[ -z "${NO_COLOR-}" ]] &amp;&amp; [[ "${TERM-}" != "dumb" ]]; then
    NOFORMAT='\033[0m' RED='\033[0;31m' GREEN='\033[0;32m' ORANGE='\033[0;33m' BLUE='\033[0;34m' PURPLE='\033[0;35m' CYAN='\033[0;36m' YELLOW='\033[1;33m'
  else
    NOFORMAT='' RED='' GREEN='' ORANGE='' BLUE='' PURPLE='' CYAN='' YELLOW=''
  fi
}

msg() {
  echo &gt;&amp;2 -e "${1-}"
}

die() {
  local msg=$1
  local code=${2-1} # default exit status 1
  msg "$msg"
  exit "$code"
}

parse_params() {
  # default values of variables set from params
  flag=0
  param=''

  while :; do
    case "${1-}" in
    -h | --help) usage ;;
    -v | --verbose) set -x ;;
    --no-color) NO_COLOR=1 ;;
    -f | --flag) flag=1 ;; # example flag
    -p | --param) # example named parameter
      param="${2-}"
      shift
      ;;
    -?*) die "Unknown option: $1" ;;
    *) break ;;
    esac
    shift
  done

  args=("$@")

  # check required params and arguments
  [[ -z "${param-}" ]] &amp;&amp; die "Missing required parameter: param"
  [[ ${#args[@]} -eq 0 ]] &amp;&amp; die "Missing script arguments"

  return 0
}

parse_params "$@"
setup_colors

# script logic here

msg "${RED}Read parameters:${NOFORMAT}"
msg "- flag: ${flag}"
msg "- param: ${param}"
msg "- arguments: ${args[*]-}"</code></pre>



<p>The idea was to not make it too long. I don’t want to scroll 500 lines to the script logic. At the same time, I want some strong foundations for any script. But Bash is not making this easy, lacking any form of dependencies management.</p>



<p>One solution would be to have a separate script with all the boilerplate and utility functions and execute it at the beginning. The downside would be to have to always attach this second file everywhere, losing the “simple Bash script” idea along the way. So I decided to put in the template only what I consider to be a minimum to keep it possible short.</p>



<p>Now let’s look at it in more detail.</p>



<h3><span id="choose_bash"></span>Choose Bash<span></span></h3>



<pre><code>#!/usr/bin/env bash</code></pre>



<p>Script traditionally starts with a shebang. For the <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/21612980/why-is-usr-bin-env-bash-superior-to-bin-bash">best compatibility</a>, it references <code>/usr/bin/env</code>, not the <code>/bin/bash</code> directly. Although, if you read comments in the linked StackOverflow question, even this can fail sometimes.</p>



<h3><span id="fail_fast"></span>Fail fast<span></span></h3>



<pre><code>set -Eeuo pipefail</code></pre>



<p>The <code>set</code> command changes script execution options. For example, <strong>normally Bash does not care if some command failed</strong>, returning a non-zero exit status code. It just happily jumps to the next one. Now consider this little script:</p>



<pre><code>#!/usr/bin/env bash
cp important_file ./backups/
rm important_file</code></pre>



<p>What will happen, if the <code>backups</code> directory does not exist? Exactly, you will get an error message in the console, but before you will be able to react, the file will be already removed by the second command.</p>



<p>For details on what options exactly <code>set -Eeuo pipefail</code> changes and how they will protect you, I refer you to the <a href="https://vaneyckt.io/posts/safer_bash_scripts_with_set_euxo_pipefail/">article I have in my bookmarks for a few years now</a>.</p>



<p>Although you should know that there are some <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/commandline/comments/g1vsxk/the_first_two_statements_of_your_bash_script/fniifmk?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;context=3">arguments against setting those options</a>.</p>



<h3><span id="get_the_location"></span>Get the location<span></span></h3>



<pre><code>script_dir=$(cd "$(dirname "${BASH_SOURCE[0]}")" &amp;&gt;/dev/null &amp;&amp; pwd -P)</code></pre>



<p>This line <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/a/246128/2512304">does its best</a> to define the script’s location directory<s>, and then we <code>cd</code> to it. Why?</s></p>



<p>Often our scripts are operating on paths relative to the script location, copying files and executing commands, assuming the script directory is also a working directory. And it is, as long as we execute the script from its directory.</p>



<p>But if, let’s say, our CI config executes script like this:</p>



<pre><code>/opt/ci/project/script.sh</code></pre>



<p>then our script is operating not in project dir, but some completely different workdir of our CI tool. We can fix it, by going to the directory before executing the script:</p>



<pre><code>cd /opt/ci/project &amp;&amp; ./script.sh</code></pre>



<p>But it’s much nicer to solve this on the script side. So, if the script reads some file or executes another program from the same directory, call it like this:</p>



<pre><code>cat "$script_dir/my_file"</code></pre>



<p>At the same time, the script does not change the workdir location. If the script is executed from some other directory and the user provides a relative path to some file, we will still be able to read it.</p>



<h3><span id="try_to_clean_up"></span>Try to clean up<span></span></h3>



<pre><code>trap cleanup SIGINT SIGTERM ERR EXIT

cleanup() {
  trap - SIGINT SIGTERM ERR EXIT
  # script cleanup here
}</code></pre>



<p>Think about the <code>trap</code> like of a <code>finally</code> block for the script. At the end of the script – normal, caused by an error or an external signal – the <code>cleanup()</code> function will be executed. This is a place where you can, for example, try to remove all temporary files created by the script.</p>



<p>Just remember that the <code>cleanup()</code> can be called not only at the end but as well having the script done any part of the work. Not necessarily all the resources you try to cleanup will exist.</p>



<h3><span id="display_helpful_help"></span>Display helpful help<span></span></h3>



<pre><code>usage() {
  cat &lt;&lt;EOF
Usage: $(basename "${BASH_SOURCE[0]}") [-h] [-v] [-f] -p param_value arg1 [arg2...]

Script description here.

...
EOF
  exit
}</code></pre>



<p>Having the <code>usage()</code> relatively close to the top of the script, it will act in two ways:</p>



<ul><li>to <strong>display help</strong> for someone who does not know all the options and does not want to go over the whole script to discover them,</li><li>as a <strong>minimal documentation</strong> when someone modifies the script (for example you, 2 weeks later, not even remembering writing it in the first place).</li></ul>



<p>I don’t argue to document every function here. But a short, nice script usage message is a required minimum.</p>



<h3><span id="print_nice_messages"></span>Print nice messages<span></span></h3>



<pre><code>setup_colors() {
  if [[ -t 2 ]] &amp;&amp; [[ -z "${NO_COLOR-}" ]] &amp;&amp; [[ "${TERM-}" != "dumb" ]]; then
    NOFORMAT='\033[0m' RED='\033[0;31m' GREEN='\033[0;32m' ORANGE='\033[0;33m' BLUE='\033[0;34m' PURPLE='\033[0;35m' CYAN='\033[0;36m' YELLOW='\033[1;33m'
  else
    NOFORMAT='' RED='' GREEN='' ORANGE='' BLUE='' PURPLE='' CYAN='' YELLOW=''
  fi
}

msg() {
  echo &gt;&amp;2 -e "${1-}"
}</code></pre>



<p>Firstly, remove the <code>setup_colors()</code> function if you don’t want to use colors in text anyway. I keep it because I know I would use colors more often if I wouldn’t have to google codes for them every time.</p>



<p>Secondly, those <strong>colors are meant to be used with the <code>msg()</code> function only</strong>, not with the <code>echo</code> command.</p>



<p>The <strong><code>msg()</code> function is meant to be used to print everything that is not a script output</strong>. This includes all logs and messages, not only the errors. Citing the great <a href="https://medium.com/@jdxcode/12-factor-cli-apps-dd3c227a0e46">12 Factor CLI Apps</a> article:</p>



<blockquote><p><strong>In short: stdout is for output, stderr is for messaging.</strong></p><cite><a href="https://jdxcode.com/">Jeff Dickey</a>, who <a href="https://github.com/oclif/oclif/graphs/contributors">knows a little</a> about <a href="https://github.com/heroku/cli/graphs/contributors">building CLI apps</a></cite></blockquote>



<p>That’s why in most cases you shouldn’t use colors for <code>stdout</code> anyway.</p>



<p>Messages printed with <code>msg()</code> are sent to <code>stderr</code> stream and support special sequences, like colors. And colors are disabled anyway if the <code>stderr</code> output is not an interactive terminal or&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="https://no-color.org/" rel="noreferrer noopener">one of the standard parameters</a>&nbsp;is passed.</p>



<p>Usage:</p>



<pre><code>msg "This is a ${RED}very important${NOFORMAT} message, but not a script output value!"</code></pre>



<p>To check how it behaves when the <code>stderr</code> is not an interactive terminal, add a line like above to the script. Then execute it redirecting <code>stderr</code> to <code>stdout</code> and piping it to <code>cat</code>. Pipe operation makes the output no longer being sent directly to the terminal, but to the next command, so the colors should be disabled now.</p>



<pre><code>$ ./test.sh 2&gt;&amp;1 | cat
This is a very important message, but not a script output value!</code></pre>



<h3><span id="parse_any_parameters"></span>Parse any parameters<span></span></h3>



<pre><code>parse_params() {
  # default values of variables set from params
  flag=0
  param=''

  while :; do
    case "${1-}" in
    -h | --help) usage ;;
    -v | --verbose) set -x ;;
    --no-color) NO_COLOR=1 ;;
    -f | --flag) flag=1 ;; # example flag
    -p | --param) # …</code></pre></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://betterdev.blog/minimal-safe-bash-script-template/">https://betterdev.blog/minimal-safe-bash-script-template/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://betterdev.blog/minimal-safe-bash-script-template/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25428621</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 09:45:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Writing SQL expressions using Java syntax]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 23 | Comments 13 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25428589">thread link</a>) | @objsql
<br/>
December 15, 2020 | http://www.objsql.com/t6 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.objsql.com/t6">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="readme">
    
        

      <div>
        <article itemprop="text"><p>ObjectiveSQL is an ORM framework in Java based on ActiveRecord pattern, which encourages rapid development and clean, codes with the least, and convention over configuration.</p>
<h3>Features</h3>
<ul>
<li>With one annotation your <code>Class</code> has fully featured capabilities of SQL programming</li>
<li>Easy to relational(<code>has_one</code>, <code>has_many</code> and <code>belongs_to</code>) query and paged query</li>
<li>Writing SQL expressions(<code>arithmetic</code>, <code>comparison</code> and <code>logical</code>) using Java syntax</li>
</ul>
<h3>Installation</h3>
<h4>IntelliJ IDEA plugin installation</h4>
<p><code>Preferences/Settings</code> -&gt; <code>Plugins</code> -&gt; <code>Search with "ObjectiveSql" in market</code> -&gt; <code>Install</code></p>
<h4>Maven dependencies</h4>
<div><pre><span><span>&lt;!--</span> In standalone <span>--&gt;</span></span>
&lt;<span>dependency</span>&gt;
    &lt;<span>groupId</span>&gt;com.github.braisdom&lt;/<span>groupId</span>&gt;
    &lt;<span>artifactId</span>&gt;objective-sql&lt;/<span>artifactId</span>&gt;
    &lt;<span>version</span>&gt;1.4.3&lt;/<span>version</span>&gt;
&lt;/<span>dependency</span>&gt;</pre></div>
<div><pre><span><span>&lt;!--</span> In Spring Boot <span>--&gt;</span></span>
&lt;<span>dependency</span>&gt;
  &lt;<span>groupId</span>&gt;com.github.braisdom&lt;/<span>groupId</span>&gt;
  &lt;<span>artifactId</span>&gt;objsql-springboot&lt;/<span>artifactId</span>&gt;
  &lt;<span>version</span>&gt;1.3.1&lt;/<span>version</span>&gt;
&lt;/<span>dependency</span>&gt;</pre></div>
<p>Refer to the <a href="https://github.com/braisdom/ObjectiveSql/blob/master/examples/mysql/pom.xml#L67">pom.xml</a> for more configuration</p>
<h3>Examples</h3>
<p>ObjectiveSQL provides full example for various databases below, You can open it directly with IntelliJ IDEA as a standalone project. In fact, they are not just examples, but also unit tests of ObjectiveSQL in various databases.</p>
<p>If you want to run without configuration, you can try: <a href="https://github.com/braisdom/ObjectiveSql/tree/master/examples/sqlite">SQLite</a></p>
<p>Others: <a href="https://github.com/braisdom/ObjectiveSql/tree/master/examples/mysql">MySQL</a>,  <a href="https://github.com/braisdom/ObjectiveSql/tree/master/examples/oracle">Oracle</a>,  <a href="https://github.com/braisdom/ObjectiveSql/tree/master/examples/sqlserver">MS SQL Server</a>, <a href="https://github.com/braisdom/ObjectiveSql/tree/master/examples/postgres">PostgreSQL</a>,  <a href="https://github.com/braisdom/ObjectiveSql/tree/master/examples/springboot-sample">Spring Boot</a></p>
<h3>Simple SQL programming without coding</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>You just define a <code>JavaBean</code> with one annotation</p>
</blockquote>
<div><pre><span>@DomainModel</span>
<span>public</span> <span>class</span> <span>Member</span> {
    <span>private</span> <span>String</span> no;
    
    <span>@Queryable</span>
    <span>private</span> <span>String</span> name;
    <span>private</span> <span>Integer</span> gender;
    <span>private</span> <span>String</span> mobile;
    <span>private</span> <span>String</span> otherInfo;

    <span>@Relation</span>(<span>relationType</span> <span>=</span> <span>RelationType</span><span><span>.</span>HAS_MANY</span>)
    <span>private</span> <span>List&lt;<span>Order</span>&gt;</span> orders;
}</pre></div>
<h4>Persistence</h4>
<div><pre><span>Member</span><span>.</span>create(newMember);
<span>Member</span><span>.</span>create(<span>new</span> <span>Member</span>[]{newMember1, newMember2, newMember3}, <span>false</span>);

<span>Member</span><span>.</span>update(<span>1L</span>, newMember, <span>true</span>);
<span>Member</span><span>.</span>update(<span><span>"</span>name = 'Smith =&gt; Jackson'<span>"</span></span>, <span><span>"</span>name = ?<span>"</span></span>, <span><span>"</span>Alice<span>"</span></span>);

<span>Member</span><span>.</span>destroy(<span>1L</span>);
<span>Member</span><span>.</span>destroy(<span><span>"</span>name = ?<span>"</span></span>, <span><span>"</span>Mary<span>"</span></span>);</pre></div>
<h4>Counting and querying</h4>
<div><pre><span>Member</span><span>.</span>countAll();
<span>Member</span><span>.</span>count(<span><span>"</span>id &gt; ?<span>"</span></span>, <span>1</span>);
<span>Member</span><span>.</span>queryByPrimaryKey(<span>1</span>);
<span>Member</span><span>.</span>queryFirst(<span><span>"</span>id = ?<span>"</span></span>, <span>1</span>);
<span>Member</span><span>.</span>query(<span><span>"</span>id &gt; ?<span>"</span></span>, <span>1</span>);
<span>Member</span><span>.</span>queryAll();</pre></div>
<h4>Paged querying</h4>
<div><pre><span>Page</span> page <span>=</span> <span>Page</span><span>.</span>create(<span>0</span>, <span>10</span>);
<span>PagedList&lt;<span>Member</span>&gt;</span> members <span>=</span> <span>Member</span><span>.</span>pagedQueryAll(page, <span>Member</span><span><span>.</span>HAS_MANY_ORDERS</span>);</pre></div>
<h4>Relation querying</h4>
<div><pre><span>Member</span><span>.</span>queryAll(<span>Member</span><span><span>.</span>HAS_MANY_ORDERS</span>);
<span>Member</span><span>.</span>queryByPrimary(<span>1</span>, <span>Member</span><span><span>.</span>HAS_MANY_ORDERS</span>);
<span>Member</span><span>.</span>queryByName(<span><span>"</span>demo<span>"</span></span>, <span>Member</span><span><span>.</span>HAS_MANY_ORDERS</span>);
<span>...</span></pre></div>
<h3>Complex SQL programming</h3>
<div><pre><span>Order</span><span>.</span><span>Table</span> orderTable <span>=</span> <span>Order</span><span>.</span>asTable();
<span>Select</span> select <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>Select</span>();

<span><span>//</span> In ObjectiveSQL, Java operator can be overloaded</span>
select<span>.</span>project(sum(orderTable<span>.</span>amount) <span>/</span> sum(orderTable<span>.</span>quantity) <span>*</span> <span>100</span>)
        .from(orderTable)
        .where(orderTable<span>.</span>quantity <span>&gt;</span> <span>30</span> <span>&amp;&amp;</span>
            orderTable<span>.</span>salesAt<span>.</span>between(<span><span>"</span>2020-10-10 00:00:00<span>"</span></span>, <span><span>"</span>2020-10-30 23:59:59<span>"</span></span>))
        .groupBy(orderTable<span>.</span>productId);</pre></div>
<div><pre><span>SELECT</span> <span>SUM</span>(<span><span>`</span>T0<span>`</span></span>.<span><span>`</span>amount<span>`</span></span>) <span>/</span> <span>SUM</span>(<span><span>`</span>T0<span>`</span></span>.<span><span>`</span>quantity<span>`</span></span>) <span>*</span> <span>100</span>
<span>FROM</span> <span><span>`</span>orders<span>`</span></span> <span>AS</span> <span><span>`</span>T0<span>`</span></span>
<span>WHERE</span> <span><span>`</span>T0<span>`</span></span>.<span><span>`</span>quantity<span>`</span></span> <span>&gt;</span> <span>30</span> <span>AND</span> 
       <span><span>`</span>T0<span>`</span></span>.<span><span>`</span>sales_at<span>`</span></span> BETWEEN <span><span>'</span>2020-10-10 00:00:00<span>'</span></span> <span>AND</span> <span><span>'</span>2020-10-30 23:59:59<span>'</span></span>)
<span>GROUP BY</span> <span><span>`</span>T0<span>`</span></span>.<span><span>`</span>product_id<span>`</span></span></pre></div>
<h3>Reference documentation</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/braisdom/ObjectiveSql/wiki/ObjectiveSQL-Tutorial">English</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/braisdom/ObjectiveSql/wiki/ObjectiveSQL-%E5%BC%80%E5%8F%91%E6%8C%87%E5%8D%97">Chinese(中文)</a></li>
</ul>
<h3>Job seeker</h3>
<p>本人正在寻找合适的工作机会，工作地点为上海，有合适资源的，请加我微信详谈：braisdom</p>
</article>
      </div>
  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.objsql.com/t6</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25428589</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 09:38:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Exhaustiveness Checking with Mypy]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 84 | Comments 17 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25428583">thread link</a>) | @rbanffy
<br/>
December 15, 2020 | https://hakibenita.com/python-mypy-exhaustive-checking | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://hakibenita.com/python-mypy-exhaustive-checking">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article data-progress-indicator="">
        <hr>
<p><a href="https://mypy-lang.org/" rel="noopener">Mypy</a> is an optional static type checker for Python. It's been around since 2012 and is gaining traction even since. One of the main benefits of using a type checker is getting errors at "compile time" rather than at run time.</p>
<p>Exhaustiveness checking is a common feature of type checkers, and a very useful one! In this article I'm going to show you <strong>how you can get mypy to perform exhaustiveness checking!</strong></p>
<figure><img alt="Playing cards are also useful for explaining enumeration types...<br><small>Photo by <a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/G6wlppP4EN8&quot;>Daniel Rykhev</a></small>" src="https://hakibenita.com/images/01-python-mypy-exhaustive-checking.png"><figcaption>Playing cards are also useful for explaining enumeration types...<br><small>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/G6wlppP4EN8">Daniel Rykhev</a></small></figcaption>
</figure>
<details open="">
    <summary>Table of Contents</summary>

</details>
<hr>
<h2 id="exhaustiveness-checking"><a href="#exhaustiveness-checking">Exhaustiveness Checking</a></h2>
<p>Say you have a system to manage orders. To represent the status of an order, you have the following enum:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>import</span> <span>enum</span>

<span>class</span> <span>OrderStatus</span><span>(</span><span>enum</span><span>.</span><span>Enum</span><span>):</span>
    <span>Ready</span> <span>=</span> <span>'ready'</span>
    <span>Shipped</span> <span>=</span> <span>'shipped'</span>
</pre></div>


<p>You also have the following code to process an <code>Order</code>:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>def</span> <span>handle_order</span><span>(</span><span>status</span><span>:</span> <span>OrderStatus</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>None</span><span>:</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>status</span> <span>is</span> <span>OrderStatus</span><span>.</span><span>Ready</span><span>:</span>
        <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>'ship order'</span><span>)</span>

    <span>elif</span> <span>status</span> <span>is</span> <span>OrderStatus</span><span>.</span><span>Shipped</span><span>:</span>
        <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>'charge order'</span><span>)</span>
</pre></div>


<p>When the order is ready, you ship it; and when it's shipped, you charge it.</p>
<p>A few months go by and your system becomes big. So big in fact, that you can no longer ship orders immediately, and you add a new status:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>import</span> <span>enum</span>

<span>class</span> <span>OrderStatus</span><span>(</span><span>enum</span><span>.</span><span>Enum</span><span>):</span>
    <span>Ready</span> <span>=</span> <span>'ready'</span>
<span>    <span>Scheduled</span> <span>=</span> <span>'scheduled'</span>
</span>    <span>Shipped</span> <span>=</span> <span>'shipped'</span>
</pre></div>


<p>Before you push this change to production, you run a quick check with mypy to make sure everything is OK:</p>
<div><pre><span></span>$ mypy main.py
Success: no issues found in <span>1</span> <span>source</span> file
</pre></div>


<p>Mypy does not see anything wrong in this code, Do you? The problem is that <strong>you forgot to handle the new status in your function</strong>.</p>
<p>One way to make sure you always handle all possible order statuses is to add an assert, or throw an exception:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>def</span> <span>handle_order</span><span>(</span><span>status</span><span>:</span> <span>OrderStatus</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>None</span><span>:</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>status</span> <span>is</span> <span>OrderStatus</span><span>.</span><span>Ready</span><span>:</span>
        <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>'ship order'</span><span>)</span>

    <span>elif</span> <span>status</span> <span>is</span> <span>OrderStatus</span><span>.</span><span>Shipped</span><span>:</span>
        <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>'charge order'</span><span>)</span>

<span>    <span>assert</span> <span>False</span><span>,</span> <span>f</span><span>'Unhandled status "{status}"'</span>
</span></pre></div>


<p>Now, when you execute the function with the new status <code>OrderStatus.Scheduled</code>, you will get a runtime error:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>&gt;&gt;&gt;</span> <span>handle_order</span><span>(</span><span>OrderStatus</span><span>.</span><span>Scheduled</span><span>)</span>
<span>AssertionError</span><span>:</span> <span>Unhandled</span> <span>status</span> <span>"OrderStatus.Scheduled"</span>
</pre></div>


<p>Another way to with deal with cases like this is to go over your test suite and add scenarios in all the places that use order status. But... if you forgot to change the function when you added the status, what are the chances you'll remember to update the tests? That's not a good solution...</p>
<p><strong>Exhaustiveness Checking in Mypy</strong></p>
<p>What if mypy could warn you at "compile time" about such cases? Well... it can, using this little magic function:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>from</span> <span>typing</span> <span>import</span> <span>NoReturn</span>
<span>import</span> <span>enum</span>

<span>def</span> <span>assert_never</span><span>(</span><span>value</span><span>:</span> <span>NoReturn</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>NoReturn</span><span>:</span>
    <span>assert</span> <span>False</span><span>,</span> <span>f</span><span>'Unhandled value: {value} ({type(value).__name__})'</span>
</pre></div>


<p>Before you dig into the implementation, try to use it to see how it works. In the function above, place <code>assert_never</code> after you handled all the possible order statuses, where you previously used <code>assert</code> or raises an exception:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>def</span> <span>handle_order</span><span>(</span><span>status</span><span>:</span> <span>OrderStatus</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>None</span><span>:</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>status</span> <span>is</span> <span>OrderStatus</span><span>.</span><span>Ready</span><span>:</span>
        <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>'ship order'</span><span>)</span>

    <span>elif</span> <span>status</span> <span>is</span> <span>OrderStatus</span><span>.</span><span>Shipped</span><span>:</span>
        <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>'charge order'</span><span>)</span>

<span>    <span>else</span><span>:</span>
</span><span>        <span>assert_never</span><span>(</span><span>status</span><span>)</span>
</span></pre></div>


<p>Now, check the code with Mypy:</p>
<div><pre><span></span>$ mypy main.py
error: Argument <span>1</span> to <span>"assert_never"</span> has incompatible <span>type</span> <span>"Literal[OrderStatus.Scheduled]"</span><span>;</span>
expected <span>"NoReturn"</span>
Found <span>1</span> error in <span>1</span> file <span>(</span>checked <span>1</span> <span>source</span> file<span>)</span>
</pre></div>


<p>Amazing! <strong>Mypy warns you about a status you forgot to handle!</strong> The message also includes the value, <code>OrderStatus.Scheduled</code>. If you use a modern editor such as VSCode you can get these warnings immediately as you type:</p>
<figure><img alt="mypy Error in VSCode" src="https://hakibenita.com/images/00-python-mypy-exhaustive-checking.png"><figcaption>mypy Error in VSCode</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>You can now go ahead and fix your function to handle the missing status:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>def</span> <span>handle_order</span><span>(</span><span>status</span><span>:</span> <span>OrderStatus</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>None</span><span>:</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>status</span> <span>is</span> <span>OrderStatus</span><span>.</span><span>Pending</span><span>:</span>
        <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>'schedule order'</span><span>)</span>

<span>    <span>elif</span> <span>status</span> <span>is</span> <span>OrderStatus</span><span>.</span><span>Scheduled</span><span>:</span>
</span><span>        <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>'ship order'</span><span>)</span>
</span>
    <span>elif</span> <span>status</span> <span>is</span> <span>OrderStatus</span><span>.</span><span>Shipped</span><span>:</span>
        <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>'charge order'</span><span>)</span>

    <span>else</span><span>:</span>
        <span>assert_never</span><span>(</span><span>status</span><span>)</span>
</pre></div>


<p>Check with mypy again:</p>
<div><pre><span></span>$ mypy main.py
Success: no issues found in <span>1</span> <span>source</span> file
</pre></div>


<p>Great! You can now rest assure you handled all order statuses. The best part is that you did that with <strong>no unit tests</strong>, and there were <strong>no runtime errors</strong>. If you include mypy in your CI, the <strong>bad code will never make it into production</strong>.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="enumeration-types"><a href="#enumeration-types">Enumeration types</a></h2>
<p>In the previous section you used mypy to perform exhaustiveness check on an <code>Enum</code>. You can use mypy, and <code>assert_never</code> to perform exhaustiveness check on other enumeration types as well.</p>
<p><strong>Exhaustiveness Checking of a Union</strong></p>
<p>A <code>Union</code> type represents several possible types. For example, a function that casts an argument to <code>float</code> can look like this:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span><span>from</span> <span>typing</span> <span>import</span> <span>Union</span>
</span>
<span><span>def</span> <span>get_float</span><span>(</span><span>num</span><span>:</span> <span>Union</span><span>[</span><span>str</span><span>,</span> <span>float</span><span>])</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>float</span><span>:</span>
</span>    <span>if</span> <span>isinstance</span><span>(</span><span>num</span><span>,</span> <span>str</span><span>):</span>
        <span>return</span> <span>float</span><span>(</span><span>num</span><span>)</span>

    <span>else</span><span>:</span>
        <span>assert_never</span><span>(</span><span>num</span><span>)</span>
</pre></div>


<p>Check the function with mypy:</p>
<div><pre><span></span>$ mypy main.py
error: Argument <span>1</span> to <span>"assert_never"</span> has incompatible <span>type</span> <span>"float"</span><span>;</span> expected <span>"NoReturn"</span>
</pre></div>


<p>Whoops... you forgot to handle the <code>float</code> type in the code:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>from</span> <span>typing</span> <span>import</span> <span>Union</span>

<span>def</span> <span>get_float</span><span>(</span><span>num</span><span>:</span> <span>Union</span><span>[</span><span>str</span><span>,</span> <span>float</span><span>])</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>float</span><span>:</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>isinstance</span><span>(</span><span>num</span><span>,</span> <span>str</span><span>):</span>
        <span>return</span> <span>float</span><span>(</span><span>num</span><span>)</span>

<span>    <span>elif</span> <span>isinstance</span><span>(</span><span>num</span><span>,</span> <span>float</span><span>):</span>
</span><span>        <span>return</span> <span>num</span>
</span>
    <span>else</span><span>:</span>
        <span>assert_never</span><span>(</span><span>num</span><span>)</span>
</pre></div>


<p>Check again:</p>
<div><pre><span></span>$ mypy main.py
Success: no issues found in <span>1</span> <span>source</span> file
</pre></div>


<p>Great! mypy is happy...</p>
<p><strong>Exhaustiveness Checking of a Literal</strong></p>
<p>Another useful type is <code>Literal</code>. It is included in the built-in <code>typing</code> module since Python3.8, and prior to that it is part of the complementary <a href="https://pypi.org/project/typing-extensions/" rel="noopener"><code>typing_extensions</code> package</a>.</p>
<p>A <code>Literal</code> is used to type primitive values such as strings and numbers. <code>Literal</code> is also an enumeration type, so you can use exhaustiveness checking on it as well:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>from</span> <span>typing_extensions</span> <span>import</span> <span>Literal</span>

<span>Color</span> <span>=</span> <span>Literal</span><span>[</span><span>'R'</span><span>,</span> <span>'G'</span><span>,</span> <span>'B'</span><span>]</span>

<span>def</span> <span>get_color_name</span><span>(</span><span>color</span><span>:</span> <span>Color</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>str</span><span>:</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>color</span> <span>==</span> <span>'R'</span><span>:</span>
        <span>return</span> <span>'Red'</span>
    <span>elif</span> <span>color</span> <span>==</span> <span>'G'</span><span>:</span>
        <span>return</span> <span>'Green'</span>
    <span># elif color == 'B':</span>
    <span>#     return 'Blue'</span>
    <span>else</span><span>:</span>
        <span>assert_never</span><span>(</span><span>color</span><span>)</span>
</pre></div>


<p>Checking the code without the commented part will produce the following error:</p>
<div><pre><span></span>$ mypy main.py
error: Argument <span>1</span> to <span>"assert_never"</span> has incompatible <span>type</span> <span>"Literal['B']"</span><span>;</span> expected <span>"NoReturn"</span>
</pre></div>


<p>Very handy indeed!</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="type-narrowing-in-mypy"><a href="#type-narrowing-in-mypy">Type Narrowing in Mypy</a></h2>
<p>Now that you've seen what <code>assert_never</code> can do, you can try and understand how it works. <code>assert_never</code> works alongside <strong>"type narrowing"</strong>, which is a mypy feature where the type of a variable is narrowed based on the control flow of the program. In other words, mypy is gradually eliminating possible types for a variable.</p>
<p>First, it's important to understand how various things translate to a <code>Union</code> type in mypy:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>Optional</span><span>[</span><span>int</span><span>]</span>
<span># Equivalent to Union[int, None]</span>

<span>Literal</span><span>[</span><span>'string'</span><span>,</span> <span>42</span><span>,</span> <span>True</span><span>]</span>
<span># Equivalent to Union[Literal['string'], Literal[42], Literal[True]]</span>

<span>class</span> <span>Suit</span><span>(</span><span>Enum</span><span>):</span>
    <span>Clubs</span> <span>=</span> <span>"♣"</span>
    <span>Diamonds</span> <span>=</span> <span>"♦"</span>
    <span>Hearts</span> <span>=</span> <span>"♥"</span>
    <span>Spades</span> <span>=</span> <span>"♠"</span>

<span>Suit</span>
<span># ~Equivalent to Union[</span>
<span>#   Literal[Suit.Clubs],</span>
<span>#   Literal[Suit.Diamonds],</span>
<span>#   Literal[Suit.Hearts],</span>
<span>#   Literal[Suit.Spades]</span>
<span># ]</span>
</pre></div>


<p>To display the type of an expression, mypy provides a useful utility called <a href="https://mypy.readthedocs.io/en/stable/common_issues.html#reveal-type" rel="noopener"><code>reveal_type</code></a>. Using <code>reveal_type</code> you can ask mypy to show you the inferred type for a variable at the point it's called:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>def</span> <span>describe_suit</span><span>(</span><span>suit</span><span>:</span> <span>Optional</span><span>[</span><span>Suit</span><span>])</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>str</span><span>:</span>
<span>    <span># Revealed type is Union[Suit, None]</span>
</span>    <span>reveal_type</span><span>(</span><span>suit</span><span>)</span>
</pre></div>


<p>In the function above, the reveled type of <code>suit</code> is <code>Union[Suit, None]</code>, which is the type of the argument <code>suit</code>.</p>
<p>At this point you haven't done anything in the function, so mypy is unable to narrow down the type. Next, add some logic and see how mypy narrows down the type of the variable <code>suit</code>:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>def</span> <span>describe_suit</span><span>(</span><span>suit</span><span>:</span> <span>Optional</span><span>[</span><span>Suit</span><span>])</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>str</span><span>:</span>
<span>    <span>assert</span> <span>suit</span> <span>is</span> <span>not</span> <span>None</span>
</span><span>    <span># Revealed type is Suit</span>
</span>    <span>reveal_type</span><span>(</span><span>suit</span><span>)</span>
</pre></div>


<p>After eliminating the option of suit being <code>None</code>, the revealed type is <code>Suit</code>. Mypy used your program's logic to narrow the type of the variable.</p>
<p>Keep in mind, the type <code>Suit</code> is equivalent to the type <code>Union[Literal[Suit.Clubs], Literal[Suit.Diamonds], Literal[Suit.Hearts], Literal[Suit.Spades]]</code>, so next, try to narrow down the type even more:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>def</span> <span>describe_suit</span><span>(</span><span>suit</span><span>:</span> <span>Optional</span><span>[</span><span>Suit</span><span>])</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>str</span><span>:</span>
    <span>assert</span> <span>suit</span> <span>is</span> <span>not</span> <span>None</span>

<span>    <span>if</span> <span>suit</span> <span>is</span> <span>Suit</span><span>.</span><span>Clubs</span><span>:</span>
</span><span>        <span># Revealed type is Literal[Suit.Clubs]</span>
</span>        <span>reveal_type</span><span>(</span><span>suit</span><span>)</span>
        <span>return</span> <span>"Clubs"</span>

<span>    <span># Revealed type is Literal[Suit.Diamonds, Suit.Hearts, Suit.Spades]</span>
</span>    <span>reveal_type</span><span>(</span><span>suit</span><span>)</span>
</pre></div>


<p>After checking if <code>suit</code> is <code>Suit.Clubs</code>, mypy is able to narrow down the type to <code>Suit.Clubs</code>. Mypy is also smart enough to understand that if the condition does not hold, the variable <em>is definitely not</em> <code>Clubs</code>, and narrows down the type to <code>Diamonds</code>, <code>Hearts</code> or <code>Spades</code>.</p>
<p>Mypy can also use other conditional statements to further narrow the type, for example:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>def</span> <span>describe_suit</span><span>(</span><span>suit</span><span>:</span> <span>Optional</span><span>[</span><span>Suit</span><span>])</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>str</span><span>:</span>
    <span>assert</span> <span>suit</span> <span>is</span> <span>not</span> <span>None</span>

    <span>if</span> <span>suit</span> <span>is</span> <span>Suit</span><span>.</span><span>Clubs</span><span>:</span>
        <span># Revealed type is Literal[Suit.Clubs]</span>
        <span>reveal_type</span><span>(</span><span>suit</span><span>)</span>
        <span>return</span> <span>"Clubs"</span>

    <span># Revealed type is Literal[Suit.Diamonds, Suit.Hearts, Suit.Spades]</span>
    <span>reveal_type</span><span>(</span><span>suit</span><span>)</span>

<span>    <span># `and`, `or` and `not` also work.</span>
</span><span>    <span>if</span> <span>suit</span> <span>is</span> <span>Suit</span><span>.</span><span>Diamonds</span> <span>or</span> <span>suit</span> <span>is</span> <span>Suit</span><span>.</span><span>Spades</span><span>:</span>
</span><span>        <span># Revealed type is Literal[Suit.Diamonds, Suit.Spades]</span>
</span>        <span>reveal_type</span><span>(</span><span>suit</span><span>)</span>
        <span>return</span> <span>"Diamonds or Spades"</span>

<span>    <span># Revealed type is Literal[Suit.Hearts]</span>
</span><span>    <span>reveal_type</span><span>(</span><span>suit</span><span>)</span>
</span></pre></div>


<p>By the end of the function, mypy narrowed down the type of <code>suit</code> to <code>Suit.Hearts</code>. If, for example, you add a condition that imply a different type for <code>suit</code>, mypy will issue an error:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>def</span> <span>describe_suit</span><span>(</span><span>suit</span><span>:</span> <span>Optional</span><span>[</span><span>Suit</span><span>])</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>str</span><span>:</span>
    <span>assert</span> <span>suit</span> <span>is</span> <span>not</span> <span>None</span>

    <span>if</span> <span>suit</span> <span>is</span> <span>Suit</span><span>.</span><span>Clubs</span><span>:</span>
        <span># Revealed type is Literal[Suit.Clubs]</span>
        <span>reveal_type</span><span>(</span><span>suit</span><span>)</span>
        <span>return</span> <span>"Clubs"</span>

    <span># Revealed type is Literal[Suit.Diamonds, Suit.Hearts, Suit.Spades]</span>
    <span>reveal_type</span><span>(</span><span>suit</span><span>)</span>

    <span># `and`, `or` and `not` also work.</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>suit</span> <span>is</span> <span>Suit</span><span>.</span><span>Diamonds</span> <span>or</span> <span>suit</span> <span>is</span> <span>Suit</span><span>.</span><span>Spades</span><span>:</span>
        <span># Revealed type is …</span></pre></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://hakibenita.com/python-mypy-exhaustive-checking">https://hakibenita.com/python-mypy-exhaustive-checking</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://hakibenita.com/python-mypy-exhaustive-checking</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25428583</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 09:38:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Saudi Arabia applied for diplomatic immunity for ten security guards in Norway]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 168 | Comments 100 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25427829">thread link</a>) | @elygre
<br/>
December 14, 2020 | https://www.dagbladet.no/nyheter/the-saudi-security-team-to-norway/73159458 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.dagbladet.no/nyheter/the-saudi-security-team-to-norway/73159458">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">

<p>In the early summer of 2018, Norway received an unusual request from Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman's government.</p><p>Saudi Arabia wanted to send ten men on an official assignment to Norway, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs confirms to Dagbladet. The ten men were all security guards, who were deployed to work at the Saudi Arabian embassy in Norway, according to Dagbladet’s sources. But Saudi Arabia wanted the security guards to be registered as diplomats in Norway. This would give them extended room for manoeuvring in Norway.</p><p><strong>The Ministry of Foreign Affairs intervened, and the Norwegian Police Security Service (PST) has informed Iyad el-Baghdadi (43) - a Norway-based journalist, activist, and critic of the Saudi regime - about the incident. </strong></p><p>Dagbladet has asked the Saudi embassy several questions regarding this article. The embassy has responded with a press release they originally sent out last year, criticising "fabricated and false" accusations, "with the intent to insult Saudi Arabia."</p>
<p><em><strong>Update Thursday 17th of December:</strong> The Saudi Arabian Embassy in Oslo has replied specifically to the deplyment of the security team. Read the full comment further down in this article.</em></p><p>Dagbladet has received confirmation from several sources that there were several issues regarding the ten-man security team that made the Norwegian authorities react.</p><figure data-zoomable="1">
    
<picture>
    <source media="(max-width: 640px)" itemprop="image" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159968.jpg?imageId=73159968&amp;width=760&amp;height=434&amp;compression=70">
    <source media="(min-width: 641px and max-width: 1024px)" itemprop="image" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159968.jpg?imageId=73159968&amp;width=900&amp;height=513&amp;compression=80">
    <source media="(min-width: 1025px)" itemprop="image" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159968.jpg?imageId=73159968&amp;width=980&amp;height=559&amp;compression=80">
<img itemprop="image" data-defer="view" title="INTERVENED: The Norwegian Ministry of Foreign Affairs. Photo: Audun Braastad / NTB" alt="INTERVENED: The Norwegian Ministry of Foreign Affairs. Photo: Audun Braastad / NTB" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159968.jpg?imageId=73159968&amp;width=760&amp;height=434&amp;compression=70 640w,https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159968.jpg?imageId=73159968&amp;width=900&amp;height=513&amp;compression=80 1024w,https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159968.jpg?imageId=73159968&amp;width=980&amp;height=559&amp;compression=80 1240w" src="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159968.jpg?imageId=73159968&amp;width=980&amp;height=559">
</picture>
      
    
    


      <figcaption itemprop="caption" data-expand="" onclick="this.classList.add('active')">
        <strong>INTERVENED:</strong> The Norwegian Ministry of Foreign Affairs. Photo: Audun Braastad / NTB
          <span role="button">Vis mer</span>
      </figcaption>
</figure>
<h2>The crucial points</h2><p>• <strong>The number:</strong> The number of security guards was unusually high. The Ministry of Foreign Affairs regularly publishes a list of all foreign diplomats accredited to Norway. According to the diplomat list from the summer of 2018, the total number of Saudi diplomats in Norway at the time was 18. Both the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and the PST were surprised that the Saudis were about to almost double the number - with only security people.</p>
<p>• <strong>The status:</strong> Both the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and the PST were surprised that Saudi Arabia requested that the security guards be granted diplomatic status - and registered in the official <a href="https://www.regjeringen.no/no/dep/ud/dep/forbindelser/id447053/">Diplomat List</a>. It is unusual for security people at embassies to be registered as diplomats. Both diplomats and other embassy personell - arriving on a so-called «D-visa» to Norway - is given <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diplomatic_immunity">diplomatic immunity</a>. Which, as one of several benefits, means that the host country cannot arrest you if you commit a crime. But being registered formally as a diplomat gives you a wider range of benefits.</p><p>• <strong>The increase:</strong> Norwegian authorities reacted to the fact that the major increase in security staff did not reflect what they knew regarding the activity level at the embassy.</p><p>• <strong>The key role:</strong> Officials at PST have later noted that security personnel, from the consulate in Istanbul, played key roles in the murder of the Saudi journalist Jamal Khashoggi, Dagbladet has learned.</p>
<p><strong>The PST declined to comment on this article, however, it has been presented with all the information herein – without finding any errors.</strong></p><figure data-zoomable="1">
    
<picture>
    <source media="(max-width: 640px)" itemprop="image" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159877.jpg?imageId=73159877&amp;width=760&amp;height=434&amp;compression=70">
    <source media="(min-width: 641px and max-width: 1024px)" itemprop="image" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159877.jpg?imageId=73159877&amp;width=900&amp;height=513&amp;compression=80">
    <source media="(min-width: 1025px)" itemprop="image" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159877.jpg?imageId=73159877&amp;width=980&amp;height=559&amp;compression=80">
<img itemprop="image" data-defer="view" title="MURDERED: Jamal Khashoggi was killed inside the Saudi Arabian consulate in Istanbul. The Norwegian PST later took note of the role played by the security staff at the consulate in conducting the killing. Photo: NTB" alt="MURDERED: Jamal Khashoggi was killed inside the Saudi Arabian consulate in Istanbul. The Norwegian PST later took note of the role played by the security staff at the consulate in conducting the killing. Photo: NTB" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159877.jpg?imageId=73159877&amp;width=760&amp;height=434&amp;compression=70 640w,https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159877.jpg?imageId=73159877&amp;width=900&amp;height=513&amp;compression=80 1024w,https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159877.jpg?imageId=73159877&amp;width=980&amp;height=559&amp;compression=80 1240w" src="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159877.jpg?imageId=73159877&amp;width=980&amp;height=559">
</picture>
      
    
    


      <figcaption itemprop="caption" data-expand="" onclick="this.classList.add('active')">
        <strong>MURDERED:</strong> Jamal Khashoggi was killed inside the Saudi Arabian consulate in Istanbul. The Norwegian PST later took note of the role played by the security staff at the consulate in conducting the killing. Photo: NTB
          <span role="button">Vis mer</span>
      </figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Guri Solberg, spokesperson at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, confirms in an e-mail to Dagbladet:</p><p>“In the summer of 2018, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs registered ten persons as new envoys at the Saudi Arabian embassy in Oslo. The status of other countries' envoys to embassies is regulated by the Vienna Convention on Diplomatic Relations (1961) and the role of the envoy at the embassy. As these were mainly persons who were to have internal tasks at the embassy, nine of the ten persons were registered as administrative / technical personnel in accordance with normal practice. One of the ten people was registered as a diplomat based on their role and responsibilities. In practice, there is little difference in the degree of immunity and privileges granted to diplomatic, administrative, and technical personnel. The rules on immunity and privileges are dictated by international law by which Norway is bound, in particular the Vienna Convention of Diplomatic Relations, that includes immunity from criminal prosecution in the host state.”</p><figure data-zoomable="1">
    
<picture>
    <source media="(max-width: 640px)" itemprop="image" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159870.jpg?imageId=73159870&amp;x=0&amp;y=18.992654774397&amp;cropw=100&amp;croph=41.238195173137&amp;width=534&amp;height=306&amp;compression=70">
    <source media="(min-width: 641px and max-width: 1024px)" itemprop="image" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159870.jpg?imageId=73159870&amp;x=0&amp;y=18.992654774397&amp;cropw=100&amp;croph=41.238195173137&amp;width=632&amp;height=362&amp;compression=80">
    <source media="(min-width: 1025px)" itemprop="image" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159870.jpg?imageId=73159870&amp;x=0&amp;y=18.992654774397&amp;cropw=100&amp;croph=41.238195173137&amp;width=688&amp;height=394&amp;compression=80">
<img itemprop="image" data-defer="view" title="SPOKESWOMAN: Guri Solberg at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs. Photo: MFA" alt="SPOKESWOMAN: Guri Solberg at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs. Photo: MFA" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159870.jpg?imageId=73159870&amp;x=0&amp;y=18.992654774397&amp;cropw=100&amp;croph=41.238195173137&amp;width=534&amp;height=306&amp;compression=70 640w,https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159870.jpg?imageId=73159870&amp;x=0&amp;y=18.992654774397&amp;cropw=100&amp;croph=41.238195173137&amp;width=632&amp;height=362&amp;compression=80 1024w,https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159870.jpg?imageId=73159870&amp;x=0&amp;y=18.992654774397&amp;cropw=100&amp;croph=41.238195173137&amp;width=688&amp;height=394&amp;compression=80 1240w" src="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159870.jpg?imageId=73159870&amp;x=0&amp;y=18.992654774397&amp;cropw=100&amp;croph=41.238195173137&amp;width=688&amp;height=394">
</picture>
      
    
    


      <figcaption itemprop="caption" data-expand="" onclick="this.classList.add('active')">
        <strong>SPOKESWOMAN:</strong> Guri Solberg at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs. Photo: MFA
          <span role="button">Vis mer</span>
      </figcaption>
</figure>
<p><strong>Solberg adds: “For reasons of confidentiality, we cannot share details in individual cases.”</strong></p>
<p>The men arrived in Norway at the end of July 2018. The one security guard who received the diplomatic status Saudi Arabia requested, now works as Head of Security at the Saudi Arabian embassy, according to Dagbladet's sources. He is formally listed in the Foreign Ministry's diplomatic list as an "attaché".</p><div>
  <div>
      
<section id="middle-east-tips">
  
  <p> Skjult støtte fra autoritære stater </p>
  
  <img src="https://graphics.dbstatic.no/Grafikk/middle-east/mosk-lilla.svg" alt="moske grafikk">
  <img src="https://graphics.dbstatic.no/Grafikk/middle-east/money2.svg" alt="pengesedler">
  
</section>


  </div>
</div>
<p>“It was a discussion. There are regulations for the type of status that the embassies' security people can hold whilst staying in Norway. They are not diplomats”, a source familiar with the case tells Dagbladet.</p><div id="factbox-73180109" aria-expanded="false" tabindex="1">
    <h2>Facts: Diplomatic immunity in Norway</h2>
        
    
        <p>According to the Vienna Convention on Diplomatic Relations, all envoys from other countries have diplomatic immunity when they are working for their country’s embassy. This applies to both diplomats and administrative personnel, such as security staff. <br></p><p>However, different degrees of immunity are granted, according to the rank of the individual within the system. Only diplomats have full immunity. <br></p><p>Neither diplomats nor security staff at embassies can be prosecuted or subjected to taxation in Norway. Security staff (administrative personnel) do not, however, have immunity from civil proceedings arising from their conduct in private. Whilst diplomats can import as much as they desire tax-free for private use, administrative personnel are only exempt from customs duties on entry to a country. <br></p><p>Norway can sanction an envoy with diplomatic immunity by declaring them persona non grata in Norway.</p><p><em>Source: Ministry of Foreign Affairs</em></p>
            
        
    
</div>
<h2>The Embassy</h2><div id="parallax-73159994">
    <div>

        <div data-parallax-sticky="" data-parallax-fullwidth="" data-parallax-content-type="image" data-parallax-layer="0" data-parallax-height="100" data-parallax-spacebelow="0" data-parallax-horizontalalign-desktop="" data-parallax-horizontalalign-mobile="" data-parallax-verticalalign="top" data-parallax-verticalposition="auto">
            <figure data-zoomable="1">
    
<picture>
    <source media="(max-width: 640px)" itemprop="image" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159833.jpg?imageId=73159833&amp;width=760&amp;height=434&amp;compression=70">
    <source media="(min-width: 641px and max-width: 1024px)" itemprop="image" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159833.jpg?imageId=73159833&amp;width=900&amp;height=513&amp;compression=80">
    <source media="(min-width: 1025px)" itemprop="image" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159833.jpg?imageId=73159833&amp;width=980&amp;height=559&amp;compression=80">
<img itemprop="image" data-defer="view" title="" alt="" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159833.jpg?imageId=73159833&amp;width=760&amp;height=434&amp;compression=70 640w,https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159833.jpg?imageId=73159833&amp;width=900&amp;height=513&amp;compression=80 1024w,https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159833.jpg?imageId=73159833&amp;width=980&amp;height=559&amp;compression=80 1240w" src="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159833.jpg?imageId=73159833&amp;width=980&amp;height=559">
</picture>
      
    
    


      <figcaption itemprop="caption" data-expand="" onclick="this.classList.add('active')">
        
      </figcaption>
</figure>

        </div>
        <div data-parallax-content-type="text_subtitle" data-parallax-layer="1" data-parallax-height="100" data-parallax-spacebelow="0" data-parallax-horizontalalign-desktop="" data-parallax-horizontalalign-mobile="" data-parallax-verticalalign="top" data-parallax-verticalposition="auto">
            <p>
    <h3 itemprop="name headline">The Saudi Arabian Embassy in Norway is beautifully located on Skarpsno, on the west side of Oslo, its façade faces the Oslofjord.</h3>
</p>
    
        </div>


    </div>
    
</div>


<p>If you travel by sea to the Frognerstranda harbour, at times you can spot the Kingdom's characteristic green flag - with a white sabre, and the inscription "There is no god without Allah, and Muhammad is his prophet" - waving over the hedge. From a magnificent villa, designed in 1899 by the famed Norwegian architect Ingvar Hjorth, Saudi Arabia manages its activities in Norway.</p>
<p>Dagbladet has asked the Embassy in Oslo why they requested the security guards be granted diplomatic immunity, about the points Norway reacted to, about the Embassy’s relationship with the activist Iyad el-Baghdadi, and about why the Embassy wanted to increase the number of security guards by so many.</p><p><strong>The Embassy has declined to meet with Dagbladet, preferring to respond by email, with a press release originally sent out in 2019:</strong></p><p>"The Embassy is informed about what has been circulated in some media in regard to Mr. Iyad el-Baghdadi and the allegations against the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia. The Embassy would like to clarify that this person is not a Saudi citizen and is unknown to the Kingdom. What he said is fabricated and false and aims to offend the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia. We have been in contact with the Norwegian Government to provide the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia with further information in this regard. The Kingdom of Saudi Arabia reserves the right to take the necessary legal measures against the mentioned-above in order to safeguard its rights."</p>
<p><em><strong>Update:</strong></em> <em>Dagbladet received the following statement on Thursday 17th of December:</em></p><p><em>«The Embassy of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia reiterates what was released in 2019, and denies any previous knowledge or existing relationship between the Kingdom and Iyad el-baghdadi.</em></p><p><em>In regards to the issue concerning the security guards, these guards are positioned at the embassy to provide the necessary protection, around the clock, for both the Embassy building and the Head of Mission’s residence. Saudi embassies in several countries have received threats and have been targeted by terrorist attacks - the most recent of which being the incident at the Embassy of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia in The Hague.»</em></p><h2>Briefed by the PST</h2><p>In a spartan apartment in Oslo, Dagbladet meets Iyad el-Baghdadi.</p><div id="parallax-73159998">
    <div>

        <div data-parallax-sticky="" data-parallax-fullwidth="" data-parallax-content-type="image" data-parallax-layer="0" data-parallax-height="100" data-parallax-spacebelow="0" data-parallax-horizontalalign-desktop="" data-parallax-horizontalalign-mobile="" data-parallax-verticalalign="top" data-parallax-verticalposition="auto">
            <figure data-zoomable="1">
    
<picture>
    <source media="(max-width: 640px)" itemprop="image" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159867.jpg?imageId=73159867&amp;x=0&amp;y=0&amp;cropw=100&amp;croph=99.13258983891&amp;width=940&amp;height=622&amp;compression=70">
    <source media="(min-width: 641px and max-width: 1024px)" itemprop="image" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159867.jpg?imageId=73159867&amp;x=0&amp;y=0&amp;cropw=100&amp;croph=99.13258983891&amp;width=1113&amp;height=736&amp;compression=80">
    <source media="(min-width: 1025px)" itemprop="image" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159867.jpg?imageId=73159867&amp;x=0&amp;y=0&amp;cropw=100&amp;croph=99.13258983891&amp;width=1212&amp;height=801&amp;compression=80">
<img itemprop="image" data-defer="view" title="" alt="" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159867.jpg?imageId=73159867&amp;x=0&amp;y=0&amp;cropw=100&amp;croph=99.13258983891&amp;width=940&amp;height=622&amp;compression=70 640w,https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159867.jpg?imageId=73159867&amp;x=0&amp;y=0&amp;cropw=100&amp;croph=99.13258983891&amp;width=1113&amp;height=736&amp;compression=80 1024w,https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159867.jpg?imageId=73159867&amp;x=0&amp;y=0&amp;cropw=100&amp;croph=99.13258983891&amp;width=1212&amp;height=801&amp;compression=80 1240w" src="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159867.jpg?imageId=73159867&amp;x=0&amp;y=0&amp;cropw=100&amp;croph=99.13258983891&amp;width=1212&amp;height=801">
</picture>
      
    
    


      <figcaption itemprop="caption" data-expand="" onclick="this.classList.add('active')">
        
      </figcaption>
</figure>

        </div>
        <div data-parallax-content-type="text_subtitle" data-parallax-layer="1" data-parallax-height="100" data-parallax-spacebelow="0" data-parallax-horizontalalign-desktop="" data-parallax-horizontalalign-mobile="" data-parallax-verticalalign="top" data-parallax-verticalposition="auto">
            <p>
    <h3 itemprop="name headline">He is the critic who was informed by the PST about the Saudi Arabian Embassy requesting diplomatic status for ten security guards.</h3>
</p>
    
        </div>


    </div>
    
</div>


<p>The apartment where he currently lives – he moves regularly - contains little other than various cutlery, some clothes, and computer equipment with heavy encryption. A small room with weights and exercise equipment emphasizes the need, as he says, to always stay “sharp”.</p>
<p>According to Dagbladet’s information it is the Oslo police district which oversee his security.</p><p><strong>He claims they advised him to move out of his previous apartment not too long ago.</strong></p><p>El-Baghdadi, originally a stateless Palestinian, became an influential voice - particularly on Twitter - during the Arab Spring. He was a friend of Jamal Khashoggi, the journalist who was killed in October 2018 at the Saudi consulate in Istanbul.</p><p>He is also a staunch critic of Mohammed bin Salman's Saudi Arabia.</p><figure data-zoomable="1">
    
<picture>
    <source media="(max-width: 640px)" itemprop="image" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159534.jpg?imageId=73159534&amp;width=760&amp;height=434&amp;compression=70">
    <source media="(min-width: 641px and max-width: 1024px)" itemprop="image" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159534.jpg?imageId=73159534&amp;width=900&amp;height=513&amp;compression=80">
    <source media="(min-width: 1025px)" itemprop="image" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159534.jpg?imageId=73159534&amp;width=980&amp;height=559&amp;compression=80">
<img itemprop="image" data-defer="view" title="STAYED HERE: Jamal Khashoggi stayed at the Hotel Christiania Theater when visiting Oslo in May 2018. Photo: NTB/Terje Pedersen" alt="STAYED HERE: Jamal Khashoggi stayed at the Hotel Christiania Theater when visiting Oslo in May 2018. Photo: NTB/Terje Pedersen" srcset="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159534.jpg?imageId=73159534&amp;width=760&amp;height=434&amp;compression=70 640w,https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159534.jpg?imageId=73159534&amp;width=900&amp;height=513&amp;compression=80 1024w,https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159534.jpg?imageId=73159534&amp;width=980&amp;height=559&amp;compression=80 1240w" src="https://www.dagbladet.no/images/73159534.jpg?imageId=73159534&amp;width=980&amp;height=559">
</picture>
      
    
    


      <figcaption itemprop="caption" data-expand="" onclick="this.classList.add('active')">
        <strong>STAYED HERE:</strong> Jamal Khashoggi stayed at the Hotel …</figcaption></figure></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.dagbladet.no/nyheter/the-saudi-security-team-to-norway/73159458">https://www.dagbladet.no/nyheter/the-saudi-security-team-to-norway/73159458</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.dagbladet.no/nyheter/the-saudi-security-team-to-norway/73159458</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25427829</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 07:16:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Legally Free Python Books List]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 166 | Comments 38 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25427504">thread link</a>) | @osdotsystem
<br/>
December 14, 2020 | https://www.pythonkitchen.com/legally-free-python-books-list/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.pythonkitchen.com/legally-free-python-books-list/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			
<p>Here is my personal list of legally free Python books. <strong>Warning: Packt free books are highly unreliable, what can be free today can no longer be free tomorrow They were included as they are free at the time of writing this post. Similarly is Oreilly’s case. The two publishing houses have been annotated as necessary.</strong> In case of no longer free or broken links please mail me at `arj.python at gmail dot com` to update article. I have to thank the internet who took the pain to point these resources to me. I have skimmed through the contents to producs a list of legally free Python books of value. Here’s how i evaluated books (you might not agree, but that’s my personal take on it):</p>




<p>Some popular listed books like Python Module of the Week  is not a book and Tango with Django 1.7 is outdated.  Materials which provide only some free chapters are not free books. Docs manuals are docs manuals, you’d have to include a quarter of pypi’s packages manuals then. github projects are gihub projects unless it’s a book. Mark pilgrim ran away so should we from his book. We don’t want some illegal 100+ free list (Mark Lutz books are not free mind you), you could include all Python books hosted on drive then. Python2 is past, we passed over. Fullstackpython’s list is a collection of various sites’ articles, not a book. Really short books more qualified as leaflets did not make it. Such materials have been deliberately left out. What remains are books that you’ll enjoy!</p><p>


Note: was pythonmembers.club before, so if you have the domain’s link, please update


</p><p>Let’s start! <b>Click on the titles to view/download the book.</b></p>



<h2>INTRODUCTORY MATERIALS</h2>



<h3> <a href="http://greenteapress.com/thinkpython2/thinkpython2.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Think Python </a></h3>



<p>Allen Downey</p>




<h3><a href="https://anandology.com/python-practice-book/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Python Practice Book</a> </h3>



<p> Anand Chitipothu</p>



<p> This book is prepared from the training notes of&nbsp;Anand Chitipothu. </p>



<h3><a href="https://dabeaz-course.github.io/practical-python/Notes/Contents.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Practical Python Programming</a> </h3>



<p> David Beazley</p>



<p> Highly recommended book. Normally taught in 3/4 days. It offers solid foundations. This course is taught to scientists and engineers. The name of the author is a trademark of excellence. Do read it even if you already know Python! </p>



<h3> <a href="https://www.packtpub.com/free-ebooks/learn-python-programming-second-edition" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Learn Python Programming – Second Edition</a> </h3>



<p> Fabrizio Romano – Packt</p>



<p>Learn Python Programming is a quick, thorough, and practical introduction to Python – an extremely flexible and powerful programming language that can be applied to many disciplines. You will begin by learning the fundamentals of Python so that you have a rock-solid foundation to build upon. Covers some data science, GUI and web (Django).</p>



<h3><a href="http://do1.dr-chuck.com/pythonlearn/EN_us/pythonlearn.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Python For Everybody</a></h3>



<p>Charles R. Severance</p>



<p>The goal of this book is to provide an Informatics-oriented introduction to programming. The primary approach taken in this book is using Python to solve data analysis problems common in the world of Informatics. </p>



<h3><a href="https://krother.gitbooks.io/python-3-basics-tutorial/content/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Python 3 Basics Tutorial</a></h3>



<p>Dr. Kristian Rother</p>



<p>The perfect introduction for completely new people </p>



<h3><a href="https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/Non-Programmer%27s_Tutorial_for_Python_3" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Non-Programmer’s Tutorial for Python 3</a></h3>



<p>Josh Cogliati</p>



<p> The Non-Programmers’ Tutorial For Python 3 is a tutorial designed to be an introduction to the Python programming language. This guide is for someone with no programming experience. </p>



<h3> <a href="http://www.spronck.net/pythonbook/pythonbook.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Coder’s Apprentice </a></h3>



<p> Pieter Spronck </p>



<p> “The Coder’s Apprentice” aims at teaching Python 3 to students and teenagers who are completely new to programming. Contrary to many of the other books that teach Python programming, this book assumes no previous knowledge of programming on the part of the students, and contains numerous exercises that allow students to train their programming skills. </p>



<h3> <a href="https://www.brianheinold.net/python/python_book.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">A Practical Introduction to Python Programming </a></h3>



<p> Brian Heinold </p>



<p> The book aims at striking the balance between a tutorial and reference book. Includes some fun exercises at the end! </p>



<h3> <a href="https://python.swaroopch.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">A Byte of Python </a></h3>



<p>Swaroop C H</p>



<p>“A Byte of Python” is a free book on programming using the Python language. It serves as a tutorial or guide to the Python language for a beginner audience. If all you know about computers is how to save text files, then this is the book for you. </p>



<h3><a href="https://buildmedia.readthedocs.org/media/pdf/intermediatepythongithubio/latest/intermediatepythongithubio.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Intermediate Python</a></h3>



<p> Muhammad Yasoob Ullah Khalid </p>



<p> Python is an amazing language with a strong and friendly community of programmers. However, there is a lack of documentation on what to learn after getting the basics of Python down your throat. Through this book I aim to solve this problem. I would give you bits of information about some interesting topics which you can further explore. The topics which are discussed in this book open up your mind towards some nice corners of Python language. This book is an outcome of my desire to have something like this when I was beginning to learn Python. If you are a beginner, intermediate or even an advanced programmer there is something for you in this book. Please note that this book is not a tutorial and does not teach you Python. The topics are not explained in depth, instead only the minimum required information is given.  A true example of legally free Python books. </p>



<h3><a href="http://ralsina.gitlab.io/boxes-book/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Boxes: Your Second Python Book</a></h3>



<p>Roberto Alcina</p>



<p>This book tries to achieve only one thing: Show you a project go from&nbsp;<strong>nothing</strong>&nbsp;to&nbsp;<strong>OK</strong>. By nothing I mean, no code at all. Not even a fleshed idea of what it does. No goals, no commitments. Just a vague interest. And by OK I mean it will work, it will have tests, it will be available to use, it will be&nbsp;<strong>useful</strong>&nbsp;and be a real thing. Think of it as a sort of documentary on the beginnings of a rock band, only instead of rockers there is a single overweight Argentinian dev, and instead of a band there is a piece of software. So, not much like a documentary on the beginnings of a rock band.</p>



<h3><a href="https://learnpythonbreakpython.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Learn Python, Break Python</a></h3>



<p>Scott Grant</p>



<p>Learn Python, Break Python is a hands-on introduction to the Python programming language, written for people who have no experience with programming whatsoever. Hey, we all have to start somewhere. As such, the examples and teaching style used in this text make absolutely no expectations about your prior programming experience. Anyone can pick up the art of programming with a little time and a bit of patience. However, when learning something new, I try to break things. In fact, in many cases, I go out of my way to break stuff. When picking up a new concept like computer programming, you can actually increase your comfort level by figuring out the type of cases that are likely to break. You’ll see what data can be used and where, and when you inevitably run into errors later (like everyone does), you won’t be surprised.</p>



<h3><a href="https://www.eecs.wsu.edu/~schneidj/PyBook/swan.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Algorithmic Problem Solving with Python</a> </h3>



<p> John B. Schneider, Shira Lynn Broschat, Jess Dahmen </p>



<p>(Not an algo book) Python’s syntax and idioms are much easier to learn than those of most other full-featured languages. This book uses programming language Python to introduce folks to programming and algorithmic thinking. </p>



<h3> <a href="https://buildmedia.readthedocs.org/media/pdf/python-guide/latest/python-guide.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Hitchhiker’s Guide to Python.</a></h3>



<p>Kenneth Reitz</p>



<p> This opinionated guide exists to provide both novice and expert Python developers a best-practice handbook to the installation, configuration, and usage of Python on a daily basis. </p>



<h3><a href="https://www.slitherintopython.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Slither Into Python</a></h3>



<p> Slither into Python is an introduction to Python for complete beginners. No prior programming experience or computer science background is necessary. Unlike any other Python resources I have found (not that they’re not out there), they don’t explain important computer science concepts such as memory or “how computers work”. In this book I will cover the fundamentals of the Python language and also introduce these important concepts. Put simply,&nbsp;<em>coding</em>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<em>computer programming</em>&nbsp;is about making computers do what you want, Computer Science is about&nbsp;<em>how</em>&nbsp;computers do it. Each go hand-in-hand, help you learn faster and improve your overall understanding of a language! This book aims to do exactly that through Python. </p>



<h3><a href="https://www.oreilly.com/programming/free/files/a-whirlwind-tour-of-python.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">A Whirlwind Tour of Python</a></h3>



<p>Jake VanderPlas – Oreilly</p>



<p>The book provides a whirlwind tour of some of Python’s essential syntax and semantics, built-in data types and structures, function definitions, control flow statements, and other aspects of the language. My aim is that readers will walk away with a solid foundation from which to explore the data science stack just outlined. </p>



<h3><a href="https://pymbook.readthedocs.io/en/latest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Python For You and Me</a></h3>



<p>Kushal Das (Core Dev)</p>



<p> A book for the total new comers into Python world. Was started as book for students before they read Python tutorial. Given it’s from a core dev, even up to chapter choice order is insightful.</p>



<h3> <a href="https://prappleizer.github.io/textbook.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Python for Astronomers </a></h3>



<p> Imad Pasha, Christopher Agostino </p>



<p> This text is designed to be an introduction to the Python programming language — which is now used nearly ubiquitously in astronomy — with applications to the types of tasks an undergraduate (or beginning graduate student) might have to tackle. It is not, in any way, meant to be comprehensive; my focus is on bringing you up to speed as efficiently and quickly as possible. This text might have useful information for those with a working knowledge of Python outside of a research setting, but is primarily designed for those with no prior programming experience. By the end of this text, I hope to have shared enough to make you feel comfortable taking the first steps into research-type problems (of which this book will contain several examples), whether in an astronomy course, a research internship, or on-campus research. </p>



<h3><a href="https://leanpub.com/intermediatepython" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OBI Intermediate Python</a></h3>



<p> Obi Ike-Nwosu </p>



<p>The python ecosystem is awash with books for beginners but few books target readers that are past the beginning stages but are not yet advanced users. The book aims to bridge that gap. The content of this book looks primarily at the various means for code organization in Python and provides user with a rigorous grounding in these. it dives into topics such as python object system, functions, decorators, metaprogramming and generators providing the reader with an in-depth knowledge of these topics that is essential for writing idiomatic and robust python code. It aims to&nbsp; provide a reader with not only a …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.pythonkitchen.com/legally-free-python-books-list/">https://www.pythonkitchen.com/legally-free-python-books-list/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.pythonkitchen.com/legally-free-python-books-list/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25427504</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 06:07:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I assume I’m below average (2010)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 358 | Comments 211 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25426976">thread link</a>) | @enigmatic02
<br/>
December 14, 2020 | https://sive.rs/below-average | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://sive.rs/below-average">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">

<article>
<header>
<div><p>from the book “<a href="https://sive.rs/n">Hell Yeah or No</a>”:</p></div>

<small>2010-07-01</small>
  <audio src="https://m.sive.rs/sive.rs.below-average.mp3" preload="none" controls="controls"></audio>
</header>

<p>
	Ninety-six percent of cancer patients claim to be in better health than the average cancer patient.
</p><p>
	Ninety-four percent of professors say they are better-than-average teachers.
</p><p>
	Ninety percent of students think they are more intelligent than the average student.
</p><p>
	Ninety-three percent of drivers say they are safer-than-average drivers.
</p><p>
	When I learned this, it shook my soul.
	At first, like almost everybody, I thought, “Yes, but I really am above average!”
	Then I realized I was doing it again.
</p><p>
	So I decided to gamble on the opposite.
	Now I just assume I’m below average.
</p><p>
	It serves me well.
	I listen more.
	I ask a lot of questions.
	I’ve stopped thinking <a href="https://sive.rs/ss">others are stupid</a>.
	I assume most people are smarter than me.
</p><p>
<strong>
	To assume you’re below average is to admit you’re still learning.
</strong>
	You focus on what you need to improve, not your <a href="https://sive.rs/expire">past accomplishments</a>.
</p><p>
	Many people are so worried about looking good that they never do anything great.
	Many people are so worried about doing something great that they never do anything at all.
</p><p>
	You destroy that paralysis when you think of yourself as just a student, and your current actions as just practice.
</p>


</article>



</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://sive.rs/below-average</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25426976</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 04:22:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[TP-Link Archer VR1600V V2 Super User Password Cracked]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 159 | Comments 93 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25426566">thread link</a>) | @stubish
<br/>
December 14, 2020 | https://www.marcelvarallo.com/so-we-cracked-the-archer-vr1600v-v2-super-user-password/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.marcelvarallo.com/so-we-cracked-the-archer-vr1600v-v2-super-user-password/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="page">






<div id="content">
	<div id="primary">
		<main id="main" role="main" itemprop="mainContentOfPage">



<article role="article" id="post-1523" itemscope="" itemprop="blogPost" itemtype="https://schema.org/BlogPosting">

	<meta itemscope="" itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage">
	<div itemprop="articleBody">

		
		<p>Well the news is out, I won’t explain the method for reasons, but our code warriors have a new fight. After requesting the SU password, they were told flat out it doesn’t exist and referred to the manual by the vendor. Taking that argument to the telco ombudsman got the same response. If there were one and you wanted to change it for security reasons, it looks like you can’t and with the vendors denying it’s existance, there’s no help coming.</p>
<p>So, the password for the SU account that doesn’t exist…</p>
<p>VExy!64a3ng</p>

		
	</div>

	
	<nav role="navigation">
		<h2>Post navigation</h2>
		
	</nav>
</article>


	

	

		</main><!-- /#main -->
	</div><!-- /#primary -->
</div><!-- /#content -->






</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.marcelvarallo.com/so-we-cracked-the-archer-vr1600v-v2-super-user-password/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25426566</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 03:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Challenging the ‘Great Reset’ theory of pandemics]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 22 | Comments 9 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25426174">thread link</a>) | @fremden
<br/>
December 14, 2020 | https://engelsbergideas.com/essays/challenging-the-great-reset-theory-of-pandemics/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://engelsbergideas.com/essays/challenging-the-great-reset-theory-of-pandemics/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-id="9549bc7" data-element_type="widget" data-settings="{&quot;_animation&quot;:&quot;fadeIn&quot;,&quot;_animation_delay&quot;:500}" data-widget_type="theme-post-content.default">
				<div>
			
<p>Few events are as compelling as an epidemic. When sufficiently severe, an epidemic evokes responses from every sector of society, laying bare&nbsp;social and economic fault lines and presenting politicians with fraught medical and moral choices. In the most extreme cases, an epidemic can foment a full-blown political crisis. Thus,&nbsp;Thucydides describes how the repeated visitations of plague to Athens in 430-426 BC&nbsp;provoked widespread social disorder and the breakdown of civic norms.</p>



<p>‘Men, not knowing what was to become of them, became utterly careless of everything, whether sacred or profane,’ writes Thucydides. ‘All the burial rites before in use were entirely upset and… many had recourse to the most shameless sepulchres.’</p>



<p>As the plague progresses, Thucydides describes how Athenians were swept up in a wave of hedonism and lawlessness, threatening the foundations of Athenian democracy: ‘Men now coolly ventured on what they had formerly done in a corner… fear of gods or law of man there was none to restrain them.’</p>



<p>The resulting crisis, Thucydides claimed, undermined Athenians’ faith in the rule of law and the democratic principles that underpinned the Greek city state, paving the way for the installation of a Spartan oligarchy known as the Thirty Tyrants. Even though the Spartans were later ejected, Athens never regained its confidence.</p>



<p>Covid-19 appears to have engendered a similar crisis in our world, the main difference being in scale. Whereas the crisis Thucydides describes was confined to Athens, the coronavirus pandemic has destabilized governments from Brazil to Belarus,&nbsp;not just that of a 5<sup>th</sup>&nbsp;century city-state. The political reckoning has been particularly rapid in the United States, where Donald Trump’s inability or unwillingness to check the spread of the coronavirus was a key factor in his recent election defeat. Now, the lockdowns and social distancing measures look set&nbsp;to&nbsp;plunge the world into the worst economic depression since the 1930s, raising the spectre of further political instability.</p>



<p>Given the wide-ranging&nbsp;social, economic and political impacts of Covid-19, it is natural to assume that the same must have been true of past epidemics and pandemics. But is this the case? Do pandemics really have the historical impacts that are often claimed for them or are these claims simply the product of particular narratives and readings of history? &nbsp;</p>



<p>For instance, in&nbsp;numerical terms, the most devastating pandemic of all time was the 1918-19 ‘Spanish influenza’. Coinciding with the end of the First World War, the Spanish flu is estimated to have killed between fifty to one hundred million people worldwide. However, while 1919 was the first year since records began that the death rate exceeded the birth rate, those that survived generally enjoyed longer and healthier lifespans and, in many instances, benefited from higher wages too. Moreover, while the global death toll was immense, in developed industrial countries the mortality rate averaged two percent, meaning the Spanish flu left most of society unaffected. Indeed, the Spanish flu appears to have made little impression on public memory and social institutions, hence its historiographical characterisation as the&nbsp;<a href="https://theconversation.com/why-historians-ignored-the-spanish-flu-101950" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">‘forgotten pandemic’.</a></p>



<h2 id="h-narrating-epidemic-crises">Narrating Epidemic Crises</h2>



<p>A crisis is normally conceived of as an isolated moment in time in which our lives are shattered and plunged into disorder – what the cultural anthropologist Hendrik Vigh has called&nbsp;‘a momentary malformation in the flow of things’.&nbsp;Vigh <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/00141840801927509" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">observes that</a> for many people crises are ‘endemic rather than episodic’ and cannot be delineated as an aberrant moment of chaos or a period of decisive change.&nbsp;This is particularly the case for those living at the margins of society for whom crises are ever present. Indeed, social critics such as Naomi Klein argue that instability is baked into the capitalist system, hence the way that&nbsp;in the last few decades<strong>&nbsp;</strong>neoliberal societies have lurched from one financial crisis to another.</p>



<p>Nevertheless, crises have long been regarded as a way of accessing deeper historical truths. As Janet Roitman <a href="https://read.dukeupress.edu/books/book/330/Anti-Crisis" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">has argued</a> in&nbsp;<em>Anti-Crisis</em>&nbsp;(2013), a crisis ‘marks and generates history’. This is particularly the case for epidemics and pandemics which, unlike other natural disasters such as famines, are not limited to a particular region or moment in time but may come to encompass the whole globe. As the medical anthropologist Christos Lynteris <a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/i40144420" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">puts it</a>, disease outbreaks involve a ‘radically different ontological order’, a mode of being that is simultaneously ‘pathological and infectious’. Or to put it another way, one could conceivably outrun a famine but those who try to flee a plague may become unwitting carriers, contaminating new communities and introducing the pathogen to new places.</p>



<p>What is also not widely appreciated is that the roots of the term ‘crisis’ lie in the Ancient Greek word&nbsp;<em>krinô</em>&nbsp;(meaning to separate, choose, cut, decide, judge) and can be traced back to Hippocrates, whose scientific method influenced Thucydides’ approach to history. For the Hippocratic school of medicine, prognosis took precedence over diagnosis, the point being to identify the turning point of a disease in order to intervene and bring about a satisfactory resolution to the illness. Similarly, Thucydides hoped that by tracking the social and moral dissolution that envelopes Athens under the strain of the plague, his history could serve as a ‘great case-book of social pathology’, enabling readers to recognise similar historical patterns in future and intervene so as to restore order and stability. In this way, <a href="https://www.waterstones.com/book/the-invention-of-medicine/robin-lane-fox/9780241277058#:~:text=Robin%20Lane%20Fox's%20remarkable%20book,that%20survive%20under%20his%20name." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">it has been argued</a>, Thucydides applied a medical template to epidemic crises that has coloured our interpretation of them ever since.</p>



<h2 id="h-the-black-death-and-demographic-change">The Black Death and demographic change</h2>



<p>Perhaps the standout example of the transformative power of disease is the fourteenth century Black Death. Caused by the plague bacillus,&nbsp;<em>Yersinia pestis</em>, the pandemic coincided with the transition from medieval to early modern European society and was greatly enhanced by new shipping networks linking Venice and Genoa with Constantinople, Tunis, London and Bruges. The larger broad-bellied ships required for these long voyages provided perfect conveyances for plague-carrying rats and were soon sparking outbreaks across Europe.</p>



<p>Some scholars claim the pandemic killed a third of Europe’s then population between 1347 and 1353; others say up to one half. Whatever the true mortality there is little doubt the Black Death represented a massive external shock to medieval society and, together with the famines that preceded it, contributed to a declining or stagnant population in Europe for almost 150 years afterwards. The result was a demographic, economic and political crisis.</p>



<p>A smaller population meant less demand for grain putting downward pressure on the price of basic foodstuffs. At the same time, a diminished population fuelled competition, exerting upward pressure on wages and challenging the villeinage system of forced labour that underpinned the feudal system. The result was a wave of popular uprisings across Europe, including the Jacquerie in France in 1358, the revolt of the Florentine&nbsp;<em>Ciompi</em>&nbsp;or wool carders in 1378-82, and the 1381 Peasants’ Revolt in England. &nbsp;</p>



<p>The demands of English peasants included the abolition of an inequitable poll tax and the removal of a statute, passed in the wake of the Black Death, that sought to restrict wages to pre-pandemic levels. The Florentine carders meanwhile demanded a more equitable fiscal policy and the right to establish guilds, fore runners of trade unions. Today, we take collective wage bargaining and trade unions for granted, but in the fourteenth century these demands threatened the basis of the feudal system, hence the observation of the French chronicler Jean Froissart that: ‘Never was any land or realm in such great danger as England at that time.’</p>



<p>This economic levelling also spurred a series of social and cultural changes, including the right of everyone except the lowliest manual worker to wear furs – a privilege that previously had been the preserve of nobles and clerics.&nbsp;In most cases the political reforms were short-lived. For instance,&nbsp;<a href="http://www.bl.uk/learning/timeline/item126561.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wat Tyler</a>, the leader of the English rebels, marched to London to petition King Richard II with 60,000 peasants at his back. Demanding that ‘all men should be free and of one condition’, the rebels occupied the Tower of London, ransacked the palaces and mansions of wealthy Londoners, and executed the Archbishop of Canterbury and the Lord Chief Justice, as well as other hated representatives of the nobility. Within a few weeks Wat Tyler and other leaders of the revolt had been arrested and executed and the crisis was over. Nonetheless, the movement resulted in concessions to peasants: the poll tax was abandoned, and wage bargaining expanded over time, leading to the emergence of a new yeoman class.</p>



<h2 id="h-the-collapse-of-the-aztec-and-incan-empires">The collapse of the Aztec and Incan empires</h2>



<p>Similar claims&nbsp;have been made about the crisis that enveloped the Aztec and Incan empires following the Spanish Conquest of Central and South America in the early sixteenth century. In&nbsp;<em>Plagues and Peoples</em>, McNeill&nbsp;<a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Plagues-People-William-McNeill/dp/0385121229" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">argued that</a>&nbsp;‘disaster is to be expected whenever some previously remote and isolated tribe comes into contact with the outside world and there encounters a series of destructive and demoralizing epidemics.’</p>



<p>In the case of the Aztecs and Inca, the&nbsp;root cause of crisis and societal collapse&nbsp;was the introduction by Columbus and, later, the conquistador Hernan Cortez, of smallpox, measles and other Old World diseases to which Amerindian populations of modern-day Mexico, Guatemala and Peru had little or no immunity. The result was that&nbsp;within a century of Cortes’s arrival in the Gulf of Mexico in 1518 the population of Central Mexico had been reduced, according to some estimates, from 25 million to 1.5 million. A similar demographic …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://engelsbergideas.com/essays/challenging-the-great-reset-theory-of-pandemics/">https://engelsbergideas.com/essays/challenging-the-great-reset-theory-of-pandemics/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://engelsbergideas.com/essays/challenging-the-great-reset-theory-of-pandemics/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25426174</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 02:03:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
