<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 20]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 20. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 04:26:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-20.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 04:26:39 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Build a Minimum Loveable Product]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 47 | Comments 25 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25175220">thread link</a>) | @grwthckrmstr
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | https://www.preetamnath.com/micro-saas/minimum-loveable-product-micro-saas | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.preetamnath.com/micro-saas/minimum-loveable-product-micro-saas">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>You've validated your micro-SaaS idea and are ready to start building the product.</p><p>The obvious next questions are</p><ol start="" role="list"><li>Which features should the product include in its first version?</li><li>How long should you take to build it?</li></ol><p>Through this post, I provide you with a framework to identify your initial product features, how to decide what to include or exclude from the first versions, and continue building upon it.</p><p>Before jumping into MLP, let's first understand what MVP&nbsp;is and why it's not enough in today's times.</p><h2>What is a Minimum Viable Product (MVP)?</h2><p><a href="https://twitter.com/ericries" target="_blank">Eric Ries</a> popularized the term <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minimum_viable_product" target="_blank">minimum viable product</a> in his book <a href="http://theleanstartup.com/" target="_blank">The Lean Startup</a> as that version of a new product that is just usable enough by early customers who can then provide feedback to the team. This feedback should help the team generate validated learnings and guide them on future product development and features.</p><h4>When MVP still works</h4><p>MVP is not dead though. It still works, given the right kind of problem statements.</p><p>Suppose you're building something that simply doesn't exist in the world, and it's something that people really want and have no alternative to getting it except from you.</p><p>At this time, people will accept a textbook MVP, simply because they have no frame of reference to compare it with. Or better yet, because they have no alternative to replace your MVP with.</p><h4>Why MVP&nbsp;is not enough in 2021</h4><p>Over the past few years as smartphone penetration boomed, products matured, product design and user experience matured, people's expectations have increased.</p><p>No longer does a quickly thrown together prototype cut it. People expect a minimum level of good UX and ease-of-use, else they'll leave your app before even giving it a proper try.</p><p>In fact, in 2021 great UX might be one strong reason people pick your product over incumbents. That's what happened with <a href="https://transistor.fm/" target="_blank">Transistor.fm</a>, who made podcast hosting simple and easy.</p><p>People expect good aesthetics that make a first impression, simply because that's what they have become used to from the plethora of beautiful and well-designed apps out there in the world.</p><p>People expect products to be fully functional as advertised. Buggy products are not acceptable, and in fact people might quickly take to Twitter or social media to let others know that a product is unreliable.</p><p>The MVP mindset intensely focuses on building the bare minimum, and that often leaves users frustrated and drives them to seek alternative solutions. Stiffer competition means that people WILL compare your product to alternatives in the market, it's inevitable. And unless you provide something unique and valuable that nobody else does, people are likely to leave.</p><p>All these reasons and more make MVP&nbsp;a dated concept, especially in the context of SaaS products. But above all, I think the MVP mindset makes product builders think too heavily about the "minimum" and often so at the cost of "viable".</p><p>That's a common pitfall and to avoid that, I propose the MLP framework.</p><h2>What is a Minimum Loveable Product (MLP)?</h2><p>A great new concept that I've fallen in love with and personally follow in every product I build is MLP, or Minimum Loveable Product.</p><p>The term MLP was first coined by Brian de Haaff, the co-founder of Aha!, in his book <a href="https://www.aha.io/lovability" target="_blank">Lovability</a>.</p><p>Its definition is an extension of what Eric Ries already introduced to the world with MVP. With MLP though, you are trying to build the minimum "loveable" product, with a focus on no matter how small or feature-stripped the first version of your product is, it is sufficient to deliver a delightful experience to your user.</p><h4>Minimum Viable Product and the burnt pizza analogy</h4><p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jiaona/" target="_blank">Jiaona Zhang</a>, who is currently VP&nbsp;of Product at Webflow (this blog is built using Webflow) introduced the <a href="https://firstround.com/review/dont-serve-burnt-pizza-and-other-lessons-in-building-minimum-lovable-products/" target="_blank">burnt pizza analogy</a> to her students at Stanford.</p><p>“<em>Say you’re trying to test whether people like pizza. If you serve them burnt pizza, you’re not getting feedback on whether they like pizza. You only know that they don’t like burnt pizza. Similarly, when you’re only relying on the MVP, the fastest and cheapest functional prototype, you risk not actually testing your product, but rather a poor or flawed version of it.</em>"</p><p>A great practical example of Minimum Loveable Product is the Apple iPad. All the tablets that came before Apple's tablet were MVPs.</p><h2>MLP vs MVP</h2><p>If you're new to all these terminologies, I understand that it can be confusing. Bear with me, you'll wrap your head around it soon enough.</p><p>Build an MLP when you are solving a problem that's already understood by people, and an MVP when people don't easily understand a problem.</p><p>Build an MLP when you can clearly define and understand a market and you are trying to stand out from the existing tools. Build an MVP when you're trying to gauge if there even exists a market to serve.</p><p>An&nbsp;MLP can be built when you know exactly what customers want. An MVP is when you don't know what customers want, and therefore you want to throw things at the wall as quickly as possible and see what sticks.</p><p>An MLP is necessary if you are building in a market where several large and well-known alternatives already exist. An MVP is the right approach for a new market with barely any alternatives, or those solutions are not yet known by the masses.</p><p>While building an MLP, you make a dedicated effort to succeed with that idea. With MVP, you are trying to determine quickly whether the idea can succeed or whether it will fail.</p><p>Building an&nbsp;MVP means you're ready for failure and also ready to pivot quickly as you learn more about the market. Which means you should make tech and architecture decisions that help you move fast above anything else. Scalability or good architecture design is a concern to pay attention to while building an MLP.</p><p>Finally, the end goal of an MLP is that the customers who use it find it sufficient in functionality and experience to be able to "love" it. With an MLP, you're building just enough that a customer with (hopefully) a real pain point would "tolerate" and continue using your product while you validate your assumptions.</p><h2>Minimum Marketable Product, Minimum Remarkable Product, Minimum Launchable Product</h2><p>The what?</p><p>I know, I know. I came across these terms for the first time today while researching to write this post. And I went through the literature so that I can tell you to safely ignore it.</p><p>If you understand and embody the concept of MLP, you don't need to think about any other frameworks or terminologies that you may discover while researching on Google.</p><h2>How to build an MLP for your Micro SaaS idea</h2><p>Alright, let's put aside theory and dive right in.</p><p>Here are the steps you should loosely follow to building an MLP.</p><h4>1. Understand the #1 problem you're trying to solve</h4><p>What's the #1 reason someone would want to use your Micro SaaS product over existing alternatives?</p><p>Is it that existing options have poor UX?&nbsp;Great, create a well designed and easy-to-use product. You'd be surprised to know how often people switch to an easier to use tool, simply because they are fed up of the poor UX that they encounter repeatedly.</p><p>Is it that existing alternatives are very expensive?&nbsp;Carve out a minimum set of features that people are paying a lot of money for and charge 1/10th for your v1 product. This might not work for very large customers, but vast majority of customers who are small or mid-sized are always looking for affordable alternatives.</p><p>It might not just be raw quantum of pricing, but certain companies targeting Enterprise customers have very complicated pricing slabs and tiers that are designed to give their sales person more room. In such a case, coming out with a competitor product which has a simple, easy-to-understand pricing is how you attract customers.</p><p>Are existing alternatives lacking certain features that leaves a subset of users very dissatisfied?&nbsp;Great, your MLP should specifically address that problem by building functionality that attracts these dissatisfied users. Side note - This is perhaps one of the best ways to go about building a new product.</p><p>In all cases, it involves understanding the problem you are solving and the exact reason why someone would use your product.</p><h4>2. Design a simple product that solves the top customer needs satisfactorily</h4><p>Once you have identified the #1 reason, it's time to decide on a feature set for your product that solves your customer's top pain points satisfactorily.</p><p><strong>Let's take an example</strong> - People want to add a feedback tracking tool inside their product, so that they can collect user feedback automatically. However, the existing solutions don't allow them to embed the feedback tracker within their tool.</p><p>That's your entry point into providing value that customers seek, but are not getting as of today.</p><p>Having understood the #1 problem, you also have to understand other requirements that fall under the "minimum" set of things you need to do to build a "loveable" product.</p><p>These could be:</p><ul role="list"><li>existing solutions are all well designed and aesthetically pleasing =&gt;&nbsp;your minimum loveable product needs to be well designed too</li><li>existing solutions are affordably priced with a easy to understand pricing structure =&gt; your MLP also needs a simple pricing structure that's affordable</li></ul><p>In general, you want to analyze your competitors and understand </p><ol start="" role="list"><li>What they are doing well</li><li>What users value from among those things</li></ol><p>In your MLP, you need to cover the intersection of (what they are doing well) x (what users value from among those).</p><h4>3. Set a short timeline for building your MLP</h4><p>No matter what you build, building in isolation for too long is dangerous. The main reason for that is - you get to know too late whether your assumptions about what the user really values are on point or off course.</p><p><strong>"But Preetam, you just told me to build a Minimum Loveable Product. And now you're saying I got to build it quickly?"</strong></p><p>Yes, that's exactly what I'm saying.</p><p>Short timeframe depends on what you are building, and the size of your team.</p><p>For example - with SuperLemon (WhatsApp plugin for Shopify), Sankalp and I built a MLP in 2 weeks time.</p><p>How?</p><p>We identified precisely the way we could do better - …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.preetamnath.com/micro-saas/minimum-loveable-product-micro-saas">https://www.preetamnath.com/micro-saas/minimum-loveable-product-micro-saas</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.preetamnath.com/micro-saas/minimum-loveable-product-micro-saas</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25175220</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 05:40:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pianists for Alternatively Sized Keyboards]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 133 | Comments 153 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25173522">thread link</a>) | @spekcular
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | http://paskpiano.org/about/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://paskpiano.org/about/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="30" data-elementor-settings="[]">
						<div>
							<div>
							<section data-id="6b7c51e" data-element_type="section">
						
		</section>
				<section data-id="0db4fdb" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="89500ce" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<section data-id="02b9628" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="c6a8384" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="39c182b" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div>
					<div><p>PASK – Pianists for Alternatively Sized Keyboards – is an international movement committed to achieving change in relation to piano keyboard size.</p><p>Specifically, PASK aims to convince piano manufacturers to begin producing piano keyboards in three standard sizes. Purchasers of new pianos will then have a choice of keyboard size. In addition to the current ‘large’ size, we need two additional sizes with <u>narrower keys</u>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>The current piano keyboard has prevailed since the 1880’s and was not designed for the physical capabilities of the population at large. It has been assumed that the current size is suitable for all, whereas in fact it is isn’t. The keys are too wide for the majority of pianists, considering men, women and children of all nationalities and across all age groups.</p><p>The current keyboard size and key width suits people with large hands, generally adult males with average to above average spans. However, for those with smaller hands, today’s piano increases technical difficulties and learning time. It limits musical expression and prevents access to a large amount of the piano repertoire. Worst of all, it can cause debilitating pain and injury.</p><p>A simple analogy illustrates the point. Does it make sense that all men in an athletics race should have to wear the same size shoes? And that female athletes have to run in the same size shoes as the men? And that children have to run in the same size shoes as adults?</p></div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
				<div data-id="86f8594" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="93ab53a" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div>
					<p><img width="290" height="300" src="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Square-logo-2-290x300.jpg" alt="" srcset="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Square-logo-2-290x300.jpg 290w, http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Square-logo-2-768x796.jpg 768w, http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Square-logo-2-989x1024.jpg 989w, http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Square-logo-2.jpg 1145w" sizes="(max-width: 290px) 100vw, 290px">											</p>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section data-id="be5765d" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="6591610" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<section data-id="721b21b" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="77af1a3" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="b67b3fe" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div>
					<p><img width="763" height="1024" src="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Kristen1-Nov-2014-763x1024.jpg" alt="" srcset="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Kristen1-Nov-2014-763x1024.jpg 763w, http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Kristen1-Nov-2014-224x300.jpg 224w, http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Kristen1-Nov-2014-768x1031.jpg 768w, http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Kristen1-Nov-2014.jpg 1216w" sizes="(max-width: 763px) 100vw, 763px">											</p>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
				<div data-id="bdfaffa" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="984bedd" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div>
					<p><img width="720" height="960" src="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Students-at-SMU-Institute-for-Young-Pianists.jpg" alt="" srcset="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Students-at-SMU-Institute-for-Young-Pianists.jpg 720w, http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Students-at-SMU-Institute-for-Young-Pianists-225x300.jpg 225w" sizes="(max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px">											</p>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section data-id="d469830" data-element_type="section">
						
		</section>
				<section data-id="6326091" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="cb76b18" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="25d103d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div>
					<div><p>The<strong> long term goal of PASK </strong>is for acoustic and digital piano manufacturers to offer a choice of three standard keyboard sizes in accordance with the DS standards. These are: DS5.5® (7/8) and the DS6.0® (15/16) as well as the current ‘large’ DS6.5<em>&nbsp;</em>keyboard. They need to be&nbsp;mass-produced and marketed worldwide in such a way that the new alternative sizes are readily available and naturally accepted options for all pianists and teachers.&nbsp;</p><p>For this to happen, we need to focus on both building the demand from the piano world as well as encouraging supply from manufacturers. Clearly, these are interdependent.&nbsp;</p><p>Pianists with smaller hands must create a united voice and demand access to keyboards with narrower keys. Piano teachers, universities and conservatoriums need to recognise their benefits. Competitions and concert venues should provide a choice of keyboard for performers.</p><p>Alternatively sized keyboards are currently only available from a limited number of sources, are expensive and often involve long wait times for customers. The major piano manufacturers need to take up this challenge.&nbsp;A key factor in creating change will be public support from prominent pianists, academics and teachers around the world.</p><p>There are three main strategies required to achieve this goal:</p><p>1.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Raising awareness of the benefits of reduced size keyboards for those with smaller hands.</p><p>2.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Creating opportunities for pianists to experience the difference in playing on narrower keys.</p><p>3.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Breaking down barriers and resistance to change.</p></div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section data-id="8b8c474" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="0033df0" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="dea7d2a" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<p>
			<h2>PASK structure and founders</h2>		</p>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section data-id="c7ddbd5" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="3edd0c6" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="925cf88" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div>
					<p>PASK is not a formally constituted organisation, but a network of people working towards a common goal.

There are three founders of PASK:

Ms Erica Booker from Sydney, Australia – Graduate of the New South Wales Conservatorium of Music, pianist and piano teacher. Erica is also a Suzuki teacher trainer and leading advocate for alternatively sized piano keyboards:<a href="https://ericabookerpiano.com/%E2%80%8B" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&nbsp;</a>&nbsp;<a href="https://ericabookerpiano.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://ericabookerpiano.com</a>

Dr Carol Leone from Dallas, Texas – Chair of Keyboard Studies at SMU Meadows School of the Arts in Dallas, internationally recognized performing artist, teacher, lecturer, and author. Carol is one of the world’s leading researchers and proponents of ergonomic piano keyboards to promote a pianist’s wellness:&nbsp;<a href="http://www.carolleone.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.carolleone.com</a>

Ms Rhonda Boyle from Melbourne, Australia – Former government policy analyst/strategic planner with qualifications in physics, environmental science and urban planning. Rhonda is a pianist, independent researcher and author of peer-reviewed articles relating to hand size and piano playing:
<a href="http://www.linkedin.com/pub/rhonda-boyle/30/931/352" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.linkedin.com/pub/rhonda-boyle/30/931/352</a>

<span>These three founders have no financial connections with any piano or keyboard manufacturers.</span>

The PASK network is gradually growing and now includes many others around the world who support the PASK goals and who are actively engaged in encouraging change.

If you would like to be an active member of PASK or be kept up to date on developments, please be in touch: <a href="mailto:info@paskpiano.org">info@paskpiano.org</a></p>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section data-id="d757218" data-element_type="section">
						
		</section>
				<section data-id="c8bb5bb" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="e92354b" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="759652a" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div>
					<div><p>The term ESPK (ergonomically scaled piano keyboard) is now mostly used in the academic community when referring to keyboards smaller than the current ‘standard’ size i.e., with 6.5 inch octave. The term ‘reduced-size keyboard’ has also been used in some literature. &nbsp;Also note that the DS5.5®<em>&nbsp;</em>is often referred to as the ‘7/8 keyboard’ as the key widths are close to (but not exactly) 7/8 of the ‘standard’ keyboard. Likewise, the DS6.0®<em>&nbsp;</em>is often referred to as the 15/16 keyboard. ESPK is a generic term that also includes keyboards of other sizes, i.e. that do not conform to the DS standards.&nbsp;</p><p>The ‘DS’ abbreviation stands for Donison-Steinbuhler. (Chris Donison and David Steinbuhler pioneered the introduction of piano keyboards with narrower keys for acoustic pianos, mainly in North America.) &nbsp;The PASK movement (Pianists for Alternatively Sized Keyboards) generally uses the term ‘alternative sizes’ to avoid confusion as ‘reduced size’ could imply fewer than 88 keys.</p></div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section data-id="41a669e" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="2e65a40" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="3ee7b0a" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="wp-widget-sfsi-widget.default">
				<div>
					<div data-position="widget">
			
			<div><div><p><a data-effect="" target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdiQ0iwCWFsGjZ1QI41KSBg/playlists" id="sfsiid_youtube"><img data-pin-nopin="true" alt="YouTube" title="YouTube" src="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/plugins/ultimate-social-media-icons/images/icons_theme/default/default_youtube.png" width="40" height="40" data-effect=""></a></p></div><div><p><a data-effect="" target="_blank" href="http://instagram.com/paskpianos" id="sfsiid_instagram"><img data-pin-nopin="true" alt="Instagram" title="Instagram" src="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/plugins/ultimate-social-media-icons/images/icons_theme/default/default_instagram.png" width="40" height="40" data-effect=""></a></p></div></div>			
		</div>
			</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
						</div>
						</div>
					</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://paskpiano.org/about/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25173522</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 23:28:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Best of NeXT Collection]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 58 | Comments 15 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25172693">thread link</a>) | @mpweiher
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | http://www.kevra.org/TheBestOfNext/index.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.kevra.org/TheBestOfNext/index.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="container">
    <!-- Start container -->

    <!-- End sidebar wrapper -->

    <div id="contentContainer">
      <!-- Start main content wrapper -->

      <div id="content">
        <!-- Start content -->

        <p><img alt="KeyFobHeader6" src="http://www.kevra.org/TheBestOfNext/files/page0_1.jpg" width="604" height="197">
        <br></p>

        <p><span>After Steve Jobs was forced out of Apple
        in 1985, everyone wanted to know what Steve would do
        next.... so NeXT was what he did.
        <p>
        
        In 1988 his NeXT team launched a new kind of computer for
        it's time, built on standards with a Unix core but with a
        user experience "my grandma could understand". It was well
        ahead of it's time, so naturally, it was not embraced by
        main stream consumers... a classic "Crossing the Chasm"
        issue. But many saw it for what it was, a breakthrough
        product as innovative as today's iTunes, iPod and iPhone.
        </p><p>
        
        Building upon NeXT's hardware and more importantly, their
        software development environment, many third party NeXT
        developers added their own magic dust to create
        revolutionary products, like the world's first web browser,
        or a new form of spread sheet, Lotus Improv or WebObjects,
        the foundation upon which the iTune store is built, to name
        only a few. Some of these ground breaking products may
        never be repeated. Most contained innovations embraced by
        future applications, with a clear lineage back to NeXTSTEP.
        </p><p>
        
        During the relatively short time of NeXT ascendency
        (1985-1996), Apple was bleeding red ink from repeated
        financial losses and two hugely expensive attempts to
        create a follow on Operating System. Apple's third
        president since Steve's departure, Gil Amelio saw the
        merits of Steve, his team and their technology. In December
        1996 Apple bought Next. Then the Next team took over Apple.
        The result is their hugely successful Mac OS X, built on
        the foundations of the NeXTSTEP OS.
        </p><p>
        
        While NeXT is no more, as a product or a stand alone
        company, it's impact on the industry will be felt for years
        to come. We should remember it, perhaps even study it. In
        decades to come, it will be understood as a watershed of
        innovation. Current Mac and iPhone users will be astonished
        to see how many of their beloved Mac OS X innovations had
        their roots in NeXTSTEP. There are many lessons about
        product innovation, market acceptance, and the creative
        people involved, that have yet to be uncovered.
        </p><p>
        
        This web site details part of our unique collection of NeXT
        related products and assorted items which grew up around
        NeXT Computer ecosystem, including of course NeXT hardware
        but also those rare items such as dealer sales kits, logo'd
        clothing, NeXT jewelry, banners, training tapes for
        servicing NeXT computers and printers, developer guides,
        plus third party software and hardware products.
        </p><p>
        
        While the site describes only part of the actual
        collection, the site does cover over 800 NeXT and third
        party products, many with multipage brochures and white
        papers. If you were to print all the html and PDF documents
        it would be over 3,000 pages.
        </p><p>
        
        This site describes what may well be the most extensive
        NeXT related collection available today.
        </p><p>
        
        It's history worth preserving.
        </p></span></p>

        
      </div><!-- End content -->

      <!-- End Footer -->
    </div><!-- End main content wrapper -->
  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.kevra.org/TheBestOfNext/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25172693</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 20:55:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[FTC commissioner met with Apple regarding Facebook’s iOS 14 complaints]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 108 | Comments 92 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25171707">thread link</a>) | @aeromusek
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | https://www.myhealthyapple.com/etc-apple-facebook-ios14/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.myhealthyapple.com/etc-apple-facebook-ios14/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a href="https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings.jpg" data-caption=""><img width="696" height="416" src="https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings-696x416.jpg" srcset="https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings-696x416.jpg 696w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings-300x179.jpg 300w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings-768x459.jpg 768w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings-702x420.jpg 702w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings.jpg 926w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px" alt="FTC-Apple-Facebook-iOS14" title="FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings"></a></p><p>In a<span>&nbsp;</span>letter sent to the Ranking Digital Rights organization, Apple’s Jane Horvath, senior director of global privacy, reiterated that the company believes that<strong> “privacy is a fundamental human right.”</strong></p><p>Horvath explains that Apple <span>delayed the App Tracking Transparency (ATT) feature</span> to give developers more time to prepare for the changes.</p><h2><strong>Facebook’s complaints about Apple’s App Tracking Transparency (ATT)</strong></h2><p>Facebook has criticized the App Tracking Transparency feature and said it <span>could cause ad revenue to&nbsp;drop as much as 40%</span>.</p><p>Facebook has reportedly met with advertising partners to discuss the impact the change has on advertising when users have the ability to easily opt-out of cross-platform tracking.</p><p>The company also announced the following <a href="https://www.facebook.com/business/news/preparing-our-partners-for-ios-14-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">in a press release</a> on Sept 10th.</p><blockquote><p>“We, along with the rest of the business community, continue to await final policy details from Apple.”</p><p>Given Apple’s delayed implementation of the user permission requirement, we will continue collecting IDFA on iOS 14 in an attempt to reduce unnecessary disruption to our customers’ businesses.”</p></blockquote><p>We checked in with FTC to see if they were looking into some of the claims made by FaceBook against Apple’s iOS 14.</p><figure id="attachment_1004628" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1004628"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-investigating-Facebooks-claim-against-Apple.jpg" alt="FTC looking into Facebook's complaints against Apple" width="977" height="511" srcset="https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-investigating-Facebooks-claim-against-Apple.jpg 977w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-investigating-Facebooks-claim-against-Apple-300x157.jpg 300w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-investigating-Facebooks-claim-against-Apple-768x402.jpg 768w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-investigating-Facebooks-claim-against-Apple-696x364.jpg 696w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-investigating-Facebooks-claim-against-Apple-803x420.jpg 803w" sizes="(max-width: 977px) 100vw, 977px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1004628">Email send by FTC commissioner on Aug 28th (Source: myHealthyApple.com)</figcaption></figure><p>It appears, based on the reports under our FOIA filing, that Noah Philips, FTC commissioner reached out to Kate Adams from <strong>Apple on 28th August</strong> to understand some of the details around Facebook’s complaints.</p><p>A meeting was subsequently scheduled between Apple’s team and FTC attorneys around the first week of September.</p><figure id="attachment_1004629" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1004629"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-meeting-with-Apple-about-IOS-14.jpg" alt="FTC Meeting with Apple on iOS 14" width="967" height="650" srcset="https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-meeting-with-Apple-about-IOS-14.jpg 967w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-meeting-with-Apple-about-IOS-14-300x202.jpg 300w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-meeting-with-Apple-about-IOS-14-768x516.jpg 768w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-meeting-with-Apple-about-IOS-14-696x468.jpg 696w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-meeting-with-Apple-about-IOS-14-625x420.jpg 625w" sizes="(max-width: 967px) 100vw, 967px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1004629">Source: MyHealthyApple.com</figcaption></figure><p>Given the timing of Apple’s announcement today, it is clear that the company has good cause to take this position following meetings with FTC.</p><p>According to the letter today, Apple continues to emphasize that advertising that protects user privacy is possible.</p><p>You can read today’s complete Apple’s letter posted by Chance Miller at <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2020/11/19/apple-privacy-letter-ios-14-facebook/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">9to5Mac</a>.</p><p><em>As an Amazon Associate MyHealthyApple may earn commissions from qualifying purchases using our links</em></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.myhealthyapple.com/etc-apple-facebook-ios14/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25171707</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 18:41:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Production-Oriented Development]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 169 | Comments 123 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25170547">thread link</a>) | @kiyanwang
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | https://paulosman.me/2019/12/30/production-oriented-development.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://paulosman.me/2019/12/30/production-oriented-development.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
          <p><span></span> read
          </p>
          <a name="topofpage"></a>
          <p>Throughout my career, I’ve developed some <em>opinions</em>. Some have worn particularly deep ruts,
reinforced by years of experience. I tried to figure out what these
had in common, and it’s
the idea that <strong>code in production is the only code that matters</strong>. Staging doesn’t
matter, code on your laptop doesn’t matter, QA doesn’t matter,
only production matters. Everything else is debt.</p>

<p>This perspective probably comes from years sitting in between
operations and product development. I strongly
believe that teams should optimize for getting code to production as quickly as
possible as well as responding to incidents in production.</p>

<p>This idea, and a lot of the practices it implies, can be
counter-intuitive or controversial, so I want to dive into them a little
further. What follows is a set of practices and principles I believe are true,
considering my underlying belief that code working in production is the only
code that matters.</p>

<h2 id="engineers-should-operate-their-code">1. Engineers should operate their code.</h2>

<p><strong>Engineers are the subject matter experts for the code they write and should be
responsible for operating it in production</strong>. In this context, “operating” means
deploying, instrumenting, and monitoring code as well as helping to resolve
incidents related to or impacting that code. The responsibility of operating
code aligns incentives - it encourages engineers to write code that is
observable and easy to debug, and connects them to what customers really care
about. It encourages them to be curious about how their code is performing in
production. Importantly, engineers should be on-call for their code - being
on-call creates a positive feedback loop and makes it easier to know if their
efforts in writing production-ready code are paying off. I’ve heard people
complain about the prospect of being on-call, so I’ll just ask this: if you’re
not on-call for your code, who is?</p>

<p>If you’re not currently on-call for your code but want to be, and can help
influence this decision, there are some things you can do. Set up PagerDuty (or
similar) schedules for each group of engineers responsible for specific
services or parts of your code. A good schedule has 6–8 engineers. There are
plenty of variations, but a typical template is to have one-week rotations,
where you’ll be on-call for secondary for a week and then primary for a week.
Configuring alerts is a separate topic, which probably deserves it’s own blog
post entirely, but focus on things that impact your customers (see:
Symptom-based alerting) and remember that you’re ultimately responsible for how
you respond to alerts, which means you can change them.</p>

<p>There are two talks I’d recommend watching that touch on the topic of
configuring alerts: Liz Fong-Jones talks about SLOs in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MT4jbUzEVL0">Cultivating Production Excellence</a> and Aditya Mukerjee does a great job talking about techniques for
managing alerts in <a href="https://vimeo.com/274820572">Warning: This Talk Contains Content Known to the State of California to Reduce Alert Fatigue</a>.</p>

<h2 id="buy-almost-always-beatsbuild">2. Buy Almost Always Beats&nbsp;Build</h2>

<p><strong>If you can avoid building something, you should.</strong> Code is the most expensive
way to solve a problem that isn’t addressing a core area of your business. For
most small to mid-sized companies, there are open source or better yet, hosted
solutions that solve a wide range of common problems. I mean things like git
repository hosting (Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket, etc), observability tooling
(Honeycomb, Lightstep, etc), managed databases (Amazon RDS, Confluent Kafka,
etc), alerting (PagerDuty, OpsGenie, etc) and a whole host of other commodity
technologies. This even applies to your infrastructure - if you can help
it, don’t roll your own Kubernetes clusters (side note: do you even need to use
Kubernetes?), don’t roll your own load balancers if you can use Amazon ELB or
ALBs.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Not_invented_here">NIH</a> syndrome is very real and some companies get burned badly by
this. I’ve seen teams light time and money on fire reinventing components when
better, more battle-tested alternatives exist in the market. Those same teams
almost always end up spending years contending with the resulting technical
debt. If you’re on such a team and have the will and ability to impact change,
start rolling back these decisions one by one. Migrate your databases to a
managed provider, migrate your feature flagging system to a SaaS tool (i.e.
LaunchDarkly). Keep going until the only software you maintain yourselves is
the software that delivers value to your customers. You’ll be much, much better
off for it.</p>

<h2 id="make-deployseasy">3. Make Deploys&nbsp;Easy</h2>

<p>Deploying should be a frequent and unexciting activity. <strong>Engineers should be
able to deploy with minimal manual steps and it should be easy to see if the
deploy is successful</strong> (this requires instrumenting your code for observability,
which - tada - is covered above), and it should be easy to roll back a deploy
if something doesn’t go well. Deploying frequently implies that
deploys are smaller, and smaller deploys are generally easier, faster and
safer.</p>

<p>Many teams implement periods where deploys are forbidden - these can be
referred to as code freezes, or deploy policies like “Don’t deploy on Fridays”.
Having such blackout periods can lead to a pile-up of changes, which increases
the overall risk of something going very wrong.</p>

<p>If you’re on a team that fears deploys, dedicate a percentage of your
engineering time to improvements in your deployment pipeline until the fear is
gone. On a recent team I worked with, we were able to improve deploy times from
3 hours to 30 minutes, which drastically improved the teams’ confidence in the
deploy process. A natural side effect of this was that engineers started
deploying much more frequently instead of waiting for changes to pile up enough
to warrant a “release” (which was synonymous with a deploy).</p>

<p>The book
<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Accelerate-Software-Performing-Technology-Organizations/dp/1942788339">Accelerate</a>
has been getting a lot of attention. If you haven’t read it, I’d recommend it.
The team behind it also publishes the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/devops/">State of DevOps</a>
reports, which are full of well-researched information about what various
companies in the industry are doing. It’s not a coincidence that two of the
four key metrics that the book focuses on are directly related to this (Deploy
Frequency, Change Lead Time). Shipping is <a href="https://www.heavybit.com/library/podcasts/o11ycast/ep-12-speed-of-deployment-with-rich-archbold-of-intercom/">your company’s heartbeat</a>.</p>

<h2 id="trust-the-people-closest-to-theknives">4. Trust the People Closest to the&nbsp;Knives</h2>

<p><strong>The people who work with a system are the ones who understand it best.</strong> This
applies to any part of the socio-technical systems within which we all work. In
the case of software systems, the engineers who deploy every day and are
on-call for critical services understand the level of risk they operate in. A
sad trend is that managers tend to overestimate their teams’ progress on
certain transitions - i.e. cloud-native, DevOps, etc. The higher up the
management chain, the larger this overestimation tends to be. Engineers who
deploy and get paged when things break know where the bodies are buried and
they know what needs the most work. They should, therefore, be the primary
stakeholders responsible for prioritizing technical work.</p>

<p>Another manifestation of this principle applies to platform or services teams.
If you’re responsible for building some shared component that’s used within
your organization (i.e. a messaging system, ci/cd infrastructure, shared
libraries or services) there’s an uncomfortable truth lurking for you: the
people who use your work know more about it than you do in many cases. They
understand implicitly how it serves customers and they know what contortions or
hoops they have to jump through to get it to work. Listen to them for
clues on how to improve the UX of your services and tools.</p>

<h2 id="qa-gates-make-qualityworse">5. QA Gates Make Quality&nbsp;Worse</h2>

<p>Many teams have a manual QA step that gets performed before deploys. The idea,
I guess, is to have someone run automated or manual tests to verify that a set
of changes are ready to be released. This sounds like a comforting
idea - having a human being (or team of human beings) “verify” a release before
it goes out - <strong>but it falls victim to several false assumptions and creates
some misalignments that do more harm than good.</strong></p>

<p>First of all, if there’s manual work that needs to be done before a deploy can
go out, that creates a bottleneck - if you’re making deploys easy, and
deploying small changes frequently, no QA team is going to be able to keep up
testing every deploy, and will inevitably block teams from deploying. That’s no
good. If you have manual tests, automate them and build them into your CI
pipeline (if they do deliver value).</p>

<p>Secondly, the teams doing QA often lack context and are under time pressure.
They may end up testing “effects” instead of “intents”. For example, I’ve seen
QA teams burn time testing that when something happens in a UI, something
related happens in a database. What happens when an engineer refactors that UI
component and changes the underlying data model? The functionality works, but
the test breaks. Because two teams are involved, this takes coordination and
time to fix. Similarly, I’ve seen QA teams block deploys because of failing
tests when caching was introduced at the CDN layer - a TTL of 5 seconds on an
activity feed may not ever be noticed by a user but it might break QA tests
causing unnecessary conflicts between product and QA engineers.</p>

<p>Luckily, solving this one is easy. Instead of having a dedicated QA team work
on creating manual and automated test cases that run in a fictitious QA
environment, reassign that team to work on continuous testing in production.
Instead of being a gate for deploys, a QA team could continuously verify that
production is working as expected. QA teams are also well situated to lead
Chaos Engineering initiatives, where faults are intentionally injected in
production. QA engineers could also work on making the CI/CD pipeline more
reliable, so that deploys are no longer a nightmare.</p>

<h2 id="boring-technology-isgreat">6. Boring Technology is&nbsp;Great.</h2>

<p>With thanks to <a href="https://mcfunley.com/choose-boring-technology">Dan McKinley</a>,
always <strong>strive for boring tech when possible</strong>. Systems are inherently
unpredictable, and you want a wide …</p></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://paulosman.me/2019/12/30/production-oriented-development.html">https://paulosman.me/2019/12/30/production-oriented-development.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://paulosman.me/2019/12/30/production-oriented-development.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25170547</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 16:25:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Winding down my Debian involvement (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 175 | Comments 186 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25170312">thread link</a>) | @ecliptik
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | https://michael.stapelberg.ch/posts/2019-03-10-debian-winding-down/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://michael.stapelberg.ch/posts/2019-03-10-debian-winding-down/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">
  
  <details>
    <summary>Table of contents</summary>
    <nav>
<ul>
<li>
<ul>
<li><a href="#what-does-this-mean">What does this mean?</a></li>
<li><a href="#why">Why?</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#change-process-in-debian">Change process in Debian</a></li>
<li><a href="#fragmented-workflow-and-infrastructure">Fragmented workflow and infrastructure</a></li>
<li><a href="#old-infrastructure-package-uploads">Old infrastructure: package uploads</a></li>
<li><a href="#old-infrastructure-bug-tracker">Old infrastructure: bug tracker</a></li>
<li><a href="#old-infrastructure-mailing-list-archives">Old infrastructure: mailing list archives</a></li>
<li><a href="#debian-is-hard-to-machine-read">Debian is hard to machine-read</a></li>
<li><a href="#complicated-build-stack">Complicated build stack</a></li>
<li><a href="#developer-experience-pretty-painful">Developer experience pretty painful</a></li>
<li><a href="#i-have-more-ideas">I have more ideas</a></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
</nav>
  </details>
  

<p>This post is hard to write, both in the emotional sense but also in the “I would
have written a shorter letter, but I didn’t have the time” sense. Hence, please
assume the best of intentions when reading it—it is not my intention to make
anyone feel bad about their contributions, but rather to provide some insight
into why my frustration level ultimately exceeded the threshold.</p>

<p>Debian has been in my life for well over 10 years at this point.</p>

<p>A few weeks ago, I have visited some old friends at the Zürich Debian meetup
after a multi-year period of absence. On my bike ride home, it occurred to me
that the topics of our discussions had remarkable overlap with my last visit. We
had a discussion about the merits of systemd, which took a detour to respect in
open source communities, returned to processes in Debian and eventually
culminated in democracies and their theoretical/practical failings. Admittedly,
that last one might be a Swiss thing.</p>

<p>I say this not to knock on the Debian meetup, but because it prompted me to
reflect on what feelings Debian is invoking lately and whether it’s still a good
fit for me.</p>

<p>So I’m finally making a decision that I should have made a long time ago: I am
winding down my involvement in Debian to a minimum.</p>

<h2 id="what-does-this-mean">What does this mean?</h2>

<p>Over the coming weeks, I will:</p>

<ul>
<li>transition packages to be team-maintained where it makes sense</li>
<li>remove myself from the <code>Uploaders</code> field on packages with other maintainers</li>
<li>orphan packages where I am the sole maintainer</li>
</ul>

<p>I will try to keep up best-effort maintenance of the
<a href="https://manpages.debian.org/">manpages.debian.org</a> service and the
<a href="https://codesearch.debian.net/">codesearch.debian.net</a> service, but any help
would be much appreciated.</p>

<p>For all intents and purposes, please treat me as permanently on vacation. I will
try to be around for administrative issues (e.g. permission transfers) and
questions addressed directly to me, permitted they are easy enough to answer.</p>

<h2 id="why">Why?</h2>

<p>When I joined Debian, I was still studying, i.e. I had luxurious amounts of
spare time. Now, over 5 years of full time work later, my day job taught me a
lot, both about what works in large software engineering projects and how I
personally like my computer systems. I am very conscious of how I spend the
little spare time that I have these days.</p>

<p>The following sections each deal with what I consider a major pain point, in no
particular order. Some of them influence each other—for example, if changes
worked better, we could have a chance at transitioning packages to be more
easily machine readable.</p>

<h3 id="change-process-in-debian">Change process in Debian</h3>

<p>The last few years, my current team at work conducted various smaller and larger
refactorings across the entire code base (touching thousands of projects), so we
have learnt a lot of valuable lessons about how to effectively do these
changes. It irks me that Debian works almost the opposite way in every regard. I
appreciate that every organization is different, but I think a lot of my points
do actually apply to Debian.</p>

<p>In Debian, packages are nudged in the right direction by a document called the
<a href="https://www.debian.org/doc/debian-policy/">Debian Policy</a>, or its programmatic
embodiment, lintian.</p>

<p>While it is great to have a lint tool (for quick, local/offline feedback), it is
even better to not require a lint tool at all. The team conducting the change
(e.g. the C++ team introduces a new hardening flag for all packages) should be
able to do their work transparent to me.</p>

<p>Instead, currently, all packages become lint-unclean, all maintainers need to
read up on what the new thing is, how it might break, whether/how it affects
them, manually run some tests, and finally decide to opt in. This causes a lot
of overhead and manually executed mechanical changes across packages.</p>

<p>Notably, the <strong>cost of each change</strong> is distributed onto the package maintainers in
the Debian model. At work, we have found that the opposite works better: if the
team behind the change is put in power to do the change for as many users as
possible, they can be significantly more efficient at it, which reduces the
total cost and time a lot. Of course, exceptions (e.g. a large project abusing a
language feature) should still be taken care of by the respective owners, but
the important bit is that the default should be the other way around.</p>

<p>Debian is <strong>lacking tooling for large changes</strong>: it is hard to programmatically
deal with packages and repositories (see the section below). The closest to
“sending out a change for review” is to open a bug report with an attached
patch. I thought the workflow for accepting a change from a bug report was too
complicated and started <a href="https://michael.stapelberg.ch/posts/2016-07-17-mergebot/">mergebot</a>, but only Guido
ever signaled interest in the project.</p>

<p>Culturally, reviews and reactions are slow. There are no deadlines. I literally
sometimes get emails notifying me that a patch I sent out a few years ago (!!)
is now merged. This turns projects from a small number of weeks into many years,
which is a huge demotivator for me.</p>

<p>Interestingly enough, you can see artifacts of the slow online activity manifest
itself in the offline culture as well: I don’t want to be discussing systemd’s
merits 10 years after I first heard about it.</p>

<p>Lastly, changes can easily be slowed down significantly by holdouts who refuse
to collaborate. My canonical example for this is rsync, whose maintainer refused
my patches to make the package use debhelper purely out of personal preference.</p>

<p>Granting so much personal freedom to individual maintainers prevents us as a
project from raising the abstraction level for building Debian packages, which
in turn makes tooling harder.</p>

<p>How would things look like in a better world?</p>

<ol>
<li>As a project, we should strive towards more unification. Uniformity still
does not rule out experimentation, it just changes the trade-off from easier
experimentation and harder automation to harder experimentation and easier
automation.</li>
<li>Our culture needs to shift from “this package is my domain, how dare you
touch it” to a shared sense of ownership, where anyone in the project can
easily contribute (reviewed) changes without necessarily even involving
individual maintainers.</li>
</ol>

<p>To learn more about how successful large changes can look like, I recommend <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TrC6ROeV4GI">my
colleague Hyrum Wright’s talk “Large-Scale Changes at Google: Lessons Learned
From 5 Yrs of Mass Migrations”</a>.</p>

<h3 id="fragmented-workflow-and-infrastructure">Fragmented workflow and infrastructure</h3>

<p>Debian generally seems to prefer decentralized approaches over centralized
ones. For example, individual packages are maintained in separate repositories
(as opposed to in one repository), each repository can use any SCM (git and svn
are common ones) or no SCM at all, and each repository can be hosted on a
different site. Of course, what you do in such a repository also varies subtly
from team to team, and even within teams.</p>

<p>In practice, non-standard hosting options are used rarely enough to not justify
their cost, but frequently enough to be a huge pain when trying to automate
changes to packages. Instead of using GitLab’s API to create a merge request,
you have to design an entirely different, more complex system, which deals with
intermittently (or permanently!) unreachable repositories and abstracts away
differences in patch delivery (bug reports, merge requests, pull requests,
email, …).</p>

<p>Wildly diverging workflows is not just a temporary problem either. I
participated in long discussions about different git workflows during DebConf
13, and gather that there were similar discussions in the meantime.</p>

<p>Personally, I cannot keep enough details of the different workflows in my
head. Every time I touch a package that works differently than mine, it
frustrates me immensely to re-learn aspects of my day-to-day.</p>

<p>After noticing workflow fragmentation in the Go packaging team (which I
started), I tried fixing this with the <a href="https://go-team.pages.debian.net/workflow-changes.html">workflow changes
proposal</a>, but did not
succeed in implementing it. The lack of effective automation and slow pace of
changes in the surrounding tooling despite my willingness to contribute time and
energy killed any motivation I had.</p>

<h3 id="old-infrastructure-package-uploads">Old infrastructure: package uploads</h3>

<p>When you want to make a package available in Debian, you upload GPG-signed files
via anonymous FTP. There are several batch jobs (the queue daemon, <code>unchecked</code>,
<code>dinstall</code>, possibly others) which run on fixed schedules (e.g. <code>dinstall</code> runs
at 01:52 UTC, 07:52 UTC, 13:52 UTC and 19:52 UTC).</p>

<p>Depending on timing, I estimated that you might wait for over 7 hours (!!)
before your package is actually installable.</p>

<p>What’s worse for me is that feedback to your upload is asynchronous. I like to
do one thing, be done with it, move to the next thing. The current setup
requires a many-minute wait and costly task switch for no good technical
reason. You might think a few minutes aren’t a big deal, but when all the time I
can spend on Debian per day is measured in minutes, this makes a huge difference
in perceived productivity and fun.</p>

<p>The last communication I can find about speeding up this process is <a href="https://lists.debian.org/debian-project/2008/12/msg00014.html">ganneff’s
post</a> from 2008.</p>

<p>How would things look like in a better world?</p>

<ol>
<li>Anonymous FTP would be replaced by a web service which ingests my package and
returns an authoritative accept or reject decision in its response.</li>
<li>For accepted packages, there would be a status page displaying the build
status and when the package will be available via the mirror network.</li>
<li>Packages should be available within a few minutes after the build completed.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="old-infrastructure-bug-tracker">Old infrastructure: bug tracker</h3>

<p>I dread interacting with the Debian bug
tracker. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Debbugs">debbugs</a> is a piece of software
(from 1994) which is only used by Debian and the GNU project these days.</p>

<p>Debbugs processes emails, which is to say it is asynchronous and cumbersome to
deal with. Despite running on the fastest machines we …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://michael.stapelberg.ch/posts/2019-03-10-debian-winding-down/">https://michael.stapelberg.ch/posts/2019-03-10-debian-winding-down/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://michael.stapelberg.ch/posts/2019-03-10-debian-winding-down/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25170312</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 15:53:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I got rich on the other hand (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 47 | Comments 87 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25170030">thread link</a>) | @damir
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | https://sive.rs/richand | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://sive.rs/richand">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">

<article>
<header>


<small>2019-10-30</small>
<audio src="https://m.sive.rs/sive.rs.richand.mp3" preload="none" controls="controls"></audio></header>

<p>
I don’t usually talk about money, but a friend asked me what it was like to get rich, and he wanted to know specifics, so I told him my story.
</p><p>
I had <a href="https://sive.rs/xn">a day job</a> in midtown Manhattan paying $20K per year — about minimum wage.
On weekends I would earn $150 per day performing circus shows for kids, though I’d spend about $50 in bus fare to get to the gigs.
I was sharing a three-bedroom apartment with two other roommates in Queens, so our rent was $333 per month each.
I made peanut butter sandwiches for three meals a day, and at night maybe some eggs.
I never ate out, and never took a taxi.
<strong>
My cost of living was about $1000/month, and I was earning $1800/month.
I did this for two years, and saved up $12,000.
</strong>
I was 22 years old.
</p><p>
Once I had $12,000 I could quit my job and become a full-time musician.
I knew I could get a few gigs per month to pay my cost of living.
So I was free.
<a href="https://sive.rs/nq">I quit my job</a> a month later, and never had a job again.
</p><p>
When I finished telling my friend this story, he asked for more.
I said no, that was it.
He said, “No, what about when you sold your company?”
</p><p>
I said no, that didn’t make a big difference in my life.
That was just more money in the bank.
The difference happened when I was 22.
</p><p>
It’s not how much you have.
<strong>
It’s the difference between what you have and what you spend.
</strong>
If you have more than you spend, you’re rich.
If you spend more than you have, you’re not.
If you live cheaply, it’s easy to be free.
</p><p>
Magicians wave one hand around to get your attention, while the other hand does the trick.
To be smart, watch the other hand.
</p>
<img src="https://sive.rs/images/magichands.jpg">


</article>



</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://sive.rs/richand</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25170030</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 14:54:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Interpretation of confidence intervals and Bayesian credible intervals]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 56 | Comments 32 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25169595">thread link</a>) | @jwb133
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | https://thestatsgeek.com/2020/11/21/interpretation-of-frequentist-confidence-intervals-and-bayesian-credible-intervals/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thestatsgeek.com/2020/11/21/interpretation-of-frequentist-confidence-intervals-and-bayesian-credible-intervals/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
<p>This post was prompted by a tweet by Frank Harrell yesterday asking:</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>In this post I'll say a little bit about trying to answer Frank's question, and then a little bit about an alternative question which I posed in response, namely, how does the interpretation change if the interval is a Bayesian credible interval, rather than a frequentist confidence interval.</p>



<h2>Frequentist confidence intervals</h2>



<p>A frequentist 95% confidence interval is constructed such that if the model assumptions are correct, if you were to (hypothetically) repeat the experiment or sampling many many times, 95% of the intervals constructed would contain the true value of the parameter. I made a short video last year which performs a simulation in R to demonstrate this definition/idea:</p>



<figure><p><span><iframe width="1125" height="633" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IGXg6L98lJM?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;fs=1&amp;autohide=2&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true"></iframe></span>
</p></figure>



<p>Frank asked how one interprets a particular realised confidence interval (0.72,0.91). The difficulty (as he is well aware!) is that all a frequentist can say is that this particular realised interval either does or does not contain the true parameter value, and they cannot tell you if it does or doesn't. All they can say is that if modelling assumptions are correct, in hypothetical repetitions 95% of the intervals constructed using this procedure contain the true value.</p>



<h2>Bayesian credible intervals</h2>



<p>Let’s now suppose that we’ve done a Bayesian analysis. We’ve specified a prior distribution for the parameter, based on prior evidence, our subjective beliefs about the value of the parameter, or perhaps we used a default ‘non-informative’ prior built into our software package. We use the same model as before, and Bayes theorem gives us the posterior distribution. A Bayesian posterior credible interval is constructed, and suppose it gives us some values. For the sake of simplicity, I’ll assume the interval is again 0.72 to 0.91, but this is not done to suggest a Bayesian analysis credible interval will generally be identical to the frequentist's confidence interval.</p>



<p>How should we interpret this credible interval? A Bayesian would I think say say something like it is an interval for which there is a 95% chance or probability the true parameter lies. At this point we must ask, what do they mean by 95% probability?</p>



<p>We could interpret it as a classical long run frequentist probability, but this means interpreting it like a confidence interval. In fact Bayesian procedures often have good frequentist properties. For example see <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://cdn1.sph.harvard.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/343/2013/03/large-sample.pdf" target="_blank">Wang and Robins 1998</a> for an analysis of the frequentist properties of multiple imputation for missing data, or <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://doi.org/10.1177%2F0962280216667764" target="_blank">Bartlett and Keogh 2018</a> for a simulation investigation of the frequentist properties of Bayesian approaches for handling covariate measurement error. In fact, under certain conditions, Bayesian procedures achieve the same frequentist properties of maximum likelihood methods when the sample size gets large - see Chapter 4 of Gelman <em>et al</em>'s excellent<a href="http://www.stat.columbia.edu/~gelman/book/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Bayesian Data Analysis book</a>.</p>



<p>But conceptually we do not choose to do a Bayesian analysis simply as a means to performing frequentist inference. We choose it because it (hopefully) answers more directly what we are interested in (see Frank Harrell's '<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.fharrell.com/post/journey/" target="_blank">My Journey From Frequentist to Bayesian Statistics</a>' post). Namely, it enables us to make probability statements about the unknown parameter given our model, the prior, and the data we have observed. So what is the interpretation of the 95% chance or probability for a credible interval? </p>



<p>I don't know the no doubt large literature on this topic well at all, but the Bayesian's interpretation or definition of probability isn't that clear to me. The Wikipedia entry on <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bayesian_probability" target="_blank">Bayesian probability</a> says:</p>



<blockquote><p>Broadly speaking, there are two interpretations of Bayesian probability. For objectivists, who interpret probability as an extension of logic, probability quantifies the reasonable expectation that everyone (even a "robot") who shares the same knowledge should share in accordance with the rules of Bayesian statistics, which can be justified by Cox's theorem.[2][8] For subjectivists, probability corresponds to a personal belief.[3] Rationality and coherence allow for substantial variation within the constraints they pose; the constraints are justified by the Dutch book argument or by decision theory and de Finetti's theorem.[3] The objective and subjective variants of Bayesian probability differ mainly in their interpretation and construction of the prior probability.</p><cite>Wikipedia entry on Bayesian probability</cite></blockquote>



<p>Section 1.5 'Probability as a measure of uncertainty' of <a href="http://www.stat.columbia.edu/~gelman/book/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bayesian Data Analysis</a> talks about the way Bayesian analysis uses probability as a measure of uncertainty, but to my mind it doesn't really define the concept. This is not a criticism. As Gelman et al say earlier in their book:</p>



<blockquote><p>Rather than argue the foundations of statistics—see the bibliographic note at the end of this chapter for references to foundational debates—we prefer to concentrate on the pragmatic advantages of the Bayesian framework, whose flexibility and generality allow it to cope with complex problems.</p></blockquote>



<p>If part of the appeal of Bayesian inference is that it answers the question we really want (i.e. conditional on what we've seen, what do we know / believe about the parameter(s)), it seems to me that the interpretation or definition of prior/posterior probabilities should be relatively straightforward and clear to us. But for me at least, it isn't. I am quite confident (whatever I mean by that!) that this reflects my ignorance on the topic. Part of my motivation for writing this post is the hope that people will help me understand better how to unambiguously define what is meant by a Bayesian prior/posterior probability. Please write a comment if you can help in this regard.</p>



<p>The above does not mean I don't like Bayesian methods. Indeed much of the last 10 years I have been working with and using methods like multiple imputation for missing data whose development take place in the Bayesian paradigm. For me this is fine because I know that methods like multiple imputation have good frequentist properties, and while there are definitely interpretational issues with things confidence intervals, I at least think I understand what they claim to do/be.</p>



<h2>22nd November 2022 postscript</h2>



<p>This evening there was further discussion of this topic on Twitter. As part of this Frank Harrell offered an interpretation for the Bayesian credible interval as follows:</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Under data model F and prior P, [0.72, 0.91] is the shortest interval such that the probability the unknown OR generating our data is in that interval is 0.95 (highest posterior density interval).</p>— Frank Harrell (@f2harrell) <a href="https://twitter.com/f2harrell/status/1330633833713111040?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 22, 2020</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>I followed up with him as to the nature of the probability being referred to here, since it is clear that the probability notion being invoked is broader or distinct than the relative frequency notion of probability. Frank helpfully pointed me in the direction of the entry for 'probability' in his course glossary of terms, which can be <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://hbiostat.org/doc/glossary.pdf" target="_blank">accessed here</a>. Part of this entry says:</p>



<blockquote><p>The&nbsp;meaning&nbsp;attached to the metric known as a probability is up to the user; it can represent long-run relative frequency of repeatable observations, a degree of belief, or a measure of veracity or plausibility.</p><cite>https://hbiostat.org/doc/glossary.pdf</cite></blockquote>



<p>and</p>



<blockquote><p>There are other schools of probability that do not require the notion of replication at all. For example, the school of&nbsp;subjective&nbsp;probability (associated with the&nbsp;Bayesian&nbsp;school) “considers probability as a measure of the degree of belief of a given subject in the occurrence of an event or, more generally, in the veracity of a given assertion” (see P. 55 of5). de Finetti defined subjective probability in terms of wagers and odds in betting. A risk-neutral individual would be willing to wager $P&nbsp;that an event will occur when the payoff is $1 and her subjective probability is&nbsp;P&nbsp;for the event.</p><cite>https://hbiostat.org/doc/glossary.pdf</cite></blockquote>



<p>As I wrote in the original post, I do not know the extensive literature on this topic well at all. But what Frank has summarised here is really useful in aiding my understanding of what the interpretation should be of the 95% probability statement attached to a 95% credible interval. It seems to me the notion of probability being invoked when interpreting a 95% credible interval has to be the subjective probability / degree of belief one described in the previous quote. Whether this definition/interpretation meets the criterion of being 'exact', as required by Frank in his tweet at the top of this post when asking for the exact interpretation of a particular realised frequentist confidence interval, I leave readers to decide.</p>
		</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thestatsgeek.com/2020/11/21/interpretation-of-frequentist-confidence-intervals-and-bayesian-credible-intervals/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25169595</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 13:21:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I Miss Working from the Office]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 553 | Comments 456 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25168589">thread link</a>) | @sysoleg
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | https://www.roguelazer.com/2020/11/i-miss-working-from-the-office/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.roguelazer.com/2020/11/i-miss-working-from-the-office/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    
    <section id="main-content" role="main">
	<article>
		


		<div><p>I went into my office yesterday for the first time in a few months to pick some stuff up. We got notified
a couple of days ago to get any personal property out of the office before Thanksgiving or else it'd be
thrown out, so I guess we're moving out of the office<sup id="fnref:moving-out"><a href="#fn:moving-out">1</a></sup>. It was a pretty eerie place to be; even now, 8
months later, most people haven't been back and it kind of looks like the entire office was abducted by aliens in
early March.</p>

<p>Despite how weird it is, I still miss working out of the office.</p>
<!-- more -->

<p>I miss having a clean delineation between "work" and "home".</p>
<p>I miss having copious desk space and a big monitor<sup id="fnref:house"><a href="#fn:house">2</a></sup>.</p>
<p>I miss the 48" TVs on the wall showing Grafana dashboards with key metrics so there was always ambient knowledge of
what was going on with the product.</p>
<p>I miss having meetings in conference rooms where you can see other people and have a giant whiteboard to sketch on.</p>
<p>I miss casual collaboration. Video chat is a poor substitute and Slack is a deeply irritating tool that combines the
worst aspects of synchronous and asynchronous communication.</p>
<p>I miss productivity! Our engineering productivity has fallen through the floor since COVID despite everyone
working longer and harder; I fundamentally do not think remote teams can <em>ever</em> be as productive as in-person teams.</p>
<p>I miss having my employer pay for electricity and heat and fast symmetric multi-gigabit Internet access instead of
shifting those costs to me.</p>
<p>I miss having a plethora of convenient and delicious options for take-out lunch! I miss the gyros and french fries
at <a href="https://www.ayolagreek.com/">Ayola</a>. I miss the chicken pesto sandwich at <a href="https://working-girls-cafe.square.site/">Working Girls'
Cafe</a>. I miss the chow mein and pork buns from <a href="https://yanksing.com/">Yank Sing</a>. I
miss the katsu curry from <a href="http://www.muraccis.com/">Muracci's</a>. I miss the curry burritos from <a href="https://www.curryupnow.com/">Curry Up
Now</a>. I miss the croque monsieur from <a href="https://cafemadeleinesf.com/">Cafe Madeline</a>. I
miss the $5 lunch specials from <a href="http://www.mehfilindian.com/">Mehfil</a>.</p>
<p>I miss the succession of friendly baristas at our <a href="https://www.yelp.com/biz/hermanos-coffee-juice-san-francisco">favorite coffee shop</a> who always knew our orders and put up with our banter.</p>
<p>I miss occasional after-work drinks at the <a href="https://sf.eater.com/2019/4/25/18516128/skydeck-spirits-in-the-sky-rooftop-bar-san-francisco">sky bar</a> with the $18 well drinks that we always convinced management to pay for.</p>
<p>Hell, I miss <a href="https://www.bart.gov/">BART</a> in all its loud and smelly glory.</p>
<p>Look, I know, it's not all bad. It's a lot easier taking care of a baby while working from home than it would be if
I were commuting 45 minutes each way every day. I'm spending a lot less money on food and coffee and BART. And I'm
not arguing that we should be in the office now; not a single one of those things I listed above is worth the health
risk of jamming 150 people<sup id="fnref:deniers"><a href="#fn:deniers">3</a></sup> into an open-plan office with a quasi-functional ventilation
system<sup id="fnref:ventilation"><a href="#fn:ventilation">4</a></sup>. But I
really hope that office-work isn't a permanent victim of this pandemic, that all the companies pushing for
permanent WFH to save a few bucks on rent reconsider their stances, and that there comes a time when I can go back to
work again.</p>
</div>
<hr>
<h2>Comments</h2>


	</article>
    </section>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.roguelazer.com/2020/11/i-miss-working-from-the-office/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25168589</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 08:58:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Mvp.css – build your landing page with only semantic HTML]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 301 | Comments 77 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25167928">thread link</a>) | @rahimnathwani
<br/>
November 20, 2020 | https://andybrewer.github.io/mvp/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://andybrewer.github.io/mvp/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <hr>
        <section>
            <header>
                <h2>Simple, reusable components</h2>
                <p>For a clean looking design that doesn't get in the way</p>
            </header>
            
            
            
        </section>
        <hr>
        <section id="testimonials">
            <blockquote>
                <img alt="Quote" src="https://andybrewer.github.io/mvp/img/icon-quote.svg" height="80"><br>
                "By far the easiest stylesheet I've ever used. It integrates easily into <s>one</s> all of my
                startup&nbsp;projects."
                
            </blockquote>
        </section>
        <hr>
        <section id="features">
            <header>
                <h2>Flexibility without complexity</h2>
                <p>A few, clean styling options without all the bells and whistles</p>
            </header>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr>
                        <th></th>
                        <th>MVP.css</th>
                        <th>No CSS</th>
                        <th>Custom CSS</th>
                    </tr>
                </thead>
                <tbody><tr>
                    <td>Mobile friendly</td>
                    <td><b>✓</b></td>
                    <td>✓</td>
                    <td>✓</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Works out of the box</td>
                    <td><b>✓</b></td>
                    <td>✓</td>
                    <td>∅</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Easy to customize</td>
                    <td><b>✓</b></td>
                    <td>✓</td>
                    <td>∅</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Only semantic HTML</td>
                    <td><b>✓</b></td>
                    <td>✓</td>
                    <td>∅</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>No class names</td>
                    <td><b>✓</b></td>
                    <td>✓</td>
                    <td>∅</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Perfect for an MVP</td>
                    <td><b>✓</b></td>
                    <td>∅</td>
                    <td>∅</td>
                </tr>
            </tbody></table>
        </section>
        <hr>
        <div id="figure">
            <header>
                <h2>A decent MVP in no time</h2>
                <p>More building and less designing with "set and forget" styling.</p>
            </header>
            <figure>
                <img alt="Stock photo" src="https://andybrewer.github.io/mvp/img/stock.jpg">
                <figcaption><i>"Uber for X" brainstorming session</i></figcaption>
            </figure>
        </div>
        <hr>
        <article id="docs">
            <h2>Docs</h2>
            <h3 id="html">HTML Reference</h3>
            
            <p>MVP.css works with the following HTML elements:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><code>&lt;a&gt;</code> <small>— text links</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;a&gt;&lt;b&gt;</code>, <code>&lt;a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;</code> <small>— solid
                                link buttons</small>
                        </li>
                        <li><code>&lt;a&gt;&lt;em&gt;</code>, <code>&lt;a&gt;&lt;i&gt;</code> <small>— outlined
                                link buttons</small>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;article&gt;</code> <small>— content area with normal styling</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;article&gt;&lt;aside&gt;</code> <small>— text callout</small>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;blockquote&gt;</code> <small>— quote callout</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;footer&gt;</code> <small>— quote attribution</small>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;body&gt;</code> <small>— default parent element</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;button&gt;</code> <small>— form buttons</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;code&gt;</code> <small>— inline code highlighting</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;details&gt;</code> <small>— default expandable content section</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;</code> <small>— expandable heading</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;div&gt;</code> <small>— unstyled element</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;figure&gt;</code> <small>— image callouts</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;</code> <small>— image callout captions</small>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;footer&gt;</code> <small>— footer area</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;form&gt;</code> <small>— small form area</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;form&gt;&lt;input&gt;</code> <small>— short input field</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;form&gt;&lt;label&gt;</code> <small>— form field labels</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;form&gt;&lt;select&gt;</code> <small>— dropdown options container</small>
                            <ul>
                                <li><code>&lt;form&gt;&lt;select&gt;&lt;option&gt;</code> <small>— dropdown option
                                        items</small></li>
                            </ul>
                        </li>
                        <li><code>&lt;form&gt;&lt;textarea&gt;</code> <small>— large input field</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;header&gt;</code> <small>— content area with centered styling</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;h1&gt;</code>, <code>&lt;h2&gt;</code>, <code>&lt;h3&gt;</code>, <code>&lt;h4&gt;</code>,
                    <code>&lt;h5&gt;</code>, <code>&lt;h6&gt;</code> <small>— headings</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;hr&gt;</code> <small>— horizontal rule (divider)</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;main&gt;</code> <small>— main content area</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;mark&gt;</code> <small>— text highlighting</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;nav&gt;</code> <small>— top navigation</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;nav&gt;&lt;ul&gt;</code> <small>— nav links container</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;nav&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;</code> <small>— nav link items</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;nav&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;ul&gt;</code> <small>— nav dropdown
                                container</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;nav&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;</code> <small>— nav dropdown
                                link items</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;ol&gt;</code> <small>— numbered list container</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;</code> <small>— numbered list items</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;p&gt;</code> <small>— paragraph tag</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;pre&gt;</code> <small>— preformatted text</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;</code> <small>— code block</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;samp&gt;</code> <small>— computer output block</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;samp&gt;</code> <small>— inline computer output</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;section&gt;</code> <small>— content area for centered / special content</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;section&gt;&lt;aside&gt;</code> <small>— content card</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;small&gt;</code> <small>— smaller text</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;sup&gt;</code> <small>— raised text (notification bubbles)</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;table&gt;</code> <small>— data table</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;table&gt;&lt;td&gt;</code> <small>— data table cell</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;table&gt;&lt;th&gt;</code> <small>— data table header cell</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;</code> <small>— data table header section</small>
                        </li>
                        <li><code>&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;</code> <small>— data table row</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;ul&gt;</code> <small>— unordered list container</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;</code> <small>— unordered list item</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <br>
            <h3 id="variables">Modifying the CSS variables</h3>
            <p>MVP.css includes a list of CSS variables. Editing these variables will change the styles globally.</p>
            <pre>                <code>
:root {
    --border-radius: 5px;
    --box-shadow: 2px 2px 10px;
    --color: #118bee;
    --color-accent: #118bee0b;
    --color-bg: #fff;
    --color-bg-secondary: #e9e9e9;
    --color-secondary: #920de9;
    --color-secondary-accent: #920de90b;
    --color-shadow: #f4f4f4;
    --color-text: #000;
    --color-text-secondary: #999;
    --font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, "Segoe UI", Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, "Helvetica Neue", sans-serif;
    --hover-brightness: 1.2;
    --justify-important: center;
    --justify-normal: left;
    --line-height: 150%;
    --width-card: 285px;
    --width-card-medium: 460px;
    --width-card-wide: 800px;
    --width-content: 1080px;
}
                </code>
            </pre>

            <p>Custom styles can be added below the <code>/* Custom styles */</code> comment at the end of the file.</p>
        </article>
        <hr>
        <article id="faq">
            <h2>Frequently Asked Questions</h2>
            <details>
                <summary>Why would I use this?</summary>
                <p>If you just want to launch already.</p>
                <p><sup>PRO TIP</sup> An MVP is a temporary site, it doesn't have to be <i>and shouldn't be</i> perfect.
                </p>
            </details>
            <details>
                <summary>What skills will I need?</summary>
                <p>Mostly HTML, maybe a hint of CSS if you want to get fancy.</p>
                <p><i>CSS</i>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <progress max="100" value="5">5</progress></p>
                <p><i>Design</i>&nbsp;&nbsp; <progress max="100" value="0">0</progress></p>
                <p><i>HTML</i>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <progress max="100" value="100">100</progress></p>
            </details>
            <details>
                <summary>Is there a minified version?</summary>
                <p>No, you don't need one for an MVP.</p>
            </details>
            <details>
                <summary>How can I improve my design?</summary>
                <p>Here are some helpful resources:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Emojis - <a href="https://www.emojicopy.com/" target="_blank">Emojicopy
                            ↗</a></li>
                    <li>Icons - <a href="https://www.toptal.com/designers/htmlarrows/" target="_blank">HTML Entities
                            List by TopTal
                            ↗</a></li>
                    <li>Icons - <a href="https://thenounproject.com/" target="_blank">TheNounProject
                            ↗</a></li>
                    <li>Illustrations - <a href="https://gallery.manypixels.co/" target="_blank">Manypixels
                            ↗</a></li>
                    <li>Illustrations - <a href="https://undraw.co/illustrations" target="_blank">Undraw ↗</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>Logo - <a href="https://www.namecheap.com/logo-maker/app/" target="_blank">Namecheap Logo
                            Maker ↗</a></li>
                    <li>Product Shots - <a href="https://www.screely.com/" target="_blank">Screely ↗</a></li>
                    <li>Stock Photos - <a href="https://www.pexels.com/" target="_blank">Pexels ↗</a></li>
                    <li>Stock Photos - <a href="https://unsplash.com/" target="_blank">Unsplash ↗</a></li>
                </ul>
            </details>
            <details>
                <summary>What if I don't like the default styles?</summary>
                <p>Most styles are editable through <em>CSS variables</em>. You can also add your own styles
                    inline, at the end of MVP.css or in a new stylesheet.</p>
                <p><sup>PRO TIP</sup> If there are two conflicting CSS styles, the last one will take precedence.</p>
                <pre>                    <code>
:root {
    --color: #118bee;
}

/* Lower in the CSS, or in a 2nd stylesheet */

:root {
    --color: green; /* This will take precedence */
}
                    </code>
                </pre>
            </details>
            <details>
                <summary>What if I still don't like it?</summary>
                <p>That's OK, you probably shouldn't love your MVP. The goal of MVP.css is to help you
                    feel <i>slightly</i> less embarrased about it.</p>
                <p><span>👉</span> If you
                    want a CSS framework with more features check out <a href="https://bulma.io/" target="_blank">Bulma
                        ↗</a> or <a href="https://tailwindcss.com/" target="_blank">Tailwind ↗</a>.</p>
            </details>
        </article>
        <hr>
        <section id="ideas">
            <header>
                <img alt="Idea" src="https://andybrewer.github.io/mvp/img/idea.svg" height="200">
                <h2>What can you build with MVP.css?</h2>
                <p>Free ideas below ↓</p>
            </header>
            
        </section>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://andybrewer.github.io/mvp/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25167928</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 04:49:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Jupystar – Run any Jupyter notebook in the browser]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 75 | Comments 15 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25167906">thread link</a>) | @protoduction
<br/>
November 20, 2020 | https://starboard.gg/jupystar | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://starboard.gg/jupystar">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://starboard.gg/jupystar</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25167906</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 04:40:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Optimizing Your Web App 100x Is Like Adding 99 Servers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 299 | Comments 236 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25165752">thread link</a>) | @QuadrupleA
<br/>
November 20, 2020 | https://lukerissacher.com/blog/optimizing_your_web_app | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://lukerissacher.com/blog/optimizing_your_web_app">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>

        
        

        
<p>
A lot of tech discussion these days is focused around scaling web app infrastructures to handle huge traffic.
</p>
<p>
Hacker News abounds with posts about Kubernetes, distributed systems and database replication; the <a href="https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer" target="_blank">Large-Scale System Design Primer</a> on GitHub is extremely well-loved (113k stars) and chock full of advice on memcache clusters and DB sharding.
</p>
<p>
In all the heady excitement of getting your web-based notepad app ready to handle 10 billion daily users, it's important not to forget the power of modern computing hardware and how far simple optimizations can go.
</p>
<p>
You're probably not Facebook. Setting up FAANG-level infrastructure won't make your company into a FAANG, any more than a cargo cult can summon supply-bearing planes by building fake runways and wooden ATC towers. 
</p>
<p>
There's a place for big, scalable cluster infrastructures, but it's a larger scale than many organizations think.
</p>
<h3>The case for optimizing</h3>

<p>
It may sound obvious, but - optimizing your app to fulfill a request in 1/10 the time is like adding 9 servers to a cluster. Optimizing to 1/100 the time (reducing requests from say 1.5 sec to 15ms) is like adding 99 servers. 
</p>
<p>
That's a 1U server doing the work of <em>two 42U server racks</em>, formerly busy turning inefficient code into heat. 
</p>
<p>
That may be an extreme case - but unnecessary bloat is common, and these kinds of gains could be as simple as adding a well-chosen index to speed up a common query by 10x or 100x, or caching some seldom-changing response in memory rather than re-rendering it every time. 
</p>
<p>
Optimizing is good for the world, too:
</p>
<ul>
<li>1/10 or 1/100 the carbon footprint</li>
<li>Cleaner, more maintainable code and systems - optimizing often just means simplifying and removing unnecessary parts</li>
<li>Snappier experience for users (latency is generally lower if you can optimize enough to run on a single server rather than a bunch of networked ones)</li>
<li>Reduced hosting costs</li>
<li>Happier users - developers can focus more on solving users' problems and less on infrastructure</li>

</ul>
<p>
Of course there's a tradeoff between the cost of cloud infrastructure and the cost of paying developers to optimize; but paying developers to set up app clusters and database replication costs money too, and has fewer of the benefits and cost savings.
</p>
<h3>Modern computers are mind-numbingly fast</h3>

<p>
Writing the game engine in C++ for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1090060/Weapon_Hacker/" target="_blank">Weapon Hacker</a>, a side project of mine, taught me a lot about how powerful modern hardware really is. 
</p>
<p>
Coming from a C# / Python / Javascript / JIT-compiled world, my early experiments putting graphics on the screen in native C++ and DirectX were startling; the compiled executable was tiny, started up instantly, and could put hundreds of thousands of objects on the screen at 60 frames per second without breaking a sweat. 
</p>
<p>
A 60 FPS target gives games about 16ms to do all the work they need to in a frame. Weapon Hacker doesn't even compare to what modern AAA engines do, but it generates its random worlds in about 15ms (which last for about an hour-long playthru), and it handles frames with thousands of particles, physics objects, textures, font glyphs and graphical primitives, as well as sound mixing and music streaming, in about 5ms on a 2010-era CPU.
</p>
<p>
Compared to a game engine, the job of most web apps is incredibly mundane: take a request (some HTTP text) and return a response (some HTML or JSON or some such). And yet, 100ms or 500ms request processing times are common. Sometimes the info returned is expensive to generate, but it pays not to forget that in the end it's just inputting some bytes and outputting some bytes. 
</p>
<p>
Given the relative simplicity of the task, 16ms of processing per request (after subtracting network latency) should be achievable in most web applications.
</p>
<p>
On a cheap $5/month dual-core cloud VM, that would allow about 7,500 requests per minute. Or 7,500 pageviews, if you offload static stuff to a CDN. That means 10.8M per day, or 324M pageviews per month. 
</p>
<p>
Of course traffic wouldn't be evenly spread throughout the day, and cloud computing is generally priced for burst loads. But, let's be honest - your traffic isn't anywhere near 324M pageviews, right?
</p>
<p>
If not, condolences that Notepadly.io isn't a market behemoth yet - but congratulations, you can divert some time from multi-master replication and spot instance auto-scaling, and add a cool Clippy virtual assistant instead. Your users will thank you for it.
</p>
<h3>Optimization basics</h3>

<p>
Server-side optimization is a big topic, and there are likely people much better at it (and at explaining it) than I am, so here are just a few general pointers.
</p>
<p>
First - measure.
</p>
<p>
This can be as simple as putting timers around sections of code to see how many milliseconds they take to execute. Or, look at TTFB (time to first byte) in the Network tab of your browser's dev tools. 
</p>
<p>
2ms and 200ms requests seem similar to human perception, despite a massive 100x time difference, so it pays to have hard data.
</p>
<p>
Run simple stress tests to see how much traffic your app can handle. A simple one-page python script on a nearby VM or a dev machine can easily spin up a bunch of threads to make requests as fast as possible. Count the number of completed requests in, say, 30 seconds and watch your server's CPU, memory and IO usage to see where they max out.
</p>
<p>
Compare your stress test results to your day-to-day traffic, and aim for enough headroom that a normal day's traffic peaks at ~1% capacity (or whatever makes sense for your business).
</p>
<p>
Once you have some baseline measurements, here are a few common performance improvements:
</p>
<ul>
<li>Cache infrequently-changing responses in server memory</li>
<li>Optimize your database queries - add a well-chosen index, or delete an unneeded one (indices are separate internal tables, so you can sometimes save a lot of storage space and I/O time by removing one); tweak your WHERE conditions to narrow down the rows the DB has to scan through internally</li>
<li>Reduce the number of HTTP requests; don't let REST purists tell you you need a separate URL for each entity - if your app always needs customer &amp; order data at the same time, make it a single API call</li>
<li>Let clients cache static files indefinitely; use cache-breakers on the URLs for content changes</li>
<li>Offload static files to a CDN</li>
<li>Make sure your web server and database are set up and tuned right - that they have enough memory, threads, etc.</li>
<li>Consider a fast single-file database like <a href="https://sqlite.org/whentouse.html" target="_blank">SQLite</a>; it's not for every application, but I've found it handles individual queries about 5x faster than the big client-server DBMS's, with about 1/5 the storage space, and with much less administrative complexity. With its performance numbers it can actually power large sites. It also supports sharding scenarios (e.g. a database file per customer) which can get around the write-concurrency limitations for some applications.</li>
<li>Learn about code performance - in particular the dominance of memory latency as a slowdown factor, and the high price of I/O. Chandler Carruth has <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fHNmRkzxHWs" target="<em>blank">a great talk</a> on these from a C++ perspective. And Mike Acton's <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rX0ItVEVjHc" target="</em>blank">talk on data-oriented design</a> is a classic.</li>

</ul>
<h3>You can upgrade your VM in a pinch</h3>

<p>
Cloud hosts usually let you upgrade to a higher-powered VM pretty easily in the event of some viral flood of traffic; in AWS, on my clients' projects, we have been able to launch more powerful EC2 instances (and vise-versa, consolidate to smaller, cheaper instances) by cloning to an AMI image, launching a new instance, and rerouting the same elastic IP, in about 5 minutes. If you freeze data changes, you can even stay online during the transition.
</p>
<p>
That could buy you time to think about clustering if you reach the scale where you need it.
</p>
<h3>In summary</h3>

<p>
There's a time and a scale for big distributed computing setups. But modern CPUs and cloud VMs are insanely fast, and the job of most web apps is incredibly mundane - you can get very far with some basic optimizations, and will likely do the world, your developers and your users some favors in the process.
</p>
<p>
Update: some interesting discussion on <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25165752" target="_blank">Hacker News</a>.
</p>


    </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://lukerissacher.com/blog/optimizing_your_web_app</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25165752</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 22:17:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Codeless TikTok component to embed on any website]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 21 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25164875">thread link</a>) | @darielnoel
<br/>
November 20, 2020 | https://woxo.tech/tiktok-widget | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://woxo.tech/tiktok-widget">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="woxo-main-container"><div><div><div><div role="button" tabindex="0"><div><p><span>Or choose a different network</span></p></div></div></div></div><div><div role="button" tabindex="0"><p>Recommended</p><p>Carousels</p><p>Grids</p><p>Small-Business</p><p>Non-profits</p><p>Influencers</p></div></div></div><div><div><h2>What do I get with a Woxo TikTok widget?</h2><div><div><div><div><p>Maximize your Social Proof</p><p>84% of millennials report that UGC on company websites has influence on what they buy.</p></div></div><div><div><p>Increase engagement</p><p>See your website grow in reach and impact with our highest level of service and security.</p></div></div><div><div><p>Boots your<span> TikTok </span>followers</p><p>Re-use your everyday communications and turn them into powerful visuals to improve your online marketing.</p></div></div><div><div><p>Easy to use: Clicks. Embed. Show.</p><p>Embedding<span> a</span><span> TikTok </span>widget into your page has never been easier: just 3 steps and no coding needed!</p></div></div></div></div></div><div><h2>What do I get with a Woxo TikTok widget?</h2><div><div><div><p>Maximize your Social Proof</p><p>84% of millennials report that UGC on company websites has influence on what they buy.</p></div></div><div><div><p>Increase engagement</p><p>See your website grow in reach and impact with our highest level of service and
                security.</p></div></div><div><div><p>Boots your<span> TikTok </span>followers</p><p>Re-use your everyday communications and turn them into powerful visuals to improve your online marketing.</p></div></div><div><div><p>Easy to use: Clicks. Embed. Show.</p><p>Embedding<span> a</span><span> TikTok </span>widget into your page has never been easier: just 3 steps and no coding needed!</p></div></div></div></div></div><div><div><h2>Woxo TikTok widget works...anywhere</h2><div><p><img data-src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dakp804eh/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1580915798/landingPage/tech-we-use-infinite.jpg" alt="Brands" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dakp804eh/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1580915798/landingPage/tech-we-use-infinite.jpg"><img data-src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dakp804eh/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1580915798/landingPage/tech-we-use-infinite.jpg" alt="Brands" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dakp804eh/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1580915798/landingPage/tech-we-use-infinite.jpg"></p></div></div></div><div><div><h2>Our clients says</h2><div><div><div><p><img alt="Jennifer Williams" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dakp804eh/image/upload/v1600111976/landingPage/client-1.png"></p><p>Jennifer Williams</p><p>Product manager</p><p>WOXO and their widgets have been a big help in connecting our social feed into our online store, which resulted in positive clients feedback. During COVID we had to adapt and WOXO was a big help into this new normality!</p></div></div><div><div><p><img alt="Luis Terrero" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dakp804eh/image/upload/v1601668297/landingPage/0.jpg"></p><p>Luis Terrero</p><p>CEO &amp; Web developer</p><p>WOXO is the best widget I've used to integrate my social networks and my blog. In 5 minutes I can do what used to take me hours to do or pay programmers to do!</p></div></div><div><div><p><img alt="Yai Bolanos" src="https://media-exp1.licdn.com/dms/image/C4E03AQHs3AQLCbZnRg/profile-displayphoto-shrink_800_800/0?e=1606953600&amp;v=beta&amp;t=VKHtxDEs2OFnJf_d6ekF6tkrK-_rBnk9WOuPlnhhJSY"></p><p>Yai Bolanos</p><p>Small business owner</p><p>A must-have for the non-coders out there who want to upgrade their online content and make their website portfolio more aesthetic! It's super easy to use -I embed my first widget in minutes- and has a nice set of templates for creative minds.</p></div></div></div></div></div><div><h2>Embed your TikTok widget and get all the help you need!</h2></div><div><h2>Plans</h2><div><p>Unlimited websites</p><svg version="1.1" id="Layer_1" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" x="0px" y="0px" width="156px" viewBox="0 0 156.1 67.2" style="enable-background:new 0 0 156.1 67.2;margin:0 24px" xml:space="preserve"><linearGradient id="Trazado_4385_1_" gradientUnits="userSpaceOnUse" x1="-556.4082" y1="429.0671" x2="-557.4082" y2="429.0671" gradientTransform="matrix(156.1901 0 0 -67.183 87061.6094 28859.625)"><stop offset="0" style="stop-color:#40BF00"></stop><stop offset="1" style="stop-color:#CDD40F"></stop></linearGradient><path id="Trazado_4385" style="fill:url(#Trazado_4385_1_)" d="M122.6,67.2L122.6,67.2c-9,0-17.5-3.5-23.7-9.9L84.8,43.2l2.8-2.8l14.1,14.1 c5.5,5.6,13,8.7,20.9,8.7h0.1c16.3,0,29.5-13.2,29.5-29.5c0-16.3-13.2-29.5-29.5-29.5l0,0h-0.1c-7.8,0-15.3,3.1-20.8,8.6L57.2,57.2 C44,70.3,22.8,70.3,9.8,57.2C-3.3,44.1-3.3,22.8,9.8,9.8C16.1,3.5,24.6,0,33.5,0h0.1C42.5,0,51,3.5,57.2,9.9L71,23.7l-2.8,2.8 L54.4,12.7C48.9,7.1,41.4,4,33.6,4h-0.1C17.2,4,4,17.2,4,33.5C4,49.8,17.2,63,33.5,63c7.8,0,15.3-3.1,20.8-8.6L99,9.9 c6.3-6.3,14.8-9.8,23.7-9.8h0.1c18.5,0,33.5,15,33.5,33.5S141.1,67.2,122.6,67.2L122.6,67.2L122.6,67.2z"></path></svg><p>Unlimited websites</p><p>Unlimited pageviews</p></div><p>on all plans!</p><div><div><div><div><p>Free</p><p>For individuals and small groups working on quick projects</p><p><sup>$</sup>0</p><p>month</p><ul><li><p><span>Unlimited Websites</span></p></li><li><p><span>Unlimited Pageviews</span></p></li><li><p><span>More than 50 templates</span></p></li><li><p><span>Email Support</span></p></li></ul></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Pro</p><p>For individuals and small teams who need more customization and productivity</p><p><sup>$</sup>3.99</p><p>month</p><p>Everything<!-- --> Free <!-- -->has, plus:</p><ul><li><p><span>Remove WOXO Watermark</span></p></li><li><p><span>24/7 Chat Support</span></p></li><li><p><span>Premium Features</span></p></li></ul></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Business</p><p>For larger teams who need advanced brand and collaboration control</p><p><sup>$</sup>99</p><p>month</p><p>Everything<!-- --> Pro <!-- -->has, plus:</p><ul><li><p><span>99.9% uptime SLA</span></p></li><li><p><span>SLA 24/7 Priority Support</span></p></li><li><p><span>Team Access</span></p></li></ul></div></div></div></div><div><p><strong>14 Day </strong>Money Back Guarantee on All Premium Plans</p><p>*We offer also an Enterprise plan starting at $2000 a month which includes<strong> Tailor customizations </strong>and<strong> 24/7 Enterprise-level support. </strong>Please<a href="https://support.woxo.tech/hc/en-us">contact us</a>for more information.</p></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://woxo.tech/tiktok-widget</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25164875</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 21:00:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Facebook’s experimental hate-speech policy seems to be working]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 65 | Comments 132 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25164676">thread link</a>) | @leoschwartz
<br/>
November 20, 2020 | https://restofworld.org/2020/pressing-pause-on-fake-news-in-myanmar/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://restofworld.org/2020/pressing-pause-on-fake-news-in-myanmar/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			
<p>Wearing a plastic face shield and his orange monastic robes, Ashin Wirathu walked into a Yangon police station on November 2 after more than a year on the run. Until he went into hiding in June of last year, Wirathu, a nationalist preacher with links to the Tatmadaw — the Burmese military — was <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2017/may/12/only-takes-one-terrorist-buddhist-monk-reviles-myanmar-muslims-rohingya-refugees-ashin-wirathu">one of Myanmar’s most prominent Islamophobes</a>, spreading bigotry and disinformation online. In May 2019, he was <a href="https://www.mmtimes.com/news/warrant-issued-arrest-ultranationalist-monk.html">charged with sedition</a>, but he <a href="https://myanmar-now.org/en/news/wirathu-declared-a-fugitive-after-failing-to-appear-at-court">never showed up</a> for his court date.</p>



<p>Wirathu’s surrender came in the final stages of an election campaign that once again exposed Myanmar’s racial and religious tensions, three years after a surge in hate speech and nationalist sentiment drove a campaign of ethnic cleansing targeting the country’s Muslim Rohingya minority.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The monk’s act was a piece of theater designed to put him and his anti-Muslim ideology back in the public eye and feed into the rumors and misinformation that was circulating online. Activists braced for a surge in hate speech on social media. It never came. The hard news of his arrest was covered by the mainstream press, but online, his supporters were strangely muted. Facebook pages sharing his views were flagged by civil society groups and quickly shut down by the platform.</p>



<p>“He didn’t get anything like the megaphone that he had hoped to get,” says Victoire Rio, a Yangon-based researcher and advisor to the Myanmar Tech Accountability Network, a consortium of nonprofit groups working on disinformation and hate speech. “The whole thing got fairly well contained, and that’s in big part because Facebook was able to take action.”</p>



	




<p>Facebook has faced years of criticism for its failings in Myanmar. In 2018, the <a href="https://uk.reuters.com/article/us-myanmar-rohingya-facebook/u-n-investigators-cite-facebook-role-in-myanmar-crisis-idUKKCN1GO2PN">United Nations alleged the platform</a>&nbsp;allowed the proliferation of hate speech that incited the genocide. Campaigners in the U.S. and in Myanmar had been pressuring the company to prepare for the 2020 elections to prevent further violence.</p>



<p>In response, Facebook began trialing a <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2020/08/preparing-for-myanmars-2020-election/">new, more active approach</a> to dealing with hate speech and political disinformation in the run up to the vote on November 8. It involved limiting users’ ability to reshare old pictures without context — a common misinformation tactic — and working with local partners to verify political parties’ pages and fact-check stories.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Most significantly, the “community standards” Facebook uses to police content on its platforms were expanded. Usually, the company does not remove misinformation unless it creates a threat of imminent harm, but for a few months in Myanmar, that policy was broadened to include anything that could “suppress the vote or damage the integrity of the electoral process” — for example, a baseless rumor that the country’s de facto leader, Aung San Suu Kyi, had died from Covid-19, which circulated before the election. Normally, the company’s community standards defines “hate speech” narrowly as attacks on people not concepts — Muslims, but not Islam. That was changed to prevent users from targeting the religion itself or attacking “invaders” or “illegals,” derogatory terms that refer to the Rohingya.</p>



	




<p>It is the first time the company has created country-specific community standards.</p>



<p>“That was a huge deal,” Rio says. “A lot of the problematic content is not framed as hate speech or as a call to violence in the way that Facebook likes it to be, like <em>Cluedo</em> — the weapon, the victim, the location, the whole thing.”</p>



<p>Myanmar has a well-documented problem with online hate speech and malicious falsehoods, which often attack the country’s Muslims. Nationalists and ultra-conservative Buddhists have successfully portrayed Muslims as a threat to the country’s culture and majority religion and as foreign interlopers. This hostility is so widespread that in the 2020 election, mainstream political parties competed to portray their opponents as more sympathetic to Islam.</p>



<p>One widely shared claim, originating from a candidate for the military-backed Union Solidarity and Development Party, was that <a href="https://www.myanmar-now.org/en/news/nld-to-report-usdp-candidate-for-making-false-claims-about-muslims-in-the-ruling-party?page=2">Suu Kyi’s National League for Democracy (NLD) had 42 Muslim candidates</a>. The true number was two. An image circulated on social media showing an NLD meeting in which Buddhist monks appeared to be sitting on the floor while Muslim attendees sat on chairs, which, presented without context, looked like a calculated insult. Normally, such falsehoods would not have breached Facebook’s community standards.&nbsp;</p>


		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/GettyImages-1229414436-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/GettyImages-1229414436-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/GettyImages-1229414436-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/GettyImages-1229414436-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/GettyImages-1229414436-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/GettyImages-1229414436-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/GettyImages-1229414436-2800x1867.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 600px(max-width: 992px) calc(100vw - 40px), (max-width: 1140px) calc(100vw - 290px), calc(100vw - ((100vw - 640px)/2))" alt="Ashin Wirathu turning himself into a Yangon police station on November 2.">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				<span itemprop="copyrightHolder">Sai Aung Main/AFP/Getty Images)</span>
			</figcaption>
		</figure>


<p>In October and November, disinformation that tried to exploit religious differences to distort the election result was taken down by Facebook, as were fake “leaked documents” feeding conspiracy theories linking Suu Kyi to the financier and human rights activist George Soros and unfounded claims by the opposition that the vote was rigged.</p>



<p>Several of Facebook’s “trusted partners,” civil society organizations that the company gives a kind of express lane for reporting violations of community standards, told <em>Rest of World</em> that in October and November, when they reported falsehoods and hate speech, their complaints were quickly escalated and the flagged content was removed. Previously, they found that their interventions carried little weight.</p>



<p>“To their credit, [Facebook has] thrown in much more effort, many more resources, for this election than we’ve seen them do … in the last few years,” says Jes Kaliebe Petersen, CEO of Phandeeyar, a social-technology accelerator in Yangon. “That’s been very positive. They’ve had boots on the ground; they’ve had people from their Singapore team dedicated to this. They’ve engaged with civil society.”</p>



<p>In October, Facebook <a href="https://uk.reuters.com/article/uk-facebook-myanmar/facebook-shuts-dozens-of-myanmar-pages-over-inauthentic-behaviour-idUKKBN27M1BC">removed dozens of accounts</a> for “coordinated inauthentic behavior,” its term for spreading disinformation, and dismantled networks of fake users and clickbait pages that were pushing political misinformation. (Data for Facebook’s takedowns in November is not yet available.) Activists told <em>Rest of World</em> that the approach led to a significant reduction in disinformation and hate speech compared to the previous election five years ago.</p>



<p>“I’m not saying there is no hate speech in 2020, but I think it’s much less than in 2015,” says Harry Myo Lin, an interfaith activist. “They have a more active response to reports and hateful content. It’s not perfect, but I think they did better than before.”</p>



<p>A side effect of Facebook’s crackdowns on hate speech some actors migrated to other platforms, including the Russian social network VK and YouTube — exposing the latter’s own deficiencies in dealing with malicious content. “YouTube, now, is the most problematic one,” says Myat Thu, founder of the Yangon-based fact-checking site Think Before You Trust.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Google-owned YouTube did not respond to a request for comment.</p>



<p>With the vote now over — the incumbent NLD won in a decisive victory — Facebook is set to return to its pre-election policies on December 6, leaving activists concerned that the platform will revert to being a place where hate and disinformation continues to circulate.</p>



<p>“The big question is: What happens next?” Petersen says. “Is this a sign of a new level of consistent support and focus from Facebook, or is it like a SWAT team that they put in, and now … the SWAT team is going to leave again, and we’re back to where we were before.”</p>



<p>In a statement, Facebook said it considers the experiment a success and could adapt it for other countries in the future.</p>



<p>At the Myanmar Tech Accountability Network, Rio said that while Facebook’s experimental approach still had profound flaws, it demonstrated that the company does have the tools to deal with the corrosive misinformation and bigotry that have proliferated on the platform worldwide.</p>



<p>“We need to give them credit where it’s due. They did pretty well,” Rio says. “But if anything, it shows that when they want to, they can.”</p>
		</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://restofworld.org/2020/pressing-pause-on-fake-news-in-myanmar/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25164676</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 20:38:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Moving from Macbook to Linux]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 501 | Comments 482 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25163685">thread link</a>) | @gk1
<br/>
November 20, 2020 | https://monadical.com/posts/moving-to-linux-desktop.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://monadical.com/posts/moving-to-linux-desktop.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://monadical.com/posts/moving-to-linux-desktop.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25163685</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 19:02:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Static Typing for Ruby: Adopting Sorbet at Scale]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 149 | Comments 69 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25162839">thread link</a>) | @ufuk
<br/>
November 20, 2020 | https://shopify.engineering/static-typing-ruby | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://shopify.engineering/static-typing-ruby">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
  <p><em><strong>Join us November 25, 2020 at 1 pm EST for ShipIt! Presents: The State of Ruby Static Typing at Shopify as we talk about static typing at Shopify. We’ll share why we chose Sorbet for the monolith and the lessons we learned along the way the&nbsp;way. <a href="#ShipIt">Please Register</a>.</strong></em></p>
<p>Shopify changes a lot. We merge around 400 commits to the main branch daily and deploy a new version of our core monolith 40 times a day. The Monolith is also big: 37,000 Ruby files, 622,000 methods, more than 2,000,000 calls. At this scale with a dynamic language, even with the most rigorous review process and over 150,000 automated tests, it’s a challenge to ensure everything&nbsp;runs smoothly. Developers benefit from a short feedback loop to ensure the stability of our monolith for our merchants.</p>
<p>Since 2018, our Ruby Infrastructure team has looked at ways to make the development process safer, faster, and more enjoyable for Ruby developers. While Ruby is different from other languages and brings amazing features allowing Shopify to be what it is today, we felt there was a feature from other languages missing: <strong>static typing</strong>.</p>

<p>Even in 2018, typing for Ruby wasn't a novelty. A few attempts were made to integrate type annotations directly into the language or through external tools (RDL, Steep), or as libraries (dry-types).&nbsp;</p>
<p>Which solution would best fit Shopify considering its codebase and culture? For the Ruby Infrastructure team, the best match for a typing solution needs:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<strong>Gradual typing: </strong>Typing a monolith isn't a simple task and can’t be done in a day. Our code evolves fast, and we can’t ask developers to stop coding while we add types to the existing codebase. We need flexibility to add types without blocking the development process or limiting our ability to satisfy merchants needs.</li>
<li>
<strong>Speed</strong>: Considering the size of Shopify’s codebase, speed is a concern. If our goal is to provide quick feedback on errors and remove pressure from continuous integration (CI), we need a solution that’s fast.</li>
<li>
<strong>Full Ruby support</strong>: We use all of Ruby at Shopify. Our culture embraces the language and benefits from all features, even hard to type ones like metaprogramming, overloading, and class reopening. Support for Rails is also a must. From code elegance to developer happiness, the chosen solution needs to be compatible as much as possible with all Ruby features.</li>
</ul>
<p>With such a list of requirements, none of the contenders at the time could satisfy our needs, especially the speed requirement. We started thinking about developing our own solution, but a perfectly timed meeting with Stripe, who were working on a solution to the problem, introduced us to <a href="https://sorbet.org/" target="_blank" title="Sorbet is a fast, powerful type checker designed for Ruby" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Sorbet</a>.</p>
<p>Sorbet was closed-source at the time and under heavy development but was already promising. It’s built for gradual typing with phenomenal performance (able to analyze 100,000 lines per second per core) making it significantly faster than running automated tests. It can handle hard to type things like metaprogramming, thanks to Ruby Interface files (RBI). This is how, at the start of 2019, Shopify began its journey toward static type checking for Ruby.</p>

<p>With only a three-person team and a lot on our plate, fully typing our monolith with Sorbet was going to be an approach based on Shopify’s <a href="https://vimeo.com/456735890" target="_blank" title="Shopify - How we Get Shit Done" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Get Shit Done (GSD) framework</a>.</p>
<ol>
<li>We tested the viability of Sorbet on our core monolith by only typing a few files, to check if we could observe benefits from it while not impairing other developers’ work. Sorbets’ gradual approach proved to be working.</li>
<li>We manually created RBI files to represent what Sorbet could not understand yet. We checked we supported Ruby’s most advanced features as well as Rails constructs.</li>
<li>We added more and more files while keeping an eye on performance ensuring Sorbet would scale with our monolith.</li>
</ol>
<p>This gave us confidence Sorbet was the right choice to solve our problem. Once we officially decided to go with Sorbet we reflected on how we can reach 100% adoption in the monolith. To determine our roadmap we looked at:</p>
<ul>
<li>how many files needed to be typed</li>
<li>the content of the files</li>
<li>the Ruby features they used.</li>
</ul>

<p>Type checking in Sorbet comes in different levels of strictness. The strictness is defined on a per file basis by adding a magic comment in the file, called a <em>sigil</em>, written <code># typed: LEVEL</code>, where <code>LEVEL</code> can be one of the following:&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>
<strong>ignore</strong>: At this level, the file is not even read by Sorbet, and no errors are reported for this file at all.</li>
<li>
<strong>false</strong>: Only errors related to syntax, constant resolution and correctness of sigs are reported. At this level sorbet doesn’t check the calls in the files even if the methods called don't exist anywhere in the codebase.</li>
<li>
<strong>true</strong>: This is the level where Sorbet actually starts to type check your code. All methods called need to exist in the code base. For each call, Sorbet will check that the arguments count matches the method definition. If the method has a signature, Sorbet will also check their types.</li>
<li>
<strong>strict</strong>: At this level all methods must have a signature, and all constants and instance variables must have explicitly annotated types.</li>
<li>
<strong>strong</strong>: Sorbet no longer allows untyped variables. In practice, this level is actually unusable for most files because Sorbet can’t type everything yet and even Stripe advises against using it.</li>
</ul>
<p>Once we were able to run Sorbet on our codebase, we needed a way to track our progress and identify which parts of our monolith were typed with which strictness or which parts needed more work. To do so we created SorbetMetrics, a tool able to collect and display metrics about typing coverage for all our internal projects. We started tracking three key metrics to measure Sorbet adoption :</p>
<ul>
<li>
<strong>Sigils</strong>: how many files are typed <code>ignore</code>, <code>false</code>, <code>true</code>, <code>strict</code> or <code>strong</code>
</li>
<li>
<strong>Calls</strong>: how many calls are sent to a method with a signature</li>
<li>
<strong>Signatures</strong>: how many methods have a signature</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="Bar graph showing increased Sorbet usage in projects over time. Below the bar graph is a table showing the percentage of sigils, calls, signatures in each project." data-src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0779/4361/files/sorbet-dashboard_ef9747c0-3326-4b45-bbe9-59a1680718f2.jpg?v=1605798789" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0779/4361/files/sorbet-dashboard_ef9747c0-3326-4b45-bbe9-59a1680718f2.jpg?v=1605798789"><br><em>SorbetMetrics dashboard homepage</em></p>
<p>Each day SorbetMetrics pulls the latest version of our monolith and other Shopify projects using Sorbet, computes those metrics and displays them in a dashboard internally available to all our developers.</p>
<p><img alt="A selection of charts from the SorbetMetrics Dashboard. 3 pie charts showing the percentage of sigils, calls, and signatures in the monolith. 3 line charts showing Sigils, calls, and signature percentage over time. A circular tree map showing the relationship between strictness level and components. 2 line charts showing Sorbet versions and typechecking time over time" data-src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0779/4361/files/Sorbet-Dashboard-Monolith_512c3e68-3865-46f5-9b6f-58864ea48a2a.jpg?v=1605761716" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0779/4361/files/Sorbet-Dashboard-Monolith_512c3e68-3865-46f5-9b6f-58864ea48a2a.jpg?v=1605761716"><br><em>SorbetMetrics dashboard for our monolith</em></p>

<p>If we treat typing as a product, we also need to focus on supporting and enabling our “customers” who are developers at Shopify. One of our goals was to have a strong support system in place to help with any problems that arise and slow developers down.</p>
<p>Initially, we supported developers with a dedicated Slack channel where Shopifolk could ask questions to the team. We’d answer these questions real-time and help Shopifolk with typing efforts where our input was important.</p>
<p>This white glove support model obviously didn't scale, but it was an excellent learning opportunity for our team—we now understood the biggest challenges and recurring problems. We ended up solving some problems over and over again, but it solidified the effort to understand the patterns and decide which features to work on next.</p>
<p>Using Slack meant our answers weren't discoverable forever. We moved most of the support and conversation to our internal Discourse platform, increasing discoverability and broader sharing of knowledge. This also allows us to record solutions in a single place and let developers self-serve as much as possible. As we onboard more and more projects with Sorbet, this solution scales better.</p>

<p>Going further from unblocking our users, we also need to ensure their happiness. Sorbet and more generally static typing in Ruby wouldn’t be a good fit for us if it made our developers miserable. We’re aware that it introduces a bit more work, so the benefits need to balance with the inconvenience.</p>
<p>Our first tool to measure developers’ opinions of Sorbet is surveys. Twice a year, we send a “Typing @ Shopify” survey to all developers and collect their sentiments regarding Sorbet’s benefits and limitations, as well as what we should focus on in the future.</p>
<p><img alt="A bar graph showing the increasing strongly agree answer over time to the question I want Sorbet to be applied to other Shopify projects. Below that graph is a bar graph showing the increasing strongly agree answer over time to the question I want more code to be typed." data-src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0779/4361/files/Sobert-at-Shopify-Survey-Results-1.jpg?v=1605764198" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0779/4361/files/Sobert-at-Shopify-Survey-Results-1.jpg?v=1605764198"><br><em>Some responses&nbsp;from our “Sorbet @ Shopify” surveys</em></p>
<p>We use simple questions (“yes” or “no”, or a “Strongly Disagree” (1) to “Strongly Agree” (5) scale) and then look at how the answers evolve over time. The&nbsp;survey results gave us&nbsp;interesting insights:</p>
<ul>
<li>Sorbet catches more errors on developer’s pull requests (PR) as adoption increased</li>
<li>Signatures help with code understanding and give developers confidence to ship</li>
<li>Added&nbsp;confidence&nbsp;directly impacted&nbsp;the increasing positive opinion about static typing in Ruby</li>
<li>Over time developers&nbsp;wanted more code and more projects to be typed</li>
<li>Developers get used to Sorbet syntax over time</li>
<li>IDE integration with Sorbet is a feature developers are rooting for</li>
</ul>
<p>Our main observation is that developers enjoy Sorbet more as the typing coverage increases. This is one reason that's increasing our motivation to reach 100% of files at <code>typed: true</code> and maximize the amount of methods with a signature.</p>
<p>The second tool is interviews with individual developers. We select a team working with Sorbet and meet each member to talk about their experience using Sorbet either in the monolith or on another project. We get a better understanding of what their likes and dislikes are, what we should be improving, but also how we can better support them when introducing Sorbet, so the team keeps Sorbet in their project.</p>

<p>Currently, Sorbet is only enforced on our main monolith and we have about 60 other internal projects that opted to use Sorbet as well. On our main monolith, we require all files to be at least <code>typed: false</code> and Sorbet is run on our continuous integration platform (CI) for every PR and fails builds if type checking errors are found. We’re currently evaluating the idea of enforcing valid type checking on CI even before running the automated tests.</p>
<p><img alt="Three pie charts showing percentage of sigils, calls, and signatures in the monolith used to measure Sorbet adoption" data-src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0779/4361/files/Typing-Coverage-Shopify-Monolith.jpg?v=1605764949" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0779/4361/files/Typing-Coverage-Shopify-Monolith.jpg?v=1605764949"><br><em>Typing coverage metrics for Shopify’s monolith</em></p>
<p>As of today, 80% of our files (including tests) are <code>typed: true</code> or higher. Almost half of our calls are typed and half of our methods have signatures. All of this can be type checked under 15 seconds on our developers machines.</p>
<p><img alt="A circular tree map showing the relationship between strictness level and components" data-src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0779/4361/files/SorbetMetrics-Circular-tree-graph-strictness-level-components.jpg?v=1605765173" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0779/4361/files/SorbetMetrics-Circular-tree-graph-strictness-level-components.jpg?v=1605765173"><br><em>Files strictness map in Shopify’s monolith</em></p>
<p>The circle map shows which …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://shopify.engineering/static-typing-ruby">https://shopify.engineering/static-typing-ruby</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://shopify.engineering/static-typing-ruby</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25162839</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 17:43:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[AB07-USB3FMC: The $1.65k eval board they can't be bothered to test]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 178 | Comments 140 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25161325">thread link</a>) | @segfaultbuserr
<br/>
November 20, 2020 | https://lab.ktemkin.com/post/ab07-usb3fmc-wtf/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://lab.ktemkin.com/post/ab07-usb3fmc-wtf/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
    

    <p>I've written a bit about my look at “commercial off-the-shelf” USB3 PHY boards; and have been
taking a look recently at the <a href="https://www.mouser.com/ProductDetail/Design-Gateway/AB07-USB3FMC?qs=5aG0NVq1C4wWGaHs8Oqcww%3D%3D">Design Gateway AB07-USBFMC module</a>. It turns out that my unit has what seems to be a pretty
embarrassing defect.</p>
<p>I've been testing my in-progress USB3 gateware with this PHY; and I've been running into an
interesting issue: periodically, some of the raw values sent were off by a single bit.</p>
<p>When training a USB3 link, one of the data sequences exchanged looks like this:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="sh">BC BC BC BC <span>00</span> <span>00</span> 4A 4A 
4A 4A 4A 4A 4A 4A 4A 4A 
</code></pre></div><p>When using the AB07-USBFMC, trying to send this pattern resulted in the following:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="sh">BC BC BC BC <span>00</span> <span>00</span> 0A 4A
0A 4A 0A 4A 0A 4A 0A 4A
</code></pre></div><p>This is interesting for two reasons:</p>
<ul>
<li>This PHY has geared inputs, and accepts two bytes of data at a time.</li>
<li>The incorrect values (<code>0A</code>) are off from the correct value (<code>4A</code>) by a single bit.</li>
</ul>
<p>Sure enough, modifying the data packet to send <code>FF</code> instead of <code>4A</code> pretty clearly shows off that missing bit:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="sh">BC BC BC BC <span>00</span> <span>00</span> BF FF
BF FF BF FF BF FF BF FF
</code></pre></div><p>At this point, I assumed that I'd gotten the pinout incorrect; and that I'd been writing to the wrong pin –
but careful examination of the documentation and my FPGA I/O definitions suggested that I had things right.
This suggested it was time to check things on the physical layer.</p>
<p>The board in question looks like this:</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://lab.ktemkin.com/post-media/ab07-usb3fmc-wtf/board.jpg" alt="The PHY board, which features a notable long span of resistors, neatly tucked in parallel."> <figcaption>
            <h4>The AB07-USBFMC (slightly modified as detailed later).</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Notably, there's a long series of what look like termination / signal conditioning resistors present at
the PHY boundary – and it looks like there's about 32 in total; which would make sense: 16 for transmit,
and 16 for receive.</p>
<p>A quick probe verifies that these are ~50R resistors, which would make a lot of sense for series termination:</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://lab.ktemkin.com/post-media/ab07-usb3fmc-wtf/50r.jpg" alt="Multimeter showing a measurement of 47.5 ohms."> <figcaption>
            <h4>Sure looks like a series termination resistor.</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>This is excellent news, as it means that the signals are easily accessible without “voiding our warranty”,
which is a bit of a comfort when dealing with a rather expensive evaluation board.</p>
<p>So, as a next-step test, I had my FPGA squirt a 100MHz clock signal into every line on the transmit bus,
and probed the PHY side of one of those termination resistors:</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://lab.ktemkin.com/post-media/ab07-usb3fmc-wtf/phy_tx_healthy.png" alt="A somewhat-rounded square wave, consistent with probing a 100MHz clock."> <figcaption>
            <h4>A nice, healthy wobble. AC coupled.</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>The frequency and amplitude of this signal are pretty in-line with what you'd expect: the amplitude corresponds
nicely to a decently healthy logic <code>1</code>. But how does the signal look on the problematic bit?</p>
<p>I adjusted the FPGA design so it only squirted a wave into the problematic bit; and probed in line until I found it:</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://lab.ktemkin.com/post-media/ab07-usb3fmc-wtf/phy_tx_unhealthy.png" alt="A somewhat-rounded square wave, consistent with probing a 100MHz clock."> <figcaption>
            <h4>A *lot* less happy. Still AC couled for display.</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Ut-oh. This signal's looking a lot less happy – and a lot more attenuated. At approximately 500mV peak,
you'd be hard pressed to consider this a logic <code>1</code>, even if you gave it your very best squint. There's no way
this thing would have worked in a test environment – which makes it seem very unlikely that this board was, y'know,
tested.</p>
<p>This immediately made me suspicious of the termination resistor sitting next to it; and apparently for good reason:</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://lab.ktemkin.com/post-media/ab07-usb3fmc-wtf/larger_50r.jpg" alt="Multimeter showing a measurement of 396.0 ohms."> <figcaption>
            <h4>Quite possibly the largest 50 Ω I've ever seen.</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>This resistor is quite clearly supposed to be 50 Ω. It's also quite clearly <em>not</em> 50 Ω, despite sitting cleanly
in the middle of a row of 50 Ω resistors, and pretty much definitely the source of my problems.</p>
<p>So, naturally it's time to perform what I assume must be several hundred dollars worth of rework on this $1.65k board.
Luckily, I stock E24 0402s, so I had the resistor replaced with an appropriate value in no time.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://lab.ktemkin.com/post-media/ab07-usb3fmc-wtf/happier.png" alt="Oscilloscope display of a corrected waveform."> <figcaption>
            <h4>Much happier. Note the amplitude.</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>With an appropriate value replaced, everything looks much happier – and everything works much more nicely.
Finally, our USB training sets look just the way they should:</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://lab.ktemkin.com/post-media/ab07-usb3fmc-wtf/yay.png" alt="Analyzer display showing the correct value of our training set."> <figcaption>
            <h4>A correct Training Set, at last.</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>I'm planning on reaching out to Design Gateway – to at least let them know that this is an issue on some boards.
I'll update this post if/when I get a reply.</p>


  </article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://lab.ktemkin.com/post/ab07-usb3fmc-wtf/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25161325</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 15:26:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The golden age of configuration languages]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 45 | Comments 49 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25160461">thread link</a>) | @iliec
<br/>
November 20, 2020 | https://cosminilie.ro/posts/evolution-of-configuration-languages/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://cosminilie.ro/posts/evolution-of-configuration-languages/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>I think DevOps, as we understand it today, is coming to an end. At least the Ops part of it. As cloud infrastructure becomes a key application concern, more and more ops tasks are done by the cloud itself or built into the application. What’s left is the provisioning and management of the infrastructure needed by the application. This comes with all the baggage associated, like security and networking, for example.</p>
<p>All of these patterns that are now being forged will make the infrastructure provisioning indistinguishable from the application itself for the general use case. Right now, in most companies, traditional IT Groups have rebranded themselves as DevOps and are now the gatekeepers of AWS, instead of the on-premise VMWare clusters. They use Terraform instead of bash scripts and are generally more agile, having adopted many of the development practices. These are specialized people that are familiar with networking, with how IAM works in AWS. They are responsible for building the networking part, the infrastructure, securing it, and handing it over to the application that uses them.</p>
<p>The developers are mostly fine with it, as they don’t want to learn the intricacies of AWS IAM or VPC’s. I’m reminded in many ways of how the database was treated when I joined the industry in the 2000s. Back then, the application would not touch the structure of the database. You would have scripts that would be run by DBAs on production systems. Those would create the database structure, the tables, indexes, and basically the entire database structure. Developers would then map these to their code and just perform DML once the application was running on a fixed schema that is managed by someone else. I see infrastructure the same way today.</p>
<p>Once ORM and various other frameworks started to manage this domain, these concerns got bundled in the application. There is no reason why the same thing won’t happen to infrastructure. The only problem is we didn’t have the right frameworks to do it, but now we’re starting to get them.</p>
<p>The need to handle application infrastructure (I see this different than managing core business services infrastructure like AD, email, finance systems, etc.) at scale happened in the age of virtualization and started with CFEngine. For those that don’t know, CFEngine was one of the first configuration management systems as we understand it today, followed by Puppet, Chef, and others. CFEngine happened in the age where most provisioned happened either by hand or by following documented step by step instructions. At the core of the proposition was a whitepaper written by Mark Burgess <sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup>. The mainline of reasoning was:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Present day computer systems are fragile and unreliable. Human beings are involved in the care and repair of computer systems at every stage in their operation. This level of human involvement will be impossible to maintain in the future. Biological and social systems of comparable and greater complexity have self-healing processes that are crucial to their survival. It will be necessary to mimic such systems if our future computer systems are to prosper in a complex and hostile environment.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>CFEngine was one of the first cracks of the problem of building a self-healing system that works at scale and shares some of the ideas from the immune system. To achieve this, it leveraged four important properties:
1) It used a DSL to describe the desired state instead of using procedural languages. This would try to abstract components to allow administrators to parameterize and reuse.
2) It has converging semantics, i.e., one describes what a system should look like, and when the system has been brought to that state, CFEngine becomes inert.
4) It offers protection against an unfortunate repetition of tasks and hanging processes in situations where several administrators are working independently with little opportunity to communicate.</p>
<p>Using these features, one could achieve a self-correcting and self-healing system, which would result in a system that maintains fault tolerance. Today with AWS, we can design a system that displays the same properties by leveraging multi-regional services. By their nature, these services can transfer these properties to the application if employed with careful design.</p>
<p>Lots of other tools appeared around the same time or soon after, each focusing on different aspects of the initial value proposition. Probably the most popular are Puppet and Chef. Each has its strong points. At the company I work, we went with Puppet to handle our infrastructure configuration mostly because it was easier to read for non-programers. From a sysadmin perspective, it was appealing to get something done without diving too much into coding. In time, it would prove to be a false choice that would hurt us more than it helped.</p>
<p>Puppet has its own DSL, its own terminology, and idiosyncrasies. It has its own ecosystem of tools, dashboards, and extensions that help you get pretty far in managing your infrastructure. Its strong point is dealing with single server systems that didn’t need distributed coordination between them. There is a way of coordination across several servers with exported resources and PuppetDB, but it always felt hacky to me((it may be a different story today, but I haven’t followed the space for a couple of years now).</p>
<pre><code>
#https://github.com/voxpupuli/puppet-minecraft/blob/master/manifests/user.pp

class minecraft::user {
  group { $minecraft::group:
    ensure =&gt; present,
    system =&gt; true,
  }

  user { $minecraft::user:
    ensure     =&gt; present,
    gid        =&gt; $minecraft::group,
    home       =&gt; $minecraft::install_dir,
    managehome =&gt; true,
    system     =&gt; true,
    require    =&gt; Group[$minecraft::group],
  }

  # Ensures deletion of install_dir does not break module, setup for plugins
  $dirs = [$minecraft::install_dir, "${minecraft::install_dir}/plugins"]

  file { $dirs:
    ensure  =&gt; directory,
    owner   =&gt; $minecraft::user,
    group   =&gt; $minecraft::group,
    require =&gt; User[$minecraft::user],
  }
}
</code></pre>
<p>This worked well and allowed us to build a lot of automation to manage hundreds of servers when dealing with simple infrastructure components. But like most things, it’s the edge cases that make you feel the pain. Since the Puppet language is a DSL, simple problems started to become big problems. Like, not being able to do a proper for-loop. Or doing string manipulation.</p>
<p>Most configuration languages suffer from these problems. In the end, you will also probably get in a situation where you need to extend them to cover a specific use case, and usually, it’s at this point that you will need to write real code. There is only so much you can do without writing in “real” languages, so we should have probably done it from the start. Looking back, probably Chef would have been a much better choice. At least with it, a lot of the things learned there could have been applied to other aspects of my career (Chef uses ruby instead of their own DSL). I don’t have a lot of experience with Ansible or with Salt, but I feel they suffer from the same shortcomings and have similar strong points.</p>
<p>A somewhat distinct category in the configuration language space is Terraform and AWS Cloud Formation. They both borrow from the legacy of configuration management systems and try to sync their internal view of how things should look with reality. The main difference, outside of the way you express intent (which is still using DSL and not full fledge languages), is that they’re designed to work at the cloud provider level.</p>
<p>Just as Puppet and Chef are very good at managing typical resources on a machine (service, package, config file), Terraform and AWS Cloud Formation are very good at managing cloud services. They were built with the notion of cloud infrastructure. This doesn’t mean that you can’t do the same thing with Puppet, Chef, and the rest of the gen2 configuration languages. You can, but due to how fast they adapted to the cloud reality, how they tried to monetize the cloud, and so on, Terraform became the uncontested king of DSL based cloud infrastructure management, while Cloud Formation reigned in AWS land.</p>
<p>All these tools adopted the best parts from CFEngine, the most important being the notion of convergent state. They would take your expressed intent, compare it to the machine, figure out any dependencies and order of steps that will bring the resources to its desired state. They usually also involve a compilation stage where they map the DSL to inner logic and create an execution plan. This would also catch basic mistakes. These are good ideas that have battle-proven and are now the default way of dealing with infrastructure.</p>
<p>As we move forward, however, fundamental shifts are happening in the way we consume and deal with infrastructure components. Now you can leverage AWS services. You can build a very complex application that uses CloudFront for static content distribution, API gateway with Lambda to build API routes and add business functionality to them. Identity management can be handled by Cognito. On the backend, these Lambda functions can interact with an entire ecosystem of infrastructure directly, like RDS or DynamoDB. You can interact with analytics systems via Redshift or display visualized data via QuickSight. Background tasks can be handled by Lambda as well, workflows driven with step functions, async batch, and ETL tasks using AWS EMR or Glue. Composing these to achieve significant business value can be done with relatively little glue code as AWS services are very well integrated together.</p>
<p>New classes of applications are emerging that try to better adapt to this landscape. One example is what AWS labeled as serverless. Provisioning these types of apps using Terraform or Cloud Formation can lead to a lot of friction. In such a tightly integrated model, your infrastructure will evolve with your application, so this probably needs to be one of the most …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://cosminilie.ro/posts/evolution-of-configuration-languages/">https://cosminilie.ro/posts/evolution-of-configuration-languages/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://cosminilie.ro/posts/evolution-of-configuration-languages/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25160461</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 13:57:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Use Anki to Improve Your Memory]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 189 | Comments 138 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25160204">thread link</a>) | @simbyotic
<br/>
November 20, 2020 | https://superpoweredself.com/gentle-introduction-how-to-use-anki-to-improve-your-memory | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://superpoweredself.com/gentle-introduction-how-to-use-anki-to-improve-your-memory">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main">

<!-- One -->
<section id="one">
	<div>
		<header>
			
		</header>
		<p><span><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/9a2914d055172609fa55702afb9713d9268ba00f/762c9/assets/images/agentleintroductiontoanki/cover.jpg" alt=""></span></p><p><span>Where would you be in life if you did not forget?</span></p>

<p>You would have done better in school, for starters. Instead of turning in your bed unable to sleep terrified of the exam coming the next day, you would soundly sleep with the knowledge that you know everything you need to know to ace the exam. And ace it you would indeed.</p>

<p>You would have spent fewer hours studying. How many times have you opened the textbook only to find that you’ve forgotten all that you’d studied the day before? If you did not forget things then those hours you spent studying would always amount to something, instead of leaving you feeling like you’re swimming against the current. School might even have been fun if you did not forget.&nbsp;</p>

<p>What would your career look like if you did not forget?</p>

<p>Forgetfulness affects us all. There is no one that has not grappled with this problem before. Our lives would be better if we did not forget.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Unfortunately, <span>forgetting is inescapable.</span> There is no such thing as a perfect memory. I am not here to sell you on a magic pill that will turn you into Bradley Cooper in the movie Limitless.</p>

<p>However, that doesn’t mean there aren’t things you can do to massively reduce the speed at which you forget things, because there are.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Science has known about what it takes to get memories to stick around in your memory for a long time. It has known about it for a while now, in fact. It’s just that it has done a terrible job so far at making sure that you know about it, you whose life would massively benefit from that knowledge.</p>

<p>My intent for writing this is to correct these wrongs and introduce you to spaced repetition, the more than established method that will put you in control of your memory once and for all, and Anki, the software that will help you do so.&nbsp;</p>

<p>So, let’s start at the beginning: <span> What is spaced repetition?</span></p>

<h2 id="the-centuries-old-science-they-dont-tell-you-about">The Centuries Old Science They Don’t Tell You About</h2>

<p>More than a hundred years ago, the German psychologist Hermann Ebbinghaus not only started the scientific study of memory, but he also made its most impactful discovery.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After all, what discovery could be more impactful than what makes memories stick?</p>

<p>Ebbinghaus created various lists of nonsense syllables that he had to memorize, and once he was able to mouth off the entire list without making a single mistake he would mark on his calendar the day where he had to memorize that list once more.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He would have to memorize some lists the day after, others a week and some a whole month after he had first memorized them. Doesn’t sound much fun, does it? This is especially true when you take into account each list must have taken him quite a long time to memorize since by design each of the three-letter syllables he had to study had been chosen so that they weren’t easily remembered. For example, the syllable BOL was out of the question as Ebbinghaus could instead use BALL to recall it.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After the requisite time had passed, to measure the extent to which he had forgotten the list he’d spent so much time memorizing, he memorized the same list once more. Not only did he have to sit still in his office for a long time trying to memorize a bunch of nonsense words once, he had to do it twice! Throughout his second attempt he did have some help since it would take him less time to memorize the list the second time around if he remembered it from his first foray cramming it into his memory.&nbsp;</p>

<p>If by that point he’d already forgotten it, then it would take him at least as much time to memorize the list the second time as it had the first. However, if some memory of it still lingered in the confines of his mind, he would be able to go through the list faster than before. By varying the amount of time between each attempt, and seeing how that influenced how long it took him then to memorize the list the second time, <span>Ebbinghaus was able to measure the effect time had on his memory.</span></p>

<p>And what an effect it had.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The first thing he noticed was that memories are at their most fragile when they are still young. From the data he’d collected, he could see that the bulk of forgetting happens in the few moments after the memory is created. Rather than forgetting happening at a linear pace over time, each day that passes nicking a constant amount of the vitality of a memory until it is completely forgotten, Ebbinghaus discovered <span>forgetting happens rather rapidly at first but slows down afterward.&nbsp;</span></p>

<p>In the first few hours of its life, it’s as if your newly created memory has jumped out of a flying airplane and is now free-falling through the sky, the wind buffeting its face violently as it quickly loses altitude. As the ground becomes uncomfortably close, our memory activates its parachute and begins to glide, still falling, of course, but much slower than it was when it first jumped out of the plane.&nbsp;
&nbsp;
Now, to be sure, <span>the forgetting curve,</span> as this discovery came to be called, is an important landmark in the scientific study of memory, but it’s not a particularly useful one. We forget things over time; what a discovery! You don’t need to be a top-level scientist to come to that conclusion. It’s why we’re here in the first place!</p>

<p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/b79bb8c6906d331e07905d708043194c5288a3bd/e385a/assets/images/agentleintroductiontoanki/forgettingcurve_alternative.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p> Behold, my superlative drawing skills!</p>
<p>But Ebbinghaus didn’t stop there.
&nbsp;
When he first started learning his lists of nonsense syllables, Ebbinghaus, like many a student, crammed all his studying in a single furious session. But then, possibly because he was fed up with all the cramming, he hit upon the idea of spreading his learning over time. Instead of spending the majority of a day learning one of his lists, he spaced out his learning over a few days. <span>What he found when he did so is the most important discovery about memory that no one ever told you about.</span></p>

<p>You would think not much would change if instead of studying a bunch of material in one day you did so over three or more days. But what Ebbinghaus found was that not only did his memory get stronger, but it also took him less time to memorize his lists. This meant that <span>simply by changing when he studied, Ebbinghaus could have the best of both worlds: a better memory with less time spent studying.&nbsp;</span></p>

<p>It need not be pointed out how important a discovery this is. If someone came up to you and told you about a revolutionary studying method that would not only cut the time you spent studying but also get you to retain the things you learn for longer, you would think you were being sold on some sort of scam.</p>

<p>Yet <span>the spacing effect,</span> as Ebbinghaus’ discovery is called, is far from being a scam. It is <span>one of the most scientifically supported discoveries in the entire field of psychology.</span></p>

<p>The gist of the spacing effect is rather simple. Given the choice between massing all your studying or spacing it out over a period of time, you are better served by spacing it out. <span>There is no catch. It really is that simple.&nbsp;</span></p>

<p>This means if you are a student and you have an exam coming up a month from now, you should start studying now rather than waiting until a single week is left. If, for example, you’re going to spend 50 hours studying, then spreading those hours over the whole month, ensuring that you get re-exposed to the material in sufficiently spaced intervals, would get you much better results than you would if you crammed those 50 hours in a single stress-filled and coffee-fueled week.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Of course, that’s easier said than done.&nbsp;</p>

<p><span>The spacing effect is one of the most important weapons a learner can have on his arsenal</span> but knowing about its amazing effects does not mean that we will necessarily apply it. After all, we all know not to eat too many processed foods do we not? Yet, that doesn’t seem to stop many of us.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Pulling an all-nighter to cram for an exam is like binging on a sugar-filled pastry when one is trying to lose weight, yet the fact it continues to be a staple learning strategy of many a student is a testament to how difficult it can be to embrace the lessons of the spacing effect.&nbsp;</p>

<p>If only there were an app for that…</p>

<h2 id="this-app-will-turn-your-memory-into-a-superpower">This App Will Turn Your Memory Into A Superpower</h2>

<p>One hundred years ago Ebbinghaus didn’t have a computer, let alone a smartphone. If he’d had them they would have taken care of the task of spacing what he had to learn for him. Instead, he had to do all of that himself, though if we consider that he was the kind of guy that did not balk at the idea of spending hundreds of hours learning endless lists of nonsense, perhaps he wasn’t that fazed by it.</p>

<p>Thankfully, today we have tools that manage all of that for us.</p>

<p><span> And it all starts with a simple flashcard.&nbsp;</span></p>

<p>Everyone knows how a flashcard is supposed to work. You write something on the front, then something on the back, and then you’re supposed to recall what it was that you wrote on the back after reading what’s on the front.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Suppose that in the process of studying for a coming exam, you wrote many of these flashcards. You have a big pile of them sitting on your desk and within them are all the things you have to know if you want to ace that exam.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Because you know about the spacing effect, you know that cramming those flashcards is a bad strategy, but then how are you supposed to space them out? There are so many cards to keep track of…</p>

<p><span>What    if those flashcards existed on your computer instead?&nbsp;</span></p>

<p>If that were possible, then the computer could take care of the task of keeping track when you’re supposed to review your flashcards and you could focus solely on the things that matter, which, in this case, is answering your flashcards correctly and acing that exam.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Which is why spaced repetition software was invented: to take care of all the grunt work so you can easily add spaced repetition into your life.</p>

<p>At its core, all spaced repetition software does is keep track of when to present you with the material that you put in it. It’s called spaced repetition software because they use special algorithms to calculate the optimal interval between when you last reviewed the material and …</p></div></section></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://superpoweredself.com/gentle-introduction-how-to-use-anki-to-improve-your-memory">https://superpoweredself.com/gentle-introduction-how-to-use-anki-to-improve-your-memory</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://superpoweredself.com/gentle-introduction-how-to-use-anki-to-improve-your-memory</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25160204</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 13:25:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I read 100 books in the last 2 years – here are 10 thoughts on reading]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 37 | Comments 17 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25159796">thread link</a>) | @durmonski
<br/>
November 20, 2020 | https://durmonski.com/private/reading-100-books/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://durmonski.com/private/reading-100-books/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																					<div>
																										
<p><em>I was a naive kid. When I was younger, whenever I came across books like <a href="https://durmonski.com/book-summaries/rich-dad-poor-dad/" target="_blank" aria-label="Rich Dad Poor Dad (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener">Rich Dad Poor Dad</a>, I thought that by just reading what’s written inside I will magically become a millionaire. Or, by studying the lessons presented in <a href="https://durmonski.com/book-summaries/the-7-habits-of-highly-effective-people/" target="_blank" aria-label="The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener">The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People</a>, I will transform into a successful business owner who is not holding any sabotaging habits. After all, these books always came with a step-by-step framework that I diligently followed. And while didn’t come close to becoming an ultra-rich entrepreneur, like these titles promised, how my life turned out eventually, which is not bad at all, is thanks to my reading habit.</em></p>



<p>I actually used to despise reading. My parents were constantly shoving books in my face and forcing me to read literature that didn’t even interest me closely. </p>



<p>The books I had to read according to my folks during my teenage years were either part of my school curriculum or titles that were famous years ago. Of course, like every self-respecting teenager trying to look cool, I rebelled against these rules and did the only thing I could – I stopped reading altogether.</p>



<p>Somewhere deep down though, I knew that reading was good, but spending my time studying historical novels related to my country, or fact-heavy encyclopedia-like hardcovers didn’t seem practical to me.</p>



<p>Probably it’s because I grew up playing video games, or because my brother and I collected choose-your-own-adventure type of books when we were younger. But I always assumed that I should get some sort of outcome when I was reading a book. A book should help me learn a skill, conquer a territory, slave a dragon, and in way level up.</p>



<p>Sadly, this wasn’t the case with the novels that the school system imposed on me. These books were only throwing isolated facts that were not related to my existence here and now. That’s why I was careless about literature when I was a teenager.</p>



<p>Fortunately, later in my life, I re-evaluate my relationship with the libraries.</p>



<p>Things changed when I found out about the existence of the applied psychology category. At least that’s how the libraries of my country label the self-help genre. I was thrilled. Books that can help you master a skill? It sounded magical. </p>



<p>That’s when I found titles like <a href="https://durmonski.com/book-summaries/think-and-grow-rich/" target="_blank" aria-label="Think and Grow Rich (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener">Think and Grow Rich</a>, <a href="https://durmonski.com/book-summaries/influence/" target="_blank" aria-label="Influence (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener">Influence</a>, <a href="https://durmonski.com/book-summaries/outwitting-the-devil/" target="_blank" aria-label="Outwitting the Devil (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener">Outwitting the Devil</a>, and similar mind-transforming hardcovers. To me, these books looked like volumes full of spells – filled with practical advice that can change your life when you apply them.</p>



<p>That’s when my reading journey began. </p>



<p>To this date, I’ve probably read more than 150 books. 100 of these titles are carefully categorized and summarized <a href="https://durmonski.com/category/book-summaries/" target="_blank" aria-label="here (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a> on my site.</p>



<p>I learned a lot from these books in terms of skills and know-how. But I also learned something that I believe is more valuable – how to approach reading. </p>



<p>When I first started reading, I picked the books that were in front of me – sort to speak. I always grabbed the most talked-about books, thinking, that they hold all the answers in the world.</p>



<p>Now, I know that the best-sellers section doesn’t include the finest titles. Also, I know that reading alone, or reading piles of books, is only half of the battle. I spend a lot of time before I decide what I should read. My approach to books and what titles I should read is completely transformed. But most importantly, I do my best to implement what’s mentioned in the titles I read.</p>



<p>In this article, I’ll share with you 10 thoughts after reading 100 books. The goal is not only to help you become a better reader and better book-picker, but also to share with you some insights about how books can change you for the better.</p>



<p>So, here are 10 things I learned from reading and later <a aria-label="summarizing (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://durmonski.com/private/summarizing-books/" target="_blank">summarizing</a> 100 books.</p>







<h2 id="0-10-thoughts-from-reading-100-books-">10 Thoughts from Reading 100 Books </h2>





<h3 id="1-1-best-selling-books-are-usually-crap">1. Best-Selling Books are Usually Crap</h3>



<p>This is not entirely true of course.</p>



<p>There are a lot of exceptions. For example, books like <a href="https://durmonski.com/book-summaries/atomic-habits/" target="_blank" aria-label="Atomic Habits (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener">Atomic Habits</a> or <a href="https://durmonski.com/book-summaries/the-laws-of-human-nature/" target="_blank" aria-label="The Laws of Human Nature (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Laws of Human Nature</a> are nice examples of how good work pays off and how word-of-mouth has the power to bring good literature into the hands of millions of people.</p>



<p>But in general, best-selling books are created with the wrong initiatives.</p>



<p>As strange as it might sound, the usefulness of the content for the authors of best-sellers is not the most important thing in a book – it’s the desire to make money. What I found out is that they usually grab a bunch of blog posts from their site, put them in one place, and call it a book. This means that the content is absent from real meaningful research. You’re basically paying (not always, but a lot of times) for content that’s already free but this time it’s on paper.</p>



<p>Most best-selling self-help books are full of vague conclusions, offer no value whatsoever, and can be summarized in the following sentence: “You can do it!”</p>



<p>Why they are successful then?</p>



<p>If you trace back the wide success of these popular books, you’ll spot that the author is someone who has a large online audience. And when you have a network of people who are following you online, the success of your book is guaranteed.</p>



<p>Also, if the above is true, the publisher will invest a lot of funds to market the book. This basically means that the success of the book relies on the large email list and social media following of the author – the distribution channels – not on the actual content.</p>



<p>Therefore, such books, best-selling books, should be approached with caution.</p>







<h3 id="2-2-read-foundational-books-often-mentioned-in-the-bibliography-section">2. Read Foundational Books – Often Mentioned in The Bibliography Section</h3>



<p>I used to skip the bibliography section of the books I read. You know, the part in the back of the book where the author lists the titles he used in the creation of his work or such that somehow influenced his project.</p>



<p>Now, I can’t wait to check this section so I can add new additions to my to-read list.</p>



<p>Once you spend enough time investigating in this rarely explored section of the back of the books, you spot patterns. You see how the same titles are cited again and again.</p>



<p>And once you read some of these books, you get to see why they are so frequently mentioned in the corner of the most successful books that are full of vague action tips – because these rarely-mentioned by big sites books are the real deal. They are full of insights and valuable thinking patterns that can change the way you approach life.</p>



<p>For example, if you want to increase your productivity, you will surely find a lot of self-help books that promise to boost your overall performance. But if you want to <em>get</em> why you procrastinate, really understand why your body is now one with the couch, you should read <a href="https://durmonski.com/book-summaries/flow/" target="_blank" aria-label="Flow (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener">Flow</a> by Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi.</p>



<p>If you want to find meaning in our crazy world and escape the modern dogma of consumerism, you’ll surely stumble on less than favorable titles like The Monk Who Sold His Ferrari, or Girl, Wash Your Face. But if you really want to understand how meaning is formed and what does it take to find your course in life, you should read <a href="https://durmonski.com/book-summaries/the-evolving-self/" target="_blank" aria-label="The Evolving Self (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Evolving Self</a> by Robert Kegan and/or <a href="https://durmonski.com/book-summaries/to-have-or-to-be/" target="_blank" aria-label="To Have or to Be? (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener">To Have or to Be?</a> by Erich Fromm.</p>



<p>Sadly, people don’t want to read these books.</p>



<p>They don’t have enough “social status” and sharing them with others won’t inspire a lot of interest from your peers towards you.</p>



<p>It’s kind of like in the tech industry. You know that a regular phone, a device that costs around 500 bucks will do the job perfectly. But no, you want the latest iPhone because this is what people really value and expect to see.</p>



<p>That’s why we spend our time digesting famous books. We are more interested in impressing others when they check our reading list, not so much ourselves.</p>







<h3 id="3-3-good-books-are-usually-hard-to-get">3. Good Books are Usually Hard to Get</h3>



<p>Hard to read, full of words you don’t really understand, these are usually the best books – especially in the field of <a href="https://durmonski.com/category/book-summaries/philosophy/" target="_blank" aria-label="philosophy (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener">philosophy</a> and <a href="https://durmonski.com/category/book-summaries/psychology-books/" target="_blank" aria-label="psychology (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener">psychology</a>.</p>



<p>At first, if you decide to explore such titles, you’ll blame the author for not using simpler words and for not expressing himself better. And if there are long-winded sections where you don’t get what the premise of the idea is, you’ll most probably ditch the book and find something else to read instead.</p>



<p>But these elaborate creations full of complicated phrases are what you need to level up your thinking.</p>



<p>Surely reading a novel where you can predict what will happen next feels good. But real learning comes from books that flex your mind and prompt you to think about the argument the author is making.</p>



<p>This is something I only recently realized. Before, I was cynical about hard to get books. That’s why I rated one of the most cited books poorly – <a href="https://durmonski.com/book-summaries/thinking-fast-and-slow/" target="_blank" aria-label="Thinking, Fast and Slow (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener">Thinking, Fast and Slow</a>.</p>



<p>When I read it 2 years ago, I considered it unrelentingly tedious and pretentious. But the book wasn’t the problem, I was.</p>



<p>My assumption was that books have to be easy to get. Now, after reading more than 100 books and summarizing most of them, I know that’s not the case.</p>



<p>A good book doesn’t have to be easy to understand. A good book should make you stop and think about what is said inside. To confuse you and make you re-read the same passage again and again. If the pages inside don’t prompt you to think and even make you feel lost at times, then you’re not reading the proper title.</p>







<h3 id="4-4-figure-out-what-you-want-to-learn-first-then-search-for-a-book">4. Figure Out What You Want to Learn First, Then Search For a Book</h3>



<p>Most people approach reading the wrong way. They don’t think about what they want to learn and master, they simply read books that are in front of them. Best-selling books, or books recommended by their peers.</p>



<p>This approach is fine if you simply want to relax and unwind from your busy day. But if you want to improve in a specific area, you shouldn’t pick the title that’s sitting on the most popular reading list. You should, first, figure out what you want to learn and then go to the library with a clear goal.</p>



<p>That’s usually how we approach pretty much everything in life. We don’t hop online with clear goals in …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://durmonski.com/private/reading-100-books/">https://durmonski.com/private/reading-100-books/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://durmonski.com/private/reading-100-books/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25159796</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 12:29:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Retargetable Forward and Inverse Renderer (Differentiable Renderer)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 94 | Comments 18 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25159154">thread link</a>) | @harperlee
<br/>
November 20, 2020 | http://rgl.epfl.ch/publications/NimierDavidVicini2019Mitsuba2 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://rgl.epfl.ch/publications/NimierDavidVicini2019Mitsuba2">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">
            

<div>
 <!-- header -->

 <!-- attachments -->


<h3>Abstract</h3>
<div>
<p>Mod­ern ren­der­ing sys­tems are con­fron­ted with a daunt­ingly large and grow­ing set of re­quire­ments: in their pur­suit of real­ism, phys­ic­ally based tech­niques must in­creas­ingly ac­count for in­tric­ate prop­er­ties of light, such as its spec­tral com­pos­i­tion or po­lar­iz­a­tion. To re­duce pro­hib­it­ive ren­der­ing times, vec­tor­ized ren­der­ers ex­ploit co­her­ence via in­struc­tion-level par­al­lel­ism on CPUs and GPUs. Dif­fer­en­ti­able ren­der­ing al­gorithms propag­ate de­riv­at­ives through a sim­u­la­tion to op­tim­ize an ob­ject­ive func­tion, e.g., to re­con­struct a scene from ref­er­ence im­ages. Ca­ter­ing to such di­verse use cases is chal­len­ging and has led to nu­mer­ous pur­pose-built sys­tems—partly, be­cause ret­ro­fit­ting fea­tures of this com­plex­ity onto an ex­ist­ing ren­der­er in­volves an er­ror-prone and in­feas­ibly in­trus­ive trans­form­a­tion of ele­ment­ary data struc­tures, in­ter­faces between com­pon­ents, and their im­ple­ment­a­tions (in oth­er words,&nbsp;everything).</p>
<p>We pro­pose Mit­suba 2, a ver­sat­ile ren­der­er that is in­trins­ic­ally re­tar­get­able to vari­ous ap­plic­a­tions in­clud­ing the ones lis­ted above. Mit­suba 2 is im­ple­men­ted in mod­ern C++ and lever­ages tem­plate meta­pro­gram­ming to re­place types and in­stru­ment the con­trol flow of com­pon­ents such as BSD­Fs, volumes, emit­ters, and ren­der­ing al­gorithms. At com­pile time, it auto­mat­ic­ally trans­forms arith­met­ic, data struc­tures, and func­tion dis­patch, turn­ing gen­er­ic al­gorithms in­to a vari­ety of ef­fi­cient im­ple­ment­a­tions without the te­di­um of manu­al re­design. Pos­sible trans­form­a­tions in­clude chan­ging the rep­res­ent­a­tion of col­or, gen­er­at­ing a “wide” ren­der­er that op­er­ates on bundles of light paths, just-in-time com­pil­a­tion to cre­ate com­pu­ta­tion­al ker­nels that run on the <span>GPU</span>, and for­ward/re­verse-mode auto­mat­ic dif­fer­en­ti­ation. Trans­form­a­tions can be chained, which fur­ther en­riches the space of al­gorithms de­rived from a single gen­er­ic&nbsp;im­ple­ment­a­tion.</p>
<p>We demon­strate the ef­fect­ive­ness and sim­pli­city of our ap­proach on sev­er­al ap­plic­a­tions that would be very chal­len­ging to cre­ate without as­sist­ance: a ren­der­ing al­gorithm based on co­her­ent <span>MCMC</span> ex­plor­a­tion, a caustic design meth­od for gradi­ent-in­dex op­tics, and a tech­nique for re­con­struct­ing het­ero­gen­eous me­dia in the pres­ence of mul­tiple&nbsp;scat­ter­ing.</p>
</div>


    
    

    
    

    
    

    
    
        <h3>Video</h3>
        
            
                <video preload="none" controls="controls" poster="http://rgl.s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/media/images/papers/NimierDavidVicini2019Mitsuba2_attachment_thumb_1.jpg">
                    <source src="http://rgl.s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/media/papers/NimierDavidVicini2019Mitsuba2.mp4" type="video/mp4">
                    <p>Your browser does not support playing this video. Please download the video below.</p>
                </video>
            
        
            
                <video preload="none" controls="controls" poster="http://rgl.s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/media/images/papers/NimierDavidVicini2019Mitsuba2_attachment_thumb_2.jpg">
                    <source src="http://rgl.s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/media/papers/NimierDavidVicini2019Mitsuba2_1.mp4" type="video/mp4">
                    <p>Your browser does not support playing this video. Please download the video below.</p>
                </video>
            
        
    

    
    



    

    

    

    

    



<div>
    
    <h6>Text citation</h6>
    <p>Merlin Nimier-David, Delio Vicini, Tizian Zeltner, and Wenzel Jakob. 2019. Mitsuba 2: A Retargetable Forward and Inverse Renderer. In <em>Transactions on Graphics (Proceedings of SIGGRAPH Asia)</em> 38(6).</p>
    

    
    <h6>BibTeX</h6>
    <pre>@article{NimierDavidVicini2019Mitsuba2,
    author = {Merlin Nimier-David and Delio Vicini and Tizian Zeltner and Wenzel Jakob},
    title = {Mitsuba 2: A Retargetable Forward and Inverse Renderer},
    journal = {Transactions on Graphics (Proceedings of SIGGRAPH Asia)},
    volume = {38},
    number = {6},
    year = {2019},
    month = dec,
    doi = {10.1145/3355089.3356498}
}</pre>
    
</div> <!-- citation -->





</div> <!-- publication -->

        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://rgl.epfl.ch/publications/NimierDavidVicini2019Mitsuba2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25159154</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 10:40:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Eight Years at Roblox]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 278 | Comments 99 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25158904">thread link</a>) | @modeless
<br/>
November 20, 2020 | https://zeux.io/2020/08/02/eight-years-at-roblox/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://zeux.io/2020/08/02/eight-years-at-roblox/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

<p><span>

02 Aug 2020

</span></p><p>I joined Roblox at the end of 2012 as a rendering engineer; I had just spent more than a year working on various titles from FIFA franchise after years of console game development and was becoming a bit tired of the “big game development”. My work on FIFA was as a contractor and I got an offer for a full-time position, but I also had a friend who worked at Roblox reach out and offer me to move to California and work on Roblox. I knew absolutely nothing about Roblox, but California was nice and my friend told me it would be awesome. The platform was so different (and so strange!) that I decided to take a chance - here I am, 8 years later, still working at Roblox and enjoying it. I started on my first full time job in April 2007 so at this point I’ve worked for 13 years in game development and 8 of them were at Roblox.</p>

<!--more-->

<p>My memory works in interesting ways. I remember my interview pretty well, I remember having lunch at some place in San Mateo downtown near the Roblox HQ - a few people were at lunch including Roblox CEO David Baszucki and I remember him asking many questions about my thoughts about the engines and rendering, and distinctly remember not finishing most of my lunch because I talked most of the time. However I don’t really remember what was going through my head in regards to my perception of Roblox - why did I join besides just thinking I want to do something else for a change? Who knows, but I am glad I did.</p>

<p>I don’t really understand why Roblox is so successful - you can invent all sorts of reasons in retrospect but it’s hard to validate them, and if you came to anybody back in 2012 and asked for an investment to build a platform where all games are user generated and run on a custom engine with a custom toolset and all users participate in a giant virtual economy and …, I think you’d have gotten a blank stare.</p>

<p>But I do understand that I found the perfect place for me, especially at that point in my career - I enjoy working on game technology but I never liked working on actual games, and Roblox maximizes the number of developers who can use the technology you work on while maintaining a good autonomy and a very wide range of problems you’d need to solve. It’s very hard to get bored here.</p>

<p>I think I could talk for hours about Roblox - it somehow became a huge part of my life. I was very fortunate to join at the time when I did and witness the growth of our technology and business. I am really unsure of what the future holds but it’s hard to imagine what, if anything, comes after Roblox - I certainly don’t intend to leave any time soon…</p>

<p>So I thought it might be fun to do what I’ve planned to do for a year or more now, and to go over all decently sized projects I’ve ever worked on at Roblox. This is based on resummarizing and reliving the source control history, which tells me I’ve had 2752 changes that made it to our main branch, with merge commits counting as one, so, uh, this blog might be on a larger side. Hopefully this will be fun!</p>

<p>Before we begin, I just want to conclude this by saying that I’m very grateful to the Roblox leadership for treating me well, for all the friends and colleagues I made along the way, and for the wonderful Roblox community. The reason why I still enjoy what I do is because whenever I write about a new big thing I’m working on or a small feature or even a bug fix, it’s usually met with excitement which keeps me going. Thank you all from the bottom of my heart. I don’t think I could have done it without you and I hope this continues for as long as possible despite the current trying and uncertain times.</p>



<p>Notably including half-pixel offset fixes for Direct3D9 which I guess is a rite of passage for rendering engineers. The rendering code back then was based on OGRE rendering engine, so I had to learn that, and this was also my first time using OpenGL professionally - prior to that I’ve used Direct3D 9 and proprietary console APIs, and Direct3D 10/11 as a hobby.</p>



<p>Initially added for “100 player” project, in October it evolved to render all parts and continued to be used as part renderer until the introduction of instancing in 2018. Otherwise known as “featherweight parts”. This was further optimized and deployed around November 2012. Most of this code survived to this day but evolved over time, and is still used when instancing doesn’t apply.</p>

<p>The core idea in this system was to dynamically batch meshes together, for characters this would be based on the character model hierarchy, and for everything else the grouping is spatial. This allowed us to reduce the number of draw calls, which was a big concern due to both driver overhead and inefficiencies in OGRE.</p>

<p>This would pave the way for what eventually turned out to be a complete, but gradual, rewrite of the rendering stack. The main motivation for this was always performance - what we ended up let us port to mobile (the old rendering code was nowhere near fast enough even for relatively simple scenes), and break new grounds on the number of objects we could render in a frame.</p>



<p>One of a few OGRE upgrades we’ve needed to do, this one was to get better GLES support. It was pretty painful to do those, just like any other big middleware update is. Read further to learn what happened to OGRE eventually…</p>

<p>One thing I remember from doing these is that documentation in source code makes the upgrade process that much more painful. I had scripts that changed the copyright years in headers back to whatever they were in our tree just to make merging less painful, but there was some OGRE upgrade where 70% of the changes were documentation, and this was very hard to get through.</p>

<p>The reason why these were challenging in general is that whenever we did an upgrade we had to a) merge our plentiful changes with the new code, b) gate dangerous parts of the upgrade with flags. We’ve used the same system of feature flags (we call them fast flags) since I joined Roblox which allows us to dynamically disable parts of the release based on metrics, but this requires actually isolating changes behind if statements selectively - which for OGRE was sometimes necessary as we didn’t know what the impact of some low level change in OpenGL code would be.</p>



<p>Before this we had hand-translated shaders, which started to be painful to maintain. The first version of the pipeline used hlsl2glsl and glsl-optimizer (same as Unity back in the day). We are using version 3 today, see below!</p>

<p>Since this was done at the point where we used OGRE, the compiler would take HLSL files, preprocess and translate them to optimized GLSL, and save the resulting GLSL back to disk - which would then be loaded by OGRE directly through the material definition file. Eventually we replaced this with a binary shader pack that could store GLSL code for OpenGL and shader bytecode for other APIs, but back then we shipped HLSL and GLSL source and compiled HLSL code on device!</p>



<p>Our equivalent of “Steam Hardware Survey” that went through SQL databases and coalesced various system information bits to help us understand the hardware at the time. This was during my era of obsession with F#, so it was written in F# instead of something like Python. We don’t use this anymore and don’t even have the SQL database in question!</p>

<p>We never published the resulting data, and I’m not sure how often we used it to make decisions, but it was fun to look at the number of graphics cards from various vendors or amount of RAM or resolution a typical Roblox user has.</p>



<p>Although I was hired as a rendering engineer, I had a lot of really deep low-level systems experience and as a consequence ended up engaging in both optimization work and security related work from the very beginning. I don’t do this anymore these days but I was often involved in the security work for the first 3 or 4 years. Now we fortunately have people who can do this full time and better than I could :)</p>



<p>A second part of “100 player project”, necessary to render every character in one draw call (these were really expensive for us back in the day!). A side effect included some resolution sacrifices on character items that shirt creators aren’t fond of. The new system managed the atlas texture memory, rebaking humanoids far away to smaller textures to conserve texture memory. The compositor survived with minor changes to this day, although we’re now working on a new one.</p>

<p>The compositor was built in a very configurable fashion, allowing the high level code to specify the layout to bake, and managing all the complex asynchronous processing and budgeting by itself. This allowed us to switch the composit layout completely years later for R15.</p>



<p>At the end of 2012 we were actively working on the mobile port. Since then we’ve had to do a lot of work in a lot of different parts of the engine to make data structures smaller and algorithms - faster. Of course you’re never done with optimizations so we do this to this day. Curiously, our minimum spec on iOS stayed the same since the initial launch in 2012!</p>

<p>A fun fact is that even though we started with iPad 2 as the min. spec we discussed adding support to iPad 1 after launch. At the time there were a lot of people who couldn’t play Roblox on iOS on older hardware. However the performance characteristics of those devices were just… not good enough. You could touch the screen with the finger and pan the camera, and during panning you lost 30% of a single available core to the OS processing the touch. We decided to not add support for this, and 8 years later it seems like a great decision for sure :D</p>



<p>It was very hard to use Xcode Instruments to profile frame spikes on an iPad; to try to figure out how to get our performance to a better place on mobile, I wrote some ad-hoc code to dump all internal log events to a binary stream, and a desktop UI tool in F# and WPF to visualize it. This included a Lua profiler as well that could display profiles of Lua code in a …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://zeux.io/2020/08/02/eight-years-at-roblox/">https://zeux.io/2020/08/02/eight-years-at-roblox/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://zeux.io/2020/08/02/eight-years-at-roblox/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25158904</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 09:47:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to force yourself to leave the computer using the leave command]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 76 | Comments 31 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25158739">thread link</a>) | @stefanjudis
<br/>
November 20, 2020 | https://www.stefanjudis.com/today-i-learned/how-to-force-yourself-to-leave-the-computer-using-the-leave-command/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.stefanjudis.com/today-i-learned/how-to-force-yourself-to-leave-the-computer-using-the-leave-command/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p> <span>This post is part of my <a href="https://www.stefanjudis.com/today-i-learned/">Today I learned</a> series in which I share all my learnings regarding web development.</span></p><div><p>While browsing <a href="https://www.stefanjudis.com/notes/1025-shell-command-one-liners-on-one-page/">a collection of shell one-liners</a>, I found out about a command that I haven't seen before: <code>leave</code>.</p><p>The command is straightforward. Run it and define an absolute or relative time, and your terminal will remind you to leave it alone and go at a certain time.</p><pre><code># set the alarm for 2:10pm
$ leave 1410
Alarm set for Fri Nov 20 14:10:00 CET 2020. (pid 3121)

# set the alarm in two minutes
$ leave +2

# set the alarm in two minutes interactively
$ leave
When do you have to leave? +2
Alarm set for Fri Nov 20 09:05:21 CET 2020. (pid 50717)
</code></pre><p>When the time arrives, the command running in the background sends shell notifications and prints new lines telling you to go. And let me tell you the best part: it doesn't do that once; it does that repeatedly every minute after the set alarm time. It will try hard to make you leave!</p><p><strong>You can only stop the running <code>leave</code> process from annoying you by logging out of your shell session (or manually stopping the process).</strong> 😆</p><p>I love that! Maybe I should define <code>leave 1900</code> in my <code>.zshrc</code> to force me to stop doing nerdy things late at night.</p><p><em>Edited:</em> For the adventurous folks – <a href="https://twitter.com/fhemberger/status/1329712452301451264">Frederic Hemberger pointed out</a> that you could also just shut down the system at a specific time using <code>sudo shutdown -h 12:00 "Feierabend!"</code>. But be careful with this command; it could lead to data loss. 😆</p><p>If you're interested in reading comments and alternatives to the <code>leave</code> command, <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25158739">this post was trending on Hacker News</a>.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.stefanjudis.com/today-i-learned/how-to-force-yourself-to-leave-the-computer-using-the-leave-command/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25158739</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 09:18:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: QuickPYTHON]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 173 | Comments 17 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25158588">thread link</a>) | @timothycrosley
<br/>
November 20, 2020 | https://timothycrosley.github.io/quickpython/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://timothycrosley.github.io/quickpython/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-md-component="container">
      
        
      
      
        
      
      <main data-md-component="main">
        <div>
          
            
              
            
            
              
            
          
          <div>
            <article>
              
                
                  <a href="https://github.com/timothycrosley/quickpython/edit/develop/README.md" title="Edit this page">
                    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M20.71 7.04c.39-.39.39-1.04 0-1.41l-2.34-2.34c-.37-.39-1.02-.39-1.41 0l-1.84 1.83 3.75 3.75M3 17.25V21h3.75L17.81 9.93l-3.75-3.75L3 17.25z"></path></svg>
                  </a>
                
                
                  
                
                
                  
                
                <p><a href="https://timothycrosley.github.io/quickpython/"><img alt="QuickPYTHON - Educational Interactive Coding Environment" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/timothycrosley/quickpython/master/art/logo_large.png"></a></p>
<hr>
<p><a href="http://badge.fury.io/py/quickpython"><img alt="PyPI version" src="https://badge.fury.io/py/quickpython.svg"></a>
<a href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi/quickpython/"><img alt="License" src="https://img.shields.io/github/license/mashape/apistatus.svg"></a>
<a href="https://pepy.tech/project/quickpython"><img alt="Downloads" src="https://pepy.tech/badge/quickpython"></a>
<a href="https://github.com/psf/black"><img alt="Code style: black" src="https://img.shields.io/badge/code%20style-black-000000.svg"></a>
<a href="https://timothycrosley.github.io/isort/"><img alt="Imports: isort" src="https://img.shields.io/badge/%20imports-isort-%231674b1?style=flat&amp;labelColor=ef8336"></a></p>
<hr>
<p><a href="https://timothycrosley.github.io/quickpython/">Read Latest Documentation</a> - <a href="https://github.com/timothycrosley/quickpython/">Browse GitHub Code Repository</a></p>
<hr>
<p><img alt="Example Usage" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/timothycrosley/quickpython/master/art/example.gif"></p>
<p><strong>QuickPYTHON</strong> A retro-futuristic educational interactive coding environment. Powered by Python and nostalgia.</p>
<p>Key features</p>
<ul>
<li>Mouse support</li>
<li>Futuristic blue color scheme</li>
<li>Auto-formatting</li>
<li>Integrated Debugging Support</li>
<li>Quick shortcuts for creating new dataclasses, static methods, etc</li>
<li>Built-in help</li>
<li>Games!</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="quick-start-instructions">Quick Start Instructions</h2>


<p>then start with</p>


<p>or</p>


<p><em>Disclaimer</em>: This project is provided as-is, for fun, with no guarantee of long-term support or maintenance.</p>
                
              
              
                


              
            </article>
          </div>
        </div>
      </main>
      
        

      
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://timothycrosley.github.io/quickpython/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25158588</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 08:53:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Go standard library benchmarks – Intel vs. M1]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 57 | Comments 33 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25158243">thread link</a>) | @jeremylevy
<br/>
November 19, 2020 | https://roland.zone/m1-go-benchmarks/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://roland.zone/m1-go-benchmarks/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<tr><th></th><th colspan="2">time/op</th><th>delta
</th></tr><tr><th colspan="4">pkg:archive/tar goos:darwin goarch:arm64</th></tr><tr><td>/Writer/USTAR</td><td>20.2Âµs Â±26%</td><td>2.4Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’87.95%</td><td>(p=0.016 n=5+4)
</td></tr><tr><td>/Writer/GNU</td><td>4.56Âµs Â± 2%</td><td>2.84Âµs Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’37.83%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>/Writer/PAX</td><td>7.95Âµs Â± 2%</td><td>4.96Âµs Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’37.59%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>/Reader/USTAR</td><td>3.60Âµs Â± 2%</td><td>2.20Âµs Â± 2%</td><td>âˆ’38.89%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>/Reader/GNU</td><td>2.29Âµs Â± 2%</td><td>1.40Âµs Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’38.74%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>/Reader/PAX</td><td>7.58Âµs Â± 3%</td><td>4.65Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’38.57%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><th colspan="4">pkg:archive/zip goos:darwin goarch:arm64</th></tr><tr><td>CompressedZipGarbage</td><td>4.84ms Â± 8%</td><td>1.57ms Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’67.51%</td><td>(p=0.016 n=5+4)
</td></tr><tr><td>Zip64Test</td><td>12.1ms Â± 3%</td><td>11.8ms Â± 1%</td><td>~</td><td>(p=0.095 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Zip64TestSizes/4096</td><td>7.44Âµs Â±12%</td><td>3.79Âµs Â± 3%</td><td>âˆ’49.01%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Zip64TestSizes/1048576</td><td>102Âµs Â± 5%</td><td>40Âµs Â± 2%</td><td>âˆ’60.29%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Zip64TestSizes/67108864</td><td>6.02ms Â± 3%</td><td>2.26ms Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’62.37%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><th colspan="4">pkg:bufio goos:darwin goarch:arm64</th></tr><tr><td>ReaderCopyOptimal</td><td>84.5ns Â± 4%</td><td>54.9ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’35.01%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ReaderCopyUnoptimal</td><td>140ns Â± 4%</td><td>91ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’34.72%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ReaderCopyNoWriteTo</td><td>3.98Âµs Â± 4%</td><td>1.55Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’60.98%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ReaderWriteToOptimal</td><td>313ns Â± 5%</td><td>321ns Â± 1%</td><td>~</td><td>(p=0.310 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ReaderReadString</td><td>107ns Â± 3%</td><td>74ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’30.38%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>WriterCopyOptimal</td><td>91.3ns Â± 2%</td><td>58.1ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’36.39%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>WriterCopyUnoptimal</td><td>116ns Â± 2%</td><td>70ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’39.42%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>WriterCopyNoReadFrom</td><td>3.85Âµs Â± 2%</td><td>1.53Âµs Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’60.21%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ReaderEmpty</td><td>792ns Â± 4%</td><td>354ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’55.27%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>WriterEmpty</td><td>694ns Â± 5%</td><td>342ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’50.76%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>WriterFlush</td><td>13.7ns Â± 2%</td><td>8.9ns Â± 4%</td><td>âˆ’34.87%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><th colspan="4">pkg:bytes goos:darwin goarch:arm64</th></tr><tr><td>ReadString</td><td>5.76Âµs Â± 5%</td><td>2.16Âµs Â± 2%</td><td>âˆ’62.56%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>WriteByte</td><td>13.2Âµs Â±12%</td><td>9.0Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’31.51%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>WriteRune</td><td>32.4Âµs Â± 2%</td><td>18.2Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’43.98%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>BufferNotEmptyWriteRead</td><td>222Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>184Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’17.11%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>BufferFullSmallReads</td><td>50.8Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>36.1Âµs Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’28.89%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexByte/10</td><td>5.17ns Â± 2%</td><td>4.16ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’19.48%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexByte/32</td><td>6.46ns Â± 2%</td><td>3.94ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’38.91%</td><td>(p=0.016 n=5+4)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexByte/4K</td><td>84.3ns Â± 2%</td><td>72.9ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’13.52%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexByte/4M</td><td>176Âµs Â±15%</td><td>64Âµs Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’63.48%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexByte/64M</td><td>4.42ms Â± 2%</td><td>1.08ms Â± 2%</td><td>âˆ’75.47%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexBytePortable/10</td><td>6.38ns Â± 1%</td><td>5.66ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’11.29%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexBytePortable/32</td><td>27.7ns Â± 1%</td><td>12.5ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’54.77%</td><td>(p=0.016 n=5+4)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexBytePortable/4K</td><td>1.55Âµs Â± 2%</td><td>1.29Âµs Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’16.30%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexBytePortable/4M</td><td>1.60ms Â± 1%</td><td>1.31ms Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’17.84%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexBytePortable/64M</td><td>26.3ms Â± 1%</td><td>21.1ms Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’19.79%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexRune/10</td><td>17.1ns Â± 2%</td><td>9.7ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’43.04%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexRune/32</td><td>17.2ns Â± 0%</td><td>13.6ns Â± 2%</td><td>âˆ’21.37%</td><td>(p=0.016 n=4+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexRune/4K</td><td>116ns Â± 2%</td><td>85ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’26.81%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexRune/4M</td><td>170Âµs Â± 3%</td><td>64Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’62.34%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexRune/64M</td><td>4.74ms Â± 2%</td><td>1.08ms Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’77.31%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexRuneASCII/10</td><td>5.39ns Â± 3%</td><td>4.05ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’24.86%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexRuneASCII/32</td><td>6.88ns Â± 2%</td><td>3.92ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’43.10%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexRuneASCII/4K</td><td>84.2ns Â± 2%</td><td>73.0ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’13.35%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexRuneASCII/4M</td><td>157Âµs Â± 4%</td><td>64Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’59.18%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexRuneASCII/64M</td><td>4.37ms Â± 1%</td><td>1.08ms Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’75.37%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Equal/0</td><td>3.01ns Â± 0%</td><td>2.05ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’32.05%</td><td>(p=0.016 n=4+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Equal/1</td><td>6.56ns Â± 0%</td><td>3.43ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’47.73%</td><td>(p=0.000 n=4+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Equal/6</td><td>6.57ns Â± 0%</td><td>3.81ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’42.01%</td><td>(p=0.000 n=4+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Equal/9</td><td>6.38ns Â± 1%</td><td>3.75ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’41.24%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Equal/15</td><td>6.36ns Â± 1%</td><td>3.73ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’41.38%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Equal/16</td><td>6.38ns Â± 2%</td><td>3.82ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’40.10%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Equal/20</td><td>7.38ns Â± 3%</td><td>4.28ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’42.02%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Equal/32</td><td>8.25ns Â± 4%</td><td>4.12ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’50.10%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Equal/4K</td><td>106ns Â± 1%</td><td>84ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’20.83%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Equal/4M</td><td>267Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>111Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’58.45%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Equal/64M</td><td>6.98ms Â± 2%</td><td>2.20ms Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’68.54%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Index/10</td><td>12.4ns Â± 2%</td><td>5.3ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’57.46%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Index/32</td><td>12.6ns Â± 2%</td><td>29.2ns Â± 1%</td><td>+131.13%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Index/4K</td><td>4.91Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>1.95Âµs Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’60.40%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Index/4M</td><td>5.04ms Â± 2%</td><td>1.99ms Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’60.58%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Index/64M</td><td>82.9ms Â± 6%</td><td>31.9ms Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’61.53%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexEasy/10</td><td>10.8ns Â± 4%</td><td>5.1ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’53.05%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexEasy/32</td><td>12.3ns Â± 7%</td><td>9.2ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’25.69%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexEasy/4K</td><td>107ns Â± 2%</td><td>77ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’27.90%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexEasy/4M</td><td>176Âµs Â± 5%</td><td>64Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’63.77%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexEasy/64M</td><td>4.62ms Â± 7%</td><td>1.07ms Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’76.76%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Count/10</td><td>18.4ns Â± 1%</td><td>9.9ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’45.98%</td><td>(p=0.016 n=5+4)
</td></tr><tr><td>Count/32</td><td>19.5ns Â± 2%</td><td>33.4ns Â± 0%</td><td>+71.29%</td><td>(p=0.016 n=5+4)
</td></tr><tr><td>Count/4K</td><td>4.92Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>1.96Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’60.24%</td><td>(p=0.016 n=4+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Count/4M</td><td>5.09ms Â± 5%</td><td>1.99ms Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’60.94%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Count/64M</td><td>81.5ms Â± 2%</td><td>31.9ms Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’60.89%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>CountEasy/10</td><td>17.0ns Â± 2%</td><td>9.5ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’43.98%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>CountEasy/32</td><td>19.1ns Â± 1%</td><td>15.2ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’20.43%</td><td>(p=0.016 n=5+4)
</td></tr><tr><td>CountEasy/4K</td><td>113ns Â± 2%</td><td>83ns Â± 2%</td><td>âˆ’26.89%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>CountEasy/4M</td><td>175Âµs Â± 4%</td><td>64Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’63.67%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>CountEasy/64M</td><td>4.72ms Â± 2%</td><td>1.07ms Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’77.23%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>CountSingle/10</td><td>6.67ns Â± 3%</td><td>6.96ns Â± 1%</td><td>+4.41%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>CountSingle/32</td><td>7.36ns Â± 1%</td><td>4.46ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’39.43%</td><td>(p=0.016 n=5+4)
</td></tr><tr><td>CountSingle/4K</td><td>100ns Â±15%</td><td>82ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’17.62%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>CountSingle/4M</td><td>171Âµs Â±21%</td><td>83Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’51.70%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>CountSingle/64M</td><td>4.50ms Â± 0%</td><td>1.38ms Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’69.26%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ToUpper/#00</td><td>8.87ns Â± 2%</td><td>4.66ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’47.40%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ToUpper/ONLYUPPER</td><td>43.7ns Â± 3%</td><td>30.4ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’30.55%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ToUpper/abc</td><td>25.9ns Â± 2%</td><td>16.6ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’36.19%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ToUpper/AbC123</td><td>32.1ns Â± 3%</td><td>19.9ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’38.10%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ToUpper/azAZ09_</td><td>31.8ns Â± 1%</td><td>18.6ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’41.54%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ToUpper/longStrinGwitHmixofsmaLLandcAps</td><td>72.5ns Â± 3%</td><td>45.7ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’36.96%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ToUpper/longÉ�stringÉ�withÉ�nonasciiâ±¯chars</td><td>425ns Â± 2%</td><td>249ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’41.31%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ToUpper/É�É�É�É�É�</td><td>229ns Â± 2%</td><td>158ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’31.24%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ToUpper/a\u0080\U0010ffff</td><td>108ns Â± 3%</td><td>73ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’32.04%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ToLower/#00</td><td>9.17ns Â± 1%</td><td>4.66ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’49.16%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ToLower/abc</td><td>34.3ns Â± 1%</td><td>20.4ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’40.56%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ToLower/AbC123</td><td>32.8ns Â± 2%</td><td>17.9ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’45.42%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ToLower/azAZ09_</td><td>35.7ns Â± 3%</td><td>20.5ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’42.66%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ToLower/longStrinGwitHmixofsmaLLandcAps</td><td>75.6ns Â± 1%</td><td>47.5ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’37.23%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ToLower/LONGâ±¯STRINGâ±¯WITHâ±¯NONASCIIâ±¯CHARS</td><td>356ns Â± 2%</td><td>220ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’38.08%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ToLower/â±­â±­â±­â±­â±­</td><td>191ns Â± 2%</td><td>134ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’29.76%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ToLower/A\u0080\U0010ffff</td><td>108ns Â± 2%</td><td>72ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’32.99%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Fields/ASCII/16</td><td>95.9ns Â± 3%</td><td>44.3ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’53.76%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Fields/ASCII/256</td><td>660ns Â± 3%</td><td>357ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’45.96%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Fields/ASCII/4096</td><td>9.66Âµs Â± 3%</td><td>4.94Âµs Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’48.82%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Fields/ASCII/65536</td><td>200Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>111Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’44.32%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Fields/ASCII/1048576</td><td>3.16ms Â± 1%</td><td>1.88ms Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’40.42%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Fields/Mixed/16</td><td>185ns Â± 3%</td><td>109ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’40.97%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Fields/Mixed/256</td><td>1.81Âµs Â± 2%</td><td>1.06Âµs Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’41.37%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Fields/Mixed/4096</td><td>33.6Âµs Â± 5%</td><td>19.3Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’42.50%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Fields/Mixed/65536</td><td>569Âµs Â± 2%</td><td>343Âµs Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’39.63%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Fields/Mixed/1048576</td><td>9.32ms Â± 5%</td><td>5.54ms Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’40.57%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>FieldsFunc/ASCII/16</td><td>154ns Â± 5%</td><td>87ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’43.61%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>FieldsFunc/ASCII/256</td><td>1.58Âµs Â± 9%</td><td>0.91Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’42.47%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>FieldsFunc/ASCII/4096</td><td>26.0Âµs Â± 2%</td><td>15.6Âµs Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’39.96%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>FieldsFunc/ASCII/65536</td><td>411Âµs Â± 0%</td><td>249Âµs Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’39.36%</td><td>(p=0.016 n=4+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>FieldsFunc/ASCII/1048576</td><td>6.64ms Â± 1%</td><td>4.00ms Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’39.73%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>FieldsFunc/Mixed/16</td><td>168ns Â± 0%</td><td>101ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’39.72%</td><td>(p=0.016 n=4+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>FieldsFunc/Mixed/256</td><td>1.59Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>0.93Âµs Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’41.16%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>FieldsFunc/Mixed/4096</td><td>29.9Âµs Â± 3%</td><td>17.5Âµs Â± 2%</td><td>âˆ’41.65%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>FieldsFunc/Mixed/65536</td><td>509Âµs Â± 2%</td><td>311Âµs Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’38.81%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>FieldsFunc/Mixed/1048576</td><td>8.22ms Â± 1%</td><td>5.05ms Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’38.53%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>TrimSpace/NoTrim</td><td>4.66ns Â± 1%</td><td>2.75ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’40.85%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>TrimSpace/ASCII</td><td>7.18ns Â± 1%</td><td>4.89ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’31.93%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>TrimSpace/SomeNonASCII</td><td>85.5ns Â± 2%</td><td>59.6ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’30.23%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>TrimSpace/JustNonASCII</td><td>158ns Â± 3%</td><td>107ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’32.38%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ToValidUTF8/Valid</td><td>29.9ns Â± 2%</td><td>18.0ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’39.99%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ToValidUTF8/InvalidASCII</td><td>36.3ns Â± 1%</td><td>24.5ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’32.62%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>ToValidUTF8/InvalidNonASCII</td><td>87.8ns Â± 2%</td><td>53.9ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’38.64%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexHard1</td><td>114Âµs Â± 2%</td><td>330Âµs Â± 0%</td><td>+190.43%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexHard2</td><td>159Âµs Â± 2%</td><td>330Âµs Â± 0%</td><td>+107.98%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexHard3</td><td>631Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>356Âµs Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’43.61%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>IndexHard4</td><td>633Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>1313Âµs Â± 0%</td><td>+107.26%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>LastIndexHard1</td><td>1.56ms Â± 1%</td><td>1.31ms Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’15.66%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>LastIndexHard2</td><td>1.57ms Â± 1%</td><td>1.31ms Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’16.03%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>LastIndexHard3</td><td>1.56ms Â± 1%</td><td>1.32ms Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’15.83%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>CountHard1</td><td>113Âµs Â± 2%</td><td>329Âµs Â± 0%</td><td>+192.21%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>CountHard2</td><td>161Âµs Â± 9%</td><td>330Âµs Â± 1%</td><td>+105.44%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>CountHard3</td><td>644Âµs Â± 8%</td><td>356Âµs Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’44.67%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>SplitEmptySeparator</td><td>12.2ms Â± 5%</td><td>4.9ms Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’59.71%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>SplitSingleByteSeparator</td><td>1.46ms Â± 3%</td><td>1.75ms Â± 0%</td><td>+19.63%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>SplitMultiByteSeparator</td><td>1.42ms Â± 1%</td><td>1.20ms Â± 2%</td><td>âˆ’15.75%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>SplitNSingleByteSeparator</td><td>207ns Â± 9%</td><td>173ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’16.49%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>SplitNMultiByteSeparator</td><td>276ns Â± 3%</td><td>212ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’23.22%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>Repeat</td><td>52.8ns Â± 3%</td><td>33.4ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’36.75%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>BytesCompare/1</td><td>4.78ns Â± 2%</td><td>2.55ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’46.67%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>BytesCompare/2</td><td>4.74ns Â± 2%</td><td>2.51ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’46.96%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>BytesCompare/4</td><td>4.80ns Â± 3%</td><td>2.20ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’54.08%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>BytesCompare/8</td><td>3.89ns Â± 2%</td><td>2.06ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’46.95%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>BytesCompare/16</td><td>3.86ns Â± 2%</td><td>2.08ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’46.21%</td><td>(p=0.016 n=5+4)
</td></tr><tr><td>BytesCompare/32</td><td>5.09ns Â± 6%</td><td>2.55ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’49.96%</td><td>(p=0.016 n=5+4)
</td></tr><tr><td>BytesCompare/64</td><td>5.99ns Â± 1%</td><td>3.45ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’42.43%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>BytesCompare/128</td><td>7.95ns Â± 3%</td><td>5.32ns Â± 0%</td><td>âˆ’33.06%</td><td>(p=0.016 n=5+4)
</td></tr><tr><td>BytesCompare/256</td><td>11.6ns Â± 9%</td><td>9.1ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’21.88%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>BytesCompare/512</td><td>18.9ns Â± 9%</td><td>16.7ns Â± 1%</td><td>âˆ’11.36%</td><td>(p=0.008 n=5+5)
</td></tr><tr><td>BytesCompare/1024</td><td>32.7ns Â± …</td></tr></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://roland.zone/m1-go-benchmarks/">https://roland.zone/m1-go-benchmarks/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://roland.zone/m1-go-benchmarks/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25158243</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 07:59:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Increase in Bitcoin Addresses as More People Join the BTC Price Surge]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 50 | Comments 139 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25157946">thread link</a>) | @coincolony
<br/>
November 19, 2020 | https://coincolony.net/increase-in-bitcoin-addresses-as-more-people-join-the-btc-price-surge/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://coincolony.net/increase-in-bitcoin-addresses-as-more-people-join-the-btc-price-surge/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>It’s been nearly three years since the Bitcoin price has reached a benchmark of over $15k and it doesn’t seem to be stopping. But, it’s not just the price of BTC that is overflowing. New Bitcoin addresses have also skyrocketed.<span>&nbsp;</span></p>
<p>On November, 18th, one week after Bitcoin broke its 15K boundary, <a href="https://twitter.com/glassnode/status/1329045245212971010?s=20">Glassnode</a>, a crypto-analysis company, tweeted an unusually high number of BTC accounts being created.<span>&nbsp;</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">In the past hour we observed the highest number of newly created addresses in the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Bitcoin?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Bitcoin</a> network since January 2018 📈</p>
<p>Chart: <a href="https://t.co/fTmoH5ezNw">https://t.co/fTmoH5ezNw</a> <a href="https://t.co/INq7sEEtoM">pic.twitter.com/INq7sEEtoM</a></p>
<p>— glassnode (@glassnode) <a href="https://twitter.com/glassnode/status/1329045245212971010?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 18, 2020</a></p></blockquote>

<p>According to Glassnode, the address per hour rate increased to almost 25,000, a rate not seen since January 2018 when BTC hit $20k.<span>&nbsp;</span></p>
<p>To put this number into perceptive, the most Bitcoin address ever created within a 24-hour period was on December 21, 2017 when nearly 600,000 popped up. Will we see this FOMO craze again if <a href="https://coincolony.net/bitcoin-technical-analysis-can-we-see-20k-again/">BTC hits $20k</a> by the end of the year?</p>
<p>We have seen a steady rise in public BTC implementation as well as business incorporation this year. This caused the price of BTC to go from $4k at the beginning of 2020 to $18k currently.<span>&nbsp;</span></p>
<p>However, universal usage is still minuscule with as much as <a href="https://www.jbs.cam.ac.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/2017-04-20-global-cryptocurrency-benchmarking-study.pdf">5.8 million cryptocurrency wallets</a> active in 2017. That equates to less than .1% of the global population own crypto.<span>&nbsp;</span></p>
<p>It will be interesting to see the adoption rates increase as the BTC price continues to rise and steady at a price that most people feel comfortable enough to buy, use, and save longterm.<span>&nbsp;</span></p>
<p>If you are just getting started with buying cryptocurrency then read our <a href="https://coincolony.net/8-ways-to-avoid-cryptocurrency-scams/">8 Ways to Avoid Cryptocurrency Scams</a>.</p>
<p><span>Advertisement </span><a href="https://coincolony.net/recommends/bybit/"><img width="728" height="90" alt="Bybit " src="https://files.coincolony.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/1.png"></a>
</p> </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://coincolony.net/increase-in-bitcoin-addresses-as-more-people-join-the-btc-price-surge/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25157946</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 07:01:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed: Valhalla and the Unfortunate Implications]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 343 | Comments 293 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25157722">thread link</a>) | @parsecs
<br/>
November 19, 2020 | https://acoup.blog/2020/11/20/miscellanea-my-thoughts-on-assassins-creed-valhalla/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://acoup.blog/2020/11/20/miscellanea-my-thoughts-on-assassins-creed-valhalla/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>We’re going to be a bit silly this week (in part because the ending of this compressed semester has left me with little time) and talk about the recently released historical action-RPG computer (and console) game, <em>Assassin’s Creed: Valhalla</em>, set in 9th century Norway and England.</p>



<p>And, as with the last time we did this, I should note that this isn’t a <em>game review</em>.  As a <strong>game</strong>, <em>AC: Valhalla</em> is perfectly serviceable and quite fun.  I don’t think it got the same amount of developer time as its predecessor, <em>Odyssey</em>, but it is also a more focused experience than <em>Odyssey</em> was, which runs to its benefit.  Everything here basically works and while I find some of the game design decisions puzzling (the largest being how long the game makes you wait <em>hours </em>before you have a full set of all three armor types and all weapon types, given that you may be getting bonuses to them in the skill tree many hours before you find <em>any at all</em>), <strong>it is overall fine.  It’s fun.</strong></p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="5179" data-permalink="https://acoup.blog/20201114012112/" data-orig-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201114012112.jpg" data-orig-size="1920,1080" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="20201114012112" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201114012112.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201114012112.jpg?w=1024" src="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201114012112.jpg?w=1024" alt="" srcset="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201114012112.jpg?w=1024 1024w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201114012112.jpg?w=150 150w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201114012112.jpg?w=300 300w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201114012112.jpg?w=768 768w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201114012112.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption>It also lets you snuggle the cats.  I am very big on this choice.</figcaption></figure>



<p>But you aren’t here for my game reviews. You are here for me to talk about the <em>history</em> behind the game.  And normally, I would leave a product like this alone (this is only thinly historical fiction, given the crazy background plot that ties the games together).  But each <em>Assassin’s Creed</em> game includes not just meticulous recreations of historical <em>places</em> (and to be clear, I mean the physical buildings and landscapes, not the cultures or politics, but also some form of this statement:</p>



<blockquote><p>Inspired by historical events and characters, this work of fiction was designed, developed, and produced by a multicultural team of various beliefs, sexual orientations and gender identities.</p></blockquote>



<p>(yes, the odd decision to use and then not use the Oxford comma is preserved from the original).  That is <em>Valhalla’s </em>version of the statement.  <strong>That statement is making a claim about the product that follows</strong>.  Some of those claims are explicit (this is based on real history at some level) and some are implicit (our diverse team means this game was produced in a careful, sensitive way).  <strong>And those claims deserve interrogation.</strong></p>



<p>As always, if you like what you are reading here, please share it; if you really like it, you can support me on <a href="https://www.patreon.com/user?u=20122096">Patreon</a>. And if you want updates whenever a new post appears, you can click below for email updates or follow me on twitter (@BretDevereaux) for updates as to new posts as well as my occasional ancient history, foreign policy or military history musings.</p>






<h2>The Nitpicks</h2>



<p>My thoughts on <em>Valhalla</em> fit into two main categories: complaints of historical accuracy that I think are largely unimportant, but fun to note, and<strong> complaints about tone and framing which I think <em>are</em> important and worth discussing</strong>.  <strong>We can start with the frivolous stuff</strong>.  If you want to skip to the meat of the analysis, you are welcome to jump right to the next section, but I know some folks like to know about this stuff, so here it is.</p>



<p><strong>First off, because it is a core area of my specialty: the weapons and armor.  </strong>The military equipment we see here is very hit-or-miss and<strong> there are honestly quite a lot of misses</strong>.  They at least have, for the most part, the relatively light design of battle axes correct, in both their two-handed and one-handed varieties.  And I can understand from a game design standpoint the decision to not give the player a one-handed sword and to instead fill that role with the more iconic one-handed axe; NPCs use one-handed swords, so it isn’t that they don’t exist, merely that our character doesn’t prefer them.  Technically, sword-and-shield and spear-and-shield are both possible, but only with a high level perk, which is pretty silly given that these were the most common non-elite fighting styles of the era by some distance.</p>



<p>But things go poorly from there.  There is a ‘flail’ type weapon, despite – <a href="https://acoup.blog/2019/06/07/collections-the-siege-of-gondor-part-v-just-flailing-about-flails/">as we’ve discussed</a>, actually – flail chain weapons being both not of this period, poorly attested in general and also not common in this part of the world in <em>any </em>period.  The large two-handed swords – the only kinds of swords the player can use – are around <em>three hundred</em> years too early and don’t really resemble their later variations either (they are much too thick and heavy, being mostly up-scaled period swords, which makes them look absurd).  And yes, there were two-handed swords in antiquity in Thrace and Illyria (the falx and rhomphaia) but this is both not that part of the world, not antiquity, and these are not those swords.  I am befuddled that, with two other two-handed weapons that fit the period (a thrusting spear and a two-handed axe) that they felt the need to include ‘greatswords.’  Also, they are carried by way of back-scabbards, which…sigh…no.</p>



<p><strong>The armor is generally a bigger ‘miss’ than the weapons.</strong>  There is a <em>lot</em> of soft ‘leather’ armor here of exactly the sort that was not used historically.  What is baffling uncommon is <em>mail</em> – especially among the Norse and Danes (there’s a bit more mail on the Saxons) –  which would have been, in this period, by far the most common metal body protection.  Pretty much all of Eivor’s warrior band ought to be wearing mail.  Instead, there is a lot of scale armor; scale was certainly used in this period in England, but it was a lot less common than mail (there are also things like brigandine armor roughly 400 years too early).  I have noticed a real trend of game developers using lots of scale armor when mail would be more correct; I wonder if it is easier for an art-team to produce the assets for it or if they think it looks cooler.  But in any event, audiences looking for a realistic sweep of ninth century equipment will not find it here.  I would say, for the more ‘exotic’ player armors, that I think the developers here missed a trick – the game sets up early that we have people from the Near East and even the Far East in the player’s clan.  I think that would set up an opportunity to have the honestly rather more varied and potentially visually interesting armors from the Near East – a lot more scale, but also Near Eastern lamellar or even Chinese-style lamellar coats.  Alas, no.</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="5171" data-permalink="https://acoup.blog/20201115222400/" data-orig-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201115222400.jpg" data-orig-size="1920,1080" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="20201115222400" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201115222400.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201115222400.jpg?w=1024" src="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201115222400.jpg?w=1024" alt="" srcset="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201115222400.jpg?w=1024 1024w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201115222400.jpg?w=150 150w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201115222400.jpg?w=300 300w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201115222400.jpg?w=768 768w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201115222400.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption>Barbarian-fashion, with nonsense biker-leather armor and lots of random, unkempt fur.  Even vikings <strong>cared</strong> about their appearances!</figcaption></figure>



<p>In terms of <em>clothing</em>, it is both hit and miss, but a bit more hit than miss compared to equipment.  Some of the Norse and Danish wear is ‘hollywood barbarian’ (lots of rough fur, inexplicably low-coverage clothing in freezing climates, lots of random leather) which remains truly frustrating.  But <em>most</em> of the clothing isn’t this way.  One odd area is color: <strong>medieval clothing, contrary to what you often see in films, was <em>colorful</em>, often with lots of bold primary colors</strong> (bright reds, yellows, greens, blues).  In <em>Valhalla</em>, the developers have opted to use clothing color to signify faction (friendly Danes wear green, the Norse blue, hostile Danes red, hostile Saxons yellow) and to keep non-combatants in drab colors.  I get the design reason (they want you to pay attention to enemies, not non-combatants) but it is frustrating, apart from the monks, that this makes so many of the townsfolk drab and dull.  <strong>Still, it was very nice to see Norse and Danes in bright primary colors, often with lovely border-stitching on their clothes and lots of clear care.</strong></p>



<p>In terms of architecture, I very much like that buildings in settlements, especially high status ones, are often well built, with lots of designs and carving work in the wood.  I am less thrilled with the way churches are done: typically in plain stone with plaster; some color is often added by lighting effects through stained glass.  But these are medieval Catholic churches, they should be brightly painted and colored in the interior and in most cases – <em>especially</em> in big towns and monasteries – very well kept up.  If you want to see this done better, <strong><em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance</em> is a deeply flawed game that nevertheless does medieval town architecture and clothing quite a lot better</strong> (but maybe watch a Let’s Play; while <em>KC:D </em>is fun once it gets properly going, it’s a case where I don’t think the juice is worth the squeeze; I invested the time to get properly into the game and I don’t think it was really worth it).</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="5170" data-permalink="https://acoup.blog/20201114231046/" data-orig-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201114231046.jpg" data-orig-size="1920,1080" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="20201114231046" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201114231046.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201114231046.jpg?w=1024" src="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201114231046.jpg?w=1024" alt="" srcset="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201114231046.jpg?w=1024 1024w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201114231046.jpg?w=150 150w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201114231046.jpg?w=300 300w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201114231046.jpg?w=768 768w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/20201114231046.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption>One of Valhalla’s inexplicably bland churches.  Also, why are the big banners so ragged and faded?  This is an active religious center!  It would be kept <strong>clean</strong> and <strong>well cared for</strong>!</figcaption></figure>



<h2>Diversity</h2>



<p>This isn’t really a nitpick or a substantive issue, so I am giving it its own section in between the two.  Let me be frank: <strong>I fully understand the desire of the developers to deviate from history on some of these points in order to make a more inclusive game</strong>.  These games do not market themselves as pure historical simulations, so this does not bother me; in fact I think it is broadly a positive thing that game studios are doing this (so long as they are <em>open</em> about fudging the history).  So if you were hoping for a lot of table-pounding here, you are bound to be disappointed.  Still, we’re assessing the game historically, so it seems worthwhile to point some of these things out.</p>



<p>First, on gender diversity, so far the game has built up a quiet contrast between the English, who are gender-stratified, and the Norse and Danes, who are much less so.  Saxon troopers are all male, but Danish and Norse NPCs include women.  All of the Saxon leaders I’ve met so far in the game are male, while one of the first jarls you meet in England is a woman ruling in her own name.  Saxon clothing is sharply gendered (men in pants, women in dresses), but Norse and Danish clothing generally isn’t (which is a clear design choice, since this is very much <em>not</em> true historically).  And, as with <em>AC: Odyssey</em>, if you play a female main character, absolutely no one seems to care or notice.</p>



<p>Now, on the one hand, there isn’t <em>nothing</em> to this characterization.  <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shield-maiden">‘Shield-maidens’</a> do show up in the …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/11/20/miscellanea-my-thoughts-on-assassins-creed-valhalla/">https://acoup.blog/2020/11/20/miscellanea-my-thoughts-on-assassins-creed-valhalla/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://acoup.blog/2020/11/20/miscellanea-my-thoughts-on-assassins-creed-valhalla/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25157722</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 06:04:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Plato at the Googleplex: Why Philosophy Won't Go Away]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 93 | Comments 142 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25157681">thread link</a>) | @unquote
<br/>
November 19, 2020 | https://www.3-16am.co.uk/articles/plato-g%C3%B6del-spinoza-ahab | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.3-16am.co.uk/articles/plato-g%C3%B6del-spinoza-ahab">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"> <div>  <nav id="mainNavMobile">    </nav>  <div id="s123PjaxMainContainer"> <div><section id="section-5c96048e70e5c">   <div> <div> <div> <div> <img src="https://static.s123-cdn.com/uploads/2029468/2000_5fb4f96199039.jpg"> </div> <div> <div><div><p>Interview by Richard Marshall</p><p><img src="https://static.s123-cdn.com/uploads/2029468/2000_5fb4f01c1c2a1.png"></p><p>'<em>Philosophical advances in epistemology and in ethics profoundly shape our points of view. We don’t see them precisely because we see with them. It’s like the fish who responds to the question “How’s the water today?” with “Water? What’s water?”'</em></p><p><em>'Gödel proved that, in any formal system that is rich enough to express arithmetic, there are truths that are expressible within it that can’t be proved. That’s the First Incompleteness Theorem.&nbsp;The second is that one of the things that can’t be proved within such a formal system is its own consistency.'</em></p><p><em>'Since Gödel had interpreted his First Incompleteness Theorem in the light of his mathematical realism, then yes, postmodernists are barking up the wrong tree. The proof shows that there is a mathematical truth—the Gödel sentence—that is not provable within the system. He’s not in any way attacking the notion of objective truth in mathematics. Quite the contrary.'</em></p><p><em>'Spinoza, the great monist, objected to dualities in just about every domain. He was everywhere interested in fusing, in unifying, what seemed to be polarities, collapsing dualities. The supernatural is fused with the natural, the ontological with the logical (which is entailed in his a priori methodology), the mental with the physical, the intellectual with the emotional, the normative with the descriptive.'</em></p><p><em>'Maybe Reality really is inconsistent with the reality of the self, and maybe then, driven by our conatus, we ought to resist Reality. That’s the path that Ahab takes, and it doesn’t end well for him, nor for those under his leadership, who have relinquished their wills to his. After all, why is it even worthwhile to struggle to know Reality, to struggle after anything at all, if the self that’s motivating the struggle is ultimately nothing at all?</em>'</p><p><img src="https://static.s123-cdn.com/uploads/2029468/2000_5fb4f9aa5c205.jpg"></p><p><a href="http://www.santafe.edu/people/profile/rebecca-goldstein"><u>Rebecca Newberger Goldstein</u></a> is an American philosopher, novelist and public intellectual. She has written ten books, both fiction and nonfiction. Here she discusses the relationship between science and philosophy, the nature of philosophical progress, Gödel’s theorems, Incompleteness, Einstein, Realism and postmodernism, Gödel and Wittgenstein, Spinoza, Spinoza and his appeal to imaginative writers, the Spinoza War, and Moby Dick.</p><p><strong>3:16:</strong> What made you become a philosopher?</p><p><strong>Rebecca Newberger Goldstein</strong> <strong>:</strong>&nbsp; I started out mostly interested in math and physics. There were problems that obsessed me in both fields—How can math be <em>a priori</em>? How can quantum mechanics be connected to a reality that is recognizably our own? I discovered, while in college, that these were actually philosophical problems. My senior year in college I went to speak to one of my professors, Sidney Morgenbesser, an amazing guy. He was the Socrates of his day. Socrates never published anything, but instead engaged in deeply probing dialogues. That was Sidney’s m.o. as well. Over the course of several long conversations Sidney convinced me that I was a philosopher, rather than a scientist. His clinching argument was that scientists are like the bourgeoisie, never questioning the system, whereas philosophers were like socialists, always examining the system critically: even if it seemed to be working, <em>ought</em> it to be working? That argument struck home. I basically applied to graduate school in philosophy on the strength of Sidney’s metaphor.&nbsp;</p><p><img src="https://static.s123-cdn.com/uploads/2029468/2000_5fb4ed28d1e2b.png"></p><p><strong>3:16:</strong> In your book <u>‘<a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B00KEW8KC4/ref=dbs_a_def_rwt_hsch_vapi_tkin_p1_i1">Plato at the Googleplex</a>’ y</u>ou have Plato brought into our century to discuss philosophy with our contemporaries. So first, can you say what you take philosophy to be and why you think it hasn’t gone away and isn’t going away soon?</p><p><strong>RNG:</strong> I think that philosophy is the systematic and rigorous investigation of one of the deepest urges that we humans have, which is the urge to get our bearings in the most general sense possible. In particular, (1) We want to know where we are. What is the nature of this universe in which we find ourselves? What fundamentally different kinds of things, belonging to different ontological categories, are there, and how do they operate? 2. We want to know our own place in the universe, whether we’re made of the same stuff, are a special category of being, and whether the universe itself has any attitudes towards us. 3. We want to know what we are meant to do with our lives. We want to know what it is to live a life worthy for a human to live, a good life.&nbsp;</p><p>The first two questions are ontological, the third is normative. Science, as it eventually developed, has the lead role in answering the ontological questions, but science is often pushed on by philosophy, in its critical probing role. And the more subtle the science becomes, the bigger the role for philosophy, since it falls to philosophy’s special techniques to figure out what is and isn’t entailed by the science. For example, what changes are we required to make to our concept of time in light of Relativity Theory? And as far as the normative questions go, there the ball falls squarely in philosophy’s court, though it’s sometimes advancements in science and technology that generate the balls, that is, new normative questions.&nbsp;</p><p>Consider the normative questions generated by advances in AI, or the question of what obligations we have to future generations, given the threat of climate change. As long as science and technology advance, philosophers will have new questions to work on.</p><p><strong>3:16:</strong>&nbsp; You place Plato in rooms having philosophical debates with all sorts of people but you never have him decisively concluding a debate or argument. For those hostile to philosophy this might be a hostage to fortune – it suggests that philosophy can’t decide anything and actually we would be better off listening to scientists, historians and novelists. Why should we heed the philosopher in our time if not even Plato can answer its questions? What do you say to those physicists who say philosophy is just pointless and has been supplanted by – well, in their case – physics?&nbsp;</p><p><strong>RNG:</strong> When it comes to ontology, I would argue that it’s science that plays the leading role. But I’d have to offer a philosophical argument to support that conclusion. I'd first have to both differentiate what is essential to science, how it differs from other fields of inquiry, including philosophy, and I’d have to argue for scientific realism, that is argue that science is in the business of ontology. Both of those are conclusions that can’t be empirically established, i.e. they are philosophical. So one can’t even make the case for science, ontologically speaking, without engaging in philosophy. And as far as the normative questions go, we are entirely in the philosophical sphere. And here I do think philosophy has offered us answers, answers which have as fundamentally changed our lives, and for the better, as the technological advances that science has given us.&nbsp;</p><p>As just one example, consider the idea of human rights. One of my points in my having Plato engage in those philosophical dialogues in which it’s not he who supplies the answer, but instead he is rather surprised by being philosophically instructed by some “regular” people, was to demonstrate the progress we’ve made since Plato, progress that has been disseminated and seeped into the points of view of non-philosophers. In the first dialogue a rather down-to-earth character, a media escort, explains to Plato in very commonsensical terms why slavery is wrong. Plato had argued that it’s wrong for Greeks to enslave other Greeks, which was an advance over the norm taken for granted by his society, but he never universalized the conclusion. Nor did Aristotle, who argued that some people are naturally suited to be slaves. So if I don’t have Plato having all the answers it’s often to show progress made in the millennia since he lived, or to show that our new conditions, many of them created by scientific and technological advances, generate new philosophical problems--in other words to show that philosophy will never go away. My showing Plato to be often instructed and/or stumped is meant to challenge the view that philosophy remains static.</p><p><strong>3:16:</strong>&nbsp; So this leads to one of the issues you raise in the book - the notion of philosophical progress. So what do you take to be the progress philosophy has made since Plato and why is it invisible to many, unlike science?&nbsp;</p><p><strong>RNG:</strong> Philosophical advances in epistemology and in ethics profoundly shape our points of view. We don’t see them precisely because we see with them. It’s like the fish who responds to the question “How’s the water today?” with “Water? What’s water?” When people hold the view, for example, that science has discovered that simultaneity is not absolute, as counter-intuitive as that seems, or that chattel slavery is an abomination, which once also had seemed counter-intuitive, they don’t realize the laborious philosophical reasoning that had laid the groundwork for their views. It takes philosophical work to claim that science can correct our fundamental views of the way the world is. It takes philosophical work to claim that we can discover, without consulting any holy books (that in fact sanction slavery), truths about the way humans can and can’t be treated. Philosophy is committed to the view that we can use human reason to come to ethical conclusions, overcoming biases, tradition, and religious authority. Just the other week the Pope gave his approval to civil unions for gay people. That is the slow progress of the philosophical idea of human rights working its way out. You could even consider such changes in ethical attitudes, eventually making their way even to the Vatican, as philosophy’s own technological products, the practical application of philosophical conclusions, analogous to the technological goodies that have come from science. In fact, you can even regard science itself as one of philosophy’s technological products, the practical application of certain epistemological conclusions.&nbsp;</p><p><img src="https://static.s123-cdn.com/uploads/2029468/2000_5fb4edb79cae4.png"></p><p><strong>3:16:</strong>&nbsp; You’ve written about <u><em>Gödel</em></u><a href="http://www.bookdepository.com/Incompleteness-Rebecca-Goldstein/9780393327601?ref=grid-view&amp;qid=1605692840648&amp;sr=1-1"><u><em>’s incompleteness theorems</em></u></a>. …</p></div></div></div></div></div></div></section></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.3-16am.co.uk/articles/plato-g%C3%B6del-spinoza-ahab">https://www.3-16am.co.uk/articles/plato-g%C3%B6del-spinoza-ahab</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.3-16am.co.uk/articles/plato-g%C3%B6del-spinoza-ahab</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25157681</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 05:52:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[An Introduction to ZFS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 369 | Comments 244 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25157491">thread link</a>) | @arm
<br/>
November 19, 2020 | https://www.servethehome.com/an-introduction-to-zfs-a-place-to-start/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.servethehome.com/an-introduction-to-zfs-a-place-to-start/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <!-- image --><div><figure><a href="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/truenas-homepage.png" data-caption="Truenas Homepage"><img width="696" height="496" src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/truenas-homepage-696x496.png" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/truenas-homepage-696x496.png 696w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/truenas-homepage-400x285.png 400w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/truenas-homepage-800x570.png 800w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/truenas-homepage-1068x761.png 1068w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/truenas-homepage-589x420.png 589w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/truenas-homepage-100x70.png 100w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/truenas-homepage.png 1291w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px" alt="Truenas Homepage" title="Truenas Homepage"></a><figcaption>Truenas Homepage</figcaption></figure></div>
            <!-- content --><p>ZFS has become increasingly popular in recent years. ZFS on Linux (ZoL) has pushed the envelope and exposed many newcomers to the ZFS fold. iXsystems has adopted the newer codebase, now called <strong>OpenZFS, </strong>into its codebase for TrueNAS CORE. The purpose of this article is to help those of you who have heard about ZFS but have not yet had the opportunity to research it.</p>
<p>Our hope is that we leave you with a better understanding of how and why it works the way it does. Knowledge is key to the decision-making process, and we feel that ZFS is something worth considering for most organizations.<br>
<span id="more-44288"></span></p>
<h2>What is ZFS?</h2>
<p>ZFS is a <strong>filesystem</strong>, but unlike most other file systems it is also the <strong>logical volume manager</strong> or LVM. What that means is ZFS directly controls not only how the bits and blocks of your files are stored on your hard drives, but it also controls how your hard drives are logically arranged for the purposes of RAID and redundancy. ZFS is also classified as a <strong>copy-on-write</strong> or <a href="https://www.ixsystems.com/documentation/freenas/11.2/zfsprimer.html">COW filesystem</a>. This means that ZFS can do some cool things like <strong>snapshots</strong> that a normal filesystem like NTFS could not. A snapshot can be thought of like it sounds, a photograph of how something was at a point in time. How a COW filesystem works, however, has some important implications that we need to discuss.</p>
<figure id="attachment_44997" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-44997"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Openzfs.svg_-322x300.png" alt="The Open ZFS Logo" width="322" height="300" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Openzfs.svg_-322x300.png 322w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Openzfs.svg_-800x746.png 800w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Openzfs.svg_-696x649.png 696w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Openzfs.svg_-450x420.png 450w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Openzfs.svg_.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 322px) 100vw, 322px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-44997">The Open ZFS Logo</figcaption></figure>
<p>Hard Drives work such that the pieces of your data are stored in <strong>Logical Block Addresses</strong>, or LBAs. ZFS is aware of what LBAs a specific file is stored in. Let us say we need to write a file that is big enough to fit into 3 blocks. We are going to store that file in LBA 1000, 1001, and 1002. This is considered a sequential write, as all of these blocks are stored directly next to each other. For spinning hard drives, this is ideal, as the write head does not have to move off of the track it is on.</p>
<figure id="attachment_23424" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-23424"><a href="https://www.servethehome.com/western-digital-red-pro-10tb-nas-hdd-review/wd-red-10tb-pro-nas-top/" rel="attachment wp-att-23424"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/WD-Red-10TB-Pro-NAS-Top.jpg" alt="WD Red 10TB Pro NAS Top" width="800" height="786" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/WD-Red-10TB-Pro-NAS-Top.jpg 800w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/WD-Red-10TB-Pro-NAS-Top-305x300.jpg 305w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/WD-Red-10TB-Pro-NAS-Top-696x684.jpg 696w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/WD-Red-10TB-Pro-NAS-Top-427x420.jpg 427w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-23424">WD Red 10TB Pro NAS Top <a href="https://www.servethehome.com/wd-red-smr-vs-cmr-tested-avoid-red-smr/">Use CMR with ZFS, not SMR</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Now, let us say we make a change to the file and the part that was stored at LBA 1001 needs to be modified. When we write that change, ZFS does not over-write the part of the file that was stored in 1001. Instead, it will write that block to LBA 2001. LBA 1001 will be kept as-is until the snapshot keeping it there expires. This allows us to have both the current version of the file, and the previous one, while <em>only storing the difference.</em> However, the next time we go to read the file back, the read head of our spinning hard drive needs to read LBA 1000, go to the track where LBA 2001 is stored, read that, and then go back to the track where LBA 1002 is stored. This phenomenon is called <strong>fragmentation.</strong></p>
<h2>A Primer on ZFS Pool Design</h2>
<p>To make ZFS pools easier to understand, we are going to focus on using small storage containers as you may have around the house or shop. Before we continue, it is worth defining some terms. A <strong>VDEV, </strong>or virtual device, is a logical grouping of one or more storage devices. A <strong>pool</strong> is then a logically defined group built from 1 or more VDEVs. ZFS is very customizable, and therefore, there are many different types of configurations for VDEVs. You can think of the construction of a ZFS pool by visualizing the following graphic:</p>
<figure id="attachment_45011" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-45011"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-800x521.jpg" alt="Nested Storage Containers" width="696" height="453" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-800x521.jpg 800w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-400x261.jpg 400w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-1536x1001.jpg 1536w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-2048x1334.jpg 2048w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-696x453.jpg 696w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-1068x696.jpg 1068w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-645x420.jpg 645w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-45011">Nested Storage Containers</figcaption></figure>
<p>Starting from the smallest container size, we have our drives. We can see that in this visualization we have two drives in each larger container. These two larger containers are our VDEVs. The single largest container, then, is our pool. In this configuration, we would have each pair of drives in a <strong>mirror. </strong>This means that one drive can fail in either (or both!) VDEV and the pool would continue to function in a <strong>degraded</strong> state.</p>
<figure id="attachment_45012" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-45012"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-With-Two-Bad-Drives-800x538.jpg" alt="Two Mirrors, Each VDEV with One Bad Drive" width="696" height="468" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-With-Two-Bad-Drives-800x538.jpg 800w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-With-Two-Bad-Drives-400x269.jpg 400w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-With-Two-Bad-Drives-1536x1034.jpg 1536w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-With-Two-Bad-Drives-2048x1378.jpg 2048w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-With-Two-Bad-Drives-696x468.jpg 696w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-With-Two-Bad-Drives-1068x719.jpg 1068w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-With-Two-Bad-Drives-624x420.jpg 624w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-45012">Two Mirrors, Each VDEV with One Bad Drive</figcaption></figure>
<p>However, if 2 drives in a <strong>single</strong> VDEV, all of the data in our entire pool is lost. There is no redundancy of the pool itself, all redundancy in ZFS is in the VDEV layer. If one <em>VDEV</em> fails, there is not enough information to rebuild the missing data.</p>
<figure id="attachment_45013" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-45013"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-With-Two-Bad-Drives-failed-800x559.jpg" alt="Two Mirrors, One VDEV where Both Drives Failed" width="696" height="486" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-With-Two-Bad-Drives-failed-800x559.jpg 800w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-With-Two-Bad-Drives-failed-400x280.jpg 400w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-With-Two-Bad-Drives-failed-1536x1074.jpg 1536w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-With-Two-Bad-Drives-failed-696x487.jpg 696w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-With-Two-Bad-Drives-failed-1068x747.jpg 1068w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-With-Two-Bad-Drives-failed-601x420.jpg 601w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-With-Two-Bad-Drives-failed-100x70.jpg 100w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Mirrored-VDEV-With-Two-Bad-Drives-failed.jpg 1991w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-45013">Two Mirrors, One VDEV where Both Drives Failed</figcaption></figure>
<p>Next, we need to define what&nbsp;<strong>RAID-Z</strong> is and what the various levels of RAID-Z are. RAID-Z is a way of putting multiple drives together into a VDEV and storing <strong>parity,&nbsp;</strong>or fault tolerance. In ZFS, there is no dedicated “parity drive” like in&nbsp;<strong>Unraid</strong>, but it instead stores parity across all of the drives in the VDEV.&nbsp; The amount of parity that is spread across the drives determines the level of RAID-Z. It is in this way more similar to traditional hardware RAID.</p>
<p>What can make RAID-Z a better approach than a mirrored configuration is that it does not matter <em>what&nbsp;</em>drive fails in a RAID-Z. Each drive is an equal partner, whereas, in a mirrored configuration, each mirrored VDEV is a separate entity. This benefit of RAID-Z comes at the cost of performance, however, and a mirrored pool will almost always be <em>faster</em>&nbsp;than RAID Z.</p>
<p><strong>RAID-Z</strong>&nbsp;is similar to a traditional&nbsp;<strong>RAID 5. </strong>In RAID-Z you have one drive worth of parity. In other words, if you lose one drive, your pool will continue to function. For RAID-Z you need a minimum of 3 drives per VDEV. You can have 3, 7, or even 12 drives in a RAID-Z VDEV. The more drives which you add, however, the longer it will take to <strong>resilver,&nbsp;</strong>or rebuild.</p>
<p>This increased time increases the risk of your data, as a second drive failure during this process would destroy your pool. ZFS will resilver while the data is still in use, it is a live recovery. The implication of this is that our disks are working harder than usual during this process, and this can increase the chances of a second drive failure. Your data is still accessible and in production, while it is reading all of the parity data from the existing members of your VDEV and then writing it to the new disk.</p>
<figure id="attachment_45014" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-45014"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Raid-Z1--800x569.jpg" alt="A Pool with a Single 3-Disk Raid Z1 VDEV" width="696" height="495" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Raid-Z1--800x569.jpg 800w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Raid-Z1--400x285.jpg 400w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Raid-Z1--1536x1093.jpg 1536w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Raid-Z1--2048x1458.jpg 2048w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Raid-Z1--696x495.jpg 696w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Raid-Z1--1068x760.jpg 1068w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Raid-Z1--590x420.jpg 590w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-Raid-Z1--100x70.jpg 100w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-45014">A Pool with a Single 3-Disk Raid-Z VDEV</figcaption></figure>
<p>A RAID-Z2 VDEV is more akin to a RAID 6. In this configuration, 2 drives worth of parity is stored across all of your devices. You can lose up to two drives per VDEV and your pool will still function. Adding more parity drives increases calculations required which means you need more processing performance to operate the array.</p>
<figure id="attachment_45015" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-45015"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-RAID-Z2-800x551.jpg" alt="A Pool with a Single 4-Disk Raid Z2 VDEV" width="696" height="479" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-RAID-Z2-800x551.jpg 800w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-RAID-Z2-400x276.jpg 400w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-RAID-Z2-1536x1059.jpg 1536w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-RAID-Z2-2048x1412.jpg 2048w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-RAID-Z2-218x150.jpg 218w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-RAID-Z2-696x480.jpg 696w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-RAID-Z2-1068x736.jpg 1068w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-RAID-Z2-609x420.jpg 609w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A-RAID-Z2-100x70.jpg 100w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-45015">A Pool with a Single 4-Disk Raid Z2 VDEV</figcaption></figure>
<p>Finally, a RAID-Z3 VDEV provides three drives worth of parity, so you can lose up to three drives per VDEV and your pool will still function. <strong>The more drives of parity you add, however, the slower your performance ends up being</strong>. You need a minimum of four but should use at least five drives to build a RAID-Z3 VDEV.</p>
<h2>The Need for Speed</h2>
<p>There are two ways in which we measure speed or <em>fastness</em>,&nbsp;<strong>IOPS,</strong>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<strong>Throughput</strong>. In RAIDZ, more drives will give you more throughput, or the actual read and write speed you see when transferring files. However, if you have ever tried to run multiple file copies in Windows simultaneously, you may have noticed the more you do, the slower it gets. It does not always get slower at a constant rate, the more you try to do disks will get exponentially slower. This is because your disk can only do so many Input/Output Operations per Second, or IOPS.</p>
<p>RAIDZ will scale in&nbsp;<em>throughput</em>&nbsp;with the more disks you add, but it does not scale with&nbsp;<em>IOPS.</em> What that generally means is, RAIDZ is not traditionally the best choice for I/O intensive workloads, as the amount of IOPS is roughly limited to the slowest member of our VDEV if we exclude all of the caching ZFS has. Virtualization, as we are discussing here, is highly dependent on I/O.</p>
<p>Earlier, we discussed that ZFS is a COW filesystem, and because of that it suffers from data fragmentation. There are direct performance implications that stem from that fact.&nbsp;<strong>The more “full” your pool is, the slower it will ultimately get.&nbsp;</strong>Write speeds in ZFS are directly tied to the amount of&nbsp;<em>adjacent</em> free blocks there are to write to. As your pool fills up, and as data fragments, there are fewer and fewer blocks that are directly adjacent to one another. A single large file may span blocks scattered all over the surface of your hard drive. Even though you would expect that file to be a sequential write, it no longer can be if your drive is full.</p>
<figure id="attachment_45006" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-45006"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Seagate-Mobile-HDD-Crystale-DIsk-Mark.png" alt="Seagate Mobile HDD Crystal Disk Mark Performance" width="482" height="351" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Seagate-Mobile-HDD-Crystale-DIsk-Mark.png 482w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Seagate-Mobile-HDD-Crystale-DIsk-Mark-400x291.png 400w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Seagate-Mobile-HDD-Crystale-DIsk-Mark-324x235.png 324w" sizes="(max-width: 482px) 100vw, 482px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-45006">Seagate Mobile HDD Crystal Disk Mark Performance</figcaption></figure>
<p>In the above graphic, we can see a Seagate 1TB mobile drive that I tested in CrystalDiskMark. It can do about 130 MB/s of sequential read and writes. We can also see that when we start doing random 4k I/O, the speed falls about <strong>100x</strong>. This is meant to illustrate the performance impact of data fragmentation. Additionally, we can see that the latency for these lookups can take about&nbsp;<strong>half of a second, </strong>and we are limited to about 350 IOPS. In order to be fast, virtualization workloads on traditional hard drives need to have many disks in order to compensate for this slowness. It would not be uncommon to see a pool constructed of 10 or more VDEVs of mirrored drives.</p>
<p>Additionally, there is some wisdom we can <a href="https://www.ixsystems.com/community/threads/the-path-to-success-for-block-storage.81165">borrow from the ZFS community</a>. As your pool fills up, and sequential writes become increasingly difficult to accomplish due to fragmentation, it will slow down in a non-linear way. As a general rule of thumb, at about 50% capacity your pool will be noticeably slower than it was when it was 10% capacity. At about 80%-96% capacity, your pool starts to become very slow, and ZFS will actually change its write algorithm to ensure data integrity, further slowing you down.</p>
<p>This is where SSDs come in. They radically change the game because they work very differently at the physical layer. They do not have read and write heads that are flying around a spinning disk back and forth trying to find your data. With the physical limitations of disk-based drives out of the way, SSDs can read and write non-sequential data <em>much&nbsp;</em>faster. They do not suffer the penalties of these rules nearly as severely, fragmentation does not hurt their performance to the same degree.</p>
<figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/970-EVO-Plus-250GB-Front.jpg" alt="A Samsung 970 EVO Plus SSD" width="1500" height="997"></figure>
<p>A Samsung 970 EVO Plus SSD</p>
<p>Hard drives have increased in capacity by leaps-and-bounds over the past couple of decades. We have seen hard drives grow from a single gigabyte in capacity and just last year <a href="https://www.servethehome.com/western-digital-volume-production-of-18tb-and-20tb-drives-in-2020/">Western Digital announced</a> that 18 and 20 …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.servethehome.com/an-introduction-to-zfs-a-place-to-start/">https://www.servethehome.com/an-introduction-to-zfs-a-place-to-start/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.servethehome.com/an-introduction-to-zfs-a-place-to-start/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25157491</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 05:12:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What's Wrong with the Media]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 26 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25156088">thread link</a>) | @jger15
<br/>
November 19, 2020 | https://www.slowboring.com/p/whats-wrong-with-the-media | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.slowboring.com/p/whats-wrong-with-the-media">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Welcome to Thursday! </p><p>I’ve been reading some interesting policy reports about everything from <a href="https://t.co/CxLqshzCAg">maternal mortality</a> to <a href="https://www.urban.org/urban-wire/can-we-design-student-loan-forgiveness-target-low-income-families">how to target student loan forgiveness</a> but at the moment there is a lot of demand for me to address the situation at Vox in detail or to assimilate my personal story into a larger narrative about “wokeness” or the culture wars. Personally I’m not a huge fan of navel-gazing. So I’ll just say that my personal interest in reclaiming my status as an independent, blog-like voice transcends any particular issues with any particular publication. I wanted to do <em>this,</em> not go find a different job, and I thank those of you who’ve joined me on this journey.</p><p>But Vox is typical of a few trends that exist broadly in the media industry and that I do think are of interest. </p><ul><li><p>The staff skews very young. </p></li><li><p>The staff is concentrated in big coastal cities, and especially New York.</p></li><li><p>The staff is overwhelmingly composed of graduates of selective colleges (state university flagship campuses and private schools with names you know).</p></li></ul><p>The media industry has long skewed young, educated, and New Yorky. But digital disruption trends have made it more so than ever before. Daily newspapers published in mid-sized cities and small towns are weaker and less significant. A lot of reporters born in the 1960s and 1970s have left the industry as it has shrunk and few of them work at digital native startups. </p><p>Separately from that change, national politics has been polarizing around age, educational attainment and population density in an unprecedented way. A group of young, recent college graduates living in Brooklyn would’ve skewed left in 1990 but this was an era when Al D’Amato could win statewide in New York and Democratic presidential campaigns would win in West Virginia. Today a demographically identical group skews much further left than it used to. None of this is really an outcome that anyone particularly wanted or intended. But it’s put a big thumb on the scales ideologically at the exact same time that economic trends have turned against the startups.</p><p>The result is that I think you should expect the instability we’ve seen this fall to be just the leading edge of the wedge.  </p><h4>Most media isn’t political journalism </h4><div><figure><a target="_blank" href="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fce695ac4-18ca-4c53-a705-9cfd4bf75644_1616x1168.png"><img src="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fce695ac4-18ca-4c53-a705-9cfd4bf75644_1616x1168.png" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/ce695ac4-18ca-4c53-a705-9cfd4bf75644_1616x1168.png&quot;,&quot;height&quot;:1052,&quot;width&quot;:1456,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:null,&quot;bytes&quot;:2381922,&quot;alt&quot;:null,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;image/png&quot;,&quot;href&quot;:null}" alt=""></a><figcaption>Culture criticism today: Calling out various problematic things</figcaption></figure></div><p>Reeves Wiedeman’s recent <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2020/11/inside-the-new-york-times-heated-reckoning-with-itself.html">article about internal tensions at The New York Times</a> includes this passage, which gets at a dynamic that I think you see across the media landscape. The vast majority of the people who work at any given publication are not professional political journalists, and generally the further you get from the ~~political journalism~~ section of a media organization the more left-wing things get: </p><blockquote><p>Of all the fronts on which the Times was being pushed to change, the strongest insurrectionary energy was coming from legions of newsroom-adjacent employees in digital jobs that didn’t exist a decade ago. The employees responsible for distributing the Times in the past — typesetters, pressmen, delivery drivers — had never been encouraged to speak up about the ethical questions at the heart of the paper’s journalism. But the app developers and software engineers who deliver the Times’ journalism to the world have held their hands up in just as many Ivy League seminars as their editorial peers. They might be too shy to march over to a masthead editor and complain about a clumsy headline, but #newsroom-feedback had opened a digital door to criticism. Reporters found that suddenly it was the Times’ programmers and developers, rather than their editors, who were critiquing their work. During the town hall about the Cotton op-ed, one data engineer said on Slack, “How many such process failures would be tolerated in tech?”</p><p>Many of the techsurrectionists had come from Facebook or Uber or Amazon to join the Times out of a sense of mission, leaving the ethical quandaries of the tech industry for what they thought were more virtuous pastures. “I joined the company for one reason, and it’s because I feel a responsibility to be a part of a mission that I believe in,” a product manager who previously worked at Apple wrote in #newsroom-feedback after the Cotton op-ed. “This feels like the rug’s been pulled out from under us — not just because it feels like that mission [has] been severely compromised by the decision to publish this piece, but even more so because the products we’re building were used to do it.”</p><p>“It’s like making telephone poles,” one software engineer added, “and finding out they’re being used as battering rams.”</p></blockquote><p>People who cover politics professionally, for better or worse, end up spending a fair amount of time talking to Republicans and trying to understand what conservatives think about public policy issues. If we’re doing our jobs at all correctly we can do stories that bring a mostly-progressive audience a greater understanding of what is happening on the other side. And when a professional political reporter does a bad job it’s often because he or she is taking a dive to maintain relationships with sources on the right, or bending over <em>too far</em> backwards to be fair. </p><p>At the same time, we political journalists have our fair share of totally ignorant hot takes about music or cooking or sports or whatever else that we can fire off. </p><p>The flip side is that our colleagues who cover sports or music or cooking also have hot takes about politics. Hot takes that come from the very narrow demographic and ideological niche that dominates the media and is untempered by the need to actually cover politics.</p><h4>Coverage has gotten really weird </h4><p>Ian Walker <a href="https://kotaku.com/playstation-5-the-kotaku-review-1845588904">recently ended his PS5 review for Kotaku with this thought</a>: </p><blockquote><p>The world is still reeling under the weight of the covid-19 pandemic. There are more Americans out of work right now than at any point in the country’s history, with no relief in sight. Our health care system is an inherently evil institution that forces people to ration life-saving medications like insulin and choose suicide over suffering with untreated mental illness.</p><p>As I’m writing this, it looks very likely that Joe Biden will be our next president. But it’s clear that the worst people aren’t going away just because a new old white man is sitting behind the Resolute desk—well, at least not&nbsp;<em>this</em>&nbsp;old white man. Our government is fundamentally broken in a way that necessitates radical change rather than incremental electorialism.</p><p>The harsh truth is that, for the reasons listed above and more, a lot of people simply won’t be able to buy a PlayStation 5, regardless of supply. Or if they can, concerns over increasing austerity in the United States and the growing threat of widespread political violence supersede any enthusiasm about the console’s SSD or how ray tracing makes reflections more realistic. That’s not to say you&nbsp;<em>can’t</em>&nbsp;be excited for those things—I certainly am, on some level—but there’s an irrefutable level of privilege attached to the ability to simply tune out the world as it burns around you.</p></blockquote><p>The problem here, to me, is not that Walker ought to “stick to sports.” It’s that the analysis is bad. But because it’s in a video game console review rather than a policy analysis section and conforms to the predominant ideological fads, it just sails through to our screens. </p><p>What actually happened is that starting in March the household savings rate soared (people are taking fewer vacations and eating out less) and while it’s been declining from its peak as of September it was still unusually high.</p><div><figure><a target="_blank" href="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F885debb5-4601-4e59-9232-382c5c1f8250_1494x718.png"><img src="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F885debb5-4601-4e59-9232-382c5c1f8250_1494x718.png" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/885debb5-4601-4e59-9232-382c5c1f8250_1494x718.png&quot;,&quot;height&quot;:700,&quot;width&quot;:1456,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:null,&quot;bytes&quot;:94064,&quot;alt&quot;:null,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;image/png&quot;,&quot;href&quot;:null}" alt=""></a></figure></div><p>One result of this is a lot of people have been able to pay off old debts. At the same time, interest rates have plunged without sparking an increase in borrowing, so household debt service costs have plummeted. </p><div><figure><a target="_blank" href="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F9dcbf3aa-9fc1-4e00-b528-26e07108ac28_1494x702.png"><img src="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F9dcbf3aa-9fc1-4e00-b528-26e07108ac28_1494x702.png" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/9dcbf3aa-9fc1-4e00-b528-26e07108ac28_1494x702.png&quot;,&quot;height&quot;:684,&quot;width&quot;:1456,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:null,&quot;bytes&quot;:109636,&quot;alt&quot;:null,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;image/png&quot;,&quot;href&quot;:null}" alt=""></a></figure></div><p>The upshot of this is that no matter what you think about Biden or the American health care system, the fact is that the sales outlook for a new video game console system is very good. There is economic hardship in America, but the larger trend is that middle class people are seeing their homeowners’ equity rise and their debt payments fall, while cash piles up on their balance sheets, because it’s not safe to throw a big birthday party or take a vacation this weekend.</p><p>Not to just pick on this one article, but it was striking to me because it was both emblematic of the way far-left politics has suffused non-political media and also because the topic had nothing to do with race or gender identity issues.  </p><h4>It’s not really about “wokeness”</h4><p>There’s a lot of talk lately about excessive “wokeness” in the media driving people away from their jobs. But I don’t really think the underlying dynamics are specific to any particular issue area. </p><p>I remember a time in December 2018 when there was a <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2018/11/26/18112769/amazon-prime-cancel">flurry of articles about an Amazon Prime backlash</a> and I felt inspired to write a corrective noting that <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/12/11/18129809/amazon-polling-popular-confidence">Amazon is actually incredibly popular</a> both as a shopping destination and in polls. In response to a similar barrage of articles about how <a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/style/2020/04/how-should-a-climate-change-reporter-think-about-having-children">maybe you shouldn’t have children because of climate change</a>, I felt inspired to write, at somewhat greater length, my book One Billion Americans. </p><p>The basic dynamic is that if you take a normal distribution (say of political views) and then shift the average a bit to one side, you end up with explosive growth in the number of outliers. In this chart, the average of the red line isn’t so different from the average of the black line. But the right-hand tail of the red line is much higher than the black.</p><div><figure><a target="_blank" href="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fa5804a44-7e3d-4e75-a0b7-4115b0f9cdee_999x461.jpeg"><img src="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fa5804a44-7e3d-4e75-a0b7-4115b0f9cdee_999x461.jpeg" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/a5804a44-7e3d-4e75-a0b7-4115b0f9cdee_999x461.jpeg&quot;,&quot;height&quot;:461,&quot;width&quot;:999,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:null,&quot;bytes&quot;:85183,&quot;alt&quot;:null,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;image/jpeg&quot;,&quot;href&quot;:null}" alt=""></a></figure></div><p>If everyone in digital media is an under-fifty college graduate living in a big city, then it’s not that everyone in digital media is a far-left weirdo, but you do get <em>drastically more</em> far-left weirdness. </p><p>This tendency could obviously be tempered by business considerations. Hollywood is famously full of left-wing people and they do produce some content that reflects those ideas. But they mostly produce content that lacks overt political themes, and they also feed the network television audience a steady diet of police procedurals that embed very …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.slowboring.com/p/whats-wrong-with-the-media">https://www.slowboring.com/p/whats-wrong-with-the-media</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.slowboring.com/p/whats-wrong-with-the-media</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25156088</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:27:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
