<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 20]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 20. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:39:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-20.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:39:42 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Beginner's Guide to Abstraction]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 140 | Comments 34 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23735991">thread link</a>) | @jesseduffield
<br/>
July 4, 2020 | https://jesseduffield.com/beginners-guide-to-abstraction/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jesseduffield.com/beginners-guide-to-abstraction/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-75">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	
	
	<div>
		<p>In <em>The Pragmatic Programmer</em>, Andrew Hunt and David Thomas introduced the DRY (Don't Repeat Yourself) principle. The rationale being that if you see the same code copy+pasted 10 times you should probably factor that code into its own method/class.</p>
<p>But then Sandi Metz came along and <a href="https://www.sandimetz.com/blog/2016/1/20/the-wrong-abstraction">said</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Duplication is far cheaper than the wrong abstraction.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And so the eternal war began.</p>
<h3>What is abstraction?</h3>
<p>For the purposes of this post I'm referring to the kind of abstraction as described in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abstraction_(computer_science)#Abstraction_in_object_oriented_programming">Abstraction Principle</a>, which Wikipedia describes like so:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In software engineering and programming language theory, the abstraction principle (or the principle of abstraction) is a basic dictum that aims to reduce duplication of information in a program (usually with emphasis on code duplication) whenever practical by making use of abstractions provided by the programming language or software libraries</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This post has nothing to say about the conceptual kind of abstraction where from the concrete examples of 'Parrot' and 'Sparrow' you create an abstraction of 'Bird'. This post is about duplicated code, how to respond to it, and how to respond to other people's responses to it.</p>
<p>I define the verb 'abstraction' to be an <em>attempt</em> to reduce complexity by combining repeated commonality into some generalisation. And so, the noun 'abstraction' is the result of that attempt. If you're somebody who believes abstraction is by definition a <em>successful</em> attempt, feel free to substitute the term 'wrong abstraction' with 'failure to abstract' throughout this post.</p>
<p>The process of abstraction typically goes like this:<br>
1) you identify different chunks of code that you think are all essentially doing the same thing<br>
2) you create a method or a class with a narrow interface which can be substituted in for all the chunks of code you found<br>
3) you go and swap out the chunks of code with a call to your method/class</p>
<h3>Abstraction is always a gamble</h3>
<p>In the world of software engineering, when requirements are always changing, every abstraction is a gamble. When you make an abstraction over some concrete things, you're making a bet that the concrete things are more similar than they are different, and that their similarities are not mere coincidences: that there is a common purpose shared by the concrete things which would lead them to evolve in lockstep as requirements evolve. If you win the bet, your codebase will be easier to work in and adding new use cases via your abstraction will be trivially easy. If you lose, you'll see a flash of fear in your colleague's eyes whenever they're assigned a ticket to make yet another extension to the misfigured monster that the once-innocent abstraction has now become</p>
<p>But risk abounds everywhere, and leaving duplicated code unabstracted is its own gamble. You're betting that the chunks of code will evolve in separate directions as requirements change and that their current similarities are more coincidence than a reflection of their common purpose. Win the bet and your colleague gets to sleep soundly at night knowing they won't be facing the abstraction monster at work the next day. Lose, and code that should have evolved in lockstep is now implemented in completely different ways across different files, where a developer fixes a bug identified in one place, only for the same bug to be reported days later in a completely different file.</p>
<p>Your job is to get good at making the right bets.</p>
<h3>The right/wrong abstraction</h3>
<p>You'll know that you've made the <em>right</em> abstraction when a long time passes and you haven't needed to expand the interface (an example of expanding the interface is adding an optional flag argument). You'll also know you've made the right abstraction when another developer doesn't find it that much harder to understand how the code behaves for a given use case than if somebody had written the code to satisfy the use case without the abstraction.</p>
<p>You'll know you've made the <em>wrong</em> abstraction when after a while the interface has been expanded to support various optional flags, each for a different use case, and you need to be a genius to reason about what the code will actually do for a given use case. By the way, if you have a string arg that merely gets fed into a switch statement inside a method and for each new use case you come up with a new accepted value for it, you <em>are</em> expanding the implicit interface, even if that fact isn't captured in your type system.</p>
<p>There is plenty of daylight between the perfect abstraction and the completely wrong abstraction (perhaps the interface needs to be fundamentally changed but afterwards you're back to having a good abstraction), and so the point of this section isn't to prescribe how much you should be abstracting, but to encourage you to think about both perspectives and be able to make a case in a PR review for why you think an abstraction should/should-not exist.</p>
<h3>Do you over or under-abstract?</h3>
<p>Given it is impossible to make the right decision with regards to abstraction every time, you are probably either somebody who over-abstracts or somebody who under-abstracts.</p>
<p>If common feedback on your PR reviews is that you should DRY up your code, you could probably benefit from doing a scan for duplicated code before submitting a PR and considering whether it belongs in its own method/class.</p>
<p>If you commonly get feedback that your methods are hard to understand because they support too many disparate use cases at once, you are probaby over-abstracting and should consider whether you should increase your tolerance for duplication.</p>
<p>Note that it's not always as simple as under-abstracting vs over-abstracting. Sometimes abstraction is appropriate, but you might take the wrong approach. If an abstraction is deemed wrong by the team, that doesn't mean no abstraction is necessarily the best alternative.</p>
<h3>Under-abstraction examples</h3>
<p>The main sign that you could be under-abstracting is that you have a heap of code doing the exact same thing called in a heap of places with no obvious reason why anybody would want the code to diverge.</p>
<h4>Example: Hard-coded formulas</h4>
<h5>Bad:</h5>
<pre><code># sphere has radius of 11
sphere_volume = 4*Math::PI/3*11**3
puts "the volume of the sphere is #{sphere_volume} cm^3"
...

radius = calculate_radius
volume = 4*Math::PI/3*radius**3
sphere.volume = volume</code></pre>
<h5>Good:</h5>
<pre><code>def sphere_volume(radius)
  4*Math::PI/3*radius**3
end

# sphere has radius of 11
sphere_volume = sphere_volume(11)
puts "the volume of the sphere is #{sphere_volume} cm^3"
...

radius = calculate_radius
volume = sphere_volume(radius)
sphere.volume = volume</code></pre>
<p>Why is it a good idea to abstract the formula for a sphere's volume into its own method? Because if mathematicians ever found out they got the formula wrong, you would want to go through all the places in your code that you used the formula and update it to be correct. That is, we know ahead of time that we want the code to be in lockstep. This is as safe a gamble as you can get.</p>
<h3>Over-abstraction examples</h3>
<p>The main sign that you're over-abstracting is that your method accepts a bunch of optional args:</p>
<h4>Example: Bloated method</h4>
<h5>Bad:</h5>
<pre><code>def average(arr, type = Integer, ignore_nulls = false)
  if arr.any?(&amp;:nil?)
    if ignore_nulls
      arr = arr.compact
    else
      return nil
    end
  end

  if type == String
    arr = arr.map(&amp;:to_i)
  end

  arr.sum / arr.size
end

puts average([1,2,3])
=&gt; 2

puts average(['1','2','3'], String)
=&gt; 2

puts average(['1','2','3', nil], String, true)
=&gt; 2

puts average([1, 2, 3, nil], Integer, false)
=&gt; nil</code></pre>
<p>If you want to know how the <code>average</code> method behaves when you're dealing with an array of strings with no <code>nil</code> values, you have to read through the first if condition which has nothing to do with your use case before reaching the code that does. Likewise if you want to know how the <code>average</code> method behaves when the array contains either nils or integers, the second if condition is irrelevant, but you'll still need to read through that to understand how the whole thing works.</p>
<p>If each of the use cases came up dozens or hundreds of times, maybe then it would make sense to retain the abstraction, but when the number of optional arguments is roughly equal to the number of different use cases, chances are you've got the wrong abstraction.</p>
<h5>Good:</h5>
<pre><code>def average(arr)
  arr.sum / arr.size
end

puts average([1,2,3])
=&gt; 2

arr = ['1','2','3'].map(&amp;:to_i)
puts average(arr)
=&gt; 2

arr = ['1','2','3', nil].compact.map(&amp;:to_i)
puts average(arr)
=&gt; 2

arr = [1, 2, 3, nil]
if arr.any?(&amp;:nil?)
  puts nil
else
  puts average(arr)
end
=&gt; nil</code></pre>
<p>In this case we're not removing the abstraction altogether: we're just keeping the part that actually applies to all cases. Now understanding the logic of any one invocation of our <code>average</code> method is trivial.</p>
<p>We now have <code>.map(&amp;:to_i)</code> being duplicated whereas it only appeared once in the <code>Bad</code> alternative, but it's a small cost for a vast improvement.</p>
<p>Note that looking at the <code>Good</code> variant, it's clear that the behaviour is quite different from one use case to the next, but that is not at all clear in the <code>Bad</code> variant because the method calls all look so simple and it was anybody's guess how much code inside <code>average</code> applied to each use case.</p>
<p>This is why abstractions go bad over time: because as you expand the interface more and more, it becomes harder and harder to judge how appropriate the abstraction is to any given use case, and developers end up assuming that all that convoluted code is vaguely relevant to the majority of use cases when in fact it's not.</p>
<h4>Example: Awkward class</h4>
<h5>Bad:</h5>
<pre><code>class Shape
  def initialize(radius: nil, width: nil, type:)
    @radius = radius
    @width = width
    @type = type
  end

  def area
    case @type
    when :square
      @width ** 2
    when :circle
      (@radius ** 2) * Math::PI
    end
  end

  def perimeter
    case @type
    when :square
      @width * 4
    when :circle
      @radius * 2 * Math::PI
    end
  end

  def diameter
    case @type
    when :square
      nil
    when :circle
 …</code></pre></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://jesseduffield.com/beginners-guide-to-abstraction/">https://jesseduffield.com/beginners-guide-to-abstraction/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jesseduffield.com/beginners-guide-to-abstraction/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23735991</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 01:12:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: FAANG Compensation Calculators]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 26 | Comments 10 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23735469">thread link</a>) | @refrigerator
<br/>
July 4, 2020 | https://mackgrenfell.com/compensation-calculators/facebook | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://mackgrenfell.com/compensation-calculators/facebook">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>These calculators show what you can expect to earn at different tech companies, accounting for career progression. </p><p>Data from <a href="https://levels.fyi/" target="_blank">levels.fyi</a>. Models built in <a href="https://causal.app/?utm_source=compensation_calculators" target="_blank">Causal</a>. Special thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/miraan_tabrez" target="_blank">Miraan</a>.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://mackgrenfell.com/compensation-calculators/facebook</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23735469</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 22:56:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How I grew my Shopify micro-SaaS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 123 | Comments 46 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23734539">thread link</a>) | @amrrs
<br/>
July 4, 2020 | https://www.preetamnath.com/blog/grow-shopify-micro-saas-to-25k-mrr-in-14-months | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.preetamnath.com/blog/grow-shopify-micro-saas-to-25k-mrr-in-14-months">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>14 months ago, my co-founder <a href="https://twitter.com/sankalpjonna" target="_blank">Sankalp</a> and I set out to build a business that can sustain our livelihood while allowing us the freedom to live life on our terms. </p><p>When we started, we each had roughly 12 months of savings to survive on, assuming we made $0. Hence our minimum goal was to make $1,500/mo and the case where we would be celebrating with champagne was set to $3,000/mo.</p><p>We launched our app on April 24, 2019. The first paid plan was launched on June 4, 2019. Around the same time, we got <a href="https://www.preetamnath.com/blog/shopify-micro-saas-growth" target="_blank">featured by Shopify</a>. Here's a <a href="https://apps.shopify.com/whatsapp-chat-button" target="_blank">link to the app</a> if you want to check it out.</p><p>14 months later, we grew past $25,000 in MRR while remaining a 2 person team.</p><figure id="w-node-e5ce9f7f0ba4-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f004959a0b62d53946fd901_shopify%20earnings%20growth.png" alt=""></p><figcaption><em>Note:&nbsp;Earnings reflect after a 1 month delay</em></figcaption></figure><p>I’m so proud of what we have built here.</p><p>If life is a video game, and there’s 100 levels to it, I feel like we have finally crossed level 1.</p><p>Here's what we've been up to in the 14 months since launch:</p><ul role="list"><li>20,000 active merchants (users) on the app</li><li>1,500+ paying merchants (customers)</li><li>450,000 automated WhatsApp messages sent in June</li><li>2.2 million WhatsApp chat messages initiated in June</li><li>Highest rated 5.0 🌟 app for all things WhatsApp with 500+ reviews</li><li>Users from 50+ countries around the world</li></ul><figure id="w-node-0cd8870c808c-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f007ba5d6c3b3532b0aa784_paying%20customers%20countries.png" alt=""></p></figure><p>We did a lot of things right, but we also messed up here and there. I've tried to capture an honest and accurate account of our journey so far.</p><h2>11 key learnings and mistakes from our journey<br></h2><h3>1- Learning: Always keep moving the needle</h3><p>Running your own business and having 100% freedom and flexibility is a gift or a curse, depending on how you use it. It’s easy to get lost in building, polishing, bringing your ideas to life. But remember, the only things that matter are what move the needle. </p><p>For every decision related to your business, you should always run it through a set of questions that help you filter out whether your idea is aligned to your business goals.</p><ul role="list"><li>Does it help our app get more users</li><li>Does it help convert more users to paying customers</li><li>Does it help users derive more value and ROI from the app</li><li>Does it meaningfully improve user experience</li><li>Does it reduce our support ticket load</li><li>Does it have any unintended 2nd order consequences that can bite us later</li></ul><p>Ultimately, you want to keep making decisions that move the needle for your business - by bringing you more customers and revenue, or making it easier and less time consuming to run the business (if that’s one of your goals, it is for us).<br></p><h3>2- Learning: Help users realise value as soon as possible</h3><p>From our research, we learnt that Shopify merchants are mostly solopreneurs or teams of 2-10. They are always time and resource crunched.</p><p>We wanted to enable our users to start using the app with the least amount of setup time or steps. This reflects in in the user experience of the app. </p><p>For example, when a first time user enters their phone number and hits the “Save” button, at this time the user is looking to test our app and see if it fits their needs. We speed that up by&nbsp;automatically enabling the chat button on first save, along with the best default configuration for all chat button related settings.</p><figure id="w-node-4b9a52f7ced2-2f0d8df6"><p><iframe allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/o3oeGyv-JJs"></iframe></p></figure><p>Another example, when a user wants to start sending automated messages, all they have to do is click on the “Enable” button. All the app’s default configuration is automatically applied and the user can start seeing value immediately.</p><figure id="w-node-4bee860d412d-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f004a6e594ffa16384d47ca_automated-message-setup-1.png" alt=""></p></figure><figure id="w-node-8c9743f7a3e0-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f004a858d5f7ceaad74de97_automated-message-setup-2.png" alt=""></p></figure><h3>3- Learning: Care about your users, they can feel it</h3><p>Users are on a mission to achieve their goals. They typically need your help when there’s something that stops them from getting there.</p><p>From day 1, we were clear on providing the best possible support. Our users would be thrilled to see bug fixes deployed in 15 minutes, WhatsApp &amp; email replies in 5 minutes, and so on. We were fast, we were responsive.</p><p>This worked in our favour - users showered us with positive reviews which is how we managed 500+ reviews while staying 5.0 star rated.</p><figure id="w-node-f55f45993a1f-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f004affbd3802acac60056d_superlemon%20whatsapp%20app%20shopify%20reviews.png" alt=""></p></figure><p>But customer support isn’t only about getting reviews. We’ve had users who prefer using our app instead of competitors because</p><p><strong>A-</strong> We reply quickly</p><p><strong>B-</strong> We proactively provide information beyond the immediate premise of the query</p><figure id="w-node-e499fce41f50-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f0065d67e883834a7802cc8_review-users-care.png" alt=""></p><figcaption><em>Your users can feel when you genuinely care about them</em></figcaption></figure><h3>4- Learning: Be smart about managing and reducing support ticket volume</h3><p>The downside of trying to be a customer support hero is, you only have finite hours in the day, and you don’t want to spend most of it replying to customers. </p><p>We took 3 specific initiatives to reduce support tickets.</p><p><strong>1- Embed FAQs within the product</strong></p><p>We found that users would have FAQs around specific features, and they wouldn’t really go to the help center and reference it. To them, it’s simpler to ask for help.</p><p>To solve this problem, we embedded FAQs inside the product itself. </p><p>Here are a few examples where we included the most commonly asked question beside the feature configuration. </p><figure id="w-node-1def5927520e-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f004c97d6c3b3b5f30a4556_faq-inside-product-1.png" alt=""></p></figure><figure id="w-node-11706312cf8a-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f004ca08216b9c33aaef853_faq-inside-product-2.png" alt=""></p></figure><figure id="w-node-9239f016ade1-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f004ca87bc6f87761475470_faq-inside-product-3.png" alt=""></p></figure><p>The results were always immediately noticeable. Where we would get 10 questions a week about X, would drop to 1-2, thereby freeing us up from answering repetitive support questions.</p><p><strong>2- Fix repetitive bugs</strong></p><p>If a bug appears more than thrice in a span of days, the third time is when we go ahead and permanently fix it. Why thrice? That way we don’t overwhelm ourselves with trying to fix every single bug, but only the ones that appear repeatedly and take up support time.</p><p><strong>3- Remove WhatsApp chat support and go with Email only</strong></p><p>During initial days, we found it useful to let our users contact us on WhatsApp. It lead to tons of conversations which shaped our understanding of the user’s needs and how we can better solve them. </p><p>But having WhatsApp as a support channel had 3 issues:</p><p><strong>1-</strong> With time, we discovered that people find dropping a message on WhatsApp to be very low barrier. Which means they wouldn’t take a moment to look around, be patient enough to find out how the issue that they are about to describe has already been solved inside the app. It’s just easier to WhatsApp us.</p><p><strong>2-</strong> We also discovered that users had an unrealistic expectation of quick replies and quick resolutions on WhatsApp. Granted, we would be quick whenever possible. But if it’s 11pm at night and the user asks if a bug is fixed 10 minutes later, it can get a bit annoying.</p><p><strong>3-</strong> I started dreading picking up my phone, seeing it full of support tickets every morning.</p><p>To solve this, we removed the WhatsApp chat button from our own app, and replaced it with an Email support button instead. All 3 problems listed above got resolved to a great degree.</p><figure id="w-node-09f7b09a3b19-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f004d01e45cb8848d6cf0f7_Email%20support%20only.png" alt=""></p></figure><p>We also made numerous smaller tweaks to optimise our support flow. One of the tiny but powerful tweaks was to automatically populate the email subject line with the user’s Shopify store url. That made it so much faster for us to look up the specific user instead of a meaningless back and forth of “what’s your store url”.</p><figure id="w-node-280b459e613d-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f00533cbd380208b160157f_store%20url.jpg" alt=""></p></figure><p>Our efforts have paid off. Unless we’re building new features, we spend only about <strong>15-30 minutes per day</strong> on customer support.<br></p><h3>5- Learning: Say No, often</h3><p>Users ask for all sorts of functionality. It doesn’t mean you should build them. </p><p>Whenever we get feature requests, we add a card in our internal Notion board and judge the card against 3 factors</p><p><strong>1-</strong> how many times do we receive the same request</p><p><strong>2-</strong> does the feature align with the rest of our product</p><p><strong>3-</strong> does the feature add core value to the user</p><p>Many times, we found users requesting features that would save them the hassle of using another app. Now, if that functionality enhances the rest of our app, it’s the right feature to add. But if it doesn’t, then we politely decline.</p><figure id="w-node-2831ff295f9b-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f00517014696c60a040b940_politely%20saying%20no.png" alt=""></p></figure><p>There are 2 types of responses we give to customers regarding feature requests:</p><p><strong>1-</strong> Tell them that this feature isn’t requested by other users that much, and since we are a small team with limited resources, we may not be prioritising this feature in the near future.</p><p><strong>2-</strong> Tell them that this feature is already part of our roadmap, and that we will reach out to them whenever it’s ready. I generally avoid giving timelines, to account for “life happens, plans change”.</p><p>This learning extends beyond just feature requests. </p><p>In the past year, we have received tons of business proposals, partnerships, integration requests, collaborative marketing invitations etc. Saying No allowed us to remain focused on what’s really important.<br></p><h3>6- Mistake: Optimise top of the funnel</h3><p>I was under the impression that during build phase, we shouldn’t focus too much on optimisation. After all, you don’t want to get busy squeezing another 10% when the potential is to 10x. </p><p>In most cases, I think I made the right call. One place I made the wrong call was the user onboarding flow.</p><p>Until March 2020, users would install the app and directly land on the chat settings page, which is the starting point of the user’s journey. We were getting a steady flow of 10-15 paid trials initiated per day. </p><p>Adding a step of friction before this would be counterintuitive, right? It couldn’t possibly increase trials, right?</p><p>Sigh. </p><p>When we added one screen which asked the user upfront whether they want to continue with the Free plan, or start a trial for the Paid plan, daily paid trials DOUBLED overnight, while trial-to-paid conversion rate remained steady at 50%. </p><figure id="w-node-c2d582bcc858-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f004d9fda26a209aa082a72_onboarding%20trial%20doubled.png" alt=""></p></figure><p>The experiment took us a day to build, and after a week we concluded what was clearly the winner.</p><p>I normally advocate for focusing on building vs optimising in the early stages, but in this case I didn’t know that optimisation was waiting to unlock 100% increase in trials.</p><p>My takeaway here is - always keep your eyes open for bottlenecks at the top of funnel. </p><p>If there’s copy on your website, or a specific sign up flow that might be holding you back from getting 2x the users, you need to unblock it early and realise compounded gains over time.<br></p><h3>7- Mistake: Competition will copy, don’t completely ignore them</h3><p>In the past year, we’ve seen competitors copy our app interface, in-app descriptions, button designs, app listing text word-for-word in many cases. Initially we were furious, but instead we kept our head down and focused on customer’s needs. </p><p>Eventually we started ignoring our competitors, which was a mistake. While …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.preetamnath.com/blog/grow-shopify-micro-saas-to-25k-mrr-in-14-months">https://www.preetamnath.com/blog/grow-shopify-micro-saas-to-25k-mrr-in-14-months</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.preetamnath.com/blog/grow-shopify-micro-saas-to-25k-mrr-in-14-months</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23734539</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 20:00:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[De-escalating social media conflict]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 412 | Comments 209 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23734535">thread link</a>) | @npunt
<br/>
July 4, 2020 | https://nickpunt.com/blog/deescalating-social-media/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nickpunt.com/blog/deescalating-social-media/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
    <p>Social media has a conflict problem.</p><p>Spending even a few minutes on public social media can expose us to dozens of people we know little about, talking about things we know little about. In such a public place, any individual's reputation, perspectives, and history are difficult to ascertain, and therefore their words must be taken at face value. Coupled with an almost complete lack of standards for participation in the community and a high degree of variance in knowledge among participants, and the environment naturally skews toward conflict and tribalism.</p><p>One particular effect of this environment is that small misunderstandings, mistakes, or disagreements can unexpectedly explode due to the public nature of discourse and assumptions of bad faith. Meanwhile, very few tools exist to moderate these effects.</p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>This is why it's my belief that <mark>as designed today, social media is out of balance</mark>. It is far easier to escalate than it is to de-escalate, and this is a major problem that companies like Twitter and Facebook need to address.</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>This got me thinking about what particular use cases need de-escalation, and whether there's something simple we can do to test the waters and address these types of problems. </p><h2 id="target-use-case-admitting-mistakes">Target Use Case: Admitting Mistakes</h2><p>One obvious issue is that <strong>people are wrong about a lot of things, but struggle to admit their mistakes</strong>. This is why many cultures have created elaborate norms around face-saving. Unfortunately, social media largely lacks these cultural norms, and even makes the problem worse in three ways:</p><ol><li><strong>No social proof</strong> - Admitting mistakes is quite difficult if nobody else is seen (genuinely) admitting mistakes, as we rely heavily on social proof to sense-make around norms. An escalation-oriented culture means there's less genuine "I was wrong" on social media than there should be.</li><li><strong>No respite</strong> - as the visibility of a mistake travels across social media, the poster is subject to a constant deluge of new readers calling them out, with the combined energy of the outraged far exceeding that of the poster. This prevents them from having the necessary emotional cool-down period to respond thoughtfully.</li><li><strong>Digging in</strong> - when feeling personally attacked, its human nature to prefer to dig in rather than apologize. Social media's escalation-oriented culture plays into this human fallibility.</li></ol><p>Take Twitter as an example environment. If we write something that turns out to be wrong and a pile-on begins, we're going to be swimming upstream fighting it. Our options are:</p><ol><li><strong>Ignore</strong> replies and hopefully let it die out</li><li><strong>Delete</strong> your tweet, posting another tweet saying "I was wrong"</li><li><strong>Reply</strong> to your tweet, posting "I was wrong"</li></ol><p>However, none of these are great. If we ignore<strong><em> </em></strong>replies, the simple amplification effects of likes, replies, retweets, and subtweets leave us exposed and the situation can get out of hand. If we delete and post another, people are unlikely to see our follow-up, as corrections are rarely viral. Similarly, even if we reply, only our viral mistake will be seen in the feed of others. </p><p>Let's also not forget the human tendency to not fully walk back statements, and instead offer unsatisfying explanations that can accidentally further enflame situations. Blaming, justifying, minimizing, or excusing are all self-sabotaging ways that people qualify their apologies to preserve their self-esteem or resolve their own cognitive dissonance, and social media is right there ready to give us this kind of rope to hang ourselves with when we're under assault.</p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>In all these cases, a person's reputation in the minds of others is damaged because <mark>social media engagement engines favor the drama of the mistake over the correction and reconciliation</mark>, which leads few people to see or remember anything other than the mistake.</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>This seems like a perfect use case to design for, so I came up with a little design change I call the Twitter Mea Culpa.</p><h2 id="design-exploration-twitter-mea-culpa">Design Exploration: Twitter Mea Culpa</h2><p>Twitter Mea Culpa is a way for a poster to flag their tweet as a mistake and de-escalate a situation, using the same action menu that deleting a post uses, and the same visual design as flagged tweets:</p><figure><img src="https://nickpunt.com/content/images/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Blue-w-Menu-NoLabel-1.png" alt="" srcset="https://nickpunt.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Blue-w-Menu-NoLabel-1.png 600w, https://nickpunt.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Blue-w-Menu-NoLabel-1.png 1000w, https://nickpunt.com/content/images/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Blue-w-Menu-NoLabel-1.png 1260w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption>Twitter Mea Culpa: flagging a post as a mistake</figcaption></figure><h3 id="clear-language">Clear Language</h3><!--kg-card-begin: html--><figure><a href="https://nickpunt.com/content/images/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Language-1.png"><img src="https://nickpunt.com/content/images/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Language-1.png" alt="" srcset="https://nickpunt.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Language-1.png 600w, https://nickpunt.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Language-1.png 1000w, https://nickpunt.com/content/images/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Language-1.png 1198w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></a><figcaption>Language:<em> @user has indicated they made a mistake in this tweet</em></figcaption></figure><!--kg-card-end: html--><p>I picked this language carefully for several reasons:</p><ol><li>Create separation between the individual and what they say (the specific post), which reduces ego threat.</li><li>Use an active voice to indicate responsibility (<em>I made a mistake</em> not <em>Mistakes were made</em>).</li><li>Indicate the poster was the one who chose to flag the post, not Twitter or any other user, to reduce the impression to other users that the poster was censored.</li><li>State the mistake unequivocally and leaving no room for ambiguity about whether it is actually a mistake, to reduce inauthentic use and self-sabotage.</li><li>Avoid direct use of 'sorry' or 'I apologize' language, because for some people these words are extremely <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-squeaky-wheel/201305/5-reasons-why-some-people-will-never-say-sorry">emotionally challenging</a> to use.</li></ol><h3 id="disable-amplification">Disable Amplification</h3><!--kg-card-begin: html--><figure><a href="https://nickpunt.com/content/images/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Amplification-1.png"><img src="https://nickpunt.com/content/images/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Amplification-1.png" alt="" srcset="https://nickpunt.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Amplification-1.png 600w, https://nickpunt.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Amplification-1.png 1000w, https://nickpunt.com/content/images/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-Amplification-1.png 1262w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></a></figure><!--kg-card-end: html--><p>Much like rules violations, once a user admits a mistake, the Mea Culpa tweet is no longer amplified. This means:</p><ul><li>The tweet is no longer made visible on everyone's home feed</li><li>Users cannot reply, like, or retweet without comment</li><li>Users may retweet <em>with</em> comment, to allow users to amplify the correction (e.g. <em>I thought this wasn't the case, looks like they realized it</em>)</li></ul><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>By admitting a mistake, the poster stops the runaway train of replies and amplifications of their mistake, and the reputation damage that follows. In other words, <mark>Mea Culpas are intentionally designed to favor respectful debate and ability to cool off over maximal information exchange</mark>.</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><figure><img src="https://nickpunt.com/content/images/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-ExampleViolation.png" alt=""><figcaption>How Twitter handles rules violations today; notice the lack of like/reply/retweet counts</figcaption></figure><p>This amplification disabling is how rules violations work today. However admitting a mistake is much more innocuous, so I would recommend that existing replies, retweets, and likes remain accessible, which is not the case with violations. After all, sometimes mistakes can create interesting conversation.</p><h3 id="surface-corrections">Surface Corrections</h3><p>One possible exception to the disable amplification rule is that a Mea Culpa tweet could show up again <em>within the home feeds of users who originally reacted to it</em>. This would basically be like issuing a correction, which would be intended to help limit accidental falsehoods from spreading. </p><figure><img src="https://nickpunt.com/content/images/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-FeedCorrection-1.png" alt="" srcset="https://nickpunt.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-FeedCorrection-1.png 600w, https://nickpunt.com/content/images/2020/07/TwitterMeaCulpa-FeedCorrection-1.png 707w"><figcaption>Mistake correction shown in Home Feed, shown because user liked the tweet</figcaption></figure><p>For instance, if someone tweeted an unsubstantiated rumor and we liked or replied to it, when we go back to our home feed a day or two later we'd see their tweet with the notice that they'd made a mistake.</p><p>This seems like the right thing to do, and a way to help social media stay more focused on truth.</p><h3 id="culture-of-use">Culture of Use</h3><p>Twitter Mea Culpa is meant to solve for a few specific use cases that involve the poster's authentic desire for de-escalation at some level:</p><ol><li><strong>I'm actually wrong </strong>- when the poster knows they are wrong and wants to stop hearing from people and just correct their mistake.</li><li><strong>I'm right if you look at it this way</strong> - when the poster is struggling to understand in what ways or from what perspectives they're wrong, but can tell they are a little bit wrong, and are considering explaining themselves.</li><li><strong>Fine, I give up </strong>- when the poster is struggling to apologize or admit they're wrong, as is often the case when people feel vulnerable or when their ego is bruised, and are starting to think it might be better to tap out than to continue.</li></ol><p>Today, the <em><strong>I'm actually wrong</strong></em><strong> </strong>case is an obvious flaw in the system, where posters have to constantly reply to people saying <em>"yeah, I know, I know, I was wrong, look at my other tweet"</em>. In this case, their reputation is less at risk and they're already at a point of emotional acceptance, so it's simply a matter of unnecessary UX friction.</p><p>The much more interesting and subtle cases are <strong><em>I'm right if you look at it this way</em></strong> and <strong><em>Fine, I give up</em></strong>. Posters in these situations may not yet have the emotional distance to gain proper perspective, still feeling a connection between what they said and who they are (ego threat). As mentioned before, the lack of respite in social media can keep people in this emotional state for a lot longer than they might otherwise be, as each new notification they receive keeps them in a state of alert.</p><p>In these situations, there's an emotional temptation to respond when it's often best not to, given the escalating nature of the medium. The temptation comes from a poster having only one tool at their disposal to repair their reputation: replying to the tweets contributing to their threatened feelings. </p><p>With Mea Culpa, users gain a second tool specifically designed to de-escalate, that only requires their acknowledgement that a) they may be at least partly wrong, and b) they do not wish to continue. When in use, it can cut off potentially escalating conversations early, giving everyone else who sees the tweet the signal to step back because the poster may not have meant it and (at least partially) admits their mistake.</p><p>There is no guarantee that most or all conversations would de-escalate after a Mea Culpa, but in imagining the possible uses for it, I think it would help considerably.</p><h3 id="correcting-for-inauthenticity">Correcting for Inauthenticity</h3><p>Unfortunately, there are also many bad faith actors on social media, and there's potential for any feature to be used in a way that means something other than what was intended, creating a culture of alternate use and meaning. A few anti-patterns may emerge here:</p><ol><li><strong>Growth hacking</strong> - a user posts something intentionally fabulist they want others to see, get a lot of engagement, and then post a mistake tag to try to have people see it again.</li><li><strong>Ironic opposite</strong> - a user flags everything they post as a mistake, either in protest or just as an ironic statement.</li><li><strong>Just kidding </strong>- a user posts something boundary-pushing to float it as an idea, then walks it back with a mistake tag.</li><li><strong>I had to do it </strong>- a user posts something boundary-pushing that they believe, then walks it back with a mistake tag as a …</li></ol></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://nickpunt.com/blog/deescalating-social-media/">https://nickpunt.com/blog/deescalating-social-media/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nickpunt.com/blog/deescalating-social-media/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23734535</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 19:59:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Iran dumps Flight 752 investigator, airspace open to conceal 'imminent' attack]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 95 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23733910">thread link</a>) | @refurb
<br/>
July 4, 2020 | https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/audio-recording-iran-lead-investigator-flight-ps752-1.5636450 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/audio-recording-iran-lead-investigator-flight-ps752-1.5636450">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>A newly released audio recording suggests Iran's highest authorities allowed commercial airliners to fly in and out of Tehran during the period of intense military activity when Flight 752 was shot down — because closing the airspace would have given away the regime's plan to strike U.S. military bases in Iraq.</p><div><figure><div><p><img alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5636477.1593791704!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/plane-crash.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>The head of Iran's investigation into Flight PS752 has been replaced following the release of a recording of a conversation he had with a victim's relation in Canada.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Reuters)</figcaption></figure><p><span><p>A newly released audio recording suggests Iran's highest authorities allowed commercial airliners to fly in and out of Tehran during the period of intense military activity when Flight 752 was shot down — because closing the airspace would have given away the regime's plan to strike U.S. military bases in Iraq.</p>  <p>CBC News obtained a recording of a&nbsp;91-minute conversation that took place March 7&nbsp;between a victim's family member in Canada and Hassan Rezaeifar, who was appointed the head of Iran's investigation into the downing of the Kyiv-bound Ukraine International Airlines aircraft. The crash of Flight 752 killed 176 people, including 57 Canadians.</p>  <p>The recording, which reveals a number of damning details about the downing of the plane and Iran's response, is also in the custody of Canadian authorities.</p>  <p>Less than 24 hours after CBC News emailed Rezaeifar a copy of the recording and requested a response Thursday, news broke that he had been removed from his role overseeing Iran's investigation into the downing of Flight 752. Families in the United Kingdom — which has&nbsp;an embassy in Iran — were notified this morning that a new investigator is now in charge.</p>  <h2>Airspace kept open to avoid signalling&nbsp;attack:&nbsp;Rezaeifar</h2>  <p>In the recording, Rezaeifar said closing the airspace over Tehran could have exposed Iran's pending ballistic missile attack on U.S. air bases in Iraq in advance. That attack was retaliation for the United States' killing of Iran's top military leader,&nbsp;Gen.&nbsp;Qasem Soleimani.</p>  <p>"Some say we should have cleared the airspace," Rezaeifar said in Farsi on the recording. "The National Security Council is in charge.</p>  <p>"But let's say we had cleared the airspace. Wouldn't [it] give away our imminent attack?"</p>  <p>Flight 752 was shot down just four hours after the strike on the U.S. base. Rezaeifar added that&nbsp;closing the airspace could have meant cancelling flights. Iran earns hundreds of thousands of dollars <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/iran-airspace-canadians-downed-flight-1.5481818" target="_blank">daily in fees for allowing flights in its airspace.</a></p>  <p>"Ok, let's assume we had delayed the Ukrainian flight for ten hours. Wouldn't it have cancelled all other flights after?" said Rezaeifar on the call.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5636474.1593790216!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/flight-752-crash.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5636474.1593790216!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/flight-752-crash.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5636474.1593790216!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/flight-752-crash.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5636474.1593790216!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/flight-752-crash.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5636474.1593790216!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/flight-752-crash.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5636474.1593790216!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/flight-752-crash.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Investigators pick up debris at the crash site of the Ukraine International Airlines plane shot down after takeoff from Iran's Imam Khomeini Airport on Jan. 8, 2020. <!-- --> <!-- -->(Nazanin Tabatabaee/WANA via Reuters)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>Thomas Juneau, an associate professor of international affairs at the University of Ottawa and former analyst of&nbsp;Middle East affairs, said Iran has been insisting the investigation will be independent — and the audio recording proves&nbsp;it's not.&nbsp;</p>  <p>"Having the lead investigator saying those things on that phone call really damages that fiction," said Juneau. "By removing him, they're trying to protect that facade."</p>  <h2>Passengers used as human shields, says expert</h2>  <p>Payam Akhavan, a Canadian-Iranian international law professor at McGill University and former UN prosecutor at The Hague, also reviewed CBC's copy of the recording. Akhavan argues the audio is a new piece of evidence showing the highest levels of Iran's government chose to keep planes full of people in the sky on a day of intense military activity.&nbsp;</p>  <p>"The senior leadership of the government willingly and knowingly disregarded these risks," said Akhavan. "This is not just a question of human error or mistake. It's a question of criminal&nbsp;recklessness.</p>  <p>"To knowingly put civilian aircraft in harm's way, to use civilian airliners in effect as human shields, clearly implicates criminal responsibility."</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5421757.1593792034!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/ps752-victims.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5421757.1593792034!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/ps752-victims.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5421757.1593792034!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/ps752-victims.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5421757.1593792034!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/ps752-victims.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5421757.1593792034!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/ps752-victims.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5421757.1593792034!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/ps752-victims.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Dozens of Canadians, as well as students and academics studying in Canada, were killed in the downing of Flight 752.<!-- --> <!-- -->(CBC)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <h2>Crash investigator in immediate contact with military</h2>  <p>Akhavan also said the audio implicates&nbsp;the investigation team in a cover-up.</p>  <p>In the recording,&nbsp;Rezaeifar —&nbsp;who was the head of the accident investigation board at the Iran Civil Aviation Organization at the time — says he&nbsp;picked up the phone five minutes after the plane crashed and was in immediate contact with Iran's military.</p>  <p>Rezaeifar said Amir-Ali Hajizadeh, the commander of the Aerospace Force of the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC), admitted the military was ordered to shoot missiles due to national security concerns.</p>  <p>"I was informed at 6:30 a.m. and I called the IRGC at 6:35 a.m. and asked, 'Did you have a missile attack?'" Rezaeifar says in the recording. "Mr. Hajizadeh explained and said&nbsp;yes, and we had orders. He said there are some national security considerations in the country."</p>  <p>On January 11, Iran's military admitted it unintentionally shot down the plane and blamed human error, saying the military&nbsp;mistook the jetliner for a hostile target. That acknowledgement&nbsp;came after three days of denial and after satellite evidence showed&nbsp;that missiles had hit the aircraft.</p>  <p>Rezaeifar did not respond to CBC's request for a comment. His name is used throughout the audio recording&nbsp;and CBC News has copies of messages sent from his Instagram account setting up the phone call.</p>  <h2>Victim's family member 'intimidated'</h2>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5521619.1585951192!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_300/javad-soleimani.jpeg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5521619.1585951192!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_460/javad-soleimani.jpeg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5521619.1585951192!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_620/javad-soleimani.jpeg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5521619.1585951192!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_780/javad-soleimani.jpeg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5521619.1585951192!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/javad-soleimani.jpeg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5521619.1585951192!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_780/javad-soleimani.jpeg"></p></div><figcaption>Javad Soleimani's wife Elnaz Nabiy died in the destruction of Flight PS752.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Supplied)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>Javad Soleimani (no relation to Gen.&nbsp;Qasem Soleimani) was&nbsp;the Edmonton PhD student on the other end of the call with Rezaeifar. He said&nbsp;Rezaeifar&nbsp;pressured him&nbsp;to remove an&nbsp;Instagram&nbsp;post critical of the Iranian regime. Soleimani has been an outspoken critic of Tehran since his wife Elnaz Nabiy died in the crash.</p>  <p>In that Instagram post, Soleimani wrote Iranians&nbsp;won't forget about the crimes the regime has committed against its own people.</p>  <p>"Please delete it from your Instagram," Rezaeifar tells&nbsp;Soleimani on the call. "Do you agree that out of 83 million people of Iran, only 10 or 12 people have hurt you? Why should those other 82 million people be insulted by this post?"</p>  <p>He then asks Soleimani if he thinks the Canadian government is more "benevolent" toward him.&nbsp;</p>  <p>"Are you certain that the whole Canadian government is good and uncorrupt?" asked Rezaeifar.</p>  <p>Two days later, Soleimani&nbsp;said,&nbsp;Iran's Ministry of Intelligence contacted his family members in Iran to exert more pressure on them about his behaviour on social media.&nbsp;</p>  <ul>   <li> <p><a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/iran-flight-752-ukraine-international-airlines-crash-1.5521377" target="_blank"><strong>Families of Flight 752 victims report threats, acts of intimidation — and blame Tehran</strong></a></p> </li>  </ul>  <p>"It's ridiculous," Soleimani told CBC News. "They just wanted to somehow threaten me to stop criticizing the regime on social media because I had many followers on Instagram.</p>  <p>"They tried to force me to be silent ... but honestly, I have nothing to lose. And I told him,&nbsp;I told him I have nothing to lose,&nbsp;so you cannot stop me by just threatening me by conversation over the phone."</p>  <h2>'Inappropriate' for investigator to pressure&nbsp;family member</h2>  <p>Juneau said it's "totally inappropriate" and "absurd" for the lead crash&nbsp;investigator&nbsp;to put pressure on&nbsp;a victim's family member in Canada. He also said it's not surprising.</p>  <p>"I did not expect the investigation to be independent and few serious analysts did," Juneau said. "This basically confirms it.</p>  <p>"It's not very smart. It's just not a good move."</p>  <p>He said the practice&nbsp;of the Islamic Republic is to exert psychological&nbsp;pressure,&nbsp;and often physical&nbsp;pressure, on anyone opposed to the regime,&nbsp;at home and abroad.</p>  <p>Juneau said he wants to know the extent of Rezaeifar's relationship with the IRGC and Iran's&nbsp;Ministry of Intelligence. He cautions the details of what Rezaeifar said on the recording might not be accurate, and might have been meant to exert pressure on Soleimani.</p>  <p>"Is it true?" said Juneau. "Is he boasting? Is he exaggerating some things to increase the level of intimidation towards family members? These are all questions that we don't know the answer to."</p>  <p>Syrine Khoury, press secretary to&nbsp;Foreign&nbsp;Affairs Minister&nbsp;François-Philippe Champagne, sent a written statement to CBC&nbsp;saying "interference with Canadian citizens is totally unacceptable, very troubling and won't be tolerated.</p>  <p>"The government of Canada denounces any and all attempts to coerce or pressure Canadians, especially those suffering the loss of a loved one," she added. "The government of Canada encourages anyone who feels threatened, unsafe or vulnerable to contact local law enforcement authorities."</p>  <p>Ralph Goodale, Canada's special adviser to the Trudeau government on the&nbsp;Flight 752 file, said the phone call&nbsp;"constitutes outrageous behaviour."</p>  <p>"It's wrong on every count of procedure, propriety, appropriateness. It's simply completely wrong," he said.&nbsp;</p>  <p>He added the International Coordination and Response Group formed by&nbsp;Canada, Ukraine, Sweden, Afghanistan and the United Kingdom to support victims' families will be investigating&nbsp;Rezaeifar's&nbsp;"interesting and provocative" comments about keeping the airspace open to see if there's truth to the remarks.&nbsp;</p>  <h2>Audio casts doubt on past reports</h2>  <p>Hamed Esmaeilion, the interim spokesperson for the association representing the families of the Canadian victims, said the recording raises serious concerns about the two reports Iran's Civil Aviation Organization has already published about Flight 752. Esmaeilion lost his wife, Parisa Eghbalian, and their nine-year-old daughter Reera in the destruction&nbsp;of Flight 752.</p>  <p>"I don't see any different between Rezaeifar and the new investigator," he said. "CAO is not independent. The whole organization is closely working with the IRGC."</p>  <p>Iran is expected to publish another report on the crash&nbsp;before heading to France on July 20 to download and analyze the plane's flight data recorders, according …</p></span></p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/audio-recording-iran-lead-investigator-flight-ps752-1.5636450">https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/audio-recording-iran-lead-investigator-flight-ps752-1.5636450</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/audio-recording-iran-lead-investigator-flight-ps752-1.5636450</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23733910</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 18:10:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Uber wants to cut costs by shifting its engineering to India]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 61 | Comments 101 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23731891">thread link</a>) | @SQL2219
<br/>
July 4, 2020 | https://www.businessinsider.in/business/news/uber-is-struggling-due-to-covid19-now-it-wants-to-cut-costs-by-shifting-its-engineering-to-india/articleshow/76768028.cms | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.businessinsider.in/business/news/uber-is-struggling-due-to-covid19-now-it-wants-to-cut-costs-by-shifting-its-engineering-to-india/articleshow/76768028.cms">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div id="datatxt76768028read"><div data-den="denmark"><div><ul>
 <li><keyword keytype="person" smid="0" usetype="2" keywordseo="Uber-CEO" actualkeyword="Uber CEO">Uber CEO</keyword> Dara Khosrowshahi is eager to shift engineering innovation to India as it will be cheaper for the company, said a report by The Information.</li>
 <li>Globally, Uber lost $2.9 billion in the first three months of the year because of the coronavirus pandemic. </li>
 <li>Khosrowshahi had earlier said that the impact of COVID-19 would be drastic for the company. </li>
</ul><p>Ride hailing giant Uber has been severely impacted by the coronavirus pandemic across the world. Globally, Uber lost 
<a target="_blank" href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/uber-earnings-q1-161-million-loss-ridership-falls-3-percent/" rel="nofollow">$2.9 billion</a> in the first three months of the year because of the coronavirus pandemic. 
</p><p>
And now, in a step to cut costs by shifting its engineering jobs to India, said a report by 
<a target="_blank" href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/uber-ceo-wants-to-shift-more-engineering-jobs-to-india-sparking-internal-debate?shared=53eda2af81f50ffb" rel="nofollow">The Information.</a> According to the report, Uber CEO Dara Khosrowshahi is eager to shift engineering innovation to India as it will be cheaper for the company.
</p><keyword keytype="person" smid="0" usetype="2" keywordseo="Uber-India" actualkeyword="Uber India">Uber India</keyword><p> didn’t comment on the same. 
</p><p>
<span>Advertisement</span></p><hr><p>Khosrowshahi had earlier said that the impact of COVID-19 would be drastic for the company. 
</p><p>
    "I won't sugarcoat it. COVID-19 has had a dramatic impact on rides, with the business down globally around 80% in April,” he 
<a target="_blank" href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/uber-earnings-q1-161-million-loss-ridership-falls-3-percent/" rel="nofollow">said</a> during the conference call for its earnings. 
</p><p>
Earlier, as a part of its massive global layoff of 6,700 employees, Uber India had laid off 600 employees in India. “The impact of Covid-19 and the unpredictable nature of the recovery has left Uber IndiaSA with no choice but to reduce the size of its workforce. Around 600 full time positions across driver and rider support, as well as other functions, are being impacted. These reductions are part of previously announced global job cuts this month,” Pradeep Parameswaran, President, Uber India and South Asia had said during the layoffs in May 2020. 
</p><p><span>Advertisement</span></p><hr><p>However, Uber’s wish to shift its engineering to India is not something new. During his visit to India in 2019, Khosrowshahi had said that India is going to be a big source of innovation for them. “One example is the Uber Lite app, was designed and built in India and moved to over 30 countries around the world,” he had said.
</p><p>
Manik Gupta who was then the Chief Product Officer of Uber had said that Uber is proud of the engineering and product talent based out of Bengaluru and Hyderabad. “We have a goal to double the headcount in these offices and have 1,000 people to build innovative products out of India,” he had said.
</p><p>
    SEE ALSO:
<br>
<a href="https://www.businessinsider.in/business/telecom/news/vodafone-idea-news-how-much-cash-does-vodafone-idea-need-to-survive/articleshow/76766763.cms">Only cash can save Vodafone Idea from a slow death⁠— and it needs a lot of it</a>
<br data-name="47" data-nm1="br"><span>Advertisement</span></p><hr>

<p><a href="https://www.businessinsider.in/business/news/reliance-jio-gets-investment-from-intel-capital/articleshow/76761995.cms">Reliance Jio gets ₹1894.5 crore from Intel Capital – the 12th investment in 11 weeks</a></p></div></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.businessinsider.in/business/news/uber-is-struggling-due-to-covid19-now-it-wants-to-cut-costs-by-shifting-its-engineering-to-india/articleshow/76768028.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23731891</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 12:48:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Targeted MitM attacks using information leakage in SSH clients [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 67 | Comments 82 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23731310">thread link</a>) | @based2
<br/>
July 4, 2020 | https://www.fzi.de/fileadmin/user_upload/2020-06-26-FSA-2020-2.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.fzi.de/fileadmin/user_upload/2020-06-26-FSA-2020-2.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.fzi.de/fileadmin/user_upload/2020-06-26-FSA-2020-2.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23731310</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 10:01:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Learn to Create and Flex Flexagons]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 62 | Comments 13 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23730865">thread link</a>) | @bhy
<br/>
July 4, 2020 | http://loki3.com/flex/explore/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://loki3.com/flex/explore/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          <div>
            
            <h2>Learn to create and flex flexagons</h2>
            
          </div>
          <hr>
          <div>
            <div><p><img src="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/static/pinch-flex.jpg"></p><canvas width="300" height="100"></canvas>
            </div>
          </div>
          <a href="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/pinch-flex.html"><p> Chapter 1: Flexagon Intro </p><p> Exploring the hidden sides of hexaflexagons </p></a>
          <ul>
            <li>Introduces the <em>hexaflexagon</em>, with
              <!-- -->6
              <!-- --> equilateral triangles per side, and the <em>pinch flex</em>, a way of folding a flexagon to
              reveal previously hidden sides</li>
            <li>Let’s you explore how to visit every side of a flexagon</li>
            <li>Describes <em>flex notation</em>, which can be used to precisely describe a sequence of flexes</li>
            <li>Introduces the <em>Tuckerman Traverse</em> <!-- -->as a technique for visiting every side of a flexagon
              using the pinch flex</li>
            <li>Provides both a flexagon simulation and the unfolded strip for all hexaflexagons with
              <!-- -->3
              <!-- -->,
              <!-- -->4
              <!-- -->,
              <!-- -->5
              <!-- -->,
              <!-- -->6
              <!-- -->,
              <!-- -->7
              <!-- -->, and
              <!-- -->8
              <!-- --> sides so you can make your own</li>
            <li>Shows flexagons made up of different shapes of triangles, like using angles of
              <!-- -->3
              <!-- -->0
              <!-- -->-
              <!-- -->6
              <!-- -->0
              <!-- -->-
              <!-- -->9
              <!-- -->0
              <!-- --> or
              <!-- -->5
              <!-- -->4
              <!-- -->-
              <!-- -->5
              <!-- -->4
              <!-- -->-
              <!-- -->7
              <!-- -->2
              <!-- -->, and different numbers of triangles per side, like
              <!-- -->4
              <!-- -->,
              <!-- -->8
              <!-- -->,
              <!-- -->1
              <!-- -->0
              <!-- -->, or
              <!-- -->1
              <!-- -->2</li>
          </ul>
          <hr>
          <div>
            <div>
              <div><p><img src="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/static/F/F1.jpg" width="320" height="240"></p>
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
          <a href="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/flexing.html"><p> Chapter 2: Flexing Flexagons </p><p> A short tour of different ways to flex a flexagon </p></a>
          <ul>
            <li>Describes a naming convention for a wide variety of triangle flexagons, like <em>pentaflexagon</em>
              <!-- -->and <em>silver octaflexagon</em></li>
            <li>Defines a <em>minimal flexagon</em> <!-- -->as the simplest flexagon that supports a given flex</li>
            <li>Demonstrates a sampling of interesting flexes on triangle flexagons: the pyramid shuffle, flip flex,
              tuck flex, v-flex, and silver tetra flex</li>
            <li>Shows that once you generalize the types of flexes you use, the concept of “sides” of a flexagon is no
              longer sufficient for understanding all the states you can explore</li>
          </ul>
          <hr>
          
          <a href="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/generators.html"><p> Chapter 3: Generating Sequences </p><p> Creating flexagons with flex sequences </p></a>
          <ul>
            <li>Summarizes the <em>flex notation</em> <!-- -->that was previously introduced for describing sequences of
              flexes</li>
            <li>Defines a <em>generating sequence</em> <!-- -->as a sequence of flexes used to create the structure
              necessary for performing them on a given flexagon</li>
            <li>Shows how different flexes move you around a pinch flex diagram</li>
            <li>Gives you an interactive tool for typing in generating sequences to see what pinch flex diagram is
              generated</li>
            <li>Allows you to type in generating sequences consisting of any of the flexes introduced so far on a wide
              variety of triangle flexagons, giving you the unfolded strip that can be used to construct a working
              flexagon</li>
          </ul>
          <hr>
          <div>
            <div>
              <div><p><img src="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/static/P4-4-4/1.jpg" width="320" height="240"></p>
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
          <a href="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/pinch-variations.html"><p> Chapter 4: Pinch Flex Variations </p><p> Relatives of the pinch flex on different flexagons </p></a>
          <ul>
            <li>Describes a class of flexes that are related to the standard pinch flex</li>
            <li>Shows the minimal flexagon for a variety of flexes (e.g. P
              <!-- -->3
              <!-- -->3
              <!-- -->4
              <!-- --> and P
              <!-- -->3
              <!-- -->3
              <!-- -->3
              <!-- -->3
              <!-- -->) on several flexagons (e.g. the enneaflexagon and decaflexagon)</li>
            <li>Demonstrates generating sequences using these flexes to create interesting flexagons</li>
          </ul>
          <hr>
          <div>
            <p><img src="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/static/slot-example.jpg"></p>
            </div>
            <a href="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/slot-flexes.html"><p> Chapter 5: Slot Flexes </p><p> Flexes that involve sliding leaves through slots </p></a>
            <ul>
              <li>Describes a class of flexes called <em>slot flexes</em></li>
              <li>Demonstrates the related flexes called the <em>slot half</em> <!-- -->and <em>slot pocket</em></li>
              <li>Shows four <em>slot tuck flex</em> <!-- -->variants</li>
              <li>Finishes with the <em>slot triple pocket flex</em> <!-- -->on a pentaflexagon</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>
            <div>
              <p><em>pre</em>:
                <code>[[[1,2],3], 4, 5, [6,7], 8, 9]</code><br><em>post</em>:
                <code>[2, 4, 5, [6,7], 8, [-1,[9,-3]]]</code></p>
            </div>
            <a href="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/new-flexes.html"><p> Chapter 6: New flexes </p><p> How to define flexes with pat notation </p></a>
            <ul>
              <li>Describes using <em>pat notation</em> <!-- -->for the internal structure of a flexagon</li>
              <li>Shows how to define what a flex does by using pat notation to enumerate a flexagon’s structure before
                and after a flex</li>
              <li>Demonstrates using a flex definition to predict where you can do a flex and to predict exactly how a
                flexagon will change if you do the flex</li>
              <li>Provides definitions of the flexes discussed so far for hexaflexagons</li>
              <li>Lists additional details you need to fully understand when a flex can be performed</li>
              <li>Walks through an example of how to define a new flex and how to add it to the flexagon simulator</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>
            <div>
              <div>
                <ul>
                  <li><code>I ~= (Sh&gt;&gt;T'&gt;^T&lt;&lt;^) 2</code></li>
                  <li><code>I ~= (Ltb&gt;P&gt;P&gt;) 12</code></li>
                  <li><code>P ~= T&gt;&gt;&gt;V&gt;&gt;&gt;</code> so
                    <code>T' ~= &gt;&gt;&gt;V&gt;&gt;&gt;^P^</code></li>
                </ul>
              </div>
            </div>
            <a href="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/flex-sequences.html"><p> Chapter 7: Flex Sequences </p><p> Cycles, traversals, primes, and equalities </p></a>
            <ul>
              <li>Tools for finding cycles, flex sequences that end where they begin</li>
              <li>Examples of traversals, cycles that visit every state of a flexagon</li>
              <li><em>Prime flexes</em> <!-- -->that can’t be replaced by other flexes</li>
              <li>Sequences of flexes that are equal or almost equal to each other</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>
            <a href="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/playground.html"><p> Appendix: Flexagon Playground </p><p> General tools for exploring flexagons </p></a>
            <ul>
              <li>Tools for creating new flexagons from generating sequences or scripts and exploring them using a
                variety of flexes</li>
              <li>Get the unfolded strip for any of your creations so you can try out the physical version</li>
              <li>An explorer that can find all the states accessible with a specified set of flexes from any flexagon
              </li>
            </ul>
            <hr>
            <a href="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/flex-compendium.html"><p> Appendix: Flex Compendium </p><p> Details about flexes on triangle flexagons </p></a>
            <ul>
              <li>Reference guide to a wide variety of flexes on triangle flexagons</li>
              <li>Shows sample slides and sample strips to fold on various triangle flexagons</li>
              <li>Shows flex definitions in pat notation, etc.</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>
            <a href="http://loki3.com/flex/explore/references.html"><p> Flexagon References </p><p> Sources for additional flexagon information </p></a>
            <ul>
              <li>Bibliography for papers and publications</li>
              <li>Additional references</li>
            </ul>
            <hr>
            <p>For additional information, see <a href="http://loki3.com/flex/">loki3.com</a>.</p>
          </div><div>
              <p>Copyright © 2018-2019 Scott Sherman</p>
            </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://loki3.com/flex/explore/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23730865</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 07:57:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A look at the Gemini protocol: a brutally simple alternative to the web]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 376 | Comments 304 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23730408">thread link</a>) | @flatlanderwoman
<br/>
July 3, 2020 | https://toffelblog.xyz/blog/gemini-overview/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://toffelblog.xyz/blog/gemini-overview/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<article>

<p>Published on <b>2020-06-18</b></p>
<p>I have really come to hate the World Wide Web. It is bloated at every level! Websites themselves are doubling in size at an alarming rate. The web standards are expanding at an alarming rate. Trying to build a web browser that works with the modern web from scratch, would take the manpower equivalent to the Snowy Mountains Scheme or the Manhattan Project (no hyperbole).</p>
<p>The state of the web has lead me to only one conclusion: It is broken beyond repair.</p>
<p>I don't think the web can replaced, but we can still look for simpler (open standards) alternatives to move our works to. Gemini is one of these alternatives that I have taken interest in recently. A fairly recent protocol, created in 2019, Gemini defines a markdown-inspired document format, and it's own protocol to serve these documents, or other files.</p>
<p>If you a looking for a 1:1 clone for the early web, you will probably be disappointed. Gemini takes way more design hints from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gopher_(protocol)">Gopher</a> then it ever will from the web. Gopher (widely considered a predecessor to the web) is built on the idea of text only documents. Gemini expands on this idea by offering basic formatting, and fixing drawbacks unaccounted for in the original Gopher protocol.</p>
<p>Gemini shys away from many standard features of the web. Although there may be plenty of benefits that one accustomed to web wouldn't be able to identify. For example the lack of styling sheets may mean that Gemini sites look plain, however this allows your readers to decide on a colour scheme which suits them best. A night reader would prefer a dark theme, someone with a vision impairment will prefer high contrast, the list goes on.</p>
<p>Gemini offers no in-line image support no client-side scripting (such as Javascript). But server-side scripting (CGI) can work, so you could expect Gemini to be a valid interface for some online services.</p>
<p>The Gemini transport protocol is unsuitable for the transfer of large files, since it misses many features that protocols such as FTP or HTTP use to recover from network instability.</p>
<p>The internet protocols of old aren't encrypted by default, since security wasn't seen as being important back in the late-80's/early-90's. Thankfully Gemini, being a recent protocol, mandates the use of TLS. There is no unencrypted version of Gemini available.</p>
<p>I could totally see Gemini being used as an alternative particularly for the non-commercial individuals who use text as a primary medium. Blogs, poems, recipes, tutorials are perfect for the Gemini format. There are always ways around the lack of media functionality, since although Gemini lacks in-line images, you can still use in-line links to images. As time goes on I could imagine some Gemini browsers providing a fancy image viewer for links to images.</p>
<p>Now, what does Gemini currently have to offer? The best way to find out is to head over to the official site: <code>gemini.circumlunar.space</code> in your Gemini browser. Here you can find two search engines dedicated to finding pages based on what you search for. And two aggregators which acts as a news feed of Gemini posts.</p>
<p>Personally I enjoy scrolling through the aggregators and seeing what people are blogging about, I find interesting stuff frequently.</p>
<p>From a server management perspective, Gemini is just a diet-Web. You buy a domain name (using the web), obtain or rent a server, install a Gemini server, and start serving your site. In order to post to Gemini you either need to self-host, or take advantage of Gemini hosting which is currently on offer by circumlunar.space. No fancy P2P or Blockchain solution here, just a good old client/server model.</p>
<p>I will no doubt keep an eye on Gemini, and serving my blog posts to Gemini should be easy since they are already in markdown. No promises yet though.</p>
<p>I will leave you with the following quote and some interesting links I found.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"When I picture it in my head I think of the early web as more of a library. Over time it has transitioned into a shopping mall." - chris_f (Hacker News comments)</p>
</blockquote>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://gemini.circumlunar.space/">(www) Project Gemini</a> - The official website for the Gemini project. FAQ is recommended reading. (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23042424">hn thread</a>)</li>
<li><a href="gemini://gemini.circumlunar.space/">(gmi) Project Gemini</a> - The defacto Gemini main page.</li>
<li><a href="gemini://gemini.circumlunar.space/software/">(gmi) Gemini software</a> - The official page on Gemini lists out some clients and servers.</li>
<li><a href="gemini://gempaper.strangled.net/mirrorlist/">(gmi) List of services with a gemini mirror</a> - Includes Wikipedia, YouTube and Lobste.rs.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://portal.mozz.us/gemini/gemini.circumlunar.space/">portal.mozz.us</a> - A Gemini gateway for Web users.</li>
<li><a href="https://sr.ht/~julienxx/Castor/">Castor</a> - A browser for Gemini, Gopher and Finger. Written in Rust and GTK. Still early days, but probably the most normie friendly. (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23161922">hn thread</a>)</li>
<li><a href="https://framagit.org/waweic/gemini-client">Android</a> - Barebones Android client.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.marmaladefoo.com/pages/geminaut">GemiNaut</a> - GUI client for Windows users.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/makeworld-the-better-one/md2gemini">md2gemini</a> - Python library that converts markdown to gemini.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23730408">Comments on Hacker News</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/coding/comments/hl6qfv/a_look_at_the_gemini_protocol_a_brutally_simple/">Comments on reddit r/coding</a></p>

</article>

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://toffelblog.xyz/blog/gemini-overview/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23730408</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 05:44:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Closos: Specification of a Lisp operating system (2013) [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 82 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23730107">thread link</a>) | @ska80
<br/>
July 3, 2020 | http://metamodular.com/closos.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://metamodular.com/closos.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>û¨&lt;“
endstream
endobj
20 0 obj
&lt;&lt;
/Length 662       
/Filter /FlateDecode
&gt;&gt;
stream
xÚåVMSÛ0½çWø(l´ú´Ž|=@§¸'Úƒ“ˆÄƒ±SÛaÊ¿ïÊ²ÓJÓ2Ó“eKZï{zoW,ZD,:�d“½Ð°Ä2Qv–¤ZGdb…ˆ²ytEŠ;ú5û°wÂíöJÁÒDp��úE‡çÙñyvé—NØðƒ½Û{âq£Ò°UÑØrFNófš/�E
dV—¥›uE]Ñ˜ƒ5)á&amp;d±›/è„ˆb‰’vˆ—���&amp;gå†tM�A™¯‡€B’ÐX1öÞÛdGWÈ‚Ð„S fw†=$ˆ}ôü¸&amp;î–�ËçÈŒ²Øœƒàã9Ô
�¥¶o¶"&lt;ý%f5BäÓ²žæe@·¶¡j-ßËy?þÈs£E¸L„Õ�,w¸t3ŠÐoVH�º¨(²ÒÕ
#Yj‰€çºNo\—ÑTŒÒZVÅ·õÀo�Ó¤jWEã¥Mý’û0&gt;þä_..114û¿gþšç@Å“¦ÒS=�êñçhÎÖFúz„¤—õ"n»KÔzÃÏ&amp;d9±½o;w‹[¹…×Ñ‘P/Ð‘	&nbsp;MÐÑ‘»+fCåž7Ø/0a×ød%€"òÙ"2ÿwé–¨Žß«ÌüTYÑ+ì†ò”¸®
*yÿÔÀK$+ÿDÖXô�Šö&amp;0ÔËÓSæå©Ì›�÷
†–ü¡¡U�X¥øŽ¡…ÁoCc8CÂ€+²¿
-ÁUst¶w2×À‰TÁÉ»¥�í6—}l&nbsp;Ü’Ïíx—ËÛ&gt;‚VÊùìkÜ¾¯F§äSñ'Võ}ÉÆ|8ËºŸ˜­o]åÏ´Ÿ¯}÷Ëü�¦ßc5#ÍZš—ÙƒbZõ¢ÉWK_Xï=•Iëc=dÿ¬š»ï¾MX©‰b;¿ŸÇÙäi€{
endstream
endobj
25 0 obj
&lt;&lt;
/Length 1006      
/Filter /FlateDecode
&gt;&gt;
stream
xÚ�VI¯ä4¾¿_‘£#ÑÁKœEœ1h0HÓ$†ƒ_âî¥ãVìL3ÿž*—“×óÔ#qr-®ª¯WÂ³sÆ³Ÿx:¿;&gt;}ýFÕ™äEUI�OYÛR¨Ls^´ZdÇ&gt;û‹}?˜k°K~Pºd"ÿûøXñL–EÝÔ­xvÐM¡DMoç\¶,,.?ÀÙ¯]ÝœìÚL”…*+™ìªª�M²…ÈBpÎþL€xUÅ5ûyôW¢žœÙÅ„q&gt;“ÌòÁ^È`ôIT™€$x»!TeÁyK‘¾Íe#’W¤ÞÁ)ë¯({Ÿ¼"ý�kŽ·ß½'þä$8ó@f.l	pI�@Äsv�ˆVŸ(²Á.Ä¸ÏÃpD*T¡Ë„tK­T’…X¤&nbsp;#hÙ0;û¤st&gt;“˜˜Û2†`gbÆt¦¤�Â¤ÌöV$ÎÃë`·&lt;ºuêD0tœ]º˜Mÿ(�0ÄºÊ²�@â¼�Nù¡ŽHD®„foòF1¬.^�Jq]JØù$q§í
©ž@tëR"|&lt;�ª·öÅÐÉÄLÞ%*�r©®ÿ£#ºÚŠ¤k¶zë7™%"”#á§ð&gt;æØqºB@?Ž‹›#èšR˜äa‘“›IA÷åòd:K/ckœ€ )¶Õât&nbsp;2¢V•ÆD–ôôæžDIW¥Ô¡¬ª._ÔÉo@·˜9Õ¦t»ˆÚ?ðùÅâ›JÊ‚ërß*ÕÊÔpÕŠ‡
/ù–Ý&gt;c½wÎ»K¢ÆÞšäÆ%Ç7Z: 1$Ø&amp;éËcÛ9ŠhÆ9åÿ¨h¤%‡²ûCB¦?p¥ì²O
O‹»eÿ}ÚwÀ½Ò(£ÊylŽnR�AŒ°°"tgíä€œŠYî†�pßç|ÿð•¬[¬	¶/¾°ÖË¦¨J½­u™Öúo‹{ž$ÍÂmÄÕƒûû.»}›§5®t&amp;|‹´|YãPîÝ3}2¤fÇ8¤µÆÖtöˆÁ-‡•¼•üÞ›(³hÁkôv]rxO.‡òuHYÿðSrØÌà3TÈí#ù‹‹^5ŒV:¶6êdð™ª=Å¸aIòº‰h»¥³X"z»¤)îI@s�Ôï¿¾ý“¨Û0nÍ�,ÒÆ?jëþUPœ–±&lt;½qˆ¶æw±Új
ÂÎ]®+,Ol\&gt;huYBƒ7¶ðQ¼í¢¹ÇP2˜žî:h'.Ÿîá¦éñ3M8s0°}¿`S"ã¯°Ø¾!:ìŸœÓ;
Ä%¶µñ#ç
lÁg¤&amp;KbwX=JpA&amp;«ûý…%)+vŒŸ§ÁMi¹ìý¯*�,dÙÀöªU¥IýìÊÇ§ÿ-¢|
endstream
endobj
31 0 obj
&lt;&lt;
/Length 2378      
/Filter /FlateDecode
&gt;&gt;
stream
xÚ�É’Û¸õî¯Ð‘ªiÑ$¸çæ8žÄ©ÏÔ”\•ªLh’XÃEC�îî|}ÞŠTÓv’Þ{Á·/vç]°ûë›?ß¼ý1LwaàAîŽ§]øyšîÒ0ö‹(Ú«Ý?=µÿ×ñïoTÅò&nbsp;
R_…p
yÿ·w¿?üº?D‘òBÈ²Èûøéøë^eÞÏùüþøñçOxÍ›@þ}ÿãƒ\xˆ?Kr¾v¼Ôvˆ“À»ýccÚÀ²è†Éå`ôØr¨?ñúùÓÇÞ´?„ž5c·Ïú®4×qý•f1£x%f^øq‘;9¯Ã&gt;	½~�w d¬å¯ÖÂDÊÏ²Â}„ê(2ï3Ñèálð#U)_eÙîF~|Z_¯M]ê±î;Pg{O{•{Ú
2ÔãhdÇö¼Ž=2TË
ÚÚŽ(8¢("}`¾àefÐ�ZÝ4f`t|tkAÉQ¦&lt;£K&lt;|!^ƒ5“t¡J¼§K-‡tÇ@íÖÑ2Ðã©'¡êªPs„Ø«.��º	¼ãÅX#ä™3uãL~ŠNÕOMÅ›eß¶H™KNf´CU¢ÕƒÈ{ÄS/_4"_ö¡W£‹tg&amp;÷�œ]Y!Xñ²7šçQ&nbsp;ž7ILú~¯ÓÈD;‚sÂZFOý Ww=8â°¥Öµí‹„~€+ÜT�ŽRˆ®#Å[3^`ä¨˜@V�•5’{S·ºŒô¦åãYkPö†¼¤ˆ· 
ó¥/_ë+ùý–×«rFêNêN¸Òâì1E˜¬¶æ�É@,¢%Cñª�mÏàB#–)·p¤D'©äèfü‰ŸÇ¯ØoênS„(ñ‹T-7Žrï�u?&nbsp;e$7ºWÂ£yÖíµq2€ZO† ±Å¡Ÿ‡áZpŽMq’*	Ðµ¸†iÁ¡\qŒ†œÂ@IË$
‘ÈÃhoèi¯šÊ=›n–ï™yòˆµ‘©ú»R9µ�^·ô· 	(F¢DÜ
Væ	€–åèÎl@aæ’uÊHRÉÕ´1�ÊØúÜ™
~ˆå$	gÇ‡Íù»Ì?»èj#òQà,w©‘B˜*Õ
Ö
`£†ÚbùJ(^Eþ‡KÿóÀÂÙAÆÇfË‹ÂÔ/n‡P´e|›§³é 1ß¸'È“ìEa—ªøµ9¾Î,8s^,\¿ü¯y�£y�Ã¯ˆp×¼"aìŒ�è·ùR�(Ô-&amp;ÍÝÿÆ&amp;ünXË~¬”TU(¿ÈÔZMì&nbsp;�;Gt±	ð~Qv.LÇ �›æÄßñ‡¬ð3°Šó‡¡?�6Scî‡yºÆ~ƒÄ„UùA"ýÖ‘ÙÅÐo¡šlo"ÈCRæaC‚&nbsp;[Ð´åD&nbsp;Pý€O‡©cB/kUW¼Åˆ)Xs¨ˆ˜xKwR0iMÛ/‡­¤ÐêNŸ
¥
ø;Ú$ÀÒ#*ð§Ÿ&gt;K #…äC@?ZNþˆ°5ù‘À7·FK~"””ò:ú¹Õû•R!g”úIò8‚{îÐ)xK˜Æ©y$gƒC˜lpëz!²Ô6”p
«nÌ|\É°]Å!´^.xº˜¯•î&nbsp;ÃÍbT¹Í`Üøî¬ o�JZ`Çq‘±[ ™|Ä4
¨?Ï!�îó“=±}3ËM}umçÿK¿�„®„ß›ÝHëj‹ùA%Þ2PÖu8Ïý$�Çû5³*ñ*TfÿÆë'èä±™ïƒæ"€ñ"I©xýÉÜ/ãöË¸r !T�’]£ÔÏâ»Në
dâÀÝÂ­“í¡ÍÁý¿µ·°m¯xX£§Ùy‡{c Tµå”Ô[Ý<puàî)•Î0à†ß]tâgØ"�ûá÷‡mŸrÕš›(ðÌéqv\@+uk6*ñÊÛ�àÊî�àxÿÙùÀ½¨d‡èj ]="" ¯?×snÁŸ¹ž¡nšÉr‹Ê-Åëxæ^¶ëªm="" ª�s·àaxtd¢ÄöÉç="" ,éÊ9o˜áË="" Ýx="">Ã©€r†[÷*BÊÍ—‚dN¯Ã0]a´ÚTwÛß²(XP�¡Nä-=OŠL‰*$H¢a44·:¾J;òM§è#Š=wÜA$ø»ÆV‚lp9‹¥@1M¯©^ ,"öŒ	£7ËÊ,i‰ÃÌûe6‡\7GœÜGß7”bŸ�&nbsp;�üZwç	2ü&amp;“vZö‰ÎßJñ�ø?e/1	°ëF|ò60/.©OŒƒþ^f—Gß¼]ÁeFœ&gt;å0„s�Ü;0bžM9ñ��¾Û}GŠgê¡yaŠ;üŽ²Õxß}½l&gt;[îP
®ùË
@›‡Ë8�‹ùm$vã/…uº�Å%µØüD‘¹±ù '‚Â�$?á)“Úƒ�®{5Á‚˜nNB~{ÈÜÛÉÚê
B3ñDÓèº{$Š¢»ž0J¡Æl]d®™
³o¾,1è
Š«~øîk51†¹gF*=j†`šŸ¤œ[Ü…mC™¬aÆ~Lö‚Qw»PŸ®ëf°ï}-ÙY4Bœ‘Í8gÆÈY'ÉŸpØï€LF�SJãqÊÏ-Ãd*Xùåc$žf”aNÄ,F"ÄØú¹X¤B¶ñ•¬«¶Üœº½&lt;]°�Ø-ˆ@/×¼ü›Þâr	`®z°Ž(»wGx…á¢–næÖèl„fã¸ßb�l±É¹´?Y™]Š{Qázì1‚ÔûD
"î»æ…ÏR{DÆsÐÔ¡pÙ[Y™C9ÄTZÖ·CÔM¦Ì@O[ø~tâ•;¶&nbsp;àu0ã@6G#…÷ˆoL¸Aï}Xêä{(r=CÒÀ�IK&amp;œ†¾•C¼ØþD¯\³ÙÛ›î¢˜�YQÊ“œP;C m~óPÞ—Ú&lt;=ð»œøn©'~ÓSâk˜g�¹sï'0U¶Z®Z¸?`·l‹¯B’ëJÌV±Ùœù©*@Ö¡ÊE9¸šKDšQkÀ`õHœo™@–ˆ¯&nbsp;.iß%Eÿ›	ë Éª�vú¿2Ö»NXF’¼¬u³Õb§èa˜{z©®xÐx5Žþ&lt;³Þ•…\ÊBäÞš(Sß×š¤î3„è·v«S•Å^‰k@ïn–¡í�~‘¨•·/N ÿÑë2&lt;³&amp;ÙÜù2¦å\S?z¨�&nbsp;Ò($ýÝõÝŸ°×ÀA;Ë­Žoþù2¥&gt;
endstream
endobj
36 0 obj
&lt;&lt;
/Length 2370      
/Filter /FlateDecode
&gt;&gt;
stream
xÚuXYsã6~÷¯Ð#U5æx=n²“Œ·’Lv­ªl*ÉDBË&lt;öxýöJ²9/Ðh�&gt;¿f´9n¢Í�wßíî&gt;þ…ET¨Íî°)Š0Vz“*ZovÕæ�@…q¸½Ï2üº½WÁ¶q|ùî§O??nïµŽƒß¶*Ø}æÉ§ÿ&gt;&lt;î~ù‘g�¿?î�ï¯Ý¿&gt;þ&nbsp;Òë›tjBSd ]¢‘ç.É6°;ã8�AfIÎL¶Ã»_·÷F%A?TnÁÒîé[7Õ­qÉFIdGf«;þŸNŽî«mÏ�cÎþpY%!�º2ÖE˜Å^Æiè‡Õ·Äa¦”g+QÈ“­;C½½¼«ð€Í}œÅ¡Ñjs¯t˜˜‚wnœ›	8Í’Á¿å¿²oÏód§ºï˜P¹óNÁG¦Ô²2Îû‰Þã—-°XÒšpùý,P�8Œƒ=œ˜nB~Úé\GâF·rÒ^­2’Š¤è;à„ÿiÄ…”¤G†§W
XÌè,x S‚FéÊj.ëîÈœ–OèÜËÍyÐƒ›uè�Ž÷òrkÅ'pÓàþžëÁ]Ëœ°È=H2°S®­U0õÌ°gÅò¤íiVÕxóŸ‘6 …«pzK†`LpÔ4L_ökÍ³?‚
›±çÑ‰¤}ÞòùHÁu…«zÞ&amp;‰8ùd�~÷têçã	=='½ñl‡©.çÆP¡5ý*K&nbsp;T8ÿ¹®üÁì³ÚÜøl…q¾øöøÚÝó{üÂ�ÅËÓ°Mh¬þûàJ¤q¨ã%&nbsp;['&amp;ïê±UÆ©×ë„Ò½à"º¬$(òq°íø§hÓ'vXª'þg�
¯<sv” ù0¨[1(¿dºvƒóÅáÜð±ì»qnÙ="" øoú†="" ã4Ìå4ct†Þ£â8ŒÉ‹(™�¸ùßv2çcì›ø@ì÷£À¾i="" 1¬="" ÚÌnËúoûq(“û*#vËÝ?Ée½lèÅÓ{¹k|'‡Êüvè�="" ¥+Ý“="" 89%ÍÉ¦^k¥g^¨g¿âfÑ1’¬°œŽÄšbô(‹r™„ì`&€ŽspÖÒor¿&;¿Ø#0 ëc‡¾Žõ±íhxa‡Á="" É8e?Áÿ%¸qâŸ“Ës€ä�akš(æîÐÓl�²“cbçp55yòëš¨ÕìÄÄ½˜ó$„¦nkº="" '¶ªÒ1™ílka¢ô="" $÷µf…"…ë€ffô~³¯Š,1Çf¹8¨¹8(¦¡÷©ñ�4*a%e¤jv²tc_2o³€*b­Ì%@öâˆÃ“ã�”Éƒ~?a5="" ŸÅ©¤aaè‹ýam="" •3�—f‡‰©œ‡zz]Ç¡ÎrÏmá“Ÿ)±+="" r@e�¤^¨°�cÞÕžÏm]jüÆy†¾Å‘ybžÕ="" ¶i^™="" Œ,¶,!#3ßeu)="" ‡w’idlÜbeÆbÁ™¬œuàÖ²p][ñÀ+aÁ’ÂpéÐy="" eÒ6Þus�*Ñ]:8f°~0:Éº¶h ¬miëÈòÔüÆœ´s.‘ëäÏ!û¼½Ò="" zæŠ…šÎõuˆàagÒh‰5xäõªcsñxðóbrgnpú@ñ4ŠÆ·Œ–i7®j�­§="" m’|…n·Ý·c¿ßwòÕòk¿�-[="" h£="" Ý„¹Ê="" °�…Š¨Åi šx“…ú!i¶Ôaá‘³z�<t—›$daƒ\”&ìkyy…Š”k�vœvqy°dÇ}#Á¤rh±¾i:¤Ò4¾˜—&="" ×¿8ua1="" àúžt39á¢="" €ÿÊn3�*‚z•œxtrfp$€¼öv'û"·_kí±«§¹rk¶å¼l®Ý³8ÿ‘µç¤È="" 6Ó&'w¬é¦ëª¿l<ØzÀ| m� ;j*g*ßî(­@‡son;äp–eqkysoÑšn‚Ý‰ð—Š�n1xãÙž|›Ž�cùˆ="" ‚ÿèþ†›†�="" ÐhË~|ä!Ëkgúˆ#†Á•="fÞ•«ëÛa" „úÚ;®1j�}="" ö2¿¡poäj�™="" oœg!_l¡s©›š(økËz²n®ãfci›·yneh¸ä'd‘Î{w¤¾¨a#ôo8¤+ß¤h^atÃcfßÿôåñË#�'ûd‰yä)å›t’æ›Û�Ó©fï]ú:¯j="ÞCîˆ¸ï!RñÜ7Š“ÇÎð”KÍÈM“ï¤D½Ê«×/³?3}±¢“Un" Ù¹tÖŠd9\]Ô="" lh6="" ªv’Ä˜Üà!&="" Ót]="">bÄð­Âçbe(·pÆ	�¹¤òeŸ‰¸Ç¢×ò&amp;¦ñ"„nŒ�þÄ íÈÒ½ä@óÀUºOé,¥¾J^Ã9y¦Eî‘Ë	„F¤cé·&lt;Õå6�ØAÉ“+ÉÁ
ä¶5lea”.Ž¼Î&nbsp;×
"’õƒË'€Þ¢$ÌRý¦Rƒ“Öxui—–œÛ2öžv¶uÍëêuf:]{"¤¶�¼rå5	è'/üfo¯ˆUK—+jZS�sm.šáGkè ¡©¿©Ú;�{ß\T„*1ßzÊ*454ÚË¨ÅBœÈ2*&amp;K®:µÌ—A"w²eo©=	KïY¨'c$˜l	\#b�øt†tãÍç·O»»¿ïð{V´Qþ“&nbsp;ŠsÒÙ¦lïþø+ÚT°Ù"Ôà¡/ÄÙn”’¢9›ÍãÝ¿ùû¢É6	 €à¨eÐÔ€À,YœÜ`£�ÀvCªe"2É£â¢uªjÏ5tcäö·ý“os#ì›ñ‰�&amp;x°…j	:}Áy¾¤V˜�
Î¥ÀGi?5Érël÷®n7ÍõU¯’Ë9‚àœ™À'7z¾]ç�Œ‰Ò0É1œÀyãåFLÜoJJ5òEÍøŠe¡•Èx‚nÒ¤€—Áç-ÊÏáÏâÉH$9R&gt;žOJ±y–[‘Ë?½¹—vÔB}8é�¿pâ–Þï^¿†öW/üÇÏÿÄÂ_óôž”ùPH%§¬¥Ÿt
œ
4ö3šœI{‚õ¤q˜±Æayá7£—#MJ°-è¬&nbsp;êš˜Å34õ©Š`I$_�^w%~\�K¨á¦ƒÝÚ3š"¼‰¦·ÿ]ÿl€W
endstream
endobj
43 0 obj
&lt;&lt;
/Length 2250      
/Filter /FlateDecode
&gt;&gt;
stream
xÚ�Ù’ã¶ñ}¾B�TÕ
C&lt;ý¶&gt;6ÞT²v¼rÅUŽ+…•0#Öò�	pfå¯w7ºAQc®]É4�¾»Átó¸I7»ûrwÿF™Š:­åfÿ°)SQÅ¦�™¨µÞì�›Ÿ“lûËþï÷oT½DTi!”2å«o_¿ÿæ‡íNk•H±Ý•¥NÞ¾Ûÿ°UeòÝ×?~µûÝ;$s—òÝ//Þ1Á�NE™WDö0ô®9ÚÑ·;U—‰¡ái›ç‰qžVMw‡­ª—Ùn+Ûã”÷‡žÆÿ¤:7~žg­¥¹»8o;Lg:M¾ðè3Ò³Oá;¾±Ò.dü¡ã“fò§at¤žLmJQ—i�F¹�õF‹:¯IEX/„f¼�,Ež²ÐöÓ¹5M·ªªNº!ÈY‚8§íN&amp;MÿèhmFd£¬’~ð&lt;1~MÛ^hyjìhÆ
qjðìTcZTåÉk¢B;v!Ó…a|4}ó›ñ
(øËí¤yÆB�ê‘Ëdp˜ÊP%=Ž0çTò¡AZ¸3Œ`Hš~‡¬GÎžƒÑlO;½é,Z¢ÖUòoà)ˆlý‰Nèˆv…ÃÔ¡¥+´4‚føoÁeÈ,r©pæ?'öÿÑ¸óý÷ãð8šÎÝ«.”úÞùéáaÍZRçBÕYôùWk”¢ÔuÄ˜I‡‹�Oÿš¾¾Ò‡Ô&nbsp;7¥nçO`~ZÚÖÙ`4”Ðª¸µLÛ|Î»Æ£¬EU«x�BžfN�ÇÀìÿÀ$†<j^k™ln"ÿc`ðk„Ã¸do½¡�$�Ì! ªdq"Í9ëìo!ÊtÑý¡…°‹çÃ@ÕàÈÄ�Î–ÜÕ…È®â(_“¢•."^ãˆ¸?q~�y<]w†="">Ì
Îþ:Ùþ`	mx è”êâ­#pdUÁÇü8 Hm”ò,¤ÙÓíOáÖB&amp;­	Áû‘Vág´D!=ð'þøîíO4;7¤tÞè� ÛÒšræx¡¥½¶ÅÜSæ1Nfr|¼¡p³cg��ñv-)@6=£;€^zE�Ž;Mlžšã„Ù×nxðsâ
™
¡‡!$ÌáœÒ™ðÁô×Ê„Ñ�¹–�#�ü€cŠfÃeÌûš­3L~)çJ™¦qÁs!âTV°r³2­›Z�iTfÉ—“§íà2°kZ7Ð¬³¦wñ¬ám$‰#§CÜ|F‚¡¸­ýD‹£ñ†ögƒ»5u	•Žº¦…óC(šZeáF„þq2+6ÝÂÒ¡”&gt;TNŒg(Tk°*\ï´P-“[»×� 2ÈÓÑå:8L9ãæn$=&lt;¬‰õïÃP=çªN^÷H}ôdûX™’&amp;n¢â†F#ˆ!ÔE¤ ´·öèh'0&nbsp;+ó°è¨ªCá
i¾(T~<o(™Á§…j¹[µÔÌ˜9vhkr¼2�&˜f«…Ãâlfn‡¹ rò­b‘&eâñ8Óö»˜km7Œœˆo³äÌ|#%´&¹âš˜a×'9ïj¡„"ÜàëÆù¦?„ò¿Ó”4ä­Æd¤) aç<6�="" Â‚Ø†‰³ÐÂgxgl­$d`bÕ¢”%÷“Ó8Î¥]ÕylÒp‘�ç©á�Ör#˜qÁähÝg?œ="" ƒj‚Œåà”¤ýÎpq="" †€ìr="">t#µ…Vu5Çåj¡’<z2w7*�%«¤Ò :zª’whÀ="" è="" �jo="" 9wÉ8™="" @%w‰â £zµÊ÷äÉ;�õÂrÂ^„;:àà¯•="„ˆ¶W/³�¡usp_¼hö¡È-Ëo!t‘Aû«D" �kyþé�¦×Þ**2d�ó°[m="" r1}zèh×­evÎÝ="" æøªxt¢="ÝÁEéúRç»Ã±Ö‡@…ù€ªÂD�§�»&nbsp;f^sWëkzî" t©ojÒÕ™@Õ="" â›º="" •´ðvªø+q§ ãÊŠÿkóïŒÁ�ùºî%¼ìê2?os`~_±½_3av‹"«&(àyö="">4ÈP5DésÓ¶#Ç§h5gny0‚†%#vš…(du	Ü•^x¼UëlMƒ`Mo¡ÐJK/¦æ-++N¡2QþDàa˜Îø4	jq¢5+ëÛ¢=lû‡J2-æ§Ó@€`…Æò™Ãh��³ý¬!2C|B`Z\M˜­àI8uD#¤VÜŸ9…–�AÄ`|©â€eÅvàù¹®Íç
#5|¥¡€_3þ;²EŒ¤ÙòÏù\­D–æÑ‰Ð;V<m¥bÊùÆm÷6ˆ.Ì©†Ãuìr0»mx´aøÀsx0Ž÷pa8Þúyi~fgßÇu"gíða Ðß‹g·_3qårñ¦y{÷(müg%Ö2jŒ}ÈhŸšar1éÏØu›¶b|âñ#œe‘ä–y="" bfƒÊÕ‹—v?kÿúzct\ðv’¥Õ‘i¶û.f‘,c+æh="" �ÌfÑßdÉþ="" �y)£‘3="" $tü®àwuqÍ³�v\}á,k¸¼f@˜‡tŽ#w_ zm}€="">ÌÄf*ç&amp;4—±VËS¡�É›m¥ÂÓáö“Á‡Að‘âŠþÏ©ýLçrGšq×„óJú‘€†÷˜µ°·øSún‡ÈN³ð`ød�;×üf	ºLqƒo\\ÄÏSþè8ûÔPöÇç¼ +@ç®�£q5c!~x¼áÖ#ê(ËRjn2Y/èBêm#ÉÐçàöÃö!ki'^KéøB@l¯—…ò›ýÝ¯wNéFÆ_§Ðiä›Cw÷ó/éæ ©ÐuµyhÝFf¥¨ü÷ÐnÞßý‹~Âfå”²,0H+-ô¦ªD•U7ÿ3€âÑ,TI!s(=¢JëX–ãÏžj�†�V5ÿè8yþâþþùùY¸S3~¼ˆ*®»w?ô~h‡ÇË‡'Vuˆ“ïÚ©_Ž&nbsp;…ßâÊ‚
endstream
endobj
47 0 obj
&lt;&lt;
/Length 2340      
/Filter /FlateDecode
&gt;&gt;
stream
xÚ…XÉ’äÆ
½÷WðÈŽ˜¢¸³x´&amp;fävØš±»’CÒ!›du1šK‰INOûë�€K�hûPÅL $–dúÎ³ã;?Ü}ºûîc˜;�ïå~8§³“ç^DNÄ^EÎ©t~q/ôîY¹Ÿï�û�ûðè~úþ¯þöxˆ¢Ðýéá&gt;pO–Î‡ŸO?þ ½Ç=ž0î·Ó_¾û¤Û�¢4öâ&lt;#Ax“cî|•Ì9ÌìCä{Yr”AmÕöÃ-�ù®I´ûtfÜNs×\¯´©3Ö}gIú$ÉÜ?YÚ—&amp;Vq»g¡Ù7;V­(«¡þ‚µ«Rç¡o¥õÏ~ž7äE�›d&gt;‘—Ä¹ÈY˜¶‚÷µ.!JE²h\‡Ê”ï„7^*[‰žÆªÀ~—®þ}ª¬Ð^Y‚AG4fx®š7™yî‡ç~«ÎÍF‰^ž$!4KÂD¹wŒƒÕ|1í„‰ûñ&gt;�Ý©ip„Ä5e9TÖìÕ•’HÐÈ‹ßŽåhý0÷’0”õªÇé"9Šb³U±&nbsp;-ŠåÎ$Ç”žQ*túNš×¡ŒÏÜ×¡Æ!…Uë·é±Äë¡™õú–¯åšîy2Ï•Ý3ËfûP·§©ïåc&nbsp;i4Ö]©c{ùŽ3Î­êMZö?Ù^× ÕY]v\f*óÌzGëW?ñ¿ÔÃ8™†š�Î-ÙS†e±
ë?�ÌË3_'ñ‚Ü‰ÈÞz®hÏJw2/ñ5€ª¯Eu¥ƒDI¨GŠ’h£ôŒ°ÕÒéÌ8
¦aÿ£!Ü¤“v×ëzóáAäCƒXô–†&gt;¡+Ôþ|³•êbk²DäUÕ �ÉÿË^‚ÏJWD&nbsp;·Ët3.PçzáŽ%\h„²
M6–��¹EmFŽ|!;7†Ö£7†žŸ(8~^&lt;6Nq"4'B§©_8–¥'Ç@‹ÂX—ÚŽý b¡O a·ŽAª&nbsp;x0Š¾½Nc5èvSîùyGçˆ‚TOwhMGÑ’ÉÔ
Â�ºz9{9Hd6Æ› úd"&nbsp;Ë‚3qF]LÐ‰k˜bm!š™7;uIwDçÔˆC
š8Úñ°á?ø.ÖåŽø
)-†Ò¬Õ95ûí1r�1©/‡¨dŽkJÚ	Sê… ‹8[©çÞ^´&gt;+èoðÅ'9"šSJ¢GEÙ‹oÎÖ[MG,˜n×?âœŒ3qì‹ïLÒ E»Æ7Êa't)ŠÈûI¹¶Ÿ†yôÍ4JS´;ãT=ª€A{jæIÅqš1VceNÃÀŠá°Üc]L”Ö�xÞ£,‡Z°îSÝqî¢*‡†ù¨…ZÍßù‚ûÂ^¼÷žPO—™&nbsp;£æ9{©Bk„¢þÕ�âb‘%s›j ¢µ+Ìd©kkB3™ÀY´I:š eÕŠ�ãnLÌRF¶½eUxHÝˆ‡Pw4/³_Ñ0SîV_î�B3¬Ž�’:‡Kä�ÉÑ:UU¢¦ar¯Ã®cÝÖÿÖINhÌª`qÃcºŒ— ¥FY�CÝ.±¿Ý²¤HÓ,:ÿ_vN-¸Ü´øÚ1t9¼®åÂÄ‡?`¹ùÔŒàä}£k]B”Þ¼��
IG�÷²Ì¶îä€ô%ð±ã0£î5&lt;ÁNõ8˜aJ3Â?�4´+µçßNcÔÀd÷¹ÝŒÐš\ïÉè«FÉ‰“¾õLÐ•Ÿ&nbsp;ö|Û	8Ž1&nbsp;P7ÃêÐ7Í’ê@1âÇ¤÷]|9]0æ9ã]˜sP¢»=h›�.§hb/æÐù™2�2
)ÀˆÈê§ïUê¡¥Ä[ü+ÏeKä…Vœªå‚ö4QpEìuÔ;ó"PÉnÞé×‚a&nbsp;i‰—+Í4E&amp;.d’œãßê+™©ã‚z\¶iå0mpšXÛÂ*—4‘äRõäš%ž¤sì¢V»äWÊUý
5ƒ$¨�3À?¶Q¯‘iGÃ¼ìÔ‘YJw„›:2Þ«#3/q
[‡¡|}½ÔK´Ò&gt;3®4ª)&nbsp;˜Ó}KIA53Ý‚T%<r'6-Êdd~¹�ÓvcÃ 9c="" ÉÒ[µlü€vë¡mÕäjháf…ÔøÛ¨0& Ò·“öfö?(›–™†aÍ�z="" ¤ê+Á—^†¨{¦Ècbx·œ\ƒÁ¥¥ÊÍ‘éêdjéÀƒÏÒ‰jnðÌ<£ðÚm™„¬Çíh«‹÷2Þö|a%j¡Õmu»{&jébvÕív?œc·buœ¼‚y¡lk9�®k(j="˜Í&nbsp;c¥cžlßPMÄ×Œ,Ôº">C)d–°ÊŸÁß–û¸ã§¡û&nbsp;›.7j—ý,‰´s½Éfâëxª&amp;¥ûW
)
ø'obÂ×…Ø½,�){º^ûn–°ò�ÊÝšÁb¾Ó¤K0[×Õ™ð&lt;®Rqµ™µ÷Ü0Ûð�ÔªR¼QÚgc©Ø*àÉg-ÎS�4J]@ë®õ8±h$¢Ãã ¢ñ9ÞxÅ;l¡g,«¦âØuP#÷8JÑÈ}Ò’éì™3!Q©Ž§Šª^ou¨/Ïpx-Ê"Õz$•ú„Ž²¥Ôæw—\�It5¼tÆÙk‚™hìÞ¥TŠpÔüÌ¤E9‰òèš2äþÉÄ­@ËýUÓø¿$[¾7Äa�î¦î5eùé¬|Í¤®‘Q`
TjKº{6£.¤oN&lt;ÛÐEX¨sù.±:èFx¹xSJq¸y¨ûpºûý.&nbsp;¦ïóãad^�¢½ûå7ß)‰GgóKœWÙ:ALy(M©Ý8�w——È8sÊN„ã”v‚ ðÒ˜2¥¢ŒFn:âÈ9bzŒ�±$HOG_]êü†.t„q¸òŽ\|µìc10£9ŸíE¹Çó£®—¨)òÍ!nŠo–WªZéSècD‡‡'^�§ÅtãMçm•J4È&nbsp;/w7g&gt;ÈY2üoòÿ&gt;ïçÕxxxãQkÍq/•DþMþÛ¼ZÄ¸òbAn`ã‹~~¸Ð©*r÷©æ(š”×‰i°@â,�ÜOØŒuÂûIÒR/9Fôõ×ÚbŠj4Nô=jîD›ªVÒee®jG+£ckéå!ç‚Š˜êé2ÄèŒW–´i¼×þöK®þ‡ú 
endstream
endobj
50 0 obj
&lt;&lt;
/Length 2216      
/Filter /FlateDecode
&gt;&gt;
stream
xÚ•XÉ’ã6½×WðHE”X\Eræä¥ÛÓsðÒ–O¶£"¡¢HBÉ–Ë_ïÜ@QÕòDÌ‰ÈD"äò2Á8xâà»‡¯÷Oï“]�ÄQ×I°?eU»]°Kò¨Î²`ß¿†»Íïûÿ&gt;½Oëµ`ï¢45$òÍ¾úqÿîãf›ei˜D›mYfá‡ï÷7iþðí/ßì?üð=ªyˆeï·oEá6‹£²¨Xm£ÇÑ:
zÓ"Tmë€�Ä.ÏªÑ°QžÕáGÝèwšº×M•…�,rÜl“Ðn’Ð1m†qRC£eZ±ÖI7¸ô4˜?fÙ¨Q]§[¾u–¯O™Åe”�]äÚx¢M‘„|ª¼GÜòŒ,ÕÐ*Á;ñ²m’EE^óâN½Úy‚ue’5´¶7©ÉØ�7ÏÓ&nbsp;Œê2¦½“,“WAÕ…¨(XìÖ’UTì*Øó*vRx¼"
áþn‚›‘„‡Í6­Bm†gžœGžIÃÉ²ÄÙéÏh4nN2yÒ&lt;8;®éEuvV3^dÓÁeã:Êàl7·&gt;&nbsp;ªWX³+Â#ÉwSâÞ-yVX
Fx¹ÈÓpî[�«±ÃhÆidÊùûl&gt;óípÑi¥{·úVçñÔ1·àÓöÊèÙoûìTÏxŠ´¾¬�98åŒ=_M&lt;2ò+Ë\k~‹³L»«u�ùÙ¸iV�lÃñ4ÄHžÖçôf�LOn)½JbòÿÈ\ý§nfˆ4jR�Qé€0qAÝ

»äÐ.£$�É^u¦1ve-gÖ„›¹—Üã©F
¼d°¢ØiÈÊ;G¶(XVr`\ó»,9�éô4;/)¼í¬Ñ5IøÌòt</r'6-êdd~¹�óvcã></m¥bêùæm÷6ˆ.ì©†ãuìr0»mx´aøàsx0ž÷pa8þúyi~fgßçu"gíða></z2w7*�%«¤ò></o(™á§…j¹[µôì˜9vhkr¼2�&˜f«…ãâlfn‡¹></j^k™ln"ÿc`ðk„ã¸do½¡�$�ì!></sv”></puàî)•î0à†ß]tâgø"�ûá÷‡mÿrõš›(ðìéqv\@+uk6*ñêû�àêî�àxÿùùà½¨d‡èj></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://metamodular.com/closos.pdf">http://metamodular.com/closos.pdf</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://metamodular.com/closos.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23730107</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 04:24:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Lisp Badge: A single-board computer that you can program in uLisp]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 83 | Comments 13 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23729970">thread link</a>) | @lnyan
<br/>
July 3, 2020 | http://www.ulisp.com/show?2L0C | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.ulisp.com/show?2L0C">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">

<p>The Lisp Badge is a self-contained computer with its own display and keyboard, based on an ATmega1284, that you can program in uLisp:</p>
<p><img src="http://www.ulisp.com/pictures/3j/lispbadgehand.jpg" alt="LispBadgeHand.jpg" width="720" height="462"></p>
<p>You can use it to run programs that interface to components such as LEDs and push-buttons via the I/O pins, read the analogue inputs, and operate external devices via the I2C and SPI interfaces. It has a greyscale OLED display that gives 8 lines of 42 characters, and an integrated 45-key keyboard optimised for Lisp.</p>
<p>For details of how to build one see&nbsp;<a href="http://www.technoblogy.com/show?2AEE" target="_blank">Lisp Badge</a>&nbsp;on Technoblogy.</p>
<h3><span>Specification</span></h3>
<p><strong>Size:</strong> 107mm x 61mm (4.2" x 2.4").</p>
<p><strong>Display</strong>: 42 characters x 8 lines.</p>
<p><strong>Keyboard:</strong>&nbsp;Integrated 45-key keyboard providing upper and lower-case characters, digits, and the symbols required by uLisp.</p>
<p><strong>Memory available</strong>: 2816 Lisp cells (11264 bytes).</p>
<p><strong>EEPROM</strong>: 1024 Lisp cells (4096 bytes), allows you to save the Lisp workspace using <strong>save-image</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Processor:</strong> ATmega1284P</p>
<p><strong>Clock speed:</strong> 16 MHz.</p>
<p><strong>Current consumption:</strong> Approx. 20 mA.</p>
<h4><strong>Language</strong></h4>
<p>uLisp, a subset of Common Lisp, with 122 Lisp functions and special forms. For a full definition see <a href="http://www.ulisp.com/show?3L" target="_blank">uLisp Language Reference</a>.</p>
<p>The language includes two extensions, <strong>plot</strong> and <strong>plot3d</strong>, for plotting graphs and 3d functions.&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Types supported</strong>: list, symbol, integer, character, string, and stream.</p>
<p>An integer is a sequence of digits, optionally prefixed with "+" or "-". Integers can be between -32768 and 32767. You can enter numbers in hexadecimal, octal, or binary with the notations #x2A, #o52, or #b101010, all of which represent 42.</p>
<p>User-defined symbol names can have arbitrary names. Any sequence that isn't an integer can be used as a symbol; so, for example, 12a is a valid symbol.</p>
<p>There is one namespace for functions and variables; in other words, you cannot use the same name for a function and a variable.</p>
<p>Includes a mark and sweep garbage collector. Garbage collection takes 5 msec.</p>
<h4><strong>Interfaces</strong></h4>
<p>These interfaces are brought to headers at the edge of the Lisp Badge board. The numbers in brackets refer to Arduino pin numbers:</p>
<ul>
<li>Four analogue input pins using <strong>analogread</strong>: A0 to A3 (24 to 27) plus VCC and GND.</li>
<li>Two analogue outputs using <strong>analogwrite</strong>:&nbsp;MISO (6), and SCK (7).</li>
<li>Digital input and output using <strong>pinmode</strong>, <strong>digitalread</strong>, and <strong>digitalwrite</strong>:&nbsp;MOSI (5), MISO (6), SCK (7),&nbsp;RX0 (8), TX0 (9), SCL (16), SDA (17), and A0 to A3 (24 to 27)</li>
<li>I2C interface using <strong>with-i2c</strong> and <strong>restart-i2c</strong>: SCL (16) and SDA (17).</li>
<li>SPI interface using <strong>with-spi</strong>: MOSI (5), MISO (6), and SCK (7).</li>
<li>Serial interface (FTDI) using&nbsp;<strong>with-serial</strong>: RX0 (8) and TX0 (9).</li>
</ul>
<p>The shift key can be used as a digital input: SHIFT (23).</p>
<p>SCK (7) is connected to an LED on the front panel. This is an analogue output pin, so you can vary the brightness of the LED.</p>
<h3>Plotting extensions</h3>
<p>The Lisp Badge contains two plotting extensions, plot and plot3d, designed to allow plotting to the greyscale graphics display.</p>
<p><span>After generating a plot both functions wait for the ESC key to be pressed before displaying the uLisp prompt.</span></p>
<h3 id="plot">plot&nbsp;<span>function</span></h3>
<p><strong>Syntax:</strong>&nbsp;<code>(plot [<em>x-intercept y-intercept</em>] [<em>function</em>]...)</code></p>
<p>Plots up to four functions on the same graph, optionally with axes.</p>
<p>Each function should be a function of one parameter, the x coordinate, and it will be called with each value of x from 0 to 255. The function should return the y value, from 0 to 63.</p>
<p>If&nbsp;<em>x-intercept</em>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<em>y-intercept</em>&nbsp;are specified,&nbsp;<strong>plot3d</strong>&nbsp;draws axes through those intercepts.</p>
<p>For example, defining:</p>
<pre>(defun sine ()
  (let ((x 0) (y 2045))
    (lambda (n) 
      n
      (incf x (/ (* y 16) 163))
      (decf y (/ (* x 16) 163))
    (+ 32 (ash x -6)))))</pre>
<p>the following command:</p>
<pre>(plot 0 32 (sine))</pre>
<p>will plot:</p>
<p><img src="http://www.ulisp.com/pictures/3j/lispsine.jpg" alt="LispSine.jpg" width="600" height="211"></p>
<h4 id="plot3d">Plotting multiple functions</h4>
<p>The following example plots the voltages on the analogue inputs 0 to 3 once a second on a single plot. First define:</p>
<pre>(defun adc (n) (lambda (x) (delay 250) (/ (analogread n) 8)))</pre>
<p>Then give the command:</p>
<pre>(plot 0 0 (adc 0) (adc 1) (adc 2) (adc 3))</pre>
<h3>plot3d&nbsp;<span>function</span></h3>
<p><strong>Syntax:</strong>&nbsp;<code>(plot3d&nbsp;[<em>x-intercept y-intercept</em>] [<em>function</em>])</code></p>
<p>The function should be a function of two parameters, the x and y coordinates, and it will be called with each value of x from 0 to 255 and y from 0 to 63. The function should return the greyscale value to be plotted, from 0 to 15.</p>
<p>If&nbsp;<em>x-intercept</em>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<em>y-intercept</em>&nbsp;are specified,&nbsp;<strong>plot3d</strong>&nbsp;draws axes through those intercepts.</p>
<p>For example, defining:</p>
<pre>(defun p (x y) 
  (let ((a (/ (- x 128) 2))
        (b (- y 32))) 
    (min (abs (- (logand (/ (+ (* a a) (* b b) (* a b)) 16) 31) 15)) 15)))</pre>
<p>the following command:</p>
<pre>(plot3d 128 32 p)</pre>
<p>will plot:</p>
<p><img src="http://www.ulisp.com/pictures/3j/lispellipses.jpg" alt="LispEllipses.jpg" width="600" height="211"></p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.ulisp.com/show?2L0C</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23729970</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 03:54:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Where Am I? NYTimes or Google?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 1092 | Comments 339 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23729160">thread link</a>) | @rwoll
<br/>
July 3, 2020 | https://theinternetbytes.com/2020/07/03/where-am-i/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://theinternetbytes.com/2020/07/03/where-am-i/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            




            
<article>
    <header>
        
        <p>
            JULY 3, 2020
        </p>
    </header>
    <section>
        <p>Take a look at the below screenshot from Safari for iOS. What website am I on?</p>

<p><img src="https://theinternetbytes.com/images/amp-nytimes-example.png" alt="AMP Example with NYTimes"></p>

<p>Based on the contents of the page, I’m clearly on a NYTimes property, but based
on the address bar I’m clearly on <code>google.com</code>. If I click in the address bar
I see <code>https://www.google.com/amp/s/www.nytimes.com/2020/05/22/technology/google-antitrust.amp.html</code>. Confused, I consult <a href="https://www.google.com/safebrowsing/static/faq.html">Google’s Safebrowsing FAQ</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
<p><strong>How can I tell if a page is a fake?</strong></p>

<p>The best thing to do is to check the page’s URL to make sure it’s actually controlled by the party it appears to be controlled by. The crucial part of the URL is the part between the http:// and the next slash (‘/’). (If there’s no slash, start at the end of the URL.) This is the part of the URL that determines site ownership. Some popular domains, for instance, are amazon, google, and ebay:</p>

<p><code>http://www.amazon.com</code><br>
<code>http://www.google.com</code><br>
<code>http://www.ebay.com</code></p>

<p>In some cases, URLs will be a bit more complex; be sure to check the name listed immediately to the left of the top level domain (.com, .net, .co.uk, etc.).
For instance, <code>http://www.google.com</code>, <code>http://news.google.com</code> and <code>http://www.google.com/firefox/</code> are all part of the same site. However, <code>google.com.fraudulentdomain.com/login.html</code> is NOT! Neither is <code>www.g00gle.com</code> (note that in this URL, the letter o is replaced by the number 0).</p>
</blockquote>

<p>and determine I’m on <code>www.google.com</code>—but the confusion remains since
this is genuinely NYTimes content and branding.</p>

<p>This is a really dangerous pattern: Google serves NYTimes’ controlled<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup>
content on a Google domain (<code>www.google.com</code>) and wants the user to trust that it is NYTimes’ content. <strong>It confuses the user whether to trust the address in
URL bar or the content of the page</strong> Meanwhile Google, Internet safety groups, and workplaces actively try to
teach users to check domains and URL address bars. The confusion over trusting page content or address bar contents is precisely why phishing
attempts work so well. Humans trust visual indicators a lot. Google, with the AMP
Cache Project, is confusing humans more and training them to trust visual content
of the page over the URL in the address bar (in certain contexts)—despite telling them to do otherwise on different sites.
This surprises me since Google
spends a lot of time researching visual indicators of security in the address bar
(like the padlock icon)<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2">2</a></sup>. In work security trainings and guides on the Internet,
we are trained to look at the address bar to help make a decision on whether to trust
a site, but the Google AMP Cache requires contradictory rules from what we’d use elsewhere.</p>

<p>The speed of AMP is a nice benefit<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3">3</a></sup>, but there are still some UX challenges to handle in order
to reinforce—not muddy—the security lessons we teach Internet users.</p>

<p>Comments on the post can be viewed here: <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23729160">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23729160</a>.</p>


    </section>
</article>

        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://theinternetbytes.com/2020/07/03/where-am-i/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23729160</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 01:14:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Scaling Linux Services: Before accepting connections]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 162 | Comments 25 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23729072">thread link</a>) | @theojulienne
<br/>
July 3, 2020 | https://theojulienne.io/2020/07/03/scaling-linux-services-before-accepting-connections.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://theojulienne.io/2020/07/03/scaling-linux-services-before-accepting-connections.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
    <p>When writing services that accept TCP connections, we tend to think of our work as starting from the point where our service accepts a new client connection and finishing when we complete the request and close the socket. For services at scale, operations can happen at such a high rate that some of the default resource limits of the Linux kernel can break this abstraction and start causing impact to incoming connections outside of that connection lifecycle. This post focuses on some standard resource limitations that exist before the client socket is handed to the application - all of which came up during the course of investigating errors on production systems as part of my role at GitHub (in some cases, multiple times across different applications).</p>

<p>In its most basic form (ignoring non-blocking variants), listening for TCP connections requires a call to <code>listen()</code> to actually start allowing incoming connections, followed by repeated calls to <code>accept()</code> to take the next pending connection and return a file descriptor that is for that particular client. In C this pattern looks something like:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>int</span> <span>server_fd</span> <span>=</span> <span>socket</span><span>(</span><span>AF_INET</span><span>,</span> <span>SOCK_STREAM</span><span>,</span> <span>0</span><span>);</span>
<span>bind</span><span>(</span><span>server_fd</span><span>,</span> <span>/* ... */</span><span>);</span>

<span>// start listening for connections</span>
<span>listen</span><span>(</span><span>server_fd</span><span>,</span> <span>512</span><span>);</span>

<span>while</span> <span>(</span><span>running</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>// block until a connection arrives and then accept it</span>
    <span>int</span> <span>client_fd</span> <span>=</span> <span>accept</span><span>(</span><span>server_fd</span><span>,</span> <span>NULL</span><span>,</span> <span>NULL</span><span>);</span>

    <span>// ... handle client_fd ...</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>close</span><span>(</span><span>server_fd</span><span>);</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This is often hidden behind further layers of abstraction, and we tend to hide away all the implementation details of accepting connections and view it as a stream of new connections that we pick up and then process in parallel. However, when building a system that runs at a certain scale, this abstraction tends to break down because there are resource limitations introduced in the period where connections are being established but are not yet returned by <code>accept()</code>. Before that point, those client connections are considered as being part of the server/listen socket and not as independent resources exposed to the application.</p>

<p>The examples mentioned in this blog post will be reproducible in the lab from <i></i> <a href="https://github.com/theojulienne/blog-lab-scaling-accept">theojulienne/blog-lab-scaling-accept</a> - clone this repository bring up the lab, then poke around at these examples in a real system:</p>
<div><div><pre><code>$ git clone https://github.com/theojulienne/blog-lab-scaling-accept.git
$ cd blog-lab-scaling-accept
$ vagrant up
$ vagrant ssh
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="from-syn-to-accept">From SYN to accept()</h2>

<p>The Linux kernel maintains 2 queues of connections that maintain the backlog of connections that are not yet <code>accept()</code>ed by the application:</p>
<p><img alt="LISTEN backlogs" src="https://theojulienne.io/images/scaling-linux-services-before-accepting-connections/pre-accept-backlogs.png">
</p>

<p>When a SYN packet is received to initiate a new connection to a listen socket, a SYN-ACK is sent to the client and the half-completed connection state is stored in the “SYN backlog” or “Request Socket Queue”. This represents connections that have not yet been fully validated as having two-way communication between the hosts, because we haven’t yet validated that the remote end has received a packet from us (the SYN could have come from another host spoofing the source IP).</p>

<p>Once the client responds to the server’s SYN-ACK with an ACK, the connection has then completed the full <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Handshaking#TCP_three-way_handshake">TCP 3-way handshake</a>, and the server knows that two-way communication has been established. At this point, the client connection is ready to be provided to the application at a future call to <code>accept()</code>, and is added to the appropriately named “accept queue”.</p>

<h2 id="syn-backlog">SYN backlog</h2>

<p>Connections in the SYN backlog remain there for a period of time relative to the Round Trip Time between the server and the client. If there are N slots in the backlog then you can have at most N connections in this backlog per average RTT, after which the backlog overflows.</p>

<p>This won’t actually cause the connections to fail by default on Linux, but cause <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SYN_cookies">SYN cookies</a> to be sent instead. This is because when only a SYN packet has been received, the server hasn’t yet validated that the client is who they say they are, so they could be spoofing packets as coming from a different IP. This is a common Denial of Service attack called a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SYN_flood">SYN Flood</a>. Because this is so common, the Linux kernel has built in mitigation to SYN floods by sending a SYN cookie when there is no room in the SYN backlog for the new connection.</p>

<p>This means that even if the SYN backlog overflows under normal circumstances with no DoS attack, the kernel allows the connection to move further along in the handshake, and won’t store any resources for the connection until an ACK completes the handshake. Sending SYN cookies during normal circumstances does however indicate that the rate of connections is probably too high for the default limits - SYN cookies are really only meant for mitigating SYN floods.</p>

<p>Whether SYN cookies are enabled is controlled via the sysctl <code>net.ipv4.tcp_syncookies</code>, by default this is set to <code>1</code> which indicates that SYN cookies should be sent when the SYN backlog overflows, but can also be set to <code>0</code> to disable entirely or <code>2</code> to force SYN cookies to be sent 100% of the time.</p>

<p>When SYN cookies are enabled as needed (the default), they are triggered when the number of pending connections in the SYN backlog is more than the configured accept queue backlog size for the socket - the logic for this is <a href="https://github.com/torvalds/linux/blob/cb8e59cc87201af93dfbb6c3dccc8fcad72a09c2/net/ipv4/tcp_input.c#L6612-L6613">here</a>. When SYN cookies are fully disabled, <code>net.ipv4.tcp_max_syn_backlog</code> configures the number of connections allowed in the SYN backlog separately - the logic for this case is <a href="https://github.com/torvalds/linux/blob/cb8e59cc87201af93dfbb6c3dccc8fcad72a09c2/net/ipv4/tcp_input.c#L6670-L6672">here</a>.</p>

<p>In the default configuration where the backlog overflows and SYN cookies are sent, the kernel increments the <code>TCPReqQFullDoCookies</code> counter and logs this line to the kernel log, which is often confused for an indicator of a real SYN flood even when it’s just due to legitimate connections coming in too fast:</p>
<div><div><pre><code>TCP: request_sock_TCP: Possible SYN flooding on port 8080. Sending cookies.  Check SNMP counters.
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>If SYN cookies are explicitly disabled, the kernel increments the <code>TCPReqQFullDrop</code> counter and the following would be logged instead:</p>
<div><div><pre><code>TCP: request_sock_TCP: Possible SYN flooding on port 8080. Dropping request.  Check SNMP counters.
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>If you see this message for internal service-to-service connections, chances are you’re dealing with a scaling problem or a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thundering_herd_problem">thundering herd problem</a>, and not an actual SYN flood or intentional bad actor.</p>

<p>Those “SNMP Counters” that the kernel mentions are available in <code>nstat</code> in the network namespace:</p>
<div><div><pre><code>$ nstat -a | grep TCPReqQFull
TcpExtTCPReqQFullDoCookies      706                0.0
</code></pre></div></div>

<h3 id="syn-backlog-in-the-lab">SYN backlog in the lab</h3>

<p>To see how the SYN backlog behaves in the lab, we can simulate latency on local connections with the following:</p>
<div><div><pre><code>vagrant@blog-lab-scaling-accept:~$ sudo /vagrant/reset-lab.sh
vagrant@blog-lab-scaling-accept:~$ sudo tc qdisc add dev lo root netem delay 200ms
vagrant@blog-lab-scaling-accept:~$ ping 127.0.0.1
PING 127.0.0.1 (127.0.0.1) 56(84) bytes of data.
64 bytes from 127.0.0.1: icmp_seq=1 ttl=64 time=401 ms
64 bytes from 127.0.0.1: icmp_seq=2 ttl=64 time=400 ms
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This means we can now simulate overflowing the SYN backlog. To make it a bit easier to reproduce, reduce the size of the SYN backlog from the default of <code>128</code> by reducing <code>net.core.somaxconn</code> (because SYN cookies are enabled):</p>
<div><div><pre><code>vagrant@blog-lab-scaling-accept:~$ sudo sysctl net.core.somaxconn
net.core.somaxconn = 128
vagrant@blog-lab-scaling-accept:~$ sudo sysctl -w net.core.somaxconn=10
net.core.somaxconn = 10
vagrant@blog-lab-scaling-accept:~$ sudo systemctl restart nginx
vagrant@blog-lab-scaling-accept:~$ 
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>At this point, if more than 10 connections arrive within 400ms (before the SYN-ACK and ACK handshake complete), then 10 connections will be in the SYN backlog, which is the maximum configured. This will trigger SYN cookies to be sent, triggering the message and counters above. Let’s test out if this works, run a simulation that opens N concurrent connections:</p>
<div><div><pre><code>vagrant@blog-lab-scaling-accept:~$ python /vagrant/test_send_concurrent_connections.py 127.0.0.1:80 20
Waiting, Ctrl+C to exit.
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And verify that SYN cookies were sent as expected:</p>
<div><div><pre><code>vagrant@blog-lab-scaling-accept:~$ sudo dmesg -c
[ 2571.784749] TCP: request_sock_TCP: Possible SYN flooding on port 80. Sending cookies.  Check SNMP counters.
vagrant@blog-lab-scaling-accept:~$ sudo nstat | grep ReqQ
TcpExtTCPReqQFullDoCookies      10                 0.0
vagrant@blog-lab-scaling-accept:~$
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Try disabling the simulated latency with <code>sudo tc qdisc del dev lo root</code> and re-run the same test, now connections move through fast enough that SYN cookies are not sent.</p>

<p>This also demonstrates the way the Round Trip Time effects the amount of connections that can burst into a LISTEN socket - <code>test_send_concurrent_connections.py</code> does actually attempt to initiate complete connections and <code>nginx</code> on the other end is readily calling <code>accept()</code> as fast as it can, but because 20 connections are initiated at once, 20 SYN packets arrive before any handshake can continue, and the SYN backlog overflows. You can imagine that in the real world, with some of these values often defaulting to <code>128</code>, and users often being far away from servers (on the other side of the world), it’s pretty easy to accidentally trigger this scenario without a true SYN flood.</p>

<h2 id="accept-queue">Accept queue</h2>

<p>Once an ACK packet is received and validated, a new client connection is ready for the application to process. This connection is moved into the accept queue, waiting for the application to call <code>accept()</code> and receive it.</p>

<p>Unlike the SYN backlog, the accept queue has no backup plan for when it overflows. Back in the original call to <code>listen()</code>, a <code>backlog</code> argument was provided, which indicates how many connections can have completed the 3-way handshake and be waiting in the kernel for the application to accept.</p>

<p>This is the first common issue: If the <code>backlog</code> number provided to <code>listen()</code> is not large enough to contain any number of connections that could reasonably complete their handshake between 2 calls to <code>accept()</code>, then a connection will be dropped on the floor, and the application generally won’t even notice - the next call to …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://theojulienne.io/2020/07/03/scaling-linux-services-before-accepting-connections.html">https://theojulienne.io/2020/07/03/scaling-linux-services-before-accepting-connections.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://theojulienne.io/2020/07/03/scaling-linux-services-before-accepting-connections.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23729072</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:58:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A practical case on why we need the humanities]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 45 | Comments 70 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23728264">thread link</a>) | @jpeanuts
<br/>
July 3, 2020 | https://acoup.blog/2020/07/03/collections-the-practical-case-on-why-we-need-the-humanities/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://acoup.blog/2020/07/03/collections-the-practical-case-on-why-we-need-the-humanities/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>I have been holding off writing something like this, because it is often such a well-worn topic and I hardly wanted to preach to the converted.  But at the same time, the humanities need all of the defenses they can get and I’ve found, looking at the genre, that my answers for why we need the humanities are rather different from the typical answer.</p>



<p>But first, the <strong>shameless plug</strong> that if <strong>you</strong>, yes <strong>you!</strong> want to support the humanities, you can support <em>this</em> humanist by sharing my writing, subscribing with the button below or by supporting me on <a href="https://www.patreon.com/user?u=20122096">Patreon</a>.  Your support enables me to continue telling you and other people to continue supporting me, a giant self-devouring<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ouroboros"> ouroboros </a>of support that will grow to become so large it will crush the world (I look forward to regretting this joke in the future).</p>






<p>Edit: A friendly reminder to those in the comments: you will be <em>civil</em>.  This thread has prompted some spirited discussion.  That’s fine.  But it will remain polite.</p>



<h2>What Humanities?</h2>



<p>First, just to define my terms, <strong>what are the humanities</strong>?  Broadly, they are the disciplines that study human society (that is, that are concerned with humanity): language study, literature, philosophy, history, art history, archaeology, anthropology, and so on.  It is necessarily a bit of a fuzzy set.  But what I think defines the humanities more than subject matter is <strong>method</strong>; the humanities study things which (we argue) <em>cannot</em> be subjected to the rigors of the scientific method or strictly mathematical approaches.  You cannot perform a controlled trial in beauty, mathematical certainty in history is almost always impossible, and there is no way to know much stress a society can bear except to see it fail.  Some things cannot be reduced to numbers, at least not by the powers of the technology-aided human mind.</p>



<p>By way of example, that methodological difference is why there’s a division between <strong>political science</strong> and <strong>history</strong>, despite the two disciplines historically being concerned with many of the same subjects and the same questions (to the point that Thucydides is sometimes produced as the founder of both):<strong> they use different methods</strong>.  History is a humanities discipline through and through, whereas political science attempts to hybridize humanities and STEM (Science, Technology, Engineering and Mathematics) approaches; that’s not to say historians never use statistical approaches (I do, actually, quite a lot) but that there are very real differences in methodology.  As you might imagine, that difference leads to some <a href="https://warontherocks.com/2020/06/want-better-strategists-teach-social-science/">competition </a>and <a href="https://warontherocks.com/2020/05/finally-getting-serious-about-professional-military-education/">conflict </a>between the disciplines as to whose methodology best answers those key questions or equips students to think about them.  Given that I have a doctorate in history and self-identify as a historian, you will have no trouble guessing which side of this I come down on, although that might be a bit self-interested on my part.</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="3760" data-permalink="https://acoup.blog/heike/" data-orig-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/heike.png" data-orig-size="7470,3435" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="heike" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/heike.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/heike.png?w=1024" src="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/heike.png?w=1024" alt="" srcset="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/heike.png?w=1024 1024w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/heike.png?w=2048 2048w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/heike.png?w=150 150w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/heike.png?w=300 300w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/heike.png?w=768 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Tale_of_the_Heike#/media/File:Battle_scenes_from_the_Tale_of_Heike_(Heike_Monogatari)_-_Google_Art_Project.jpg">Via Wikipedia</a>, a 17th century illustration from the 14th century Japanese epic the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Tale_of_the_Heike">Heike Monogatari</a>, which I read (in translation) as a college Freshman in a Japanese literature class.  I was struck reading this (and the Genji Monogatari; the two works were paired in the course) by how radically different the culture was from any of the ones I knew.  It was one of the first moments I ‘got’ the ‘past is a foreign country’ thing.  At the same time, when I later dug deeper into Roman martial culture, the commonalities between Roman elite military virtue and the values of the Tale of the Heike were striking.  The human part of ‘the human experience’ is common, even if the experience part is not.<br>Since this isn’t a topic where visual illustration is strictly on-point, I am going to use the images here to share some of the works outside of Greek and Roman history, which I encountered in my education in the humanities which influenced me and my thinking.</figcaption></figure>



<p>So if the STEM fields are, at some level, fundamentally about numbers, the humanities are <strong>fundamentally about language</strong>.  The universe may be made of numbers, but the human mind and human societies are constructed out of language.  Unlike computers, we do not think in numbers, but in words and consequently, the study of humans as <em>thinking</em> creatures is mostly about those words (yes, yes, I see you there, economics and psychology; there are edge cases, of course).  Our laws are written in words because our thoughts form <em>in our heads</em> as words; we naturally reason with words and we even <em>feel</em> with words.  Humans are linguistic creations in a mathematical universe; consequently, while the study of the universe is mediated through math, the study of humans and human minds is fundamentally linguistic in nature.</p>



<p>Thus, the humanities.</p>



<h2>Oh, the Humanities!</h2>



<p>Now I want to note here the standard defense of the humanities, which is that the study of human culture, literature and art enriches the soul and the experience of life.  <strong>This is, to be clear, undoubtedly true</strong>.  There is joy and richness in the incredible kaleidoscope of human expression and a deep wisdom in the realization of both how that expression joins us, and how radically different it can be.  There is also the enjoyment of developing a ‘palette’ for art and literature which is enhanced by knowing <em>more</em> of it, in being able to see the innovations and cross-connections (the ‘intertext’ to use the unnecessarily fancy academic term).  This is all very much the case.  There is a reason that rich people with abundant free time have consistently gravitated to the study of the humanities, or supported it.</p>



<p><strong>But this is a weak defense of the humanities as they are currently constructed</strong>.  The fact is that the academic humanities exist because people who <em>do not study the humanities</em> fund them.  The modern study of the humanities, in its infancy, was paid for by wealthy elites who wanted either that joyful richness or at least the status that came from funding it.  I should note here also that the humanities were never for the <em>teachers</em> of the humanities, but for its students.  The rich funders of the humanities were rarely the authors of the great treatises or studies; rather they wished to be the <em>readers of them</em> (and likewise, the modern academic humanities are not <em>for</em> professors, but the students we teach; more on this next time).  Down until really quite recently, education in the humanities was largely reserved for that elite and their academic clients.  As public support for the humanities continues to decline, many humanities fields seem in real danger of reverting back to that status: a prestigious toy for the already-rich and already-elite.</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="3762" data-permalink="https://acoup.blog/1280px-chamber_a_yazilikaya_06/" data-orig-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/1280px-chamber_a_yazilikaya_06.jpg" data-orig-size="1280,850" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="1280px-chamber_a_yazilikaya_06" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/1280px-chamber_a_yazilikaya_06.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/1280px-chamber_a_yazilikaya_06.jpg?w=1024" src="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/1280px-chamber_a_yazilikaya_06.jpg?w=1024" alt="" srcset="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/1280px-chamber_a_yazilikaya_06.jpg?w=1024 1024w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/1280px-chamber_a_yazilikaya_06.jpg?w=150 150w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/1280px-chamber_a_yazilikaya_06.jpg?w=300 300w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/1280px-chamber_a_yazilikaya_06.jpg?w=768 768w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/1280px-chamber_a_yazilikaya_06.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hurrian_religion#/media/File:Chamber_A,_Yazilikaya_06.jpg">Via Wikipedia</a>, a Hurrian-Hittite relief showing parts of the pantheon, including <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Teshub">Tessub</a>, the storm-god, which I really first encountered in earnest during my M.A., but which I now include in my basic ancient history survey.  In high school, I had largely been taught Greek mythology as a stand-alone idea, something the Greeks came up with all on their own – indeed, I was taught all of ancient Greek culture that was, as if it just sprang out of the ground.  Reading Kingship in Heaven – the myth of Teshub’s origin – was revelatory, because here was a forerunner to Hesiod’s Theogony, the foundation-stone for teaching Greek mythology.  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/East-Face-Helicon-Clarendon-Paperbacks/dp/0198152213">Hesiod had been borrowing</a>, he had been influenced and Greek mythology no longer stood on its own but slowly wrapped itself into an older, richer edifice of literature stretching back to the haziest beginnings of our knowledge.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Avoiding that retreat of the humanities back into the wealthy elite means defending the humanities on different grounds.  Of course, the traditional humanities will always survive at Harvard or Cambridge or Yale.  But for the humanities to actually be <em>generally</em> available, they need to survive, to thrive, outside of those spaces.  And yet, no good that is tethered to colleges can be justified solely through the benefit it gives the holder.  <strong>Colleges, after all, are publicly funded, but while everyone pays taxes, not everyone goes to college</strong>.  The OECD average rate for tertiary-education-completion among adults<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_tertiary_education_attainment"> is around 37% </a>and not all of those are four-year university degrees.  To break down the United States’ data, while 44% of Americans have completed some kind of tertiary education, putting the USA towards the top of the scale (and around two-thirds have at least <em>some</em> college, though they may not have completed it), <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Educational_attainment_in_the_United_States">only 35% of Americans have a four-year degree</a>.  And of course, only a subset of those degree-holders will have taken very much in the way of the humanities.  Which means <strong>the taxes that pay to fund the public universities that make up the great bulk of the study of the humanities are going to mostly come from people who have not, or could not, avail themselves of a humanistic education</strong>.</p>



<p>Even if we made the humanities available to all – a goal I robustly support (it is one reason I am spending all this time working on this open, free web platform, after all) – that effort would likely have to be publicly funded through a great many tax-payers who did not care to consume much of the <em>academic</em> products of the humanities (even if they consume many of its pop-cultural byproducts without knowing it).  <strong>We must be able to justify the expense to them</strong>.  And alas, while I love crowd-funding (did I mention, you can support me on <a href="https://www.patreon.com/user?u=20122096">Patreon</a>?), it is simply not an alternative for the research and teaching environment of the university (though I think it is and ought to be an important parallel model, for reasons I’ll get into in a moment).  The fact is that while ‘short’ essays, blog posts and public-facing books can be popularly funded, <strong>the slow, painstaking work that forms the <em>foundation</em> for those efforts has no ready popular market</strong>; but without the latter, the former withers (as a note: my <em>next</em> Collections post will be on the process by which knowledge filters from the latter to the former).</p>



<p><strong>We must be prepared to explain the value of the humanities to people for …</strong></p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/07/03/collections-the-practical-case-on-why-we-need-the-humanities/">https://acoup.blog/2020/07/03/collections-the-practical-case-on-why-we-need-the-humanities/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://acoup.blog/2020/07/03/collections-the-practical-case-on-why-we-need-the-humanities/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23728264</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 22:41:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Bitcoin From Scratch – Part 1]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 281 | Comments 68 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23728228">thread link</a>) | @monokh
<br/>
July 3, 2020 | https://monokh.com/posts/bitcoin-from-scratch-part-1 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://monokh.com/posts/bitcoin-from-scratch-part-1">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <div id="post">
                
                <p>3 July 2020</p>
                <p>Understanding the fundamental building blocks(😉) of Bitcoin can be daunting for some developers. I find it difficult
    to meaningfully understand a system without knowing how everything fits together. </p>
<p>A good way to go through this process is to lay down, however rudimentary, a set of processes by which the system
    operates. Hence the purpose of this guide is to explain through simple pieces of code, how Bitcoin works.</p>
<p>Note: The intention is not to create a real implementation of the Bitcoin protocol. It also does not aim to explain
    every concept. Look for the embedded links if you find a concept you need to go over. Also look out for notes where
    concepts have been simplified and differ from the real Bitcoin implementation.</p>
<p>Hopefully by the end of this series, we should have a bitcoin-like protocol anyone can run.</p>
<p>The code written until this point is available <a href="https://github.com/monokh/nibble/tree/813d3d694d1ea0b6c71ce5854a1393e9deb61904">here</a>.</p>
<p>From a very high level. This is bitcoin:</p>
<pre><code>let keypair = crypto::KeyPair::new();
let keypair2 = crypto::KeyPair::new();

let tx1 = create_signed_tx(&amp;keypair, keypair2.public_key, 123);
let tx2 = create_signed_tx(&amp;keypair2, keypair.public_key, 75);

let txs = vec![tx1, tx2];

let proposed_block = block::ProposedBlock {
    transactions: txs,
};

println!("Mining block with {} txs.", proposed_block.transactions.len());
let block = proposed_block.mine(3); // Difficulty 3 i.e. hash must begin with "000"
println!("Mined block: {:#?}", block);
</code></pre>
<p>We can split what we see here into the following categories:</p>
<ul>
    <li>Keys</li>
    <li>Transactions</li>
    <li>Blocks</li>
    <li>Mining</li>
</ul>

<h2>Keys</h2>
<p>Keys are required as a means to achieve ownership. In other words, you need to have the key to spend a certain amount
    of bitcoin.</p>
<pre><code>pub struct KeyPair {
    pub public_key: key::PublicKey,
    private_key: key::SecretKey,
}
</code></pre>
<p>Your keys actually consist of 2 parts. The private key and the public key. The public key can be shared with the
    world and is used to receive bitcoin, whereas the private key is something you keep secure as it can be used to
    spend your bitcoin. <a href="https://nakamoto.com/public-key-cryptography/#public-keys-as-identity">More on public
        key cryptography.</a></p>

<h3>Creating keys</h3>
<p>In bitcoin, <a href="https://hackernoon.com/what-is-the-math-behind-elliptic-curve-cryptography-f61b25253da3">eliptic
        curves are used for public key cryptography</a> - specifically secp256k1. In essense, using a (psuedo)random
    number we can generate a pair of keys that can be thought of as a user's wallet. </p>
<pre><code>let mut rand = rand::OsRng::new().unwrap();
let secp = Secp256k1::new();
let (private_key, public_key) = secp.generate_keypair(&amp;mut rand);
KeyPair {
    secp,
    public_key,
    private_key,
}
</code></pre>

<h2>Transaction</h2>
<p>Transactions are the smallest unit of the Bitcoin system. A transaction is a data structure which encodes a payment
    of x bitcoins from a to b.</p>
<p>In Bitcoin, transactions are not as simple as transferring a balance (account based), but rather a
    collection of inputs and outputs. This is generally called the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unspent_transaction_output">"UTXO model"</a>.</p>
<pre><code>pub struct Transaction {
    pub from: PublicKey,
    pub to: PublicKey,
    pub amount: u32
}
</code></pre>
<p>The public keys here are precisely from the key pairs that were generated. </p>
<p>What then prevents anyone from transferring on behalf of others? Public key cryptography. To be a valid transaction
    and be accepted into the network by others, the transaction needs to be "Signed" by the `from` private key. </p>
<pre><code>impl KeyPair {
    pub fn sign(&amp;self, message: &amp;[u8]) -&gt; Signature {
        ...
        self.secp.sign(&amp;message, &amp;self.private_key);
    }
}
</code></pre>

<h3>Signed transaction</h3>
<p>As mentioned previously, private keys exercise control over a number of bitcoins. A's private key is used to sign a
    transaction so that anyone can verify that the transaction from A to B was in fact authorised by A. </p>
<pre><code>let tx = transaction::Transaction {
    from: keypair.public_key,
    to,
    amount,
};

let sig = keypair.sign(&amp;tx.hash());

return transaction::SignedTransaction{
    transaction: tx,
    sig: sig.to_string(),
};
</code></pre>

<h2>Block</h2>
<p>A block is a collection of transactions. These transactions should be signed and therefore valid.</p>
<pre><code>let tx1 = create_signed_tx(&amp;keypair, keypair2.public_key, 123);
let tx2 = create_signed_tx(&amp;keypair2, keypair.public_key, 75);

let txs = vec![tx1, tx2];

let proposed_block = block::ProposedBlock {
    transactions: txs,
};
</code></pre>
<p>In fact, on the bitcoin network, the only data which is replicated across are the blocks. The purpose of the block is
    to effectively write it's containing transactions into history. It achieves this by mining.</p>

<h2>Mining</h2>
<p>The process of <a href="https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/Mining">mining</a> is to do a computation to ensure that there is
    something at stake. In other words, the miner has to prove they have done some work - <a href="https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/Proof_of_work">"Proof of Work"</a></p>
<p>To provide the correct proof of work for a block:</p>
<ol>
    <li>Serialise the block</li>
    <li>Append a number</li>
    <li>Hash it</li>
    <li>Increment the number</li>
    <li>Go back to 1</li>
</ol>

<p>The PoW is suffice if the hash begins with a certain number of 0s. The number of 0s required is called <a href="https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/Difficulty">difficulty</a>. The more difficulty - the more 0s are required.
</p>

<p>In reality, the difficulty is defined on a more granular level. See <a href="https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/Difficulty">difficulty on the bitcoin wiki</a> for more information.</p>

<pre><code>let mut nonce: u32 = 0;
let block_string = self.serialize();

loop {
    let block = format!("{}{}", block_string, nonce);
    let block_hash = hex::encode(crypto::sha256(block.clone()));
    if block_hash.starts_with(&amp;"0".repeat(difficulty)) {
        return Block {
            hash: block_hash,
            nonce,
            transactions: self.transactions
        }
    }
    nonce += 1;
}
</code></pre>

<p>You should hopefully now see how this all fits together. To recap the high level code <a href="#code-main">initially
        presented</a>:</p>

<ol>
    <li>Generate keypairs for each user</li>
    <li>Using the private key of the user, sign transactions that move bitcoin</li>
    <li>Combine these transactions in a "block"</li>
    <li>Perform the PoW on this block until the difficulty condition is met</li>
</ol>

<p>Finally running this program will produce a block including the signed transactions. Take note of the hash. It begins
    with "000", therefore it is a valid block when difficulty is set to 3.</p>

<pre><code>Mining block with 2 txs.
Mined block: Block {
    hash: "000cc7b72695c1ab8b7969cb400f73d763bce1cafa866b0aab59fe762eb7fbed",
    nonce: 96,
    transactions: [
        SignedTransaction {
            transaction: Transaction {
                from: PublicKey(
                    bf9d4f6c8142956ac683f73ef009369b43aec7d765e18c6ac3b48341bf14ebd9e0a06bec8897e392725dae273eaa51400320130cba64143e61c1f61b3bc4f324,
                ),
                to: PublicKey(
                    c1c6bd81ff1a657ae4053149682502c749fbc4b638e047d36c4bdf637ebcd0e93d0f987638c248c099deef8ec76199c1818f3b387e232a2d8da5de5ca91cf13b,
                ),
                amount: 123,
            },
            sig: "304402206fb0e6ab4a6acfcc0725f048c7fbfed734accc0a4bad864ac161302410ed3f94022035ef86194f8de575658b7e4b3bae2aee193c507d78fe8ba4e43e22bce948271a",
        },
        SignedTransaction {
            transaction: Transaction {
                from: PublicKey(
                    c1c6bd81ff1a657ae4053149682502c749fbc4b638e047d36c4bdf637ebcd0e93d0f987638c248c099deef8ec76199c1818f3b387e232a2d8da5de5ca91cf13b,
                ),
                to: PublicKey(
                    bf9d4f6c8142956ac683f73ef009369b43aec7d765e18c6ac3b48341bf14ebd9e0a06bec8897e392725dae273eaa51400320130cba64143e61c1f61b3bc4f324,
                ),
                amount: 75,
            },
            sig: "30440220752b3ea25bd2ab2b29d44659af665caddd7ce9b54144c41e6adcdfde7ef807fa022066682bdb49666a91fd28e14c05cf8229d668c061f404f218bb62619e4604eb59",
        },
    ],
}
</code></pre>

<p>There is much more to Bitcoin to uncover. We have not presented yet:</p>
<ul>
    <li>How blocks are validated (consensus rules)</li>
    <li>How it's possible to derive balances.</li>
    <li>How blocks are constructed such that they are not reversible</li>
    <li>How the peers communicate over the internet</li>
</ul>
<p>This and much more will be covered in future parts.</p>
            </div>
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://monokh.com/posts/bitcoin-from-scratch-part-1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23728228</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 22:35:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Silence Is Deafening]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 428 | Comments 211 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23728212">thread link</a>) | @pagade
<br/>
July 3, 2020 | https://devonzuegel.com/post/the-silence-is-deafening | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://devonzuegel.com/post/the-silence-is-deafening">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-type-cleanup="true">
                  <p>Imagine you're at a dinner party, and you're getting into a heated argument. As you start yelling, the other people quickly hush their voices and start glaring at you. None of the onlookers have to take further action—it's clear from their facial expressions that you're being a jerk.</p>

<p>In digital conversations, giving feedback requires more conscious effort. Silence is the default. Participants only get feedback from people who join the fray. They receive no signal about how the silent onlookers perceive their dialogue. In fact, they don't receive much signal that onlookers observed the conversation at all.<span><sup id="footnote-label--1">1</sup></span></p>

<p><span>As a result, the feedback you do receive in digital conversations is more polarized, because the only people who will engage are those who are willing to take that extra step and bear that cost of wading into a messy conversation. </span></p>

<p>When Angry Alice tweets something obnoxious or unproductive, reasonable people just scroll past it. If Alice develops a pattern of bad behavior, reasonable people will just unfollow, mute, or block her. The result is that it's hard for Alice to notice the silent majority of people who saw the trash fire and walked away when they recognized that engaging would only fuel its flames.</p>

<p>It gets worse—Angry Alice only sees feedback from extremists, so she doesn't receive more nuanced signals that might actually cause her to reflect on her behavior. <span>If no reasonable people give feedback, only the unreasonable people are left. </span>From Alice's perspective, the only people who disagree with her are jerks.</p>

<p>This is a coordination problem. Reasonable people understand that if they join the fray alone, they'll most likely be drowned out by the yelling, or worse they'll get dragged deeper into it. As a result, they choose stay out of it. </p>

<p>A huge part of the problem is that digital spaces generally have no equivalent of a disapproving glare. You're stuck choosing between staying silent and entering the fray, with few options in between. If you have little reason to believe that other reasonable people will back you up, you're going to stick with the default: silence.</p>

<p>This is a hard problem to solve, but it's not impossible. <span>You</span> can break the coordination trap! <span><sup id="footnote-label--2">2</sup></span></p>

<p>For example, I often send friendly DMs to combatants to share my perspective on how they could make combative Twitter threads more productive.</p>

<p>This works far better than you'd expect! In the last few years, I've DMed at least a dozen people who were being unreasonable or mean on Twitter. In all cases but one, it resulted in a constructive conversation between me and that person. In most cases, that in turn led to a retraction of their original tweet, a clarification of their position, or a marked improvement in subsequent discourse.</p>

<p>Four things I've found that make this approach more likely to succeed:</p><ol><li><p>You must show the person that you're not trying to attack them but to make them <span>more effective</span>. You're giving them feedback on process, not a moral lecture.</p></li><li><p>Bringing it into a private space<span><sup id="footnote-label--3">3</sup></span> like DMs is crucial, because it credibly shows that you're not trying to get brownie points from your in-group by bashing them in public.</p></li><li><p>This works better if the conversation at hand is in a thread you yourself started. It's a bit like giving feedback to someone at a party you're hosting—they're more likely to respect your boundaries in a social space you created. This is not a requirement, but it helps.</p></li><li><p>Make sure you're not dealing with a grifter. A grifter is someone who benefits from perpetuating the problem and has no actual desire to solve it (despite their rhetoric that may say otherwise). If they're a grifter, all the above advice is useless. Get away from the trash fire as fast as you can.</p></li></ol>
<p>I should note, this is a lot of work. There's a reason I've only done it about a dozen times over the last few years, even though there have been far, far more opportunities to do so. </p>

<p>But if everyone tried this method just a few times a year, then we just might break through this silence and raise the quality of our digital discourse.</p>
<hr>
<p><span>Footnotes</span></p>
<p><span>Thanks to </span><span>Sebastián</span><span> Bensusan and John Backus for reading and providing feedback on drafts of this essay.</span></p>
<p><span><p><span></span><span><span>1</span></span><span></span> The technical term for these silent onlookers is "lurkers".</p></span></p><p><span><p><span></span><span>2</span><span></span> Although this post is focused on how you as an individual can make a difference one conversation at a time, I'm even more excited about the structural opportunity that platforms have to enable users to express disapproval more subtly. <span>One idea I'd really like to see platforms like Twitter or Reddit try is to provide a mechanism for low-friction, private, negative feedback. For example, you could imagine offering a button where you can downvote or thumbs-down content (i.e. the opposite of a Like), but the count is only visible to the OP and not to anyone else. </span><span>EDIT 7/4/2020:</span><span> My friend Zooko </span><a href="https://twitter.com/zooko/status/1279492581655588864">evolved</a><span> this idea slightly, and I dig the suggestion: "</span><span>Imagine a "ಠ_ಠ" button on each tweet. The poster finds out how many people *THAT THEY FOLLOW* clicked that button, but can't find out specifically who. They just know that the crowd of people *that they respect* has a certain air of disapproval."</span><span></span></p></span></p><p><span><p><span></span><span>3</span><span></span> Of course the downside of this approach is that you don't get the opportunity to spread these norms to onlookers of the conversation. This is not always the right tradeoff! Public feedback can help onlookers understand reasons why they should not admire that behavior. But doing it privately makes it much more likely that that particular person will actually change their behavior, which is what I'm optimizing for in these cases.</p></span><span andale="" mono";"="">






</span></p>
                </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://devonzuegel.com/post/the-silence-is-deafening</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23728212</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 22:33:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[2+1=4, by quinoa]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 350 | Comments 161 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23727749">thread link</a>) | @efavdb
<br/>
July 3, 2020 | https://www.efavdb.com/quinoa%20packing | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.efavdb.com/quinoa%20packing">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            
            <p>
         <img src="https://www.efavdb.com/images/quinoa.jpg">
</p>

<p>I was struck the other day by the following:  The cooking instructions on my
Bob’s tri-colored quinoa package said to combine 2 cups of water with 1 cup of
dried quinoa, which would ultimately create 4 cups of cooked quinoa.  See image&nbsp;above.</p>
<p>My first reaction was to believe that some error had been made.  However, I
then realized that the explanation was packing:  When one packs spheres or
other awkward solid geometric shapes into a container, they cannot fill the
space completely.  Little pockets of air sit between the spheres.  A quick
google search for the packing fraction of spheres gives a value of <span>\(0.75\)</span> for a
crystalline structure and about <span>\(0.64\)</span> for random packings — apparently a
universal&nbsp;law.</p>
<p>We can get a similar number out from my quinoa instructions: Suppose that
before the quinoa is cooked, the water fills its volume completely.  However,
after cooking, the water is absorbed into the quinoa and forced to share its
packing fraction.  The quinoa stays at the same packing fraction before and
after cooking, so the water must be responsible for the volume growth.  This
implies it went from 2 cups to 3,&nbsp;or
</p>
<p>\begin{eqnarray} \tag{1} \label{1}
2 = \rho \times 3,
\end{eqnarray}</p>
<p>
where <span>\(\rho\)</span> is the packing fraction of the quinoa “spheres”. We conclude that
the packing fraction is <span>\(\rho = 2/3\)</span>, very close to the googled value of <span>\(\rho
= 0.64\)</span>.</p>



             
 
                

                <hr>
    <p><a href="" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">
            <img src="https://www.efavdb.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/JonathanLinkedIn.jpg" alt="Jonathan Landy Avatar" title="Jonathan Landy">
            
        </a>
        Jonathan grew up in the midwest and then went to school at Caltech and&nbsp;UCLA. Following this, he did two postdocs, one at UCSB and one at UC Berkeley. &nbsp;His academic research focused primarily on applications of statistical mechanics, but his professional passion has always been in the mastering, development, and practical application of slick&nbsp;math methods/tools. He worked as a data-scientist at Square for four years and is now working on a quantitative investing startup.
    </p>

            






<section>
    
    

    
</section>

            <hr>
            
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.efavdb.com/quinoa%20packing</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23727749</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 21:17:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Millennium Falcon (2016)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 92 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23726762">thread link</a>) | @rbanffy
<br/>
July 3, 2020 | https://kitbashed.com/blog/a-complete-history-of-the-millennium-falcon | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://kitbashed.com/blog/a-complete-history-of-the-millennium-falcon">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <section>

        

        <section><div data-layout-label="Post Body" data-type="item" data-updated-on="1455577171362" id="item-56c257f5cf80a18166b526e7"><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1455578337095_34199"><div><h2>“She may not look like much, but she's got it where it counts, kid. I've made a lot of special modifications myself.”<p>— Han Solo</p></h2></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1521508724765_91748"><div><p>The Millennium Falcon is the most famous starship of all time, and a bonafide cultural icon in its own right.&nbsp;</p><p>But it underwent a long and arduous conceptual phase before that final iconic shape emerged; the one now blasting its way across the big screen once again.&nbsp;In fact it wasn't even known by its famous name until well into production, having up until then gone under the much more mundane moniker:&nbsp;Pirate Ship.</p><p>The conceptualization mythology as it has been related down through the decades since the film first blared across cineplexes goes that the final design, perhaps best described as a ‘mandible’d saucer’,&nbsp;was one Lucas had found in a burger with a bite taken out of it, and an olive pinned to its side.</p><p>Voila; Falcon.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_10_1456667504271_122134"><div>







 

  
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/4f209325d09a4f024c85b060/1456669875605-WXFJB1TLZZOH7R33OIAI/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kLMfXykz0PXTTE_Zu0p42epZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpx10a6pTZrm-wFwdSOxyHmr032ZJaNy7te7ixJYOrr0wvKiVu23kRzTssIIfh9wbbc/lego_millennium_falcon_burger_55c1943f65c7c105ae98e6703cd64127b6585656.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/4f209325d09a4f024c85b060/1456669875605-WXFJB1TLZZOH7R33OIAI/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kLMfXykz0PXTTE_Zu0p42epZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpx10a6pTZrm-wFwdSOxyHmr032ZJaNy7te7ixJYOrr0wvKiVu23kRzTssIIfh9wbbc/lego_millennium_falcon_burger_55c1943f65c7c105ae98e6703cd64127b6585656.jpg" data-image-dimensions="579x373" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Corellian Cheeseburger by Angus MacLane" data-load="false" data-image-id="56d304b38a65e2c2b919d5fb" data-type="image" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/4f209325d09a4f024c85b060/1456669875605-WXFJB1TLZZOH7R33OIAI/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kLMfXykz0PXTTE_Zu0p42epZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpx10a6pTZrm-wFwdSOxyHmr032ZJaNy7te7ixJYOrr0wvKiVu23kRzTssIIfh9wbbc/lego_millennium_falcon_burger_55c1943f65c7c105ae98e6703cd64127b6585656.jpg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
          
          <figcaption>
            
          </figcaption>
        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  



</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1495914232691_93807"><div><p>There are variations of that story. In some versions he was eating a burger at the time, in others he saw someone eating a burger.&nbsp;The gist remains the same and much like the <a href="http://kitbashed.com/blog/chewbacca">dog-as-copilot origin story of Chewbacca</a> it's compelling enough that it will likely stay around as part of <em>Star Wars</em> lore forever.</p><p>I don't buy it.&nbsp;</p><p>But the Falcon's conceptual development has always intrigued me because the conceptualization phase is unclear and hard to discern. I've researched this subject extensively over years and it's only recently I've been able to make out some sort of sensible process.</p><p>So this then is <em>The Complete Conceptual History of The Millennium Falcon</em>&nbsp;or <em>How I Started Worrying and Lost My Mind Completely Over a Fictional Spaceship Someone Please Do Something Send Help Why Are You Still Reading Someone Do Something</em>.</p><p>From the Adventures of Luke Starkiller, Third Draft:</p></div></div><div data-block-type="44" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1456076433030_25534"><div><p><code data-preserve-html-node="true">52. INT. MOS EISLEY SPACEPORT – DOCKING AREA 23</code></p><p><code data-preserve-html-node="true"><p>Chewbacca leads the group along a tall gantry overlooking a long Rube Goldburg[sic]-pieced together contraption, which can only be loosely called a spaceship. Luke gives Old Ben a skeptical look. Old Ben just smiles. As they approach the ship, it looks even more homemade and shabby than it did at a distance. The Wookiee calls out to someone inside the ship, but there is no reply.</p>
<p>LUKE<br>
What a piece of junk. This ship isn’t going to get us anywhere!</p>
<p>A tall figure steps out of the shadows of the imposing spacecraft.
This is HAN SOLO, a tough James Dean style starpilot about twenty-five years old. A cowboy in a starship — simple, sentimental and cocksure of himself.</p></code></p><p><code data-preserve-html-node="true">HAN<br>
This ship has been to Terminus and back. There isn’t anyplace she can’t go. She may not look like much, but she’s special. I built her myself, and there is nothing faster… What can I do for you?</code></p>
</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1456087657563_139062"><div><p>In short order, you'll get to know the work of artist and model maker Colin Cantwell who worked on <em>Star Wars</em>.&nbsp;In 2014 he <a href="https://www.juliensauctions.com/press/2014/colin-cantwell.html">put up for auction</a>&nbsp;a swath of material which hadn't been seen, and as far as I know even heard of, for nearly forty years, including <a href="http://kitbashed.com/blog/colin-cantwells-concept-art">a heap of concept art</a>&nbsp;which either preceded or was at least concurrent with the work of artist Ralph McQuarrie.</p><p>We'll touch on some of Cantwell's artwork later on, but first we have to turn our attention to a very, very special piece of yellow legal pad paper which was part of that auction but which — it turned out afterwards despite what <a href="http://www.julienslive.com/view-auctions/catalog/id/142/lot/59147/STAR-WARS-ORIGINAL-PRE-PRODUCTION-ART-SET-REBEL-amp-IMPERIAL-SHIPS-OUTLINE-FIRST-TIE-FIGHTER-amp-DEATH-STAR-DESIGNS">the auction listing</a>&nbsp;says — was not from Cantwell's hand.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1456888580326_212019"><div>







 

  
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/4f209325d09a4f024c85b060/1456890652590-12T1YQTUJEFHKFL1YOWQ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNPKiK96WRsg86EysDyiQwwUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8PaoYXhp6HxIwZIk7-Mi3Tsic-L2IOPH3Dwrhl-Ne3Z2WRM3Icfgi4F1DrufRfEx4Rc6P7HkKB0eflBtHnea9wYKMshLAGzx4R3EDFOm1kBS/image-asset.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/4f209325d09a4f024c85b060/1456890652590-12T1YQTUJEFHKFL1YOWQ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNPKiK96WRsg86EysDyiQwwUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8PaoYXhp6HxIwZIk7-Mi3Tsic-L2IOPH3Dwrhl-Ne3Z2WRM3Icfgi4F1DrufRfEx4Rc6P7HkKB0eflBtHnea9wYKMshLAGzx4R3EDFOm1kBS/image-asset.png" data-image-dimensions="861x1244" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="" data-load="false" data-image-id="56d6631b37013b3ec7bf6be4" data-type="image" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/4f209325d09a4f024c85b060/1456890652590-12T1YQTUJEFHKFL1YOWQ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNPKiK96WRsg86EysDyiQwwUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8PaoYXhp6HxIwZIk7-Mi3Tsic-L2IOPH3Dwrhl-Ne3Z2WRM3Icfgi4F1DrufRfEx4Rc6P7HkKB0eflBtHnea9wYKMshLAGzx4R3EDFOm1kBS/image-asset.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  



</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1456888580326_212448"><div><p>Yes, this is from the hand of <a href="https://twitter.com/jason_debord/status/704875146109014017">George Lucas</a>&nbsp;on his characteristic yellow legal pad. It's a list of ships for Cantwell to begin work on, which given that Cantwell was the first creative hire, makes this the earliest conceptual artwork for <em>Star Wars</em>,&nbsp;and therefore the holy grail for nerdy space fantasy historians.</p><p>It is too much to unpack in this Falcon-centric piece without going off the rails,&nbsp;but since this is the first time I get to address it, here are a few notes:</p><ol data-rte-list="default"><li><p><em>RF-1 (Dart)</em>; now you know what inspired the X-Wing (a name Colin Cantwell came up with)<br></p></li><li><p><em>RF-2 (Stingray)</em> never made it, but it is circular, so maybe it shows the saucer shape already on Lucas's mind?<br></p></li><li><p><em>RF-3 (WWII Torpedo Fighter) colon design</em>. The drawing seems to depict (abstractly) the cockpit of a ‘<a href="https://www.google.com/search?sa=G&amp;hl=en&amp;tbs=simg:CAES7AEa6QELEKjU2AQaAggKDAsQsIynCBpiCmAIAxIosB3AErMSwRLCErASugaxEq4dnQLVJtU5zznQOfgp1ibXOdcm5TnWORowSExAuuhQWoJhRHyn1Y6Zx8OdEUDmzJ8vAXCzrIj9lA2tHHwSqwJyXMEkrvhj_1WSuIAMMCxCOrv4IGgoKCAgBEgQ-QvpgDAsQne3BCRpXCgoKCGFpcnBsYW5lChMKEW1vZGUgb2YgdHJhbnNwb3J0CgsKCXByb3BlbGxlcgoKCghhaXJjcmFmdAobChlwcm9wZWxsZXIgZHJpdmVuIGFpcmNyYWZ0DA&amp;q=tbf+avenger&amp;tbm=isch&amp;ved=0ahUKEwivyNSCzaXLAhVMWh4KHZmfAxkQsw4ILA&amp;biw=1482&amp;bih=1203&amp;dpr=2#hl=en&amp;tbm=isch&amp;q=tbf-1+avenger&amp;imgrc=m2j1H4kiL_nJrM%3A">TBF Avenger</a>’ torpedo bomber, indicating the positions of the people, with the circle on the right being the rear-facing gun turret; and idea which might have become Episode V's Snow Speeder.<br></p></li><li><p>I-111 (Finned Sausage). Yes, that is literally what it says! Moreover, it lists “<em>Stainless Steel Rat”</em>, which is now our verified inspiration for the TIE Fighter!</p></li></ol></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1456888580326_368594"><div>







 

  
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          
        

        
          
          <figcaption>
            <p>Published by Four Square Books in 1966, 1973, 1974, 1976 &amp; 1978, cover by Eddie Jones — <a href="http://bearalley.blogspot.com/2012/08/harry-harrison-1925-2012.html">Source</a>.</p>
          </figcaption>
        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  



</div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1456888580326_421715"><div>







 

  
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          
        

        
          
          <figcaption>
            <p>A history of the TIE Fighter is out of scope, so I'll come back to it at some later date. But I think it's safe to say that 'Finned Sausage' will sit with us all for years to come. Here's Colin Cantwell's subsequence drawing.</p>
          </figcaption>
        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  



</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1456894994398_117258"><p>Our main focus however are items C and D,&nbsp;<em>Rebel Blockade Runner</em>, the ship that opens the film as we know it today, and <em>Pirate Ship</em>, a moniker it would carry throughout most of development, until it was finally renamed <em>The Millennium Falcon</em>.</p></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1456895690169_303307"><div>







 

  
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/4f209325d09a4f024c85b060/1456922826468-IVCL0S5522CWBUF997CW/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kN6cByEr5w3F7YrA9FIyfkBZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpxL-_XqJS273Q01cOn8CHuyQHjk3gOKw6s--AKPmvmAq1WvmCQQr1UBvtyjbIZzFng/image-asset.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/4f209325d09a4f024c85b060/1456922826468-IVCL0S5522CWBUF997CW/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kN6cByEr5w3F7YrA9FIyfkBZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpxL-_XqJS273Q01cOn8CHuyQHjk3gOKw6s--AKPmvmAq1WvmCQQr1UBvtyjbIZzFng/image-asset.png" data-image-dimensions="709x314" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="" data-load="false" data-image-id="56d6e0ca86db43480aa10fa6" data-type="image" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/4f209325d09a4f024c85b060/1456922826468-IVCL0S5522CWBUF997CW/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kN6cByEr5w3F7YrA9FIyfkBZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpxL-_XqJS273Q01cOn8CHuyQHjk3gOKw6s--AKPmvmAq1WvmCQQr1UBvtyjbIZzFng/image-asset.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  



</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1456895690169_303736"><div><p>The original <em>Star Wars</em>&nbsp;story went through a lot of changes as Lucas worked out its kinks, turning it from a hot mess into the story that became the final film (a process which continued throughout production, and arguably to this day), and those continuing changes makes it hard at times to know when what occurred.</p><p>What this piece of yellow paper tells us, is that the Rebel Blockade Runner and the Pirate Ship were concurrent, but that Lucas seemed in two minds regarding which one was supposed to have the "longish" design he had found.&nbsp;First it was the Blockade Runner, but then right after he seems to have changed his mind to the Pirate Ship. An ironic decision as we'll see later, when outside influence forced him to change his mind back.</p><p>He also wrote “see book cover”, although we have no idea which book is referring to. He clearly had something very specific in mind since the note is right next to that drawing (and so the sci-fi book cover trawling begins anew). This along with the <em>Stainless Steel Rat</em> reference reaffirms Lucas's approach to developing ideas and visual starting points, by trawling every science fiction book and magazine he could get his hands on.</p><p>We'll remember this bit later on, but for now, let's get introduced to our cast.</p><p>About a year and a half into his space fantasy screenplay, George Lucas hired one of the first creatives to help flesh out the world of <em>Adventures of the Luke Starkiller</em>. The studios didn't get what Lucas was selling, and his best bid was to jump start their imaginations with some visuals.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_3_1456074203728_22957"><div>







 

  
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          
        

        
          
          <figcaption>
            <p>Colin Cantwell and George Lucas inspecting an early Y-Wing model</p>
          </figcaption>
        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  



</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1456895690169_337037"><div><p>Colin Cantwell, who started “a few days or weeks” before Ralph McQuarrie (according to McQuarrie himself)&nbsp;in November of 1974, had worked with Stanley Kubrick on realizing many of the extremely complicated effects on <em>2001: A Space Odyssey</em>. He was an avid spaceship nut, a model maker and a painter to boot; a perfect fit for Lucas's space film.</p><p>He immediately set to work bringing bringing the screenplay's many vehicles to life, starting with the Y-Wing and working his way through the X-Wing, the landspeeder, the Death Star, the Jawa Sandcrawler and the so-called Pirate Ship and finally the Rebel Blockade Runner.</p><p>Cantwell is an intriguing person in his own right, and I highly recommend <a href="http://www.originalprop.com/blog/2014/11/13/colin-cantwell-video-interviews-star-wars-prototype-models-nasa/">Jason Debord's video interviews</a>&nbsp;which explore his varied career, including his work for NASA, CBS, Kubrick,&nbsp;<em>Star Wars</em>,&nbsp;<em>Close Encounters of the Third Kind</em>,&nbsp;<em>War Games</em>&nbsp;and much more.</p><p>Says <a href="https://www.facebook.com/JoeJohnstonSketchbook/posts/852331911579599">Joe Johnston</a>:</p><blockquote><p>Colin deserves a lot of credit for the initial vision of what A NEW HOPE looked like, at least in the form of its hardware. It's true that all his designs were re-designed to a varying degree but a strong Cantwell influence shows through on most of them.</p></blockquote><blockquote></blockquote><p>If the primordial ooze of <em>Star Wars</em> is Lucas's mind, then the following Ralph McQuarrie sketches are what crawled out of it.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1456895690169_352621"><div><p>Sketched on the day he received the screenplay, they represent some of the earliest visual developments on <em>Star Wars</em>.</p><p>The first sketch was the very first drawing McQuarrie made for <em>Star Wars</em>. But it is the following two, also made on that first day, that are of particular interest to us as they bear a resemblance to what we will become key to understanding the evolution of the Pirate Ship and Rebel Blockade Runner.</p><p>Note the rearward engine cluster, the elongated shape, the possibly spherical cockpit and just behind that (on the second sketch), two protruding 'pods'.</p><p>Ralph McQuarrie was another early hire and perhaps contributed more than anyone else bar Lucas himself to the success of <em>Star Wars</em>. The exact division of labor in the concept …</p></div></div></div></div></div></section></section></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://kitbashed.com/blog/a-complete-history-of-the-millennium-falcon">https://kitbashed.com/blog/a-complete-history-of-the-millennium-falcon</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://kitbashed.com/blog/a-complete-history-of-the-millennium-falcon</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23726762</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 19:29:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Lessons learned from building a commercial open-source bot development platform]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 77 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23724723">thread link</a>) | @softmodeling
<br/>
July 3, 2020 | https://livablesoftware.com/lessons-learned-building-commercial-oss-bot-platform/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://livablesoftware.com/lessons-learned-building-commercial-oss-bot-platform/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
					<p>As part of the <a href="http://botse.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2nd International Workshop on Bots in Software Engineering</a> (BotSE 2020), I gave the keynote <a href="https://www.slideshare.net/jcabot/lessons-learned-from-building-a-commercial-bot-development-platform" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">“Lessons learned from building a commercial bot development platform”</a> where I discussed some of the key aspects we have learned while building our opensource and <a href="https://modeling-languages.com/low-code-platforms-smart-apps-ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">low-code</a> chatbot development platform <a href="https://xatkit.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Xatkit</a>&nbsp; (see also the <a href="https://github.com/xatkit-bot-platform" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Xatkit organization in GitHub</a>)</p>
<p>After an introductory <a href="https://xatkit.com/chatbot-videos-presentations-xatkit/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">mini-tutorial on Xatkit</a> and explaining why the world needs yet another bot solution, I moved to discuss the struggles we are facing when trying to move Xatkit from a research prototype to a commercial-grade tool. Some of the challenges are common to any<a href="https://jordicabot.com/industrialization-of-research-tools-the-atl-case/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> industrialization effort</a> (when you’re at the same time the research team and the technology provider in charge of maturing the tool) and shared as well with any other core open source project fighting for its <a href="https://sustainoss.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">long-term sustainability</a> (a topic on which, btw, <a href="https://livablesoftware.com/bots-open-source-sustainability/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">bots can also play a key role</a>).</p>
<p>You can check the slides of my talk below but let me also highlight some of our key lessons learned in building a chatbot platform for you, ranging from organizational, technical, and business challenges:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Organizational challenges</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>You need to be a Polymath to create a bot platform</strong>. Plenty of core bot tech: NLU, Sentiment Analysis, Xtext, Slack/GH/… APIs,…., but even more non-bot tech: InfluxDB, Nginx, eCharts, React, web sockets, Docker… that you’ll need to master when building a bot platform.</li>
<li>Commercial-grade quality involves<strong> spending more and more time on “boring” tasks</strong> as you need to polish all aspects of the tool (interface, docs,…) that you can easily skip when just building a prototype.</li>
<li><strong>Common challenges to any OSS project</strong> like attracting contributors, giving support to <a href="https://livablesoftware.com/5-ways-to-thank-open-source-maintainers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">users that don’t even say thank you</a> or the cost of maintaining external contributions (e.g. connectors) especially when the core is still evolving</li>
<li><strong>Being pragmatic.</strong> Make sure everything you do has a good Return of Investment. Example: we went from having official releases, to core releases to no releases (compile from sources). Also, we don’t support older versions and don’t keep backward compatibility. These are all things that would be nice to have but that we cannot afford.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Technical challenges</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Eat your own chatbot food</strong> for a better language. Evolving your DSLs is expensive, try to design a variety of bots to make sure your language is expressive enough for your needs (e.g. when we moved to our current <a href="https://xatkit.com/chatbot-dsl-state-machines-xatkit-language/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">state-machine language semantics</a>, we had to reimplement the editor, the examples, the docs,…</li>
<li><strong>Combine textual and graphical notations</strong>. Textual for writing + <a href="https://xatkit.com/graphical-rendering-of-your-chatbot-models/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Graphical for Reading</a></li>
<li>Do not reinvent the wheel. <strong>We came close to reinvent Java!</strong> (and moved to <a href="https://www.eclipse.org/Xtext/documentation/305_xbase.html#xbase-language-ref-introduction" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Xbase</a>)</li>
<li>Think long-term. <strong>Research prototypes are pure technical debt</strong></li>
<li>Security. <strong>Are you protected against DDoS attacks via a bot?. </strong>It’s not only a security concern but also an economical one if you’re paying to an external provider (e.g. DialogFlow) to process your input texts. There are also privacy concerns if you keep the session data for further <a href="https://xatkit.com/dashboard-monitoring-chatbot/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">bot monitoring and analysis</a>.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Natural Language Processing</strong>
<ul>
<li>NLP engines don’t speak Catalan. Once you’re out of the mainstream languages (English, Spanish, French,….) you may need to combine several NLP engines to cover well the languages you’re interested in.</li>
<li><strong>NLP engines are not bilingual. </strong>In some countries, bots should be able to combine different languages <strong>in the same conversation</strong></li>
<li><strong>Everybody seems interested in having sex with a bot.</strong> Trolls are also a huge problem with bots. As a brand you don’t want to risk going viral because your bot gave the wrong response to a Troll question.</li>
<li><strong>Reusable intent libraries</strong>. You don’t want to define again <em>Greetings</em>, <em>Thank You</em> or <em>Troll</em> intents.</li>
<li><strong>Testing chatbots is a largely unexplored area</strong> • <a href="https://xatkit.com/testing-chatbots-with-botium-and-xatkit/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">We use Botium to record conversation</a>s to be used as test cases but need much more (e.g. automatic generation of test cases)</li>
<li><strong>More training sentences are not always better.</strong> Overall quality may decrease if they start overlapping with sentences for other intents.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Business</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Most end-users do not want to define chatbots.</strong> It doesn’t matter how nice is your interface. They just want to give you their data and get a bot from you.</li>
<li><strong>Find your niche. </strong>There are over a hundred bot solutions out there. Choose wisely your domain (e.g. <a href="https://xatkit.com/free-chatbot-wordpress-plugin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">our WordPress plugin</a>) and your business model. E.g. Consider Selling a service (such as our consulting and <a href="https://xatkit.com/digital-assistant-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">managed chatbot hosting services</a>) and not a tool.</li>
<li><strong>Understand what really matters to your future clients</strong>. You’ll be surprised. For instance, making sure the color of your chatbot widget perfectly matches the look and feel of their website may be more important to them that your latest cool AI-based feature.</li>
<li><strong>Help your clients understand what their visitors want to use the bot for. </strong>You think you know what your visitors will want to use the bot for but in reality, you don’t. So having a dashboard to monitor the conversations the bot doesn’t know how to answer is vital.</li>
<li><strong>Self-learning bots</strong>. Your clients will want that but it’s risky. You don’t want the bot to learn the wrong things.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>At the end of the talk I also emphasized why we belive you should consider using Xatkit</p>
<ul>
<li>As <strong>a bot teaching platform. </strong>If you teach any course involving bots, chatbots, NLP or DSLs / software modeling and are looking for a use-case or a ready-to-use bot platform for experimentation we’ll be happy to help with materials and assistance and even (remote) seminars</li>
<li>As <strong>a bot research platform</strong>. In many bot-related research, researchers spend a significant amount of time putting together the bot pieces they need to create their bots and/or run their experiments. We ask you not to reinvent the wheel and, instead, <strong>adopt Xatkit as base platform.</strong> You’ll benefit from all Xatkit features and connectors to have powerful bots with less effort and will be able to spend more time on the core research aspects</li>
</ul>


<p>Of course, mine was just one of the many interesting talks that took place in the workshop. In the <a href="http://botse.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">BotSE</a> website, you have the full program and links to the videos and slides of all presentations (e.g. don’t miss the great <a href="https://probot.github.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Probot</a> talk by <a href="https://dev.to/gr2m/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gregor Martynus</a>). Thanks again to <a href="http://das.encs.concordia.ca/members/emad-shihab/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Emad Shihab</a>, <a href="https://www.iste.uni-stuttgart.de/institute/team/Wagner-00017/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Stefan Wagner</a> and <a href="https://www.ime.usp.br/~gerosa/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Marco A. Gerosa</a> for inviting me!.</p>
<p>As always, any feedback is appreciated! If you have questions or comments on how to build bots or bot development platforms, share them below!</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://livablesoftware.com/lessons-learned-building-commercial-oss-bot-platform/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23724723</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 15:17:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[There's never been an easier time to write your own language (2016)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 75 | Comments 47 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23723803">thread link</a>) | @lowmemcpu
<br/>
July 3, 2020 | https://joshsharp.com.au/blog/never-been-an-easier-time-to-write-a-language.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://joshsharp.com.au/blog/never-been-an-easier-time-to-write-a-language.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <div>

            

            <p>As programming matures and shifts to higher-level abstractions, it becomes more and more about assembling
pre-made building blocks and less about writing new, novel solutions of your own. When I create web apps
(the bread and butter of my day job) I'm using an open-source OS, programming language, database, database
connector library, web server, web framework, authentication libraries, API libraries, payment service libraries...
You get the idea. Increasingly the code I write is "glue" code, simply binding together my building
blocks in the correct order, like a more complicated <a href="https://ifttt.com/">IFTTT</a>, or textual Lego.</p>

<p>It's not surprising that this collection of building blocks is expanding to encompass ever-more-complicated
areas of programming. Today, it's possible to build a simple programming language in the same way you'd
build a web app.</p>


<h3 id="what-s-involved-in-writing-a-language-">What's involved in writing a language?</h3>
<p>The components of a language usually boil down to a "front-end" and a "back-end".</p>
<p>The front-end traditionally consists of a lexer, for turning raw source code into tokens based on grammar
rules, and a parser, for turning tokens into an Abstract Syntax Tree, or AST — nested blocks that represent
operations.</p>
<p>The back-end is the "compiler" which performs steps like type-checking, optimisation, and finally converting
the AST into a lower-level representation. If you're writing an interpreted language, this lower-level is
probably bytecode, rather than an executable, and a corresponding interpreter which reads
and performs bytecode instructions. For example, Python is an interpreted language where <code>.py</code> denotes the raw
source code file, and <code>.pyc</code> the compiled bytecode. When first running a <code>.py</code> file, Python will build a
bytecode-compiled equivalent it can run next time (until your source changes, anyway). If instead you're writing
a compiled language, your back-end builds native executables that can be run directly by the OS.</p>
<p>So once you have a grammar for your syntax, to plug into your front-end, and you can compile the resulting
AST with your back-end, what else is there to do? Well, don't forget about writing a standard library —
defining your built-in types, classes (if you have those), and all of the standard functions to
operate on them. This step is at least as much work.</p>
<h3 id="why-is-it-so-easy-then-">Why is it so easy then?</h3>
<p>If you're writing a language today, many of the parts we defined above already exist for you. Your back-end
and your front-end can both be built out of existing parts.</p>
<p>There are plenty of lexers and parsers available — for example, Lexx and Yacc are a venerable
lexing and parsing combo that have spawned countless modern interpretations. <a href="https://rply.readthedocs.org/">RPly</a>
(RPython Lexx/Yacc) is my current tool of choice in this area. If you use a lexer and parser, the work
left for you is to write your grammar rules, objects representing your AST, and simple functions
telling the parser how to turn grammar into AST. Defining a grammar and an AST are fun! If your syntax
is simple, this step probably won't be that hard either.</p>
<p>For the back-end, <a href="http://llvm.org/">LLVM</a> is the most well-known and respected tool for the job. LLVM powers Clang,
a C and C++ compiler, and other well-known languages like Rust and Swift. The beauty of LLVM is its
Intermediate Representation, or IR. IR looks a lot like assembly language, or really ugly C, but if
you're up for translating your language to LLVM IR, LLVM will take care of optimising and compiling this to a
native executable for you! This is huge. It can even be run in interpreted mode for debugging, or used
as a Just-In-Time (JIT) compiler within your interpreter, if that's your jam.</p>
<p>Fortunately you needn't write IR by hand. Because LLVM has a C interface, there are many LLVM libraries
in many languages to help you create your IR. <a href="http://llvmlite.pydata.org/">Llvm-lite</a> is the most mature Python binding I found,
and what I'm currently using. Essentially, using llvm-lite means you can ask it to create a new function definition for you,
for example, and it'll take care of generating the right IR syntax, and give you back a higher-level interface
for managing variables and code blocks within.</p>
<p>So with this combination of pieces, many of the trickiest parts of writing a language can be wholly outsourced.</p>
<p>Let me give you a concrete example. I'll use my current toy language, written in Python, to demonstrate
how it all goes together:</p>
<ul>
<li>I write a list of tokens (essentially a set of strings) in Python, and feed them to RPly's lexer</li>
<li>I create a Python class to represent each type of AST node or block of code (a function, an if statement, and so on)</li>
<li>I write a set of grammar rules in Python, telling it how to turn tokens into AST instances, and feed them to RPly's parser</li>
<li>I write a compiler class which can turn each AST type into LLVM IR using llvm-lite</li>
</ul>
<p>Then, to compile some source code:</p>
<ul>
<li>The lexer turns my source into tokens</li>
<li>The parser turns tokens into AST</li>
<li>The compiler turns AST into IR, and dumps it to a file</li>
<li>I use the <code>llc</code> tool to compile from IR to an object file</li>
<li>I use <code>gcc</code> to compile that file into an executable</li>
</ul>
<p>Voila, a working program I can run. It can't do much without a standard library, but if I define
the grammar and AST for some "binary operations" like addition and substraction, I can compile
simple arithmetic and return or print the result.</p>
<p>What I'm trying to get at is that once you decide on a grammar for your language, most of the code you
write is glue, turning output from one library into input for another. Of course, this glue code
can get quite complex, but for the modern language developer, so much is already done for you and ready
to plug in. If you have some ideas for a language, it's never been easier to try them out.</p>
            
            <p><a href="#">To top</a></p>        </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://joshsharp.com.au/blog/never-been-an-easier-time-to-write-a-language.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23723803</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 13:27:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Building a BASIC Interpreter, '80s style]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 74 | Comments 11 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23723179">thread link</a>) | @new_here
<br/>
July 3, 2020 | https://able.bio/kerrishotts/building-a-basic-interpreter-80s-style--79a9d703 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://able.bio/kerrishotts/building-a-basic-interpreter-80s-style--79a9d703">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It’s funny the rabbit holes one ends up. One of my personal projects for several years has been the creation (exploration, really) of a “fake emulator” — that is, an emulator for a computer that never existed all written in JavaScript. Instead, the machine would pay homage to the eight and sixteen bit machines of the 1980s and ‘90s.</p>
<p>I like to do things the hard way, though: this machine would also be based on a novel instruction set as well. The instruction set would be similar to that of the era, but also be a little easier to use. And so, <a href="https://github.com/kerrishotts/retroputer" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer">Retroputer</a> was born. Over several years, the implementation has been built out and improved, although it’ll probably never be “complete” (it’s a personal exploration, after all).</p>
<p>Then @bbcmicrobot became a thing, and I wanted to be able to do a similar thing for Retroputer. My JS development skills are mostly in the arena of the front-end, and so this would be a cool way to get some more back-end skills. One problem: Retroputer could only understand its own assembly language. It had no BASIC support yet.</p>
<p>And so here I am, building a BASIC interpreter, ‘80s style — that is, entirely in assembly language, just like it used to be done. And I thought I’d share that journey, since it’s not often we delve into areas so far from our typical abstractions. My daily driver (JavaScript) makes a lot of things trivial and sometimes those things feel magical. Understanding the lowest levels of the process can often help with understanding those abstractions.</p>
<p>And so… let’s begin.</p>
<h2 id="parsing-in-low-level-assembly-language">Parsing in Low-Level Assembly Language</h2>
<p>When I wrote the assembler for Retroputer, I was able to use a really nice tool called Pegjs. This made quick work of the assembler’s custom syntax, but was unfortunately there’s nothing like it for Retroputer ASM.</p>
<p>Which means we have to do it the hard way.</p>
<p>Parsing actually occurs in multiple phases. A language that uses a compiler parses the code into an abstract syntax tree (or similar concept), and can then use that tree to generate the resulting native code. A consequence of this is that the program must be syntactically correct in order for the compilation to be successful.</p>
<p>Some interpreters today also have this concept because it’s often useful to generate the intermediate AST and execute from there than it is to execute from the original source.</p>
<p>But for a BASIC interpreter in a machine with limited resources, the most resource-effective way to parse is to do it in multiple phases — some of which occurs at run time. This means, however, that syntax errors often can’t be detected until the program is run and the area of code with the error is encountered.</p>
<p>The three phases of Retroputer BASIC parsing are as follows:</p>
<ol>
<li>Line Transformation</li>
<li>Tokenization</li>
<li>Runtime Syntax Checking</li>
</ol>
<p>The first two steps occur as the user enters a program (or loads one). The last one occurs while the program is running. Essentially, the first two build out the rough scaffolding of an airplane, but with no guarantee of flight. The last step is essentially acting as a test pilot — hoping you’ll get off the ground, but not knowing until you try.</p>
<p>Thankfully Retroputer BASIC doesn’t come with such dire consequences for raising an error during runtime.</p>
<p><em><strong>Note:</strong></em> Source code (in progress) for Retroputer BASIC is <a href="https://github.com/kerrishotts/retroputer/tree/master/asm/kernel/basic" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer">available on GitHub</a>.</p>
<h2 id="line-transformation">Line Transformation</h2>
<p>This is the easiest part of the entire process. Essentially, the line that the user enters is converted to uppercase so that later processes are easier (and faster). BASIC is not sensitive to case, and so we can use that to our advantage.</p>
<pre><code>print 2+2
' becomes:
PRINT 2+2
</code></pre>
<p>Doing this in JavaScript is easy, right?</p>
<pre><code>theLine = theLine.toUpperCase();
</code></pre>
<p>But in assembly language, we have to be more detailed about how things get done. We need to read in a character, convert it to uppercase, and then store it somewhere.</p>
<pre><code>           ld  y,  0                # y is our index
_loop:     ld  al, [d, x, y]        # [d,x] is pointer to string
           cmp al, 97               # is al (char) in range?
           brs n   _continue        # Not a lowercase char; continue
           cmp al, 123              # high portion
           brs !n  _continue        # not a lowercase char; continue
           and al, 0b1101_1111      # uppercase!
           st  [d, x, y], al        # store back (we modify the original)
_continue: inc y                    # move our index along
           cmp al, 0                # check for NULL
           brs !z _loop             # No? Go back for more.
</code></pre>
<p>The above doesn’t quite match the same semantics as the JavaScript version. One important difference is that we now use Unicode to work with text, and so converting input from lowercase to uppercase can often be more difficult — and maybe impossible (depending on the language). Retroputer lives in the world of ASCII (rather, it’s own variation, named RetSCII), meaning that all supported characters are encoded into eight bits. This is woefully inadequate for many languages, but also true to the period.</p>
<p>It also means that we can use a nice feature of ASCII to convert from lowercase to uppercase. It turns out that uppercase “A” is represented with <code>65</code> in ASCII, and lowercase “a” is represented with <code>97</code>. If you’re familiar with your powers-of-two, that difference should catch your eye.</p>
<p>So it turns out that lowercase letters are represented with a number that’s exactly 32 above the uppercase letter. Once we know something’s in range, all we need to do is subtract 32!</p>
<p>That works, but we could just do some bit twiddling. For Retroputer this wouldn’t actually be any faster than subtraction, but avoiding subtraction means we don’t have to worry about the carry/borrow flag during arithmetic. It turns out we can use a bitwise <code>and</code> to turn off the bit for the 32 place value instead.</p>
<pre><code>and al, 0b1101_1111         # turn off bit in 32-place
# versus
clr c                       # clear carry
sub al, 32                  # subtract 32
</code></pre>
<p>But there’s a catch: not <em>everything</em> can be converted to uppercase. If the user has included a string literal, for example, we have to be more careful. After all, we don’t want Retroputer BASIC to scream at the user all the time, right? (Although many computers of the era didn’t have lowercase capability, Retroputer doesn’t share that same limitation.)</p>
<p>For example:</p>
<pre><code>print "Hello, World!"
' should become:
PRINT "Hello, World!"
' and not
PRINT "HELLO, WORLD!"
</code></pre>
<p>This means we need to keep track of whether or not we’re in the middle of a string literal. In BASIC, there’s only one signifier for this: the double quote. If we check if a character is a double quote, we can set a flag, and depending on the flag’s value, we can perform an uppercase operation or leave things alone.</p>
<p>It turns out that in JavaScript there’s no built-in to accomplish this, but we can build one:</p>
<pre><code>const len = theLine.length;
let insideString = false;
for (let i = 0; i &lt; len; i++) {
    const ch = theLine[i];
    if (ch === `"`) insideString = !insideString;
    if (!insideString) {
        const newCh = ch.toUpperCase();
        if (ch !== newCh) theLine[i] = newCh;
    }
}
</code></pre>
<p>Now the logic of the JS more closely matches that of the assembly version, although we’re taking advantage of JS’s unicode support a bit more.</p>
<p>The assembly version looks like this:</p>
<pre><code>           ld  y,  0                # y is our index
           ld  bl, 0                # === insideString (false)
_loop:     ld  al, [d, x, y]        # [d,x] is pointer to string
           cmp al, 34               # is al a double quote?
           brs !z  check_char       # no? should we uppercase it?
           xor bl, 0xFF             # yes? toggle insideString
_check_char:
           cmp bl, 0xFF             # inside a string?
           brs z   _continue        # yes? don't modify it
           cmp al, 97               # is al (char) in range? "a"
           brs n   _continue        # Not a lowercase char; continue
           cmp al, 123              # high portion           "z"
           brs !n  _continue        # not a lowercase char; continue
           and al, 0b1101_1111      # uppercase!
           st  [d, x, y], al        # store back (we modify the original)
_continue: inc y                    # move our index along
           cmp al, 0                # check for NULL
           brs !z _loop             # No? Go back for more.
</code></pre>
<p>So far all we’ve done is transform the input text to uppercase, but there’s one extra benefit here in the way we’ve had to track if we’re inside a string. We can do one round of syntax checking here!</p>
<p>If, at the end of the process we find that <code>inString</code> is still true (<code>bl = 0xFF</code>), we can trigger an error, because it means that there’s an unterminated string literal somewhere in the line.</p>
<p><em><strong>Side note:</strong></em> It turns out many BASICs are quite lenient when it comes to terminating quotes for strings. One of many things I learned while building my own interpreter. Even so, it doesn’t feel right to me, and so Retroputer BASIC doesn’t permit it.</p>
<h2 id="tokenization">Tokenization</h2>
<p>The next phase of parsing involves converting an entered line into something more efficient for Retroputer BASIC to execute. This is as close to the concept of an abstract syntax tree that we’ll get here — the result will definitely not be a tree. But it will be something that we can quickly evaluate during runtime.</p>
<p>One common feature of early microcomputers was a very limited memory capacity. Retroputer has more memory than most machines of the time had by default, but it still has much less than modern machines. As such, long BASIC programs could easily consume far too much memory if they were stored as the user typed them.</p>
<p>To save space, keywords are <em>tokenized</em> as the program is entered into memory. This process converts keywords into single-byte tokens. Keywords are always at least two bytes long, and so this savings can add up. It also means that we can use a lookup table during execution to call the appropriate assembly language routines.</p>
<p>Retroputer BASIC goes a little further than most BASICs of the time, …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://able.bio/kerrishotts/building-a-basic-interpreter-80s-style--79a9d703">https://able.bio/kerrishotts/building-a-basic-interpreter-80s-style--79a9d703</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://able.bio/kerrishotts/building-a-basic-interpreter-80s-style--79a9d703</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23723179</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 11:49:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Sphere Eversion]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 198 | Comments 45 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23722275">thread link</a>) | @colinprince
<br/>
July 3, 2020 | https://rreusser.github.io/explorations/sphere-eversion/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rreusser.github.io/explorations/sphere-eversion/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Topology is the study of the properties of geometric objects which aren’t changed by continuous deformation. A standard low-grade math joke is that toplogists consider a coffee mug and a doughnut equivalent because they’re both torii—(pauses for laughter)—one can be continuously deformed into the other, called a <em>homeomorphism</em>, without cutting or creasing the surface.</p><figure><img src="https://rreusser.github.io/explorations/sphere-eversion/static/images/Mug_and_Torus_morph.gif"><figcaption>
    Homeomorphism between a doughnut and a mug. Source: <a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Mug_and_Torus_morph.gif">Wikipedia</a></figcaption></figure><p>In this post, we play a topological game called <em>eversion</em>. Our objective is simple: turn a sphere inside out without cutting or creasing it. We consider a sphere, though a torus is also an <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kQcy5DvpvlM">interesting challenge</a>.</p><p>That a sphere (specifically the two-sphere <span><span> <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><msup><mi>S</mi><mn>2</mn></msup></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">S^2</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> </span></span> embedded in three dimensional space <span><span> <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><msup><mi mathvariant="double-struck">R</mi><mn>3</mn></msup></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">\mathbb{R}^3</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> </span></span>) can be turned inside out was proved by Stephen Smale in 1957. However the proof is a proof of existence, offering no particular guidance for those hoping to perform the feat.</p><figure><img src="https://rreusser.github.io/explorations/sphere-eversion/static/images/2d.jpg" idyll="[object Object]"><figcaption>
    Circle eversion in two dimensions is impossible. We always get stuck!</figcaption></figure><p>We should take a moment to appreciate that the analogous problem of everting a circle in two dimensions is impossible. The figure above illustrates that there’s really nothing to do but introduce loops which we can’t then get rid of. Don’t take my word for it though! The classic video <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wO61D9x6lNY">Outside In</a> has an much more involved discussion of what happens when we try.</p><p>Since the original proof, a number of realizations of sphere eversion have been discovered, ranging in generality and complexity. This post follows the method of Bednorz and Bednorz from <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1711.10466">Analytic sphere eversion using ruled surfaces</a>.</p><p>Before stepping through the eversion, we lay out our ground rules, of which there are just two: We may not cut the surface, and the surface must always remain smooth.  Note that unlike physical objects, self-intersection <em>is</em> permitted.</p><h2 id="bednorz’-sphere-eversion">Bednorz’ Sphere Eversion</h2><p>We start with a full presentation of the sphere eversion of Bednorz and Bednorz in <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1711.10466">Analytic sphere eversion using ruled surfaces</a>. It goes by quickly, so we’ll then break it down and try to understand it a bit better. Along the way, you can drag the slider at the top to examine cross-sections.</p><p>
Quality: </p></div><div><p>Success! But that all happened very quickly. What happens at the top is clearly the key. In some sense, we do simply push one end of the sphere right through the other, but we need some clever tricks to keep the hole at the top smooth.</p><p>Bednorz and Bednorz break down the method as follows. As long as nothing topologically interesting happens at the poles of the sphere, we can simply remove them from the equation and focus on a cylindrical band around the equator. All that’s left then is to manipulate the cylindrical band carefully and replace the poles at the end of the process.</p><p>The key element of their method is a family of <em><a href="https://mathworld.wolfram.com/RuledSurface.html">ruled surfaces</a></em>, or surfaces swept out by a straight line moving through space, which accomplish this task. They propose a family parameterized by time <span><span> <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mi>t</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">t</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> </span></span>. They’re careful to prove the surface remains smooth during the process, but we’ll remain content to get to our destination and visually check the smoothness along the way.</p><p>They propose the family of ruled surfaces given by the equations</p><p><span><span> <span><span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mtable><mtr><mtd><mstyle scriptlevel="0" displaystyle="true"><mrow><mi>x</mi></mrow></mstyle></mtd><mtd><mstyle scriptlevel="0" displaystyle="true"><mrow><mrow></mrow><mo>=</mo><mi>t</mi><mi>cos</mi><mo>⁡</mo><mi>ϕ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>p</mi><mi>sin</mi><mo>⁡</mo><mo>(</mo><mi>n</mi><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>)</mo><mi>ϕ</mi><mo>−</mo><mi>h</mi><mi>sin</mi><mo>⁡</mo><mi>ϕ</mi></mrow></mstyle></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mstyle scriptlevel="0" displaystyle="true"><mrow><mi>y</mi></mrow></mstyle></mtd><mtd><mstyle scriptlevel="0" displaystyle="true"><mrow><mrow></mrow><mo>=</mo><mi>t</mi><mi>sin</mi><mo>⁡</mo><mi>ϕ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>p</mi><mi>cos</mi><mo>⁡</mo><mo>(</mo><mi>n</mi><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>)</mo><mi>ϕ</mi><mo>+</mo><mi>h</mi><mi>cos</mi><mo>⁡</mo><mi>ϕ</mi></mrow></mstyle></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mstyle scriptlevel="0" displaystyle="true"><mrow><mi>z</mi></mrow></mstyle></mtd><mtd><mstyle scriptlevel="0" displaystyle="true"><mrow><mrow></mrow><mo>=</mo><mi>h</mi><mi>sin</mi><mo>⁡</mo><mi>n</mi><mi>ϕ</mi><mo>−</mo><mo>(</mo><mi>t</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">/</mi><mi>n</mi><mo>)</mo><mi>cos</mi><mo>⁡</mo><mi>n</mi><mi>ϕ</mi><mo>−</mo><mi>q</mi><mi>t</mi><mi>h</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">.</mi></mrow></mstyle></mtd></mtr></mtable></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">
\begin{aligned}
x &amp;= t \cos \phi + p \sin (n - 1) \phi - h \sin \phi \\
y &amp;= t \sin \phi + p \cos (n - 1) \phi + h \cos \phi \\
z &amp;= h \sin n \phi - (t / n) \cos n \phi - qth.
\end{aligned}
</annotation></semantics></math></span></span></span> </span></span></p><p>The variable <span><span> <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mi>ϕ</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">\phi</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> </span></span> parameterizes the polar angle of the cylinder from <span><span> <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mo>−</mo><mi>π</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">-\pi</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> </span></span> to <span><span> <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mi>π</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">\pi</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> </span></span> while <span><span> <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mi>h</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">h</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> </span></span> parameterizes the vertical dimension of the cylinder. They suggest <span><span> <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mi>q</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>2</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">/</mi><mn>3</mn></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">q = 2/3</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> </span></span> and <span><span> <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mi>p</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>−</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">∣</mi><mi>q</mi><mi>t</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">∣</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">p = 1 - |qt|</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> </span></span>.</p><p>Adjust the time parameter <span><span> <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mi>t</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">t</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> </span></span> and observe the shape of the surface. There are two particular things to note. First, the surface always remains smooth, despite self-intersections, and second, the top and bottom of the edges of the cylinder swap places (with a bit of rotation which doesn’t trouble us) as we move from <span><span> <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mi>t</mi><mo>=</mo><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">.</mi><mn>5</mn></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">t = -1.5</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> </span></span> to <span><span> <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mi>t</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>1</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">.</mi><mn>5</mn></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">t = 1.5</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> </span></span>.</p><p>Note also that although we’ll visualize eversion with <span><span> <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mi>n</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>2</mn></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">n = 2</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> </span></span>, the eversion also works for values greater than two.</p><p> t = <span>1.500000</span><br> n = <span>2</span><br></p><figure idyll="[object Object]"><figcaption idyll="[object Object]">
    The proposed cylindrical ruled surface.
  </figcaption></figure><p>Of course we want to evert a full sphere and not just a cylindrical band, so the remainder of their paper focuses on using stereographic projections to smoothly close the caps of the cylindrical band and maintain the topology of the sphere during the entire process. The full eversion is illustrated above, but let’s now step back through it, taking a bit more care to focus on the region of interest.</p></div><div><p>And that’s that! I regret that I have nothing novel or nuanced to say about the eversion itself, but my goal here was to explore the visual presentation since videos and images always left me wishing it were a bit more tangible.</p><p>There’s no shortage of really great visualizations and resources regarding sphere eversion, among other topics. Below are a few links relevant to both this eversion and the topic in general.</p><ul><li><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1711.10466">Analytic sphere eversion using ruled surfaces</a></li><li><a href="https://www.fuw.edu.pl/~abednorz/eversion/index.html">Adam Bednorz Sphere Eversion</a>: a webpage with videos and DIY instructions using paper<!-- -->!</li><li><a href="https://www3.math.tu-berlin.de/geometrie/wp_padilla/sphere-eversion-with-transparency-video/">Visualization by Marcel Padilla</a></li><li><a href="https://chrishills.org.uk/ChrisHills/sphereeversion/">Everting a Sphere by Chris Hills</a>: an excellent collection of links and resources</li><li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sphere_eversion">Sphere Eversion on Wikipedia</a></li></ul><p>
This post is created using <a href="https://idyll-lang.org/">idyll</a> and <a href="https://github.com/regl-project/regl">regl</a>. You can find the full article <a href="https://github.com/rreusser/explorations/tree/master/posts/sphere-eversion">source here</a>.</p><p>Comments? Questions? Corrections? <a href="https://twitter.com/rickyreusser">Let me know!</a></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rreusser.github.io/explorations/sphere-eversion/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23722275</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 08:52:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[QuickBasic64: Basic for the Modern Era]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 170 | Comments 47 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23722192">thread link</a>) | @daitangio
<br/>
July 3, 2020 | https://www.qb64.org/portal/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.qb64.org/portal/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">

<div id="primary">

	<main id="main" role="main">

		
			
<article id="post-156" class="page">

	
		
	
	
<div>

	
<div data-columns="1" data-layout="100"><div>
<div><div>
<h2 id="home">Get QB64 v1.4</h2>



<p>QB64 is a modern extended BASIC programming language that retains QBasic/QuickBASIC 4.5 compatibility and compiles native binaries for Windows, Linux, and macOS. <a href="#about">→ Read more</a></p>




</div></div>
</div></div>



<div>








<div>




<p>Repository hosted on<br><a href="https://github.com/QB64Team/qb64"><img src="https://www.qb64.org/portal/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/GitHub_Logo-300x123.png" alt="" width="75" height="31" srcset="https://www.qb64.org/portal/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/GitHub_Logo-300x123.png 300w, https://www.qb64.org/portal/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/GitHub_Logo-768x315.png 768w, https://www.qb64.org/portal/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/GitHub_Logo.png 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 75px) 100vw, 75px"></a></p>
</div>
</div>







<h4>SUPPORT THE PROJECT</h4>











<h4 id="about">ABOUT</h4>



<div>
<div>
<h2>From the 80s to eternity</h2>



<p><strong>How BASIC made its way into the 21st century</strong></p>



<p>The BASIC language has been the gateway into programming for countless people. Popular as a beginner programming language in the 80’s and evolving into a powerful professional tool in 90’s, BASIC (and its successor QBasic), helped many people develop a love for programming. These languages provided the foundational learning platform for most of today’s professional developers.</p>



<p>The QB64 project has evolved over the last decade to bring the magic and educational potential of BASIC from its 20th century roots into the modern era. The QB64 project is already in use in both educational and professional contexts and has an active and helpful user community.</p>



<p>Unlike traditional BASIC and QBasic code, QB64 gets compiled automatically into machine code – allowing exceptional performance, easy distribution, and the ability to link with external C and C++ programming libaries. Compatible with most QBasic 4.5 code, QB64 adds a number of extensions, such as OpenGL and other modern features, providing the perfect blend of classic and modern program development.</p>



<p>QB64 is available for all recent Windows, Linux, and macOS versions.</p>



<p><a href="#">↑ Back to top</a></p>
</div>








</div>



<p><a href="#">↑ Back to top</a></p>











<h4 id="download">DOWNLOAD</h4>



<p>You can either get the stable build or help us beta test the development build.</p>







<h2>Historical Versions</h2>



<p>Collection of old QB64 versions for historical purposes.</p>







<p><a href="#">↑ Back to top</a></p>



<div data-columns="1" data-layout="100"><div>
<div><div>
<h2>More QB64 Team software</h2>



<p>Great companions to QB64</p>
</div></div>
</div></div>



<div>




<div>
<div><figure><a href="https://www.qb64.org/vwatch"><img src="http://www.qb64.org/portal/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/beehive.png" alt="" width="128" height="128" srcset="https://www.qb64.org/portal/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/beehive.png 512w, https://www.qb64.org/portal/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/beehive-300x300.png 300w, https://www.qb64.org/portal/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/beehive-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 128px) 100vw, 128px"></a></figure></div>



<h2><a href="https://www.qb64.org/vwatch">vWATCH</a></h2>



<p>The debugging features you loved using in QuickBASIC are now available to help you squash those hard-to-find bugs in your projects. Made with QB64.</p>
</div>



<div>
<div><figure><a href="http://www.qb64.org/inform"><img src="http://www.qb64.org/portal/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Application-icon.png" alt="" width="128" height="128" srcset="https://www.qb64.org/portal/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Application-icon.png 512w, https://www.qb64.org/portal/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Application-icon-300x300.png 300w, https://www.qb64.org/portal/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Application-icon-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 128px) 100vw, 128px"></a></figure></div>



<h2><a href="https://www.qb64.org/inform">InForm</a></h2>



<p>Design feature-rich graphical interfaces that blend in perfectly with today’s Operating Systems all without leaving BASIC behind. Made with QB64.</p>
</div>




</div>



<p><a href="#">↑ Back to top</a></p>











<h4 id="utilities">UTILITIES</h4>



<p>It’s all about sharing</p>



<div>
<div>
<div><figure><a href="http://www.qb64.org/portal/basbin/"><img src="http://www.qb64.org/portal/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/paper.png" alt="" width="128" height="128" srcset="https://www.qb64.org/portal/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/paper.png 512w, https://www.qb64.org/portal/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/paper-300x300.png 300w, https://www.qb64.org/portal/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/paper-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 128px) 100vw, 128px"></a></figure></div>
</div>



<div>
<h2><a href="http://www.qb64.org/portal/basbin/">BASBin</a></h2>



<p>Need to share a code snippet but don’t need all the fuss of traditional online tools?<br>BASBin is what you’re after.<br>Just paste code, hit the button, and share the link away.<br>Files are wiped regularly, so treat it as the temporary storage it is, OK?</p>
</div>
</div>



<div>
<div>
<div><figure><a href="https://www.qb64.org/portal/binbin/"><img src="http://www.qb64.org/portal/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/code.png" alt="" width="128" height="128" srcset="https://www.qb64.org/portal/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/code.png 512w, https://www.qb64.org/portal/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/code-300x300.png 300w, https://www.qb64.org/portal/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/code-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 128px) 100vw, 128px"></a></figure></div>
</div>



<div>
<h2><a href="https://www.qb64.org/portal/binbin/">BINBin</a></h2>



<p>Or maybe you need to share an image, or other type of binary file. If that’s the case, BINBin is for you.<br>Select the file to share, hit the button, and share the link.<br>Files are wiped regularly, so treat it as the temporary storage it is, OK?</p>
</div>
</div>



<p><a href="#">↑ Back to top</a></p>





</div><!-- .page-content -->

	
</article><!-- #post-## -->

			
		
	</main><!-- #main -->

</div><!-- #primary -->


		</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.qb64.org/portal/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23722192</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 08:37:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Intro to Fully Homomorphic Encryption]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 120 | Comments 30 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23721661">thread link</a>) | @yuedongze
<br/>
July 2, 2020 | http://blog.higashi.tech/2020/06/16/fhe_01.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://blog.higashi.tech/2020/06/16/fhe_01.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <h2 id="preface">Preface</h2>

<p>Recently I have taken <a href="https://cs355.stanford.edu/"><strong>CS355 (Topics in Cryptography)</strong></a> at Stanford. This was a comprehensive course on advanced crypto topics.</p>

<p>Throughout the 3-month course, the instructors covered various topics that span the history of Cryptography, starting from One-way Functions, PRFs all the way to applied cryptosystems such as <strong>MPC, Zero-Knowledge, and PIR</strong>. This was really a great course to take, and I’ve surely learned a lot about modern cryptosystems.</p>

<p>In order to strengthen my understanding of these topics, I’ve decided to start a series of blog posts that (gently) introduces these cool crypto topics. I’ll be summarizing lecture notes and paraphrase them into my own words. Hopefully, it should be an interesting (and not obscure) read that helps you understand these topics as well.</p>

<p>For the first series of posts, I want to talk about <strong>Fully Homomorphic Encryption (FHE)</strong>, a fairly hot topic in the security industry.</p>

<p><em>Note that I’ll try to make my explanation as simple as possible, but still make sure that you have some security/cryptography context before continuing…</em></p>

<p><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1510511459019-5dda7724fd87?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2100&amp;q=80" alt=""></p>

<h2 id="what-is-fhe">What is FHE?</h2>

<p>I shall begin the post with a brief introduction of FHE, or <strong>Fully Homomorphic Encryption</strong>.</p>

<p>According to Wikipedia, the definition of Homomorphic Encryption is:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>A form of encryption that allows computation on ciphertexts, generating an encrypted result which, when decrypted, matches the result of the operations as if they had been performed on the plaintext.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The definition is exactly right - Homomorphic Encryption is simply the encryption scheme where one can combine encrypted ciphertexts and obtain interesting computations on the original plaintext in an encrypted form without knowing the actual encryption key.</p>

<h3 id="an-overview-of-encryption-schemes">An Overview of Encryption Schemes</h3>

<p>If you are familiar with crypto/security materials, you might know a few common encryption schemes such as AES and RSA. Although there’s a difference between symmetric and asymmetric encryption schemes, every scheme could be generalized in the following form.</p>


<p>
graph LR;
	G((KeyGen)) -.- pk(EncKey)
	G -.- sk(DecKey)
	pk --&gt; Encryption
	sk --&gt; Decryption
	Plaintext --&gt; Encryption
	Encryption --&gt; Ciphertext
	Ciphertext --&gt; Decryption
	Decryption --&gt; Pt2[Plaintext]
</p>

<p>From the diagram, we can see the overall composition of an encryption scheme:</p>

<ol>
  <li>There is a \(KeyGen\) algorithm that generates the key used for both encrypting and decrypting. Notice that in a symmetric scheme both keys are the same, and in an asymmetric scheme the keys are different. (One is called Public Key and the other is called Private Key)</li>
  <li>The \(Encryption\) algorithm applies encryption to a given plaintext using the encryption key. Then it produces the ciphertext, which is the encrypted plaintext.</li>
  <li>The \(Decryption\) algorithm inverts the encryption done on a ciphertext using the decryption key. It restores the ciphertext back to the original plaintext.</li>
</ol>

<p>There it is. It doesn’t matter which algorithm we use (AES or RSA or something else), the overall structure is always the same.</p>

<p>In Cryptography, we tend to always write about <strong>properties</strong> of a system after introducing it. Therefore, I should also talk about it for the sake of completeness.</p>

<p>First, an encryption needs to have <strong>Correctness</strong>. This means that applying decryption on a ciphertext that was the result of applying encryption on some plaintext \(pt\), using the keys derived from \(KeyGen\), will always guarantee to result in the same plaintext \(pt\) as before. To capture this relation in the language of probability, we use the following expression:</p><p>

\[\forall pt \in PT, (k_{enc}, k_{dec}) \leftarrow KeyGen(1^\lambda):\\
Pr[Decryption(k_{dec}, Encryption(k_{enc}, pt)) = pt] = 1\]

</p><p>This means that the <strong>probability</strong> of applying decryption on encrypted ciphertext using the appropriate keys will <strong>always result in the exact same plaintext</strong> as before.</p>

<p>The second property that we want is <strong>Semantic Security</strong>. I’m not going to do the full proof here, but the basic idea is that, given two encrypted ciphertexts \(ct_0, ct_1\) that corresponds to the encryption of \(pt_0, pt_1\), one cannot distinguish which ciphertext is the encryption of \(ct_0\). This basically means that the encrypted ciphertext looks random and doesn’t provide any hint to its original plaintext, therefore ensuring that this scheme is secure against eavesdropping.</p>

<p><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1526732928503-5c58853877ae?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1650&amp;q=80" alt=""></p>

<h3 id="homomorphic-encryption---an-unexpected-property">Homomorphic Encryption - an unexpected property</h3>

<p>If encrypted ciphertexts look just like random garbage to any viewers, does this mean that ciphertexts are totally useless unless the corresponding decryption key is present?</p>

<p><strong>Both luckily and unluckily, the answer is NO.</strong></p>

<p>Some encryption schemes actually exhibits an amazing property, where if you obtain the encryption of number 1 and number 2, although you have no idea what the original plaintexts are, you can simply add these two ciphertexts together, and obtain the encrypted ciphertext for \(1 + 2 = 3\).</p>

<p>This property is called <strong>Homomorphism</strong> - where the algebraic relationship on plaintexts is also preserved in the ciphertexts. And encryption schemes that exhibits this trait are therefore referred as <strong>Homomorphic Encryption</strong>.</p>

<p>The example we gave above is just an instance of Homomorphic Encryption. Namely, this is an instance of <strong>Additively Homomorphic Encryption</strong>, where one can freely add ciphertexts together and obtain any linear combination of the original plaintexts, in encrypted form. Of course, there is also <strong>Multiplicative Homomorphic Encryption</strong>, the counterpart of AHE. In a MHE scheme, one can freely multiply ciphertexts together and obtain any products of the original plaintexts.</p>

<p>Pretty interesting right? However, if you think this concept is still a bit vague, allow me to provide an example.</p>

<h4 id="example-anonymous-polling">Example: Anonymous Polling</h4>

<p>We all know how polling works - for example, when a group of people want to vote on something (say whether they want to order Japanese for lunch), they could start a poll.</p>

<p>In the poll process, everyone will submit their choice of either <strong>going (1)</strong> or <strong>not going (0)</strong> to the host. Then the host simply adds everyone’s share together, and compares whether this final result is larger than \(1/2\) of the population.</p>

<p>However, the problem with this scheme is that the polling process is not anonymous. This means that anyone who can see the data traffic will know who likes and dislikes Japanese food - just by looking at everyone’s shares.</p>

<p>We can convert this protocol into an anonymous one easily with the help of <strong>Additively Homomorphic Encryption</strong>.</p>

<p>First, the host will run the \(KeyGen\) algorithm that generates a pair of encryption key \(pk\) and decryption key \(sk\). (Here, we are using an asymmetric encryption scheme.) Then the host distributes the encryption key \(pk\) to the public.</p>

<p>Now the polling begins. Every participant will encrypt their choice (either 1 or 0) under the encryption key \(pk\) using the \(Encryption\) algorithm. Then they will all send their ciphertexts to the host.</p><p>

\[ct_i = Encryption(pk, pt_i):pt_i \in \{0,1\}\]

</p><p>The host adds up all the encrypted ciphertexts and forms one ciphertext \(\hat{ct}\). Finally the host then runs the decryption algorithm on the ciphertext and obtain the result of the poll.</p><p>

\[Decryption(sk, \sum_i ct_i) = \sum_i pt_i\]

</p><p>This might not do the full justice to the true power of HE. But this should be a solid example where HE allows us to do some kind of <strong>Secure Delegated Computation</strong> - meaning that we can <strong>delegate</strong> some third party to compute on <strong>secret inputs</strong> we have by encrypting our inputs using HE schemes. The third party then applies whatever computation directly on the ciphertext and obtains the result ciphertext that is the encryption of the computation result. Finally we can decrypt that ciphertext and receive the result.</p>

<p><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1529420258850-3c3631829385?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1500&amp;q=80" alt=""></p>

<h3 id="levels-of-homomorphic-encryption">Levels of Homomorphic Encryption</h3>

<p>We should be pretty comfortable with what HE is, and what kind of application it enables us to do. Now, I want to briefly go over different levels (or stages) of HE that will eventually lead us to Fully Homomorphic Encryption.</p>

<h4 id="partially-homomorphic-encryption">Partially Homomorphic Encryption</h4>

<p>This is the very first stage of HE. If there exists an encryption scheme that is <strong>partially homomorphic</strong>, this means that this scheme is <strong>either additively homomorphic or multiplicatively homomorphic</strong>.</p>

<p>In other words, let’s say that in the Delegated Computation example, we would like the remote server to compute some functionality \(F\). If the HE scheme we choose is only partially homomorphic (for example, additively homomorphic), it means that the only thing we can do to the ciphertexts is to <strong>obtain an encrypted linear combination of the plaintexts</strong>.</p>

<p>Therefore, if we have inputs \(ct_0, ct_1\) that corresponds to \(pt_0, pt_1\), this HE scheme allows us to compute \(Enc(pk, c_0 \cdot pt_0 + c_1 \cdot pt_1)\) where \(c_0, c_1\) are some constants. However, with this scheme it is not possible to compute the product of the two plaintexts \(Enc(pk, pt_0 \cdot pt_1)\) or anything like that.</p>

<p>To summarize, if the HE scheme is just additively homomorphic, then the functionality \(F\) that the third party can compute is <strong>limited to all the functions where their outputs can be expressed as linear combinations of all the inputs</strong>.</p>

<p>This is exactly the same for schemes that are only <strong>multiplicatively homomorphic</strong> - the functionality \(F\) then will be limited to all functions where their outputs can be expressed as products of their inputs.</p>

<h4 id="somewhat-homomorphic-encryption">Somewhat Homomorphic Encryption</h4>

<p>This next category brings us closer to our ideal world. If we say that an HE scheme is <strong>somewhat homomorphic</strong>, this means that the HE scheme is capable of doing both addition and multiplication to the original plaintexts but its capability is heavily limited.</p>

<p>A typical HE scheme example would be - let’s say that there is a somewhat homomorphic HE scheme where  you can perform unlimited additions but only one level of multiplication to the ciphertext. In such scheme, given \(ct_0, ..., ct_2\), we can obtain something like \(Enc(pk, …</p></div></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://blog.higashi.tech/2020/06/16/fhe_01.html">http://blog.higashi.tech/2020/06/16/fhe_01.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://blog.higashi.tech/2020/06/16/fhe_01.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23721661</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 06:53:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
