<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 20]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 20. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 12:53:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-20.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 12:53:30 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[On Repl-Driven Programming]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 34 | Comments 10 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25620256">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
January 2, 2021 | http://mikelevins.github.io/posts/2020-12-18-repl-driven/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://mikelevins.github.io/posts/2020-12-18-repl-driven/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<div>
			
			<div>

				<div>

					

					<p>Once upon a time, someone with the handle “entha_saava” posted this question on <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23791152">Hacker News</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Can someone knowledgeable explain how are lisp REPLs different from
Python / Ruby REPLs? What is the differentiating point of REPL
driven development?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The answer is that there is a <a href="http://mikelevins.github.io/2020/02/03/programming-as-teaching.html">particular kind of programming</a>
in which you build a program by <em>interacting</em> with it as it runs, and
there are certain languages and runtimes that are designed from the
ground up to support that kind of programming.</p>
<p>Python and Ruby are not examples of such languages.</p>
<p>Why not? That’s the crux of entha_saava’s question, right? What are
these <strong>repl-driven</strong> programming systems, and what makes them
different from Python and Ruby and every other language that offers a
repl?</p>
<p>For that matter, what’s a repl?</p>
<p>The word <strong>repl</strong> is an acronym that stands for <strong>read-eval-print
loop</strong>. The term comes from the history of Lisp. From the start, sixty
years ago, the standard way of working with a Lisp has been to start a
language processor, type expressions at its prompt, and wait for it to
evaluate the expressions and print their results, before prompting for
another expression. Read, eval, print. Loop.</p>
<p>Nowadays, repls are all the rage. Every language and its brother
offers a repl. There’s a website, <a href="https://repl.it/">repl.it</a>, whose
entire purpose is to provide all the repls.</p>
<p>It doesn’t actually provide <em>all</em> the repls, of course. What’s
particularly ironic is that it doesn’t provide either of the canonical
repl-driven development environments: Common Lisp and Smalltalk.</p>
<p>That brings us back to entha_saava’s question: if Common Lisp and
Smalltalk are repl-driven environments, and Python and Ruby are not,
what’s the difference? What do Lisp and Smalltalk have that Python and
Ruby don’t?</p>
<p>What they have is a language and runtime system that are designed from
the ground up with the assumption that you’re going to develop
programs by starting the language engine and talking to it, teaching
it how to be your program <em>interactively</em>, by changing it <em>while it
runs</em>.</p>
<p>I can hear the objections formulating already. I’ve seen them
before. Yes, every language with a repl can do some things in the
repl. Obviously that’s true; if it weren’t, then the repl would be
entirely useless.</p>
<p>Being able to do <em>some</em> things in the repl does not make an engine
into a repl-driven programming environment. What distinguishes
old-fashioned Lisp and Smalltalk environments is that you can do
<em>everything</em> in the repl. They place no gratuitous limitations on what
you can do; if the language and runtime can do it, then the repl can
do it.</p>
<p>For example, you can ask the current version of Clozure Common Lisp to
rebuild itself from scratch by evaluating the following expression at
the repl prompt:</p>
<pre><code>(rebuild-ccl :full t)
</code></pre>
<p>CCL responds by completely rebuilding itself from source.</p>
<p>The point is not that you would want to rebuild CCL this way all the
time. The point is that there are no artificial limitations on what
the repl can do. The full range of the development system’s
capabilities is accessible from the repl.</p>
<p>That’s one of the first things I notice when using newer, lesser
repls: I’m always running into things I can’t do from the repl.</p>
<p>It’s not just about freedom from restrictions, though. Proper support
for interactive programming means that the language and its runtime
have positive features that support changing your program <em>while it
runs</em>.</p>
<p>Try this in your favorite repl:</p>
<p>Define a function, <code>foo</code>, that calls some other function, <code>bar</code>, that
is not yet defined. Now call <code>foo</code>. What happens?</p>
<p>Obviously, the call to <code>foo</code> breaks, because <code>bar</code> is not defined. But
what happens when it breaks? What happens next?</p>
<p>If your favorite repl is Python’s or Ruby’s or any of a few dozen
other modern repls, the answer is most likely that it prints an error
message and returns to its prompt. In some cases, perhaps it crashes.</p>
<p>So what’s my point, right? What else could it do?</p>
<p>The answer to that question is the “differentiating point” of
repl-driven programming. In an old-fashioned Lisp or Smalltalk
environment, the break in <code>foo</code> drops you into a <strong>breakloop</strong>.</p>
<p>A <strong>breakloop</strong> is a full-featured repl, complete with all of the
tools of the main repl, but it exists inside the dynamic environment
of the broken function. From the breakloop you can roam up and down
the suspended call stack, examining all variables that are lexically
visible from each stack frame. In fact, you can inspect all live data
in the running program.</p>
<p>What’s more, you can <em>edit</em> all live data in the program. If you think
that a break was caused by a wrong value in some particular variable
or field, you can interactively change it and resume the suspended
function. If it now works correctly, then congratulations; you found
the problem!</p>
<p>Moreover, because the entire language and development system are
available, unrestricted, in the repl, you can define the missing
function <code>bar</code>, resume <code>foo</code>, and get a sensible result.</p>
<p>In fact, there’s a style of programming, well known in Lisp and
Smalltalk circles, in which you define a toplevel function with calls
to other functions that don’t yet exist, and then define those
functions as you go in the resulting breakloops. It’s a fast way to
implement a procedure when you already know how it should work.</p>
<p>If you’re a user of old-fashioned Lisp or Smalltalk systems then this
all sounds obvious to you, but that reaction is not common. Surprise
is much more common, or even suspicion: what’s the catch?</p>
<p>The catch is that the designers of your language system had to think
that facility through in the planning stages. You don’t get a decent
implementation of it by bolting it on after the fact. Breakloops need
<em>full</em> access to the <em>entire</em> development system, interactively, with
a computation and its call stack suspended in the breakloop’s
environment.</p>
<p>Let’s take another example of a facility designed to support
interactive programming. Once again, try this in your favorite repl:</p>
<p>Define a datatype. I mean a class, a struct, a record type–whatever
user-defined type your favorite language supports. Make some instances
of it. Write some functions (or methods, or procedures, or whatever)
to operate on them.</p>
<p>Now change the definition of the type. What happens?</p>
<p>Does your language runtime notice that the definition of the type has
changed? Does it realize that the existing instances have a new
definition? When something touches one of them, does it automatically
reinitialize it to conform to the new definition, or, if it doesn’t
know how to do that, does it start a breakloop and ask you what to do
about it?</p>
<p>If the answer is “yes,” then you’re probably using a Lisp or Smalltalk
system. If the answer is “no,” then you’re missing a crucial element
of repl-driven development.</p>
<p>Remember: the point is to support programming <em>interactively</em>. You
don’t want to have to kill your program and rebuild it from scratch
just because you changed a definition. That’s silly; adding and
changing definitions is most of what you do! If your development
environment is going to support interactive development, then it had
better know how to keep your program running when you change some
definitions.</p>
<p>Old-fashioned Lisp and Smalltalk system know how to do that. There are
also a few other kinds of systems, mostly older ones, that know how to
do it.</p>
<p>These are not eccentric new ideas out of left field. They’ve been
around for half a century. They contribute materially to productivity
in interactive development.</p>
<p>They’re what sets <strong>repl-driven development</strong> apart from mere
development with a repl.</p>
<p>Now, not every programmer prefers that kind of development. Some
programmers prefer to think of development as a process of designing,
planning, making blueprints, and assembling parts on a
workbench. There’s nothing wrong with that. Indeed, a
multibillion-dollar international industry has been built upon it.</p>
<p>But if you prefer interactive development, if it’s more natural to
you, then it can make you enormously more productive, not to mention
happier in your work.</p>
<p>Interactive development with a proper repl-driven environment is the
exception. Most programming is done in other ways.</p>
<p>As a consequence, there are a lot of programmers out there who’ve
never even heard of it, who have no idea that it exists. My intuition
is that some fraction of those programmers would prefer well-supported
interactive programming, and would benefit from it, if they just knew
what it was.</p>
<p>Maybe if enough programmers are exposed to that style of programming
then we’ll begin to see new tools that embrace it.</p>


				</div>

			</div>
			
		</div>
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://mikelevins.github.io/posts/2020-12-18-repl-driven/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25620256</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 07:35:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The “Sublime Text of X”]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 21 | Comments 24 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25620176">thread link</a>) | @mastermojo
<br/>
January 2, 2021 | http://www.growthalytics.com/startups/programming/product/2021/01/02/the-sublime-text-editor-of-x/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.growthalytics.com/startups/programming/product/2021/01/02/the-sublime-text-editor-of-x/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    


    <div role="main">
      <div>
        




<article>
  <!-- date:       2021-02-01 -->
<!-- Why does the date cause the post to not render? -->

<center>
<small>
Note: The author has never paid for, is not affiliated with, and is not endorsing Superhuman as a product.
</small>
</center>

<h3 id="superhuman">Superhuman</h3>

<p>Superhuman is an invite-only $30/month email client.<sup id="fnref:pricing" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:pricing">1</a></sup> People like it for its sleek design, responsive speed, and suite of keyboard shortcuts to improve a user’s email efficiency. People justify this purchase over free alternatives by the fact that they spend hours on email everyday. Part of Superhuman’s feature offering includes read statuses, which is useful for executives and sales people who like to keep a pulse on their conversations.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.growthalytics.com/images/2021-01-02-the-sublime-text-editor-of-x/superhuman.png" alt="Superhuman Product Screenshot"></p>

<p>Users love Superhuman. Take a quick peak on Twitter<sup id="fnref:twitter" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:twitter">2</a></sup> at the effusive praise the company gets. Andreessen Horowitz led the latest investment round in the company with a valuation of roughly $260 million.</p>

<p>Following in the tailwind of this prosumer email client that has taken Silicon Valley and Twitter by storm are a suite of companies claiming to be “Superhuman for x”.<sup id="fnref:superhumanofx" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:superhumanofx">3</a></sup></p>

<p>As identified by Todd Goldberg, the “Superhuman of X” has the following traits:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Designed for speed.</li>
  <li>Built as an opinionated product experience for a specific use case and/or target audience.</li>
  <li>Driven primarily by keyboard shortcuts.</li>
  <li>Beautiful and thoughtfully designed.</li>
  <li><em>Optional</em>: Built as a modern alternative to a product that has legacy distribution effects</li>
  <li><em>Optional</em>: Positioned as a premium product vs. free alternatives.</li>
</ul>

<p><img src="http://www.growthalytics.com/images/2021-01-02-the-sublime-text-editor-of-x/commands_superhuman.png" alt="Superhuman Commands Screenshot"><br>
<small>
  Superhuman Command bar: short-cut triggered command search bar
</small></p>

<hr>

<center>
<small>
Note: The author has never paid for, is not affiliated with, but likes using Sublime Text as a product.
</small>
</center>

<h3 id="sublime-text">Sublime Text</h3>

<p>I present Sublime Text: a piece of software more than a decade older than Superhuman, that shares the above attributes. Sublime can be driven primarily by keyboard shortcuts. It’s as thoughtfully designed as I have been shamefully unwilling to purchase the non-trial version for 80 USD. The similarities lie much deeper than that. Sublime has two close-to-instant-speed search-bars: one for opening a file in your project [goto] and one for executing commands.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.growthalytics.com/images/2021-01-02-the-sublime-text-editor-of-x/commands_sublime.png" alt="Sublime Commands Screenshot"><br>
<small>
  Sublime Text Command Palette: short-cut triggered command search bar
</small><br></p>

<p>Sublime Text is also simultaneously opinionated but also configurable. It is simple enough for a programmer to install, open, and “hit the ground running” on a big project with a combination of GOTO (⌘+P) and project search (⌘+Shift+F).</p>

<hr>

<h3 id="the-sublime-text-of-x">The “Sublime Text of X”</h3>

<p>Without futhur ado, I present a case study sampling of “Sublime Texts of X”.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.growthalytics.com/images/2021-01-02-the-sublime-text-editor-of-x/sublime.png" alt="Sublime Text Screenshot"><br>
<small>The (Eponymous) Sublime Text of Text Editors: <a href="https://www.sublimetext.com/">https://www.sublimetext.com/</a>
</small></p>

<p><img src="http://www.growthalytics.com/images/2021-01-02-the-sublime-text-editor-of-x/fman.png" alt="Fman Product Screenshot"><br>
<small>The Sublime Text of Finder/File Explorer: <a href="https://fman.io/">https://fman.io/</a>
</small></p>

<p><img src="http://www.growthalytics.com/images/2021-01-02-the-sublime-text-editor-of-x/linear.png" alt="Linear Product Screenshot"><br>
<small>The Sublime Text of Task/Bug Tracking: <a href="https://linear.app/">https://linear.app/</a>
</small></p>

<p><img src="http://www.growthalytics.com/images/2021-01-02-the-sublime-text-editor-of-x/cron.png" alt="Cron Product Screenshot"><br>
<small>The Sublime Text of Calendars: <a href="https://cron.app/">https://cron.app/</a>
</small></p>

<p><img src="http://www.growthalytics.com/images/2021-01-02-the-sublime-text-editor-of-x/merge.png" alt="Sublime Merge Product Screenshot"><br>
<small>The Sublime Text of Git GUI Clients: <a href="https://www.sublimemerge.com/">https://www.sublimemerge.com/</a>
</small></p>

<p>The “Sublime Text of X” is software having the following traits:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Designed for speed.</li>
  <li>Built as an opinionated product experience for a specific use case and/or target audience.</li>
  <li>Driven primarily by keyboard shortcuts.</li>
  <li>Beautiful and thoughtfully designed.</li>
  <li><span><em>Not Optional</em>: &nbsp;Dark mode&nbsp;</span></li>
</ul>

<p>I look forward to a <del>bright</del> dark future where everything can be done fast and efficiently through keyboard shortcuts. If there are other startups or products that give you Sublime Text vibes I would love to know!</p>

<p><img src="http://www.growthalytics.com/images/2021-01-02-the-sublime-text-editor-of-x/terminal.png" alt="Terminal Product Screenshot"><br></p>

<hr>



</article>





<br>
<hr>






      </div>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.growthalytics.com/startups/programming/product/2021/01/02/the-sublime-text-editor-of-x/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25620176</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 07:14:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Rust Design Patterns as a Book]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 45 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25620110">thread link</a>) | @WnZ39p0Dgydaz1
<br/>
January 2, 2021 | https://rust-unofficial.github.io/patterns/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rust-unofficial.github.io/patterns/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
        <!-- Provide site root to javascript -->
        

        <!-- Work around some values being stored in localStorage wrapped in quotes -->
        

        <!-- Set the theme before any content is loaded, prevents flash -->
        

        <!-- Hide / unhide sidebar before it is displayed -->
        

        <nav id="sidebar" aria-label="Table of contents">
            
            
        </nav>

        <div id="page-wrapper">

            <div class="page">
                
                
                

                
                
                

                <!-- Apply ARIA attributes after the sidebar and the sidebar toggle button are added to the DOM -->
                

                <div id="content">
                    <main>
                        
<h2><a href="#design-patterns" id="design-patterns">Design patterns</a></h2>
<p>When developing programs, we have to solve many problems. A program can be viewed as a solution to a problem. It can also be viewed as a collection of solutions to many different problems. All of these solutions work together to solve a bigger problem.</p>
<h2><a href="#design-patterns-in-rust" id="design-patterns-in-rust">Design patterns in Rust</a></h2>
<p>There are many problems that share the same form. Due to the fact that Rust is not object-oriented design patterns vary with respect to other object-oriented programming languages. While the details are different, since they have the same form they can be solved using the same fundamental methods. </p>
<p><a href="https://rust-unofficial.github.io/patterns/patterns/index.html">Design patterns</a> are methods to solve common problems when writing software.</p>
<p><a href="https://rust-unofficial.github.io/patterns/anti_patterns/index.html">Anti-patterns</a> are methods to solve these same common problems. </p>
<p>However, while design patterns give us benefits, anti-patterns create more problems.</p>
<p><a href="https://rust-unofficial.github.io/patterns/idioms/index.html">Idioms</a> are guidelines to follow when coding. They are social norms of the community. 
You can break them, but if you do you should have a good reason for it. </p>
<p>TODO: Mention why Rust is a bit special - functional elements, type system, borrow checker</p>

                    </main>

                    <nav aria-label="Page navigation">
                        <!-- Mobile navigation buttons -->
                        

                        
                            <a rel="next" href="https://rust-unofficial.github.io/patterns/idioms/index.html" title="Next chapter" aria-label="Next chapter" aria-keyshortcuts="Right">
                                <i></i>
                            </a>
                        

                        
                    </nav>
                </div>
            </div>

            <nav aria-label="Page navigation">
                

                
                    <a rel="next" href="https://rust-unofficial.github.io/patterns/idioms/index.html" title="Next chapter" aria-label="Next chapter" aria-keyshortcuts="Right">
                        <i></i>
                    </a>
                
            </nav>

        </div>

        

        

        

        
        
        

        

        
        
        
        
        

        
        
        

        <!-- Custom JS scripts -->
        

        

    

</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rust-unofficial.github.io/patterns/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25620110</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 06:58:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The design flaws of password managers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 23 | Comments 49 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25619451">thread link</a>) | @_wldu
<br/>
January 2, 2021 | https://www.go350.com/posts/the-design-flaws-of-password-managers/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.go350.com/posts/the-design-flaws-of-password-managers/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I once worked in highly regulated environments and needed a way to recall dozens of complex passwords that changed frequently. I tried to use a password manager, but could not due to the burdens and insecurity of some common design flaws. I wrote a Deterministic Password Generator <a href="https://github.com/62726164/dpg">DPG</a> to address this.</p><p>If after reading this you still wish to use a traditional password manager, I suggest that you put your passwords into a plain text file and symmetrically encrypt it with <a href="https://gnupg.org/">GnuPG</a> or use <a href="https://www.pwsafe.org/">Password Safe</a>. I have no relation with either.</p><p>Here are three common design flaws in password managers:</p><ol><li>Password storage</li><li>Reliance on remote systems</li><li>Web browser integration</li></ol><h2 id="password-storage">Password storage</h2><p>When passwords are stored, they must be encrypted and then retrieved later when needed. Storage, of any type, is a burden. Users are required to backup stored passwords, synchronize them across devices and implement measures to protect them.</p><p>Users must also devise a master password to unlock the encrypted passwords stored by the password manager. This is similar to a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Master_keying">master key</a>. It is generally accepted that master keyed locks are less secure than non-master keyed locks. If the master password is exposed, then confidence (in all the passwords that it unlocks) is lost.</p><p>And, are we certain that the encryption used to store the passwords is implemented correctly? Has the encryption been externally validated? Some password managers are closed-source and proprietary and cannot be examined.</p><p>Encryption is hard. Even respected, expert developers with many years of experience (who seldom make mistakes) <a href="http://www.daemonology.net/blog/2011-01-18-tarsnap-critical-security-bug.html">do make mistakes</a> that render encryption weak or in some cases almost useless.</p><h2 id="reliance-on-remote-systems">Reliance on remote systems</h2><p>Ironically, password managers rely on remote systems largely because they store passwords. The first design flaw causes the second.</p><p>Remote systems are outside the user’s control. They are opaque and cannot be examined and should not be trusted with password management. These systems may not be available when needed. They may not be storing or transmitting passwords correctly.</p><p>Externally, the systems may seem correct (strong HTTPS, reasonable CSP) but behind the scenes, no one really knows what’s going on. How are the passwords being transmitted, generated and stored internally? Who has access to them?</p><p>Several popular cloud-based password managers have reported security breaches: <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/attacks-breaches/onelogin-breach-reignites-concerns-over-password-managers/d/d-id/1329034">1</a>, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2017/03/potent-lastpass-exploit-underscores-the-dark-side-of-password-managers/">2</a>, <a href="https://www.wired.com/2015/06/hack-brief-password-manager-lastpass-got-breached-hard/">3</a>.</p><h2 id="web-browser-integration">Web browser integration</h2><p>Web browsers today have “everything but the kitchen sink” capabilities built-in and are becoming more and more complex each year. They are turning into whole platforms that have browser plug-ins and extensions for every possible need known to humankind.</p><p>While many of these add-ons are handy and useful, we should not trust them with password management. Browsers are just too complex and have far too much going on.</p><h2 id="dpg">DPG</h2><p>I wrote DPG (The Deterministic Password Generator) around 2010 to address the design flaws described above. Here are its key concepts.</p><ol><li>Never store passwords. Rather, generate them as needed based on user input. The need to backup, synchronize and properly encrypt passwords is removed. There is no master password that immediately unlocks all of the other passwords. There is nothing to become lost, stolen or corrupt.</li><li>Only run locally on end-use devices. No reliance on remote systems or web browsers.</li><li><a href="https://github.com/62726164/dpg">DPG is open-source</a> and has several implementations. The passwords it generates can be verified and validated by external implementations in multiple programming languages.</li></ol><h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2><p>DPG removes many of the flaws that I have experienced with traditional password managers over the years. Try it. You may like it. I hope you find it as useful as I have.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.go350.com/tags/passwords">passwords</a></li><li><a href="https://www.go350.com/tags/compliance">compliance</a></li></ul></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.go350.com/posts/the-design-flaws-of-password-managers/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25619451</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 04:27:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Encrypted Backup Shootout]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 137 | Comments 62 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25618346">thread link</a>) | @andrewchambers
<br/>
January 2, 2021 | https://acha.ninja/blog/encrypted_backup_shootout/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://acha.ninja/blog/encrypted_backup_shootout/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
				<p>Recently I have been spending time on improving the performance of <a href="https://github.com/andrewchambers/bupstash">bupstash</a> (my encrypted backup tool), and wanted to compare it to some existing tools to try and find its relative performance in the backup tool landscape.</p>
<p>This post compares <a href="https://github.com/andrewchambers/bupstash">bupstash</a>, <a href="https://restic.net/">restic</a>, <a href="https://www.borgbackup.org/">borg backup</a> and plain old tar + gzip + GPG across a series of simple benchmarks.</p>
<p>What do all these tools have in common?</p>
<ul>
<li>They encrypt data at rest.</li>
<li>They compress data.</li>
<li>They have some form of incremental and/or deduplicated snapshotting.</li>
<li>They are all pretty great backup systems.</li>
</ul>
<p>Feel free to checkout the project websites to learn more, let’s get to the benchmarks.</p>
<h2 id="benchmarks">Benchmarks</h2>
<p>For these tests we are using the following versions of the given software:</p>
<ul>
<li>GNU tar 1.32 + gzip 1.10 + GPG 2.2.23</li>
<li>Bupstash 0.6.1</li>
<li>Borg 1.1.14</li>
<li>Restic 0.11.0</li>
</ul>
<p>The test machine has an AMD Ryzen Threadripper 1950X 16-Core Processor with 16 GB of ram, and an NVMe SSD hard drive. It is probably best to simply compare results relatively, as reproducing my test environment exactly would be difficult.</p>
<p>The scripts I used for my benchmarking can be found <a href="https://github.com/andrewchambers/EncryptedBackupShootout">here</a>, though they will definitely need tweaking for your environment.</p>
<h3 id="deduplication-and-compression">Deduplication and compression</h3>
<p>For this benchmark we take 20 different consecutive versions of the linux kernel source code and add them all to the same directory, we then create a snapshot and measure the size of the resulting tarball/repository.</p>
<p>The linux kernel versions chosen for this test are all the consecutive git commits preceeding version 5.9, with the resulting directory containing 21 GB of uncompressed files.</p>
<p><img src="https://acha.ninja/img/Test_Snapshot_Size.svg" alt="plot"></p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Command</th>
<th>Size</th>
<th>Compression Ratio</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>bupstash</td>
<td>0.378 GB</td>
<td>55x</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>borg</td>
<td>0.476 GB</td>
<td>49x</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>restic</td>
<td>1.5 GB</td>
<td>14x</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>tar + gzip + gpg</td>
<td>3.6 GB</td>
<td>5.8x</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>This benchmark shows the advantage the more sophisticated tools have over plain tarballs, they all have extremely good compression ratios when similar data is added multiple times to
a backup repository.</p>
<h3 id="creating-a-fresh-directory-snapshot">Creating a fresh directory snapshot</h3>
<p>For this benchmark we are snapshotting a copy of the linux
5.9.8 source code.</p>
<p>The directory we are snapshotting is 1.1 GB comprised of 74725 files and directories.</p>
<p>The snapshots are all made to tmpfs so hopefully does not measure delays introduced by the network or disk activity.</p>
<p><img src="https://acha.ninja/img/Time_for_1.1_GB_Snapshot.svg" alt="plot"></p>
<details>
<summary>Raw data (Click to expand)</summary>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Command</th>
<th>Mean Duration</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>bupstash put</td>
<td>3.939 s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>restic backup</td>
<td>6.026 s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>borg create</td>
<td>13.831 s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>tar | gzip | gpg</td>
<td>24.505 s</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</details>
<p>Bupstash is the clear winner here for raw snapshotting speed.</p>
<h3 id="sending-a-fresh-snapshot-to-a-remote-server">Sending a fresh snapshot to a remote server</h3>
<p>This benchmark is the same as the fresh local snapshot benchmark except the files are sent to a remote server hosted on google cloud via ssh. This benchmark should only be considered an approximation of the effect latency has on the tool performance as it is so dependent on network speeds.</p>
<p>At the time of benchmarking my connection to the remote server can be summarized as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>server -&gt; client 10MiB/s</li>
<li>client -&gt; client 2.5MiB/s</li>
<li>ping 32 milliseconds</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="https://acha.ninja/img/Time_for_1.1_GB_Remote_Snapshot.svg" alt="plot"></p>
<details>
<summary>Raw data (Click to expand)</summary>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Command</th>
<th>Mean Duration</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>tar | gzip | gpg | ssh</td>
<td>72.640 s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>bupstash put</td>
<td>121.817 s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>borg create</td>
<td>143.942 s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>restic backup</td>
<td>414.859 s</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</details>
<p>Plain tar takes the win, Restic performs poorly here, it has a far more latency-sensitive upload protocol.</p>
<h3 id="creating-an-incremental-directory-snapshot">Creating an incremental directory snapshot</h3>
<p>This benchmark is the same as the fresh local snapshot benchmark, except now we measure the time for an incremental snapshot using the builtin caching mechanism of the tools. What this means is each tool keeps a record of what files it has already sent, and is able to
skip doing that work again.</p>
<p><img src="https://acha.ninja/img/Time_for_Incremental_Snapshot.svg" alt="plot"></p>
<details>
<summary>Raw data (Click to expand)</summary>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Command</th>
<th>Mean Duration</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>tar –listed-incremental | gzip | gpg</td>
<td>0.209 s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>bupstash put</td>
<td>0.394 s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>restic backup</td>
<td>3.916 s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>borg create</td>
<td>7.724 s</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</details>
<p>Incremental tar is the clear winner here, but why are the other tools slower? I think this is mainly because the other tools present each snapshot to the user as a full backup and thus do extra work to spare the end user from managing incremental backups manually.</p>
<p>It is also interesting to me that <code>bupstash put</code> is an order of magnitude faster than the other similar tools, though I currently can not explain clearly why that may be the case.</p>
<h3 id="sending-an-incremental-snapshot-to-a-remote-server">Sending an incremental snapshot to a remote server</h3>
<p>This benchmark is the same as the incremental local snapshot benchmark except the files are sent to a remote server hosted on google cloud via ssh.</p>
<p>Benchmark conditions are the same as the fresh remote snapshot benchmark.</p>
<p><img src="https://acha.ninja/img/Time_for_Remote_Incremental_Snapshot.svg" alt="plot"></p>
<details>
<summary>Raw data (Click to expand)</summary>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Command</th>
<th>Mean Duration</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>tar –listed-incremental | gzip | gpg | ssh</td>
<td>0.779 s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>bupstash put</td>
<td>0.999 s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>restic backup</td>
<td>6.140 s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>borg create</td>
<td>10.772 s</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</details>
<p>These results match closely with the local incremental snapshots.</p>
<h3 id="restoring-a-snapshot">Restoring a snapshot</h3>
<p>In this benchmark we will restore the snapshot made in the fresh local snapshot benchmark to tmpfs. This is what measuring what happens when you need to do a bulk disaster recovery from your backup repository.</p>
<p><img src="https://acha.ninja/img/Time_for_1.1GB_Restore.svg" alt="plot"></p>
<details>
<summary>Raw data (Click to expand)</summary>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Command</th>
<th>Mean Duration</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>bupstash get | tar -x</td>
<td>2.712 s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>gpg -d | gzip -d | tar -x</td>
<td>4.449 s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>restic restore</td>
<td>4.890 s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>borg extract</td>
<td>9.694 s</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</details>
<p>Bupstash is the winner for restoring backups.</p>
<h3 id="restoring-a-snapshot-from-a-remote-server">Restoring a snapshot from a remote server</h3>
<p>In this benchmark we will restore the snapshot made in the fresh remote snapshot benchmark to tmpfs. The main difference from the previous benchmark is the introduction of
an internet connection between the backup repository and restore point.</p>
<p>Network conditions are the same as the fresh network snapshot benchmark.</p>
<p><img src="https://acha.ninja/img/Time_for_Remote_1.1GB_Restore.svg" alt="plot"></p>
<details>
<summary>Raw data (Click to expand)</summary>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Command</th>
<th>Mean Duration</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>ssh | gpg -d | gzip -d | tar -x</td>
<td>28.082 s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>bupstash get | tar -x</td>
<td>48.893 s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>borg extract</td>
<td>52.931 s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>restic restore</td>
<td>146.098 s</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</details>
<p>Interestingly, the introduction of the network pushed tar ahead of bupstash for backup restoration - this is something I am very interested in investigating further.</p>
<h3 id="pruning-an-old-backup">Pruning an old backup</h3>
<p>In this benchmark we will be removing an old snapshot from the backup repository on the same computer. For this test we generate a backup repository with 50 different snapshots of different versions of the linux kernel source code and then time how long it takes to remove one of the snapshots. This benchmark simulates
cycling old backups out of your backup repository when you no longer need them.</p>
<p>Tar with incremental backups does not easily support pruning of old backups, so does not participate in this benchmark.</p>
<p><img src="https://acha.ninja/img/Time_for_Snapshot_Removal.svg" alt="plot"></p>
<details>
<summary>Raw data (Click to expand)</summary>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Command</th>
<th>Mean Duration</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>bupstash rm &amp;&amp; bupstash gc</td>
<td>0.0386 s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>borg delete</td>
<td>0.497 s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>restic forget &amp;&amp; restic prune</td>
<td>2.030 s</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</details>
<p>The bupstash garbage collector is an order of magnitue faster than both restic and borg at pruning the backup repository.</p>
<h3 id="pruning-an-old-backup-on-a-remote-server">Pruning an old backup on a remote server</h3>
<p>In this benchmark we will be removing an old snapshot from the backup repository stored on a remote server. The remote server is the same as the one used in fresh remote snapshot benchmark, and the test data is the same as the local prune bench mark.</p>
<p><img src="https://acha.ninja/img/Time_for_Remote_Snapshot_Removal.svg" alt="plot"></p>
<details>
<summary>Raw data (Click to expand)</summary>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Command</th>
<th>Mean Duration</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>bupstash rm &amp;&amp; bupstash gc</td>
<td>2.137 s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>borg delete</td>
<td>3.111 s</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>restic forget &amp;&amp; restic prune</td>
<td>145.540 s</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</details>
<p>Once again restic suffers the worst from introduced network latency of all the tools.</p>
<h3 id="approximate-peak-client-side-ram-usage">Approximate peak client side ram usage</h3>
<p>For this benchmark we repeat the fresh snapshot benchmark, but measure the peak client ram usage (RSS) as reported by the ‘time’ command. For tar we approximate this by summing the peak memory usage across tar, gpg and gzip.</p>
<p><img src="https://acha.ninja/img/Test_Peak_Memory_Usage.svg" alt="plot"></p>
<details>
<summary>Raw data (Click to expand)</summary>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Command</th>
<th>Peak Memory Usage</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>tar + gzip + GPG</td>
<td>10.312 MB</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>bupstash</td>
<td>18.192 MB</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>borg</td>
<td>96.696 MB</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>restic</td>
<td>191.252 MB</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</details>
<p>Bupstash is very memory-efficient compared to restic and borg, but ultimately loses out to the simplicity of tar + gzip + GPG.</p>
<h2 id="conclusions-and-discussion">Conclusions and discussion</h2>
<p>GNU Tar + gzip + gpg is an excellent encrypted backup option and performed better than I expected. I think tar and gpg is still a great choice for users who prefer to DIY their own backup scripts. With this in mind, we must ask what are the problems with tar that the other tools address? My opinion is that managing
incremental backups, deduplication, pruning, and searching backups are far more difficult when using incremental tar compared to borg/restic/bupstash. With incremental tar, it quickly becomes quite hard to track which incremental
tarballs depend on eachother and you often need to periodically do full snapshots - losing most of the speed benefits.</p>
<p>As the biased author of bupstash, I am also pleased with how it has performed and hope I can push it further in the future. Restic, while fast at local operation, seems to trail the other tools when network latency is thrown into the mix. Borg is an all-around great tool and performed very well.</p>
<p>I can see both strengths and room for improvement in each of the tools tested, and encourage everyone to give them a try for yourself if you haven’t already.</p>
<p>As always, thank you for your time and see you next time :).</p>

			</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://acha.ninja/blog/encrypted_backup_shootout/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25618346</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 01:04:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Ongoing Accomplishment of the Big Five]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 35 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25618048">thread link</a>) | @barry-cotter
<br/>
January 2, 2021 | https://carcinisation.com/2020/07/04/the-ongoing-accomplishment-of-the-big-five/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://carcinisation.com/2020/07/04/the-ongoing-accomplishment-of-the-big-five/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-732">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	
	
	<div>
		
<p><em>by a literal banana</em></p>
<p>I have been trying to understand the “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexical_hypothesis" target="_blank" rel="noopener">lexical hypothesis</a>” of personality, and its modern descendant, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Five_personality_traits" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Five Factor Model of personality</a>, for <a href="https://carcinisation.com/2020/01/27/ignorance-a-skilled-practice/">several</a> <a href="https://carcinisation.com/2020/06/24/the-extended-sniff-test/">months</a>. In that time, I have said some provocative things about the Big Five, and even some unkind things that I admit were unbecoming to a banana. Here, I wish to situate the Five Factor Model in the context of its historical development and modern use, and to demonstrate to the reader the surprising accomplishment that it represents for the field of psychology.<span id="more-732"></span></p>
<p>In personality research, the “lexical hypothesis” refers to a hypothesis attributed to Francis Galton (1884). Galton supposed that each human language would reflect important realities of human character within that language and culture. In particular, he noted that the words used to evaluate character and personality are very numerous (he estimated over a thousand, using a thesaurus), and often overlap in meaning.</p>
<p>But Galton immediately left his thesaurus behind, readily admitting of the impossibility of <a href="https://carcinisation.com/2020/06/26/words-fail/">defining</a> any aspect of character. Rather, he turned to experimental means of testing the character in various ways, and insisted that <em>no particular map or model of personality is needed to start from</em>.</p>
<p>Nowhere in his essay does Galton propose surveys as a means for studying character. He would probably regard such methods as unscientific, as indicated in his final paragraph:</p>
<blockquote><p>[C]haracter ought to be measured by carefully recorded acts, representative of the usual conduct. An ordinary generalisation is nothing more than a muddle of vague memories of inexact observations. It is an easy vice to generalise. We want lists of facts, every one of which may be separately verified, valued and revalued, and the whole accurately summed. It is the statistics of each man’s conduct in small every-day affairs, that will probably be found to give the simplest and most precise measure of his character.</p></blockquote>
<p>The methods that Galton proposed are exclusively non-linguistic. For instance, he commented that observing children involved in play quickly gives one an idea of each child’s emotional expression. Galton’s proposed methods prefigure both hidden camera prank shows and Goffman’s “breaching experiments:”</p>
<blockquote><p>I will not attempt to describe particular games of children or of others, nor to suggest experiments, more or less comic, that might be secretly made to elicit the manifestations we seek, as many such will occur to ingenious persons. They exist in abundance, and I feel sure that if two or three experimenters were to act zealously and judiciously together as secret accomplices, they would soon collect abundant statistics of conduct. They would gradually simplify their test conditions and extend their scope, learning to probe character more quickly and from more of its sides.</p></blockquote>
<p>Other methods Galton expressed enthusiasm for include heart rate measurement (he wore a home-brew heart-rate-measuring apparatus while he delivered the lecture that makes up the text) and methods discoverable from personal context (giving an example from Benjamin Franklin, of a man with one attractive and one deformed leg, who kept track of which leg his interlocutors paid attention to, as a gauge of their optimism or pessimism). Galton would be surprised, I think, to find that the most promising and scientific theory of personality in the twenty-first century is premised entirely on survey responses as its “facts.”</p>
<p>Early in the study of personality, there was a major shift of meaning in the lexical hypothesis. At first, the thesaurus and the word list were its tools of study (e.g., Allport &amp; Odbert, 1936); the idea was to find common factors of meaning in the words themselves. Of course, there is no particularly scientific way to decide how much the word “annoying” is the same as “obnoxious,” or how much either is the same as “low-status.” The major shift was to begin to measure the correlations of an entirely different construct: the correlations of the words <em>when used to describe a particular person</em>. That is, rather than trying to measure the underlying meaning of words, researchers began to measure the degree to which different words were applied to the same person. “Sameness” and “correlation” were no longer distinguishable concepts for the methods.</p>
<p>Initially, lists of adjectives, and eventually, short survey questions, were administered to subjects, who described either a person they knew or themselves. When the responses were subjected to factor analysis—a mathematical analysis to reveal the structure of correlations between responses—a varying number of factors emerged, depending on the methods and the researchers and the questions and the subjects, and these factors were given varying names. Since the early 1990s, the Five Factor Model has been dominant, although the names of the factors vary somewhat even today. The acronym OCEAN is used for the traits: Openness to experience (sometimes called “intellect” or “imagination” or “open-mindedness”), Conscientiousness, Extraversion (sometimes called “surgency”), Agreeableness, and Neuroticism (sometimes called “negative emotionality” or “emotional stability” reversed).<span>&nbsp;</span></p>
<p>Today, the five traits are measured with various survey instruments, with five questions on the shortest version (one for each aspect) and sixty questions on a common long-form version (that used by Soto, 2019). Survey instruments are validated in a number of ways: how much their responses correlate between testings (test-retest reliability, with astrological sign as the gold standard), how much different raters agree using the criteria (inter-rater reliability), and a nebulous concept of construct validity, which sometimes includes scientific gestures designed to ensure that the instrument measures what it purports to measure. Many papers present elaborate numerical artifacts of validation, and I have found that some characterize the validity of their instruments as “good” without providing an indication of what would be “not good enough.” From a brief review of dozens of validated instruments in social psychology, it seems to me that it is relatively easy to “validate” meaningless instruments. As long as the mathematical bona fides are present, the construct need not be meaningful in other ways. (The reader who is rightly suspicious of my broad and unsourced claims may wish to search Google Scholar with variations of “scale,” “inventory,” and “survey instrument,” and examine the results critically. The naming of factors is often a particularly interesting step.)</p>
<p>The strong claim made by advocates of the Five Factor Model is that any set of questions describing a human being, administered to subjects and the responses subjected to factor analysis, will reveal the same five factors (paraphrasing Jordan Peterson in <a href="https://youtu.be/pCceO_D4AlY" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this video</a>, around 11:10-16:40). This strong claim, though dubious in a number of respects, is a major part of the basis for the scientific legitimacy of the Big Five. It is interesting to see which aspects of the strong claim are admitted to be false by advocates of the Big Five, and how much is excused on the grounds that <i>at least it’s something</i>. The Five Factor Model is not perfect, advocates grant, but it is better than nothing. It is not clear how they measure “better than nothing;” this is a potentially interesting hypothesis in need of precisification, perhaps.</p>
<p>The Big Five exist as a special, scientifically validated property of language and survey methods, and that is one basis for their legitimacy. The other basis for the legitimacy of the Five Factor Model is its <i>replicable correlation with consequential life outcomes</i>. We know that the Big Five are not merely phantoms that fall out of a certain analysis of a certain use of language in WEIRD college students, because these traits are reliably correlated with things we care about.<span>&nbsp;</span></p>
<p>One of the most interesting features of the Big Five is the nature of its scientific evidence. Observe what is held out as a “replication” of the theory, and you will discover the theory’s true nature. The most impressive aspect of the ongoing accomplishment of the Five Factor Model is the degree to which it <i>deflects curiosity </i>about its underlying meaning with <i>rituals of scientific validation</i>, regardless of the rituals’ appropriateness in context. Since “replication” is the scientific ritual most recently shown to detect poor science in psychology, being shown to reliably “replicate” is a huge boost to the credibility of a theory.<span>&nbsp;</span></p>
<p>The interesting thing about the Five Factor Model is what it gets away with, in terms of being considered a theory, even though it is not causal, and makes no predictions. What counts as a “replication” of the Five Factor Model, as in Soto (2019), is the following: a correlation is found between one or more factors of the Five Factor Model and some other construct, and that correlation is found again in another sample, regardless of the size of the correlation. In almost all cases, and in 100% of Soto (2019)’s measures, the construct compared to a Big Five factor is derived from an online survey instrument.</p>
<p>What counts as a “consequential life outcome” is also fascinating. In most cases, the life outcome constructs are vague abstractions measured with survey instruments, much like the Big Five themselves. For instance, the life outcome “Inspiration” is measured with the Inspiration Scale, which asks the subject in four ways how often and how deeply inspired they are. Amazingly, this scale correlates a little bit with Extraversion and with Open-mindedness. Do these personality traits “predict” the life outcome of inspiration? Is “Inspiration” as instrumentalized here meaningfully different from the Big Five constructs, such that this correlation is meaningful?<span>&nbsp;</span></p>
<p>Compare the items for the construct “Inspiration” with the items for Extraversion and Open-mindedness used in Soto (2019):</p>
<p><b>Inspiration Scale Items</b></p>
<ul>
<li>I experience inspiration.</li></ul></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://carcinisation.com/2020/07/04/the-ongoing-accomplishment-of-the-big-five/">https://carcinisation.com/2020/07/04/the-ongoing-accomplishment-of-the-big-five/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://carcinisation.com/2020/07/04/the-ongoing-accomplishment-of-the-big-five/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25618048</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:18:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How a startup can survive technical debt]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 104 | Comments 77 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25617083">thread link</a>) | @fidrelity
<br/>
January 2, 2021 | https://andreschweighofer.com/tech/how-your-startup-can-survive-technical-debt/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://andreschweighofer.com/tech/how-your-startup-can-survive-technical-debt/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-387">

	<!-- .entry-header -->

	
	<div>

		
<p>How can your early stage startup use technical debt to survive and thrive? How does technical debt in young startups look and where does it come from?</p>



<p>It’s hard to avoid technical debt completely but you can manage it and use it to your advantage. Let us have a look how technical debt is created in startups and how you can keep it in check even when your company is in hyper growth.</p>



<figure><img src="https://andreschweighofer.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/survive-technical-debt-1024x648.jpg" alt="" srcset="https://andreschweighofer.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/survive-technical-debt-1024x648.jpg 1024w, https://andreschweighofer.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/survive-technical-debt-300x190.jpg 300w, https://andreschweighofer.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/survive-technical-debt-768x486.jpg 768w, https://andreschweighofer.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/survive-technical-debt-648x410.jpg 648w, https://andreschweighofer.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/survive-technical-debt.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"></figure>



<h2>The paradox of success</h2>



<p>The most common way for startups to create technical debt is ironically the very thing that makes them succeed: A validated idea. You build things and test them out. Most ideas don’t stick. You move on. Until suddenly you have something that people really want and things spin out of control. That hacked together throwaway prototype is so sticky you can’t afford to lose your momentum. There is no time to rebuild it. You build upon it. That’s your first piece of technical debt – your prototype turned MVP.</p>



<h2>The right kind of technical debt</h2>



<p>The successful prototype sounds much like a eulogy of failed startups but it doesn’t have to be. Up to this point your technical debt is manageable and it’s enabling you to stay in business. You have turned your throwaway prototype into a bridge loan to get to the next milestone. You can use it to close the next funding round or spend money on customer acquisition to grab a foothold in the market.</p>



<h2>Paying the interest on your technical debt</h2>



<p>If you keep funding your success with debt it will catch up to you once one of two things happen. Either your growth will slow down or your technical debt has accumulated and development slows down. Both lead to you struggling to pay the interest on your debt. So it’s vital so reduce your technical debt <em>before</em> it spirals out of control. Here is a strategy to do exactly that.</p>



<h2>Balancing the short term with the long term</h2>



<p>When you build out your product you will come across technical debt. At this point don’t work around it but work through the technical debt. You need to <a href="https://killalldefects.com/2019/12/24/technical-debt-as-risks/">understand the risk your technical debt carries</a> and not get lost in the short term opportunities ahead. As a lead engineer or CTO it’s your responsibility to advocate maintenance work as a <em>Must have</em>, not a <em>nice to have</em>.</p>



<p>Unfortunately this ties the faith of your startup’s technical debt to one single person – you. To mitigate this we can try to bake it into the organisation’s behaviour by designing a process which balances the short term and long term thinking.</p>



<h2>Manage technical debt through your product</h2>



<p>When you build something new you should commit to do two things with it: Either you remove the feature if it does not bring in the expected results or you iterate on it. Axe any code before it turns into a liability or grant yourself the time to fix it and redo it properly. This strategy is effective because when you build a new feature you know the least about it, so even if you tried you probably couldn’t build it completely <em>right</em>. But once you’ve released it you have learned a lot more which will help greatly paying back that technical debt.</p>



<p>With this commitment the burden of fixing technical debt is not solely on you anymore. The product side is now your party in crime. However, in an early startup that probably just means two people instead of one. Once your organisation grows you need to ensure this attitude survives.</p>



<h2>Culture can beat technical debt</h2>



<p>When your company grows you want to fight technical debt before it gets out of control. Unfortunately the rapidly changing structures in a fast growing startup are a great breeding ground for technical debt.</p>



<p>You can try to establish specific roles like architects and lead engineers and processes like code reviews to fight your technical debt. But an engineer can’t manage technical debt unless the organisation enables them to. You need to create a culture which balances the short term with the long term thinking. A culture where engineers can take pride in their craft and not have to be the bad guys who say No all the time. Here are some hints how such a culture could look like.</p>



<h3>Do less but do it well</h3>



<p>Instead of getting <a href="https://andreschweighofer.com/agile/anxiety-in-product-development/">trapped in a fear driven culture</a> focus on your strengths. What makes your startup stand out from the competitors? Hone that skill. This is important to cut out distractions. It also keeps the technical debt at bay because you’re not racing from one feature to the next.</p>



<h3>Celebrate your engineering</h3>



<p>What your startup celebrates and rewards is what it creates more of. So if you only celebrate sale numbers and growth rates but none of your engineering accomplishments you end up with stunted engineering. So celebrate the engineering solutions and put the engineers in the spotlight. They are behind the scenes of product too often.</p>



<h3>Hire the best and train them</h3>



<p>Your technical debt is rarely caused by just bad engineering. But it can be part of the problem. Great engineers can avoid many forms of careless technical debt. You should leverage their skills to keep the growth of your technical debt in check. We all want to hire the best engineers. That’s easier said than done. But you can work with what you already have. Invest in training your engineers the best you can. This not only avoids technical debt but greatly improves the satisfaction of your engineers and their retention.</p>







<p>What makes startups successful is often the root of their technical debt. If your startup struggles with technical debt it’s important to note that this is neither a death&nbsp;sentence nor something to be ignored. Use it wisely and give your organisation room to tackle it so your startup can continue to thrive.</p>


		
	</div>

	

</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://andreschweighofer.com/tech/how-your-startup-can-survive-technical-debt/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25617083</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 22:15:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to overcome Phone Addiction]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 652 | Comments 255 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25616472">thread link</a>) | @Shred77
<br/>
January 2, 2021 | https://cognitiontoday.com/phone-addiction-coping-solutions-research-statistics/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://cognitiontoday.com/phone-addiction-coping-solutions-research-statistics/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
<p>Phone addiction is one of the <a href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBM/article-abstract/F86F13618106" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">biggest non-drug addiction</a> in human history. Studies show that <em>excessive phone</em> use is linked to <a href="https://cognitiontoday.com/procrastinating-with-your-phone-reduce-procrastinatory-phone-dependence/" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self" rel="follow noopener noreferrer">procrastination</a>, <a href="https://europepmc.org/article/med/29877640" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">suicide</a> (<a href="https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/news-pubg-mobile-addiction-13-year-old-boy-commits-suicide-over-the-mobile-game-635604" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer"><em>example</em></a>), <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/1660-4601/14/7/701" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">spoilt sleep</a>, <a href="https://www.onlinescientificresearch.com/articles/social-media-internet-and-electronic-devices-addiction-among-children-and-adolescents-in-global-contexts-modern-cities.pdf" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">food and water neglect</a>, <a href="https://headachejournal.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/head.12840" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">headaches</a>, <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2352853217300159" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">lower productivity</a>, <a href="https://aisel.aisnet.org/ecis2016_rp/109/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">unstable relationships</a>, poor physical health (<a href="https://www.omicsonline.org/a-study-on-some-of-the-common-health-effects-of-cell-phones-amongst-college-students-2161-0711.1000214.php?aid=14036" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">eye strain, body-aches</a>, <a href="https://www.jstage.jst.go.jp/article/jpts/26/4/26_jpts-2013-459/_article/-char/ja/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">posture</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5680647/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">hand strain</a>), and poor mental health (<a href="http://www.dbpia.co.kr/Journal/articleDetail?nodeId=NODE01121669" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">depression</a>,<a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10826-018-01323-2" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer"> </a><a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/smi.2805" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">anxiety, stress</a>). Some of these problems can be both causes and effects of phone addiction (procrastination, anxiety, unstable relationships, etc.).</p>



<p>So what can be done about phone addiction in a world that <a href="https://www.emerald.com/insight/content/doi/10.1108/IntR-08-2012-0155/full/html" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">loves the internet so much</a>? After all, it helps <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0733464816669805" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">older people stay independent</a>, <a href="https://cognitiontoday.com/effect-of-social-media-on-mental-health-well-being/" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self" rel="follow noopener noreferrer">gratifies our social needs, comforts us from stress</a>, and <a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44430520?seq=1" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">helps us learn</a> (common interest groups, affinity spaces).</p>




<p><strong>Trivia:</strong> When you are bored in face-to-face conversations or don’t want to interact with others, do you slowly start using your phone and divert your attention away from the person? Snubbing another person in favor of your phone is called <em>phubbing</em> (phone + snubbing) and it is a <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0747563215300704" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">common complaint in relationships</a>. <em>Phubbing your partner is called Pphubbing or Partner phubbing and research acknowledges that it worsens relationship satisfaction, life satisfaction, and could also add to depression.</em> Phubbing could be a form of social exclusion and researchers argue that <a href="https://cyberpsychology.eu/article/view/12590/11560" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">even watching others phub</a> can induce stress and lower regard for the phubbers.</p>



<h2><span id="What_is_phone_addiction">What is phone addiction?</span></h2>



<p>Let’s first understand what is phone addiction and what counts as excessive phone use.  Phone addiction or compulsive phone use goes along-side internet addiction and social media addiction. Psychologists also call it “problematic phone use.” For this post, we will consider them together. Cell-phones are habit-forming – once you go down that rabbit hole, you use more and more. Like drugs, one can get hooked to a phone or an activity on the phone that leads to addiction. There is abuse without control, changes in mood, excessive desire to use, withdrawals like irritability and anger when you can’t use the phone, low tolerance to avoid the phone, and the phone interferes with life in a negative way. </p>



<p>Strictly speaking, addiction is “the loss of control, the establishment of a dependent relationship, tolerance, the need for progressively more time and dedication, and severe interference with daily life (Echeburua et al., 2009).” Phones, internet-based activities, and any technology for that matter can <a href="https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fpsyt.2016.00175/full" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">become an addiction</a> in the truest sense (even though many disagree). And sometimes, phone addicts need to be rehabilitated in a hospital.</p>



<p>Not all phone use is a sign of addiction, even if the volume of use is high. A <em>loss of control</em> in how the phone is used and <em>psychological dependency</em> is an indicator of addiction. <a href="https://academic.oup.com/hcr/article-abstract/42/3/441/4064735?redirectedFrom=fulltext" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">Recreational phone use</a> and productive phone use isn’t the problem, it’s the inability to regulate usage and unhealthy coping for larger problems that usually makes screen-time problematic. If you are addicted to your phone, you probably can’t let go of phone-related activities no matter how often you tell yourself you need to let go.</p>




<p>People often get addicted to the phone because they want to <em>escape from reality</em>, <em>gain social karma</em>, <em>cope with stress caused by social anxiety and low self-esteem</em>, <em>follow their greed for social validation</em>, <em>likes</em>, <em>and other types of rewards</em>, or <em>play rewarding games</em>. The constant flow of digital rewards and information can <em>pull</em> a person into addiction and day-to-day difficulties can <em>push</em> a person toward addiction. Social media addiction usually comes down to these “internet reward points.”</p>



<div><figure><img width="640" height="426" src="https://cognitiontoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/pexels-roman-odintsov-4555321.jpg" alt="Phone addiction" srcset="https://cognitiontoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/pexels-roman-odintsov-4555321.jpg 640w, https://cognitiontoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/pexels-roman-odintsov-4555321-300x200.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-old-src="data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%20640%20426'%3E%3C/svg%3E" data-lazy-srcset="https://cognitiontoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/pexels-roman-odintsov-4555321.jpg 640w, https://cognitiontoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/pexels-roman-odintsov-4555321-300x200.jpg 300w" data-lazy-src="https://cognitiontoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/pexels-roman-odintsov-4555321.jpg"></figure></div>



<h3><span id="Indicators_of_problematic_phone_use">Indicators of problematic phone use</span></h3>



<p><strong>There is no cut-off point to show you are addicted to your phone which everyone agrees to but here are some indicators</strong>.</p>



<ol><li>You spend continuous hours on the phone to play games, scroll through social media, open and close apps, text people to invite a chat, etc.</li><li>You frequently pick up the phone without any aim to check for notifications or see if something has changed in your social feeds.</li><li>Your online and offline behavior gets more integrated and you don’t know what you did in the digital reality or the material reality.</li><li>You get restless if your phone is dead or has low-battery, is out-of-coverage, or low on data/balance.</li><li>You treat your phone as a security blanket without which you get uncomfortable in social gatherings.</li><li>Your day-to-day activities take a backseat, relationships are strained, and you can’t focus and commit to the important things in your life.</li><li>You feel bad about yourself and you go online to feel good but you end up feeling worse looking at what others are doing.<em> Such compulsive phone use is likely to emerge from other mental health issues.</em></li></ol>



<h3><span id="Common_examples_of_problematic_phone_use">Common examples of problematic phone use</span></h3>



<ol><li>Infinitely scrolling through Instagram.</li><li>Playing Call of Duty or PubG for hours and social activities contain little to no honest communication.</li><li>Excessive display of hurt, loneliness, attention-seeking behavior, hate, jealousy, and disapproval on social media.</li><li>Social needs are not met (sexual intimacy, close friendship, physical touch, etc.) and online alternatives are used to compensate for poor social health (chatbots, echo-chambers, porn, social gaming, virtual reality social games like second life, camming relationships).</li><li>Inability to feel pleasure and excitement in the offline world but excessive emotions are tied to online rewards like gambling, likes, shares, followers, sexting, masturbation to porn, etc.</li><li><em>FOMO</em> (fear of missing out) and <em>Nomophobia</em> (no-mobile phobia) cause mental and physical discomfort.</li><li>You frequently experience <em>Ringxiety</em> or <em>Textaphrenia</em> or Phantom notifications – the feeling that you received a notification when you actually did not.</li></ol>



<h2><span id="Statistics_on_phone_and_internet_use">Statistics on phone and internet use</span></h2>



<ol><li><a href="https://blog.rescuetime.com/screen-time-stats-2018/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">According to a 2019 report</a>, the average person spends about 3.5 hours on their phone in a day with the top 20% of people spending more than 4.5 hours a day. <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/03/24/screen-time-iphone-coronavirus-quarantine-covid/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">The quarantine</a> has increased these numbers – many users report over 8 hours a day.</li><li>The 2019 report also says that 70% of all phone use lasts lesser than 2 minutes and 50% of all phone pick-ups occur within 3 minutes of the previous pick-up.</li><li><a href="https://wearesocial.com/blog/2019/01/digital-2019-global-internet-use-accelerates" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">Another 2019 report</a> (2018 data) says at least 3.3 billion people use the internet and social media from their phones.</li><li><a href="https://www.comscore.com/Insights/Presentations-and-Whitepapers/2019/Global-State-of-Mobile" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">Comscore’s 2019 Global state of mobile</a> report says 70% of all digital media engagement in the US happens from a smartphone. So TV, games, laptops, gaming consoles, theatres, etc. are all squeezed into the tiny remainder of 30%. </li></ol>



<h2><span id="Important_research_highlights_on_phone_addiction">Important research highlights on phone addiction</span></h2>



<p>Phone addiction goes <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/08934215.2020.1780456" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">hand in hand</a> with anxiety and that anxiety often lowers the motivation to engage with people in real life. This is a huge problem because re-connecting with people in the offline world is a solution that improves the quality of life. The unnecessary drop in motivation because of addiction makes it that much harder to maintain social health.</p>



<p>Phone addiction can <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0306460319311839" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">cause poor cognitive performance</a> in day-to-day life. That means poor attention, poor memory, poor reasoning skills, bad decision making, etc. One of the main reasons is the role of sleep. Addiction can disturb sleep and sleep worsens cognitive performance. However, self-regulation (personal control, commitment to healthy choices, tolerating negative emotions) can counter the negative effects of addiction and that can help you overcome it.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0190740919311296" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">A dysfunctional family can push</a> children into addiction and one reason is social anxiety. A broken family or unhealthy parenting like neglect or excessive control can often hamper emotional growth. Children might fail to learn how to behave in social settings. There may be a fear of ridicule, disapproval, disappointment, etc. or simply a looming belief like “I am not good enough” or “I am a bad child” that creates pressure on children. These fears or thoughts transfer into the real-world and children cope with the social anxiety it causes by withdrawing into their phones – where the fantasy digital world rescues them from their real life. Fortunately, mindfulness – being aware of your actions and living in the moment as an observer – can reduce the negative impact of phone addiction.</p>




<p>Underlying mental health conditions like bipolar disorder, depression, anxiety, and attachment issues can <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7215249/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">increase the risk</a> of phone addiction. And improving mental health can <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4354213/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">counter addiction</a>. Proneness to boredom <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0894439317741087" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">can increase</a> the likelihood of problematic phone use but not the frequency of phone use. This ultimately makes boredom a pathway between problematic phone use and anxiety or depression.</p>







<h2><span id="9_Ways_to_overcome_phone_addiction_and_reduce_screen_time">9 Ways to overcome phone addiction and reduce screen time</span></h2>



<h3><span id="1_Schedule_a_time_for_un-monitored_phone_use">1.&nbsp;<strong>Schedule a time for un-monitored phone use</strong></span></h3>



<p>Grant yourself as much time as you want within a fixed daily limit at a specific hour of the day. As long as you can first demonstrate some output. Random notifications and random experiences are potent in pulling you to check your phone precisely because they are random. Unpredictable notifications and call-to-actions are hard to anticipate so the brain maximizes their potential reward (feeling great) by constantly creating the urge to pick up the phone and check. Schedule an hour to commit to your phone or make it a rule to check it every 45 minutes. That way, the rewards will be hard to anticipate but they will occur at a known time and your brain will find it easier to adjust than completely abandoning your phone.</p>




<h3><span id="2_Interrupt_your_habitual_routine">2.&nbsp;<strong>Interrupt your habitual routine</strong>&nbsp;</span></h3>



<p>Habits are hard to break because neurons in your brain rigidly fire a certain way. Once an action is repeated enough, neural circuits become efficient. They then direct and dictate behavior automatically. Countering their tendencies becomes harder. Higher the repetitions, the more stable those neurons get. These neural circuits fire in a predictable way and they fire automatically with almost no external push. You may have little to no awareness about the start of habitual actions. …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://cognitiontoday.com/phone-addiction-coping-solutions-research-statistics/">https://cognitiontoday.com/phone-addiction-coping-solutions-research-statistics/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://cognitiontoday.com/phone-addiction-coping-solutions-research-statistics/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25616472</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 20:59:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Ultimate MacBook+PC Monitor Showdown]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 58 | Comments 91 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25613244">thread link</a>) | @yeahgoodok
<br/>
January 2, 2021 | https://jamejone.github.io/2021/01/01/the-ultimate-macbook-pc-monitor-showdown/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jamejone.github.io/2021/01/01/the-ultimate-macbook-pc-monitor-showdown/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div> <header> <h3> <a href="https://jamejone.github.io/" title="Home">So long, and thanks for all the bits</a> </h3> <h3> <small>an engineering blog</small> </h3>  </header> <main> <article>  <span> <time datetime="2021-01-01T00:00:00+00:00">Jan 1, 2021</time> · 2 minutes to read </span> <p><img src="https://jamejone.github.io/generated/public/usb-c-monitor-800-785df26bf.jpg" srcset="https://jamejone.github.io/generated/public/usb-c-monitor-400-785df26bf.jpg 400w, https://jamejone.github.io/generated/public/usb-c-monitor-600-785df26bf.jpg 600w, https://jamejone.github.io/generated/public/usb-c-monitor-800-785df26bf.jpg 800w, https://jamejone.github.io/generated/public/usb-c-monitor-1000-785df26bf.jpg 1000w"></p> <p>Like many folks finding their way through the COVID-19 pandemic, I’ve <a href="https://twitter.com/james_output/status/1320110838792003584">recently accepted a job</a> working permanently remote. So for the foreseeable future my workstation will be pulling double-duty for macOS-based software development with a MacBook Pro and Windows-based gaming on a PC.</p> <p>Modern monitors come with a lot of interesting features. Did you know you can connect a MacBook to a monitor using a single USB-C cable and transmit USB, power, audio <strong><em>and</em></strong> video?</p> <p>Unfortunately, it’s not as simple as knowing whether a monitor supports USB-C. Many monitors support USB-C but don’t have any sort of way to pipe the audio out from the monitor (for example, to a sound bar). And some monitors have USB-C and audio out, but only provide 15W of power.</p> <p>With enough features, the monitor effectively acts as a KVM+audio, like so:</p> <p><img src="https://jamejone.github.io/public/usb-c-monitor-diagram.png" alt="USB-C monitor diagram"></p> <p>So I set out to identify a monitor that meets all of my criteria. Specifically:</p> <ul> <li>Has a built-in KVM switch that lets me easily switch between my PC and MacBook.</li> <li>Provides at least 60W power over USB-C (the bare minimum to power a 16-inch MacBook Pro).</li> <li>Some sort of audio output (almost always analog).</li> <li>Upstream USB-B Port so that I can plug my keyboard and mouse into the monitor and pipe PC audio through the monitor to the sound bar.</li> <li>VESA mountable.</li> <li>IPS panel. The viewing angles on my TN panel are so bad it interferes with my work so IPS is a must.</li> <li>27” or 34” ultrawide @ 1440p. Good for gaming and happens to be <a href="https://bjango.com/articles/macexternaldisplays/">the ideal non-retina DPI for macOS</a>. Full retina @ 5k instead of 1440p would be nice, but unfortunately I couldn’t find such a monitor that meets all the minimum criteria. Awkward DPIs are a deal-breaker due to scaling and “shimmering” effects mentioned in the linked post.</li> </ul> <p>Nice-to-haves:</p> <ul> <li>Adaptive sync (AS).</li> <li>144hz refresh rate. At 60hz I lose track of my mouse cursor in League of Legends and we can’t have that!</li> <li>90W power delivery over USB-C.</li> <li>Reasonable price.</li> </ul> <p>Here’s what I found after about 15 hours of research:</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th>Model</th> <th>Size</th> <th>Pros</th> <th>Cons</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td>ViewSonic VP2771</td> <td>27” 1440p</td> <td>$200-$450</td> <td>60hz, 60W USB-C</td> </tr> <tr> <td>LG 34WK95C-W</td> <td>34” 1440p UW</td> <td>Adaptive Sync</td> <td>75hz, 60W USB-C, ~$1,000</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Dell U3421WE</td> <td>34” 1440p UW</td> <td>90W USB-C</td> <td>60hz, ~$1,000</td> </tr> <tr> <td>LG 34WK95U</td> <td>34” 4k UW</td> <td>85W USB-C</td> <td>60hz, ~$1,300, awkward DPI</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Dell U3219Q</td> <td>32” 4k</td> <td>90W USB-C</td> <td>60hz, ~$800, awkward DPI</td> </tr> <tr> <td>BenQ PD3220U</td> <td>32” 4k</td> <td>85W USB-C</td> <td>60hz, ~$1,200, awkward DPI</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Razer Raptor 27</td> <td>27” 1440p</td> <td>AS, 144hz, HDR</td> <td>15W USB-C, No VESA mount, $700</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Philips 346B1C</td> <td>34” 1440p UW</td> <td>90W, AS, $450</td> <td>100hz, VA panel</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Acer Predator X34 S</td> <td>34” 1440p UW</td> <td><strong>200hz</strong>, AS, 85W</td> <td>Not available (yet)</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>I can’t guarantee this is an exhaustive list, but it might be. I left off monitors that are no longer for sale or lack crucial features like an audio output or upstream USB-B port.</p> <p>As you can see, there’s no ideal monitor except for the Acer Predator X34 S, which <a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/news/acer-predator-x34-s-a-34-inch-200hz-nano-ips-curved-monitor-w-05ms-response-time">isn’t available in the US yet and currently costs ¥9999</a> (roughly $1,500). In terms of what’s available today, you ultimately need to choose whether you want to sacrifice refresh rate, VESA mounting, USB-C charging, or panel type.</p> <p>As luck would have it, I ended up snagging a ViewSonic VP2771 on eBay for $200 shipped. After all, I still have a 144hz TN panel that I can keep plugged into the gaming PC. It’s not ideal but it’ll work until I get my hands on that Acer.</p> <p>Let me know in the comments if you find a monitor that should be in this list. If you want to play League of Legends together you can find me under the summoner name JamesJonesJrJr.</p> <p>Stay safe out there, friends.</p> <h3>Thanks for reading. Feel free to leave a comment.</h3>  </article>  </main>  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jamejone.github.io/2021/01/01/the-ultimate-macbook-pc-monitor-showdown/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25613244</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 15:05:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Setting up personal OKR (objectives and key-results)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 144 | Comments 87 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25613187">thread link</a>) | @pravj
<br/>
January 2, 2021 | https://hackpravj.com/blog/personal-okr-2021-plan/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://hackpravj.com/blog/personal-okr-2021-plan/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

      <section>
            

          

			


			

      <div>
        <p>This article describes the approach I’m following to set personal goals for myself, in the form of Objectives and Key-results (OKR).</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you are new to OKR, scroll down to the <strong>Resources</strong> section for more details.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://hackpravj.com/images/pageimage-setting-up-personal-okr-jfm-2021.png" alt="Personal OKR for JFM 2021" title="Personal OKR for JFM 2021"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>A publically available worksheet for my personal OKRs for January-February-March 2021 is available <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1hN5ldi0SgoGFyvXwyLCmf98337AyIt1xzbynVicGH-8/edit?usp=sharing">here</a>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I’ve worked them out in order to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Get a better grip on the concept by implementing them in a relatively newer setting/environment outside of the work</li>
<li>Effectively set goals in the personal life where it’s easy to measure progress and find out weeker/strong areas to work on</li>
</ul>
<p>I will continue updating this article and the attached document in case of any changes or updates. If you want to discuss more, or in case of any feedback, please reach out to me at <a href="https://twitter.com/hackpravj">@hackpravj</a></p>
<h3 id="themes">Themes</h3>
<p>Start with the themes representing the different areas of life. For example, in your case, it can be Personal-finance, Health, Creativity, and more. You can have your own personal reasons behind selecting the final themes.</p>
<p>Here are the 7 separate themes in my current plan.</p>
<ol>
<li>Health</li>
<li>Habits</li>
<li>Networking</li>
<li>Reading</li>
<li>Writing</li>
<li>Learning</li>
<li>Relationships</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="backlog">Backlog</h3>
<p>For each of the themes, I came up with a backlog of aspirations and ideas.</p>
<p>This has helped me connect the ideas with each other if there is any such possibility, OR ruling out ideas that are duplicate to each other.</p>
<p>Some of the themes or ideas that didn’t make it to the current plan, will be considered during the next quarter’s OKRs.</p>
<h3 id="objectives">Objectives</h3>
<p>To come up with the objectives associated with the themes, ask yourself</p>
<ul>
<li>Where do you want to reach? (in relation to this theme or some specific area related to the theme)</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>As a rule-of-thumb, objectives are ambitious and qualitatively represent an end state. It’s more of an outcome, rather than an output.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>For example, if you’ve selected “Health” as one of the themes, the following can be an objective for you:</p>
<ul>
<li>Objective-1: Get in a better shape</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="key-results">Key-results</h3>
<p>Once you’ve decided your objective, the key-results will be a mechanism to show your progress towards that objective.</p>
<p>To come up with the key-results associated with the objective, ask yourself</p>
<ul>
<li>How will I know I am getting there (<em>reaching the objective</em>)?</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Key-results are milestones that will move you closer to the objective if achieved.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Considering the earlier example of the Objective (<em>Get in a better shape</em>), here are two representative key-results:</p>
<ul>
<li>Key-result-1: Reduce weight by 10 kilograms (<em>or pounds</em>)</li>
<li>Key-result-2: Achieve a daily step count of 10K steps walked</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="initiatives">Initiatives</h3>
<p>Once you know the key-results, ask yourself the following question to come up with the initiatives:</p>
<ul>
<li>What are we doing to get there (to the milestone set by the key-result)?</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>One of the common mistake during OKR planning is; ignoring the difference between the initiatives/key-results.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>For example, consider the first key-result (<em>Reduce weight by 10 kilograms</em>), there can be different initiatives (that you can do to reach the milestone set by the key-result).</p>
<ul>
<li>Initiative-1: Limit total meals per day to 2</li>
<li>Initiative-2: Stop eating after 7 PM</li>
<li>Initiative-3: Start intermittent-fasting every other day</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="okr-check-in">OKR check-in</h3>
<p>As you’re moving ahead with your OKR planning, you need to ensure that you’re regularly measuring your progress.</p>
<h3 id="measurement">Measurement</h3>
<ul>
<li>You can provide different weights to the key-results associated with an objective.
<ul>
<li>For example, the first key-result (<em>Reduce weight by 10 kilograms</em>) can take up 70% (<em>relatively higher</em>) weightage than the second key-result (<em>Walking 10K steps daily</em>).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The progress for a key-result can be measured based on the % completion of the same.
<ul>
<li>A typically considered “sweet-spot” for OKRs is 60-70%.</li>
<li>If a key-result’s progress is higher than 70%, it might be a sign of lower ambitious objectives.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="summary">Summary</h3>
<ul>
<li>OKRs can also be implemented in personal life, out of the business/work (refer to Manas’s work on personal OKR [<a href="https://manassaloi.com/2020/01/15/personal-OKRs-2020.html">start</a>] [<a href="https://manassaloi.com/2020/12/31/okrs-2020-update.html">final update</a>]).</li>
<li>They serve as a goal-setting tool that helps you assess your progress on a regular basis.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="resources">Resources</h3>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://rework.withgoogle.com/guides/set-goals-with-okrs/steps/introduction/">Google’s guide to OKR</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLE7C8Y5NNLkMrMsqbe0igtYgPopb7IXBH">OKR training session (YouTube playlist</a>) by Directi CEO Bhavin Turakia</li>
<li>I will be maintaining a Twitter thread for the same topic, <a href="https://twitter.com/hackpravj/status/1345382233851326464">here</a>.</li>
</ol>
<hr>
<p>If you work at the intersection of <strong>Product-Management</strong> and <strong>Artificial-Intelligence</strong>, I would love to <strong>connect and exchange notes</strong> with you regarding your experience/learnings.</p>
<ul>
<li>Can we connect over <a href="https://hackpravj.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#7f171e1c140f0d1e09153f18121e1613511c1012">email</a> OR <a href="https://twitter.com/hackpravj">Twitter</a>?</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>If you want to discuss more, or in case of any feedback, please reach out to me at <a href="https://twitter.com/hackpravj">@hackpravj</a></p>

      </div>
	
			

      </section></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://hackpravj.com/blog/personal-okr-2021-plan/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25613187</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 14:56:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Virtual Environments Demystified]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 89 | Comments 29 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25611307">thread link</a>) | @meribold
<br/>
January 2, 2021 | https://meribold.org/python/2018/02/13/virtual-environments-9487/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://meribold.org/python/2018/02/13/virtual-environments-9487/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article>
  <header>
    
    <time datetime="2018-02-13T00:00:00+08:00">2018-02-13</time>
  </header>
  <p><img src="https://meribold.org/assets/virtual-boy-avgn.jpg" alt="The nerd with his Virtual Boy"></p>

<p>Here’s a non-exhaustive list of programs that are all meant to help create or manage
virtual environments in some way:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><a href="https://github.com/ofek/hatch">Hatch</a>,
  <a href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi/VirtualEnvManager">VirtualEnvManager</a>,
  <a href="https://github.com/kennethreitz/autoenv">autoenv</a>,
  <a href="https://github.com/PyAr/fades">fades</a>,
  <a href="https://gist.github.com/datagrok/2199506#a-better-activate-inve">inve</a>,
  <a href="https://github.com/berdario/pew">pew</a>,
  <a href="https://github.com/kennethreitz/pipenv">pipenv</a>,
  <a href="https://github.com/pyenv/pyenv-virtualenv">pyenv-virtualenv</a>,
  <a href="https://github.com/pyenv/pyenv-virtualenvwrapper">pyenv-virtualenvwrapper</a>,
  <a href="https://github.com/pyenv/pyenv">pyenv</a>,
  <a href="https://github.com/python/cpython/blob/3.6/Tools/scripts/pyvenv">pyvenv</a>,
  <a href="https://github.com/kvbik/rvirtualenv">rvirtualenv</a>,
  <a href="https://github.com/tox-dev/tox">tox</a>,
  <a href="https://github.com/borntyping/v">v</a>,
  <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/venv.html" title="The Python Standard Library: venv — Creation of virtual environments">venv</a>,
  <a href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi/vex">vex</a>,
  <a href="http://peak.telecommunity.com/DevCenter/EasyInstall#creating-a-virtual-python">virtual-python</a>,
  <a href="https://github.com/brainsik/virtualenv-burrito">virtualenv-burrito</a>,
  <a href="https://github.com/brbsix/virtualenv-mv">virtualenv-mv</a>,
  <a href="https://github.com/pypa/virtualenv">virtualenv</a>,
  <a href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi/virtualenvwrapper-win">virtualenvwrapper-win</a>,
  <a href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi/virtualenvwrapper">virtualenvwrapper</a>,
  <a href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi/workingenv.py">workingenv</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Clearly, this stuff must be really hard to get right.  I also must be a moron, since,
after having written some thousand lines of Python, I don’t even know what problem we are
trying to solve here, and the abundance of relevant programs with subtly different names
has deterred me from reading up on it so far.</p>

<h2 id="so-what-is-a-virtual-environment">So what <em>is</em> a virtual environment?</h2>

<p>The <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/tutorial/venv.html" title="The Python Tutorial: Virtual Environments and Packages">official docs’ tutorial</a> describes a virtual environment as</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>a self-contained directory tree that contains a Python installation for a particular
  version of Python, plus a number of additional packages.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>So it’s a directory with a Python interpreter?  Easy enough.</p>

<div><pre><code><span>$ </span>mkdir virtual_env
<span>$ </span>cp /bin/python3 virtual_env/
</code></pre>
</div>

<p>Let’s see.  Directory?  Check.  Contains a Python installation?  Check.  Contains a number
of additional packages?  Zero is a number!  (Check.)  Particular version?  Um…</p>

<div><pre><code><span>$ </span><span>cd </span>virtual_env/
<span>$ </span>./python3 --version
Python 3.6.3
</code></pre>
</div>

<p>I think that will do.  Is it self-contained, though?  It doesn’t contain itself…</p>

<p><span>
<img src="https://meribold.org/assets/russell.png" alt="Another nerd: Bertrand Russell in 1916" title="Consider the directory containing all directories that don't contain themselves.">
</span></p>

<p>Jokes aside, there are only two things missing to actually make our directory a virtual
environment as specified by <a href="https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0405/" title="PEP 405 -- Python Virtual Environments"><abbr title="Python Enhancement Proposal">PEP</abbr> 405</a>, the proposal that integrated a standard mechanism
for virtual environments with Python.<sup id="fnref:before-405"><a href="#fn:before-405">1</a></sup></p>

<ol>
  <li>A file named <code>pyvenv.cfg</code> containing the line <code>home = /usr/bin</code></li>
  <li>A <code>lib/python3.6/site-packages</code> subdirectory</li>
</ol>

<p>(Both paths are subject to the <abbr title="Operating system">OS</abbr> and the second one also to the Python version used.)</p>

<div><pre><code><span>$ </span><span>echo</span> <span>'home = /usr/bin'</span> &gt; pyvenv.cfg
<span>$ </span>mkdir -p lib/python3.6/site-packages
</code></pre>
</div>

<p>I will also move the Python binary into a <code>bin</code> subdirectory.<sup id="fnref:why-tho"><a href="#fn:why-tho">2</a></sup></p>

<div><pre><code><span>$ </span>mkdir bin <span>&amp;&amp;</span> mv python3 bin/
</code></pre>
</div>

<!-- >   [T]he internal virtual environment layout mimics the layout of the Python installation
>   itself on each platform.  
>   ---<https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0405/#creating-virtual-environments> -->

<p>Fair.  We have a directory that formally qualifies as a virtual environment:</p>

<div><pre><code><span>$ </span>tree --noreport
.
├── bin
│&nbsp;&nbsp; └── python3
├── lib
│&nbsp;&nbsp; └── python3.6
│&nbsp;&nbsp;     └── site-packages
└── pyvenv.cfg
</code></pre>
</div>

<p>This leads us to the next question.</p>

<h2 id="whats-the-point">What’s the point?</h2>

<p>When we run our copy of the Python binary, the <code>pyvenv.cfg</code> file changes what happens
during startup: the presence of the <code>home</code> key tells Python the binary belongs to a
virtual environment, the key’s value (<code>/usr/bin</code>) tells it where to find a complete Python
installation that includes the standard library.</p>

<p>The bottom line is that <code>./lib/python3.6/site-packages</code> becomes part of the <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/site.html">module search
path</a>.  The point is that we can now install packages to that location, in particular,
specific versions that may conflict with the dependencies of another Python program on the
same system.<sup id="fnref:python-level-isolation"><a href="#fn:python-level-isolation">3</a></sup></p>

<p>For example, if your project needs exactly version 0.0.3 of
<a href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi/left-pad">left-pad</a>:</p>

<div><pre><code><span>$ </span>pip3 install -t lib/python3.6/site-packages/ left-pad<span>==</span>0.0.3
</code></pre>
</div>

<p>Now this will work:</p>

<div><pre><code><span>$ </span>./bin/python3 -c <span>'import left_pad'</span>
</code></pre>
</div>

<p>While this should raise <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/exceptions.html#ModuleNotFoundError"><code>ModuleNotFoundError</code></a>, as desired:</p>

<div><pre><code><span>$ </span>python3 -c <span>'import left_pad'</span>
</code></pre>
</div>

<p>Another project on the same system could have a different version of left-pad in its own
virtual environment, without interfering with this one.</p>

<!--
TODO: talk about isolation from the system-level and user-level site-packages directories?
-->



<p>In practice, one does not simply create virtual environments by hand, which brings us back
to the dauntingly long list of tools above.  Fortunately, one of them is not like the
others.  While it’s predated by most of them, this one ships with Python as part of the
standard library: <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/venv.html" title="The Python Standard Library: venv — Creation of virtual environments"><em>venv</em></a>.<sup id="fnref:venv-and-pyvenv"><a href="#fn:venv-and-pyvenv">4</a></sup></p>

<p>In its simplest form, venv is used to create a virtual environment like so:</p>

<div><pre><code><span>$ </span>python3 -m venv virtual_env
</code></pre>
</div>

<p>This creates the <code>virtual_env</code> directory and also copies or symlinks the Python
interpreter:</p>

<div><pre><code><span>$ </span><span>cd </span>virtual_env
<span>$ </span>find -name python3
./bin/python3
</code></pre>
</div>

<p>It also copies a bunch of other stuff: I get 650 files in 89 subdirectories amounting to
about 10 MiB in total.  One of those files is the <code>pip</code> binary, and we can use it to
install packages into the virtual environment without passing extra command-line
arguments:</p>

<div><pre><code><span>$ </span>./bin/pip install left-pad
</code></pre>
</div>

<p>You can read more about using venv and <em>optional</em> magic like “activate” scripts in the
<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/tutorial/venv.html">Python tutorial</a> or venv’s
<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/venv.html">documentation</a>—this post is only meant to
boil down what a virtual environment actually is.</p>

<h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>

<p>A virtual environment is a directory containing a Python interpreter, a special
<code>pyvenv.cfg</code> file that affects startup of the interpreter, and some third-party Python
packages.  Python packages installed into a virtual environment will not interfere with
other Python applications on the same system.  The “<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/installing/">standard tool for creating virtual
environments</a>” is venv.</p>

<h2 id="appendix-history">Appendix: History</h2>

<!-- TODO: When and by whom was the term "virtual environment" coined? -->

<p>I think Ian Bicking’s <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20051203055434/http://svn.colorstudy.com/home/ianb/non_root_python.py"><code>non_root_python.py</code></a> qualifies as the first tool for creating
virtual environments.  Based on that, <a href="http://peak.telecommunity.com/dist/virtual-python.py"><code>virtual-python.py</code></a> was
<a href="https://github.com/pypa/setuptools/commit/3df2aabcc056e6d001355d4cec780437387ac4fa">added</a> to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Setuptools#EasyInstall">EasyInstall</a> in version
<a href="http://peak.telecommunity.com/DevCenter/EasyInstall#release-notes-change-history">0.6a6</a> in October 2005.  Here’s a timeline summarizing some
main events.</p>

<dl>
  <dt>2005-10-17</dt>
  <dd><a href="http://peak.telecommunity.com/dist/virtual-python.py"><code>virtual-python.py</code></a> is <a href="https://github.com/pypa/setuptools/commit/3df2aabcc056e6d001355d4cec780437387ac4fa">added</a> to EasyInstall.</dd>
  <dt>2006-03-08</dt>
  <dd>Ian Bicking, the author of <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20051203055434/http://svn.colorstudy.com/home/ianb/non_root_python.py"><code>non_root_python.py</code></a>—on which <a href="http://peak.telecommunity.com/dist/virtual-python.py"><code>virtual-python.py</code></a>
is based—publishes a blog post about improving <a href="http://peak.telecommunity.com/dist/virtual-python.py"><code>virtual-python.py</code></a> titled
“<a href="http://www.ianbicking.org/working-env-brainstorm.html">Working Environment Brainstorm</a>”.</dd>
  <dt>2006-03-15</dt>
  <dd>Ian Bicking <a href="http://www.ianbicking.org/working-env.html">announces</a> <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20060425105635/http://svn.colorstudy.com/home/ianb/working-env.py"><code>working-env.py</code></a>.</dd>
  <dt>2006-04-26</dt>
  <dd>Ian Bicking <a href="http://www.ianbicking.org/workingenv-revisited.html">announces</a> an improved version of
<a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20060425105635/http://svn.colorstudy.com/home/ianb/working-env.py"><code>working-env.py</code></a> called <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20060516191525/http://svn.colorstudy.com:80/home/ianb/workingenv">workingenv</a>.
<!-- 
TODO: did anything important happen here?
 --></dd>
  <dt>2007-09-14</dt>
  <dd><a href="https://github.com/pypa/virtualenv/commit/e02aa46f4f0eb5321c31641e89bde2c9b92547bb">virtualenv</a>’s first commit</dd>
  <dt>2007-10-10</dt>
  <dd>Ian Bicking announces <a href="https://github.com/pypa/virtualenv">virtualenv</a>: “<a href="http://www.ianbicking.org/blog/2007/10/workingenv-is-dead-long-live-virtualenv.html">Workingenv is dead, long live
Virtualenv!</a>”</dd>
  <dt>2009-10-24</dt>
  <dd><a href="http://peak.telecommunity.com/dist/virtual-python.py"><code>virtual-python.py</code></a> is <a href="https://github.com/pypa/setuptools/commit/43d34734c801d2d9a72d5fa6e7fc74d80bdc11c1">removed</a> from EasyInstall.
<!-- 
TODO: did anything important happen here?
 --></dd>
  <dt>2011-06-13</dt>
  <dd><a href="https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0405/" title="PEP 405 -- Python Virtual Environments"><abbr title="Python Enhancement Proposal">PEP</abbr> 405</a> is created.</dd>
  <dt>2012-05-25</dt>
  <dd><a href="https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0405/" title="PEP 405 -- Python Virtual Environments"><abbr title="Python Enhancement Proposal">PEP</abbr> 405</a> is accepted for inclusion in Python 3.3.</dd>
  <dt>2012-09-29</dt>
  <dd><a href="https://docs.python.org/dev/whatsnew/3.3.html#pep-405-virtual-environments">Python 3.3</a> is released; <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/venv.html" title="The Python Standard Library: venv — Creation of virtual environments">venv</a> and <a href="https://github.com/python/cpython/blob/3.6/Tools/scripts/pyvenv">pyvenv</a> become part of the
standard library.</dd>
  <dt>2014-03-16</dt>
  <dd><a href="https://docs.python.org/dev/whatsnew/3.4.html">Python 3.4</a> is released; “<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/installing/">[venv] defaults to installing <abbr title="pip installs packages">pip</abbr> into all created
virtual environments.</a>”</dd>
  <dt>2015-09-13</dt>
  <dd><a href="https://docs.python.org/dev/whatsnew/3.5.html">Python 3.5</a> is released.  “<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/installing/">The use of venv is now recommended for creating virtual
environments.</a>”</dd>
  <dt>2016-12-23</dt>
  <dd><a href="https://docs.python.org/dev/whatsnew/3.6.html#id8">Python 3.6</a> is released; “<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/installing/">pyvenv was the recommended tool for creating virtual
environments for Python 3.3 and 3.4, and is deprecated in Python 3.6.</a>”</dd>
</dl>

<h2 id="image-sources">Image sources</h2>

<p>The “Virtual Boy” image is used with permission from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Rolfe">James
Rolfe</a>.</p>



<!-- vim: set tw=90 sts=-1 sw=4 et spell wrap: -->


</article>

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://meribold.org/python/2018/02/13/virtual-environments-9487/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25611307</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 08:31:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A review of endianness bugs in Qt, and how they were fixed]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 64 | Comments 66 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25611172">thread link</a>) | @pabs3
<br/>
January 1, 2021 | https://mitya57.me/weblog/2021/01/qt-big-endian-history.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://mitya57.me/weblog/2021/01/qt-big-endian-history.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

		  <div role="main">
	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">
			
		
		
		
		<p>As you may know, I am Qt 5 maintainer in Debian. Maintaning Qt means not only
bumping the version each time a new version is released, but also making sure
Qt builds successfully on all architectures that are supported in Debian (and
for some submodules, the automatic tests pass).</p>
<p>An important sort of build failures are endianness specific failures. Most
widely used architectures (x86_64, aarch64) are little endian. However, Debian
officially supports one big endian architecture (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linux_on_IBM_Z">s390x</a>), and unofficially
a few more ports are provided, such as <a href="https://wiki.debian.org/PPC64">ppc64</a> and <a href="https://wiki.debian.org/Sparc64">sparc64</a>.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, Qt upstream does not have any big endian machine in their CI
system, so endianness issues get noticed only when the packages fail to build
on our build daemons. In the last years I have discovered and fixed some such
issues in various parts of Qt, so I decided to write a post to illustrate how
to write really cross-platform C/C++ code.</p>
<h2>Issue 1: the WebP image format handler (<a href="https://codereview.qt-project.org/c/qt/qtimageformats/+/86275">code review</a>)</h2>
<p>The relevant code snippet is:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>srcImage</span><span>.</span><span>format</span><span>()</span> <span>!=</span> <span>QImage</span><span>::</span><span>Format_ARGB32</span><span>)</span>
    <span>srcImage</span> <span>=</span> <span>srcImage</span><span>.</span><span>convertToFormat</span><span>(</span><span>QImage</span><span>::</span><span>Format_ARGB32</span><span>);</span>
<span>// ...</span>
<span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>!</span><span>WebPPictureImportBGRA</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>picture</span><span>,</span> <span>srcImage</span><span>.</span><span>bits</span><span>(),</span> <span>srcImage</span><span>.</span><span>bytesPerLine</span><span>()))</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>// ...</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div>

<p>The code here is serializing the images into <code>QImage::Format_ARGB32</code> format, and
then passing the bytes into WebP’s import function. With this format, the image
is stored using a 32-bit ARGB format (0xAARRGGBB). This means that the bytes
will be 0xBB, 0xGG, 0xRR, 0xAA or little endian and 0xAA, 0xRR, 0xGG, 0xBB on
big endian. However, <code>WebPPictureImportBGRA</code> expects the first format on all
architectures.</p>
<p>The fix was to use <code>QImage::Format_RGBA8888</code>. As the <a href="https://doc.qt.io/qt-5/qimage.html#Format-enum">QImage documentation</a>
says, with this format <em>the order of the colors is the same on any architecture
if read as bytes 0xRR, 0xGG, 0xBB, 0xAA</em>.</p>
<h2>Issue 2: <code>qimage_converter_map</code> structure (<a href="https://codereview.qt-project.org/c/qt/qtbase/+/101769">code review</a>)</h2>
<p>The code seems to already support big endian. But maybe you can spot the error?</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>#if Q_BYTE_ORDER == Q_LITTLE_ENDIAN</span>
        <span>0</span><span>,</span>
        <span>convert_ARGB_to_ARGB_PM</span><span>,</span>
<span>#else</span>
        <span>0</span><span>,</span>
        <span>0</span>
<span>#endif</span>
</code></pre></div>

<p>It is the missing comma! It is present in the little endian block, but not in
the big endian one. This was fixed trivially.</p>
<h2>Issue 3: QHandle, part of Qt 3D module (<a href="https://codereview.qt-project.org/c/qt/qt3d/+/162737">code review</a>)</h2>
<p>QHandle class uses a union that is declared as follows:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>struct</span> <span>Data</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>quint32</span> <span>m_index</span> <span>:</span> <span>IndexBits</span><span>;</span>
    <span>quint32</span> <span>m_counter</span> <span>:</span> <span>CounterBits</span><span>;</span>
    <span>quint32</span> <span>m_unused</span> <span>:</span> <span>2</span><span>;</span>
<span>};</span>
<span>union</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>Data</span> <span>d</span><span>;</span>
    <span>quint32</span> <span>m_handle</span><span>;</span>
<span>};</span>
</code></pre></div>

<p>The sizes are declared such as IndexBits + CounterBits + 2 is always
equal to 32 (four bytes).</p>
<p>Then we have a constructor that sets the values of Data struct:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>QHandle</span><span>(</span><span>quint32</span> <span>i</span><span>,</span> <span>quint32</span> <span>count</span><span>)</span>
<span>{</span>
    <span>d</span><span>.</span><span>m_index</span> <span>=</span> <span>i</span><span>;</span>
    <span>d</span><span>.</span><span>m_counter</span> <span>=</span> <span>count</span><span>;</span>
    <span>d</span><span>.</span><span>m_unused</span> <span>=</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div>

<p>The value of <code>m_handle</code> will be different depending on endianness!
So the test that was expecting a particular value with given constructor
arguments was failing. I fixed it by using the following macro:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>#if Q_BYTE_ORDER == Q_BIG_ENDIAN</span>
<span>#define GET_EXPECTED_HANDLE(qHandle) ((qHandle.index() &lt;&lt; (qHandle.CounterBits + 2)) + (qHandle.counter() &lt;&lt; 2))</span>
<span>#else </span><span>/* Q_LITTLE_ENDIAN */</span><span></span>
<span>#define GET_EXPECTED_HANDLE(qHandle) (qHandle.index() + (qHandle.counter() &lt;&lt; qHandle.IndexBits))</span>
<span>#endif</span>
</code></pre></div>

<h2>Issue 4: QML compiler (<a href="https://codereview.qt-project.org/c/qt/qtdeclarative/+/197746">code review</a>)</h2>
<p>The QML compiler used a helper class named LEUInt32 (based on <a href="https://doc.qt.io/qt-5/qleinteger.html">QLEInteger</a>)
that always stored the numbers in little endian internally. This class
can be safely mixed with native quint32 on little endian systems, but not
on big endian.</p>
<p>Usually the compiler would warn about type mismatch, but here the code used
<code>reinterpret_cast</code>, such as:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>quint32</span> <span>*</span><span>objectTable</span> <span>=</span> <span>reinterpret_cast</span><span>&lt;</span><span>quint32</span><span>*&gt;</span><span>(</span><span>data</span> <span>+</span> <span>qmlUnit</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>offsetToObjects</span><span>);</span>
</code></pre></div>

<p>So this was not noticed on build time, but the compiler was crashing. The fix
was trivial again, replacing quint32 with QLEUInt32.</p>
<h2>Issue 5: QModbusPdu, part of Qt Serial Bus module (<a href="https://codereview.qt-project.org/c/qt/qtserialbus/+/245206">code review</a>)</h2>
<p>The code snippet is simple:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>QModbusPdu</span><span>::</span><span>FunctionCode</span> <span>code</span> <span>=</span> <span>QModbusPdu</span><span>::</span><span>Invalid</span><span>;</span>
<span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>stream</span><span>.</span><span>readRawData</span><span>((</span><span>char</span> <span>*</span><span>)</span> <span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>code</span><span>),</span> <span>sizeof</span><span>(</span><span>quint8</span><span>))</span> <span>!=</span> <span>sizeof</span><span>(</span><span>quint8</span><span>))</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>stream</span><span>;</span>
</code></pre></div>

<p><code>QModbusPdu::FunctionCode</code> is an enum, so <code>code</code> is a multi-byte value (even if
only one byte is significant). However, <code>(char *) (&amp;code)</code> returns a pointer to
the first byte of it. It is the needed byte on little endian systems, but it is
the wrong byte on big endian ones!</p>
<p>The correct fix was using a temporary one-byte variable:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>quint8</span> <span>codeByte</span> <span>=</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span>
<span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>stream</span><span>.</span><span>readRawData</span><span>((</span><span>char</span> <span>*</span><span>)</span> <span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>codeByte</span><span>),</span> <span>sizeof</span><span>(</span><span>quint8</span><span>))</span> <span>!=</span> <span>sizeof</span><span>(</span><span>quint8</span><span>))</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>stream</span><span>;</span>
<span>QModbusPdu</span><span>::</span><span>FunctionCode</span> <span>code</span> <span>=</span> <span>(</span><span>QModbusPdu</span><span>::</span><span>FunctionCode</span><span>)</span> <span>codeByte</span><span>;</span>
</code></pre></div>

<h2>Issue 6: <code>qt_is_ascii</code> (<a href="https://codereview.qt-project.org/c/qt/qtbase/+/258164">code review</a>)</h2>
<p>This function, as the name says, checks whether a string is ASCII. It does
that by splitting the string into 4-byte chunks:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>while</span> <span>(</span><span>ptr</span> <span>+</span> <span>4</span> <span>&lt;=</span> <span>end</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>quint32</span> <span>data</span> <span>=</span> <span>qFromUnaligned</span><span>&lt;</span><span>quint32</span><span>&gt;</span><span>(</span><span>ptr</span><span>);</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>data</span> <span>&amp;=</span> <span>0x80808080U</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>uint</span> <span>idx</span> <span>=</span> <span>qCountTrailingZeroBits</span><span>(</span><span>data</span><span>);</span>
        <span>ptr</span> <span>+=</span> <span>idx</span> <span>/</span> <span>8</span><span>;</span>
        <span>return</span> <span>false</span><span>;</span>
    <span>}</span>
    <span>ptr</span> <span>+=</span> <span>4</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div>

<p><code>idx / 8</code> is the number of trailing zero bytes. However, the bytes which are
trailing on little endian are actually leading on big endian! So we can use
<code>qCountLeadingZeroBits</code> there.</p>
<h2>Issue 7: the bundled copy of tinycbor (<a href="https://github.com/thiagomacieira/tinycbor/pull/1">upstream pull request</a>)</h2>
<p>Similar to issue 5, the code was reading into the wrong byte:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>bytesNeeded</span> <span>&lt;=</span> <span>2</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>read_bytes_unchecked</span><span>(</span><span>it</span><span>,</span> <span>&amp;</span><span>it</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>extra</span><span>,</span> <span>1</span><span>,</span> <span>bytesNeeded</span><span>);</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>bytesNeeded</span> <span>==</span> <span>2</span><span>)</span>
        <span>it</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>extra</span> <span>=</span> <span>cbor_ntohs</span><span>(</span><span>it</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>extra</span><span>);</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div>

<p><code>extra</code> has type uint16_t, so it has two bytes. When we need only one byte,
we read into the wrong byte, so the resulting number is 256 times higher on
big endian than it should be. Adding a temporary one-byte variable fixed it.</p>
<h2>Issue 8: perfparser, part of Qt Creator (<a href="https://codereview.qt-project.org/c/qt-creator/perfparser/+/305990">code review</a>)</h2>
<p>Here it is not trivial to find the issue just looking at the code:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>qint32</span> <span>dataStreamVersion</span> <span>=</span> <span>qToLittleEndian</span><span>(</span><span>QDataStream</span><span>::</span><span>Qt_DefaultCompiledVersion</span><span>);</span>
</code></pre></div>

<p>However the linker was producing an error:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>undefined reference to `QDataStream::Version qbswap<qdatastream::version>(QDataStream::Version)'</qdatastream::version></p>
</blockquote>
<p>On little endian systems, <code>qToLittleEndian</code> is a no-op, but on big endian
systems, it is a template function defined for some known types. But it turns
out we need to explicitly convert enum values to a simple type, so the fix
was passing <code>qint32(QDataStream::Qt_DefaultCompiledVersion)</code> to that function.</p>
<h2>Issue 9: Qt Personal Information Management (<a href="https://codereview.qt-project.org/c/qt/qtpim/+/319865">code review</a>)</h2>
<p>The code in test was trying to represent a number as a sequence of bytes,
using <code>reinterpret_cast</code>:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>static</span> <span>inline</span> <span>QContactId</span> <span>makeId</span><span>(</span><span>const</span> <span>QString</span> <span>&amp;</span><span>managerName</span><span>,</span> <span>uint</span> <span>id</span><span>)</span>
<span>{</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>QContactId</span><span>(</span><span>QStringLiteral</span><span>(</span><span>"qtcontacts:basic%1:"</span><span>).</span><span>arg</span><span>(</span><span>managerName</span><span>),</span> <span>QByteArray</span><span>(</span><span>reinterpret_cast</span><span>&lt;</span><span>const</span> <span>char</span> <span>*&gt;</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>id</span><span>),</span> <span>sizeof</span><span>(</span><span>uint</span><span>)));</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div>

<p>The order of bytes will be different on little endian and big endian systems!
The fix was adding this line to the beginning of the function:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>id</span> <span>=</span> <span>qToLittleEndian</span><span>(</span><span>id</span><span>);</span>
</code></pre></div>

<p>This will cause the bytes to be reversed on big endian systems.</p>
<h2>What remains unfixed</h2>
<p>There are still some bugs, which require deeper investigation, for example:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://bugreports.qt.io/browse/QTBUG-56806">https://bugreports.qt.io/browse/QTBUG-56806</a></li>
<li><a href="https://bugreports.qt.io/browse/QTBUG-56975">https://bugreports.qt.io/browse/QTBUG-56975</a></li>
</ul>
<p>P.S. We are <a href="https://perezmeyer.blogspot.com/2020/08/stepping-down-as-qt-6-maintainers.html">looking for new people</a> to help with maintaining Qt 6.
Join our team if you want to do some fun work like described above!</p>	

	</article>

		  </div>	
		  
		  

	  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://mitya57.me/weblog/2021/01/qt-big-endian-history.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25611172</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 07:54:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How Not to Teach Recursion]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 44 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25610690">thread link</a>) | @alokrai
<br/>
January 1, 2021 | https://parentheticallyspeaking.org/articles/how-not-to-teach-recursion/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://parentheticallyspeaking.org/articles/how-not-to-teach-recursion/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><table><tbody><tr><td><p><span>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><a href="#%28part._.Some_.Canonical_.Examples%29" data-pltdoc="x">1<span>&nbsp;</span>Some Canonical Examples</a></p></td></tr><tr><td><p><span>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><a href="#%28part._.Factorial%29" data-pltdoc="x">1.1<span>&nbsp;</span>Factorial</a></p></td></tr><tr><td><p><span>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><a href="#%28part._.Fibonacci%29" data-pltdoc="x">1.2<span>&nbsp;</span>Fibonacci</a></p></td></tr><tr><td><p><span>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><a href="#%28part._.Euclid_s_.Algorithm%29" data-pltdoc="x">1.3<span>&nbsp;</span>Euclid’s Algorithm</a></p></td></tr><tr><td><p><span>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><a href="#%28part._.Towers_of_.Hanoi%29" data-pltdoc="x">1.4<span>&nbsp;</span>Towers of Hanoi</a></p></td></tr><tr><td></td></tr><tr><td><p><span>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><a href="#%28part._.Recursion_versus_.Cyclicity%29" data-pltdoc="x">2<span>&nbsp;</span>Recursion versus Cyclicity</a></p></td></tr><tr><td></td></tr><tr><td><p><span>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><a href="#%28part._.Is_.Recursion_in_the_.Problem_%29" data-pltdoc="x">3<span>&nbsp;</span>Is Recursion in the Problem?</a></p></td></tr><tr><td></td></tr><tr><td><p><span>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><a href="#%28part._.How_to_.Teach_.Recursion%29" data-pltdoc="x">4<span>&nbsp;</span>How to Teach Recursion</a></p></td></tr><tr><td><p><span>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><a href="#%28part._.Function_.Follows_.Form%29" data-pltdoc="x">4.1<span>&nbsp;</span>Function Follows Form</a></p></td></tr><tr><td><p><span>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><a href="#%28part._.One_.Datatype__.Many_.Problems%29" data-pltdoc="x">4.2<span>&nbsp;</span>One Datatype, Many Problems</a></p></td></tr><tr><td><p><span>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><a href="#%28part._.When_.Recursion_.Becomes_.Difficult%29" data-pltdoc="x">4.3<span>&nbsp;</span>When Recursion Becomes Difficult</a></p></td></tr><tr><td><p><span>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><a href="#%28part._.Back_to_the_.Canonical_.Problems%29" data-pltdoc="x">4.4<span>&nbsp;</span>Back to the Canonical Problems</a></p></td></tr><tr><td><p><span>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><a href="#%28part._.Going_.Beyond_.Loops%29" data-pltdoc="x">4.5<span>&nbsp;</span>Going Beyond Loops</a></p></td></tr><tr><td><p><span>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><a href="#%28part._.That_.Was_.Pretty_.Dense%29" data-pltdoc="x">4.6<span>&nbsp;</span>That Was Pretty Dense</a></p></td></tr></tbody></table><p>We all know how to teach recursion. We’ve done it for decades. We pick some
honored, time-tested examples—<wbr>Fibonacci numbers and factorial being leading
candidates—<wbr>and use them to teach the general idea. They’re so canonical they
come directly from the gods: you can find these in books by people like
Niklaus Wirth.</p><p>But I’m here to tell you they got it wrong, and everyone’s been getting it
wrong ever since. Students come away underwhelmed and baffled, and go on to
become the next generation of teachers who repeat this process. However, we
need not repeat this cycle; we have much better methods.</p><h3>1<tt>&nbsp;</tt><a name="(part._.Some_.Canonical_.Examples)"></a>Some Canonical Examples</h3><p>Let’s start by looking at what’s wrong with our canonical examples.</p><h4>1.1<tt>&nbsp;</tt><a name="(part._.Factorial)"></a>Factorial</h4><p>First off, almost nobody has ever needed to compute a factorial. I’ve been
programming for about 35 years and the only times I’ve needed to compute a
factorial was when doing recreational mathematics or using programming to
explore some especially thorny combinatorics problem. Otherwise, I’ve never had
any need for factorials.</p><p>Second, the answer isn’t <span>meaningful</span>. Quick, what’s the factorial of 13?
Most people have no idea and (related to the above) don’t care. There’s nothing
recognizable about the answer. The only reason most programmers recognize the
number 3628800 is because we’ve tested factorial on a “big enough number” to
confirm that it worked, not because we actually cared about it. If you adopt a
curriculum that asks students to <a href="https://cs.brown.edu/~sk/Publications/Papers/Published/wk-examplar/">develop examples
before they write code</a>, students would be hard-pressed to write the answer
independently; many would resort to implementing it first and plugging in the
answer.</p><p>Third, factorial has poor numeric properties in most languages. Unless you have
built-in, automatic support for big numbers, you will soon either get answers
that print in odd-looking scientific notation, or worse, overflow (on many
languages, with default integers, factorial of 17 is -288522240).</p><p>Finally, many students have written factorial-like programs before, perhaps
even factorial itself, using loops. A natural question they (should!) ask an
instructor is, “Why should I do this again?” The answer, inevitably, is,
“Because I’m asking you to.” There’s no better way to turn off a student.</p><p>So let’s summarize the “recursion experience”: a useless problem, with
unrecognizable answers, with wonky-looking behavior, using an unnecessary new
technique that you’re forced to use “because”.</p><h4>1.2<tt>&nbsp;</tt><a name="(part._.Fibonacci)"></a>Fibonacci</h4><p>Let’s turn our gaze to Fibonacci.</p><p>First off, almost nobody has ever needed to compute a Fibonacci number,
either. I’ve been programming for about 35 years and the only times I’ve needed
it was when doing recrea—<wbr>you see where this is going.<span><span><span>I do find them
useful to convert beween miles and kilometers, though.</span></span></span></p><p>Second, the answer isn’t meaningful, and students would again be hard-pressed
to write the answer independently (what, keep track of all those
calls?!?). Third, it has poor numeric properties: around 44, Fibonacci is
correct, then becomes negative (which is obviously incorrect), then immediately
again is a very reasonable-looking positive number that just happens to be
completely wrong. The main reason we haven’t cared for decades is because we
really just don’t have much use for Fibonacci numbers.</p><p>Finally, it has atrocious time-complexity.</p><p>So let’s summarize the “recursion experience”: a useless problem, with
unrecognizable answers, with wonky-looking behavior, that runs really sloooowly
(and worse, the slowness first creeps up on you stealthily and then suddenly
administers a hammer-blow to the back of your head). In fact, its main value is
as a function that you should <span>not</span> write (straightforwardly) recursively.</p><p>This is how we teach recursion.</p><h4>1.3<tt>&nbsp;</tt><a name="(part._.Euclid_s_.Algorithm)"></a>Euclid’s Algorithm</h4><p>Oh, I’m not done.</p><p>Another famous mathematician, another famous function.</p><p>Okay, I’ll grant, many students have at least heard of the greatest common
divisor. They may vaguely recall using it in school for dealing with
fractions. So it has familiarity going for it.</p><p>Unfortunately, it was useful in a context that <span>no longer makes
sense</span>. Once you have a programming language, you have a calculator. Unless
you’re implementing a calculator (and perhaps even then), you have no real need
to implement Euclid’s algorithm.</p><p>And even if you do, admit it: you don’t remember why Euclid’s algorithm
works. I certainly have to re-derive why it produces the right answer every
time I’ve implemented it (purely for illustrative purposes, every few
years). Otherwise, it’s just a mystical pattern.</p><p>So what’s the lesson we get from Euclid’s algorithm? That recursion is for
encoding mystical patterns for no-longer-useful functions? In fact, is
recursion useful for anything <span>other</span> than weird math functions?</p><h4>1.4<tt>&nbsp;</tt><a name="(part._.Towers_of_.Hanoi)"></a>Towers of Hanoi</h4><p>Oh yes it is! Maybe that’s why we have this old standby.</p><p>First, we’ll start with some invented Eastern mysticism. Orientalism is always
a good pedagogic device, right?</p><p>Next, it’s a problem fraught with questions of representation: how exactly do
you represent the content of the towers? That is actually a somewhat
interesting question for a beginning student, but (a) it’s not obvious until
you’ve had some programming practice, and (b) it has absolutely nothing to do
with recursion. So you have a hard, unrelated sub-problem in the middle of your
example that “demonstrates” recursion. Doesn’t that utterly violate the
pedagogic principle of changing just one thing at a time so students can focus
on what’s salient? (And don’t forget, this is another problem with exponential
time behavior!)</p><p>Furthermore, if you don’t tell students the (recursive) solution and leave them
to figure it out for themselves, you haven’t given them a programming problem:
you’ve given them a puzzle. Those are different things. In particular, the
Towers of Hanoi is a particularly <span>difficult</span> kind of recursion—<wbr>oh, you
didn’t know there are different kinds of recursion? Read on.</p><p>Finally, again, does anyone care? Do students believe they would be called on
to help monks move disks around? What other problem is similar to this one? And
if there are any, do we teach them, or do we present these magnificently
isolated monks…in magnificent isolation?</p><p>What’s worse is that so many of these are fundamentally <span>static</span> problems:
there are only so many interesting inputs, and each one has a completely
deterministic solution, so once one builds up a table of outputs for standard
inputs, the problem is essentially solved. For such problems, it would be smart
(especially when the run-time complexity is exponential in the input) to just
stash the answers and never run the code again.<span><span><span>Yes, I know,
memoization.</span></span></span></p><h3>2<tt>&nbsp;</tt><a name="(part._.Recursion_versus_.Cyclicity)"></a>Recursion versus Cyclicity</h3><p>Another standard, time-honored pedagogic device is the dumb joke: “to
understand recursion you must understand recursion”, and so on.</p><p>These confuse recursion with cyclicity.</p><p>If you don’t understand the difference, don’t use the dumb jokes.</p><p>If you do understand the difference, don’t use the dumb jokes then
either. They’re still <span>dumb</span> jokes.</p><h3>3<tt>&nbsp;</tt><a name="(part._.Is_.Recursion_in_the_.Problem_)"></a>Is Recursion in the Problem?</h3><p>An attempt at a better answer might be that a <span>problem</span> is “inherently”
recursive. However, that’s just a limitation of viewpoint. There’s nothing more
inherently recursive than iterative about factorial. All the problems above can
be expressed even more declaratively, as in a mathematical specification, that
eliminates any implementation directive (e.g.: the greatest common divisor is the
<span>greatest</span>, <span>common</span>, <span>divisor</span>: the definition of the problem
says nothing about how to find it, and searching through all numbers to find
divisors that are common and taking the largest one is no less valid a
solution).</p><p>No, the essence lies elsewhere. But we’re getting closer.</p><h3>4<tt>&nbsp;</tt><a name="(part._.How_to_.Teach_.Recursion)"></a>How to Teach Recursion</h3><p>Wait up, I didn’t promise this. Check the title again.</p><p>But I know, I can’t just stop here. So I’ll give you a brief peek of how to
proceed.</p><p>In <span><a href="https://htdp.org/">How to Design Programs</a></span> (<span>HTDP</span>), we have a rather different view of
recursion. The key idea is this.</p><h4>4.1<tt>&nbsp;</tt><a name="(part._.Function_.Follows_.Form)"></a>Function Follows Form</h4><p>Where does recursion come from? <span>HTDP</span> argues that it arises from
<span>self-references in data</span>. That is, <span>recursive data suggest recursive
solutions</span>. This is the key insight you need for understanding recursion. Not
only does it make sense once you think about it, it also demonstrates why most
other approaches to teaching recursion are essentially incorrect.</p><p><span>HTDP</span> teaches a design “recipe”. In it, you describe your program’s (or
function’s) data structures, and identify self-references in these
data. Self-referential data are pretty straightforward: even kids can understand
them. For instance, even a child informed about biology can answer basic
questions like these:
</p><div><table><tbody><tr><td><p><span>- Does a child have (biological) parents?</span></p></td></tr><tr><td><p><span>- Yes.</span></p></td></tr><tr><td><p><span>- How many?</span></p></td></tr><tr><td><p><span>- Two, a (biological) male and (biological) female.</span></p></td></tr><tr><td><p><span>- Does the female have parents?</span></p></td></tr><tr><td><p><span>- Yes.</span></p></td></tr><tr><td><p><span>- How many?</span></p></td></tr><tr><td><p><span>- Two, a (biological) mother and a (biological) father.</span></p></td></tr><tr><td><p><span>- Does the male…</span></p></td></tr></tbody></table></div><p>They can see where this goes. They grasp the idea of a (biological) family tree
pretty intuitively. They can similarly see other kinds of self-referential data
even at a young age, well before they program.</p><p>Next, <span>HTDP</span> explains how the structure of the data suggest a structure to the
solution. This solution structure is generic, and called the “template”. You
arrive at this entirely mechanically from the data structure, even before
you’ve contemplated the exact problem you’re trying to solve.</p><p>(The template is not a rule, it’s a suggestion. It helps you overcome the
“blank page” problem by offering the outline of a suggestion. Sometimes, the
template leads to a correct but insufficiently-efficient solution. Such a
solution is …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://parentheticallyspeaking.org/articles/how-not-to-teach-recursion/">https://parentheticallyspeaking.org/articles/how-not-to-teach-recursion/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://parentheticallyspeaking.org/articles/how-not-to-teach-recursion/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25610690</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 05:36:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How Ray Kurzweil’s 1998 predictions about 2019 are faring]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 115 | Comments 110 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25610275">thread link</a>) | @apsec112
<br/>
January 1, 2021 | https://www.militantfuturist.com/how-ray-kurzweils-2019-predictions-are-faring-pt-4/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.militantfuturist.com/how-ray-kurzweils-2019-predictions-are-faring-pt-4/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-1933">
		<!-- .entry-header -->

	
	<div>
		
<p>This is the fourth…and LAST…entry in my series of blog posts analyzing the accuracy of Ray Kurzweil’s predictions about what things would be like in 2019. These predictions come from his 1998 book&nbsp;<em>The Age of Spiritual Machines</em>.&nbsp;You can view the previous installments of this series here:</p>



<p><a href="https://www.militantfuturist.com/how-ray-kurzweils-2019-predictions-are-faring-pt-1/">Part 1</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.militantfuturist.com/how-ray-kurzweils-2019-predictions-are-faring-pt-2/">Part 2</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.militantfuturist.com/how-ray-kurzweils-2019-predictions-are-faring-pt-3/">Part 3</a></p>



<p><strong><em>“An undercurrent of concern is developing with regard to the influence of machine intelligence. There continue to be differences between human and machine intelligence, but the advantages of human intelligence are becoming more difficult to identify and articulate. Computer intelligence is thoroughly interwoven into the mechanisms of civilization and is designed to be outwardly subservient to apparent human control. On the one hand, human transactions and decisions require by law a human agent of responsibility, even if fully initiated by machine intelligence. On the other hand, few decisions are made without significant involvement and consultation with machine-based intelligence.”</em></strong></p>



<p><strong>MOSTLY RIGHT</strong></p>



<p>Technological advances have moved concerns over the influence of machine intelligence to the fore in developed countries. In many domains of skill previously considered hallmarks of intelligent thinking, such as driving vehicles, recognizing images and faces, analyzing data, writing short documents, and even diagnosing diseases, machines had achieved human levels of performance by the end of 2019. And in a few niche tasks, such as playing Go, chess, or poker, machines were superhuman. Eroded human dominance in these and other fields did indeed force philosophers and scientists to grapple with the meaning of “intelligence” and “creativity,” and made it harder yet more important to define how human thinking was still special and useful. </p>



<p>While the prospect of artificial general intelligence was still viewed with skepticism, there was no real doubt among experts and laypeople in 2019 that task-specific AIs and robots would continue improving, and without any clear upper limit to their performance. This made technological unemployment and the solutions for it frequent topics of public discussion across the developed world. In 2019, one of the candidates for the upcoming U.S. Presidential election, Andrew Yang, even made these issues central to his political platform. </p>



<p>If “algorithms” is another name for “computer intelligence” in the prediction’s text, then yes, it is woven into the mechanisms of civilization and is ostensibly under human control, but in fact drives human thinking and behavior. To the latter point, great alarm has been raised over how algorithms used by social media companies and advertisers affect sociopolitical beliefs (particularly, conspiracy thinking and closedmindedness), spending decisions, and mental health. </p>



<p>Human transactions and decisions still require a “human agent of responsibility”: Autonomous cars aren’t allowed to drive unless a human is in the driver’s seat, human beings ultimately own and trade (or authorize the trading of) all assets, and no military lets its autonomous fighting machines kill people without orders from a human. The only part of the prediction that seems wrong is the last sentence. Probably most decisions that humans make are done without consulting a “machine-based intelligence.” Consider that most daily purchases (e.g. – where to go for lunch, where to get gas, whether and how to pay a utility bill) involve little thought or analysis. A frighteningly large share of investment choices are also made instinctively, with benefit of little or no research. However, it should be noted that one area of human decision-making, dating, has become much more data-driven, and it was common in 2019 for people to use sorting algorithms, personality test results, and other filters to choose potential mates. </p>



<p><strong><em>“Public and private spaces are routinely monitored by machine intelligence to prevent interpersonal violence.”</em></strong></p>



<p><strong>MOSTLY RIGHT</strong></p>



<p>Gunfire detection systems, which are comprised of networks of microphones emplaced across an area and which use machine intelligence to recognize the sounds of gunshots and to triangulate their origins, were emplaced in over 100 cities at the end of 2019. The dominant company in this niche industry, “ShotSpotter,” used human analysts to review its systems’ results before forwarding alerts to local police departments, so the systems were not truly automated, but nonetheless they made heavy use of machine intelligence. </p>



<p>Automated license plate reader cameras, which are commonly mounted next to roads or on police cars, also use machine intelligence and are widespread. The technology has definitely reduced violent crime, as it has allowed police to track down stolen vehicles and cars belonging to violent criminals faster than would have otherwise been possible. </p>



<p>In some countries, surveillance cameras with facial recognition technology monitor many public spaces. The cameras compare the people they see to mugshots of criminals, and alert the local police whenever a wanted person is seen. China is probably the world leader in facial recognition surveillance, and in a famous 2018 case, it used the technology to find one criminal among 60,000 people who attended a concert in Nanchang. </p>



<p>At the end of 2019, several organizations were researching ways to use machine learning for real-time recognition of violent behavior in surveillance camera feeds, but the systems were not accurate enough for commercial use. </p>



<p><strong><em>“People attempt to protect their privacy with near-unbreakable encryption technologies, but privacy continues to be a major political and social issue with each individual’s practically every move stored in a database somewhere.” </em></strong></p>



<p><strong>RIGHT</strong></p>



<p>In 2013, National Security Agency (NSA) analyst Edward Snowden leaked a massive number of secret documents, revealing the true extent of his employer’s global electronic surveillance. The world was shocked to learn that the NSA was routinely tracking the locations and cell phone call traffic of millions of people, and gathering enormous volumes of data from personal emails, internet browsing histories, and other electronic communications by forcing private telecom and internet companies (e.g. – Verizon, Google, Apple) to let it secretly search through their databases. Together with British intelligence, the NSA has the tools to spy on the electronic devices and internet usage of almost anyone on Earth. </p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="2011" data-permalink="https://www.militantfuturist.com/how-ray-kurzweils-2019-predictions-are-faring-pt-4/edward-snowden/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.militantfuturist.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/edward-snowden.jpg?fit=992%2C744&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="992,744" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="edward-snowden" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.militantfuturist.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/edward-snowden.jpg?fit=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.militantfuturist.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/edward-snowden.jpg?fit=525%2C394&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="525" height="394" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.militantfuturist.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/edward-snowden.jpg?resize=525%2C394&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.militantfuturist.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/edward-snowden.jpg?w=992&amp;ssl=1 992w, https://i0.wp.com/www.militantfuturist.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/edward-snowden.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.militantfuturist.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/edward-snowden.jpg?resize=768%2C576&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px" data-recalc-dims="1"><figcaption>Edward Snowden</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Snowden also revealed that the NSA unsurprisingly had sophisticated means for cracking encrypted communications, which it routinely deployed against people it was spying on, but that even its capabilities had limits. Because some commercially available encryption tools were too time-consuming or too technically challenging to crack, the NSA secretly pressured software companies and computing hardware manufacturers to install “backdoors” in their products, which would allow the Agency to bypass any encryption their owners implemented. </p>



<p>During the 2010s, big tech titans like Facebook, Google, Amazon, and Apple also came under major scrutiny for quietly gathering vast amounts of personal data from their users, and reselling it to third parties to make hundreds of billions of dollars. The decade also saw many epic thefts of sensitive personal data from corporate and government databases, affecting hundreds of millions of people worldwide. </p>



<p>With these events in mind, it’s quite true that concerns over digital privacy and confidentiality of personal data have become “major political and social issues,” and that there’s growing displeasure at the fact that “each individual’s practically every move stored in a database somewhere.” The response has been strongest in the European Union, which, in 2018, enacted the most stringent and impactful law to protect the digital rights of individuals–the “General Data Protection Regulation” (GDPR). </p>



<p>Widespread awareness of secret government surveillance programs and of the risk of personal electronic messages being made public thanks to hacks have also bolstered interest in commercial encryption. “Whatsapp” is a common text messaging app with built-in end-to-end encryption. It was invented in 2016 and had 1.5 billion users by 2019. “Tor” is a web browser with built-in encryption that became relatively common during the 2010s after it was learned even the NSA couldn’t spy on people who used it. Additionally, virtual private networks (VPNs), which provide an intermediate level of data privacy protection for little expense and hassle, are in common use. </p>



<p><strong><em>“The existence of the human underclass continues as an issue. While there is sufficient prosperity to provide basic necessities (secure housing and food, among others) without significant strain to the economy, old controversies persist regarding issues of responsibility and opportunity.” </em></strong></p>



<p><strong>RIGHT</strong></p>



<p>It’s unclear whether this prediction pertained to the U.S., to rich countries in aggregate, or to the world as a whole, and “underclass” is not defined, so we can’t say whether it refers only to desperately poor people who are literally starving, or to people who are better off than that but still under major daily stress due to lack of money. Whatever the case, by any reasonable definition, there is an “underclass” of people in almost every country. </p>



<p>In the U.S. and other rich countries, welfare states provide even the poorest people with access to housing, food, and other needs, though there are still those who go without because severe mental illness and/or drug addiction keep them stuck in homeless lifestyles and render them too behaviorally disorganized to apply for government help or to be admitted into free group housing. Some people also live in destitution in rich countries because they are illegal immigrants or fugitives with arrest warrants, and contacting the authorities for welfare assistance would lead to their detection and …</p></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.militantfuturist.com/how-ray-kurzweils-2019-predictions-are-faring-pt-4/">https://www.militantfuturist.com/how-ray-kurzweils-2019-predictions-are-faring-pt-4/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.militantfuturist.com/how-ray-kurzweils-2019-predictions-are-faring-pt-4/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25610275</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 04:01:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Getting Started in Robotics]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 266 | Comments 56 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25608932">thread link</a>) | @networdtwo
<br/>
January 1, 2021 | https://allshire.org/getting-started-robotics/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://allshire.org/getting-started-robotics/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<figure>
<img src="https://allshire.org/img/post/getting-started/spot_mini.jpg">
<figcaption>Boston Dynamics' Spot Mini Robot. <em><a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:SpotMini,_Boston_Dynamics,_Robot.jpg">CC</a></em></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>People sometimes ask me for robotics resources. There aren’t many high quality internet-first lists available on this topic, so I made one I can link to. I’ll continually update this list so feel free to give <strong><a href="mailto:arthur@allshire.org">suggestions if things are missing or you have better links</a></strong>.</p>
<p>There’s some more interesting comments on this topic in the <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25608932">Hacker News discussion</a>.</p>
<h3 id="general-advice">General Advice</h3>
<p>Robotics can be overwhelming from the sheer number of fields involved (everything from mathematics to physics to computer science to mechanical engineering enters in). Remember: <em>you won’t start as an expert in anything; you can’t end up as an expert in everything</em>. Also learning will not be a linear path; outside of courses, acquire knowledge as you need it in projects.</p>
<p>Try as much as possible to avoid this antipattern (I still struggle)…
</p><blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">An illustrated guide to learning absolutely nothing <a href="https://t.co/bKIMX2r6iU">pic.twitter.com/bKIMX2r6iU</a></p>— Eugene Vinitsky (@EugeneVinitsky) <a href="https://twitter.com/EugeneVinitsky/status/1343701831210307586?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 28, 2020</a></blockquote>


<h4 id="communities">Communities</h4>
<p>Instead of attempting to pre-load your head with maximum theory, try to get as much <strong>practical experience</strong> as possible (see below), whether that be joining a club, lab, or if you’re lucky in an internship or job.</p>
<p>It is incredibly hard to do something on your own without some kind of <a href="https://dcgross.com/the-environment-diet/">environmental forcing function</a>.  If at all possible, embed yourself in a community of people working on problems of interest to you.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.firstinspires.org/robotics/frc">FIRST robotics competition</a> - Simply put, FRC was the awesomest thing ever for me. If you can find a team, beg them to let you participate…</li>
<li>If you are a student at a university - try joining a lab!</li>
</ul>
<p>Unfortunately outside of these robotics is currently not an easy field to break into. The sheer number of ‘moving parts’ to a (useful) robotic system - from hardware to drivers to algorithms to user interfaces - means it’s tough to hack together a demo in a few weeks, get users, and bootstrap / apply to some accelerator like in many software projects. Making the jump from “hacker” to “career”, even with all the knowledge in the world is hard. If you know solutions to this, let me know.</p>
<h3 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites</h3>
<p><strong>Computer programming</strong> - this is essential if you want to do basically anything in robotics. Python and <a href="https://www.stroustrup.com/Tour.html">C++</a> are the most important languages to know - learn both.
Familiarity with basic data-structures and algorithms concepts is helpful for problem solving and in some fields like motion planning but initially less vital than you may think - it’s not necessary to be a master leetcoder.</p>
<p><strong>Maths</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Linear algebra - vital in most topics beyond basic basic control. If you want to become an expert, <a href="https://linear.axler.net/">Axler’s book</a> is good (though I didn’t make it through the whole thing 😳).</li>
<li>Calculus - fundamental differential calculus and partial derivatives is required to understand optimisation algorithms which are everywhere in robo.</li>
<li>The book <a href="https://pimbook.org/">A Programmer’s Introduction to Mathematics</a> is actually a solid foundation if you want a quick overview of both of the above topics.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="important-concepts">Important Concepts</h3>
<p><strong>Controllers</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Wiki’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PID_controller">PID controller</a> isn’t bad if you want to learn the basics (<a href="https://www.argmin.net/2018/04/19/pid/">95%</a> of controllers used in industry are PID). Ben Recht’s <a href="https://www.argmin.net/2018/04/19/pid/">blog post</a> is also decent.</li>
<li><a href="https://web.stanford.edu/class/archive/ee/ee392m/ee392m.1056/">These course slides</a> are good for basics and more advanced concepts like <strong>MPC</strong> .</li>
<li><a href="https://janismac.github.io/ControlChallenges/">Control challenges</a> is a set of (very fun) challenges that will allow you to test your ability to write basic controllers.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8319J1BEHwM">This talk</a> from FIRST Robotics team 254 is great for going over the basics of robot control and showing how we can improve on basic PID using simple interpolation.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mathematics and Mechanics of Robotics &amp; Manipulation</strong> - This set of <a href="http://www.nathanratliff.com/pedagogy">notes by Nathan Ratliff</a> provides a great overview of many topics.  These <a href="https://ethz.ch/content/dam/ethz/special-interest/mavt/robotics-n-intelligent-systems/rsl-dam/documents/RobotDynamics2017/RD_HS2017script.pdf">notes on robot dynamics</a> from ETH are also great.</p>
<p><strong>Filtering</strong> - <a href="https://github.com/rlabbe/Kalman-and-Bayesian-Filters-in-Python">Kalman and Bayesian Filters in Python</a> is a great read with interactive notebook examples throughout. Good for building intuition on both Bayesian statistics as well as how filters for linear and nonlinear dynamical systems work. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kalman_filter#Technical_description_and_context">wiki article on the Kalman Filter</a>  and <a href="https://www.bzarg.com/p/how-a-kalman-filter-works-in-pictures/">this blog post</a> is also well written if you want a shorter overview.</p>
<p><strong>Machine Learning &amp; Neural Networks</strong> - Focus less on the basics of machine learning than the application of neural networks as function approximators, which is their primary utility as perception and decision making modules in robotics. <a href="http://neuralnetworksanddeeplearning.com/">Michael Nielsen’s book</a> is my favourite resource in this regard. The <a href="https://www.deeplearningbook.org/">canonical deep learning book</a> is good reference but you don’t need to read the whole thing - pick out specific topics as required.</p>
<p><strong>Path and motion planning</strong> - Wiki has a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Motion_planning">decent overview</a> and details some <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rapidly-exploring_random_tree">basic</a> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A*_search_algorithm">algorithms</a>. I haven’t read it but this book is apparently a <a href="http://lavalle.pl/planning/">good comprehensive guide</a>, and a course based on it is available <a href="https://web.eecs.umich.edu/~dmitryb/courses/winter2019motionplanning/index.html">here</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Reinforcement Learning</strong> &amp; more on controllers - Ben Recht’s “<a href="http://www.argmin.net/2018/06/25/outsider-rl/">outsider’s tour of RL</a>” provides a nice concise overview of many relevant concepts and ties them to classical control. <a href="https://openai.com/blog/spinning-up-in-deep-rl/">Spinning up in Deep Reinforcement Learning</a> is another great reference on the topic and exhibits many of the most important algorithms for research in the field.</p>
<h3 id="other-topics--resources">Other Topics &amp; Resources</h3>
<h4 id="books">Books</h4>
<ul>
<li>For beginners looking for a single book, <a href="https://link.springer.com/book/10.1007/978-3-319-62533-1">Elements of Robotics</a> looks like an a great resource, and I’m only sorry it didn’t exist when I was starting. Provides self-contained introductions to many topics listed, pitched at a level high-schoolers / beginning university students can understand.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.springer.com/gp/book/9781846286414">Robotics: Modelling, Planning and Control</a> is <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25609653">apparently</a> an all time classic covering many topics listed above..</li>
<li>Convex Optimisation is used in everything from simulators to controllers and beyond. I intend to read the <a href="https://web.stanford.edu/~boyd/cvxbook/">canonical book</a> (free) at some point.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="courses">Courses</h4>
<ul>
<li>The Berkley <strong><a href="https://people.eecs.berkeley.edu/~pabbeel/cs287-fa19/">Advanced Robotics</a></strong> course provides relatively self contained expositions of many topics in lecture format (don’t be scared off by the ‘advanced' moniker, it’s not that incomprehensible 😅.)</li>
<li>Russ Tedrake’s courses on <a href="http://underactuated.mit.edu/">Underactuated Robotics</a> and <a href="http://manipulation.csail.mit.edu/">Manipulation</a> seem really high quality (I haven’t gotten around to doing them myself yet).</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="software">Software</h3>
<p>The space of software is so vast I couldn’t fit it all here… <a href="http://jslee02.github.io/awesome-robotics-libraries/">this list</a> provides a much more comprehensive overview in this regard. Some utilities I’ve found useful are:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ros.org/install/">ROS</a> is very widely used many projects, worth picking up the basics.</li>
<li><a href="https://docs.ray.io/en/latest/rllib.html">RLLib</a> has implementations of many reinforcement learning algorithms and support for distributed training.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="simulators">Simulators</h4>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/ARISE-Initiative/robosuite">Robosuite</a> is great for robot learning and has many richly-designed built-in environments.</li>
<li><a href="https://developer.nvidia.com/isaac-gym">Isaac Gym</a> is recently released and provides extremely fast samples for reinforcement learning. It does this by running thousands of environments in parallel on the GPU (in almost all other sims physics is run on the CPU meaning you can only run one environment at once). You can train tasks in minutes that previously took hours.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="interesting-lines-of-work">Interesting Lines of Work</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Domain Randomisation</strong>  is highly underrated, and will likely get more important as we get faster simulators which are able to generalize better. <a href="https://openai.com/blog/learning-dexterity/">Learning Dexterity</a> from OpenAI is a very interesting paper, and the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SRupIVknV-A">line</a> of <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1906.01728.pdf">work</a> around improving simulator parameter show two different and interesting takes on this powerful approach.</li>
<li><strong>Hierarchy</strong> in reinforcement learning has shown promising results in getting behaviour that generalises, the <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1909.08399.pdf">DeepGait</a> and <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2011.15119">UniCon</a> paper being two interesting examples.</li>
<li><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1910.03135">DexPilot</a> is a really cool low-cost system for teleoperation (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qGE-deYfb8I">video</a>). Partially inspired <a href="https://allshire.org/teleop/">my piece on teleoperation</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="hardware">Hardware</h3>
<p>Probably my weakest area… up for recommendations about specific great resources.
<a href="https://www.onshape.com/en/">OnShape</a> is a great resource for designing things and is great even with minimal CAD experience (even I am able to use it!)</p>
<p><a href="https://open-dynamic-robot-initiative.github.io/">Open Dynamic Robot initiative</a> has many robots that you can build with off-the-shelf components.</p>
<p>Others' recommendations -</p>
<p>In the HN thread, <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25612255">contingencies had some tips</a> on how to get started yourself on the hardware side.</p>
<p>I’m told cadathons such as those <a href="https://blogs.solidworks.com/tech/2020/03/20-years-of-model-mania.html">organised by Solidworks</a> are a good way to get started. They also have a <a href="https://my.solidworks.com/training/path/14/cswa-exam-prep-course">series of lessons</a> on CADding fundamentals.</p>
<p><a href="https://grabcad.com/">GrabCAD</a> has big libries of pre-existing models you can use.</p>
<h3 id="business--higher-level-thinking">Business &amp; Higher-Level Thinking</h3>
<p>Very interesting side of things, however there is somewhat of a paucity of great resources (I’m pretty sure many in the space refrain from publishing their theses.) Please send if you have others I have missed!</p>
<ul>
<li>Michael Dempsey has some <a href="http://www.michaeldempsey.me/archive.html">great writing</a> on the business of autonomy.</li>
<li>Trucks VC has an interesting newsletter about <a href="https://www.trucks.vc/">autonomy</a>.</li>
<li>Jessy Lin wrote <a href="http://jessylin.com/blog/">some essays</a> on topic surrounding the economics and future of autonomy and HRI.</li>
<li><a href="https://rodneybrooks.com/blog/">Rodney Brooks</a> makes predictions in the robotics space on a yearly basis and has some good rigorous thinking on there.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/">EE Times</a> has news and frequent opinion pieces in this space.</li>
<li>Though inexperienced, I sometimes try my best to <a href="https://allshire.org/">write on this topic</a> :)</li>
</ul>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://allshire.org/getting-started-robotics/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25608932</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:33:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
