<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 12:30:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 12:30:45 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pianists for Alternatively Sized Keyboards]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 133 | Comments 153 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25173522">thread link</a>) | @spekcular
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | http://paskpiano.org/about/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://paskpiano.org/about/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="30" data-elementor-settings="[]">
						<div>
							<div>
							<section data-id="6b7c51e" data-element_type="section">
						
		</section>
				<section data-id="0db4fdb" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="89500ce" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<section data-id="02b9628" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="c6a8384" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="39c182b" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div>
					<div><p>PASK – Pianists for Alternatively Sized Keyboards – is an international movement committed to achieving change in relation to piano keyboard size.</p><p>Specifically, PASK aims to convince piano manufacturers to begin producing piano keyboards in three standard sizes. Purchasers of new pianos will then have a choice of keyboard size. In addition to the current ‘large’ size, we need two additional sizes with <u>narrower keys</u>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>The current piano keyboard has prevailed since the 1880’s and was not designed for the physical capabilities of the population at large. It has been assumed that the current size is suitable for all, whereas in fact it is isn’t. The keys are too wide for the majority of pianists, considering men, women and children of all nationalities and across all age groups.</p><p>The current keyboard size and key width suits people with large hands, generally adult males with average to above average spans. However, for those with smaller hands, today’s piano increases technical difficulties and learning time. It limits musical expression and prevents access to a large amount of the piano repertoire. Worst of all, it can cause debilitating pain and injury.</p><p>A simple analogy illustrates the point. Does it make sense that all men in an athletics race should have to wear the same size shoes? And that female athletes have to run in the same size shoes as the men? And that children have to run in the same size shoes as adults?</p></div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
				<div data-id="86f8594" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="93ab53a" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div>
					<p><img width="290" height="300" src="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Square-logo-2-290x300.jpg" alt="" srcset="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Square-logo-2-290x300.jpg 290w, http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Square-logo-2-768x796.jpg 768w, http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Square-logo-2-989x1024.jpg 989w, http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Square-logo-2.jpg 1145w" sizes="(max-width: 290px) 100vw, 290px">											</p>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section data-id="be5765d" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="6591610" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<section data-id="721b21b" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="77af1a3" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="b67b3fe" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div>
					<p><img width="763" height="1024" src="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Kristen1-Nov-2014-763x1024.jpg" alt="" srcset="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Kristen1-Nov-2014-763x1024.jpg 763w, http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Kristen1-Nov-2014-224x300.jpg 224w, http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Kristen1-Nov-2014-768x1031.jpg 768w, http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Kristen1-Nov-2014.jpg 1216w" sizes="(max-width: 763px) 100vw, 763px">											</p>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
				<div data-id="bdfaffa" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="984bedd" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div>
					<p><img width="720" height="960" src="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Students-at-SMU-Institute-for-Young-Pianists.jpg" alt="" srcset="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Students-at-SMU-Institute-for-Young-Pianists.jpg 720w, http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Students-at-SMU-Institute-for-Young-Pianists-225x300.jpg 225w" sizes="(max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px">											</p>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section data-id="d469830" data-element_type="section">
						
		</section>
				<section data-id="6326091" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="cb76b18" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="25d103d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div>
					<div><p>The<strong> long term goal of PASK </strong>is for acoustic and digital piano manufacturers to offer a choice of three standard keyboard sizes in accordance with the DS standards. These are: DS5.5® (7/8) and the DS6.0® (15/16) as well as the current ‘large’ DS6.5<em>&nbsp;</em>keyboard. They need to be&nbsp;mass-produced and marketed worldwide in such a way that the new alternative sizes are readily available and naturally accepted options for all pianists and teachers.&nbsp;</p><p>For this to happen, we need to focus on both building the demand from the piano world as well as encouraging supply from manufacturers. Clearly, these are interdependent.&nbsp;</p><p>Pianists with smaller hands must create a united voice and demand access to keyboards with narrower keys. Piano teachers, universities and conservatoriums need to recognise their benefits. Competitions and concert venues should provide a choice of keyboard for performers.</p><p>Alternatively sized keyboards are currently only available from a limited number of sources, are expensive and often involve long wait times for customers. The major piano manufacturers need to take up this challenge.&nbsp;A key factor in creating change will be public support from prominent pianists, academics and teachers around the world.</p><p>There are three main strategies required to achieve this goal:</p><p>1.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Raising awareness of the benefits of reduced size keyboards for those with smaller hands.</p><p>2.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Creating opportunities for pianists to experience the difference in playing on narrower keys.</p><p>3.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Breaking down barriers and resistance to change.</p></div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section data-id="8b8c474" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="0033df0" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="dea7d2a" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<p>
			<h2>PASK structure and founders</h2>		</p>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section data-id="c7ddbd5" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="3edd0c6" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="925cf88" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div>
					<p>PASK is not a formally constituted organisation, but a network of people working towards a common goal.

There are three founders of PASK:

Ms Erica Booker from Sydney, Australia – Graduate of the New South Wales Conservatorium of Music, pianist and piano teacher. Erica is also a Suzuki teacher trainer and leading advocate for alternatively sized piano keyboards:<a href="https://ericabookerpiano.com/%E2%80%8B" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&nbsp;</a>&nbsp;<a href="https://ericabookerpiano.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://ericabookerpiano.com</a>

Dr Carol Leone from Dallas, Texas – Chair of Keyboard Studies at SMU Meadows School of the Arts in Dallas, internationally recognized performing artist, teacher, lecturer, and author. Carol is one of the world’s leading researchers and proponents of ergonomic piano keyboards to promote a pianist’s wellness:&nbsp;<a href="http://www.carolleone.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.carolleone.com</a>

Ms Rhonda Boyle from Melbourne, Australia – Former government policy analyst/strategic planner with qualifications in physics, environmental science and urban planning. Rhonda is a pianist, independent researcher and author of peer-reviewed articles relating to hand size and piano playing:
<a href="http://www.linkedin.com/pub/rhonda-boyle/30/931/352" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.linkedin.com/pub/rhonda-boyle/30/931/352</a>

<span>These three founders have no financial connections with any piano or keyboard manufacturers.</span>

The PASK network is gradually growing and now includes many others around the world who support the PASK goals and who are actively engaged in encouraging change.

If you would like to be an active member of PASK or be kept up to date on developments, please be in touch: <a href="mailto:info@paskpiano.org">info@paskpiano.org</a></p>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section data-id="d757218" data-element_type="section">
						
		</section>
				<section data-id="c8bb5bb" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="e92354b" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="759652a" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div>
					<div><p>The term ESPK (ergonomically scaled piano keyboard) is now mostly used in the academic community when referring to keyboards smaller than the current ‘standard’ size i.e., with 6.5 inch octave. The term ‘reduced-size keyboard’ has also been used in some literature. &nbsp;Also note that the DS5.5®<em>&nbsp;</em>is often referred to as the ‘7/8 keyboard’ as the key widths are close to (but not exactly) 7/8 of the ‘standard’ keyboard. Likewise, the DS6.0®<em>&nbsp;</em>is often referred to as the 15/16 keyboard. ESPK is a generic term that also includes keyboards of other sizes, i.e. that do not conform to the DS standards.&nbsp;</p><p>The ‘DS’ abbreviation stands for Donison-Steinbuhler. (Chris Donison and David Steinbuhler pioneered the introduction of piano keyboards with narrower keys for acoustic pianos, mainly in North America.) &nbsp;The PASK movement (Pianists for Alternatively Sized Keyboards) generally uses the term ‘alternative sizes’ to avoid confusion as ‘reduced size’ could imply fewer than 88 keys.</p></div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section data-id="41a669e" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="2e65a40" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="3ee7b0a" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="wp-widget-sfsi-widget.default">
				<div>
					<div data-position="widget">
			
			<div><div><p><a data-effect="" target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdiQ0iwCWFsGjZ1QI41KSBg/playlists" id="sfsiid_youtube"><img data-pin-nopin="true" alt="YouTube" title="YouTube" src="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/plugins/ultimate-social-media-icons/images/icons_theme/default/default_youtube.png" width="40" height="40" data-effect=""></a></p></div><div><p><a data-effect="" target="_blank" href="http://instagram.com/paskpianos" id="sfsiid_instagram"><img data-pin-nopin="true" alt="Instagram" title="Instagram" src="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/plugins/ultimate-social-media-icons/images/icons_theme/default/default_instagram.png" width="40" height="40" data-effect=""></a></p></div></div>			
		</div>
			</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
						</div>
						</div>
					</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://paskpiano.org/about/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25173522</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 23:28:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Best of NeXT Collection]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 58 | Comments 15 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25172693">thread link</a>) | @mpweiher
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | http://www.kevra.org/TheBestOfNext/index.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.kevra.org/TheBestOfNext/index.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="container">
    <!-- Start container -->

    <!-- End sidebar wrapper -->

    <div id="contentContainer">
      <!-- Start main content wrapper -->

      <div id="content">
        <!-- Start content -->

        <p><img alt="KeyFobHeader6" src="http://www.kevra.org/TheBestOfNext/files/page0_1.jpg" width="604" height="197">
        <br></p>

        <p><span>After Steve Jobs was forced out of Apple
        in 1985, everyone wanted to know what Steve would do
        next.... so NeXT was what he did.
        <p>
        
        In 1988 his NeXT team launched a new kind of computer for
        it's time, built on standards with a Unix core but with a
        user experience "my grandma could understand". It was well
        ahead of it's time, so naturally, it was not embraced by
        main stream consumers... a classic "Crossing the Chasm"
        issue. But many saw it for what it was, a breakthrough
        product as innovative as today's iTunes, iPod and iPhone.
        </p><p>
        
        Building upon NeXT's hardware and more importantly, their
        software development environment, many third party NeXT
        developers added their own magic dust to create
        revolutionary products, like the world's first web browser,
        or a new form of spread sheet, Lotus Improv or WebObjects,
        the foundation upon which the iTune store is built, to name
        only a few. Some of these ground breaking products may
        never be repeated. Most contained innovations embraced by
        future applications, with a clear lineage back to NeXTSTEP.
        </p><p>
        
        During the relatively short time of NeXT ascendency
        (1985-1996), Apple was bleeding red ink from repeated
        financial losses and two hugely expensive attempts to
        create a follow on Operating System. Apple's third
        president since Steve's departure, Gil Amelio saw the
        merits of Steve, his team and their technology. In December
        1996 Apple bought Next. Then the Next team took over Apple.
        The result is their hugely successful Mac OS X, built on
        the foundations of the NeXTSTEP OS.
        </p><p>
        
        While NeXT is no more, as a product or a stand alone
        company, it's impact on the industry will be felt for years
        to come. We should remember it, perhaps even study it. In
        decades to come, it will be understood as a watershed of
        innovation. Current Mac and iPhone users will be astonished
        to see how many of their beloved Mac OS X innovations had
        their roots in NeXTSTEP. There are many lessons about
        product innovation, market acceptance, and the creative
        people involved, that have yet to be uncovered.
        </p><p>
        
        This web site details part of our unique collection of NeXT
        related products and assorted items which grew up around
        NeXT Computer ecosystem, including of course NeXT hardware
        but also those rare items such as dealer sales kits, logo'd
        clothing, NeXT jewelry, banners, training tapes for
        servicing NeXT computers and printers, developer guides,
        plus third party software and hardware products.
        </p><p>
        
        While the site describes only part of the actual
        collection, the site does cover over 800 NeXT and third
        party products, many with multipage brochures and white
        papers. If you were to print all the html and PDF documents
        it would be over 3,000 pages.
        </p><p>
        
        This site describes what may well be the most extensive
        NeXT related collection available today.
        </p><p>
        
        It's history worth preserving.
        </p></span></p>

        
      </div><!-- End content -->

      <!-- End Footer -->
    </div><!-- End main content wrapper -->
  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.kevra.org/TheBestOfNext/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25172693</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 20:55:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[FTC commissioner met with Apple regarding Facebook’s iOS 14 complaints]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 108 | Comments 92 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25171707">thread link</a>) | @aeromusek
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | https://www.myhealthyapple.com/etc-apple-facebook-ios14/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.myhealthyapple.com/etc-apple-facebook-ios14/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a href="https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings.jpg" data-caption=""><img width="696" height="416" src="https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings-696x416.jpg" srcset="https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings-696x416.jpg 696w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings-300x179.jpg 300w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings-768x459.jpg 768w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings-702x420.jpg 702w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings.jpg 926w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px" alt="FTC-Apple-Facebook-iOS14" title="FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings"></a></p><p>In a<span>&nbsp;</span>letter sent to the Ranking Digital Rights organization, Apple’s Jane Horvath, senior director of global privacy, reiterated that the company believes that<strong> “privacy is a fundamental human right.”</strong></p><p>Horvath explains that Apple <span>delayed the App Tracking Transparency (ATT) feature</span> to give developers more time to prepare for the changes.</p><h2><strong>Facebook’s complaints about Apple’s App Tracking Transparency (ATT)</strong></h2><p>Facebook has criticized the App Tracking Transparency feature and said it <span>could cause ad revenue to&nbsp;drop as much as 40%</span>.</p><p>Facebook has reportedly met with advertising partners to discuss the impact the change has on advertising when users have the ability to easily opt-out of cross-platform tracking.</p><p>The company also announced the following <a href="https://www.facebook.com/business/news/preparing-our-partners-for-ios-14-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">in a press release</a> on Sept 10th.</p><blockquote><p>“We, along with the rest of the business community, continue to await final policy details from Apple.”</p><p>Given Apple’s delayed implementation of the user permission requirement, we will continue collecting IDFA on iOS 14 in an attempt to reduce unnecessary disruption to our customers’ businesses.”</p></blockquote><p>We checked in with FTC to see if they were looking into some of the claims made by FaceBook against Apple’s iOS 14.</p><figure id="attachment_1004628" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1004628"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-investigating-Facebooks-claim-against-Apple.jpg" alt="FTC looking into Facebook's complaints against Apple" width="977" height="511" srcset="https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-investigating-Facebooks-claim-against-Apple.jpg 977w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-investigating-Facebooks-claim-against-Apple-300x157.jpg 300w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-investigating-Facebooks-claim-against-Apple-768x402.jpg 768w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-investigating-Facebooks-claim-against-Apple-696x364.jpg 696w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-investigating-Facebooks-claim-against-Apple-803x420.jpg 803w" sizes="(max-width: 977px) 100vw, 977px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1004628">Email send by FTC commissioner on Aug 28th (Source: myHealthyApple.com)</figcaption></figure><p>It appears, based on the reports under our FOIA filing, that Noah Philips, FTC commissioner reached out to Kate Adams from <strong>Apple on 28th August</strong> to understand some of the details around Facebook’s complaints.</p><p>A meeting was subsequently scheduled between Apple’s team and FTC attorneys around the first week of September.</p><figure id="attachment_1004629" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1004629"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-meeting-with-Apple-about-IOS-14.jpg" alt="FTC Meeting with Apple on iOS 14" width="967" height="650" srcset="https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-meeting-with-Apple-about-IOS-14.jpg 967w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-meeting-with-Apple-about-IOS-14-300x202.jpg 300w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-meeting-with-Apple-about-IOS-14-768x516.jpg 768w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-meeting-with-Apple-about-IOS-14-696x468.jpg 696w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-meeting-with-Apple-about-IOS-14-625x420.jpg 625w" sizes="(max-width: 967px) 100vw, 967px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1004629">Source: MyHealthyApple.com</figcaption></figure><p>Given the timing of Apple’s announcement today, it is clear that the company has good cause to take this position following meetings with FTC.</p><p>According to the letter today, Apple continues to emphasize that advertising that protects user privacy is possible.</p><p>You can read today’s complete Apple’s letter posted by Chance Miller at <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2020/11/19/apple-privacy-letter-ios-14-facebook/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">9to5Mac</a>.</p><p><em>As an Amazon Associate MyHealthyApple may earn commissions from qualifying purchases using our links</em></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.myhealthyapple.com/etc-apple-facebook-ios14/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25171707</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 18:41:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Production-Oriented Development]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 169 | Comments 123 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25170547">thread link</a>) | @kiyanwang
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | https://paulosman.me/2019/12/30/production-oriented-development.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://paulosman.me/2019/12/30/production-oriented-development.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
          <p><span></span> read
          </p>
          <a name="topofpage"></a>
          <p>Throughout my career, I’ve developed some <em>opinions</em>. Some have worn particularly deep ruts,
reinforced by years of experience. I tried to figure out what these
had in common, and it’s
the idea that <strong>code in production is the only code that matters</strong>. Staging doesn’t
matter, code on your laptop doesn’t matter, QA doesn’t matter,
only production matters. Everything else is debt.</p>

<p>This perspective probably comes from years sitting in between
operations and product development. I strongly
believe that teams should optimize for getting code to production as quickly as
possible as well as responding to incidents in production.</p>

<p>This idea, and a lot of the practices it implies, can be
counter-intuitive or controversial, so I want to dive into them a little
further. What follows is a set of practices and principles I believe are true,
considering my underlying belief that code working in production is the only
code that matters.</p>

<h2 id="engineers-should-operate-their-code">1. Engineers should operate their code.</h2>

<p><strong>Engineers are the subject matter experts for the code they write and should be
responsible for operating it in production</strong>. In this context, “operating” means
deploying, instrumenting, and monitoring code as well as helping to resolve
incidents related to or impacting that code. The responsibility of operating
code aligns incentives - it encourages engineers to write code that is
observable and easy to debug, and connects them to what customers really care
about. It encourages them to be curious about how their code is performing in
production. Importantly, engineers should be on-call for their code - being
on-call creates a positive feedback loop and makes it easier to know if their
efforts in writing production-ready code are paying off. I’ve heard people
complain about the prospect of being on-call, so I’ll just ask this: if you’re
not on-call for your code, who is?</p>

<p>If you’re not currently on-call for your code but want to be, and can help
influence this decision, there are some things you can do. Set up PagerDuty (or
similar) schedules for each group of engineers responsible for specific
services or parts of your code. A good schedule has 6–8 engineers. There are
plenty of variations, but a typical template is to have one-week rotations,
where you’ll be on-call for secondary for a week and then primary for a week.
Configuring alerts is a separate topic, which probably deserves it’s own blog
post entirely, but focus on things that impact your customers (see:
Symptom-based alerting) and remember that you’re ultimately responsible for how
you respond to alerts, which means you can change them.</p>

<p>There are two talks I’d recommend watching that touch on the topic of
configuring alerts: Liz Fong-Jones talks about SLOs in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MT4jbUzEVL0">Cultivating Production Excellence</a> and Aditya Mukerjee does a great job talking about techniques for
managing alerts in <a href="https://vimeo.com/274820572">Warning: This Talk Contains Content Known to the State of California to Reduce Alert Fatigue</a>.</p>

<h2 id="buy-almost-always-beatsbuild">2. Buy Almost Always Beats&nbsp;Build</h2>

<p><strong>If you can avoid building something, you should.</strong> Code is the most expensive
way to solve a problem that isn’t addressing a core area of your business. For
most small to mid-sized companies, there are open source or better yet, hosted
solutions that solve a wide range of common problems. I mean things like git
repository hosting (Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket, etc), observability tooling
(Honeycomb, Lightstep, etc), managed databases (Amazon RDS, Confluent Kafka,
etc), alerting (PagerDuty, OpsGenie, etc) and a whole host of other commodity
technologies. This even applies to your infrastructure - if you can help
it, don’t roll your own Kubernetes clusters (side note: do you even need to use
Kubernetes?), don’t roll your own load balancers if you can use Amazon ELB or
ALBs.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Not_invented_here">NIH</a> syndrome is very real and some companies get burned badly by
this. I’ve seen teams light time and money on fire reinventing components when
better, more battle-tested alternatives exist in the market. Those same teams
almost always end up spending years contending with the resulting technical
debt. If you’re on such a team and have the will and ability to impact change,
start rolling back these decisions one by one. Migrate your databases to a
managed provider, migrate your feature flagging system to a SaaS tool (i.e.
LaunchDarkly). Keep going until the only software you maintain yourselves is
the software that delivers value to your customers. You’ll be much, much better
off for it.</p>

<h2 id="make-deployseasy">3. Make Deploys&nbsp;Easy</h2>

<p>Deploying should be a frequent and unexciting activity. <strong>Engineers should be
able to deploy with minimal manual steps and it should be easy to see if the
deploy is successful</strong> (this requires instrumenting your code for observability,
which - tada - is covered above), and it should be easy to roll back a deploy
if something doesn’t go well. Deploying frequently implies that
deploys are smaller, and smaller deploys are generally easier, faster and
safer.</p>

<p>Many teams implement periods where deploys are forbidden - these can be
referred to as code freezes, or deploy policies like “Don’t deploy on Fridays”.
Having such blackout periods can lead to a pile-up of changes, which increases
the overall risk of something going very wrong.</p>

<p>If you’re on a team that fears deploys, dedicate a percentage of your
engineering time to improvements in your deployment pipeline until the fear is
gone. On a recent team I worked with, we were able to improve deploy times from
3 hours to 30 minutes, which drastically improved the teams’ confidence in the
deploy process. A natural side effect of this was that engineers started
deploying much more frequently instead of waiting for changes to pile up enough
to warrant a “release” (which was synonymous with a deploy).</p>

<p>The book
<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Accelerate-Software-Performing-Technology-Organizations/dp/1942788339">Accelerate</a>
has been getting a lot of attention. If you haven’t read it, I’d recommend it.
The team behind it also publishes the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/devops/">State of DevOps</a>
reports, which are full of well-researched information about what various
companies in the industry are doing. It’s not a coincidence that two of the
four key metrics that the book focuses on are directly related to this (Deploy
Frequency, Change Lead Time). Shipping is <a href="https://www.heavybit.com/library/podcasts/o11ycast/ep-12-speed-of-deployment-with-rich-archbold-of-intercom/">your company’s heartbeat</a>.</p>

<h2 id="trust-the-people-closest-to-theknives">4. Trust the People Closest to the&nbsp;Knives</h2>

<p><strong>The people who work with a system are the ones who understand it best.</strong> This
applies to any part of the socio-technical systems within which we all work. In
the case of software systems, the engineers who deploy every day and are
on-call for critical services understand the level of risk they operate in. A
sad trend is that managers tend to overestimate their teams’ progress on
certain transitions - i.e. cloud-native, DevOps, etc. The higher up the
management chain, the larger this overestimation tends to be. Engineers who
deploy and get paged when things break know where the bodies are buried and
they know what needs the most work. They should, therefore, be the primary
stakeholders responsible for prioritizing technical work.</p>

<p>Another manifestation of this principle applies to platform or services teams.
If you’re responsible for building some shared component that’s used within
your organization (i.e. a messaging system, ci/cd infrastructure, shared
libraries or services) there’s an uncomfortable truth lurking for you: the
people who use your work know more about it than you do in many cases. They
understand implicitly how it serves customers and they know what contortions or
hoops they have to jump through to get it to work. Listen to them for
clues on how to improve the UX of your services and tools.</p>

<h2 id="qa-gates-make-qualityworse">5. QA Gates Make Quality&nbsp;Worse</h2>

<p>Many teams have a manual QA step that gets performed before deploys. The idea,
I guess, is to have someone run automated or manual tests to verify that a set
of changes are ready to be released. This sounds like a comforting
idea - having a human being (or team of human beings) “verify” a release before
it goes out - <strong>but it falls victim to several false assumptions and creates
some misalignments that do more harm than good.</strong></p>

<p>First of all, if there’s manual work that needs to be done before a deploy can
go out, that creates a bottleneck - if you’re making deploys easy, and
deploying small changes frequently, no QA team is going to be able to keep up
testing every deploy, and will inevitably block teams from deploying. That’s no
good. If you have manual tests, automate them and build them into your CI
pipeline (if they do deliver value).</p>

<p>Secondly, the teams doing QA often lack context and are under time pressure.
They may end up testing “effects” instead of “intents”. For example, I’ve seen
QA teams burn time testing that when something happens in a UI, something
related happens in a database. What happens when an engineer refactors that UI
component and changes the underlying data model? The functionality works, but
the test breaks. Because two teams are involved, this takes coordination and
time to fix. Similarly, I’ve seen QA teams block deploys because of failing
tests when caching was introduced at the CDN layer - a TTL of 5 seconds on an
activity feed may not ever be noticed by a user but it might break QA tests
causing unnecessary conflicts between product and QA engineers.</p>

<p>Luckily, solving this one is easy. Instead of having a dedicated QA team work
on creating manual and automated test cases that run in a fictitious QA
environment, reassign that team to work on continuous testing in production.
Instead of being a gate for deploys, a QA team could continuously verify that
production is working as expected. QA teams are also well situated to lead
Chaos Engineering initiatives, where faults are intentionally injected in
production. QA engineers could also work on making the CI/CD pipeline more
reliable, so that deploys are no longer a nightmare.</p>

<h2 id="boring-technology-isgreat">6. Boring Technology is&nbsp;Great.</h2>

<p>With thanks to <a href="https://mcfunley.com/choose-boring-technology">Dan McKinley</a>,
always <strong>strive for boring tech when possible</strong>. Systems are inherently
unpredictable, and you want a wide …</p></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://paulosman.me/2019/12/30/production-oriented-development.html">https://paulosman.me/2019/12/30/production-oriented-development.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://paulosman.me/2019/12/30/production-oriented-development.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25170547</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 16:25:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Winding down my Debian involvement (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 175 | Comments 186 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25170312">thread link</a>) | @ecliptik
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | https://michael.stapelberg.ch/posts/2019-03-10-debian-winding-down/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://michael.stapelberg.ch/posts/2019-03-10-debian-winding-down/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">
  
  <details>
    <summary>Table of contents</summary>
    <nav>
<ul>
<li>
<ul>
<li><a href="#what-does-this-mean">What does this mean?</a></li>
<li><a href="#why">Why?</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#change-process-in-debian">Change process in Debian</a></li>
<li><a href="#fragmented-workflow-and-infrastructure">Fragmented workflow and infrastructure</a></li>
<li><a href="#old-infrastructure-package-uploads">Old infrastructure: package uploads</a></li>
<li><a href="#old-infrastructure-bug-tracker">Old infrastructure: bug tracker</a></li>
<li><a href="#old-infrastructure-mailing-list-archives">Old infrastructure: mailing list archives</a></li>
<li><a href="#debian-is-hard-to-machine-read">Debian is hard to machine-read</a></li>
<li><a href="#complicated-build-stack">Complicated build stack</a></li>
<li><a href="#developer-experience-pretty-painful">Developer experience pretty painful</a></li>
<li><a href="#i-have-more-ideas">I have more ideas</a></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
</nav>
  </details>
  

<p>This post is hard to write, both in the emotional sense but also in the “I would
have written a shorter letter, but I didn’t have the time” sense. Hence, please
assume the best of intentions when reading it—it is not my intention to make
anyone feel bad about their contributions, but rather to provide some insight
into why my frustration level ultimately exceeded the threshold.</p>

<p>Debian has been in my life for well over 10 years at this point.</p>

<p>A few weeks ago, I have visited some old friends at the Zürich Debian meetup
after a multi-year period of absence. On my bike ride home, it occurred to me
that the topics of our discussions had remarkable overlap with my last visit. We
had a discussion about the merits of systemd, which took a detour to respect in
open source communities, returned to processes in Debian and eventually
culminated in democracies and their theoretical/practical failings. Admittedly,
that last one might be a Swiss thing.</p>

<p>I say this not to knock on the Debian meetup, but because it prompted me to
reflect on what feelings Debian is invoking lately and whether it’s still a good
fit for me.</p>

<p>So I’m finally making a decision that I should have made a long time ago: I am
winding down my involvement in Debian to a minimum.</p>

<h2 id="what-does-this-mean">What does this mean?</h2>

<p>Over the coming weeks, I will:</p>

<ul>
<li>transition packages to be team-maintained where it makes sense</li>
<li>remove myself from the <code>Uploaders</code> field on packages with other maintainers</li>
<li>orphan packages where I am the sole maintainer</li>
</ul>

<p>I will try to keep up best-effort maintenance of the
<a href="https://manpages.debian.org/">manpages.debian.org</a> service and the
<a href="https://codesearch.debian.net/">codesearch.debian.net</a> service, but any help
would be much appreciated.</p>

<p>For all intents and purposes, please treat me as permanently on vacation. I will
try to be around for administrative issues (e.g. permission transfers) and
questions addressed directly to me, permitted they are easy enough to answer.</p>

<h2 id="why">Why?</h2>

<p>When I joined Debian, I was still studying, i.e. I had luxurious amounts of
spare time. Now, over 5 years of full time work later, my day job taught me a
lot, both about what works in large software engineering projects and how I
personally like my computer systems. I am very conscious of how I spend the
little spare time that I have these days.</p>

<p>The following sections each deal with what I consider a major pain point, in no
particular order. Some of them influence each other—for example, if changes
worked better, we could have a chance at transitioning packages to be more
easily machine readable.</p>

<h3 id="change-process-in-debian">Change process in Debian</h3>

<p>The last few years, my current team at work conducted various smaller and larger
refactorings across the entire code base (touching thousands of projects), so we
have learnt a lot of valuable lessons about how to effectively do these
changes. It irks me that Debian works almost the opposite way in every regard. I
appreciate that every organization is different, but I think a lot of my points
do actually apply to Debian.</p>

<p>In Debian, packages are nudged in the right direction by a document called the
<a href="https://www.debian.org/doc/debian-policy/">Debian Policy</a>, or its programmatic
embodiment, lintian.</p>

<p>While it is great to have a lint tool (for quick, local/offline feedback), it is
even better to not require a lint tool at all. The team conducting the change
(e.g. the C++ team introduces a new hardening flag for all packages) should be
able to do their work transparent to me.</p>

<p>Instead, currently, all packages become lint-unclean, all maintainers need to
read up on what the new thing is, how it might break, whether/how it affects
them, manually run some tests, and finally decide to opt in. This causes a lot
of overhead and manually executed mechanical changes across packages.</p>

<p>Notably, the <strong>cost of each change</strong> is distributed onto the package maintainers in
the Debian model. At work, we have found that the opposite works better: if the
team behind the change is put in power to do the change for as many users as
possible, they can be significantly more efficient at it, which reduces the
total cost and time a lot. Of course, exceptions (e.g. a large project abusing a
language feature) should still be taken care of by the respective owners, but
the important bit is that the default should be the other way around.</p>

<p>Debian is <strong>lacking tooling for large changes</strong>: it is hard to programmatically
deal with packages and repositories (see the section below). The closest to
“sending out a change for review” is to open a bug report with an attached
patch. I thought the workflow for accepting a change from a bug report was too
complicated and started <a href="https://michael.stapelberg.ch/posts/2016-07-17-mergebot/">mergebot</a>, but only Guido
ever signaled interest in the project.</p>

<p>Culturally, reviews and reactions are slow. There are no deadlines. I literally
sometimes get emails notifying me that a patch I sent out a few years ago (!!)
is now merged. This turns projects from a small number of weeks into many years,
which is a huge demotivator for me.</p>

<p>Interestingly enough, you can see artifacts of the slow online activity manifest
itself in the offline culture as well: I don’t want to be discussing systemd’s
merits 10 years after I first heard about it.</p>

<p>Lastly, changes can easily be slowed down significantly by holdouts who refuse
to collaborate. My canonical example for this is rsync, whose maintainer refused
my patches to make the package use debhelper purely out of personal preference.</p>

<p>Granting so much personal freedom to individual maintainers prevents us as a
project from raising the abstraction level for building Debian packages, which
in turn makes tooling harder.</p>

<p>How would things look like in a better world?</p>

<ol>
<li>As a project, we should strive towards more unification. Uniformity still
does not rule out experimentation, it just changes the trade-off from easier
experimentation and harder automation to harder experimentation and easier
automation.</li>
<li>Our culture needs to shift from “this package is my domain, how dare you
touch it” to a shared sense of ownership, where anyone in the project can
easily contribute (reviewed) changes without necessarily even involving
individual maintainers.</li>
</ol>

<p>To learn more about how successful large changes can look like, I recommend <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TrC6ROeV4GI">my
colleague Hyrum Wright’s talk “Large-Scale Changes at Google: Lessons Learned
From 5 Yrs of Mass Migrations”</a>.</p>

<h3 id="fragmented-workflow-and-infrastructure">Fragmented workflow and infrastructure</h3>

<p>Debian generally seems to prefer decentralized approaches over centralized
ones. For example, individual packages are maintained in separate repositories
(as opposed to in one repository), each repository can use any SCM (git and svn
are common ones) or no SCM at all, and each repository can be hosted on a
different site. Of course, what you do in such a repository also varies subtly
from team to team, and even within teams.</p>

<p>In practice, non-standard hosting options are used rarely enough to not justify
their cost, but frequently enough to be a huge pain when trying to automate
changes to packages. Instead of using GitLab’s API to create a merge request,
you have to design an entirely different, more complex system, which deals with
intermittently (or permanently!) unreachable repositories and abstracts away
differences in patch delivery (bug reports, merge requests, pull requests,
email, …).</p>

<p>Wildly diverging workflows is not just a temporary problem either. I
participated in long discussions about different git workflows during DebConf
13, and gather that there were similar discussions in the meantime.</p>

<p>Personally, I cannot keep enough details of the different workflows in my
head. Every time I touch a package that works differently than mine, it
frustrates me immensely to re-learn aspects of my day-to-day.</p>

<p>After noticing workflow fragmentation in the Go packaging team (which I
started), I tried fixing this with the <a href="https://go-team.pages.debian.net/workflow-changes.html">workflow changes
proposal</a>, but did not
succeed in implementing it. The lack of effective automation and slow pace of
changes in the surrounding tooling despite my willingness to contribute time and
energy killed any motivation I had.</p>

<h3 id="old-infrastructure-package-uploads">Old infrastructure: package uploads</h3>

<p>When you want to make a package available in Debian, you upload GPG-signed files
via anonymous FTP. There are several batch jobs (the queue daemon, <code>unchecked</code>,
<code>dinstall</code>, possibly others) which run on fixed schedules (e.g. <code>dinstall</code> runs
at 01:52 UTC, 07:52 UTC, 13:52 UTC and 19:52 UTC).</p>

<p>Depending on timing, I estimated that you might wait for over 7 hours (!!)
before your package is actually installable.</p>

<p>What’s worse for me is that feedback to your upload is asynchronous. I like to
do one thing, be done with it, move to the next thing. The current setup
requires a many-minute wait and costly task switch for no good technical
reason. You might think a few minutes aren’t a big deal, but when all the time I
can spend on Debian per day is measured in minutes, this makes a huge difference
in perceived productivity and fun.</p>

<p>The last communication I can find about speeding up this process is <a href="https://lists.debian.org/debian-project/2008/12/msg00014.html">ganneff’s
post</a> from 2008.</p>

<p>How would things look like in a better world?</p>

<ol>
<li>Anonymous FTP would be replaced by a web service which ingests my package and
returns an authoritative accept or reject decision in its response.</li>
<li>For accepted packages, there would be a status page displaying the build
status and when the package will be available via the mirror network.</li>
<li>Packages should be available within a few minutes after the build completed.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="old-infrastructure-bug-tracker">Old infrastructure: bug tracker</h3>

<p>I dread interacting with the Debian bug
tracker. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Debbugs">debbugs</a> is a piece of software
(from 1994) which is only used by Debian and the GNU project these days.</p>

<p>Debbugs processes emails, which is to say it is asynchronous and cumbersome to
deal with. Despite running on the fastest machines we …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://michael.stapelberg.ch/posts/2019-03-10-debian-winding-down/">https://michael.stapelberg.ch/posts/2019-03-10-debian-winding-down/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://michael.stapelberg.ch/posts/2019-03-10-debian-winding-down/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25170312</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 15:53:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Interpretation of confidence intervals and Bayesian credible intervals]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 56 | Comments 32 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25169595">thread link</a>) | @jwb133
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | https://thestatsgeek.com/2020/11/21/interpretation-of-frequentist-confidence-intervals-and-bayesian-credible-intervals/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thestatsgeek.com/2020/11/21/interpretation-of-frequentist-confidence-intervals-and-bayesian-credible-intervals/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
<p>This post was prompted by a tweet by Frank Harrell yesterday asking:</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>In this post I'll say a little bit about trying to answer Frank's question, and then a little bit about an alternative question which I posed in response, namely, how does the interpretation change if the interval is a Bayesian credible interval, rather than a frequentist confidence interval.</p>



<h2>Frequentist confidence intervals</h2>



<p>A frequentist 95% confidence interval is constructed such that if the model assumptions are correct, if you were to (hypothetically) repeat the experiment or sampling many many times, 95% of the intervals constructed would contain the true value of the parameter. I made a short video last year which performs a simulation in R to demonstrate this definition/idea:</p>



<figure><p><span><iframe width="1125" height="633" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IGXg6L98lJM?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;fs=1&amp;autohide=2&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true"></iframe></span>
</p></figure>



<p>Frank asked how one interprets a particular realised confidence interval (0.72,0.91). The difficulty (as he is well aware!) is that all a frequentist can say is that this particular realised interval either does or does not contain the true parameter value, and they cannot tell you if it does or doesn't. All they can say is that if modelling assumptions are correct, in hypothetical repetitions 95% of the intervals constructed using this procedure contain the true value.</p>



<h2>Bayesian credible intervals</h2>



<p>Let’s now suppose that we’ve done a Bayesian analysis. We’ve specified a prior distribution for the parameter, based on prior evidence, our subjective beliefs about the value of the parameter, or perhaps we used a default ‘non-informative’ prior built into our software package. We use the same model as before, and Bayes theorem gives us the posterior distribution. A Bayesian posterior credible interval is constructed, and suppose it gives us some values. For the sake of simplicity, I’ll assume the interval is again 0.72 to 0.91, but this is not done to suggest a Bayesian analysis credible interval will generally be identical to the frequentist's confidence interval.</p>



<p>How should we interpret this credible interval? A Bayesian would I think say say something like it is an interval for which there is a 95% chance or probability the true parameter lies. At this point we must ask, what do they mean by 95% probability?</p>



<p>We could interpret it as a classical long run frequentist probability, but this means interpreting it like a confidence interval. In fact Bayesian procedures often have good frequentist properties. For example see <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://cdn1.sph.harvard.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/343/2013/03/large-sample.pdf" target="_blank">Wang and Robins 1998</a> for an analysis of the frequentist properties of multiple imputation for missing data, or <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://doi.org/10.1177%2F0962280216667764" target="_blank">Bartlett and Keogh 2018</a> for a simulation investigation of the frequentist properties of Bayesian approaches for handling covariate measurement error. In fact, under certain conditions, Bayesian procedures achieve the same frequentist properties of maximum likelihood methods when the sample size gets large - see Chapter 4 of Gelman <em>et al</em>'s excellent<a href="http://www.stat.columbia.edu/~gelman/book/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Bayesian Data Analysis book</a>.</p>



<p>But conceptually we do not choose to do a Bayesian analysis simply as a means to performing frequentist inference. We choose it because it (hopefully) answers more directly what we are interested in (see Frank Harrell's '<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.fharrell.com/post/journey/" target="_blank">My Journey From Frequentist to Bayesian Statistics</a>' post). Namely, it enables us to make probability statements about the unknown parameter given our model, the prior, and the data we have observed. So what is the interpretation of the 95% chance or probability for a credible interval? </p>



<p>I don't know the no doubt large literature on this topic well at all, but the Bayesian's interpretation or definition of probability isn't that clear to me. The Wikipedia entry on <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bayesian_probability" target="_blank">Bayesian probability</a> says:</p>



<blockquote><p>Broadly speaking, there are two interpretations of Bayesian probability. For objectivists, who interpret probability as an extension of logic, probability quantifies the reasonable expectation that everyone (even a "robot") who shares the same knowledge should share in accordance with the rules of Bayesian statistics, which can be justified by Cox's theorem.[2][8] For subjectivists, probability corresponds to a personal belief.[3] Rationality and coherence allow for substantial variation within the constraints they pose; the constraints are justified by the Dutch book argument or by decision theory and de Finetti's theorem.[3] The objective and subjective variants of Bayesian probability differ mainly in their interpretation and construction of the prior probability.</p><cite>Wikipedia entry on Bayesian probability</cite></blockquote>



<p>Section 1.5 'Probability as a measure of uncertainty' of <a href="http://www.stat.columbia.edu/~gelman/book/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bayesian Data Analysis</a> talks about the way Bayesian analysis uses probability as a measure of uncertainty, but to my mind it doesn't really define the concept. This is not a criticism. As Gelman et al say earlier in their book:</p>



<blockquote><p>Rather than argue the foundations of statistics—see the bibliographic note at the end of this chapter for references to foundational debates—we prefer to concentrate on the pragmatic advantages of the Bayesian framework, whose flexibility and generality allow it to cope with complex problems.</p></blockquote>



<p>If part of the appeal of Bayesian inference is that it answers the question we really want (i.e. conditional on what we've seen, what do we know / believe about the parameter(s)), it seems to me that the interpretation or definition of prior/posterior probabilities should be relatively straightforward and clear to us. But for me at least, it isn't. I am quite confident (whatever I mean by that!) that this reflects my ignorance on the topic. Part of my motivation for writing this post is the hope that people will help me understand better how to unambiguously define what is meant by a Bayesian prior/posterior probability. Please write a comment if you can help in this regard.</p>



<p>The above does not mean I don't like Bayesian methods. Indeed much of the last 10 years I have been working with and using methods like multiple imputation for missing data whose development take place in the Bayesian paradigm. For me this is fine because I know that methods like multiple imputation have good frequentist properties, and while there are definitely interpretational issues with things confidence intervals, I at least think I understand what they claim to do/be.</p>



<h2>22nd November 2022 postscript</h2>



<p>This evening there was further discussion of this topic on Twitter. As part of this Frank Harrell offered an interpretation for the Bayesian credible interval as follows:</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Under data model F and prior P, [0.72, 0.91] is the shortest interval such that the probability the unknown OR generating our data is in that interval is 0.95 (highest posterior density interval).</p>— Frank Harrell (@f2harrell) <a href="https://twitter.com/f2harrell/status/1330633833713111040?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 22, 2020</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>I followed up with him as to the nature of the probability being referred to here, since it is clear that the probability notion being invoked is broader or distinct than the relative frequency notion of probability. Frank helpfully pointed me in the direction of the entry for 'probability' in his course glossary of terms, which can be <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://hbiostat.org/doc/glossary.pdf" target="_blank">accessed here</a>. Part of this entry says:</p>



<blockquote><p>The&nbsp;meaning&nbsp;attached to the metric known as a probability is up to the user; it can represent long-run relative frequency of repeatable observations, a degree of belief, or a measure of veracity or plausibility.</p><cite>https://hbiostat.org/doc/glossary.pdf</cite></blockquote>



<p>and</p>



<blockquote><p>There are other schools of probability that do not require the notion of replication at all. For example, the school of&nbsp;subjective&nbsp;probability (associated with the&nbsp;Bayesian&nbsp;school) “considers probability as a measure of the degree of belief of a given subject in the occurrence of an event or, more generally, in the veracity of a given assertion” (see P. 55 of5). de Finetti defined subjective probability in terms of wagers and odds in betting. A risk-neutral individual would be willing to wager $P&nbsp;that an event will occur when the payoff is $1 and her subjective probability is&nbsp;P&nbsp;for the event.</p><cite>https://hbiostat.org/doc/glossary.pdf</cite></blockquote>



<p>As I wrote in the original post, I do not know the extensive literature on this topic well at all. But what Frank has summarised here is really useful in aiding my understanding of what the interpretation should be of the 95% probability statement attached to a 95% credible interval. It seems to me the notion of probability being invoked when interpreting a 95% credible interval has to be the subjective probability / degree of belief one described in the previous quote. Whether this definition/interpretation meets the criterion of being 'exact', as required by Frank in his tweet at the top of this post when asking for the exact interpretation of a particular realised frequentist confidence interval, I leave readers to decide.</p>
		</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thestatsgeek.com/2020/11/21/interpretation-of-frequentist-confidence-intervals-and-bayesian-credible-intervals/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25169595</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 13:21:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I Miss Working from the Office]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 553 | Comments 456 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25168589">thread link</a>) | @sysoleg
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | https://www.roguelazer.com/2020/11/i-miss-working-from-the-office/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.roguelazer.com/2020/11/i-miss-working-from-the-office/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    
    <section id="main-content" role="main">
	<article>
		


		<div><p>I went into my office yesterday for the first time in a few months to pick some stuff up. We got notified
a couple of days ago to get any personal property out of the office before Thanksgiving or else it'd be
thrown out, so I guess we're moving out of the office<sup id="fnref:moving-out"><a href="#fn:moving-out">1</a></sup>. It was a pretty eerie place to be; even now, 8
months later, most people haven't been back and it kind of looks like the entire office was abducted by aliens in
early March.</p>

<p>Despite how weird it is, I still miss working out of the office.</p>
<!-- more -->

<p>I miss having a clean delineation between "work" and "home".</p>
<p>I miss having copious desk space and a big monitor<sup id="fnref:house"><a href="#fn:house">2</a></sup>.</p>
<p>I miss the 48" TVs on the wall showing Grafana dashboards with key metrics so there was always ambient knowledge of
what was going on with the product.</p>
<p>I miss having meetings in conference rooms where you can see other people and have a giant whiteboard to sketch on.</p>
<p>I miss casual collaboration. Video chat is a poor substitute and Slack is a deeply irritating tool that combines the
worst aspects of synchronous and asynchronous communication.</p>
<p>I miss productivity! Our engineering productivity has fallen through the floor since COVID despite everyone
working longer and harder; I fundamentally do not think remote teams can <em>ever</em> be as productive as in-person teams.</p>
<p>I miss having my employer pay for electricity and heat and fast symmetric multi-gigabit Internet access instead of
shifting those costs to me.</p>
<p>I miss having a plethora of convenient and delicious options for take-out lunch! I miss the gyros and french fries
at <a href="https://www.ayolagreek.com/">Ayola</a>. I miss the chicken pesto sandwich at <a href="https://working-girls-cafe.square.site/">Working Girls'
Cafe</a>. I miss the chow mein and pork buns from <a href="https://yanksing.com/">Yank Sing</a>. I
miss the katsu curry from <a href="http://www.muraccis.com/">Muracci's</a>. I miss the curry burritos from <a href="https://www.curryupnow.com/">Curry Up
Now</a>. I miss the croque monsieur from <a href="https://cafemadeleinesf.com/">Cafe Madeline</a>. I
miss the $5 lunch specials from <a href="http://www.mehfilindian.com/">Mehfil</a>.</p>
<p>I miss the succession of friendly baristas at our <a href="https://www.yelp.com/biz/hermanos-coffee-juice-san-francisco">favorite coffee shop</a> who always knew our orders and put up with our banter.</p>
<p>I miss occasional after-work drinks at the <a href="https://sf.eater.com/2019/4/25/18516128/skydeck-spirits-in-the-sky-rooftop-bar-san-francisco">sky bar</a> with the $18 well drinks that we always convinced management to pay for.</p>
<p>Hell, I miss <a href="https://www.bart.gov/">BART</a> in all its loud and smelly glory.</p>
<p>Look, I know, it's not all bad. It's a lot easier taking care of a baby while working from home than it would be if
I were commuting 45 minutes each way every day. I'm spending a lot less money on food and coffee and BART. And I'm
not arguing that we should be in the office now; not a single one of those things I listed above is worth the health
risk of jamming 150 people<sup id="fnref:deniers"><a href="#fn:deniers">3</a></sup> into an open-plan office with a quasi-functional ventilation
system<sup id="fnref:ventilation"><a href="#fn:ventilation">4</a></sup>. But I
really hope that office-work isn't a permanent victim of this pandemic, that all the companies pushing for
permanent WFH to save a few bucks on rent reconsider their stances, and that there comes a time when I can go back to
work again.</p>
</div>
<hr>
<h2>Comments</h2>


	</article>
    </section>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.roguelazer.com/2020/11/i-miss-working-from-the-office/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25168589</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 08:58:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Mvp.css – build your landing page with only semantic HTML]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 301 | Comments 77 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25167928">thread link</a>) | @rahimnathwani
<br/>
November 20, 2020 | https://andybrewer.github.io/mvp/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://andybrewer.github.io/mvp/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <hr>
        <section>
            <header>
                <h2>Simple, reusable components</h2>
                <p>For a clean looking design that doesn't get in the way</p>
            </header>
            
            
            
        </section>
        <hr>
        <section id="testimonials">
            <blockquote>
                <img alt="Quote" src="https://andybrewer.github.io/mvp/img/icon-quote.svg" height="80"><br>
                "By far the easiest stylesheet I've ever used. It integrates easily into <s>one</s> all of my
                startup&nbsp;projects."
                
            </blockquote>
        </section>
        <hr>
        <section id="features">
            <header>
                <h2>Flexibility without complexity</h2>
                <p>A few, clean styling options without all the bells and whistles</p>
            </header>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr>
                        <th></th>
                        <th>MVP.css</th>
                        <th>No CSS</th>
                        <th>Custom CSS</th>
                    </tr>
                </thead>
                <tbody><tr>
                    <td>Mobile friendly</td>
                    <td><b>✓</b></td>
                    <td>✓</td>
                    <td>✓</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Works out of the box</td>
                    <td><b>✓</b></td>
                    <td>✓</td>
                    <td>∅</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Easy to customize</td>
                    <td><b>✓</b></td>
                    <td>✓</td>
                    <td>∅</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Only semantic HTML</td>
                    <td><b>✓</b></td>
                    <td>✓</td>
                    <td>∅</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>No class names</td>
                    <td><b>✓</b></td>
                    <td>✓</td>
                    <td>∅</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Perfect for an MVP</td>
                    <td><b>✓</b></td>
                    <td>∅</td>
                    <td>∅</td>
                </tr>
            </tbody></table>
        </section>
        <hr>
        <div id="figure">
            <header>
                <h2>A decent MVP in no time</h2>
                <p>More building and less designing with "set and forget" styling.</p>
            </header>
            <figure>
                <img alt="Stock photo" src="https://andybrewer.github.io/mvp/img/stock.jpg">
                <figcaption><i>"Uber for X" brainstorming session</i></figcaption>
            </figure>
        </div>
        <hr>
        <article id="docs">
            <h2>Docs</h2>
            <h3 id="html">HTML Reference</h3>
            
            <p>MVP.css works with the following HTML elements:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><code>&lt;a&gt;</code> <small>— text links</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;a&gt;&lt;b&gt;</code>, <code>&lt;a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;</code> <small>— solid
                                link buttons</small>
                        </li>
                        <li><code>&lt;a&gt;&lt;em&gt;</code>, <code>&lt;a&gt;&lt;i&gt;</code> <small>— outlined
                                link buttons</small>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;article&gt;</code> <small>— content area with normal styling</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;article&gt;&lt;aside&gt;</code> <small>— text callout</small>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;blockquote&gt;</code> <small>— quote callout</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;footer&gt;</code> <small>— quote attribution</small>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;body&gt;</code> <small>— default parent element</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;button&gt;</code> <small>— form buttons</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;code&gt;</code> <small>— inline code highlighting</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;details&gt;</code> <small>— default expandable content section</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;</code> <small>— expandable heading</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;div&gt;</code> <small>— unstyled element</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;figure&gt;</code> <small>— image callouts</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;</code> <small>— image callout captions</small>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;footer&gt;</code> <small>— footer area</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;form&gt;</code> <small>— small form area</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;form&gt;&lt;input&gt;</code> <small>— short input field</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;form&gt;&lt;label&gt;</code> <small>— form field labels</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;form&gt;&lt;select&gt;</code> <small>— dropdown options container</small>
                            <ul>
                                <li><code>&lt;form&gt;&lt;select&gt;&lt;option&gt;</code> <small>— dropdown option
                                        items</small></li>
                            </ul>
                        </li>
                        <li><code>&lt;form&gt;&lt;textarea&gt;</code> <small>— large input field</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;header&gt;</code> <small>— content area with centered styling</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;h1&gt;</code>, <code>&lt;h2&gt;</code>, <code>&lt;h3&gt;</code>, <code>&lt;h4&gt;</code>,
                    <code>&lt;h5&gt;</code>, <code>&lt;h6&gt;</code> <small>— headings</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;hr&gt;</code> <small>— horizontal rule (divider)</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;main&gt;</code> <small>— main content area</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;mark&gt;</code> <small>— text highlighting</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;nav&gt;</code> <small>— top navigation</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;nav&gt;&lt;ul&gt;</code> <small>— nav links container</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;nav&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;</code> <small>— nav link items</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;nav&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;ul&gt;</code> <small>— nav dropdown
                                container</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;nav&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;</code> <small>— nav dropdown
                                link items</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;ol&gt;</code> <small>— numbered list container</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;</code> <small>— numbered list items</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;p&gt;</code> <small>— paragraph tag</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;pre&gt;</code> <small>— preformatted text</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;</code> <small>— code block</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;samp&gt;</code> <small>— computer output block</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;samp&gt;</code> <small>— inline computer output</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;section&gt;</code> <small>— content area for centered / special content</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;section&gt;&lt;aside&gt;</code> <small>— content card</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;small&gt;</code> <small>— smaller text</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;sup&gt;</code> <small>— raised text (notification bubbles)</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;table&gt;</code> <small>— data table</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;table&gt;&lt;td&gt;</code> <small>— data table cell</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;table&gt;&lt;th&gt;</code> <small>— data table header cell</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;</code> <small>— data table header section</small>
                        </li>
                        <li><code>&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;</code> <small>— data table row</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;ul&gt;</code> <small>— unordered list container</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;</code> <small>— unordered list item</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <br>
            <h3 id="variables">Modifying the CSS variables</h3>
            <p>MVP.css includes a list of CSS variables. Editing these variables will change the styles globally.</p>
            <pre>                <code>
:root {
    --border-radius: 5px;
    --box-shadow: 2px 2px 10px;
    --color: #118bee;
    --color-accent: #118bee0b;
    --color-bg: #fff;
    --color-bg-secondary: #e9e9e9;
    --color-secondary: #920de9;
    --color-secondary-accent: #920de90b;
    --color-shadow: #f4f4f4;
    --color-text: #000;
    --color-text-secondary: #999;
    --font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, "Segoe UI", Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, "Helvetica Neue", sans-serif;
    --hover-brightness: 1.2;
    --justify-important: center;
    --justify-normal: left;
    --line-height: 150%;
    --width-card: 285px;
    --width-card-medium: 460px;
    --width-card-wide: 800px;
    --width-content: 1080px;
}
                </code>
            </pre>

            <p>Custom styles can be added below the <code>/* Custom styles */</code> comment at the end of the file.</p>
        </article>
        <hr>
        <article id="faq">
            <h2>Frequently Asked Questions</h2>
            <details>
                <summary>Why would I use this?</summary>
                <p>If you just want to launch already.</p>
                <p><sup>PRO TIP</sup> An MVP is a temporary site, it doesn't have to be <i>and shouldn't be</i> perfect.
                </p>
            </details>
            <details>
                <summary>What skills will I need?</summary>
                <p>Mostly HTML, maybe a hint of CSS if you want to get fancy.</p>
                <p><i>CSS</i>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <progress max="100" value="5">5</progress></p>
                <p><i>Design</i>&nbsp;&nbsp; <progress max="100" value="0">0</progress></p>
                <p><i>HTML</i>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <progress max="100" value="100">100</progress></p>
            </details>
            <details>
                <summary>Is there a minified version?</summary>
                <p>No, you don't need one for an MVP.</p>
            </details>
            <details>
                <summary>How can I improve my design?</summary>
                <p>Here are some helpful resources:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Emojis - <a href="https://www.emojicopy.com/" target="_blank">Emojicopy
                            ↗</a></li>
                    <li>Icons - <a href="https://www.toptal.com/designers/htmlarrows/" target="_blank">HTML Entities
                            List by TopTal
                            ↗</a></li>
                    <li>Icons - <a href="https://thenounproject.com/" target="_blank">TheNounProject
                            ↗</a></li>
                    <li>Illustrations - <a href="https://gallery.manypixels.co/" target="_blank">Manypixels
                            ↗</a></li>
                    <li>Illustrations - <a href="https://undraw.co/illustrations" target="_blank">Undraw ↗</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>Logo - <a href="https://www.namecheap.com/logo-maker/app/" target="_blank">Namecheap Logo
                            Maker ↗</a></li>
                    <li>Product Shots - <a href="https://www.screely.com/" target="_blank">Screely ↗</a></li>
                    <li>Stock Photos - <a href="https://www.pexels.com/" target="_blank">Pexels ↗</a></li>
                    <li>Stock Photos - <a href="https://unsplash.com/" target="_blank">Unsplash ↗</a></li>
                </ul>
            </details>
            <details>
                <summary>What if I don't like the default styles?</summary>
                <p>Most styles are editable through <em>CSS variables</em>. You can also add your own styles
                    inline, at the end of MVP.css or in a new stylesheet.</p>
                <p><sup>PRO TIP</sup> If there are two conflicting CSS styles, the last one will take precedence.</p>
                <pre>                    <code>
:root {
    --color: #118bee;
}

/* Lower in the CSS, or in a 2nd stylesheet */

:root {
    --color: green; /* This will take precedence */
}
                    </code>
                </pre>
            </details>
            <details>
                <summary>What if I still don't like it?</summary>
                <p>That's OK, you probably shouldn't love your MVP. The goal of MVP.css is to help you
                    feel <i>slightly</i> less embarrased about it.</p>
                <p><span>👉</span> If you
                    want a CSS framework with more features check out <a href="https://bulma.io/" target="_blank">Bulma
                        ↗</a> or <a href="https://tailwindcss.com/" target="_blank">Tailwind ↗</a>.</p>
            </details>
        </article>
        <hr>
        <section id="ideas">
            <header>
                <img alt="Idea" src="https://andybrewer.github.io/mvp/img/idea.svg" height="200">
                <h2>What can you build with MVP.css?</h2>
                <p>Free ideas below ↓</p>
            </header>
            
        </section>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://andybrewer.github.io/mvp/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25167928</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 04:49:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Jupystar – Run any Jupyter notebook in the browser]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 75 | Comments 15 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25167906">thread link</a>) | @protoduction
<br/>
November 20, 2020 | https://starboard.gg/jupystar | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://starboard.gg/jupystar">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://starboard.gg/jupystar</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25167906</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 04:40:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
