<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 10]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 10. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 08:34:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-10.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 08:34:15 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Migrate Everything from Linux to BSD]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 104 | Comments 128 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26060307">thread link</a>) | @zdw
<br/>
February 7, 2021 | https://www.unixsheikh.com/articles/why-you-should-migrate-everything-from-linux-to-bsd.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.unixsheikh.com/articles/why-you-should-migrate-everything-from-linux-to-bsd.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>

<p>Published on <span id="pubdate">2020-01-18</span>. Modified on <span id="moddate">2021-02-10</span>.</p>
<p>As an operating system GNU/Linux has become a mess because of the fragmented nature of the project, the bloatware in the kernel, but mainly because of the manipulation by corporate interests. There exist <a href="https://unixsheikh.com/articles/technical-reasons-to-choose-freebsd-over-linux.html">several technical reasons</a> for when a migration from GNU/Linux to BSD make sense, but this article isn't about that, it's an "analyzes" of the current status in Linux-land, and it is an opinionated rant, more than anything else.</p>
<h3>Table of Contents</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="#introduction">Introduction</a></li>
<li><a href="#fragmented">Linux is fragmented</a></li>
<li><a href="#hijacked">Linux is being heavily influenced by corporate interests</a></li>
<li><a href="#bsd">BSD is the place to be</a></li>
<li><a href="#license">License problems</a></li>
<li><a href="#migrate">Time to migrate everything to BSD</a></li>
<li><a href="#links">Relevant links</a></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>In the past I have always been a favorite of choosing operating system and tools based upon technical merit. However, in today's world of companies like Microsoft, Apple, Google, and many others, compromising user privacy, and conducting controversial activities, I don't believe that to be the right cause of action.</p>
<p>Proprietary operating systems like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windows_10#Privacy_and_data_collection">Microsoft Windows 10</a>, <a href="https://gist.github.com/iosecure/357e724811fe04167332ef54e736670d">Apple MacOS</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Android_%28operating_system%29#Security_and_privacy">Google Android</a> have become famous for their ill conduct, and even companies like Lenovo is using UEFI boot to inject custom Windows components, so that the system can phone home to Lenovo.</p>
<p>I have been a proponent for the open source alternatives, like GNU/Linux and BSD, for a very long time. Not only that, I also believe that the open source alternatives are much better in many technical areas.</p>
<p>I have also always been very much against <a href="https://www.unixsheikh.com/articles/the-typical-discussions-about-bsd-vs-linux.html">The typical discussions about BSD vs Linux</a>, and as I wrote in my article back then, I have always believed that the different open source projects can help each other and cooperate, and that end-users should only debate such issues from a technical stand point rather than personal preference.</p>
<p>Whenever it has been possible, I have proposed people, both private and in the industry, to change the operating systems they use to open source alternatives, and when people have been receptive to my advocacy I have helped them migrate from Microsoft Windows on their workstations to BSD or Linux. And likewise on the server side. This has been a truly successful endeavor and I have honestly never experienced a dissatisfied person or company.</p>
<p>However, things are beginning to change in the GNU/Linux world as more and more corporations want to control the direction of Linux as an operating system. Due to the structure and organization of GNU/Linux as an operating system, it is unfortunately susceptible to these influences, and while it is still open source, and still not anywhere near the bad things that is going on with the proprietary alternatives, some opt-out features have slowly been introduced into both the kernel and systemd.</p>
<p>You can still choose to opt-out of these features and go your merry way, but as an open source enthusiast and proponent, and as a privacy concerned individual, perhaps the better approach is to migrate systems to something where you don't have to concern yourself with "creepware".</p>
<p>As a system administrator I don't want to worry about whether I am going to be surprised the next time I upgrade a system, and I don't want to keep a list of spyware I have to remember to opt-out of whenever I run one of these systems.</p>
<p>Several Linux distributions have decided (not only because of privacy opt-out issues, but other issues as well) to implement <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Category:Linux_distributions_without_systemd">other init solutions than systemd</a>, but with the situation going on in the kernel development, and with many third party applications becoming more and dependent upon systemd, the problems are spreading to other parts of the operating system and I believe this is becoming an uphill battle.</p>
<p>From a community perspective, and from a security perspective, I don't believe the future of GNU/Linux looks very bright, and as a possible alternative solution I suggest migrating everything (when possible) to something a bit more sane, like one of the BSD projects.</p>

<h2 id="fragmented">Linux is fragmented</h2>
<p>In 1983 Richard Stallman announced his intent to start coding the GNU Project in a Usenet message. By June 1987, the project had accumulated and developed free and open source software for an assembler, an almost finished portable optimizing C compiler (GCC), an editor (GNU Emacs), and various Unix utilities, such as ls, grep, awk, make and ld.</p>
<p>In 1991, the Linux kernel appeared, developed outside the GNU project by Linus Torvalds, and in December 1992 it was made available under version 2 of the GNU General Public License. Combined with the operating system utilities already developed by the GNU project, it became the GNU/Linux operating system, better known as just "Linux".</p>
<p>Then came the Linux distributions. Different projects took the Linux kernel, the GNU tools and libraries, additional third party software, documentation, the X Window System, a window manager, and a desktop environment, and combined those components into the distributions. Different distributions focused on different goals, some put focus on the desktop while others put their main focus on servers, and again others tried to provide a multi-purpose operating system.</p>
<p>In the past all these different components and projects where developed by open source enthusiasts and communities and the passion for programming and open source was the driving force.</p>
<p>This is no longer the case! Please see <a href="https://unixsheikh.com/articles/the-real-motivation-behind-systemd.html">The real motivation behind systemd</a>.</p>
<p>Linus Torvalds has many times made it very clear that he doesn't care about what goes on in the "Linux world", all he cares about is the kernel development, and on January 6, 2020 in the "Moderated Discussions" forum at <a href="https://www.realworldtech.com/forum/?threadid=189711&amp;curpostid=189841">realworldtech.com</a>, Linus Torvalds answered a user's question, with an absolute jaw-dropping comment, about a year-old kernel maintenance controversy that heavily impacted the <a href="https://zfsonlinux.org/">ZFS on Linux</a> project.</p>
<p>After answering the user's actual question, Torvalds went on to make very wrong and damaging claims about the ZFS filesystem. Torvalds said:</p>
<blockquote>
It (ZFS) was always more of a buzzword than anything else.
</blockquote>
<p>By that statements Linus Torvalds has just reduced more that 15 years of development of one of the most robust and popular filesystems in the world into a "buzzword"!</p>
<p>ZFS is described as "The last word in filesystems". It is a combined filesystem and logical volume manager originally designed by Sun Microsystems. ZFS is a stable, fast, secure, and future-proof filesystem. It is scalable, and includes extensive protection against data corruption, support for high storage capacities, a maximum 16 Exabyte file size, and a maximum 256 Quadrillion Zettabytes storage with no limit on number of filesystems (datasets) or files, efficient data compression, snapshots and copy-on-write clones, continuous integrity checking and automatic repair, RAID-Z, native NFSv4 ACLs, and can be very precisely configured.</p>
<p>The two main implementations, by Oracle and by the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OpenZFS">OpenZFS</a> project, are extremely similar, making ZFS widely available within Unix-like systems.</p>
<p>As mentioned in the Wikipedia article, OpenZFS is an umbrella project aimed at bringing together individuals and companies that use the ZFS file system and work on its improvements, aiming as well at making ZFS more widely used and developed in an open-source manner. OpenZFS brings together developers from the illumos, Linux, FreeBSD, and macOS platforms, and a wide range of companies. High-level goals of the project include raising awareness of the quality, utility and availability of open-source implementations of ZFS, encouraging open communication about ongoing efforts toward improving open-source variants of ZFS, and ensuring consistent reliability, functionality and performance of all distributions of ZFS.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/zfsonlinux/zfs/commits/master">OpenZFS on Linux</a>, which is the Linux part of the project, has currently 345 active contributors with more that 5.600 commits, and commits are being made on an almost daily basis!</p>
<p>Some of the worlds biggest CDN and data storage services runs ZFS on either FreeBSD or Linux!</p>
<p>In another situation Linus Torvalds gave an interview on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mysM-V5h9z8">TFiR: open source and Emerging Tech YouTube channel</a> about Linux on the desktop in which he makes another amazing statement saying that Linux still isn't ready for the desktop and that perhaps <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chrome_OS">Chrome OS</a> is the solution to that problem.</p>
<p>These and many other statements by Linus Torvalds show that Linux as an operating system has no real direction and no clear management because the kernel development is performed in isolation from the rest of the Linux world.</p>
<p>Linus Torvalds is generally also very open to the rapid influence by corporate interests and his perspective on security is also worrying.</p>
<p>In 2009 Linus Torvalds admitted that the kernel development is getting out of control.</p>
<blockquote>
We're getting bloated and huge. Yes, it's a problem ... Uh, I'd love to say we have a plan ... I mean, sometimes it's a bit sad that we are definitely not the streamlined, small, hyper-efficient kernel that I envisioned 15 years ago ... The kernel is huge and bloated, and our icache footprint is scary. I mean, there is no question about that. And whenever we add a new feature, it only gets worse.
</blockquote>
<p>At LinuxCon 2014, he said that he thinks the bloat situation is better because modern PCs are a lot faster!</p>
<blockquote>
We've been bloating the kernel over the last 20 years, but hardware has grown faster.
</blockquote>
<p>This is a very problematic attitude.</p>
<p>When software gets bloated it not only becomes more insecure and more error prone, but it also becomes much slower. Thinking that the problem goes away because hardware becomes faster is an immature attitude. In this day and age we need to optimize software so that less power is required, we need to save power and limit pollution.</p>
<p>In a 2007 interview "Why I quit": kernel developer Con Kolivas he stated:</p>
<blockquote>
If there is any one big problem with kernel development and Linux it is the complete disconnection of the development process from normal users. You know, the ones who constitute 99.9% of the Linux user base. The Linux kernel mailing list is the …</blockquote></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.unixsheikh.com/articles/why-you-should-migrate-everything-from-linux-to-bsd.html">https://www.unixsheikh.com/articles/why-you-should-migrate-everything-from-linux-to-bsd.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.unixsheikh.com/articles/why-you-should-migrate-everything-from-linux-to-bsd.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26060307</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 03:02:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Change your MAC address with a shell script]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 123 | Comments 63 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26060152">thread link</a>) | @mooreds
<br/>
February 7, 2021 | https://josh.works/shell-script-basics-change-mac-address | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://josh.works/shell-script-basics-change-mac-address">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
  

  <time datetime="2019-12-18T13:00:00+00:00">December 2019</time>
  <section>
    
    <!-- https://planetjekyll.github.io/snippets/reading-time -->
<p>
  
  
    Reading time: 8 mins
  
</p>

  </section>
  
  
  <h2>Article Table of Contents</h2>
<ul>
  <li><a href="#get-your-current-mac-address">Get your current MAC address</a></li>
  <li><a href="#figure-out-which-adapter-your-machine-is-using-to-connect-to-the-wifi">Figure out which adapter your machine is using to connect to the wifi</a></li>
  <li><a href="#generate-a-random-new-mac-address">Generate a random new MAC address</a></li>
  <li><a href="#set-current-mac-address-to-temporarynew-mac-address">Set current mac address to temporary/new MAC address</a></li>
  <li><a href="#feb-9-2021-update">Feb 9, 2021 update</a></li>
  <li><a href="#related-reading">Related Reading</a></li>
</ul>
  <p>For a while, I’ve had notes from <a href="https://www.online-tech-tips.com/computer-tips/how-to-change-mac-address/">Change or Spoof a MAC Address in Windows or OS X</a> saved, so if I am using a wifi connection that limits me to thirty minutes or an hour, I can “spoof” a new MAC address, and when I re-connect to the wifi, the Access Point thinks I’m on a new, unique device.</p>

<p>For the record - when I’m posted up at a coffee shop for an extended period of time, I make sure to <em>buy products regularly</em> in payment for my time. So, if you’re spoofing your MAC address to use wifi for a longer period of time, maybe make sure to spend $5 or $10 when you run the script.</p>

<p>Now, in case you think that I’m actually saving myself time here, I’m totally not. Here’s why:</p>

<p><img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/automation.png" alt="XKCD Automation" title="'Automating' comes from the roots 'auto-' meaning 'self-', and 'mating', meaning 'screwing'."></p>

<p><em><a href="https://xkcd.com/1319/">XKCD: Automation</a></em></p>

<p>And:</p>

<p><img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/is_it_worth_the_time.png" alt="XKCD Is it worth the time?" title="Don't forget the time you spend finding the chart to look up what you save. And the time spent reading this reminder about the time spent. And the time trying to figure out if either of those actually make sense. Remember, every second counts toward your life total, including these right now."></p>

<p><em><a href="https://xkcd.com/1205/">XKCD: Is it worth the time?</a></em></p>

<p>Here’s the steps, for someone who’s on a MAC, to spoof your MAC address:</p>
      <h3 id="get-your-current-mac-address">
        
        
          Get your current MAC address <a href="#get-your-current-mac-address">#</a>
        
        
      </h3>
    

<p>Hold down <code>option</code> key, click your wifi icon:</p>

<p><img src="https://josh.works/images/2019-12-11-bash-basics-01.jpg" alt="wifi details"></p>
      <h3 id="figure-out-which-adapter-your-machine-is-using-to-connect-to-the-wifi">
        
        
          Figure out which adapter your machine is using to connect to the wifi <a href="#figure-out-which-adapter-your-machine-is-using-to-connect-to-the-wifi">#</a>
        
        
      </h3>
    

<div><div><pre><code>ifconfig en0 | <span>grep </span>ether <span># one of these will return a MAC address that matches</span>
ifconfig en1 | <span>grep </span>ether <span># the value you saw when looking for your current</span>
ifconfig en2 | <span>grep </span>ether <span># mac address.</span>
ifconfig en3 | <span>grep </span>ether <span># Keep incrementing the `en0` value until you run out of </span>
                          <span># devices</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Here’s me working through the list:</p>

<p><img src="https://josh.works/images/2019-12-11-basic-bash-02.jpg" alt="checking all ports"></p>

<p>For me, the very first result matched the MAC address I got from <code>option+click</code>ing the wifi network.</p>

<p>That means I’ll be using <code>en0</code> as the [E]ther[N]et adapter I’ll update shortly.</p>

<!--more-->
      <h3 id="generate-a-random-new-mac-address">
        
        
          Generate a random new MAC address <a href="#generate-a-random-new-mac-address">#</a>
        
        
      </h3>
    

<p>A MAC address has a standard-looking format.</p>

<p>It looks like six blocks of two digits, which happen to be <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hexadecimal">hexadecimal representations</a> of <code>00000000</code> through <code>11111111</code>.</p>

<p>Here’s some randomly-generated MAC addresses:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>e2:81:f6:f6:f9:e8
1f:24:37:47:d6:25
03:20:3f:48:46:ad
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>To generate a random string of characters that produces a <a href="http://sqa.fyicenter.com/1000208_MAC_Address_Validator.html">valid MAC address</a>, run:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>openssl rand -hex 6 | sed 's/\(..\)/\1:/g; s/.$//'
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And boom. You’ve got a MAC address.</p>

<p>Now we need to update our current MAC address to this new MAC address.</p>
      <h3 id="set-current-mac-address-to-temporarynew-mac-address">
        
        
          Set current mac address to temporary/new MAC address <a href="#set-current-mac-address-to-temporarynew-mac-address">#</a>
        
        
      </h3>
    

<p>You can use <code>ifconfig</code> to set the ethernet address (is that interchangable with the MAC address?) to the randomly-generated string you got from the <code>openssl</code> command:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span># you need to sudo it, unfortunately. No quotes around the mac address</span>
<span>sudo </span>ifconfig en0 ether xx:xx:xx:xx:xx:xx

<span># here's the full command</span>
<span>sudo </span>ifconfig en0 ether 8c:85:90:5a:79:56
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And with that, you can re-connect to the wifi network, and it <em>should</em> recognize you as a new device, and let you onto the network.</p>

<p>Here’s what I first ended up with:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>#!/bin/bash</span>

<span>echo</span> <span>"Hi! lets change our mac address."</span>
<span>echo</span> <span>"Step 1: hold down option key, click wifi logo. Note the mac address"</span>
<span>echo</span> <span>"Step 2: click 'disconnect from network' "</span>
<span>echo</span> <span>"Step 3: note which ethernet adapter lines up with the mac address you just saw"</span>

<span>en0</span><span>=</span><span>$(</span> ifconfig en0 | <span>grep </span>ether <span>)</span>
<span>en1</span><span>=</span><span>$(</span> ifconfig en1 | <span>grep </span>ether <span>)</span>
<span>en2</span><span>=</span><span>$(</span> ifconfig en2 | <span>grep </span>ether <span>)</span>
<span>en3</span><span>=</span><span>$(</span> ifconfig en3 | <span>grep </span>ether <span>)</span>
<span>en4</span><span>=</span><span>$(</span> ifconfig en4 | <span>grep </span>ether <span>)</span>
<span>en5</span><span>=</span><span>$(</span> ifconfig en5 | <span>grep </span>ether <span>)</span>

<span>echo </span>en0 is: <span>$en0</span>
<span>echo </span>en1 is: <span>$en1</span>
<span>echo </span>en2 is: <span>$en2</span>
<span>echo </span>en3 is: <span>$en3</span>
<span>echo </span>en4 is: <span>$en4</span>
<span>echo </span>en5 is: <span>$en5</span>

<span>read</span> <span>-p</span> <span>'Step 4: Enter which ethernet device lined up with the given mac address: '</span> ether_adapter
<span>export </span><span>ether_adapter</span><span>=</span><span>$ether_adapter</span>

<span>mac</span><span>=</span><span>$(</span> openssl rand <span>-hex</span> 6 | <span>sed</span> <span>"s/</span><span>\(</span><span>..</span><span>\)</span><span>/</span><span>\1</span><span>:/g; s/.</span><span>$/</span><span>/"</span> <span>)</span>
<span>export </span><span>mac</span><span>=</span><span>$mac</span>

<span>echo</span> <span>"btw, here's the new mac address we're going to use: </span><span>$mac</span><span>"</span>
<span>echo</span> <span>"OK, we will change the mac address associated with: </span><span>$ether_adapter</span><span>"</span>

<span>old_mac</span><span>=</span><span>$(</span> ifconfig <span>$ether_adapter</span> | <span>grep </span>ether <span>)</span>

<span>echo</span> <span>"The old value was: </span><span>$old_mac</span><span>"</span>

<span>sudo </span>ifconfig <span>$ether_adapter</span> ether <span>$mac</span>

<span>new_mac</span><span>=</span><span>$(</span> ifconfig <span>$ether_adapter</span> | <span>grep </span>ether <span>)</span>

<span>echo</span> <span>"The new value is: </span><span>$new_mac</span><span>"</span>
<span>echo</span> <span>"go ahead and re-connect to the wifi. You should be able to join the network."</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Believe it or not, this script was far from perfect.</p>

<p>First off, not all randomly-generated mac addresses are valid, even though they were passing an online mac address validator I was testing against. <a href="https://askubuntu.com/a/536221">AskUbuntu</a> nicely shared what was going on.</p>

<p>I didn’t want to deal with manually building a valid MAC address; I just noticed that about 2 out of 3 attempts to change my mac address, using the above script, the MAC address didn’t change.</p>

<p>So, my next version of this script pulls the <code>generate mac address</code> and <code>set current mac address to generated mac address</code> steps into a function, and keeps calling the function until the mac address has changed.</p>

<p>Why be elegant and precise when you can brute force a crappy solution?</p>

<p>Here’s my finished “solution”:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>#!/bin/bash</span>
<span># skipping some lines</span>
<span>read</span> <span>-p</span> <span>'Step 4: Which device lined up would you like to change? (hit return for en0) '</span> ether_adapter

<span>if</span> <span>[</span> <span>-z</span> <span>$ether_adapter</span> <span>]</span>
<span>then
  </span><span>ether_adapter</span><span>=</span><span>"en0"</span>
<span>fi

</span><span>export </span><span>ether_adapter</span><span>=</span><span>$ether_adapter</span>

generate_and_set_new_mac_address<span>()</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>mac</span><span>=</span><span>$(</span> openssl rand <span>-hex</span> 6 | <span>sed</span> <span>"s/</span><span>\(</span><span>..</span><span>\)</span><span>/</span><span>\1</span><span>:/g; s/./0/2; s/.</span><span>$/</span><span>/"</span><span>)</span>
  <span>export </span><span>mac</span><span>=</span><span>$mac</span>
  <span>echo</span> <span>"OK, we will change the mac address associated with: </span><span>$ether_adapter</span><span>"</span>

  <span>old_mac</span><span>=</span><span>$(</span> ifconfig <span>$ether_adapter</span> | <span>grep </span>ether <span>)</span>

  <span>echo</span> <span>"The old value was: </span><span>$old_mac</span><span>"</span>
  <span>sudo </span>ifconfig <span>$ether_adapter</span> ether <span>$mac</span>

  <span>new_mac</span><span>=</span><span>$(</span> ifconfig <span>$ether_adapter</span> | <span>grep </span>ether <span>)</span>
  <span>echo</span> <span>"The new value is: </span><span>$new_mac</span><span>"</span>
<span>}</span>
<span>echo</span> <span>$new_mac</span>
<span>echo</span> <span>$old_mac</span>

<span>while</span> <span>[</span> <span>"</span><span>$new_mac</span><span>"</span> <span>==</span> <span>"</span><span>$old_mac</span><span>"</span> <span>]</span>
<span>do
  </span><span>echo</span> <span>"not the same"</span>
  generate_and_set_new_mac_address
<span>done

</span><span>echo</span> <span>"go ahead and re-connect to the wifi. You should be able to join the network."</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>and this seems to work pretty well:</p>

<p><img src="https://josh.works/images/2019-12-17-bash_script_success.jpg" alt="success"></p>

<p>I hope that in the near future, I’ll look at this bash script and have many ways to improve it. For now, it’ll do the trick.</p>
      <h3 id="feb-9-2021-update">
        
        
          Feb 9, 2021 update <a href="#feb-9-2021-update">#</a>
        
        
      </h3>
    

<p>Following <a href="https://twitter.com/serent/status/1359208380435361792">this tweet</a> by <code>@serent</code>, I updated the script a little. To generate a valid MAC address:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>@@ -160,7 +162,7 @@</span> fi
 export ether_adapter=$ether_adapter

 generate_and_set_new_mac_address() {
<span>-  mac=$( openssl rand -hex 6 | sed "s/\(..\)/\1:/g; s/.$//" )
</span><span>+  mac=$( openssl rand -hex 6 | sed "s/\(..\)/\1:/g; s/./0/2; s/.$//")
</span>   export mac=$mac
   echo "OK, we will change the mac address associated with: $ether_adapter"
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>There’s other pain points in the script. I’ll fix them at some point.</p>
      
    

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26060152#26060229">Hacker News comments from 2021 on this post</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://ryanstutorials.net/bash-scripting-tutorial/bash-script.php">Bash Scripting Tutorial</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.online-tech-tips.com/computer-tips/how-to-change-mac-address/">Change or Spoof a MAC Address in Windows or OS X</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/13781216/meaning-of-too-many-arguments-error-from-if-square-brackets">Resolution to <code>[: too many arguments</code> error</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://askubuntu.com/questions/423530/cant-change-my-mac-address-cant-assign-requested-address/536221">AskUbuntu: “Can’t change my mac address - can’t assign requested address”</a></li>
</ul>
  

</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://josh.works/shell-script-basics-change-mac-address</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26060152</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 02:28:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I'm an interviewer at my company and burnt out]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 51 | Comments 70 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26060099">thread link</a>) | @mooreds
<br/>
February 7, 2021 | https://dear.mariechatfield.com/interviewer-burn-out | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dear.mariechatfield.com/interviewer-burn-out">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><blockquote>
<p>Dear Marie,</p>
<p>I am one of a handful of women engineers at my company and I have been interviewing 1-2 candidates per week for the past several months. Since I started interviewing, we have only hired white or Asian men.</p>
<p>Bringing in underrepresented identities to my workplace is important to me, and leadership at my company constantly says they value ‘Diversity and Inclusion’. I’ve offered ideas on how to attract a wider group of candidates, but I don’t feel like I am heard or taken seriously. I’m exhausted being part of the interview team with the results we have. At this point, I only want to interview underrepresented candidates, but that seems inappropriate to ask for.</p>
<p>Am I complicit in a racist, sexist system? How can I push for change and preserve my energy?</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- question -->

<p>Hey there,</p>
<p>Interviewing one or two candidates per week for months sounds absolutely exhausting. It’s no wonder that you’re tired and burnt out—especially if it seems like your company isn’t actually hiring anyone outside their established pattern, despite their avowed dedication to diversity and inclusion.</p>
<p><strong>I have found conducting interviews to be difficult and energy-consuming work, particularly if you are invested in treating candidates equitably and with empathy.</strong> It’s not just that the hour-long calendar block in the middle of the day, it’s also:</p>
<ul>
<li>preparing for the interview ahead of time, making sure you have all the resources you need and your environment is set up.</li>
<li>being deeply focused during the interview, paying attention to the smallest of interactions to discern signals (of varying reliability) about a person’s areas of technical expertise and approach to work and collaboration.</li>
<li>responding to candidates on the fly, figuring out the right balance of giving them a hint when they’re stuck and seeing how they solve a problem themselves, and ensuring they have an excellent experience with your company.</li>
<li>writing up feedback afterwards and deliberating your evaluation and whether you’ve let unconscious bias influence you and if your feedback is well-calibrated with the rest of the hiring group so that you’re not consistently scoring everyone higher or lower than the average.</li>
<li>participating in decisions and conversations around interviewing as a whole, and how to make it more equitable and inclusive.</li>
</ul>
<p>It sounds like you aren’t hiring specifically for roles on your immediate team, but rather part of a group of interviewers who support hiring across the whole company. This structure makes sense for larger organizations who have a steady stream of open roles. If everyone helps out a little bit all the time, then no one team’s productivity is completely sunk when they need to hire.</p>
<p>The downside, of course, is that the hiring never really stops. <strong>You don’t get to celebrate by welcoming your new teammate; you just keep interviewing. And interviewing. And interviewing.</strong></p>
<p>At one company, I completed over 100 technical interviews in about two years. I had prided myself on being a very good interviewer, in part because of all the practice. By the end, I was completely miserable and I hated everything about it. I couldn’t convince myself to care about candidates anymore and I was having trouble focusing and giving them my full attention. So, I stopped interviewing. And it was <em>such</em> a relief. It wasn’t even necessarily the time back that I cared about; it was <strong>letting go of the immense responsibility of contributing to hiring decisions, but with so little authority to change anything.</strong></p>
<p>Consider a few of these options, and what each one feels like:</p>
<ul>
<li>What if you reduced your availability to one interview a week?</li>
<li>What if you reduced your availability to two interviews a month?</li>
<li>What if you stopped interviewing for a month?</li>
<li>What if you stopped interviewing for a quarter?</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Did you feel a sense of relief or joy when you imagined those? Which ones feels the most like what you need right now?</strong></p>
<p>You say that you’ve offered ideas about how to improve your hiring practices and that you <em>“don’t feel like I am heard or taken seriously.”</em> I am guessing that you are not a manager, or any other person who makes the final call on hiring decisions. If you were, my advice would be very different<sup id="fnref-1"><a href="#fn-1">1</a></sup>.</p>
<p>But if I’m right, your main job responsibility is probably to write, release, and maintain software—<em>not</em> to build a team or manage their collective effectiveness. A manager <em>must</em> hire at some point if they want to ensure their team has the right balance of expertise and experience. You probably help out managers at your company by giving them quality feedback about the people they are considering hiring; but it’s unlikely that your annual evaluation centers on your participation in the hiring process or the hiring outcomes at your company.</p>
<p>So… take a break. Don’t stop entirely or forever; you are doing the important work of advocating for inclusion and equity, I would hate for you to give that up entirely. But it sounds like what you’re doing now isn’t working the way you had hoped, and you’re too tired to imagine a bigger and bolder approach right now.</p>
<p><strong>I have quipped that my main career goal is to do such outstanding work that I can be a complete and total pain in the ass about the things that truly matter, like accessibility and inclusion and equity.</strong> That doesn’t mean that I’m waiting until I’ve “arrived” to advocate for what I know is right and to put my privilege to use. It means that I don’t waste my battles on inconsequential things and I try to make myself valuable enough that I’m harder to push out when I do dig in my heels.</p>
<p>But in order to spend social capital, you have to build it up first—and for you, that might mean giving up interviewing for a bit, focusing on your main job responsibility and building relationships with your coworkers, then coming back with a fresh perspective, renewed energy, and a group of like-minded peers with a common goal of improving the hiring process.</p>
<p>Assuming that you don’t have the authority to make a hire/no-hire decision or to revamp your recruiting process, you’re a bit limited in what you can do on your own. <strong>But there is strength in numbers, and it’s harder to ignore a group.</strong> See if you can find or organize a few people who <em>also</em> care about diversity and inclusion in recruiting and hiring. It doesn’t have to be anything formal<sup id="fnref-2"><a href="#fn-2">2</a></sup>, it can just be three people who all +1 each other’s ideas and bring up the same important questions again and again.</p>
<p><strong>You also asked: <em>“Am I complicit in a racist, sexist system?”</em> I’m not sure that I can answer that one for you.</strong> You know your situation much better than I do; if that’s a concern that keeps coming up for you, sit with it. It may be that there’s something you need to do that you haven’t yet.</p>
<p>I think you would definitely be complicit if you stopped raising concerns about inclusion entirely; if you ignored or minimized the concerns raised by other marginalized people because it makes you feel uncomfortable about your own choices or privilege; or if you had the authority to make a change for the better and you didn’t use it.</p>
<p><strong>If you do come to the conclusion that you have not been living up to your values and have instead prioritized your comfort or advancement over the equity of all—welcome to the club.</strong> We mess up a lot, and we learn with empathy and gratitude for the people who corrected us. That’s another benefit to finding some peers who can advocate alongside you—you’ll each have areas of insight the others won’t and you can teach each other.</p>
<p>I hope that you’re able to take a break from interviewing. I hope that when you’re ready to resume, it’s because you’re genuinely excited to have some influence over hiring at your company and you feel equipped to push for practices that you know are worthwhile<sup id="fnref-3"><a href="#fn-3">3</a></sup>. I hope you find support from other engineers who care about inclusion. I hope your company figures out a way to stop using whatever metrics they love that so consistently undervalue Black and Indigenous people, Hispanic/Latinx people, women and people with other minoritized genders, disabled people, LGTBQ+ people, and those who span more than one of those communities.</p>
<p>In short: I hope you get good rest, and that rest fuels you for another round. There is much work to be done. Let’s do it together. 💖</p>
<p>With so much warmth,<br>
Marie</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dear.mariechatfield.com/interviewer-burn-out</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26060099</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 02:16:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Do Offer a Free Plan]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 85 | Comments 9 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26060038">thread link</a>) | @chrisfrantz
<br/>
February 7, 2021 | https://www.chrisfrantz.com/how-to-kill-a-unicorn/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.chrisfrantz.com/how-to-kill-a-unicorn/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-179"><div><p>I took a deep dive on freemium pricing and decided to document it in this post. Why freemium? I think it's how the little guys can win against market leaders.</p><p>Basically, it's how you kill a unicorn.</p><p>Notion, Figma, Canva, Mailchimp, and Segment. What do all of these platforms have in common, besides being category leaders? Each one has unseated the previous category leaders with less money and smaller teams. Each has also opted for a product led growth strategy that is fueled by product virality and an innovative pricing strategy.</p><p>But let's back up. How did we get here?</p><p>The year is 2012 and the preeminent name in design isn't Sketch or Figma - it's Adobe. 2012 era Adobe is a much different beast to where we are now. There was no real SaaS model and licenses were hundreds of dollars each, locked to a machine, and didn't get upgrades. Still, Adobe is unequivocally the category leader. But in just a few years, that would all change due to an enterprising young entrepreneur and her new business model.</p><p>Canva launched in 2012 and spread like wildfire. In 3 years, the company was able to accumulate accumulated 10 million users, with almost 1 million coming in the first year alone. By the next year, they had 17 thousand videos about their product.</p><p>This kind of fervent user adoption is the stuff of legend. I started hearing about Canva around that time. My then-girlfriend (now wife) had put together a project and it looked much better than anything I could knock out in Photoshop or Illustrator. She mentioned it was not only really easy to use, but it was free! At the time I think I was still bouncing from Adobe license to Adobe license, each of which was half a month's rent, so I was blown away.</p><p>Then I started seeing it everywhere. It was being used for school projects, large advertising campaigns, and was the first recommendation in online groups whenever someone needed a design tool.</p><p>That space used to be occupied by Adobe, but in a matter of a few years, they were being overtaken in the B2C and even a bit in the B2B space by a brand new company with a limited amount of funding.</p><figure><img width="1024" height="570" src="https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled1-1024x570.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled1-1024x570.png 1024w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled1-300x167.png 300w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled1-768x427.png 768w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled1.png 1215w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7" data-src="https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled1-1024x570.png" data-srcset="https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled1-1024x570.png 1024w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled1-300x167.png 300w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled1-768x427.png 768w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled1.png 1215w"></figure><figure><img width="1024" height="572" src="https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled2-1024x572.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled2-1024x572.png 1024w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled2-300x167.png 300w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled2-768x429.png 768w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled2.png 1227w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7" data-src="https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled2-1024x572.png" data-srcset="https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled2-1024x572.png 1024w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled2-300x167.png 300w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled2-768x429.png 768w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled2.png 1227w"></figure><p>Meanwhile, another company, Sketch, was eating away at their market share by offering design-focused tools for modern internet companies. Adobe had Photoshop and Illustrator, neither of which was purpose-built for the internet and both of which were expensive af. Adobe XD wasn't quite production-ready at that point, so Sketch was able to make inroads by offering a lower-priced license for its software.</p><p>Out of left-field comes the Canva of professional design tools: Figma.</p><figure><img width="1024" height="565" src="https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled3-1024x565.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled3-1024x565.png 1024w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled3-300x165.png 300w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled3-768x423.png 768w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled3.png 1255w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7" data-src="https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled3-1024x565.png" data-srcset="https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled3-1024x565.png 1024w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled3-300x165.png 300w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled3-768x423.png 768w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled3.png 1255w"></figure><p>Figma quickly overtakes Sketch by offering a few unique features and an unbeatable pricing model. Freemium, with a twist.</p><p>Figma, like Canva before it, quickly discovered the power that a free product with shareable outputs offers. Users create content with the tool, share the content and then inevitably get asked how it was made. Of course, the user is both happy to share and give a positive recommendation since the output content is being appreciated, and the platform gains another user.</p><p>A couple points to understand about the shiny world of marketing:</p><ul><li>Recommendations from trusted people always lead to higher conversion rates. It's easy to recommend free things since the only exchange is time.</li><li>Backlinks are everything, still. Google hasn't cracked how to build page authority without backlinks and having them everywhere, attached with positive recommendations and high user dwell time once a user clicks a link, is seen as a positive signal.</li><li>Creating content in the app means content can be shared outside the app. That's a simple growth mechanism that can be leveraged mightily once a certain user volume has been hit.</li><li>Finally, email is the best marketing channel still. Freemium platforms exchange email addresses for access and make lead generation a snap.</li></ul><p>So Adobe now is taking fire from all sides and they eventually pivot to a cloud-based subscription model while also focusing all their efforts upmarket on the professional landscape, effectively ceding their B2C audience to Canva.</p><p><em>Quick note: There are many other factors that go into making a platform successful, from the founder to tech to the support. Pricing is just one of the pieces.</em></p><h2><strong>How Freemium really works</strong></h2><p>The common misconception with freemium is that it’s an easy way to not generate any revenue. How many stories have you heard about independent projects that have been worked on for years, only to launch with only a few dollars in revenue, followed by months of slogging before eventually shutting down. That’s very likely&nbsp;<em>not</em>&nbsp;a pricing problem, but a positioning problem. You need to position your product in front of the right audiences and the price becomes a natural fit for your expansion strategy.</p><p>In reality, there are a number of different ingredients in the recipe you need to nail before you can actually execute a freemium strategy effectively. You don’t need a team of hundreds of people, but it does help to lay out the strategy ahead of time.</p><p>Let's break out the different factors involved in setting up a freemium plan.</p><ul><li>Pricing that scales with usage</li><li>Shareable content</li><li>In-app upsells</li><li>Massive market opportunity</li><li>Pricing innovation on the primary value</li></ul><p>First, if you are missing even one of these, it might not be the pricing strategy for you. Each part is key in building out a converting freemium funnel.</p><p><strong>Pricing that scales with usage</strong></p><p>If a user wants to dip a toe in and play around with your platform, they can do that at zero cost (outside of an email address). That’s the basic premise of a freemium plan, but what happens when a user is converted and wants to expand their usage?</p><p>Your pricing should accommodate that natural urge and your product should gracefully allow them to expand their usage with as few barriers as possible.</p><p><strong>In-app upsells aka feature gating</strong></p><p>You need to rope off some of your app so there’s a reason to pay! However, you should charge based on either&nbsp;<strong>secondary user value or</strong>&nbsp;expanding the primary user value, but ideally both.</p><p>Let me explain. Google Analytics made analytics free and accessible to everyone. They charge based on primary user value, but only if you want to expand to a much higher tier of usage. For 99% of people, it will always be free.</p><p>That’s great, but really they only offer expanding their primary user value (analytics) as an upsell. Profitwell, one of my favorite companies utilizing this technique, charges entirely on secondary user value. They offer Profitwell Retain, a dunning service, on top of their analytics. Analytics are totally free. After all, you already have all your financial information integrated into it and onboarded your team.</p><p>Canva however offers all that and more. They let users expand their primary usage through additional templates, but also access other tools like scheduling posts on social media once you upgrade. Why pay 12K a year for Hootsuite when you can just upgrade Canva?</p><figure><img width="1024" height="673" src="https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled4-1024x673.jpg" alt="" srcset="https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled4-1024x673.jpg 1024w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled4-300x197.jpg 300w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled4-768x505.jpg 768w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled4-1536x1009.jpg 1536w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled4-2048x1346.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7" data-src="https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled4-1024x673.jpg" data-srcset="https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled4-1024x673.jpg 1024w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled4-300x197.jpg 300w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled4-768x505.jpg 768w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled4-1536x1009.jpg 1536w, https://www.chrisfrantz.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Untitled4-2048x1346.jpg 2048w"></figure><p>With each of these product incentives, users are motioned into the next stage of the tool.</p><p><strong>Shareable content</strong></p><p>This could be considered a growth loop, since we’re building in some type of publishing into the platform so users can share links. Our goal with shareable content is to increase the k factor of a user, effectively turning a free user into a marketing machine. Every time they create content in the app and share it externally, you have another potential opportunity for user acquisition which helps balance out the slightly lower conversion rate you’ll see with a freemium plan.</p><p>You can do this with reports, tables, images, videos, etc. If it can be shared inside a team, you should enable it to be published from your platform.</p><p><strong>Massive Market Opportunity</strong></p><p>Freemium works best when you can boil the ocean. No really, let it rip. The ocean should be a massive existing user base or the early signs of a large user base. You will need the volume to make it work with freemium pricing. Here are the TAMs for a few of the examples.</p><ul><li>Canva: Anyone that needs to create images.</li><li>Profitwell: Anyone that wants to know their businesses metrics</li><li>Google Optimize: Anyone that wants to test anything on their site.</li><li>Microsoft Teams: Anyone that uses Slack. 😉</li></ul><p>Each of these audience segments is huge and represents uniquely large opportunities. Freemium pricing becomes much more difficult to pull off once you have to compete for a small audience with specific needs. You want to create a product that will work with 90% of users.</p><p><strong>Pricing Innovation on Primary Value</strong></p><p>What does this mean?</p><p>A competitive advantage that can’t be innovated against. This is the most important point. How does Slack compete with Teams when users have Teams included in their subscription? How does Baremetrics compete with Profitwell when most of what Baremetrics offered is free with Profitwell?</p><p>Well...they don’t. Baremetrics sold. Slack sold. You can’t compete against freemium when you’re able to offer the primary value for free. The existing market leaders can’t match your pricing without giving up millions in recurring revenue and they’re not going to do that.</p><p>That’s how you beat Adobe or fill-in-the-blank industry behemoth.</p><p>Create a great competitor (the hardest part), offer the primary value for free, then monetize on expanding that primary value or offer a secondary value.</p><h2><strong>I want to be free</strong></h2><p>So I'm putting my money where my mouth is. I'm switching over all my projects to freemium.</p><p>As of today:</p><ul><li><a href="http://snazzy.ai/">Snazzy.ai</a>, content marketing powered by GPT-3, now has a free tier</li><li><a href="http://ga-insights.com/">GA-Insights.com</a>, all your ad networks into Slack, has a free tier being built out</li><li><a href="http://weld.ai/">Weld.ai</a>, in beta as a Supermetrics alternative, will now be completely free at launch.</li></ul><p>The riskiest part of a freemium pricing tier as a bootstrapped founder is getting the volume you need to make up any initial drop in conversion rate.</p><h2><strong>Reference: The market leaders (and the victims)</strong></h2><ul><li>Profitwell: Baremetrics, Chartmogul</li><li>Canva: Photoshop, Illustrator, Word</li><li>Google Optimize: Optimizely, VWO</li><li>Microsoft Teams: Slack</li><li>Figma: Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch Invision</li></ul><p>Early …</p></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.chrisfrantz.com/how-to-kill-a-unicorn/">https://www.chrisfrantz.com/how-to-kill-a-unicorn/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.chrisfrantz.com/how-to-kill-a-unicorn/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26060038</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 02:03:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Lisp REPL as my main shell]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 54 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26059023">thread link</a>) | @qazwse_
<br/>
February 7, 2021 | https://ambrevar.xyz/lisp-repl-shell/index.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ambrevar.xyz/lisp-repl-shell/index.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">
<header>

<p>The shell is dead, long live the REPL!</p>
</header><nav id="table-of-contents">
<h2>Table of Contents</h2>

</nav>
<p>
If you enjoy this article and would like to help me keep writing, consider
chipping in, every little bit helps to keep me going&nbsp;:)
</p>

<center></center>
<center></center>

<p>
Thank you!
</p>

<blockquote>
<p>
Update: As of 2021-02-07, not all the code and configurations used in this
presentation have been published.  Should happen in the coming days, stay tuned!
</p>
</blockquote>

<div id="outline-container-orgf1dd13f">
<h2 id="orgf1dd13f">Introduction video</h2>
<div id="text-orgf1dd13f">
<p>
The concepts I’m going to present in this article were featured in a
<a href="https://fosdem.org/2021/schedule/event/lisprepl/">presentation at FOSDEM 2021</a>.  The video demonstrates a rather novel paradigm how
to think the REPL as a “shell” interface to the machine.
</p>

<p>
In this article I’m going to dive into more in details in the theory, the setup,
as well as more advanced features.
</p>

<p>
Mind the title: this is <i>not</i> about another system shell implemented in Lisp
(such as <a href="https://github.com/scheme/scsh">scsh</a>, <a href="https://clisp.sourceforge.io/clash.html">clash</a> or <a href="https://github.com/SquircleSpace/shcl">shcl</a>); rather, I tried to approach the problem in the
opposite direction by trying to bring the “shell” to a programming language
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/REPL">REPL</a>.
</p>

<blockquote>
<p>
I want to emphasize that while I use <a href="https://common-lisp.net/">Common Lisp</a> and <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/">Emacs</a> as support technology
for my demos, the thesis of this article concerns itself with a new shell
interface paradigm.
</p>

<p>
Should you dislike Emacs or Lisp, never mind: the concept presented here can be
adapted using other (editor) interfaces and other programming languages (but not
all, as I will explain later).
</p>
</blockquote>

<p>
This article is bordering the format of an extensive tutorial and as such it’s
rather long.  The various top sections starting from <a href="#orga7eb7d8">SLY: A tour of a most-advanced REPL</a> are mostly independent so feel free to read them in any
order.  (I’ve interlinked them whenever necessary.)
</p>

<p>
Happy reading!
</p>
</div>
</div>

<div id="outline-container-org22c0fa8">
<h2 id="org22c0fa8">Challenging the dominating paradigm</h2>

<div id="outline-container-org40c8022">
<h3 id="org40c8022">The universal computer usage paradigm, and why traditional shells are poor tools</h3>
<div id="text-org40c8022">
<p>
What a computer user (and in particular a technically minded user such as a
developer) does on a computer can be understood as one of three actions:
</p>

<ul>
<li>Data collection and filtering.</li>
<li>Data visualization (which I also call “inspection” in this article).</li>
<li>Data transformation (which I also call “processing” in this article).</li>
</ul>

<p>
Opening a file or multiple files with a program, say, to play a music album, is
in effect “collection + visualization”.  Shrinking a bunch of photos is
“collection + processing”.
</p>

<p>
I believe that most, if not all our interactions with a computer can be summed
up in those three tasks.
</p>

<p>
More interestingly, there is a feedback loop between collection and
visualization, which is very common when manipulating large bunches of files
from a shell: the user first displays the file list to process, then filters it,
displays the filtered list, re-filters if needed, re-displays it, and so on.
When the file list is finalized, the user can process it and finally visualizes
the result.
</p>

<p>
This feedback loop that’s best represented by this simple diagram:
</p>


<figure>
<img src="https://ambrevar.xyz/lisp-repl-shell/feedback-loop.png" alt="feedback-loop.png">

<figcaption><span>Figure 1: </span>User interaction feedback loop</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>
It turns out that traditional shells are particularly poor interactive tools
to deal with such a feedback loop.
</p>

<p>
To paraphrase the example in <a href="http://howardism.org/Technical/Emacs/piper-presentation-transcript.html">Howard’s presentation on piper</a>, typical
“collection + processing” in the shell happens with a pipeline and some control
structures:
</p>

<div>
<pre>for S in $(systemctl --all | grep openstack | sed 's/\.service.*//' | cut -c3-)
do
    systemctl restart $S
done
</pre>
</div>

<p>
In the above example, as is customary in the shell, the whole “collection +
processing” step remains a blackbox to the user who can visualize the data only
before and after, but never for the intermediate steps.
</p>

<p>
While we are at it, shell languages from the <code>sh</code> family have poor control
structures, which make simple things like a <code>for</code> loop too cumbersome to write
and riddled with <a href="https://mywiki.wooledge.org/BashPitfalls">pitfalls</a>.
</p>
</div>
</div>

<div id="outline-container-org2e2682e">
<h3 id="org2e2682e">The local minimal of terminals and shells</h3>
<div id="text-org2e2682e">
<p>
There is a common misconception that terminals and shells are inherently bound
to each other, to the point that there is sometimes a confusion between the
two.
</p>

<ul>
<li><p>
A terminal, actually a terminal emulator, is a program that <i>visually</i>
emulates the hardware of the 1970s and 1980s, such as the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/VT100">VT100</a>.  These tools
are by definition stuck in the past.
</p>

<p>
(A common misconception is that they are fast.  Ironically, they are not:
emulators emulate the physical properties of the terminal such as the baud
rate, and this limits the speed at which text can be printed.)
</p></li>

<li>A shell is a programming language interpreter.  A <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/REPL">REPL</a> of a sort.
It often embeds interactive features such as a prompt with history support.</li>
</ul>

<p>
Terminals have no reason to continue to be used in my opinion.  Note that this
does not mean we shouldn’t use “textual” interfaces, quite the opposite: textual
data is a bliss to manipulate.  But we can very well manipulate text, along with
other types of data, in something other than a terminal, that is faster,
prettier, more powerful.  (Graphical Emacs is one such example.)
</p>

<p>
In the past I’ve discussed the drawbacks of using a terminal as an interface
(see my article <a href="https://ambrevar.xyz/emacs-eshell/index.html">Eshell as a main shell</a>).  I won’t go into the details again, but
allow me to summarize terminal-induced limitations of traditional shells:
</p>

<ul>
<li>Can’t search the outputs.</li>
<li>Can’t interact with output (like opening a path under the cursor).</li>
<li>Can’t copy/paste without a mouse (barring a few hacks).</li>
<li>Can’t navigate the prompts.</li>
<li>Limited colors (barring a few hacks), formatting and rendering is convoluted and
not portable.</li>
<li>Can’t render anything beside text.</li>
<li>Interface toolkits like ncurses can’t render <i>structured</i> widgets (to see what
I mean, try selecting text in an ncurses frame: the selection will grab the
whole line, beyond the frame).</li>
<li>Slow text output.</li>
<li>Poor font support (single size).</li>
<li>No per-pixel elements (e.g. cannot draw a line separator).</li>
<li>Prompts and their output cannot be folded, moved arround, etc.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>

<div id="outline-container-orgab9b972">
<h3 id="orgab9b972">Readline-shells, “go-to scripts” and code composition</h3>
<div id="text-orgab9b972">
<p>
I was an <a href="https://ambrevar.xyz/emacs-eshell/index.html">Eshell</a> user for a while, then I switched to <a href="https://ambrevar.xyz/emacs-eshell-versus-shell/index.html">M-x shell</a>.  Both these
non-terminal-based shells rid me of most of the aforementioned terminal
limitations, since graphical Emacs is a full-blown graphical application.
</p>

<p>
But I still wasn’t satisfied, in particular with the programming language used
by the shell (I’ve used <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/bash/">Bash</a>, <a href="https://www.zsh.org/">Zsh</a>, <a href="https://fishshell.com/">Fish</a> and Eshell).
</p>

<p>
I fancy the Lisp programming languages, so why not use the language I’m most
comfortable with, say Common Lisp?
</p>

<p>
For a long time I tried really hard to stick to the paradigm of what I call the
“readline shells”.  Almost all shells are developed with the idea of running in
a terminal with a <a href="https://savannah.gnu.org/projects/readline/">readline</a>-based prompt (if not <code>readline</code>, then a similar
interface).
Even shells as exotic as <a href="https://github.com/scheme/scsh">scsh</a> or <a href="https://github.com/SquircleSpace/shcl">SHCL</a> are developed with this paradigm in mind.
</p>

<p>
This can only perpetuate the problem: these shells can’t really escape the poor
feedback loop problem I mentioned above because of the lack of interactivity
options in the user interface.  And it is still limited in terms of rendering,
prompt navigation and manipulation, etc.
</p>
</div>

<div id="outline-container-orge795939">
<h4 id="orge795939">“Go-to scripting languages”</h4>
<div id="text-orge795939">
<p>
Power users and developers alike <a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/emacs/comments/csvje9/lisp_people_whats_your_goto_language_for_when_you/">fancy having their personal “shell scripts”</a>,
usually short and simple programs that don’t warrant an official distribution,
to perform every day tasks from file processing to shell helpers.
</p>

<p>
These programs can be written in various languages, but unfortunately the choice
must be restricted for practical reasons:
</p>

<ul>
<li>Some languages are “compile-only”, so they won’t take scripts.</li>
<li>Some language interpreters are too slow to start (e.g. above 100ms), which
makes the script prohibitive to use in a tight loop from another script.</li>
<li>Some languages are poor at process management.</li>
<li>Portability may be a concern: if a script requires libraries to be
locally installed, it may hinder its use on another system, like your other
machine or a friend’s computer.</li>
</ul>

<p>
<code>Bash</code>, <code>POSIX sh</code> and friends address all these points rather well, which
probably explains why they are so ubiquitous (especially the point on
portability).
</p>

<p>
But is it enough a reason to surrender and keep using among the worst
programming languages out there today?
</p>

<p>
I believe it’s high time we challenged the status quo and stepped up in the
shell game.
</p>

<p>
As we will see in the rest of the this article, a required feature for a programming
language to be used as a shell is meta-programmability, or the ability to
redefine at least part of its syntax.  Here Lisp languages perform really well thanks
to their <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homoiconicity">homoiconicity</a> property.
</p>

<p>
Perl or Python are often quoted as good alternatives: It’s certainly more expressive and
less limited than Bash while enjoying a broad ecosystem of libraries.
</p>

<p>
Being a Lisper at heart, I’ve explored the surface of various options:
</p>
</div>

<ul>
<li><a id="orga6ec8ef"></a><a href="https://github.com/scheme/scsh">scsh</a>
<p>
<a href="https://github.com/scheme/scsh">scsh</a> is an obvious choice since its name stands for the “Scheme shell”.  While a
Scheme, it seems that it is does not have a broad ecosystem of libraries, which
may make it a bit limiting in practice, or forcing the users to write most of
their own.  (Please correct me if I’m wrong.)
</p>
</li>

<li><a id="org2cd2ba6"></a>Guile
<p>
<a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/guile/">Guile</a> is a good contender: it’s reasonably fast, it has a developing ecosystem,
it has good support for scripting.
</p>
</li>

<li><a id="orgd56ae50"></a>Gauche
<p>
<a href="https://practical-scheme.net/gauche/index.html">Gauche</a> design goal is to be a fast scripting language.  So it could be ideal for
go-to scripts.
</p>
</li>

<li><a id="orga6bad10"></a>TXR
<p>
I am mostly ignorant about <a href="https://nongnu.org/txr/">TXR</a>, so I can only tell from the little I’ve played
with it: it seemed rather slow (maybe in the ballpark of Bash), and I’m unsure
about its ecosystem.
</p>
</li>

<li><a id="orgb2d639b"></a>Racket
<p>
At first, Racket startup time around 100ms on my machine seems prohibitive for
scripts.  But maybe there is a way to overcome this.  Any Racketeer around? :)
</p>
</li>

<li><a id="orgcb7dcf5"></a>Emacs Lisp<br>
<div id="text-orgcb7dcf5">
<p>
<a href="http://howardism.org/Technical/Emacs/piper-presentation-transcript.html">Howard’s piper</a> is very inspiring, but I decided not to go with Elisp which I
believe is too limiting (for now) to be used as a shell language.
</p>

<p>
Eshell cannot separate standard input from standard error.  This is a blocker in
my opinion, until we fix it or implement some other shell in Emacs Lisp.
</p>

<p>
As a scripting language, Emacs Lisp is not a great choice either because <code>emacs
--script</code> can only print to <code>stderr</code>.
</p>

<p>
Besides, as of Emacs 27, Emacs Lisp has poor threading support.  This is quickly
limiting, in particular when it comes to process management.
</p>

<p>
Finally Emacs …</p></div></li></ul></div></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://ambrevar.xyz/lisp-repl-shell/index.html">https://ambrevar.xyz/lisp-repl-shell/index.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ambrevar.xyz/lisp-repl-shell/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26059023</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 22:59:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Forgiveness: The Essential Virtue]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 23 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26058495">thread link</a>) | @dsrnewell
<br/>
February 7, 2021 | https://realclearconservatism.com/2021/02/07/forgiveness-the-essential-virtue/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://realclearconservatism.com/2021/02/07/forgiveness-the-essential-virtue/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Forgiveness is one of the most, if not the most, essential virtue for any civilized society. And yet it seems to be one of the virtues most lacking in America today. Politicians who are disloyal to the party line are censured, despite being faithful to political principle and their conscience. Professionals who years earlier used an inappropriate slur are fired, despite sincere apologies. Public figures whose image is once tarnished by inappropriate behavior are consigned to permanent pariah status, despite their contrition. It seems that once you are out of society’s good graces nowadays, you have little hope of return.</p>



<p>This is a worrying trend because forgiveness is critical to maintaining the integrity of society by providing a way to reintegrate society’s lost sheep. Without the possibility of personal contrition and social rituals of repentance leading to a welcoming of these lost sheep back into the social fold, there is no possibility for social learning and improvement, only perfection or social exile.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Everyone makes mistakes. In the pre-internet era, an inopportune remark during the foolishness of teenagehood might have faded with the years as those hurt moved on and those guilty changed their ways. Now, a tonedeaf post on Twitter becomes part of a person’s permanent social record and decades later could lead to the loss of livelihood or opportunity, despite the individual having since renounced their youthful indiscretions.</p>



<p>Because of a lack of forgiveness, people are not allowed to mature, they are not allowed to change. Who you are today is judged by who you were at your worst moment instead of who you have grown to become. This has created social anxiety and fear in the youth of today, and many of the not-so-young as well.</p>



<p>Jesus’ disciple, Peter, once asked Jesus, “Lord, how oft shall my brother sin against me, and I forgive him? till seven times? Jesus saith unto him, I say not unto thee, Until seven times: but, Until seventy times seven” (Matthew 18:21-22, KJV). </p>



<p>The Jews of Peter and Jesus’ time had strict codes of behavior, according to the Law of Moses. Yet they also had well-established means of repentance and forgiveness for those who violated the Law. Here, Jesus reaffirmed the great importance of forgiveness.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While the America of today has fewer rules than the Jews under the Law of Moses, we have lost any meaningful mechanism for offenders of our social codes to repent and be reintegrated into respectable society.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If processes of receiving forgiveness are not rediscovered in America, the group of social pariahs will only grow and contribute to the sense of hopelessness that leads to the social and political extremism already evident in our country today. After all, if you are an outcast or “deplorable,” what do you have to lose from tearing down the system that excludes you?</p>



<p>But forgiveness is about so much more than being brought back into society’s good graces for big, public mistakes. It is just as much about how we treat each other in our daily interactions. How do we treat the person who cut us off in traffic? How do we react to the person who failed to use our preferred pronoun? How do we respond when someone demonstrates ignorance of our own suffering or that of another?</p>



<p>The millions of daily acts of forgiveness or condemnation of the perpetrators of social misdemeanors weave the tapestry of social cohesion. If condemnation prevails, the social grace that makes up the very fiber of civilization unwinds.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Forgiveness does not require acceptance of bad behavior, quite the contrary. Forgiveness is a recognition that behavior is, in fact, bad, but also has the insight to see that everyone is imperfect and should be afforded the chance to try to do better next time. As such, forgiveness is the ultimate expression of love.</p>



<p>A great irony is that those who fail to forgive, at a personal level, often suffer much more than those in need of forgiveness. How often has a long-held grudge consumed its patron until the consequences are manifold greater than the original offense? This is perhaps most true when, at the personal level, we fail to forgive those who are <em>not</em> penitent.</p>



<p>Even those guilty of criminal behavior need the forgiveness of both society and the individuals harmed by the crime. This does not mean that criminals should not serve their time, simply that, for the good of society and the victims of crime, forgiveness needs to be granted for psycho-social resolution and progress.</p>



<p>Ultimately, forgiveness is the great arbiter, the reconciliator. It is forgiveness that allows society to be both just and merciful. It allows institutions to be created and people to be held accountable to those institutions, while also setting forth means for those who violate the rules to regain social acceptance. Without forgiveness, America will continue to devolve into Thomas Hobbes’ dystopian vision of the pre-civilized, natural state of life for man as, “solitary, poor, nasty, brutish, and short.”</p>
	</div><div>
				<p><strong>Published</strong>
			<time datetime="2021-02-07T22:35:56+01:00">February 7, 2021</time><time datetime="2021-02-07T23:23:43+01:00">February 7, 2021</time>		</p><!-- .site-posted-on -->
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://realclearconservatism.com/2021/02/07/forgiveness-the-essential-virtue/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26058495</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 21:45:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Talent Is Largely a Myth]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 125 | Comments 148 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26058457">thread link</a>) | @rayrey
<br/>
February 7, 2021 | https://blog.nukemberg.com/post/talent-is-largely-a-myth/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.nukemberg.com/post/talent-is-largely-a-myth/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main"><div><div><article role="main"><p>One of the repeating motifs of recruiting in the software industry are mantras of “talent”: “We recruit the best talent”, “talent attracts talent”, “we value talent” and so on. Some companies have so called “head of talent”, “talent acquisition”, “talent development” professionals on their payroll - basically a re-branding of HR. With the amount of conversations, conference talks and hype going on around talent, you would expect people will have an answer to the question “what is talent?”. You’d expect, and you’d be wrong: “it’s like porn, you know it when you see it” is the answer I usually get - and as with porn, this only conveys that the word is merely an unhelpful judgemental label. If you cannot give <em>some</em> attributes of “talent”, how are you going to find it, develop it, keep it? Also, it’s not as if the subject of talent hasn’t been researched - quite the contrary! Although research is far from being exhaustive of the subject (or anything related to intelligence for that matter), there is plenty we do know. As it turns out, most of what we hear about “talent” in the software industry is just plain wrong and based on naive and deprecated models if not outright self delusions. For example, <a href="https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2005/01/27/news-58/">Joel Spolsky has observed years ago</a> that almost all companies are somehow convinced they hire only the top 1% of developers - a clear case of selection bias. When people tell me they want to hire the top 1% of developers, I laugh. First because as Joel Spolsky noted everyone says that. Second, it implies we have some measurement of developers abilities - if we had that, why are we working so hard on interviews? Third, do they mean “top 1% of the population” of developers or the developers with top 1% of the skill scale? they are not the same. Fourth, it assumes that skill is static and when they hire a top 1% developer she will remain a top 1% developer - in other words that performance is dependent only on the identity of the developer.</p><p>All of these assumptions are completely wrong.</p><h2 id="talent-is-multi-dimensional">Talent is multi dimensional</h2><p>Suppose for a second we have some kind of metric by which we can sort developers on a scale to choose the best 1% of them. If such a metric exists, design a test for it and stop doing interviews! The reason why we have interviews, test projects and hiring committees is that there is no metric or even a group of metrics which can be measured and by which we can evaluate developers. In sports a large surrounding industry of gambling and statistics popped up because while the game itself has a clear score the relative strength and weaknesses of players and teams are far from being easily measurable - and it isn’t even clear which attributes impact the game and should be measured. Likewise, software engineering involves many different skills and let’s be honest here, we don’t really know what skills contribute to success and which of them are necessary or sufficient. But unlike sport matches, in software engineering we don’t know how to score relative performance of engineers - we have no measurement of goodness for code nor are we likely to ever have one. There are many different dimensions to goodness of code, and their relative important can change between projects or time. Even performance which is the most measurable of these is contextually defined, for one project performance means throughput while for another it’s the 99th percentile of latency.</p><h2 id="talent-isnt-static">Talent isn’t static</h2><blockquote><p>A genius is not born but is educated and trained….When a child is born healthy, it is a potential genius.</p></blockquote>Everyone wants to hire talent, but few people are asking “where does talent come from?”. There are a lot of evidence that “ingrained talent” is largely a myth. The more we learn about the brain the more we understand the answer to the nature vs nurture question is always “both”. On the one hand, we have Mozart: a brilliant musician from childhood; on the other side of the spectrum we have the Polgar sisters - geniuses by design. But Mozart was born to a musician father and grew up immersed in music, nurtured from an early age and no one can tell how he would have developed in another family. Conversely, how many potential Mozarts have we missed due to lack of nurture? no one knows.<p>None of us started proficient in programming, nor were we born with the ability to speak or think - we <em>developed</em> these abilities. If there’s one thing we know for sure about intelligence, it’s that it is adaptive - in fact, the general definition of intelligence is “adapting to provide better results predictably better than random”. The “better than random” part is important, because there’s nothing intelligent in winning 50% of coin tosses (or making profit in a rising market). The “adaptive” part is of particular interest though, as all strategies are specialized to some degree; being good at something doesn’t mean you’ll be good at something else, a fact worth remembering when hiring fresh graduates based on their University score - being good at University tests is not a transferrable skill to developing software. Intelligence is adaptation, and while it’s true that some individuals adapt faster than others it should be clear the reasons for that are mixture of innate abilities and environmental factors. All standard tests are remarkably bad at measuring this because they are focused on measuring specific skills and not adaptation. Personally I believe the best predictor of a person’s adaptive abilities are what we call “personality traits” - things like curiosity, openness and critical thinking (it turns out this belief has grounding in research). Anyway, if we accept that intelligence is adaptive it should be clear any measurement of current skill is less interesting than the adaptive potential of the individual. “Talent” is a network effect and exhibits all the familiar behaviors of network effects. It shouldn’t be surprising to learn that people <a href="https://blog.atomist.com/the-origins-of-opera-and-the-future-of-programming/">better develop their talent in groups</a>. The <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Where-Good-Ideas-Come-Innovation/dp/1594485380">history of innovation</a> demonstrates that innovation isn’t driven by heroic geniuses but by intricate collaborative networks - although popular media would have you believe otherwise. Indeed, people augment each other not only in skill but in adaptation and learning as well.</p><blockquote><p>“we don’t have these Netflix superstar engineers to do the things you’re talking about”, and when I looked around the room at the company names my response was “we hired them from you and got out of their way”</p></blockquote><p>How often was someone who was thought to be talented in his previous company hired only to have them perform poorly in the new one? How many times have you seen “diamonds in the rough” who displayed no talent in one workplace but suddenly became a rising star after moving to a new one? The prevalence of these occurrences should be enough to convince you that talent development is highly linked to the environment. Understanding this, we shouldn’t say that “A graders hire other A graders, B graders hire C graders” but rather that “A graders create A graders, B graders create C graders”. You’ve witnessed this yourself for sure - the loss or rise of motivation, the challenges, mentoring or put downs by teammates can make a star a disgruntled moron or spark flames of wisdom and enthusiasm in a once mediocre person. <strong>You hire potential talent, but manifestation of talent is developed</strong>.</p><h2 id="talent-isnt-linear">Talent isn’t linear</h2><p>The entire world has an estimated 25-30 million developers, and Google reportedly employees over 100,000 of them. Even if we think this number is exaggerated, Google, Amazon, Facebook, Microsoft and the rest of Silicon Valley giants employ hundreds of thousands of developers - well over the 1% mark. It’s obvious they can’t hire “the top 1%” simply because they are too big, but perhaps a small startup can?
</p><div><figure itemprop="associatedMedia" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject"><p><img itemprop="thumbnail" src="https://i0.wp.com/btwb.blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/image1.png" alt="https://i0.wp.com/btwb.blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/image1.png"></p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/btwb.blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/image1.png" itemprop="contentUrl"></a></figure></div>This is what skill distributions looks like, for any measurement of skill I have ever seen. For natural skills or attributes the distributions tend to be normal or log-normal, but is this the case for <em>results</em> of applying these skills? We have argued before that talent is a network effect and for network effects power distributions reign, e.g. the Zipfian distribution of city sizes. Skill isn’t uniformly distributed - which means there’s a big difference between hiring the top %1 of the <em>population</em> and hiring the people with the top 1% of results and that difference is extremely large when power laws are involved. That’s the Pareto principle in a nutshell, 80% of results come from 20% of the effort. The developers producing the top 1% of results, for whatever measurement of results you choose, are a tiny fraction of the population. You are unlikely to ever meet one. So let’s assume people mean the top 1% of the population. Here’s what the compensation distribution chart looks like:<div><figure itemprop="associatedMedia" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject"><p><img itemprop="thumbnail" src="https://blog.nukemberg.com/img/compensation-distribution.png" alt="/img/compensation-distribution.png"></p><a href="https://blog.nukemberg.com/img/compensation-distribution.png" itemprop="contentUrl"></a></figure></div>This specific data is self reported from the San Francisco area and the tail goes well beyond the million $ mark. All compensation and wealth distributions have similar shapes, the top 1% of any free profession don’t make 50% or even 100% more than the mean, they make hundreds of percents more<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>. In other words, there is no way for a startup to pay a top 1% developer (but perhaps they can offer some other incentive, and I don’t mean stock options because that’s crap).<p>If all of these prevalent assumptions about talent are wrong, what does it say about our hiring and management practices? what do managers even mean when they set out to hire “good developers” given that their goodness cannot be measured and is highly volatile? And if talent is as László Polgár claimed not born but rather developed, what is the value of testing for <em>present</em> level of proficiency. Is it possible that <em>where we hire to</em> is more important than <em>who</em> we hire? It’s clear we need a better model of talent, one which focuses on the conditions suitable for development and nurture of talent rather than attracting talent. I have some hunches about what this model would look like, and there are definitely tell-tale examples out there to learn from. But this kind of new model …</p></article></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.nukemberg.com/post/talent-is-largely-a-myth/">https://blog.nukemberg.com/post/talent-is-largely-a-myth/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.nukemberg.com/post/talent-is-largely-a-myth/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26058457</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 21:40:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Facebook Downgrades WikiLeaks Article Page]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 52 | Comments 58 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26058146">thread link</a>) | @zoobab
<br/>
February 7, 2021 | https://www.explica.co/facebook-downgrades-wikileaks-article-page-supported-assange/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.explica.co/facebook-downgrades-wikileaks-article-page-supported-assange/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
		
		

		<div itemprop="articleBody">
			



<p><strong>-The elimination of the WikiLeaks Shop on Facebook is strongly criticized for being considered “one more censorship action of social networks”</strong><br>
<strong>-WikiLeaks Shop sells t-shirts, hoodies and mugs with the organization’s logo, which carry messages such as: “Exposing crimes is not a crime”</strong><br>
<strong>-The site now offers discounted merchandise if buyers use the code “NOCENSORSHIP”</strong></p>
<p>The removal of the WikiLeaks Shop Facebook page is the latest example of high-profile organizations experiencing what critics argue: it’s the increasingly censorious nature of social media.</p>








<p>It has not been posted on the WikiLeaks Shop Facebook page for allegedly violating the “community standards” of the social networking site.  On February 2, 2021, the Facebook page belonging to the marketing arm of the transparency and news outlet was blocked from public view with a statement that read: “Your page, WikiLeaks Store, has not been published.” .</p>
<p>This would later be explained with a message that simply stated, “This is because WikiLeaks Shop is against our community guidelines.”  The Facebook page has existed since December 3, 2011.</p>
<p>WikiLeaks Shop sells T-shirts, hoodies and mugs with the organization’s logo, which carry messages such as: “Exposing crimes is not a crime”, “Free Julian Assange” and “1984 is not an instruction manual”, in reference to the dystopian novel about life in a totalitarian state written by George Orwell.</p>

<p>Related Notes: #Pizzagate: Pedophile Cult Now Trending Thanks to Justin Bieber Promotion </p>
<p>“I spoke with a person [a través del soporte empresarial de Facebook] and they told me that they couldn’t help me and that the appeal process was the only way ”, explains the person who runs the WikiLeaks store to the Russian media Sputnik.</p>
<p>The source added to the outlet that there was an appeal process but that it was fully automated.  “The appeal did not allow [ninguna opción para publicar] nothing, it was more of a ‘if you don’t agree with this decision, please click this button’ ”.  Possible attack by bots for supporting WikiLeaks founder</p>
<p>However, the WikiLeaks Shop manager “discovered something interesting,” he told Sputnik.  They realized that the decision to unpublish the Facebook page followed what appears to be an attack by apparent bots (automated accounts).  “Someone probably made it look like we were paying someone to share our posts with the bots,” the source explained.</p>
<p>The final post made by WikiLeaks Shop, before their page was taken down, simply contained a graphic with a black t-shirt and the words “Free Assange” on it.</p>

<p>“I don’t think that’s the content that would violate their policies,” explained the source.  “I read their policies, we do not participate in anything against them as far as I know,” they added.  The site now offers discounted merchandise if shoppers use the code “NOCENSORSHIP” through the website.</p>
<p>The management of the page contacted the Facebook press department to obtain a right of reply on the removal of their site from networks.  A member of Facebook’s press team responded asking for more information and a link to the unpublished page, explaining that they could not comment until they investigated further on the matter.</p>
<p>Julian Assange, co-founder of WikiLeaks, remains in Belmarsh prison while the US government appeals the decision of District Judge Vanessa Baraitser on the refusal to grant extradition.</p>




<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->
		</div>
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.explica.co/facebook-downgrades-wikileaks-article-page-supported-assange/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26058146</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 21:01:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[DVD-Drive Based Laser Scanning Microscope]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 129 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26057897">thread link</a>) | @zimmerfrei
<br/>
February 7, 2021 | https://loetlabor-jena.de/doku.php?id=projekte:dvdlsm:start | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://loetlabor-jena.de/doku.php?id=projekte:dvdlsm:start">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div class="page">
                                                            <!-- wikipage start -->
                    



<div>

<p>
<a href="https://loetlabor-jena.de/lib/exe/detail.php?id=projekte%3Advdlsm%3Astart&amp;media=projekte:dvdlsm:dvdlsm_full.jpg" title="projekte:dvdlsm:dvdlsm_full.jpg"><img src="https://loetlabor-jena.de/lib/exe/fetch.php?w=450&amp;tok=16dc0d&amp;media=projekte:dvdlsm:dvdlsm_full.jpg" alt="" width="450"></a>
</p>

<p>
Due to an abundance of one specific type of DVD drives, plans were made to give a useful afterlife to these devices. A laser scanning microscope seemed to be the most useful project.
</p>

</div>

<h2 id="preface">Preface</h2>
<div>

<p>
This project was inspired by the work done by Hannes Zöllner towards his Ph.D., during which he evaluated commercial DVD drives for fault injection in semiconductor devices. At some point, his system was also repurposed for imaging, with surprisingly remarkable results. An effort was made to optimize the system used in this project for imaging rather than for fault injection.
</p>

<p>
A DVD drive is a remarkable device, being able to discern the height of tiny pits of about 440 nm in length, laid out in tracks separated by only 780 nm. Of course, Blu-Ray technology decreased both these numbers further, but DVD drives tend to be thrown away in large quantities these days, which makes them available to the hobbyist basically free of charge.
</p>

</div>

<h2 id="concept">Concept</h2>
<div>

<p>
The OPU (Optical Pickup Unit) of a DVD drive normally contains all the optical and most of the electrical components required to read data from a disk. Normally, it includes laser diodes (and sometimes their driver electronics), a multi-quadrant detector diode (PDIC or OPIC), the required optical elements (lenses, mirrors, prisms, gratings) and the actors for focus, tilt and tracking control (typically electromagnetic actuators moving the primary lens close to the disk). Normally, the OPU is mounted on a linear rail equipped with a stepper motor for one-axis position control.
</p>

<p>
In the available drives, all OPU components are interfaced using a single FFC (flat cable) to a custom board that houses a proprietary microprocessor and various components not quite available to the average consumer. Therefore a replacement for these electronics that utilizes commercially available components open source hardware/software should be created.
</p>

<p>
This replacement should provide the following basic functionalities:
</p>
<ul>
<li><p> Interface to PC for data acquisition</p>
</li>
<li><p> Driving of OPU actuators (lens coils)</p>
</li>
<li><p> Driving of laser diode(s)</p>
</li>
<li><p> Readout of the PDIC for focusing and image acquisition</p>
</li>
</ul>

</div>

<h2 id="opu_architecture">OPU Architecture</h2>
<div>

<p>
The OPU in the available drives is a tightly integrated component, mostly consisting of a single cast-aluminum block, in which various optical components are glued. A top-down-view of the OPU after removing the cover can be seen below.
</p>

<p>
<a href="https://loetlabor-jena.de/lib/exe/detail.php?id=projekte%3Advdlsm%3Astart&amp;media=projekte:dvdlsm:opu_disassembled.jpg" title="projekte:dvdlsm:opu_disassembled.jpg"><img src="https://loetlabor-jena.de/lib/exe/fetch.php?w=500&amp;tok=364a3d&amp;media=projekte:dvdlsm:opu_disassembled.jpg" alt="" width="500"></a>
</p>

</div>

<h3 id="laser_diodes_lens_and_actuators">Laser Diodes, Lens and Actuators</h3>
<div>

<p>
The OPU houses two laser diodes. As this is just a DVD/CD reader, the lasers are not very powerful but provide sufficient power for microscopy applications. The (red) DVD diode starts laser operation above approx. 60 mA and requires about 2-2.5 V of forward voltage. Its polarity can be easily determined by measurements.
</p>

<p>
The primary lens is positioned using electromagnetic actuators. These come in the form of three coils, which tilt or move the coil proportionally to the current flowing though them. Their polarity and required full-scale DC actuation current can be easily found by using a lab power supply.
</p>

<p>
The focusing control loop driving these coils is normally deriving its error signal from the astigmatic focus error detection method. It requires (in its basic form) a four-quadrant diode, and focus is optimized when all quadrants of the diode are equally illuminated. Deviation from this point will cause the circular illumiation to become elliptical and therefore illuminate two diagonal quadrants more strongly. A schematic explanation of that scheme can be found <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/figure/Astigmatic-detection-method-a-Schematic-diagram-of-the-optical-system-with-commercial_fig1_329138728" title="https://www.researchgate.net/figure/Astigmatic-detection-method-a-Schematic-diagram-of-the-optical-system-with-commercial_fig1_329138728" rel="ugc nofollow">here</a> and in many textbooks.
</p>

</div>

<h3 id="pdic">PDIC</h3>
<div>

<p>
The PDIC (Photo Diode Integrated Circuit), in a DVD reader application, serves multiple purposes. These include gathering focus, tilt and tracking information from the disk as well as recovery of the RF data stored on the disk tracks. For this reason, PDICs typically consist of at least 6 active diode areas, sometimes even more. The PDIC used in the available drive type is seen below. Given its a very niche device, oftentimes custom-designed for a specific drive vendor, datasheets are hard to come by. Initial pinout probing revealed only the power supply pin locations and a number of analog output pins, but I was unable to find any matching ICs datasheets, so some reverse engineering effort was required to figure out its secrets.
</p>

<p>
First, the device was placed on a little break-out PCB to allow easy access to all of its pins, especially during microscope inspections.
</p>

<p>
<a href="https://loetlabor-jena.de/lib/exe/detail.php?id=projekte%3Advdlsm%3Astart&amp;media=projekte:dvdlsm:pdic_breakout.jpg" title="projekte:dvdlsm:pdic_breakout.jpg"><img src="https://loetlabor-jena.de/lib/exe/fetch.php?w=600&amp;tok=63dc0c&amp;media=projekte:dvdlsm:pdic_breakout.jpg" alt="" width="600"></a>
</p>

</div>

<h4 id="pdic_reverse_engineeringoptical">PDIC Reverse Engineering: Optical</h4>
<div>

<p>
Using an IC inspection microscope, a die shot of the PDIC was produced. This was useful to get a better idea of the internal structure of the device. This process is made way easier by the fact that it is an optical integrated circuit, and is therefore housed inside a clear plastic package with good optical properties, suitable for direct microscope inspection without decapsulation. The picture below could be used to identify some functional blocks of the circuit, however full tracing from the bondpads through internal circuits to the diode quadrants didn't really go anywhere for me. However, it became apparent that the PDIC apparently houses at least independent eight photo diode channels. (Four quadrants in the center square, and at least two segments for each of the outer squares).
</p>

<p>
<a href="https://loetlabor-jena.de/lib/exe/detail.php?id=projekte%3Advdlsm%3Astart&amp;media=projekte:dvdlsm:chip_res.jpg" title="projekte:dvdlsm:chip_res.jpg"><img src="https://loetlabor-jena.de/lib/exe/fetch.php?w=600&amp;tok=2205d3&amp;media=projekte:dvdlsm:chip_res.jpg" alt="" width="600"></a>
</p>

</div>

<h4 id="pdic_reverse_engineeringelectro-optical">PDIC Reverse Engineering: Electro-Optical</h4>
<div>

<p>
On most of the pins, some change in output voltage could be seen when illuminating the device with a bright source of light. At first, the output behavior of each pin was simply put into different categories:
</p>
<ul>
<li><p> Low light sensitivity: 4 outputs</p>
</li>
<li><p> High light sensitivity: 4 outputs</p>
</li>
<li><p> Same magnitude, but opposite polarity outputs (differential pair): 2 pins</p>
</li>
<li><p> Negative output voltage: 1 pin</p>
</li>
</ul>

<p>
It was conjectured that the smaller inner quadrants were responsible for the low-sensitivity outputs, while the outer segments would produce a large amplitude (due to their larger light collection area).
</p>

<p>
In a second reverse engineering session, the exact pinout was determined by means of selective illumination: For a given test, two IC output pins were compared using two DVMs, and an aperture was slowly moved along the surface, either vertically or horizontally. This would in result a change of the output voltage for one of the outputs slightly earlier than for the other one. In this way, the positional relationships between all output pins could be resolved, forming a final assignment of diode quadrants to output pins.
</p>

<p>
<a href="https://loetlabor-jena.de/lib/exe/detail.php?id=projekte%3Advdlsm%3Astart&amp;media=projekte:dvdlsm:pinout_bg.png" title="projekte:dvdlsm:pinout_bg.png"><img src="https://loetlabor-jena.de/lib/exe/fetch.php?w=800&amp;tok=eea749&amp;media=projekte:dvdlsm:pinout_bg.png" alt="" width="800"></a>
</p>

<p>
The output producing negative voltages is not considered to be useful in the final application, while the differential output pair is likely a summed output of the four inner quadrants (the high bandwidth RF output). With the assignment of pins to diode quadrants done, the OPU could be modified to fan-out the required connections to custom electronics
</p>

</div>

<h3 id="opu_modification">OPU Modification</h3>
<div>

<p>
The whole top assembly of the DVD drive is reused. This includes not only the OPU, but also the linear (worm gear) axis driven by a stepper motor and its base plate. A breadboard header was added to the OPU, fanning out all required signals to the custom electronics on a ribbon cable. The analog output signals are separated on one side, while the current inputs for the laser diode and the lens actuators are kept to the other side. This should help mitigate electrical coupling between these signals, even though the diode outputs are actively driven by the PDIC.
</p>

<p>
The other axis (below the drive mechanism) is built from a commercial precision linear actuator that was donated to the project. Other people have simply used another DVD drive in its place, which would certainly be a possibility here.
</p>

<p>
<a href="https://loetlabor-jena.de/lib/exe/detail.php?id=projekte%3Advdlsm%3Astart&amp;media=projekte:dvdlsm:dvdlsm_head.jpg" title="projekte:dvdlsm:dvdlsm_head.jpg"><img src="https://loetlabor-jena.de/lib/exe/fetch.php?w=600&amp;tok=04af7c&amp;media=projekte:dvdlsm:dvdlsm_head.jpg" alt="" width="600"></a>
</p>

</div>

<h2 id="electronics">Electronics</h2>
<div>

<p>
A PCB was designed that would fulfill all necessary interfacing between PC and the optical components. Those would be:
</p>
<ul>
<li><p> Drive motors for X/Y axes</p>
</li>
<li><p> Drive the lens actuator coils (constant current/voltage)</p>
</li>
<li><p> Drive the laser LEDs (constant current)</p>
</li>
<li><p> Provide power supply</p>
</li>
</ul>

<p>
It was pretty obvious that at least all the mechanical actuation and laser driving could be handled by an IC foreseen for an optical drive. Texas Instruments offers a line-up of such chips, which are one of the few types that can easily be sourced from common distributors. The <a href="https://www.ti.com/product/TPIC2050" title="https://www.ti.com/product/TPIC2050" rel="ugc nofollow">TI TPIC2050</a> was chosen due to its all-digital interface and flexible output options. Given it's a pretty high-quantity component, its cost is very reasonable (€2.50 in single quantities) and can hardly be beaten by any other integrated options.
</p>

<p>
A PCB was designed around this IC, with an additional 16 bit ADC plus analog MUX for the PDIC outputs. The PCB was built to house an <a href="https://www.crowdsupply.com/1bitsquared/icebreaker-fpga" title="https://www.crowdsupply.com/1bitsquared/icebreaker-fpga" rel="ugc nofollow">iceBreaker FPGA board</a> that would take care of all the interfacing. All electronics were designed in KiCad and are available publicly in its <a href="https://git.loetlabor-jena.de/dvdlaser/dvdlaser_hw" title="https://git.loetlabor-jena.de/dvdlaser/dvdlaser_hw" rel="ugc nofollow">GitLab repository</a>.
</p>

<p>
<a href="https://loetlabor-jena.de/lib/exe/detail.php?id=projekte%3Advdlsm%3Astart&amp;media=projekte:dvdlsm:dvdlsm_pcb_unpopulated.jpg" title="projekte:dvdlsm:dvdlsm_pcb_unpopulated.jpg"><img src="https://loetlabor-jena.de/lib/exe/fetch.php?w=700&amp;tok=5e3c53&amp;media=projekte:dvdlsm:dvdlsm_pcb_unpopulated.jpg" alt="" width="700"></a>
</p>

<p>
<a href="https://loetlabor-jena.de/lib/exe/detail.php?id=projekte%3Advdlsm%3Astart&amp;media=projekte:dvdlsm:dvdlsm_pcb_res.jpg" title="projekte:dvdlsm:dvdlsm_pcb_res.jpg"><img src="https://loetlabor-jena.de/lib/exe/fetch.php?w=700&amp;tok=a47004&amp;media=projekte:dvdlsm:dvdlsm_pcb_res.jpg" alt="" width="700"></a>
</p>

</div>

<h2 id="fpga_design">FPGA Design</h2>
<div>

<p>
The FPGA had to fulfill a couple of interfacing tasks, and the design uses the <abbr title="Free &amp; Open-Source Software">FOSS</abbr> FPGA toolchain for the Lattice ice40 UP5k FPGA on the iceBreaker board. It mainly does the following things:
</p>
<ul>
<li><p> Automatically cycle through ADC MUX channels and read out photo diode currents</p>
</li>
<li><p> Provide register-level access to the TPIC2050 from the host software</p>
</li>
<li><p> Provide fast write access to the TPIC2050 DACs</p>
</li>
<li><p> Allow communications to the host PC using a 1Mbps USB-Serial connection</p>
</li>
</ul>

<p>
The design itself is quite straight forward, but I had a bit of fun with the verification environment. I used <a href="https://github.com/cocotb/cocotb/" title="https://github.com/cocotb/cocotb/" rel="ugc nofollow">cocotb</a> and iverilog for all the simulations. The testbenches contain proper hardware device models for all ICs as well as the optical chain. The simulated UART interface can be connected to a virtual serial port, which can then be stimulated by the real host software. This allows running a full „simulated hardware in the loop“ test, which is quite a neat thing to have.
</p>

<p>
Setting a focus actuator current would alter the optical chain, resulting in different values digitized by the ADC for the various photo diode …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://loetlabor-jena.de/doku.php?id=projekte:dvdlsm:start">https://loetlabor-jena.de/doku.php?id=projekte:dvdlsm:start</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://loetlabor-jena.de/doku.php?id=projekte:dvdlsm:start</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26057897</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 20:25:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Scientists find male praying mantises taking a stand against cannibal females]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 20 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26057854">thread link</a>) | @Bluestein
<br/>
February 7, 2021 | https://www.cbc.ca/radio/quirks/jan-30-new-climate-war-tactics-lizard-burrows-are-wildlife-condos-sleep-lunacy-and-more-1.5889807/scientists-find-male-praying-mantises-taking-a-stand-against-cannibal-females-1.5891923 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/radio/quirks/jan-30-new-climate-war-tactics-lizard-burrows-are-wildlife-condos-sleep-lunacy-and-more-1.5889807/scientists-find-male-praying-mantises-taking-a-stand-against-cannibal-females-1.5891923">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Male springbok mantises violently wrestle and sometimes injure females they fight to mate — and survive.</p><div><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5893321.1611936105!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/female-mantis.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>The female mantis is famous for cannibalizing the male<!-- --> <!-- -->(Submitted by Nathan Burke)</figcaption></figure><p><span><div><div role="button" tabindex="0" title="Scientists find male praying mantises taking a stand against cannibal females"><div><p><img src="https://thumbnails.cbc.ca/maven_legacy/thumbnails/123/691/Quirks-640x360.jpg" alt=""></p><p><span>Quirks and Quarks</span><span>7:59</span><span>Scientists find male praying mantises taking a stand against cannibal females</span></p></div></div></div></span></p><p><span><p>Female praying mantises of many species cannibalize their mates, who often have no defence against their large and aggressive partners.&nbsp;</p>  <p>But a new <a href="https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/10.1098/rsbl.2020.0811" target="_blank">study</a>&nbsp;by <a href="https://www.nathwilliamb.com/" target="_blank">Nathan Burke</a>, a postdoctoral research fellow in biological sciences at the University of Auckland in New Zealand, has found that that is not always the case. The male Springbok mantis can be the aggressor, and does what it takes to win the fight in order to successfully mate - and survive.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5893333.1611936405!/fileImage/httpImage/image.png_gen/derivatives/original_300/miomantis-single-image-of-female-wounds-png.png 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5893333.1611936405!/fileImage/httpImage/image.png_gen/derivatives/original_460/miomantis-single-image-of-female-wounds-png.png 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5893333.1611936405!/fileImage/httpImage/image.png_gen/derivatives/original_620/miomantis-single-image-of-female-wounds-png.png 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5893333.1611936405!/fileImage/httpImage/image.png_gen/derivatives/original_780/miomantis-single-image-of-female-wounds-png.png 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5893333.1611936405!/fileImage/httpImage/image.png_gen/derivatives/original_1180/miomantis-single-image-of-female-wounds-png.png 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5893333.1611936405!/fileImage/httpImage/image.png_gen/derivatives/original_780/miomantis-single-image-of-female-wounds-png.png"></p></div><figcaption>This photo shows a wound inflicted on the female Springbok mantis by the male during a violent mating encounter<!-- --> <!-- -->(Submitted by Nathan Burke)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <h2>Hyper cannibalism</h2>  <p>In the Springbok species the female is described as 'hyper cannibalistic,' eating her mate often without any mating even taking place.</p>  <p>As a result the male Springbok mantis goes to extraordinary - and very risky - lengths to pass on his genes, and live another day.</p>  <p>He sneaks up on the female and launches a surprise attack by leaping on top of her. What follows is a violent wrestling match, in which the female often gets stabbed by the sharp, dagger-like claws of the male, and begins to bleed. The male uses his front legs to grab hold of her and pin her down.&nbsp;</p>  <p><em>Pre-mating struggle&nbsp;showing smaller male&nbsp;wrestling with larger female&nbsp;and winning the encounter by grabbing hold of her first. A male-inflicted puncture wound&nbsp;results in the loss of haemolymph&nbsp;- or blood - for the female (Nathan Burke)</em></p>    <p>Researchers observed this behaviour in 52 pairs of mantises. If the male won, mating was achieved in 58 percent of all encounters. If the female won, she almost always cannibalized the male without him getting an opportunity to mate.&nbsp;</p>  <p>By attacking the female, the male greatly increased his mating chances, and significantly reduced the risk of being cannibalized.&nbsp;</p>  <p><em>A female unsuccessfully tries to grab hold of a male (Nathan Burke)</em></p>      </span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/radio/quirks/jan-30-new-climate-war-tactics-lizard-burrows-are-wildlife-condos-sleep-lunacy-and-more-1.5889807/scientists-find-male-praying-mantises-taking-a-stand-against-cannibal-females-1.5891923</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26057854</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 20:20:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Communicate Architecture]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 28 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26057336">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
February 7, 2021 | http://beza1e1.tuxen.de/communicate_architecture.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://beza1e1.tuxen.de/communicate_architecture.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
<p>Repeatedly software architects tell me that
their stakeholders pay no attention to their architecture.
One question I always have: Did you actually tell them?
An answer I got was that it was discussed
with some other team member a year ago.
Since <a href="http://beza1e1.tuxen.de/definitions_software_architecture.html">architecture is important</a>,
they expect such knowledge to spread on its own.
Unfortunately, natural spread does not happen.
Maybe because "important" is very often steamrolled by "urgent".
Maybe because the architecture has subtle complexities which get lost.
Thus the proper communication is a task many architects neglect.</p>
<p>(Disclaimer: This is about architectures which affect many people.
For a single team, the natural spread can be sufficient.)</p>
<h2>How architects should spend their time</h2>
<p>This raises the question how much time an architect should spend on communication.
<a href="https://philippe.kruchten.com/">Philippe Kruchten</a>,
a well known researcher, gave an answer in
<em>What do software architects really do?</em> (<a href="https://pkruchten.files.wordpress.com/2010/05/kruchten_2008_journal-of-systems-and-software.pdf">pdf</a>).
The abstract:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>To be successful, a software architect—or a software architecture team, collectively—must strike a delicate balance between an external focus—both outwards: Listening to customers, users, watching technology, developing a long-term vision, and inwards: driving the development teams—and an internal,reflective focus: spending time to make the right design choices, validating them, and documenting them.
Teams that stray too far away from this meta stable equilibrium fall into some traps that we describe as antipatterns of software architecture teams</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So, Kruchten distinguishes between three working modes of an architect.
As a knowledge worker, it roughly maps to the input, processing, and output of information.</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Internal working</strong>:
   This is the deep work an architect performs,
   essentially thinking and processing information.
   It may involve communication if there is a whole team of architects.</li>
<li><strong>Inwards communication</strong>:
   Architects must acquire a broad knowledge.
   This involves listening, reading, and asking questions.</li>
<li><strong>Outwards communication</strong>:
   Once new information is created, the architect spreads it.
   This involves presentations, writing documentation, and supporting.</li>
</ol>
<p>The ideal balance, according to Kruchten, is 50:25:25.
So only half the time the architect should spend on developing the architecture.
The other half is split in learning about the current state
and communicating the desired state.</p>
<p><img alt="50:25:25" src="http://beza1e1.tuxen.de/img/arch_50-25-25.jpeg"></p>
<p>If the balance is lost,
various clichees are the result.</p>
<p>One example are perfectionists, who neglect the outward communication.
Kruchten calls it "goldplating" the architecture.
While the work product is great,
it is obsolete on arrival.</p>
<p><img alt="60:30:10" src="http://beza1e1.tuxen.de/img/arch_60-30-10.jpeg"></p>
<p>An architect who neglects outward and inward communication
works "in an ivory tower".
While the work product might be internally consistent
and beautiful enough to make the creators arrogant,
it is impractical and thus ignored.
Especially academics tend to fall into this trap.</p>
<p><img alt="70:15:15" src="http://beza1e1.tuxen.de/img/arch_70-15-15.jpeg"></p>
<p>If the architect neglects the internal working,
the absence of a consistent architecture will show in the overall product.
It might consist of well crafted parts
but they don't fit together well.</p>
<p><img alt="30:40:30" src="http://beza1e1.tuxen.de/img/arch_30-40-30.jpeg"></p>
<p>An extreme focus on the outward communication turns the architect into a consultant.
While the developers appreciate the support,
there is no coherent mind behind the architecture.</p>
<p><img alt="25:25:50" src="http://beza1e1.tuxen.de/img/arch_25-25-50.jpeg"></p>
<p>In practice there seems to be no extreme focus on inward communication.
It might be that such architects produce
neither architecture documentation nor do they support the team.
So they produce nothing of even superficial value and
do not survive for long for business reasons.</p>
<h2>Effectively communicating the architecture</h2>
<p>Let's come back to the initial question:
Why don't people know the architecture well enough?
Assuming there is solid architecture,
the architect is either goldplating or working in an ivory tower.
In both cases, the outward communication is lacking,
so more focus should be put there.
Here are a few ideas which worked for me.</p>
<h3>Asynchronous Communication</h3>
<p>I love asynchronous communication.
As does Elon Musk, so it must be truly great.</p>
<p><img alt="Elon Musk communicates asynchronously" src="http://beza1e1.tuxen.de/img/elon_musk_async.jpeg"></p>
<p>The big advantage of asynchronous communication is
that it scales much better.
In the case of email, you can copy&amp;paste or forward information quickly.
Actually, writing in general scales well.
Unfortunately, writing skills are underrated in my profession.
Other media like podcasts or videos can also scale,
but I rarely see them used in the context of software architecture.</p>
<p>What is used heavily are diagrams.
Unfortunately, the focus is too extreme.
I have seen lots and lots of architectural diagrams
which are incomprehensible because textual explanation was missing.
Some diagrams are inherently bad (for example they use inconsistent symbols)
but even good diagrams require context.</p>
<p>The slides of great presentations are similar.
They were designed to work in a presentation.
For example, Steve Jobs' keynotes are legendary.
Here is one of the most important moments of them all.</p>
<p><img alt="Steve Jobs introducing the iPhone" src="http://beza1e1.tuxen.de/img/steve_jobs_keynote.jpeg"></p>
<p>The slide shows three icons of three relevant technologies.
During the next seconds later he announces the iPhone
which combines those three technologies into one device.
The slide works as part of the narrative context
but on its own is useless.
If you design slides to also work as a handout on their own,
the presentation will suffer for it.</p>
<p>Well, if you remember the presentation
the slide works as a reminder though.
Likewise, my hypothesis is that most architecture diagrams
are only useful as a memory aid.
To become an effective communication medium it requires more.</p>
<p>One case of asynchronous communication are architectural decision records
and <a href="http://beza1e1.tuxen.de/decision_records.html">I already wrote about them</a>.
In our context here the relevant aspect is that
decision records should be comprehensible on their own,
so you can give people a link to them
and they can learn about an aspect of the architecture on their own.
You don't have to explain it to them.
This doesn't mean you focus <em>more</em> time on outward communication
but you spend it more efficiently.</p>
<h3>Regular Newsletter</h3>
<p>For the last two years, I sent a weekly newsletter to everybody in my project,
which is roughly 250 people.
Additionally, a few dozen other people receive it as well
because they asked explicitly.
This shotgun approach means that
at least half of the recipients are not my target audience
because they are no developers.
However, even managers appreciated it as it gives them an impression
of the technical issues in the project.
My department head said "please, don't stop writing them!"</p>
<p>The newsletter is composed of whatever crosses my desk during the week.
It might a little tool how-to which I felt was not known enough yet.
It announces new architectural decision records
and upcoming/ongoing initiatives.
Sometimes developers learned something
they should have gotten from project management weeks ago.</p>
<p>Blogging experience helps a lot for writing such a newsletter.
The oldest blog post here is from 2009
and I blogged a few years before that already.
The most important part of such a newsletter is to do it consistently.</p>
<p>I use meme pictures.
They are out of the ordinary at my work
and they actually distract from the seriousness of some information.
However, multiple people told me that they only wanted to look at the funny pictures
and later realized they read the whole mail.
Also, developers appreciate the hacker vibes they know
from the internet sites they visit regularly.
Some told me, the newsletter was the highlight of their week.</p>
<p>Also helpful is writing scientific papers.
Assuming proper reviewing from supportive colleagues,
you train to write terse yet correct.
My newsletter only contains short summaries but plenty of links for more details.
Sometimes I even sneak in some self-promotion, like links to my blog here.
(I wonder if <em>you</em> found this via such a link?)</p>
<h3>The Universal Language is Concrete</h3>
<p>The book <a href="http://beza1e1.tuxen.de/made_to_stick.html">Made to Stick</a>
contains many ideas to make a message more memorable (sticky).
One of them is concreteness
and they tell a story about the conflict
between manufacturing people on the shop floor
and engineers drawing blueprints (page 115).
That resembles the architect-developer roles quite well.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The manufacturing people were thinking, <em>Why don't you just come down to the factory floor and show me where the part should go?</em> And the engineering people were thinking, <em>What do I need to do to make the drawings better?</em></p>
<p>[...] Should both parties learn greater empathy for the other and, in essence, meet in the middle? Actually, no. The solution is for the engineers to change their behavior. Why? As Bechky notes, the physical machine was the most effective and relevant domain of communication. Everyone understands the machines fluently. Therefore problems should be solved at the level of the machine. [...]</p>
<p>The moral of the story is not to "dumb things down." The manufacturing people faced complex problems and they needed smart answers. Rather, the moral of the story is to find a "universal language," one that everyone speaks fluently. Inevitably, that universal language will be concrete.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It sounds remarkably similar to our initial question.
Developers might ignore the architecture because
it is not concrete enough for their problem at hand.
The book strongly suggests that the solution is not that developers
should be educated better.
It puts the burden on the architects to explain the architecture
in concrete situations.</p>
<p>My newsletter reinforces this.
Since I need to pump out something every week,
I have to pick something small to fill it.
Even if it is not relevant to everybody,
it nudges me to explain the wider architectural background.</p>
<p>Abstractions are the luxury of the expert.
They are shortcuts between well known concrete concepts.
If the concepts are not well understood yet,
the abstraction is not helpful.
So architects should rarely talk about the big overview.
At least, keep it short and rough.</p>
<p>All this concrete communication implies a lot of work for the architect
in comparison to mere abstract outlines.
Remember it should only take you 25% of your time, …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://beza1e1.tuxen.de/communicate_architecture.html">http://beza1e1.tuxen.de/communicate_architecture.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://beza1e1.tuxen.de/communicate_architecture.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26057336</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 19:16:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Hatboro Blues]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 33 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26056977">thread link</a>) | @newest
<br/>
February 7, 2021 | https://libertiesjournal.com/now-showing/the-hatboro-blues/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://libertiesjournal.com/now-showing/the-hatboro-blues/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main" role="main">
    
  <article>
    
    <header>
    <h2>Now Showing</h2>
    <p>Time-limited &amp; rotating highlights from the inaugural issue for a rich sampling of <em>Liberties</em>.</p>
      
            
            <p><em>Liberties Journal </em>is available for a reduced rate by <a href="https://subscribe.libertiesjournal.com/LIB/?f=paid" target="_blank" rel="noopener">subscription</a>; from your favorite bookstore — <a href="https://www.indiebound.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Indiebound.org</a>, <a href="https://bookshop.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bookshop.org</a>; &nbsp;or from online booksellers —&nbsp;<a href="https://www.amazon.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a>&nbsp;and <a href="https://www.barnesandnoble.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Barnes&nbsp;&amp;&nbsp;Noble</a>.</p>



    </header>
    
    <section>
      <h4>Leon Wieseltier</h4>
      <h3>Steadying</h3>
      <p>For some time now it has felt like history is itself the pandemic. In our country and elsewhere, it has been in overdrive, teeming with evils, flush with collapses, abounding in fear and rage, a wounding contest between the sense of an ending and the sense of a beginning, between inertia and momentum, with all the terribilities of ages of transition. What is going has not yet gone and what is coming has not yet come. We have become connoisseurs of convulsion. At sea is our new sea.</p>
<p>For better and for worse, axioms and assumptions are dying everywhere around us. Such vertiginous hours always come with both clarities and confusions — there is no promise of illumination. The guidance we need in our circumstances will not be provided by the circumstances themselves: they are too many and too contradictory and too volatile; passion increasingly unconstrained and power increasingly unconstrained. As the sense of injustice grows, injustice seems to keep pace with it. There is a piercing sensation of flux, of uncontrollable effects and unmanageable consequences. The masks on our faces are emblems of an entire era of vulnerability. The most important thing, therefore, is that we keep our heads. A disequilibrium of history demands an equilibrium of the mind. Steadiness in the midst of turbulence is not complicity with the existing order. It is precisely in such binges of history that we must teach ourselves to sort through the true and the false, the good and the bad, the continuities and the discontinuities, the right statues and the wrong statues, the humane and the utopian.</p>
<p>Everything will be different: this is a ubiquitous sentiment. In all our upheavals — social and epidemiological — so much seems to be wrong and so much seems to be slipping away that one may be forgiven for enjoying a fantasy of total change. All these horrors, all these outrages, all these marches, and the world stays the same? So the first thing that needs to be said in the effort to keep our heads is that everything never changes. More, the idea that everything will change usually plays into the hands of those who want nothing to change. The cycle of revolution and reaction has never been the most effective engine of progress. Nothing suits the interests of the old regime like utopianism. The thirst for change will not be slaked by the cheap whiskey of apocalyptic thinking. The only certain outcome of the apocalyptic temper is catharsis, and one way of describing the decline of our politics in recent decades is that it has increasingly become a politics of catharsis, in which crisis is met mainly by emotion. (Populism is just mass emotionalism, and the emotions are often ugly ones.) Apocalypse is not an analysis, it is the death of analysis. It sets the stage only for salvation, but salvation must never become a political goal. This is especially true in a democratic society, where the only saviors are, alas, ourselves.</p>
<p>Thus it is that the struggle against injustice imposes upon us a paradoxical psychology: it demands both impatience and patience. Impatience about injustice, patience about justice. This is hard to do. It looks too much like, and in many cases it may well be, complacence. It is certainly difficult to preach incrementalism to the injured. So why not be impatient about justice, too? There are historical and practical reasons why not. History is stained by tales of instantaneous justice, by the consequences of the rush to perfection, by the victims of the victims. The ethical calculus of means and ends is never teleologically suspended, if just causes are to remain just. Nor is it a quantitative calculus: when I first studied the modern history of the Jews I drew a variety of conclusions from the Dreyfus affair, and one of them, which was an important moment in my moral education, was that Zola and his comrades appropriately threw an entire country into crisis for the sake of <i>one man</i>. Similarly, due process is not a legal formality, a procedural exercise that slows the way to a satisfying climax; it is the very honor of a liberal society.</p>
<p>More concretely, the establishment of justice involves not only revisions in opinions but also revisions in institutions. A dreary point! But anyone who denies the institutional dimension, in all its exasperating machinery, is not serious about the change. Paroxysms, unlike laws, vanish. This was the year in which the campaign for racial justice found support in virtually all the sectors of American society, with the exception of the White House — an unprecedented national epiphany that cannot be dismissed as “performative”, because culture matters; but the road from protest to policy is long and winding. It is not a betrayal of the ideal of social justice to tread carefully and tenaciously, with a mastery of the scruples and the methods that would make a reform defensible and durable. Tenacity is what patience looks like in the middle of a struggle.</p>
<p>I will give an example of the complicated nature of the mentality of change. One of the consequences of recent social movements in America — #MeToo (which came also to my door, with its lesson and its recklessness) and Black Lives Matter—has been to reveal how poorly we understand each other. Or more precisely, they have exposed the extent to which the failure to understand others may be owed to the failure to understand oneself — the limitations of one’s own standpoint, the comfortable assumption that one appears to others as one wishes to appear to them, or to oneself. This is nonsense, though sometimes you learn so the hard way. There are limits to our epistemological jurisdiction. The failure to observe these limits is solipsism, and we all begin as solipsists, awaiting correction by social experience.</p>
<p>Our epistemological jurisdiction stops at the encounter with another person. She is another epistemological kingdom, not more perfect but certainly different, with something important to add, and a perceptual contribution to make. I may like to think that I am what I present myself to be, but I am also what she sees me to be, because she sees me as I cannot, or will not, see myself. I am never in control of my self-representation and never complete in my self-awareness. We always show more of ourselves than we think we do, which is why we may learn from the responses of others. We spill beyond our intentions and our conceits, and what we gain from this overflow is criticism.</p>
<p>But criticism, too, must be assessed critically – there is no exemption. The enlightenment that one acquires from the judgments of others is owed only to their accuracy. It is certainly not warranted by the belief that a person’s identity or socio-economic position or experience of hardship confers an absolute authority, a special relationship to truth, a vatic privilege. What a simple world it would be if pain were a sufficient guarantee of credibility. But it is not – indeed, the opposite is the case, pain is myopic and sees chiefly itself, which is one of the reasons it hurts. Finally we are all left with the modesty of our grasp. No whole classes of people are right and no whole classes of people are wrong.</p>
<p>The ineradicability of ambiguity from human relations, the ignorance of ourselves that accompanies our ignorance of others, the whole fallible heap, creates an urgent need for tolerance and, more strenuously, for forgiveness. Historians will record that in the early decades of the twenty-first century we became an unforgiving society, a society of furies, a society in search of guilt and shame, a society of sanctimonies and “struggle sessions” American-style. They will admire our awakening to prejudice but lament the sometimes prejudicial ways in which we acted on our progressive realizations. In this respect America should become more Christian. (There, I said it.) For all our elaborate culture of self-knowledge, for all the hectoring articulateness of our identity vocabularies, we are still, each of us, our own blind spots. We should welcome every person we meet as a small blow against blindness.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://libertiesjournal.com/wp-content/uploads/insignia-break.png" width="300" height="127"></p>
<p>The partiality of perspective: this is the great teaching of the contemporary tumult. The problem is that we have not only begun to acknowledge our partiality, and the partiality of others, we have also begun to revere it, and this is a mistake. We are gagging on all our roots. If pain does not provide access to truth, neither does particularity. The worship of particularism is one of the great impediments to social justice, and in its exhilarating way it coarsens us all. In our moral and social thinking, our obsession with otherness has concealed that the foundation of moral and social action is sameness. The “other” is exotic, but there is nothing exotic about the homeless man on the street: he is the same as me, a human being, except that he is hungry and I am not. The difference in our circumstances is not a difference in our definition. When I hand him a few dollars I am not extending myself toward an alien being; I am practicing species solidarity. I am not discovering his humanity; I am responding to it. I am acting, in other words, universally, and none of the social problems that afflict us will be solved unless we recover the universalist standpoint that sees beyond the visible divisions, and is not trapped in, or enraptured by, the specificities of our tribes. Pluralism secures the right to turn inward, but it also broaches the duty to turn outward. By surrounding us with other partialities it legitimates our own partiality, but it also reveals that there …</p></section></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://libertiesjournal.com/now-showing/the-hatboro-blues/">https://libertiesjournal.com/now-showing/the-hatboro-blues/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://libertiesjournal.com/now-showing/the-hatboro-blues/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26056977</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:35:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Awesome cheatsheets for popular programming languages, frameworks etc.]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 32 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26056968">thread link</a>) | @URfejk
<br/>
February 7, 2021 | https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets" target="_blank"><img src="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/common/logo.png" srcset="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/common/logo@2x.png"></a></p><p>Awesome cheatsheets for popular programming languages, frameworks and development tools.<br>
&nbsp;They include everything you should know in one single file. 👩‍💻👨‍💻</p><section><div><p><span>01. Languages</span></p><hr></div><div><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/languages/bash.sh" target="_blank"><img src="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/components/BaseCheatsheet/bash.jpg"></a></p><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/languages/bash.sh" target="_blank">The Bash Cheatsheet</a></p></div></div><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/languages/C.txt" target="_blank"><img src="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/components/BaseCheatsheet/c.jpg"></a></p><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/languages/C.txt" target="_blank">The C Cheatsheet</a></p></div></div><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/languages/C%23.txt" target="_blank"><img src="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/components/BaseCheatsheet/c-sharp.jpg"></a></p><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/languages/C%23.txt" target="_blank">The C# Cheatsheet</a></p></div></div><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/languages/javascript.js" target="_blank"><img src="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/components/BaseCheatsheet/javascript.jpg"></a></p><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/languages/javascript.js" target="_blank">The JavaScript Cheatsheet</a></p></div></div><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/languages/php.php" target="_blank"><img src="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/components/BaseCheatsheet/php.jpg"></a></p><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/languages/php.php" target="_blank">The PHP Cheatsheet</a></p></div></div></div></section><section><div><p><span>02. Backend</span></p><hr></div><div><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/backend/django.py" target="_blank"><img src="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/components/BaseCheatsheet/django.jpg"></a></p><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/backend/django.py" target="_blank">The Django Cheatsheet</a></p></div></div><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/backend/feathers.js" target="_blank"><img src="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/components/BaseCheatsheet/feathers.jpg"></a></p><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/backend/feathers.js" target="_blank">The Feathers.js Cheatsheet</a></p></div></div><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/backend/laravel.php" target="_blank"><img src="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/components/BaseCheatsheet/laravel.jpg"></a></p><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/backend/laravel.php" target="_blank">The Laravel Cheatsheet</a></p></div></div><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/backend/moleculer.js" target="_blank"><img src="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/components/BaseCheatsheet/moleculer.jpg"></a></p><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/backend/moleculer.js" target="_blank">The Moleculer Cheatsheet</a></p></div></div><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/backend/node.js" target="_blank"><img src="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/components/BaseCheatsheet/node.jpg"></a></p><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/backend/node.js" target="_blank">The Node.js Cheatsheet</a></p></div></div><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/backend/sails.js" target="_blank"><img src="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/components/BaseCheatsheet/sails.jpg"></a></p><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/backend/sails.js" target="_blank">The Sails.js Cheatsheet</a></p></div></div></div></section><section><div><p><span>03. Frontend</span></p><hr></div><div><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/frontend/angularjs.js" target="_blank"><img src="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/components/BaseCheatsheet/angularjs.jpg"></a></p><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/frontend/angularjs.js" target="_blank">The Angular.js Cheatsheet</a></p></div></div><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/frontend/angular.js" target="_blank"><img src="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/components/BaseCheatsheet/angular.jpg"></a></p><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/frontend/angular.js" target="_blank">The Angular 2+ Cheatsheet</a></p></div></div><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/frontend/ember.js" target="_blank"><img src="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/components/BaseCheatsheet/ember.jpg"></a></p><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/frontend/ember.js" target="_blank">The Ember.js Cheatsheet</a></p></div></div><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/frontend/html5.html" target="_blank"><img src="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/components/BaseCheatsheet/html5.jpg"></a></p><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/frontend/html5.html" target="_blank">The HTML5 Cheatsheet</a></p></div></div><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/frontend/react.js" target="_blank"><img src="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/components/BaseCheatsheet/react.jpg"></a></p><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/frontend/react.js" target="_blank">The React.js Cheatsheet</a></p></div></div><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/frontend/vue.js" target="_blank"><img src="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/components/BaseCheatsheet/vue.jpg"></a></p><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/frontend/vue.js" target="_blank">The Vue.js Cheatsheet</a></p></div></div></div></section><section><div><p><span>04. Databases</span></p><hr></div><div><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/databases/redis.sh" target="_blank"><img src="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/components/BaseCheatsheet/redis.jpg"></a></p><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/databases/redis.sh" target="_blank">The Redis Cheatsheet</a></p></div></div></div></section><section><div><p><span>05. Tools</span></p><hr></div><div><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/tools/docker.sh" target="_blank"><img src="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/components/BaseCheatsheet/docker.jpg"></a></p><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/tools/docker.sh" target="_blank">The Docker Cheatsheet</a></p></div></div><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/tools/kubernetes.sh" target="_blank"><img src="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/components/BaseCheatsheet/kubernetes.jpg"></a></p><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/tools/kubernetes.sh" target="_blank">The Kubernetes Cheatsheet</a></p></div></div><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/tools/vim.txt" target="_blank"><img src="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/components/BaseCheatsheet/vim.jpg"></a></p><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/tools/vim.txt" target="_blank">The VIM Cheatsheet</a></p></div></div><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/tools/xcode.txt" target="_blank"><img src="https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets//images/components/BaseCheatsheet/xcode.jpg"></a></p><div><p><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/tools/xcode.txt" target="_blank">The Xcode Cheatsheet</a></p></div></div></div></section></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26056968</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:34:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Making Sense of the Audio Stack on Unix]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 152 | Comments 78 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26056588">thread link</a>) | @zdw
<br/>
February 7, 2021 | https://venam.nixers.net/blog/unix/2021/02/07/audio-stack.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://venam.nixers.net/blog/unix/2021/02/07/audio-stack.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <article>
    <p><img src="https://venam.nixers.net/blog/assets/audio_unix/gramophone_player.jpg" alt="Come see my magical gramophone" loading="lazy"></p>

<p>Audio on Unix is a little zoo, there are so many acronyms for projects
and APIs that it’s easy to get lost. Let’s tackle that issue! Most
articles are confusing because they either use audio technical jargon,
or because they barely scratch the surface and leave people clueless. A
little knowledge can be dangerous.<br>
In this article I’ll try to bridge the gap by not requiring any
prerequisite knowledge while also giving a good overview of the whole Unix
audio landscape. There’s going to be enough details to remove mysticism
(Oh so pernicious in web bubbles) and see how the pieces fit.</p>

<p>By the end of this article you should understand the following terms:</p>
<ul>
  <li>ALSA</li>
  <li>OSS</li>
  <li>ESD</li>
  <li>aRts</li>
  <li>sndio</li>
  <li>PulseAudio</li>
  <li>PipeWire</li>
  <li>GStreamer</li>
  <li>LADSPA</li>
</ul>

<p>We’ll try to make sense of their utility and their link. The article
will focus a bit more on the Linux stack as it is has more components than
others and is more advanced in that respect. We’ll also skip non-open
source Unix-like systems.<br>
As usual, if you want to go in depth there’s a list of references at
the bottom.</p>

<p>Overall, we got:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Hardware layer: the physical devices, input and output</li>
  <li>Kernel layer: interfacing with the different hardware and managing
their specificities (ALSA, OSS)</li>
  <li>Libraries: used by software to interface with the hardware directly,
to manipulate audio/video, to interface with an intermediate layer
for creating streams (GStreamer, Libcanberra, libpulse, libalsa, etc..),
and to have a standard format (LADSPA).</li>
  <li>Sound servers: used to make the user facing (user-level) interaction
easier, more abstract, and high level. This often acts as glue, resolving
the issue that different software speak different protocols. (PulseAudio,
ESD, aRts, PipeWire, sndio)</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Table of Content</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="#hardware-layer">Hardware layer</a></li>
  <li><a href="#analog-to-digital--digital-to-analog-adc--dac">Analog to Digital &amp; Digital to Analog (ADC &amp; DAC)</a></li>
  <li><a href="#libraries">Libraries</a></li>
  <li><a href="#audio-driver">Audio Driver</a>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="#advanced-linux-sound-architecture-alsa">Advanced Linux Sound Architecture (ALSA)</a></li>
      <li><a href="#open-sound-system-oss-and-sada">Open Sound System (OSS) and SADA</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#sound-servers">Sound Servers</a>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="#sndio">sndio</a></li>
      <li><a href="#arts-analog-real-time-synthesizer-and-esd-or-esound-enlightened-sound-daemon">aRts (analog Real time synthesizer) and ESD or ESounD (Enlightened Sound Daemon)</a></li>
      <li><a href="#pulseaudio">PulseAudio</a></li>
      <li><a href="#jack">JACK</a></li>
      <li><a href="#pipewire">PipeWire</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#its-the-same-on-all-os---conclusion">It’s The Same On All OS - Conclusion</a></li>
  <li><a href="#references">References</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Let me preface this by saying that I am not a developer in any of these
tech, neither am I a sound engineer. I am simply regrouping my general
understanding of the tech so that anyone can get an overview of what
the pieces involved are, and maybe a bit more.</p>



<p>It’s essential to have a look at the hardware at our disposal to
understand the audio stack because anything above it will be its direct
representation.<br>
There are many types of audio interfaces, be it input or output,
with different varieties of sound cards, internal organizations,
and capabilities.
Because of this diversity of chipsets, it’s simpler to group them into
families when interacting with them.</p>

<p>Let’s list the most common logical components that these cards can have.</p>

<ul>
  <li>An interface to communicate with the card connected to the bus, be it
interrupts, IO ports, DMA (direct memory access), etc..</li>
  <li>Output devices (DAC: Digital to analog converter)</li>
  <li>Input devices  (ADC: Analog to digital converter)</li>
  <li>An output amplifier, to raise the strength of output devices</li>
  <li>An input amplifier, same as above but for input devices (ex:
microphones).</li>
  <li>Controls mechanism to allow different settings</li>
  <li>Hardware mixer, which controls each devices volume and routing,
usually volume is measured in decibel.</li>
  <li>A MIDI (Musical Instrument Digital Interface) device/controller, a
standard unified protocol to control output devices (called
synthesizers) — think of them like keyboards for sounds.</li>
  <li>A sequencer, a builtin MIDI synthesizer (output of the above)</li>
  <li>A timer used to clock audio</li>
  <li>Any other special features such as a 3D spatializer</li>
</ul>

<p>It is important to have a glance at these components because everything
in the software layers attempts to make them easier to approach.</p>



<p>A couple of concepts related to the interaction between the real
and digital world are also needed to kick-start our journey.</p>

<p>In the real world, the analog world, sound is made up of waves, which
are air pressures that can be arbitrarily large.</p>

<p>Speakers generating sound have a maximum volume/amplitude, usually
represented by 0dB (decibels). Volume lower than the maximum is
represented by negative decibels: -10dB, -20dB, etc.. And no sound is
thus -∞ dB.<br>
This might be surprising and actually not really true either. Decibel
doesn’t mean much until it’s tied to a specific absolute reference
point, it’s a relative scale. You pick a value for 0dB that makes sense
for what you are trying to measure.</p>

<p><img src="https://venam.nixers.net/blog/assets/audio_unix/VU_meter.jpg" alt="vu meter" loading="lazy"></p>

<p>The measurement above is the dBFS, the dB relative to digital full-scale,
aka digital 0. There are other measurements such as dB SPL and dBV.<br>
One thing to note about decibels is that they follow a strictly
exponential law , which matches it to human perception. What sounds like
a constantly increasing volume is indicated by a constantly rising dB
meter, corresponding to an exponentially rising output power. This is why
you can hear both vanishingly soft sounds and punishingly loud sounds.
The step from the loudest you can hear up to destroying your ears or
killing you is only a few more dB.</p>

<p>While decibels are about loudness, the tone is represented as sine
waves of certain frequency, the speed. For example, the note A is a
440Hz sine wave.</p>

<p>Alright, we got the idea of decibel and tone but how do we get from
waves to our computer or in reverse? This is what we call going from
analog to digital or digital to analog.<br>
To do this we have to convert waves into discrete points in time,
taking samples per second — what we call sample rate. The higher the
sample rate, the more accurate the representation of the analog sound (a
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lollipop_graph">lollipop graph</a>). Each
sample has a certain accuracy, how much information we store in it,
the number of bits for each sample — what we call the bit rate (the
higher the less noise). For example, CDs use 16 bits.<br>
Which value you choose as your sample rate and bit rate will depend on
a trade-off between quality and memory use.</p>

<p><em>NB</em>: That’s why it makes no sense to convert from digital low sample
rate to digital high sample rate, you’ll just be filling the void in
the middle of the discrete points with the same data.</p>

<p>Additionally, you may need to represent how multiple channels play sound
— multichannel. For example, mono, stereo, 3d, surround, etc..</p>

<p>It’s important to note that if we want to play sounds from multiple
sources at the same time, they will need to agree on the sample rate,
bit rate, and format representation, otherwise it’ll be impossible to
mix them. That’s something essential on a desktop.</p>

<p>The last part in this equation is how to implement the mechanism to
send audio to the sound card. That highly depends on what the card
itself supports, but the usual simple mechanism is to fill buffers with
streams of sound, then let the hardware read the samples, passing them
to the DAC (digital to analog converter), to then reach the speaker,
and vice versa. Once the hardware has read enough samples it’ll do an
interrupt to notify the software side that it needs more samples. This
cyclic mechanism goes on and on in a ring fashion.<br>
If the buffer samples aren’t filled fast enough we call this an underrun
or drop-out (aka xruns), which result in a glitch, basically audio
stopping for a short period before the buffer is filled again.</p>

<p>The audio can be played at a certain sample rate, with a certain
granularity, as we’ve said. So if we call <code>buffer-size</code> the number of
samples that can be contained in a cyclic-buffer meant to be read by
the hardware, <code>fragment-size</code> or <code>period-size</code> the number of samples
after which an interrupt is generated, <code>number-fragments</code> the number of
fragments that can fit in a hardware buffer (<code>buffer-size/fragment-size</code>),
and <code>sample-rate</code> the number of samples per seconds.<br>
Then the latency will be <code>buffer-size/sample-rate</code>, for example if we
can fit 100 samples in a buffer and the samples are played once every
1ms then that’s a 100ms latency; we’ll have to wait 100ms before the
hardware finishes processing the buffer.<br>
From the software side, we’ll be getting an interrupt every
<code>period-size/sample-rate</code>. Thus, if our <code>buffer-size</code> is 1024 samples, and
<code>fragment-size</code> is 512, and our <code>sample-rate</code> is <code>44100 samples/second</code>,
then we get an interrupt and need to refill the buffer every <code>512/44100
= 11.6 ms</code>, and our latency for this stage is up to <code>1024/44100 = 23
ms</code>. Audio processing pipelines consist of a series of buffers like this,
with samples read from one buffer, processed as needed, and written to
the next.</p>

<p>Choosing the values of the <code>buffer-size</code> and <code>period-size</code> are hard
questions. We need a buffer big enough to minimize underruns, but we also
need a buffer small enough to have low latency. The fragments should
be big enough to avoid frequent interrupts, but we also need them small
enough so that we’re able to fill the buffer and avoid underruns.<br>
What some software choose to do is to not follow the sound card
interrupts but to rely on the operating system scheduler instead,
to be able to rewrite the buffer at any time so that it stays
responsive to user input (aka buffer rewinding). This in turn allows
to make the buffer as big as possible. Though, <a href="https://venam.nixers.net/blog/unix/2020/05/02/time-on-unix.html">timers often
deviate</a>,
but that can be fixed with good real-time scheduling.<br>
There are no optimal solutions to this problem, it will depend on
requirements, and these values can often be configured.</p>

<p>So we’ve seen how sound is represented in the real world with strength and
tone, to then be converted in the digital world via digital to analog DAC
or analog to digital ADC converters. This is done by taking samples at
a rate and of a certain accuracy called the bit rate. There can also be
other information needed such as the channel, byte ordering, etc.. Sound
that needs to be mixed needs to agree on these properties. Lastly, we’ve
seen how software has to manage a buffer of samples so that sound plays
continuously on the device, while also being responsive to users.</p>



<p>Audio related libraries seem to be an alphabet soup of keywords. Here are</p></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://venam.nixers.net/blog/unix/2021/02/07/audio-stack.html">https://venam.nixers.net/blog/unix/2021/02/07/audio-stack.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://venam.nixers.net/blog/unix/2021/02/07/audio-stack.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26056588</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 17:46:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Web Spectrogram using your Mic]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 45 | Comments 18 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26056350">thread link</a>) | @sova
<br/>
February 7, 2021 | https://borismus.github.io/spectrogram/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://borismus.github.io/spectrogram/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://borismus.github.io/spectrogram/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26056350</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 17:12:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Art of Picking Intel Registers (2003)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 75 | Comments 48 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26055703">thread link</a>) | @Tomte
<br/>
February 7, 2021 | http://www.swansontec.com/sregisters.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.swansontec.com/sregisters.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">

<p><i>I wrote this article for an online magazine called <a href="http://www.scenerep.org/scenezine/issue12.php">Scene Zine</a>. Scene Zine caters to the Demo Scene, which is an digital art community dedicated to pushing the limits of computers through a mix of music, art, and computer programming. A particular category of demoscene productions, 4K intros, focus on the final production's raw file size. The goal is to put as much high-quality music, graphics, and animation as possible into only 4096 bytes. Doing this requires highly-specialized size optimization techniques, since 4096 bytes is less space than two pages of typed text or a true-color Windows XP icon. This article discusses some of these techniques.</i></p>

<p>Some people have commented that they want to see more expert programming articles in Scene Zine. To remedy the situation, this article is for all assembly language programmers out there. It discusses the fine art of picking which registers to use in your code. This information should simplify your coding and help you write smaller routines.</p>

<p>When the engineers at Intel designed the original 8086 processor, they had a
special purpose in mind for each register. As they designed the instruction
set, they created many optimizations and special instructions based on the
function they expected each register to perform. Using registers according to
Intel's original plan allows the code to take full advantage of these
optimizations. Unfortunately, this seems to be a lost art. Few coders are aware
of Intel's overall design, and most compilers are too the simplistic or focused
on execution speed to use the registers properly. Understanding how the
registers and instruction set fit together, however, is an important step on
the road to effortless size-coding.</p>

<p>Using the registers consistently has other advantages besides size
optimization. Like using good variable names, using consistent registers makes
code more readable. When they are used properly, the registers have meanings
almost as clear as the loop counter, <var>i</var>, in higher-level languages. In fact, I
occasionally name my variables in C after x86 registers because the register
names are so descriptive. With proper register use, x86 assembler can be almost
as self-documenting as a high-level language.</p>

<p>Another benefit that consistent register use brings is better compression. In
productions which use a compressor to pack the final build, such as 4K intros,
creating more redundant code leads to smaller packed sizes. When code uses
registers consistently, the same instruction sequences begin to appear over and
over. This, in turn, improves the compression ratio.</p>

<p>As a review, all x86-family CPU's have 8 general-purpose registers. The
registers are 32 bits wide, although 16-bit versions are also accessible with a
special one-byte instruction prefix. In 16-bit mode, the situation is reversed.
The lower 16 bits are accessible by default, and the full registers are
accessible only with a prefix byte.</p>

<p>Each register name is really an acronym. This is true even for the
"alphabetical" registers EAX, EBX, ECX, and EDX. The following list shows the
register names and their meanings:</p>

<ul>
<li>EAX - Accumulator Register</li>
<li>EBX - Base Register</li>
<li>ECX - Counter Register</li>
<li>EDX - Data Register</li>
<li>ESI - Source Index</li>
<li>EDI - Destination Index</li>
<li>EBP - Base Pointer</li>
<li>ESP - Stack Pointer</li>
</ul>

<p>In addition to the full-sized general registers, the x86 processor also has
eight byte-sized registers. Since these registers map directly into EAX, EBX,
ECX, and EDX, most people view them as parts of the larger registers. From the
instruction set point of view, however, the 8-bit registers are separate
entities. For example, the CL and CH registers share none of the ECX register's
useful properties. Except for AL and AH, none of the 8-bit registers have any
special significance in the instruction set, so this article does not mention
them.</p>

<h3>EAX: The Accumulator</h3>

<p>There are three major processor architectures: register, stack, and
accumulator. In a register architecture, operations such as addition or
subtraction can occur between any two arbitrary registers. In a stack
architecture, operations occur between the top of the stack and other items on
the stack. In an accumulator architecture, the processor has single calculation
register called the accumulator. All calculations occur in the accumulator, and
the other registers act as simple data storage locations.</p>

<p>Obviously, the x86 processor does not have an accumulator architecture. It
does, however, have an accumulator-like register: EAX / AL. Although most
calculations can occur between any two registers, the instruction set gives the
accumulator special preference as a calculation register. For example, all nine
basic operations (ADD, ADC, AND, CMP, OR, SBB, SUB, TEST, and XOR) have special
one-byte opcodes for operations between the accumulator and a constant.
Specialized operations, such as multiplication, division, sign extension, and
BCD correction can only occur in the accumulator.</p>

<p>Since most calculations occur in the accumulator, the x86 architecture contains
many optimized instructions for moving data in and out of this register. To
start, the processor has sixteen byte-sized XCHG opcodes for swapping data
between the accumulator and any other register. These aren't terribly useful,
but they show how strongly the Intel engineers preferred the accumulator over
the other registers. For them, it was better to swap data into the accumulator
to than to work with it where it was. Other instructions that move data in and
out of the accumulator are LODS, STOS, IN, OUT, INS, OUTS, SCAS, and XLAT.
Finally, the MOV instruction has a special one-byte opcode for moving data into
the accumulator from a constant memory location.</p>

<p>In your code, try to perform as much work in the accumulator as possible. As
you will see, the remaining seven general-purpose registers exist primarily to
support the calculation occurring in the accumulator.</p>

<h3>EDX: The Data Register</h3>

<p>Of the seven remaining general-purpose registers, the data register, EDX, is
most closely tied to the accumulator. Instructions that deal with over sized
data items, such as multiplication, division, CWD, and CDQ, store the most
significant bits in the data register and the least significant bits in the
accumulator. In a sense, the data register is the 64-bit extension of the
accumulator. The data register also plays a part in IO instructions. In this
case, the accumulator holds the data to read or write from the port, and the
data register holds the port address.</p>

<p>In your code, the data register is most useful for storing data related to the
accumulator's calculation. In my experience, most calculations need only these
two registers for storage if they are written properly.</p>

<h3>ECX: The Count Register</h3>

<p>The count register, ECX, is the x86 equivalent of the ubiquitous variable i.
Every counting-related instruction in the x86 uses ECX. The most obvious
counting instructions are LOOP, LOOPZ, and LOOPNZ. Another counter-based
instruction is JCXZ, which, as the name implies, jumps when the counter is 0.
The count register also appears in some bit-shift operations, where it holds
the number of shifts to perform. Finally, the count register controls the
string instructions through the REP, REPE, and REPNE prefixes. In this case,
the count register determines the maximum number of times the operation will
repeat.</p>

<p>Particularly in demos, most calculations occur in a loop. In these situations,
ECX is the logical choice for the loop counter, since no other register has so
many branching operations built around it. The only problem is that this
register counts downward instead of up as in high level languages. Designing a
downward-counting is not hard, however, so this is only a minor difficulty.</p>

<h3>EDI: The Destination Index</h3>

<p>Every loop that generates data must store the result in memory, and doing so
requires a moving pointer. The destination index, EDI, is that pointer. The
destination index holds the implied write address of all string operations. The
most useful string instruction, remarkably enough, is the seldom-used STOS.
STOS copies data from the accumulator into memory and increments the
destination index. This one-byte instruction is perfect, since the final result
of any calculation should be in the accumulator anyhow, and storing results in
a moving memory address is a common task.</p>

<p>Many coders treat the destination index as no more than extra storage space.
This is a mistake. All routines must store data, and some register must serve
as the storage pointer. Since the destination index is designed for this job,
using it for extra storage is a waste. Use the stack or some other register for
storage, and use EDI as your global write pointer.</p>

<h3>ESI: The Source Index</h3>

<p>The source index, ESI, has the same properties as the destination index. The
only difference is that the source index is for reading instead of writing.
Although all data-processing routines write, not all read, so the source index
is not as universally useful. When the time comes to use it, however, the
source index is just as powerful as the destination index, and has the same
type of instructions.</p>

<p>In situations where your code does not read any sort of data, of course, using
the source index for convenient storage space is acceptable.</p>

<h3>ESP and EBP: The Stack Pointer and the Base Pointer</h3>

<p>Of the eight general purpose registers, only the stack pointer, ESP, and the
base pointer, EBP, are widely used for their original purpose. These two
registers are the heart of the x86 function-call mechanism. When a block of
code calls a function, it pushes the parameters and the return address on the
stack. Once inside, function sets the base pointer equal to the stack pointer
and then places its own internal variables on the stack. From that point on,
the function refers to its parameters and variables relative to the base
pointer rather than the stack pointer. Why not the stack pointer? For some
reason, the stack pointer lousy addressing …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://www.swansontec.com/sregisters.html">http://www.swansontec.com/sregisters.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.swansontec.com/sregisters.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26055703</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 15:39:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Frontex Files]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 195 | Comments 82 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26055440">thread link</a>) | @ruph123
<br/>
February 7, 2021 | https://frontexfiles.eu/en.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://frontexfiles.eu/en.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000"><b>Name</b></span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000"><b>Meeting</b></span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000"><b>Date of meeting</b></span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000"><b>Type of body</b></span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000"><b>Document source</b></span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000"><b>Name of document</b></span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000"><b>Type of document</b></span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">eu-LISA</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">EU body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Croatia</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Finland</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Estonia</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Lithuania</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Iceland</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Germany</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Slovakia</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Slovenia</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Netherlands</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Austria</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Norway</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Bulgaria</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Luxembourg</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Poland</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Latvia</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Romania</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Czech Republic</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Italy</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Portugal</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Switzerland</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Belgium</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Sweden</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Hungary</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">France</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Denmark</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Greece</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Workshop with Industry on Border Control Devices and Systems for Entry/Exit</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43383" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43383</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 3</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">b-Outcome(1)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Meeting report</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Australian Government</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">9-10 October 2019 - International Conference on Biometrics for Borders</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43718" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43718</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body (non-EU)</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 1</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Conf programme 2 - International Conference on Biometrics for Borders</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Agenda</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">DG HOME</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">9-10 October 2019 - International Conference on Biometrics for Borders</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43718" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43718</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">EU body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 1</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Conf programme 2 - International Conference on Biometrics for Borders</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Agenda</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Dutch Ministry of the Interior and KIngdom Relation</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">9-10 October 2019 - International Conference on Biometrics for Borders</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43718" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43718</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 1</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Conf programme 2 - International Conference on Biometrics for Borders</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Agenda</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Dutch Vehicle Authority</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">9-10 October 2019 - International Conference on Biometrics for Borders</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43718" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43718</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 1</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Conf programme 2 - International Conference on Biometrics for Borders</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Agenda</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">German Federal Criminal Police</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">9-10 October 2019 - International Conference on Biometrics for Borders</span></td>
																	<td sdval="43718" sdnum="1033;"><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">43718</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Public body</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Batch 1</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Conf programme 2 - International Conference on Biometrics for Borders</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Agenda</span></td>
																</tr>
																<tr>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">Join Research Center</span></td>
																	<td><span face="Times New Roman" color="#000000">9-10 October 2019 - International Conference on …</span></td></tr></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://frontexfiles.eu/en.html">https://frontexfiles.eu/en.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://frontexfiles.eu/en.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26055440</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 14:59:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Performance Impact of Ad Blockers (2020)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 159 | Comments 65 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26054460">thread link</a>) | @DyslexicAtheist
<br/>
February 7, 2021 | https://www.debugbear.com/blog/2020-chrome-extension-performance-report#performance-impact-of-ad-blockers | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.debugbear.com/blog/2020-chrome-extension-performance-report#performance-impact-of-ad-blockers">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  
  <div>
    <div>
    
      
      

      

      <div>
        
        

        <p>I tested how the 1000 most popular Chrome extensions affect browser performance.</p>
<p>The main metrics I'll consider are CPU consumption, memory consumption, and whether the extension makes pages render more slowly.</p>
<p>Here's a <a href="https://www.debugbear.com/chrome-extension-performance-lookup">list of all tested extensions and their results</a>.</p>
<p><em>Update 8 July 2020: I originally reported the simulated FCP metric provided by Lighthouse rather than the First Contentful Paint observed in the browser. I've now updated the charts and the list of extensions.</em></p>
<p><strong>Outline</strong></p>
<p><a href="#performance-impact-of-the-top-100-extensions">Top 100</a><br>
<a href="#performance-impact-of-the-top-1000-extensions">Top 1000</a><br>
<a href="#performance-impact-of-ad-blockers">Ad blockers</a><br>
<a href="#performance-impact-of-the-top-100-developer-tools">Developer Tools</a><br>
<a href="#grammarly-and-honey">Grammarly and Honey</a><br>
<a href="#what-can-extension-developers-do-to-keep-their-extensions-fast">Tips for extension developers</a><br>
<a href="#conclusion">Conclusion</a></p>
<h2 id="performance-impact-of-the-top-100-extensions">Performance impact of the Top 100 extensions</h2>
<p>Let’s start by looking at the 100 most used Chrome extensions. Each of these has been installed more than 2 million times.</p>
<p>We’ll look at four different metrics:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Page CPU time</strong> How long is the page main thread busy for, and what is it doing?</li>
<li><strong>Page rendering delays</strong> How long does it take until the page displays some content?</li>
<li><strong>Background CPU time</strong> How much processing does the extension do in the background?</li>
<li><strong>Browser memory consumption</strong> How much memory do different components of the browser use?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="page-cpu-usage">Page CPU Usage</h3>
<p>JavaScript execution or running layout logic blocks the browser main thread. This means the browser can’t respond to user interactions.</p>
<p>If no extension is installed loading example.com takes around 40ms of CPU time. If you’ve installed Evernote or Grammarly this jumps to over 500ms.</p>
<p>This chart shows the 20 slowest extensions out of the 100 most used Chrome extensions. The other 80 all add less than 100ms of additional CPU time to the page.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.debugbear.com/public/blog/2020-chrome-extension-performance-report/chrome-extension-page-cpu-time.png" alt="On-page CPU time by Chrome extension, Top 100"></p>
<p>Rather than targeting specific sites, these extensions add code to every page opened by the user. Let’s take a look at what some of they are doing.</p>
<h4 id="evernote-web-clipper">Evernote Web Clipper</h4>
<p>The Evernote extension has over 4 million users. It adds a 2.9MB content script to every page. 140ms are spent just parsing and compiling that code.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.debugbear.com/public/blog/2020-chrome-extension-performance-report/evernote-page-trace.png" alt="Evernote trace showing code being parsed, compiled, and executed"></p>
<p>Once the bundle has been loaded it needs to be evaluated, which takes another 300ms.</p>
<p>Does this code actually do anything? As far as I can tell, no, not unless the user clicks the Evernote extension icon.</p>
<p>The code does set up an event listener that’s fired when the user clicks the icon, but this can be done without loading the full JavaScript bundle.</p>
<h4 id="grammarly-clever-avira-password-manager-skype">Grammarly, Clever, Avira Password Manager, Skype</h4>
<p>This pattern of loading large amounts of unnecessary code repeats with other Chrome extensions.</p>

<table id="chrome-extension-cpu-table">
  <thead>
  <tr>
   <th>Extension
   </th>
   <th>Page Script Size
   </th>
   <th>Page CPU Time
   </th>
  </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody><tr>
   <td>No Extension
   </td>
   <td>0MB
   </td>
   <td>42ms
   </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>Evernote Web Clipper
   </td>
   <td>2.9MB
   </td>
   <td>559ms
   </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>Grammarly
   </td>
   <td>1.3MB
   </td>
   <td>507ms
   </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>Clever
   </td>
   <td>2.6MB
   </td>
   <td>335ms
   </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>Avira Password Manager
   </td>
   <td>1.5MB
   </td>
   <td>405ms
   </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>LastPass
   </td>
   <td>0.8MB
   </td>
   <td>241ms
   </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>Skype
   </td>
   <td>1.5MB
   </td>
   <td>191ms
   </td>
  </tr>
</tbody></table>

<p>Extensions often need to inject code into every page, rather than only targeting certain domains. Password managers need to check if there's a login form. Spell checkers need to look for text fields.</p>
<p>However, for performance it would be much better if the code that checks the relevant conditions was separated from the primary functionality of the extension. Then most of the code would only be loaded when necessary. Honey made this change last year and it <a href="#grammarly-and-honey">greatly reduced their performance impact</a>.</p>
<p>Interestingly, Skype only adds 150ms of CPU time, even though it has a large JavaScript bundle. My guess is that this is due to the code mostly consisting of static configuration objects and long strings that are easy to parse and evaluate.</p>
<h4 id="ghostery">Ghostery</h4>
<p>I was surprised to see Ghostery relatively high up in the list. Unlike the other extensions it actually does something on the page, namely displaying how many trackers were blocked.</p>
<p>Ghostery loads 160KB of JavaScript and adds 120ms of CPU time –&nbsp;not a huge amount. However some of this code is render-blocking, as we’ll see in the next section.</p>
<h3 id="page-rendering-delays">Page rendering delays</h3>
<p>While extra CPU time means the page isn’t interactive for some time, this doesn’t normally completely block the page from rendering. To see if an extension blocks rendering we can look at the <a href="https://www.debugbear.com/docs/metrics/first-contentful-paint">First Contentful Paint</a> metric –&nbsp;when the browser starts to display text or images.</p>
<p>Most extensions introduce no or only minor rendering delays. This chart shows the extensions with the largest negative impact on initial content rendering.</p>
<p>Note that the FCP impact of Avira isn't caused by request blocking logic running in the background. We'll see what's going there in the next section.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.debugbear.com/public/blog/2020-chrome-extension-performance-report/extension-fcp.png" alt="Impact of Chrome extension on First Contentful Paint"></p>
<p>Chrome extensions can define scripts and stylesheets that should be injected into the page. By default these are added to the page once the page has finished loading and is idle.</p>
<p>However, extensions developers can decide to load these resources as soon as the page starts loading. For example, the Dark Reader extension changes website content to a dark theme. It would be jarring to first render pages in a bright theme and then suddenly transition. Here it makes sense to run the code before the page starts to render.</p>
<p>The amount of this code should be reduced to a minimum. The good news is that only 12 of the extensions in the chart cause a rendering delay of more than 100ms.</p>
<h4 id="clever-grammarly-rakuten-get-cash-back-for-shopping-last-pass">Clever, Grammarly, Rakuten Get Cash Back for Shopping, LastPass</h4>
<p>These extensions all run significant amounts of code before the page starts rendering. In the case of Clever, page content only starts showing 300ms later than without the extension installed.</p>
<h4 id="avg-avast-safe-price">AVG/Avast SafePrice</h4>
<p>While SafePrice doesn’t wait until the page is idle before injecting scripts, it does wait until the document has loaded. I'm not sure why, but somehow the JavaScript code still appears to run before the initial render.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.debugbear.com/public/blog/2020-chrome-extension-performance-report/safeprice-trace.png" alt="SafePrice Trace showing FCP after content scripts have run"></p>
<h3 id="background-cpu-usage">Background CPU Usage</h3>
<p>Not all processing that a browser extension does happens on a page that's visible to the user. Most Chrome extensions also have something called a background page which lets the extension do things like listen to network requests or update the extension icon.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.debugbear.com/public/blog/2020-chrome-extension-performance-report/background-page-cpu.png" alt="Background page CPU usage, with Avira spending alsmost 3s while Ghostery is a far-off second with 180ms"></p>
<p>Avira Browser Safety spends almost 3s running code in the background page, while all other extensions spend less than 200ms.</p>
<p>Background pages often run code in response to network requests made by the page that was opened by the user. The page from the previous test only makes one network requests, far less than normal. So I ran this test again, this time loading the Apple homepage, which makes around 50 requests.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.debugbear.com/public/blog/2020-chrome-extension-performance-report/background-page-cpu-apple.png" alt="Background page CPU usage when loading Apple homepage, Ghostery spend a bit over 1s"></p>
<p>Interestingly Avira is now significantly faster, 600ms instead of 2.7s! What’s going on?</p>
<p>The Avira Browser Safety extension contains a website allowlist with 30k+ regular expressions. When the user navigates to a new page Avira checks if the page URL is in that allowlist:</p>
<pre><code>{
  <span>key</span>: <span>"_isWhitelisted"</span>,
  <span>value</span>: <span><span>function</span> <span>_isWhitelisted</span>(<span>url</span>) </span>{
    <span>return</span> !!<span>this</span>._whitelist &amp;&amp; <span>this</span>._whitelist.some(<span><span>function</span> (<span>pattern</span>) </span>{
      <span>return</span> pattern.test(url);
    });
  }
}
</code></pre>
<p>Apple.com is in the allowlist, and because the list is sorted alphabetically the function quickly finishes. Example.com is not in the list, so the extension ends up checking the URL against all 30 thousand regex patterns.</p>
<h3 id="browser-memory-consumption">Browser memory consumption</h3>
<p>Chrome extensions can increase memory consumption, both in pages opened by the user and in the extension background page.</p>
<p>Again, Avira Browser Safety is at the top of the list, increasing memory consumption by 218MB. This is due to the 30k+ regular expressions –&nbsp;I think they are compiled to bytecode or machine code, which needs to be stored in memory.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.debugbear.com/public/blog/2020-chrome-extension-performance-report/top-100-extension-browser-memory-consumption.png" alt="Browser memory consumption –&nbsp;140MB with no extensions, many extensions raise that by 100-200MB"></p>
<p>Some background pages also contain iframes, for example the Amazon Assistant extension:</p>
<p><img src="https://www.debugbear.com/public/blog/2020-chrome-extension-performance-report/amazon-assistant-subframes.png" alt="DevTools Elements tab for Amazon Assistent background page showing multiple iframes"></p>
<p>An extension with a background page increases memory consumption by at least 10MB. If there’s no background page and only a small on-page script then an extension's the memory impact can be minimal.</p>
<h2 id="performance-impact-of-the-top-1000-extensions">Performance impact of the Top 1000 extensions</h2>
<p>Let’s look at some slightly less popular extensions with 100k+ users.</p>
<h3 id="page-cpu-usage-1">Page CPU Usage</h3>
<p>Previously Evernote had the greatest negative performance impact, increasing CPU times by 560ms. There are 9 extensions among the top 1000 with a greater negative impact than that.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.debugbear.com/public/blog/2020-chrome-extension-performance-report/page-cpu-top-1000.png" alt="Vigia de Preco and Snap &amp; Read both spend over 1s of one-page CPU time"></p>
<h4 id="vigia-de-preco">Vigia de Preço</h4>
<p>Vigia de Preço is a Brazilian coupon and price watching extension with 200k users. It blocks the main thread for 1.6s.</p>
<p>A big part of this is using <a href="https://github.com/Valve/fingerprintjs2">fingerprintjs2</a> to generate a token. For example, this involves rendering an image and generating a data URL for it, in order to detect if certain Canvas features are supported by the browser.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.debugbear.com/public/blog/2020-chrome-extension-performance-report/vigia-de-preco-trace.png" alt="Vigia de Preco Chrome trace showing fingerprinting"></p>
<h4 id="snap-amp-read">Snap &amp; Read</h4>
<p>Snap &amp; Read has over half a million users and helps them read and understand texts. On every page it loads a 3.8MB lexicon.js file, which is where most of the parse and compile time is spent. Parsing this would likely be much more efficient as a JSON file.</p>
<p>It then processes the lexicon and loads a bunch of libraries like <a href="https://github.com/spencermountain/compromise">compromise</a>, jQuery, pdfmake and citeproc. In total Snap &amp; Read loads 7.5MB of JavaScript code on every page.</p>
<h4 id="yi-ban-xiao-cha-jian">壹伴 · 小插件</h4>
<p>This is a Chinese Chrome extension with 300 thousand users. It seems mostly extend the WeChat web editor, but it loads 4MB of code on every page anyway.</p>
<h4 id="moz-bar">MozBar</h4>
<p>MozBar is an SEO tool with 700 thousand users. It doesn’t seem to do much unless you actually click the extension icon, but still runs 3MB of code.</p>
<h3 id="page-rendering-delays-1">Page rendering delays</h3>
<p>Do the additional processing block the page from rendering? Most of the time, no.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.debugbear.com/public/blog/2020-chrome-extension-performance-report/rendering-delays-top-1000.png" alt="FCP increase by Top 1000 Chrome extension"></p>
<p>壹伴 · 小插件 loads 14 content scripts that take over 700ms to process before the page rendering starts. Axe loads two content scripts worth 1.8MB before the page is rendered.</p>
<h3 id="background-cpu-usage-1">Background CPU Usage</h3>
<p>Looking at background pages, no other extension exceeds the additional processing introduced by Avira Browser Safety and Avira Safe Shopping.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.debugbear.com/public/blog/2020-chrome-extension-performance-report/top-1000-background-page-cpu.png" alt="Top 1000 Chrome extension background CPU consumption"></p>
<h4 id="traffic-light">TrafficLight</h4>
<p>Bitdefender TrafficLight is a security extension with 600k users. It checks request URLs against a list of several thousand criteria that might indicate a security issue. To do that it needs to iterate over that list and check if the current URL matches.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.debugbear.com/public/blog/2020-chrome-extension-performance-report/traffic-light-bg-cpu.png" alt="TrafficLight trace showing getRule, runRule, and runMetaRule"></p>
<h3 id="browser-memory-consumption-1">Browser memory consumption</h3>
<p>Interestingly, on a page without ads, ad blockers significantly increase browser memory consumption. This is mostly due to …</p></div></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.debugbear.com/blog/2020-chrome-extension-performance-report#performance-impact-of-ad-blockers">https://www.debugbear.com/blog/2020-chrome-extension-performance-report#performance-impact-of-ad-blockers</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.debugbear.com/blog/2020-chrome-extension-performance-report#performance-impact-of-ad-blockers</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26054460</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 12:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Things JRR Tolkien has never said, done, written or had anything to do with]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 131 | Comments 50 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26053846">thread link</a>) | @BerislavLopac
<br/>
February 7, 2021 | https://thetolkienist.com/things-j-r-r-tolkien-has-never-said-done-written-or-had-anything-to-do-with-an-on-going-series/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thetolkienist.com/things-j-r-r-tolkien-has-never-said-done-written-or-had-anything-to-do-with-an-on-going-series/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><article class="page"><div><p>A successful author such as J.R.R. Tolkien does have many admirers and even more people would like to use his popularity for their own ends, that is, they would like to cash in on the writer of some of the most popular stories in the history of mankind. They come up with brilliant ideas that there has to be some link between City A, Building B or Person C (which they usually happen to represent) and aforementioned author – and you, dear reader, should be making the most of this: Spend your money on it.</p><p>For some people it is just wishful thinking. As a Tolkienist I would love a many cities A, buildings B or persons C to have some sort of link to my favourite author but in the end I have to stick with the facts.</p><p>To show you the facts I will produce an on-going series of things J.R.R. Tolkien has never said, done, written or had anything to do with. I will try and provide you with articles to the best of my abilities and will always be open for correction – this is the point about research (when well done): be open to admit a mistake, correct it and let people know you corrected it.</p><p>1. <a title="Things J.R.R. Tolkien has never said, done, written or had anything to do with. An on-going series." href="https://thetolkienist.com/2013/02/27/how-to-misappropriate-a-gardening-picture-enter-clarence-elliott-exit-j-r-r-tolkien-tthnsdwohatdw-part-1/">How to misappropriate a gardening picture</a>. Enter: Clarence Elliott. Exit: J.R.R. Tolkien. TThnsdwohatdw, Part 1.</p><p>2. <a title="“Little by little, one travels far” is not a J.R.R. Tolkien quote. TThnsdwohatdw, Part 2." href="https://thetolkienist.com/2013/04/06/little-by-little-one-travels-far-is-not-a-j-r-r-tolkien-quote-tthnsdwohatdw-part-2/">“Little by little, one travels far”</a> is not a J.R.R. Tolkien quote. TThnsdwohatdw, Part 2.</p><p>3. <a title="&quot;A single dream is more powerful than a thousand realities&quot; is not a Tolkien quote" href="https://thetolkienist.com/2013/04/24/not-a-tolkien-quote-a-single-dream-is-more-powerful-than-a-thousand-realities-tthnsdwohatdw-part-3/">“A single dream is more powerful than a thousand realities”</a> is not a Tolkien quote. TThnsdwohatdw, Part 3.</p><p>4. <a title="“Not all those who wander are lost” – “All that is gold does not glitter” the right way" href="https://thetolkienist.com/2013/05/20/not-all-those-who-wander-are-lost-all-that-is-gold-does-not-glitter-the-right-way/">“Not all those who wander are lost” – “All that is gold does not glitter” the right way</a>. TThnsdwohatdw, Part 4.</p><p>5. <a title="How a hobby turns into a Hobbit in Cape Town" href="https://thetolkienist.com/2013/07/13/how-a-hobby-turns-into-a-hobbit-in-cape-town/">How a hobby turns into a Hobbit in Cape Town</a>. TThnsdwohatdw, Part 5.</p><p>6. <a title="Not a Tolkien quote: Fantasy is escapist, and that is its glory" href="https://thetolkienist.com/2014/01/03/not-a-tolkien-quote-fantasy-is-escapist-and-that-is-its-glory/" target="_blank">Fantasy is escapist, and that is its glory</a> is not a Tolkien quote. TThnsdwohatdw, Part 6.</p><p>7. <a title="Not a Tolkien quote: It simply isn't an adventure worth telling if there aren't any dragons" href="https://thetolkienist.com/2014/01/14/not-a-tolkien-quote-it-simply-isnt-an-adventure-worth-telling-if-there-arent-any-dragons/">It simply isn’t an adventure worth telling if there aren’t any dragons</a> is not a Tolkien quote. TThnsdwohatdw, Part 7.</p><p>8. <a title="Not a Tolkien quote: You can only come to the morning through the shadow" href="https://thetolkienist.com/2014/06/08/tolkien-quote-can-come-morning-shadow/">You can only come to the morning through the shadows</a> is not a Tolkien quote. TThnsdwohatdw, Part 8.</p><p>9. <a title="Not a Tolkien quote: Living by faith includes the call to something greater than cowardly self-preservation" href="https://thetolkienist.com/2014/06/21/tolkien-quote-living-faith-includes-call-something-greater-cowardly-self-preservation/">Living by faith includes the call to something greater than cowardly self-preservation</a> is not a Tolkien quote. TThnsdwohatdw, Part 9.</p></div></article></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thetolkienist.com/things-j-r-r-tolkien-has-never-said-done-written-or-had-anything-to-do-with-an-on-going-series/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26053846</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 09:42:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Full Automation Fallacy]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 66 | Comments 39 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26053760">thread link</a>) | @pabs3
<br/>
February 7, 2021 | https://futuresofwork.co.uk/2020/12/02/the-full-automation-fallacy/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://futuresofwork.co.uk/2020/12/02/the-full-automation-fallacy/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
	
		<article>
				               
			<p>We are at a critical moment, when digital technologies of automation, often referred to with buzzy vocabulary like “algorithms” and “AI,” are poised to transform work in a “Fourth Industrial Revolution.” Headlines scream about the imminent replacement of workers, often in language reminiscent of anti-immigrant rhetoric: robots are threatening to “take” or “steal” jobs. You can even go to the website willrobotstakemyjob.com and input specific occupations to get statistics on the likelihood of such theft. Writers have only a 3.8 percent chance—“totally safe”—while machinists face an alarming 65 percent. “Robots are watching,” the site cautions. These numbers are drawn from a widely cited 2013 report by economist Carl Benedikt Frey and computer scientist Michael A. Osborne that concluded 47 percent of total US employment would be automated by 2034.</p>
<p>Many writers on the radical left have accepted this framing of automation, while detourning its implications, making “full automation” central to the transcendence of capitalist exploitation. In <em>Inventing the Future</em>, Alex Williams and Nick Srnicek argue, “Without full automation, postcapitalist futures must necessarily choose between abundance at the expense of freedom (echoing the work-centricity of Soviet Russia) or freedom at the expense of abundance, represented by primitivist dystopias.” Aaron Bastani’s <em>Fully Automated Luxury Communism</em> pushes this idea to its limits, promising a future of boundless leisure for all, supplemented by a profusion of goods and services delivered sans human exploitation: “We will see more of the world than ever before, eat varieties of food we never have heard of, and lead lives equivalent—if we so wish—to those of today’s billionaires.”</p>
<p>Such a framing is both simple and attractive, especially to those of us trapped in dead-end jobs and eking out precarious existences; if robots, rather than we and our fellow workers, performed these tasks, and the productivity of technology were widely and equally dispersed, maybe we could spend our days doing more fulfilling activities than punching a clock. Like those cheesy banner ads that were all over the web in the late 2000s, you could have an egalitarian society with “one weird trick.” The bourgeoisie would hate this!</p>
<p>But Full Automators, whether dystopian or utopian, have a misguided approach to the question. According to historian Aaron Benanav, the specter of a postwork future has been conjured by anemic growth rates, not new technologies. Without radical change, our fate is further stagnation and crisis, not the world of the Jetsons. But new technologies certainly exist, and they are certainly doing, well, <em>something</em> to the work. But what?</p>
<p>Let’s start with a more basic question. What is automation? Machines have replicated and augmented human work processes for centuries, and that is often the colloquial use of “automation” in our current moment. But “automation” was not used to describe this process until 1947, when Delmar Harder, vice president of manufacturing at Ford Motor Company, created its Automation Department. The department’s engineers redesigned automobile production so that materials were automatically conveyed from one process to another, obviating the need for laborers to load and unload machines. Further, the process was itself increasingly machine-controlled, through a system of timers, switches, and relays—what technology historian David Hounsell calls the “electromechanical brain.”</p>
<p>Most of the technologies involved in automation had been developed and implemented in other industries years before their incorporation into Ford’s production process. What made automation new was its centrality to Ford’s manufacturing strategy, coming at a time of historic unrest among autoworkers, and in particular, on the heels of a costly twenty-four-day strike at Ford’s massive River Rouge plant in May of 1949. Not only would the new technologies dramatically reduce an unruly labor force, but they allowed Ford to decentralize its production away from the roiling unrest of Detroit as the company opened new automated factories, with new less militant employees, in Cleveland and Buffalo. Workers immediately perceived the threat, and automation was, from its inception, a deeply politicized issue. The history of automation reveals it as a political tool to subvert worker power, not simply an economic one to increase productivity.</p>
<p>Digging into the technical side of automation unearths more problems with the Full Automation Fallacy. David Autor, an economist, offers a useful corrective in his 2015 article “Why Are There Still So Many Jobs?,” its plaintive title a response to John Maynard Keynes’s Depression-era predictions of an automated future with a 15-hour work week. As Autor explains, rather than simply replace human jobs with machinic processes, automation affects labor in complex ways:</p>
<p>Changes in technology do alter the types of jobs available and what those jobs pay. In the last few decades, one noticeable change has been “polarization” of the labor market, in which wage gains went disproportionately to those at the top and at the bottom of the income and skill distribution, not to those in the middle.</p>
<p>Automation thus recomposes the workforce, isolating and rearranging tasks, altering job descriptions, and hollowing out middle-tier occupations.</p>
<p>Why does automation polarize instead of outright replace jobs? For one, many jobs require labor that is challenging to automate. Computers have to follow instructions laid out by programmers, so in order to substitute a computer for a worker, the worker’s tasks must be understood and articulated. However, much of the labor process is encompassed in tacit knowledge that workers are unable to articulate: “There are tasks for which neither computer programmers nor anyone else can enunciate the explicit ‘rules’ or procedures.” Even when tasks are known, automating them is easier said than done. On one end, computers cannot replicate the high levels of abstract thought required for managerial positions. On the other, jobs that require both manual work and flexibility, such as service sector jobs in food preparation and maintenance, are both difficult and cost-prohibitive to automate.</p>
<p>Take an example. In March 2018, Flippy, a burger-flipping robot, was rolled out at the Pasadena location of fast-food chain CaliBurger, to great fanfare and numerous headlines. The implication was clear: Would this humble machine spell the end of the fast-food job, the metonym for low-skilled entry-level occupations?</p>
<p>Not exactly. In an event that provoked far less press coverage, Flippy was retired after one day of work. CaliBurger’s owners took the honorable path of blaming Flippy’s failure on their human employees: workers, they explained, were simply too slow with tasks such as dressing the burgers, causing Flippy’s meaty achievements to pile up. However, a few discerning journalists had previously noted Flippy’s numerous errors in the relatively simple task that gave the robot its name. Flippy just wasn’t very good at its job. And so, yet another fully automated dream came crashing into messy reality.</p>
<p>According to Autor, the introduction of new kinds of information and control technology, such as what is currently hyped as “artificial intelligence,” supplements managerial work, and so increases the power and wages of bosses. On the other end, manual laborers (such as Flippy’s coworkers) see tasks eaten away and their movements reorganized and tightly controlled to make room for more rigid machines. Wages and working conditions deteriorate. But even then, automation stops short of “full”: such systems, as we will see, rely upon a stratum of human labor that is all but ineradicable. This is as true of Flippy as it is of the most powerful AI.</p>
<p>What do tend to be substitutable are not the lowest rungs, but those jobs requiring repetitive physical labor, as well as middle management jobs in operations. For example, Amazon’s warehouses use a software-directed system that coordinates human laborers, who select individual goods, with robots, who move large shelves. Algorithms replace middle-income jobs in managing the floor, leading to a polarized workforce of increasingly wealthy and powerful executives and programmers and increasingly degraded laborers who are substitutable not by machines, but by other humans; in other words, they are eminently replaceable.</p>
<p>But some have their targets set on precisely those positions in “knowledge work” that once promised a future safe from the robots. Technologists such as Kai-Fu Lee, former president of Google China, vow that white-collar jobs will go first. According to Lee, “The white collar jobs are easier to take because they’re purely a quantitative analytical process. Reporters, traders, telemarketing, telesales, customer service, analysts, they can all be replaced by software.”</p>
<p>But, of course, automation never completely erases human labor. Lee’s prediction of total replacement of knowledge work is a profound exaggeration, as a report by the think tank Data &amp; Society makes plain: “AI technologies reconfigure work practices rather than replace workers,” while at the same time, “automated and AI technologies tend to mask the human labor that allows them to be fully integrated into a social context while profoundly changing the conditions and quality of labor that is at stake.” Investigating grocery store self-checkout, researchers found that Luddite customers hated and avoided the technology. In response, management cut staff to make lines so unbearable that customers gave up and used the machines instead. Even then, cashiers were still required to assist and monitor transactions; rather than reduce workload, the technologies were “intensifying the work of customer service and creating new challenges.”</p>
<p>Self-checkout is an example of what technology journalist Brian Merchant calls “shitty automation”:</p>
<p>If …</p></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://futuresofwork.co.uk/2020/12/02/the-full-automation-fallacy/">https://futuresofwork.co.uk/2020/12/02/the-full-automation-fallacy/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://futuresofwork.co.uk/2020/12/02/the-full-automation-fallacy/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26053760</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 09:20:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A visual guide to SSH tunnels]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 861 | Comments 76 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26053323">thread link</a>) | @brendanfalk
<br/>
February 6, 2021 | https://robotmoon.com/ssh-tunnels/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://robotmoon.com/ssh-tunnels/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="app"><section data-v-4fc16f31="" id="introduction"><div data-v-4fc16f31=""><nav data-v-4fc16f31=""><ul data-v-4fc16f31=""><li data-v-4fc16f31=""><a data-v-4fc16f31="" href="#introduction">Introduction</a></li><li data-v-4fc16f31=""><a data-v-4fc16f31="" href="#port-forwarding">Port forwarding</a><ul data-v-4fc16f31=""><li data-v-4fc16f31=""><a data-v-4fc16f31="" href="#local-port-forwarding">Local</a></li><li data-v-4fc16f31=""><a data-v-4fc16f31="" href="#remote-port-forwarding">Remote</a></li><li data-v-4fc16f31=""><a data-v-4fc16f31="" href="#dynamic-port-forwarding">Dynamic</a></li></ul></li><li data-v-4fc16f31=""><a data-v-4fc16f31="" href="#jump-hosts">Jump hosts</a></li><li data-v-4fc16f31=""><a data-v-4fc16f31="" href="#reliable-ssh-tunnels">Reliable SSH tunnels</a></li><li data-v-4fc16f31=""><a data-v-4fc16f31="" href="#more-examples">More examples</a></li><li data-v-4fc16f31=""><a data-v-4fc16f31="" href="#resources">Resources</a></li></ul></nav><p data-v-4fc16f31="">This page explains use cases and examples of SSH tunnels while visually presenting
the traffic flows. For example, here's a reverse tunnel that allows only users from
IP address 1.2.3.4 access to port 80 on the SSH client through an SSH server.</p><p data-v-4fc16f31="">SSH tunnels are encrypted TCP connections between SSH clients and servers
that allows traffic entering one side of the tunnel to transparently exit
through the other. While the term originally referred to tunnels using TUN/TAP virtual
network interfaces, it's commonly used to refer to SSH port forwarding nowadays.
Use cases include:</p><ul data-v-4fc16f31=""><li data-v-4fc16f31="">Providing encrypted channels for protocols that use plaintext</li><li data-v-4fc16f31="">Opening backdoors into private networks</li><li data-v-4fc16f31="">Bypassing firewalls</li></ul><p data-v-4fc16f31="">This page is a work-in-progress. Feel free to&nbsp;<a data-v-4fc16f31="" href="https://github.com/linrock/ssh-tunnels">suggest examples or corrections on Github</a></p></div></section><section data-v-47beec60="" id="port-forwarding"><div data-v-47beec60=""><header data-v-47beec60=""><h2 data-v-47beec60="">Port forwarding</h2><h3 data-v-47beec60="">Forwards a port from one system (local or remote) to another</h3></header><div data-v-47beec60=""><h4 data-v-47beec60="">Local port forwarding</h4><p data-v-47beec60="">Local port forwarding allows you to forward traffic on the SSH client
to some destination through an SSH server. This lets you access
remote services over an encrypted connection as if they were local services.
Example use cases:</p><ul data-v-47beec60=""><li data-v-47beec60="">Accessing a remote service (redis, memcached, etc.) listening on internal IPs</li><li data-v-47beec60="">Locally accessing resources available on a private network</li><li data-v-47beec60="">Transparently proxying a request to a remote service</li></ul></div><div data-v-47beec60=""><h4 data-v-47beec60="">Remote port forwarding</h4><p data-v-47beec60="">Remote port forwarding allows you to forward traffic on an SSH server
to a destination through either the SSH client or another remote host.
This gives users on public networks access to resources on private networks.
Example use cases:</p><ul data-v-47beec60=""><li data-v-47beec60="">Making a local development server available over a public network</li><li data-v-47beec60="">Granting IP-restricted access to a remote resource on a private network</li></ul></div><div data-v-47beec60=""><h4 data-v-47beec60="">Dynamic port forwarding</h4><p data-v-47beec60="">Dynamic port forwarding opens a SOCKS proxy on the SSH client that lets
you forward TCP traffic through the SSH server to a remote host.</p></div><div data-v-47beec60=""><h4 data-v-47beec60="">Forwarding from privileged ports</h4><p data-v-47beec60="">If you want to open a privileged port (ports 1-1023) to forward traffic, you'll
need to run SSH with superuser privileges on the system that opens the port.</p><p><code data-v-47beec60="">sudo ssh -L 80:example.com:80 ssh-server</code></p></div><div data-v-47beec60=""><h4 data-v-47beec60="">SSH command-line flags</h4><p data-v-47beec60="">These are some useful SSH command-line flags when establishing tunnels</p><p><code data-v-47beec60="">-f
  # forks the ssh process into the background<br data-v-47beec60="">-n
  # prevents reading from STDIN<br data-v-47beec60="">-N
 # do not run remote commands. Used when only forwarding ports<br data-v-47beec60="">-T
 # disables TTY allocation</code></p><p data-v-47beec60="">Here's an example of a command you would run to create an SSH tunnel
in the background that forwards a local port through the ssh server.</p><p><code data-v-47beec60="">ssh -fnNT -L 127.0.0.1:8080:example.org:80 ssh-server</code></p><p data-v-47beec60="">For brevity, the examples below will leave out these command-line
flags.</p></div></div></section><section data-v-42eeae9a="" id="local-port-forwarding"><div data-v-42eeae9a=""><header data-v-42eeae9a=""><h2 data-v-42eeae9a="">Local port forwarding</h2><h3 data-v-42eeae9a="">Forwards connections from a port on a local system to a port on a remote host</h3></header><div data-v-42eeae9a=""><p><code data-v-42eeae9a="">ssh -L 127.0.0.1:8080:example.org:80 ssh-server</code></p><p data-v-42eeae9a="">Forwards connections to 127.0.0.1:8080 on your local system
to port 80 on example.org through ssh-server. The traffic between your
local system and ssh-server is wrapped in an SSH tunnel,
but the traffic between ssh-server and example.org is not.
From the perspective of example.org the traffic originates from
ssh-server.</p></div><div data-v-42eeae9a=""><p><code data-v-42eeae9a="">ssh -L 8080:example.org:80 ssh-server</code><code data-v-42eeae9a="">ssh -L *:8080:example.org:80 ssh-server</code></p><p data-v-42eeae9a="">Forwards connections to port 8080 on all interfaces on your local system
to example.org:80 through a tunnel to ssh-server.</p></div><div data-v-42eeae9a=""><p><code data-v-42eeae9a="">ssh -L 192.168.0.1:5432:127.0.0.1:5432 ssh-server</code></p><p data-v-42eeae9a="">Forwards connections to 192.168.0.1:5432 on your local system to
127.0.0.1:5432 on ssh-server. Note that 127.0.0.1 here is localhost
from the viewpoint of ssh-server.</p></div><div data-v-42eeae9a=""><h4 data-v-42eeae9a="">SSH configurations</h4><p data-v-42eeae9a="">Make sure that TCP forwarding is enabled on the SSH server. By default it should be.</p><p><code data-v-42eeae9a="">AllowTcpForwarding yes</code></p><p data-v-42eeae9a="">If you're forwarding ports on interfaces other than 127.0.0.1 then you'll
need to enable GatewayPorts on your local system, either within ssh_config or as
a command-line option</p><p><code data-v-42eeae9a="">GatewayPorts yes</code></p></div><h4 data-v-42eeae9a="">Use cases</h4><p data-v-42eeae9a="">If you want to use a secure connection to access a remote service
that communicates over plaintext. For example, redis and memcached
all use plaintext protocols. If you securely access one of these services
on a remote server over public networks, you can tunnel a connection
from your local system to the remote server instead of having it listen
over the public internet.</p></div></section><section data-v-63ab32db="" id="remote-port-forwarding"><div data-v-63ab32db=""><header data-v-63ab32db=""><h2 data-v-63ab32db="">Remote port forwarding</h2><h3 data-v-63ab32db="">Forwards a port on a remote system to another system</h3></header><div data-v-63ab32db=""><p><code data-v-63ab32db="">ssh -R 8080:localhost:80 ssh-server</code></p><p data-v-63ab32db="">Forwards traffic to all interfaces on port 8080 on ssh-server to
localhost port 80 on your local computer. If one of these interfaces is available
to the public internet, traffic connecting to port 8080 will be forwarded to your
local system.</p></div><div data-v-63ab32db=""><p><code data-v-63ab32db="">ssh -R 1.2.3.4:8080:localhost:80 ssh-server</code></p><p data-v-63ab32db="">Forwards traffic to ssh-server:8080 to localhost:80 on your local system
while only allowing access to the SSH tunnel entrance on ssh-server
from IP address 1.2.3.4. Use The GatewayPorts clientspecified directive
with this.</p></div><div data-v-63ab32db=""><p><code data-v-63ab32db="">ssh -R 8080:example.org:80 ssh-server</code></p><p data-v-63ab32db="">Forwards traffic to all interfaces on ssh-server:8080 to localhost:80
on your local system. From your local system, traffic is then forwarded
to example.org:80. From the perspective of example.org the traffic
is originating from your local system.</p></div><div data-v-63ab32db=""><h4 data-v-63ab32db="">SSH server configuration</h4><p data-v-63ab32db="">By default, forwarded ports are not accessible to the public internet.
You'll need to add this to your sshd_config on your remote server to forward
public internet traffic to your local computer.</p><p><code data-v-63ab32db="">GatewayPorts yes</code></p><p data-v-63ab32db="">Or if you'd like to specify which clients are allowed access, you can use
the following in your sshd_config instead</p><p><code data-v-63ab32db="">GatewayPorts clientspecified</code></p></div></div></section><section data-v-7fa32086="" id="dynamic-port-forwarding"><div data-v-7fa32086=""><header data-v-7fa32086=""><h2 data-v-7fa32086="">Dynamic port forwarding</h2><h3 data-v-7fa32086="">Forward traffic from a range of ports to a remote server</h3></header><div data-v-7fa32086=""><p><code data-v-7fa32086="">ssh -D 3000 ssh-server</code></p><p data-v-7fa32086="">Opens a SOCKS proxy on port 3000 of all interfaces on your local system.
This allows you to forward traffic sent through the proxy to the ssh-server
on any port or destination host. By default, SSH will use the SOCKS5 protocol,
which forwards TCP and UDP traffic.</p></div><div data-v-7fa32086=""><p><code data-v-7fa32086="">ssh -D 127.0.0.1:3000 ssh-server</code></p><p data-v-7fa32086="">Opens a SOCKS proxy on 127.0.0.1:3000 on your local system.</p></div><p data-v-7fa32086="">When you have a SOCKS proxy running, you can configure your web browser
to use the proxy to access resources as if connections were originating
from ssh-server. For example, if ssh-server had access to other servers
within a private network, by using using a SOCKS proxy you could access
those other servers locally as if you were on the network, without needing
to set up a VPN.</p><div data-v-7fa32086=""><p data-v-7fa32086="">When you have a SOCKS proxy running, you can test it like so</p><p><code data-v-7fa32086="">curl -x socks5://127.0.0.1:12345 https://example.org</code></p></div><div data-v-7fa32086=""><h4 data-v-7fa32086="">SSH client configuration</h4><p data-v-7fa32086="">If you want the SOCKS proxy to be available to more interfaces than just
localhost, make sure to enable GatewayPorts on your local system.</p><p><code data-v-7fa32086="">GatewayPorts yes</code></p><p data-v-7fa32086="">Since GatewayPorts is being configured on the SSH client here, you can also 
configure it with a command-line option instead of ssh_config.</p><p><code data-v-7fa32086="">ssh -o GatewayPorts=yes -D 3000 ssh-server</code></p></div></div></section><section data-v-8405b8ce="" id="jump-hosts"><div data-v-8405b8ce=""><header data-v-8405b8ce=""><h2 data-v-8405b8ce="">Jump hosts and proxy commands</h2><h3 data-v-8405b8ce="">Transparently connecting to a remote host through intermediate hosts</h3></header><div data-v-8405b8ce=""><p><code data-v-8405b8ce="">ssh -J user1@jump-host user2@remote-host</code><code data-v-8405b8ce="">ssh -o "ProxyJump user1@jump-host" user2@remote-host</code></p><p data-v-8405b8ce="">Establishes an SSH connection with jump-host and forwards TCP traffic
to remote-host. Connecting to remote-host through an intermediate jump-host.
The above command should work out of the box if jump-host already has
SSH access to remote-host. If it does not, you can use agent forwarding
to forward the SSH identity of your local computer to remote-host.</p></div><div data-v-8405b8ce=""><p><code data-v-8405b8ce="">ssh -J jump-host1,jump-host2 ssh-server</code></p><p data-v-8405b8ce="">You can specify multiple comma-separated jump hosts.</p></div><div data-v-8405b8ce=""><p><code data-v-8405b8ce="">ssh -o ProxyCommand="nc -X 5 -x localhost:3000 %h %p" user@remote-host</code></p><p data-v-8405b8ce="">Connecting to a remote server through a SOCKS5 proxy using netcat.
From the perspective of the server, the originating IP is from proxy-host.
However, the SSH connection itself is end-to-end encrypted so proxy-host
only sees an encrypted stream of traffic between the local system
and remote-host.</p></div><div data-v-8405b8ce=""><h4 data-v-8405b8ce="">SSH client configuration</h4><p data-v-8405b8ce="">To enable agent forwarding, you can use ssh-add to add your local SSH
identity to your local ssh agent.</p><p><code data-v-8405b8ce="">ssh-add</code></p></div></div></section><section data-v-61bcd1b8="" id="reliable-ssh-tunnels"><div data-v-61bcd1b8=""><header data-v-61bcd1b8=""><h2 data-v-61bcd1b8="">Reliable SSH Tunnels</h2><h3 data-v-61bcd1b8="">How to keep SSH tunnels open through network failures</h3></header><div data-v-61bcd1b8=""><p data-v-61bcd1b8="">The commands listed above work on an ad-hoc basis, but if
you want to maintain SSH tunnels through network outages or
unreliable connections, you'll have to do some additional setup.</p><p data-v-61bcd1b8="">By default, the TCP connection used to establish an SSH tunnel
may time out after a period of inactivity. To prevent timeouts,
you can configure the server to send heartbeat messages.</p><p><code data-v-61bcd1b8="">ServerAliveInterval 15<br data-v-61bcd1b8="">ServerAliveCountMax 4</code></p><p data-v-61bcd1b8="">You can also configure the client to send heartbeat messages.</p><p><code data-v-61bcd1b8="">ClientAliveInterval 15<br data-v-61bcd1b8="">ClientAliveCountMax 4</code></p></div><div data-v-61bcd1b8=""><h4 data-v-61bcd1b8="">Using AutoSSH</h4><p data-v-61bcd1b8="">While the above options may prevent a connection from dropping
due to inactivity, they will not re-establish dropped connections.
To ensure that an SSH tunnel will be re-established, you can use
autossh, which builds an SSH tunnel and monitors its health.</p><p data-v-61bcd1b8="">AutoSSH accepts the same arguments for port forwarding as SSH.</p><p><code data-v-61bcd1b8="">autossh -R 2222:localhost:22 ssh-server</code></p><p data-v-61bcd1b8="">This establishes a reverse tunnel that comes back after network failures.
By default, AutoSSH will open extra ports on the SSH client and server for
health checks. If traffic appears to no longer pass between the health check
ports, AutoSSH will restart the SSH tunnel.</p></div><div data-v-61bcd1b8=""><p><code data-v-61bcd1b8="">autossh -R 2222:localhost:22 \<br data-v-61bcd1b8="">&nbsp;&nbsp;-M 0 \<br data-v-61bcd1b8="">&nbsp;&nbsp;-o "ServerAliveInterval 10" -o "ServerAliveCountMax 3" \<br data-v-61bcd1b8="">&nbsp;&nbsp;remote-host</code></p><p data-v-61bcd1b8="">Using the -M 0 flag disables the health check ports and allows the SSH client
to handle the health checks. In this example, the SSH client expects the server
to send a heartbeat every 10 seconds. If 3 heartbeats fail in a row, the SSH client
exits, and AutoSSH will re-establish a new connection.</p></div></div></section><section data-v-c0e61440="" id="more-examples"><div data-v-c0e61440=""><header data-v-c0e61440=""><h2 data-v-c0e61440="">More examples and use cases</h2></header><div data-v-c0e61440=""><h4 data-v-c0e61440="">Transparent access to remote resource on a private network</h4><p data-v-c0e61440="">Let's say there's a git repository on a private network that's only accessible
through a private server on the network. This server is not accessible to the public
internet. You have direct access to the server, but don't have VPN access to the
private network.</p><p data-v-c0e61440="">For convenience, you'd …</p></div></div></section></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://robotmoon.com/ssh-tunnels/">https://robotmoon.com/ssh-tunnels/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://robotmoon.com/ssh-tunnels/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26053323</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 07:22:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Scientists Develop Transparent Wood That Is Stronger and Lighter Than Glass]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 17 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26052510">thread link</a>) | @abraxas
<br/>
February 6, 2021 | https://www.cbc.ca/radio/quirks/scientists-develop-transparent-wood-that-is-stronger-and-lighter-than-glass-1.5902739 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/radio/quirks/scientists-develop-transparent-wood-that-is-stronger-and-lighter-than-glass-1.5902739">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Bob McDonald's blog: A simple backyard procedure results in see-through wood with enormous potential as a building material.</p><div><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902788.1612553036!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/transparent-wood-university-of-maryland.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>A flower is visible behind a piece of the transparent material.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Qinqin Xia, University of Maryland/Science Advances)</figcaption></figure><p><span><p>Researchers at the University of Maryland have turned ordinary sheets of wood into <a href="https://advances.sciencemag.org/content/7/5/eabd7342" target="_blank"><u>transparent material</u></a> that is nearly as clear as glass, but stronger and with better insulating properties. It could become an energy efficient building material in the future.</p>  <p>Wood is made of two basic ingredients: cellulose, which are tiny fibres, and lignin, which bonds those fibres together to give it strength.</p>  <p>Tear a paper towel in half and look closely along the edge. You will see the little cellulose fibres sticking up. Lignin is a glue-like material that bonds the fibres together, a little like the plastic resin in fibreglass or carbon fibre. The lignin also contains molecules called chromophores, which give the wood its brown colour and prevent light from passing through.</p>  <p>Early attempts to make transparent wood involved removing the lignin, but this involved hazardous chemicals, high temperatures and a lot of time, making the product expensive and somewhat brittle. The new technique is so cheap and easy it could literally be done in a backyard.</p>  <p>Starting with planks of wood a metre long and one millimetre thick, the scientists simply brushed on a solution of hydrogen peroxide using an ordinary paint brush. When left in the sun, or under a UV lamp for an hour or so, the peroxide bleached out the brown chromophores but left the lignin intact, so the wood turned white.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902789.1612553066!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/transparent-wood-university-of-maryland.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902789.1612553066!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/transparent-wood-university-of-maryland.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902789.1612553066!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/transparent-wood-university-of-maryland.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902789.1612553066!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/transparent-wood-university-of-maryland.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902789.1612553066!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/transparent-wood-university-of-maryland.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902789.1612553066!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/transparent-wood-university-of-maryland.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Researchers demonstrated after brushing a coat of hydrogen peroxide on the opaque wood material, and exposing it to one hour of sunlight, it turns transparent.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Qinqin Xia, University of Maryland/Science Advances)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>Next, they infused the wood with a tough transparent epoxy designed for marine use, which filled in the spaces and pores in the wood and then hardened.&nbsp;This made the white wood transparent.</p>  <p>You can see a similar effect by taking that same piece of paper towel, dip half of it in water and place it on a patterned surface.&nbsp;The white paper towel will become translucent with light passing through the water and cellulose fibres without being scattered by refraction.</p>  <p>The epoxy in the wood does an even better job, allowing 90 per cent of visible light to pass through. The result is a long piece of what looks like glass, with the strength and flexibility of wood.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902790.1612552994!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/transparent-wood-usda-forest-service-jpg.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902790.1612552994!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/transparent-wood-usda-forest-service-jpg.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902790.1612552994!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/transparent-wood-usda-forest-service-jpg.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902790.1612552994!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/transparent-wood-usda-forest-service-jpg.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902790.1612552994!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/transparent-wood-usda-forest-service-jpg.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902790.1612552994!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/transparent-wood-usda-forest-service-jpg.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>A researcher holds up a square of transparent wood material against a green leaf.<!-- --> <!-- -->(USDA Forest Service)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>As window material, it would be much more resistant to accidental breakage. The clear wood&nbsp;is lighter than glass, with better insulating properties, which is important because windows are a major source of heat loss in buildings. It also might take less energy to manufacture clear wood because there are no high temperatures involved.</p>  <p>Transparent wood could become an alternative to glass in energy efficient buildings, or perhaps coverings for solar panels in harsh environments. There could be no end of uses.</p>      <p>Many different types of wood, from balsa to oak, can be made transparent, and it doesn't matter if it is cut along the grain or against it. If the transparent wood is made a little thicker, it would be strong enough to become part of the structure of a building, so there could be entire transparent wooden walls.</p>  <p>While this technology has yet to&nbsp; be scaled up to industrial levels, the researchers say it has great potential as a new building material. In fact, they say that theoretically, an entire house could be made transparent. It is not clear why anyone would want to live in a transparent house, but for people who do, it would be OK to throw stones…</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902787.1612553101!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/transparent-wood-qinqin-xia-university-of-maryland.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902787.1612553101!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/transparent-wood-qinqin-xia-university-of-maryland.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902787.1612553101!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/transparent-wood-qinqin-xia-university-of-maryland.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902787.1612553101!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/transparent-wood-qinqin-xia-university-of-maryland.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902787.1612553101!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/transparent-wood-qinqin-xia-university-of-maryland.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902787.1612553101!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/transparent-wood-qinqin-xia-university-of-maryland.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>A researcher holds up a 10-centimetre long slab of the see-through wood.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Qinqin Xia, University of Maryland/Science Advances)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>Images copyright Xia et al.&nbsp;<a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" rel="license">Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial license</a>,&nbsp;</p></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/radio/quirks/scientists-develop-transparent-wood-that-is-stronger-and-lighter-than-glass-1.5902739</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26052510</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 03:58:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Fun with a Functional Programming Interview Question]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 11 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26051899">thread link</a>) | @amscotti
<br/>
February 6, 2021 | https://danielbmarkham.com/fun-with-an-interview-question/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://danielbmarkham.com/fun-with-an-interview-question/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <div id="post-body">
        <p><a href="https://twitter.com/Al_Grigor/status/1357028887209902088?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">The other day on Twitter</a></p><blockquote>Most candidates cannot solve this interview problem:<p>Input: "aaaabbbcca"</p><p>Output: [("a", 4), ("b", 3), ("c", 2), ("a", 1)] Write a function that converts the input to the output I ask it in the screening interview and give it 25 minutes How would you solve it?</p></blockquote><p>I thought about it for a few minutes while I was doing other things, came up with the answer, congratulated myself (yay me!) and went on to other things.</p><p>Then it was posted on a tech forum. How would you answer the question? Lots of folks weighed in, all with seemingly (to me) long-winded coding solutions. Surely they didn't realize the genius of &nbsp;my solution in F#! So I posted it.</p><blockquote>In F#, t looks to me like “aaaabbbcca” |&gt; Seq.countBy id;;<br>I don’t know how to make it any simpler than that.</blockquote><p>Once again, I congratulated myself (yay me!) and moved on. Later that day, I logged on again and a commenter was nice enough to give me my comeuppance.</p><blockquote>Unfortunately, this doesn’t return the expected output. That last “a” is what throws a wrench in solutions like this.</blockquote><p>Looking back at that tweet, holy shit! I missed that second "a"! Well hell, this is a completely different kind of problem than I first thought. I'll just copy the input string from the website and bang something out in order to save my honor. A wrong must be righted.</p><p>I spent the next hour or two staring at the code and wondering what the hell is going on. Twenty lines of code and it doesn't compile. Gives me something like:</p><blockquote>error FS0010: Unexpected character '“' in interaction</blockquote><p>Did I cast something the wrong way? I tried recasting things. Did I hose up my environment? I reloaded. Is my code structure off in subtle ways? Nothing I did seemed to work. Finally, out of desperation, I started a new project and re-typed everything in by hand.</p><p>It worked.</p><p>The problem? When I copied and pasted the input code, it was using typographic quotes, not programming quotes. It was a copy-and-paste problem, of the freaking input data, that had defeated me all of that time.</p><p>Once that was out of the way, I kicked out the solution rather quickly, first coding it up as a strongly-typed function and then removing the type restrictions to make it one day a generic library function. As another commenter pointed out, this is classic Run Length Encoding, so that's what I named the function.</p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><pre><code>
let runLengthEncode&lt;'a when 'a:equality&gt; inputSeq =
  let rec rleInnerLoop inputSeq acc =
    if inputSeq|&gt;Seq.isEmpty then acc else
    let itemWereWatching=inputSeq |&gt;Seq.head
    let chunk=inputSeq |&gt; Seq.takeWhile itemWereWatching.Equals
    let chunkLength=chunk|&gt;Seq.length
    let newInputSeq = inputSeq |&gt; Seq.skip chunkLength
    let newItem=seq{itemWereWatching, chunkLength}
    rleInnerLoop newInputSeq newItem |&gt; Seq.append acc
  rleInnerLoop inputSeq Seq.empty
</code></pre>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>The only type constraint I had was that whatever stream of stuff I'm processing, it has to support equality, or a=b, otherwise how could I remove duplicates? I'm also quite taken back by the size of the code. Now my code was the big honking solution. Yikes!</p><p>Could I shorten it? Well sure, since it's pure FP and written in an idiomatic style, the whole thing could collapse to one line of code. But why do that? All of those labels in there are for my benefit, in case I need to debug. Until I've tested the hell out of it, I need the labels. (Plus the labels and size shouldn't matter to the compiler anyway, if I can collapse it, the compiler should be able to collapse it)</p><p>But something about this feels odd to me, as if it were one of those situations where non-idiomatic code might be better for performance reasons. That's what happens under-the-hood with some F# library functions. For now, though, I'll let the library guys worry about optimization and I'm stay happy with a solved problem. yay me</p><p>Of course I have to write the inverse function, Run Length Decode:</p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><pre><code>let runLengthDecode (inputSeq:seq&lt;'a*int&gt;) =
  seq {yield! inputSeq|&gt;Seq.collect(fun x-&gt;Seq.replicate (snd x) (fst x))}
</code></pre>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>That's a lot shorter and makes me happy. When I see functions like the first one I worry that I've gone far afield of the best solution, perhaps by reinventing the wheel. When I see functions like the second one, I am reassured that this is a common problem. Many others have been here before me. (This goes back to my statement that "I need the labels until I've tested the hell out of it" Other people have done the testing work. Woot!)</p><p>What lessons were learned? Well, I really suck at coding in my head. I knew already but continue to be amazed when it happens with only the simplest problems. One of the major points of <a href="https://leanpub.com/info-ops2">Info-Ops II</a> is that our belief in our understanding of the code, no matter what it is, is much more unfounded than founded. Even with "perfect" code, battle-tested and hardened, the most you can say is that it works, it has no bugs, and you can trust it. You can't say you understand all that's going on. Modern programming if far, far too complex for that ever to be true. </p><p>We're all like that, even non-coders. As much as some of us think we can code in our head, it doesn't work that way, even many times with the most trivial of problems. That doesn't stop us, though. There are people who think they can talk at length about deep issues like foreign policy, all the while maintaining a logical and coherent set of symbols. They're being logical. They're running the code they've created in their head. Other folks, though, are not. (Other folks see this the same way, only with the players reversed) </p><p>This is true in policy discussion for the exact same reasons it's true with coding. There's simply too much depth and nuance in language for it to work like code, and even if it did work like code, we'd think we understood far, far more than we actually do. We lose either way.</p><p>Secondly, test cases don't always save you. Yes, my initial mistake was not having test cases, just doing it in my head, but once I had test cases and started coding it out, the major part of my hang-up was dealing with some kind of IDE/OS/Unicode/UTF-8 crap, not the code itself. Doesn't matter, I still would have taken more than the allotted 25 minutes. I do not get the job.</p><p>But I had fun. That made it worth the effort.</p><p>P.S. For those interested in how this all would collapse into one line, here's a hint:</p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><pre><code>let runLengthEncode2&lt;'a when 'a:equality&gt; inputSeq =
  let rec rleInnerLoop inputSeq acc = match inputSeq|&gt;Seq.isEmpty with |true-&gt;acc|false-&gt;rleInnerLoop (inputSeq |&gt; Seq.skip ((inputSeq |&gt; Seq.takeWhile (inputSeq |&gt;Seq.head).Equals)|&gt;Seq.length)) (seq{(inputSeq |&gt;Seq.head), ((inputSeq |&gt; Seq.takeWhile (inputSeq |&gt;Seq.head).Equals)|&gt;Seq.length)}) |&gt; Seq.append acc
  rleInnerLoop inputSeq Seq.empty
</code></pre>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown-->    </div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://danielbmarkham.com/fun-with-an-interview-question/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26051899</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 01:51:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Solar-assisted fabrication of large-scale, patternable transparent wood]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 294 | Comments 149 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26051883">thread link</a>) | @lazycrazyowl
<br/>
February 6, 2021 | https://www.cbc.ca/1.5902739 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/1.5902739">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Bob McDonald's blog: A simple backyard procedure results in see-through wood with enormous potential as a building material.</p><div><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902788.1612553036!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/transparent-wood-university-of-maryland.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>A flower is visible behind a piece of the transparent material.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Qinqin Xia, University of Maryland/Science Advances)</figcaption></figure><p><span><p>Researchers at the University of Maryland have turned ordinary sheets of wood into <a href="https://advances.sciencemag.org/content/7/5/eabd7342" target="_blank"><u>transparent material</u></a> that is nearly as clear as glass, but stronger and with better insulating properties. It could become an energy efficient building material in the future.</p>  <p>Wood is made of two basic ingredients: cellulose, which are tiny fibres, and lignin, which bonds those fibres together to give it strength.</p>  <p>Tear a paper towel in half and look closely along the edge. You will see the little cellulose fibres sticking up. Lignin is a glue-like material that bonds the fibres together, a little like the plastic resin in fibreglass or carbon fibre. The lignin also contains molecules called chromophores, which give the wood its brown colour and prevent light from passing through.</p>  <p>Early attempts to make transparent wood involved removing the lignin, but this involved hazardous chemicals, high temperatures and a lot of time, making the product expensive and somewhat brittle. The new technique is so cheap and easy it could literally be done in a backyard.</p>  <p>Starting with planks of wood a metre long and one millimetre thick, the scientists simply brushed on a solution of hydrogen peroxide using an ordinary paint brush. When left in the sun, or under a UV lamp for an hour or so, the peroxide bleached out the brown chromophores but left the lignin intact, so the wood turned white.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902789.1612553066!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/transparent-wood-university-of-maryland.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902789.1612553066!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/transparent-wood-university-of-maryland.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902789.1612553066!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/transparent-wood-university-of-maryland.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902789.1612553066!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/transparent-wood-university-of-maryland.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902789.1612553066!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/transparent-wood-university-of-maryland.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902789.1612553066!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/transparent-wood-university-of-maryland.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Researchers demonstrated after brushing a coat of hydrogen peroxide on the opaque wood material, and exposing it to one hour of sunlight, it turns transparent.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Qinqin Xia, University of Maryland/Science Advances)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>Next, they infused the wood with a tough transparent epoxy designed for marine use, which filled in the spaces and pores in the wood and then hardened.&nbsp;This made the white wood transparent.</p>  <p>You can see a similar effect by taking that same piece of paper towel, dip half of it in water and place it on a patterned surface.&nbsp;The white paper towel will become translucent with light passing through the water and cellulose fibres without being scattered by refraction.</p>  <p>The epoxy in the wood does an even better job, allowing 90 per cent of visible light to pass through. The result is a long piece of what looks like glass, with the strength and flexibility of wood.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902790.1612552994!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/transparent-wood-usda-forest-service-jpg.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902790.1612552994!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/transparent-wood-usda-forest-service-jpg.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902790.1612552994!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/transparent-wood-usda-forest-service-jpg.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902790.1612552994!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/transparent-wood-usda-forest-service-jpg.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902790.1612552994!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/transparent-wood-usda-forest-service-jpg.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902790.1612552994!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/transparent-wood-usda-forest-service-jpg.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>A researcher holds up a square of transparent wood material against a green leaf.<!-- --> <!-- -->(USDA Forest Service)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>As window material, it would be much more resistant to accidental breakage. The clear wood&nbsp;is lighter than glass, with better insulating properties, which is important because windows are a major source of heat loss in buildings. It also might take less energy to manufacture clear wood because there are no high temperatures involved.</p>  <p>Transparent wood could become an alternative to glass in energy efficient buildings, or perhaps coverings for solar panels in harsh environments. There could be no end of uses.</p>      <p>Many different types of wood, from balsa to oak, can be made transparent, and it doesn't matter if it is cut along the grain or against it. If the transparent wood is made a little thicker, it would be strong enough to become part of the structure of a building, so there could be entire transparent wooden walls.</p>  <p>While this technology has yet to&nbsp; be scaled up to industrial levels, the researchers say it has great potential as a new building material. In fact, they say that theoretically, an entire house could be made transparent. It is not clear why anyone would want to live in a transparent house, but for people who do, it would be OK to throw stones…</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902787.1612553101!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/transparent-wood-qinqin-xia-university-of-maryland.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902787.1612553101!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/transparent-wood-qinqin-xia-university-of-maryland.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902787.1612553101!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/transparent-wood-qinqin-xia-university-of-maryland.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902787.1612553101!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/transparent-wood-qinqin-xia-university-of-maryland.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902787.1612553101!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/transparent-wood-qinqin-xia-university-of-maryland.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902787.1612553101!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/transparent-wood-qinqin-xia-university-of-maryland.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>A researcher holds up a 10-centimetre long slab of the see-through wood.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Qinqin Xia, University of Maryland/Science Advances)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>Images copyright Xia et al.&nbsp;<a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" rel="license">Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial license</a>,&nbsp;</p></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/1.5902739</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26051883</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 01:48:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Mediocre Programmer]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 127 | Comments 86 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26051600">thread link</a>) | @celadevra_
<br/>
February 6, 2021 | http://themediocreprogrammer.com/what-is-the-mediocre-programmer.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://themediocreprogrammer.com/what-is-the-mediocre-programmer.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>The Mediocre Programmer? What's that?</p>
<p>The Mediocre Programmer is a book about the journey of becoming a better programmer. But before we can become better programmers we have to pass through being mediocre programmers. Mediocre doesn't mean a bad programmer --- far from it. It means lacking skill. As beginners we start our journey full of fresh ideas of how we'll be great programmers, but as we learn more we realize that the gap between being a beginner and an expert programmer requires us to be mediocre for a time. And that period of mediocrity can be frustrating. As beginning programmers we're given all the encouragement to explore and make mistakes. As we move to the intermediate and mediocre stages of programming that encouragement fades. Instead of encouragement we are faced with expectations, both from ourselves and from others. We start to question our abilities. Why do we have to keep looking things up? Shouldn't we already know this? Why does programming feel like a struggle? Am I ever going to be good at this? </p>
<p>This book is about helping you along on the journey of being a mediocre programmer. Together we'll uncover some of common misconceptions we have about programming, failure, and growth and come to understand that the act of programming and development is something we undertake each day and improve in small ways. It's these small changes that over time transform us from being mediocre programmers into better programmers.</p>
<p>There are plenty of books on how to become a better programmer out there. Books like this tend to have checklists and other advice that the author deems important enough for you to do in order to become a better programmer. They tend to focus on specific improvements like choosing a better editor, writing better test cases, or drinking lots of water. Those books have lots of useful advice, but they read like a laundry list of things that you must do all at once in order to succeed. This book will try not to saddle you with more work (you likely have enough as it is). Rather, we'll discuss what it feels like to be a programmer. We'll talk about the emotions in being a programmer; the feelings of frustration, guilt, anger, and inadequacy. We'll cover the struggles in learning new things and keeping your skills current. We'll talk about those times when you feel like giving up and walking away from computing and whether those feelings come from a place of love or a worry that you're not keeping up.</p>
<p>This book is a personal journey for both of us. It's a memoir of my time as a programmer and my feelings along the way. I've thought many times about giving up and finding a different career path but doing anything other than being a computer programmer scares me even more. Does that mean I'm stuck in a perverse ouroboros of self-pity and self-doubt? Hardly. It means that I need to dig deeper to understand why I chose the path of being a programmer and realize that it took a lot to get here and it's going to take a lot more to get where I want to be. It's a commitment to seeing things as they are now and moving forward from wherever I'm standing.</p>
<p>I hope you'll join me on this journey.</p>
<p>(The book is released under a <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike license (CC-BY-SA)</a>. You are encouraged to read it, share it, and use it to help others through their struggle).</p>  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://themediocreprogrammer.com/what-is-the-mediocre-programmer.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26051600</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:46:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
