<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 08:22:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 08:22:19 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A tale of webpage speed, or throwing away React]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 75 | Comments 53 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24258855">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
August 24, 2020 | https://solovyov.net/blog/2020/a-tale-of-webpage-speed-or-throwing-away-react/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://solovyov.net/blog/2020/a-tale-of-webpage-speed-or-throwing-away-react/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section itemprop="articleBody">
  <p>Back in 2011, I happened to get a job writing <a href="https://backbonejs.org/">Backbone.js</a> app. If you never did that, don’t. I was complaining about difficulties with composition left and right to whoever would listen. As I started digging into alternatives for the front-end, I discovered <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Functional_reactive_programming">FRP</a> and <a href="https://www.flapjax-lang.org/">Flapjax</a>, and <a href="https://clojurescript.org/">ClojureScript</a>. The last one got me hooked on <a href="https://clojure.org/">Clojure</a>. I even did a <a href="https://fwdays.com/event/js-frameworks-day-2013/review/Functional-Reactive-Programming-&amp;-ClojureScript">successful talk</a> on FRP and ClojureScript (and precursor to <a href="https://hoplon.io/">Hoplon</a>, called hlisp).</p>
<h2 id="react">React</h2>
<p>Then in May 2013 React was released. I championed it on my new job and discovered during Clojure-themed hackaton (<a href="https://solovyov.net/blog/2013/clojurecup/">Clojure Cup 2013</a>) that CLJS and React are a great match. What’s so good about React though? To me, the main selling point is that it composes well.</p>
<p>When you use predecessors like jQuery or Backbone or Angular or whatever after just a year of development your code is a mess of event listeners and triggers. Don’t get me started on unobtrusive JS, code locality is non-existent with jQuery. Which handler is bound where and what it does? It’s too hard to discover to be a good base for a good codebase!</p>
<p>Then I started working at <a href="https://kasta.ua/">Kasta</a>, where web frontend was exactly that jQuery-ish mess. Nobody ever wanted to touch checkout, since you could spend hours, if not days, making the smallest change. Then QA would find more invalid states than you can dream of. And then users would report more bugs to our call center. It was just as awful as you can imagine.</p>
<p>So after some experiments, tests, and checks, I decided that we’re going React + ClojureScript way with server-side rendering done in Clojure.</p>
<h2 id="demise">Demise</h2>
<p>And for a while, things were looking good. We had this <a href="https://solovyov.net/blog/2017/server-side-rendering/">architecture</a> where our components are executed as Clojure on the backend, so no Node.js on the server, hurray! And developer UX is through the roof with the excellent live reload (thanks CLJS), ability to connect from your editor to browser REPL, and experiment there. It is just great!</p>
<p>To make a long story short, our frontend grew bigger and bigger. Incremental compilation started to become slower — it now routinely takes more than a second or two. And while there were few attempts on keeping the whole app performant, ultimately we failed. It’s a death by a thousand cuts. The application became too big and its boot time became too long. Server side rendering helps partially, but then hydration freezes the browser. On the older hardware or Androids it became unacceptable!</p>
<p>One of the main reasonings back in 2016 was that we take a hit on startup time, but in turn, get no page loads and have a rich web application with a lot of interactions. And for a while that worked! But startup time became longer and longer, leading to a shameful rating of 5/100 from Google’s PageSpeed (okay, it was sometimes up to ~25/100, whatever).</p>
<p>More than that, while doing what is described below, we’ve discovered that React also leads to some questionable practices. Like hovers in JS (rather than in CSS), drop-down menus in JS, not rendering hidden (under a hover) text (Google won’t be happy), weird complex logic (since it’s possible!), etc. You can have a React app without those problems, but apparently, you have to have better self-control than we had (nobody’s perfect!).</p>
<p>Also since then, the vast majority of our users switched to mobile apps. This made the web app the main entry point for new users. This means its main goal is rendering fast for a newcomer, because old-timers, which want more functionality, are on mobile app now. And <a href="https://web.dev/tti/">TTI</a> (time to interactive) is so much more important here.</p>
<h2 id="time-for-a-change">Time For A Change</h2>
<p>So given that circumstances have changed, what do we do? I read articles “how I survive on vanilla JS” since before React appeared and they usually don’t make sense — it’s either a pink-glassed rant about how great it is, disregarding all the problems (separation of concerns, cohesion, composability, code locality) or a project by one (or few) persons, who just keep everything in their head.</p>
<p>Somewhere back in February I stumbled upon <a href="https://intercoolerjs.org/">Intercooler.js</a>. I’m not sure if I ever saw it before — maybe I did but skimmed over — it does not matter. This time it captured my attention.</p>
<p>The idea is that all HTML is rendered on the server. And client updates parts of HTML, controlled by element’s attributes. Basically like HTML+XHR on steroids. You can’t do anything you want, but that’s partially the point: some limits are good so you won’t do crazy stuff. And you need some support from the server, so you can render partial results — just an optimization, but quite an important one.</p>
<p>There is an alternative library — <a href="https://unpoly.com/">Unpoly</a>. It has more features around layout and styling but has a little bit less thought out XHR stuff (hard to do a POST request with parameters without having a form, for example). And the library size is much bigger. And it’s written in CoffeeScript with lots of classes, <a href="https://solovyov.net/blog/2020/inheritance/">ugh</a>.</p>
<p>So I made a proof-of-concept implementation of our catalogue page in Intercooler and it worked! Except there was a dependency on jQuery and some other irritating stuff… As I was struggling to make a batch request for HTML fragments I understood one thing: when I wrote down a roadmap for catalogue the last point was “small intercooler-like thing for analytics”.</p>
<p>So why wait?</p>
<h2 id="twinspark">TwinSpark</h2>
<p>I liked Intercooler’s coherent approach to working around AJAX, so I decided to name the library after some automotive stuff as well, and TwinSpark seems like an appropriate name. So what’s the deal?</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/kasta-ua/twinspark-js">TwinSpark</a> is a framework for declarative HTML enhancement: you put additional attributes on your element and TwinSpark does something with them. Like makes an AJAX call and replaces target with a response, or adds a class, or… well, see <a href="https://kasta-ua.github.io/twinspark-js/">examples</a>, shall you?</p>
<p>There are some differences with Intercooler, of course, because why would it exist? The most noticeable one is that there is no dependency on jQuery. It supports only modern browsers (not IE or Opera Mini) but drops that 88kb monster.</p>
<p>It also has:</p>
<ul>
<li>no inheritance — can’t stress that enough!</li>
<li>clear extension points for your directives</li>
<li>support for batching requests to a server</li>
<li>tighter attribute name convention (my own opinion, but <code>ic-get</code> and <code>ic-post</code> irritate me: do not make me change keys!)</li>
<li>much smaller payload (thanks to no jQuery!)</li>
<li>should be faster (thanks to no jQuery again)</li>
</ul>
<p>Honestly speaking, the main reasons are <a href="https://kasta-ua.github.io/twinspark-js/#batch">batching</a> and <a href="https://solovyov.net/blog/2020/inheritance/">no inheritance</a>. Inheritance is particularly painful here. In Intercooler, if you declared <code>ic-target</code> on the body, all tags inside will think it’s their target too. So you include a component somewhere in HTML tree and an attribute higher on tree changes this component behavior. I mean this is a freaking dynamic scope, I want none of that! :)</p>
<p>Funnily enough, after about a month of dabbling with TwinSpark, Intercooler’s author announced that he’s doing a jQuery-less modern version: <a href="https://htmx.org/">htmx</a>. :) It has really good extensions points, so maybe it’s possible to add batching… but inheritance is still there. :-(</p>
<h2 id="why-is-that-a-good-idea">Why is that a good idea</h2>
<p>We need to look at it from two sides: if it’s good for developers and if it’s good for users. React was great at former and terrible at later.</p>
<p>TwinSpark approach is much better in most cases for the user: less JavaScript, less jitter, more common HTML-like behavior. In the worst case, we would serve you 2.5MB of minified (non-gzipped) JS and 700KB of HTML (half of it were initial data for React) for catalogue. JS bundle is not that big because of embedded images or css or some other obscure stuff, it’s big because it’s the whole app, with a lot of views and logic.</p>
<p>Now it’s 40KB of minified non-gzipped JS (TwinSpark, analytics, some behavior, IntersectionObserver polyfill) and 350KB of HTML. Two orders of magnitude difference and even HTML is smaller! This is just like Christmas in childhood!</p>
<p>On the developer side, I think React is better still, but code locality is great, composability is much better (since you are forced in a limited world of working in a simplistic model) than with jQuery. Plus there are a lot of ways to improve it.</p>
<p>The good news is that the development process did not change that much! We’re still writing components that query necessary data from site-wide memory store (and make a call to API when needed), but they are executed only on the server. We effectively piggy-backend on our previous architecture, and this gives us the perfect ability to render “partial” HTML - since components do not wait for some “controller” to give them all necessary data. This is what allowed us to have both React and non-React versions to co-exist and make an A/B test without writing the markup twice.</p>
<h2 id="results">Results</h2>
<p>It took us four months since the first experiments to release. Not exactly the amount of time I imagined when we started (“should take two to three weeks at most!"), heh, but we were not exclusively doing that. It still took a lot of time and energy to remove React-isms from the code and wrangle our app to be a server-side citizen. It still could use some polishing, but we decided to release it despite that just to cut it short. And A/B test showed that we were right — especially for Android phones.</p>
<p>Google gives our catalogue 75/100 now instead of 5/100. Hurray, I guess? :)</p>

  </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://solovyov.net/blog/2020/a-tale-of-webpage-speed-or-throwing-away-react/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24258855</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 09:25:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Clean Start for the Web]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 87 | Comments 66 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24255541">thread link</a>) | @tannhaeuser
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://macwright.com/2020/08/22/clean-starts-for-the-web.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://macwright.com/2020/08/22/clean-starts-for-the-web.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The web is in need of some reinvention right now.</p><p>The web’s evolution over the last decade has mirrored the American economy. All of the essential indicators are going “up and to the right,” a steady stream of fundamental advances reassure use that there “is progress,” but the actual experience and effects for individuals stagnates or regresses.</p><p>The crisis affects platforms, creators, and consumers alike.</p><p><em>I’m going to try and dissect and diagnose this situation, a bit. You can skip forward if you just want to read my casual, unprofessional pitch for a reboot of the web. The idea is that we could choose a new lightweight markdown format to replace HTML &amp; CSS, split the web into documents and applications, and find performance, accessibility, and fun again.</em></p><details><summary>This post uses the pedantic definition of "the web"</summary>I've discussed attempts to reinvent the "Internet" a few times. Things like dat, IPFS, and arweave are all projects to reinvent an Internet, or a transport and data-sharing layer. The web is what lies on top of that, the HTML, CSS, URLs, JavaScript, browsing experience.</details><h3 id="the-platform-collapse">The platform collapse</h3><p>The platform side is what changed last week, when <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/08/firefox-maker-mozilla-lays-off-250-workers-says-covid-19-lowered-revenue/">Mozilla laid off 250 employees</a> and indicated that it would affect Firefox development. Firefox wasn’t the #2 browser - that’s Safari, mainly because of the captive audience of iPhone and iPad users. But it was the most popular browser that people <em>chose</em> to use.</p><p><img alt="Chart of browser market share, with Chrome becoming the monopoly" src="https://macwright.com/images/2020-08-22-clean-starts-for-the-web-chart-of-browser-market-share-with-chrome-becoming-the-monopoly.png"></p><p><em>Chart from <a href="https://gs.statcounter.com/browser-market-share#monthly-200901-202007">statcounter</a></em></p><p>The real winner is not just Chrome, but Chrome’s engine. One codebase, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KHTML">KHTML</a>, split into <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WebKit">WebKit</a> (Safari), and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blink_(browser_engine)">Blink</a> (Chrome, Microsoft Edge, Opera, etc.)</p><p>This a textbook monoculture. In one sense, it’s a victory for collaboration because nobody’s ‘wasting time’ on competing implementations and web developers can expect the same features and bugs across different browsers. But in a deeper way, it threatens one of the basic principles of how the web has evolved.</p><h3 id="specs--implementations">Specs &amp; implementations</h3><p><picture><source srcset="https://macwright.com/images/2020-08-22-clean-starts-for-the-web-decline.webp" type="image/webp"><img alt="Decline" src="https://macwright.com/images/2020-08-22-clean-starts-for-the-web-decline.jpg"></picture></p><p>The web has evolved through a combination of <em>specifications</em> and <em>implementations</em>. Organizations like the <a href="https://whatwg.org/">WHATWG</a>, <a href="https://www.w3.org/">W3C</a>, and <a href="https://www.ietf.org/">IETF</a> have been collaboration spaces for independent developers, corporations, and academics to discuss potential new features of the web. Then, browsers would test those ideas out in a variety of implementations.</p><p>This was an interesting structural piece: it reassured us all that it was <em>possible</em> to follow along, and that a multi-participant web was one of our goals. It was frustrating to pull up <a href="https://caniuse.com/">caniuse</a> and see blank spots, but the idea was that different browsers may take the lead in some areas, but everyone catches up eventually. Chrome was not always the first to jump on features, or the first to optimize.</p><p>It’s slower to collaborate than to work alone, but it was beneficial in some ways that we’ve lost now. Chrome has been moving extremely fast, adding new specifications and ideas at a startling rate, and it’s becoming one of the hardest pieces of software to replicate.</p><p>Mike Healy I think <a href="https://twitter.com/mike_hasarms/status/1296575224599556097">said it best</a>:</p><blockquote><p>Do you think the web has almost ‘priced itself out of the market’ in terms of complexity if only 1-2 organisations are capable of building rendering engines for it?</p></blockquote><p>Not only is it nearly impossible to build a new browser from scratch, once you have one the ongoing cost of keeping up with standards requires a full team of experts. Read Drew DeVault’s <a href="https://drewdevault.com/2020/08/13/Web-browsers-need-to-stop.html">Web browsers need to stop</a> for that point, and keep reading all of Drew’s stuff.</p><details><summary>What about Flow?</summary>Yep, there’s a <a href="https://www.ekioh.com/flow-browser/">browser called Flow</a>, which may exist and may support a full range of web standards. If it does exist, I’ll be very excited about it, but it has been teased for almost a year now without any concrete evidence, so it could equally be vaporware.</details><h3 id="the-problem-for-creators">The problem for creators</h3><p>The web has gotten much harder to develop for.</p><p>The web has had about 25 years to grow, few opportunities to shrink, and is now surrounded by an extremely short-sighted culture that is an outgrowth of economic and career short-termism. There are lots of <a href="https://frankchimero.com/blog/2018/everything-easy/">ways to do anything</a>, and some of the most popular ways of building applications on the web are - in my opinion - <a href="https://macwright.com/2020/05/10/spa-fatigue.html">usually ghoulish overkill</a>.</p><p>The best way for folks to enter <em>web development</em> in 2020 is to choose a niche, like <a href="https://vuejs.org/">Vue.js</a> or <a href="https://reactjs.org/">React</a>, and hope that there’s a CSS and accessibility expert on their team.</p><p>For folks who just want to create a web page, who don’t want to enter an industry, there’s a baffling array of techniques, but all the simplest, probably-best ones are stigmatized. It’s easier to stumble into building your resume in React with GraphQL than it is to type some HTML in Notepad.</p><h3 id="the-problem-for-consumers">The problem for consumers</h3><p>We hope that all this innovation is <em>for the user</em>, but often it isn’t. Modern websites seem to be as large, slow, and buggy as they’ve ever been. Our computers are <a href="https://macwright.com/2019/11/15/something-is-wrong-with-computers.html">barely getting faster</a> and our internet connection speeds are stagnating (don’t even <em>try</em> to mention 5G). Webpage <a href="https://www.pingdom.com/blog/webpages-are-getting-larger-every-year-and-heres-why-it-matters/">size growth</a> is outpacing it all.</p><p>The end result is that I no longer expect pages to be fast, even with <a href="https://github.com/gorhill/uBlock">uBlock</a> installed in Firefox and a good local <a href="https://sonic.net/">fiber internet provider</a>.</p><p>I don’t want to lay all of the blame at <em>those web developers</em>, though. Here’s a story from an old job that I find kind of funny. We were collecting some data from user interactions to answer simple questions like “do people click to upload or do they drag &amp; drop?” So we enabled <a href="https://segment.com/">Segment</a>, a tool that lets you add data-collection pipelines by including a single script. The problem, though, is that Segment offered a big page of on/off switches with hundreds of data providers &amp; ad-tech companies on it. And, sure, enough, some folks closer to the business side started <em>clicking all those buttons</em>.</p><p>See, the problem with ads and data tracking is that <em>you can</em>, and who is going to say no? (In that instance, I said no, and added a <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/CSP">CSP</a> that would block new advertiser access at the page level.)</p><h2 id="recreating-simplicity">Recreating simplicity</h2><blockquote><p>You cannot get a simple system by adding simplicity to a complex system. - <a href="http://erlang.org/pipermail/erlang-questions/2012-March/065087.html">Richard O’Keefe</a></p></blockquote><p>Where do we go from here? Some of the smartest folks out there have been <a href="https://twitter.com/_developit/status/1296628134406692865">advocating for a major version revision</a> of the web.</p><p><em>I am in no way qualified to speculate on a whole new web from scratch, but the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/08/21/us/california-wildfires.html">air quality</a> is scary so I’m skipping my run and it’s Saturday morning so here we are.</em></p><p>How do we make the web fun, participatory, and good?</p><p>My first thought is that there are two webs:</p><h3 id="the-document-web">The document web</h3><p><picture><source srcset="https://macwright.com/images/2020-08-22-clean-starts-for-the-web-illustration-of-web-pages.webp" type="image/webp"><img alt="Illustration of web pages" src="https://macwright.com/images/2020-08-22-clean-starts-for-the-web-illustration-of-web-pages.jpg"></picture></p><p>There is the “document web”, like blogs, news, Wikipedia, Twitter, Facebook. This is basically the original vision of the web, as far as I can understand it (I was 2). Basically CSS, which we now think of as a way for designers to add brand identity and tweak pixel-perfect details, was instead mostly a way of making plain documents readable and letting the <em>readers</em> of those documents customize how they looked. This attribute actually <a href="https://twitter.com/autiomaa/status/1296755641164468224">survived for a while in Chrome, in the form of user stylesheets</a>, and <a href="https://davidwalsh.name/firefox-user-stylesheet">still works in Firefox</a>. Though it’s going to be a rough ride in the current web which has basically thrown away <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_HTML">semantic HTML</a> as an idea.</p><h3 id="the-application-web">The “application” web</h3><p><picture><source srcset="https://macwright.com/images/2020-08-22-clean-starts-for-the-web-illustration-of-machines.webp" type="image/webp"><img alt="Illustration of machines" src="https://macwright.com/images/2020-08-22-clean-starts-for-the-web-illustration-of-machines.jpg"></picture></p><p>Then there’s the “application web”. This started as <em>server</em> applications, built with things like <a href="https://www.djangoproject.com/">Django</a> and <a href="https://rubyonrails.org/">Ruby on Rails</a> and before them a variety of technologies that will live forever in corporations, like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jakarta_Servlet">Java Servlets</a>.</p><p><a href="https://backbonejs.org/">Backbone.js</a> demonstrated that a lot of these applications could be moved into the browser, and then <a href="https://reactjs.org/">React</a> and its many SPA-style competitors established a new order for the web – highly-interactive, quite complex, client-side applications.</p><h3 id="the-war-between-the-parts-of-the-web">The war between the parts of the web</h3><p>I posit that this dual-nature is part of what gives the web its magic. But it’s also a destructive force.</p><p>The magic is that a simple blog can be creative expression, can be beautifully interactive. This one isn’t, but I’m just saying - <a href="https://www.typewolf.com/site-of-the-day">it’s possible</a>.</p><p>The problem is that the “document web” is often plagued by application characteristics - it’s the JavaScript and animations and complexity that makes your average newspaper website an unmitigated disaster. Where document websites adopt application patterns they often accidentally sacrifice <a href="https://www.a11yproject.com/">accessibility</a>, performance, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_scraping">machine readability</a>.</p><p>And the “application web” is plagued by the document characteristics - interactive applications are going to great lengths to avoid most of the essential characteristics of HTML &amp; CSS and just use them as raw materials - avoiding writing any HTML directly at all, avoiding <a href="https://mxstbr.com/thoughts/css-in-js">writing any CSS directly at all</a>, avoiding <a href="https://www.react-spring.io/">default animation features</a>, replacing <a href="https://reactrouter.com/">page-based navigation with something that looks like it but works completely differently</a>. The application web uses <a href="https://reactjs.org/docs/introducing-jsx.html">JSX</a>, not HTML, and would like that in the browser itself, or <a href="https://svelte.dev/">Svelte</a>, instead of JavaScript, and would like that too.</p><p>When I read blog posts from ‘traditional web developers’ who are mad that HTML &amp; CSS aren’t enough anymore and that everything is complicated –&nbsp;I think this is largely that the application stack for building websites has replaced the document stack in a lot of places. Where we would use Jekyll or server-side rendering, we now use React or Vue.js. There are advantages to that, but for a lot of minimally-interactive websites, it’s throwing away decades worth of knowledge in exchange for certain performance perks that might not even matter.</p><p>The appeal of social networks is partly because they let us create <em>documents</em> without thinking about web technology, and they provide guarantees around performance, accessibility, and polish that otherwise would take up our time. You don’t have to think about whether your last Facebook post will load quickly on your friend’s phone or whether your Instagram post will be correctly cropped and resized in the timeline - those things are taken care of.</p><p>To some extent, this doesn’t <em>need</em> to be something that only social networks provide, though: standards like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS">RSS</a> and services like <a href="https://www.instapaper.com/">Instapaper</a> show that pleasing formatting and distribution can be done at the <em>platform level</em> and be provided on top of existing vanilla websites.</p><details><summary>These are not absolutes.</summary>Yeah, I can hear it now: but these categories are not …</details></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://macwright.com/2020/08/22/clean-starts-for-the-web.html">https://macwright.com/2020/08/22/clean-starts-for-the-web.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://macwright.com/2020/08/22/clean-starts-for-the-web.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24255541</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 21:47:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Bare Metal Rust Generics]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 195 | Comments 40 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24254048">thread link</a>) | @cube00
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-1/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-1/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <p>I've had the pleasure to work with very experienced firmware developers; the
kind of people who know the size of their <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_zone_(computing)">red
zones</a> and routinely
transform coffee into linker scripts and pointer dereferences. In other words,
the <a href="http://www.catb.org/%7Eesr/jargon/html/story-of-mel.html">Mels</a> and <a href="https://www.usenix.org/system/files/1311_05-08_mickens.pdf">Zeus
Hammers</a> of the
world.</p>
<p>When it comes to the tools of our trade, many of them are curious and
experimental. Some of them—very much myself included—explore far enough to leave
pragmatism behind and veer into idealism, stubbornly forcing beautiful round
pegs into industrial square holes. Hey, maybe they're square for a reason, but
it doesn't hurt to try.</p>
<p>The majority of them aren't like that. Your average battle-tested firmware
developer has accrued a healthy distrust of the abstract, probably born of
watching shiny platonic constructs crash and burn with painfully <em>real</em> and
<em>concrete</em> error traces. It is sobering, having to chase a hardfault on a tiny
MCU across enough vtables and templated code to make Herb Sutter puke angle
brackets. No wonder modern approaches are met with some resistance unless the
LOADs and the STOREs are in clear view.</p>
<p>I felt this way too when someone suggested to me, back in 2014, that an
up-and-coming language called <a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/">Rust</a> showed promise
in the embedded field. <em>Surely not</em>, I thought, <em>too high level.</em> Even though I
had been playing with it already, my profoundly ingrained bit-twiddling
instincts told me not to trust a language that supported functional programming,
or one that dared to have an <em>opinion</em> on how I managed my memory. Bah! That's
how you get philosophers to run out of forks, and your forks to turn into
SIGSEGVs.</p>
<p>I was wrong.</p>
<p>Through the past five years of experimentation, I've gone from intrigued, to
optimistic, to <em>convinced</em> that Rust is an ideal language to build industrial
grade, bulletproof bare metal software. Beyond that, I've come to realize that
even the highest level constructs that the base language offers are applicable
to firmware development, very much unlike other languages that span a wide range
of paradigms (I'm looking at you, C++). There are a few reasons I felt this way:</p>
<ul>
<li>Rust's safety guarantees and general strictness bring the debug time down
significantly, so there's less need to spend time developing mental maps of
how high level constructs correspond to hardware primitives.</li>
<li>The type system is <em>great</em> at enforcing local reasoning and preventing leaky
abstractions. Building decoupled systems with no runtime cost is easy.</li>
<li>The compiler error messages are worthy of an AI assistant with <em>concerning</em>
mind-reading abilities.</li>
</ul>
<p>Lately, I've had the chance to work on a Rust
<a href="https://www.st.com/en/microcontrollers-microprocessors/stm32f412.html">STM32F412</a>
project in a professional setting, with one of the goals being to foster a Rust
knowledge pool at my company. The project, <code>Loadstone</code>, is a 32kb secure
bootloader targeting bare metal devices for the medical industry.</p>
<p>While it would've been easier—and much less of a headache to my colleagues—to
stick to a subset of Rust more familiar to C developers, with your <code>for</code>s, your
<code>*mut u8</code>s and your <code>unsafe</code>s, I instead decided not to pull any punches and
make liberal use of generics, iterator adapters, typestate programming and other
stuff that would've made 2010's cuervo cry blood and hug the closest copy of
Kernighan and Ritchie.</p>
<p>The pressures of a real collaborative project have taught me a lot, and many
assumptions have been refined thanks to the criticism of several skilled
outsiders who, as outsiders often do, had a privileged view on things I took for
granted.</p>
<p>A topic that came up frequently in code review is
<a href="https://thume.ca/2019/07/14/a-tour-of-metaprogramming-models-for-generics/">generics</a>.
Perhaps still recovering from a SFINAE nightmare, some colleagues were
unsure about the use of generics to group behaviour that we'd normally write
separate implementations for. The concerns tended to fall in one of three
categories:</p>
<ul>
<li>Runtime performance.</li>
<li>Binary size bloat.</li>
<li>Habitability and readability.</li>
</ul>
<p>The first is easy to dispel, as it often comes from unfamiliarity with static
dispatch. No vtables or heap allocations in anything we're doing, promise! The
second concern is valid but I've found it to be negligible in practice; I have
plans for another blog post giving some concrete benchmarks.</p>
<p>The last concern is the most subjective and thus the hardest to argue, so I
decided to focus on it in this blog series. I'll go over the design process of
two similar flash memory drivers, and hopefully show how generic programming can
make the job easier and the result more habitable, even in the barren, heapless,
rugged world of bare metal firmware.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Compile times are another common—and very valid—argument against liberal use
of generics. However, it is not a big problem for low footprint embedded
projects like this one.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flash_memory">Flash memory</a> is electronic
non-volatile storage. It's ubiquitous in consumer electronics; any time you
switch a small device off and it <em>remembers something</em>—whether it's settings,
songs, documents, even its own program—chances are you have flash memory to
thank. We'll be looking at two different <em>NOR</em> flash chips, since the first demo
port of <code>Loadstone</code> requires us to operate both:</p>
<ul>
<li>The embedded
<a href="https://www.st.com/en/microcontrollers-microprocessors/stm32f412.html">STM32F412</a>
1MB MCU flash.</li>
<li>The external 128MB <a href="https://www.micron.com/-/media/client/global/documents/products/data-sheet/nor-flash/serial-nor/n25q/n25q_128mb_1_8v_65nm.pdf">Micron
N25Q128</a>
flash chip present in the <a href="https://www.st.com/en/evaluation-tools/32f412gdiscovery.html">STM32F412ZGT6 Discovery
Kit</a></li>
</ul>
<p>You probably knew what flash memory is used for already, but what non-firmware
developers may not know is that flash memory is <em>quirky</em>. You cannot simply
write a byte to a NOR flash address, sir, that would be rude. While a blob of
flash memory will happily turn a <code>1</code> into a <code>0</code>, the opposite operation will
fail silently.</p>
<p>You can think of every <code>1</code> bit (NOR flash's <em>erased</em> state) as a lit candle you
can blow out. However, in this metaphor you don't get a lighter
to light them back up; you get a flamethrower. Without getting into the hardware
principles involved, the design of NOR flash memory requires that you erase
(i.e. set to <code>1</code>) memory <em>in bulk</em>, in chunks often orders of magnitude bigger
than the minimum addressable memory. On most chips you even have a three way
mismatch: your read, write and erase sizes aren't equal. Ugh.</p>
<p>As you can imagine, this makes writing flash drivers a bit of a pain,
particularly because even the smallest write operations turn into <em>read/write
cycles</em>. Writing a single byte requires reading the minimum erasable block
surrounding the targeted address (which may itself require multiple reads),
potentially erasing the entire block, then writing back the original data merged
with the desired byte.</p>
<p>As you can also imagine, nobody but the person writing this driver <em>wants to
care about this</em>. Even in the minimalistic world of bare metal software,
productive collaboration depends on developers filing away these sharp edges,
presenting interfaces that uniformize or hide any aspects of hardware irrelevant
to the bigger design. As such, a first stab at a flash memory interface should
simply offer a way to read and write ranges of memory.</p>
<p>Let's look at some code:</p>
<pre><code><span>pub trait </span><span>ReadWrite {
   </span><span>type </span><span>Error;
   </span><span>type </span><span>Address;
   </span><span>fn </span><span>read</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>mut </span><span>self</span><span>, </span><span>address</span><span>: </span><span>Self::</span><span>Address, </span><span>bytes</span><span>: </span><span>&amp;</span><span>mut</span><span> [</span><span>u8</span><span>]) -&gt; </span><span>Result</span><span>&lt;(), </span><span>Self::</span><span>Error&gt;;
   </span><span>fn </span><span>write</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>mut </span><span>self</span><span>, </span><span>address</span><span>: </span><span>Self::</span><span>Address, </span><span>bytes</span><span>: </span><span>&amp;</span><span>[</span><span>u8</span><span>]) -&gt; </span><span>Result</span><span>&lt;(), </span><span>Self::</span><span>Error&gt;;
   </span><span>fn </span><span>range</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>self</span><span>) -&gt; (</span><span>Self::</span><span>Address, </span><span>Self::</span><span>Address);
   </span><span>fn </span><span>erase</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>mut </span><span>self</span><span>) -&gt; </span><span>Result</span><span>&lt;(), </span><span>Self::</span><span>Error&gt;;
}
</span></code></pre>
<p>The above is what I converged on as a generic interface to a flash
driver. If you're unfamiliar with Rust generics, the above isn't a type, or a
parent class to inherit from. It's more like a Haskell typeclass; a set of
requirements for a concrete type to implement, described in this case in the
form of associated types (<code>Error</code> and <code>Address</code>) and method signatures (<code>read</code>,
<code>write</code>, <code>range</code> and <code>erase</code>).</p>
<p>Even at this early step, some tradeoffs have to be made. The keen,
hardfault-traumatized reader will notice that this interface doesn't lend itself
well to timing sensitive problems. All methods are blocking, and abstracting the
read/write cycle away will naturally lead to non-deterministic write times; a
write may take very little if it only requires toggling bits off, or it might
take very long if it straddles two big sectors requiring erase operations. The
<code>bytes</code> output parameter in <code>read</code> might also strike you as not too rusty, where
returning a <code>Vec&lt;u8&gt;</code> is often idiomatic. Unfortunately we have no heap to work
with, so if you want to take your bytes home you'll have to bring your own bag.</p>
<p>Indeed, it's hard to write the universal interface. This one made sense for the
problems we're solving, but make sure to keep in mind the requirements of your
project!</p>
<h3 id="why-not-simply-write-a-concrete-type">Why not simply write a concrete type?<a href="#why-not-simply-write-a-concrete-type" aria-label="Anchor link for: why-not-simply-write-a-concrete-type">🔗</a></h3>
<p>Ah, the word "simply" is tricky. Datasheet in hand, it may have been easier to
write. It might even save us a few bytes down the line. But altogether I think
the benefits of starting here are well worth the drawbacks:</p>
<ul>
<li>Makes it easy to write test doubles and leverage static dispatch for unit
testing. This kind of approach is what I miss the most when writing C, where
I'm forced to resort to link time substitution or to do things with the
preprocessor too vile to even mention here.</li>
<li>Decouples your design from the get go and makes collaboration easy. Another
developer can immediately start working against this interface, and it's
abstract enough to give you confidence it won't need to be changed as more
knowledge of the hardware emerges.</li>
<li>Going abstract first forces you to think long and hard about what behaviour is
common to each implementation and what behaviour isn't, which helps to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_repeat_yourself">not
repeat yourself</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>But the biggest reason, and one where C++ and Rust diverge, is the fact that
<em>you can reason about this interface locally</em>. This stems from a non-obvious
difference between the C++ template system and Rust traits. Where C++ templates
type check at the point of instantiation, Rust traits type check at the point of
definition.</p>
<p>What does this mean? It means that the inscrutable, seven-feet-deep-in-a-library
C++ template errors are impossible in Rust, because the compiler doesn't need to
go beyond the interface to prove it is used correctly.</p>
<p>A similar interface using C++ …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-1/">https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-1/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-1/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24254048</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 18:26:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Finding vulnerable Twitter accounts with expired domains]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 183 | Comments 113 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24252524">thread link</a>) | @zainamro
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://zainamro.com/hacks/finding-vulnerable-twitter-accounts | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://zainamro.com/hacks/finding-vulnerable-twitter-accounts">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
    <p><a href="https://zainamro.com/hacks">← hacks</a></p>
    <h3>Finding vulnerable Twitter accounts with expired domains</h3>
    <p>August 23, 2020</p>
    <p>Recently, I discovered a simple yet suprisingly effective attack vector against Twitter accounts (and which likely applies to other platforms as well). This attack vector makes it easy to find and hack vulnerable accounts with login emails that are using expired domains. If a user creates a Twitter account with an email on their own domain, then forgets to renew their domain at some point, that account can be hijacked by registering the domain, forwarding all emails to your email, then submitting a password reset on that account. By itself, this is hardly an attack vector since finding such vulnerable accounts is the more important part, and we already know that owning someone's email is essentially a "game over" situation. This attack becomes more dangerous when you can combine it with an efficient method to find these vulnerable accounts quickly and at scale. As it turns out, this is trivial on Twitter for several reasons attributable to their platform design.</p>
    <p>If you're familiar with Twitter, you know that users are given the option to add a public website url. With a simple script and proxy, an attacker can quickly iterate over millions of accounts and check if the domain in that url is not registered; this usually indicates some likelihood that the Twitter account was created with an email address on a now-expired domain. To verify this, they can submit a password reset which will show them a censored version of the account email address for confirmation; however, even though it's censored, it still provides enough information to check if the email domain matches the expired domain listed on their account profile. If it does, the attacker now knows this is an account that can be hacked. Once this entire process is automated, it makes finding these accounts very easy. This method of account hijacking is very likely being used right now by malicious hackers, and I believe it accounts for a large portion of stolen accounts/handles on the platform.</p>
    <img src="https://zainamro.com/assets/img/twitter-emails.png">
    <p>This attack can potentially be executed on other platforms besides Twitter, assuming one can find a similar discovery method. In Twitter's case, they could make it harder to discover these accounts by not showing any email confirmation upon requesting a password reset. This would make the process more costly for attackers who would no longer be able to verify whether an account can be hacked prior to registering the domain. Or perhaps, Twitter should monitor and unlist domains that are no longer registered and notify users when this happens so that they're aware. As for most users, in addition to turning on 2FA, it's important to be very cautious when using an email on your own domain to create accounts; it makes it much easier to lose access if you forget to renew or can't under certain extreme circumstances like incarceration or death.</p>
    <p><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24252524">Comments</a></p>
    <!-- Global site tag (gtag.js) - Google Analytics -->
    
    
  

</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://zainamro.com/hacks/finding-vulnerable-twitter-accounts</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24252524</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 15:25:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Persisting as a solo founder]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 622 | Comments 232 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24251403">thread link</a>) | @vishnumohandas
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://vishnu.tech/posts/persistence/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://vishnu.tech/posts/persistence/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><img src="https://sa.vishnu.tech/noscript.gif" alt="">




    



  



    
    <p><time itemprop="datePublished">August 19, 2020</time>
    </p>
    

<p>I quit my job in January 2020 to build a privacy friendly photo organizer.</p>

<p>As a 30 year old whose friends are either getting married or planning
off-springs, what I had underestimated was the difficulty involved in finding a co-founder and how that would compound the difficulty involved in
finding an investor.</p>

<p>Once I accepted the loneliness and the lack of a financial cushion I had to figure out a way to keep building without burning myself out.</p>

<p>It took me a while, but I have found a rhythm that works, and with it, a steady
source of endorphins. Here are some changes that helped me to keep things
moving.</p>

<h2 id="being-patient">Being patient</h2>

<p>Life is no longer as comfortable as it used to be and things are not always
going the way I want them to. Preseverance has been key and indirectly patience
too. Naval’s <a href="https://twitter.com/naval/status/1261481752448524289" target="_blank">take on
meditation</a> (60 minutes x
60 days), was an eye opener. I’ve stuck with it since, and I now have an easier
time identifying negative thought patterns and sitting out situations that would
otherwise overwhelm me.</p>

<p>On some level, spending the last few months locked indoors with my parents, who
are not the most rational people in the world has also helped. But I wouldn’t
recommend it.</p>

<h2 id="reducing-procrastination">Reducing procrastination</h2>

<p>Over time I’ve realized that action precedes motivation and procrastination precedes guilt.</p>

<p>Breaking down tasks into chunks that seem trivial to accomplish has helped reduce the friction in getting started on unexciting grunt work.</p>

<p>Then there are tasks which I loathe from my core, like writing out applications
to VCs explaining why what I’m doing will matter. To those I attach reinforcing
personal reasons, like, “I need the $50k to hire that college junior who I love
working with, and that will give me spare bandwidth to focus on traction channels”.</p>

<h2 id="thinking-clearer">Thinking clearer</h2>

<p>It is sub-optimal to not have a coworker to bounce ideas off and rant about problems to. A lot of times it’s these conversations that help you gain clarity.</p>

<p>It’s a luxury I do not have so every time I feel stuck, I type/scribble my thoughts out, and then question everything that was written, and then document my realizations.</p>

<p>Task tracking has also helped in clearing the path. I write down unstructured
thoughts into a diary, and once I’ve clarity, I promote them to a Notion board
(that’s divided into <em>Thinking</em>, <em>Building</em>, <em>Reading</em>, <em>Writing</em> and
<em>Adulting</em>) and every Monday within an Excel sheet I track what was done, and
what is left to be done.</p>

<h2 id="reducing-distractions">Reducing distractions</h2>

<p>I’ve reduced my information consumption to free up brain cycles. I’ve disabled all notifications on my phone barring a few contacts, and I’ve more or less stopped browsing on it. As an added bonus, this has reduced the negativity with which I perceived the world.</p>

<p>To minimize the overhead of context switches, I split tasks into a tree of checkpoints. Before taking a break I note down the next simplest checkpoint so that when I get back to work there’s little friction to resume.</p>

<p>To help me zone out I keep <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5qap5aO4i9A" target="_blank">lofi
beats</a> or
<a href="http://github.audio/" target="_blank">github.audio</a> playing in the background. Listening to the
latter gives me a strange sense of motivation and makes me feel less alone.</p>

<h2 id="staying-grounded">Staying grounded</h2>

<p>I’m lucky to have some friends who call/text every other week. I look at them as my accountability partners and I talk to them about what I’m doing on a high level. While not all of them genuinely care, some do, and these conversations force me to reflect on how well I’m doing what I’m doing.</p>

<p>While Silicon Valley wisdom suggests that if I’m not sleeping I should be
working, failing because of a burn out would be stupid. An advantage of not
having a VC onboard so far has been the freedom to dictate my pace. So I spend
days thinking, reading, fiddling with my violin or just doing nothing when I
feel like writing code is not what I want to do.</p>

<hr>

<p>It’s been 7 months of building alone, and while this is not how I pictured things to be on my last day at work, this is the happiest I have ever been. There’s a long way to go, and the grind seems inviting.</p>

<p>This list is by no means exhaustive, for I’m still learning. If you’ve
anything to share, please join <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24251403" target="_blank">the discussion on HackerNews</a>.</p>

<hr>

<p>If you are curious about what I’ve been building, check out
<a href="https://ente.io/" target="_blank">ente.io</a>.</p>

    <br>
    


</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://vishnu.tech/posts/persistence/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24251403</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 12:27:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
