<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 10]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 10. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 08:25:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-10.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 08:25:33 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Short History of Romaji]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 24 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25108455">thread link</a>) | @polm23
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://www.dampfkraft.com/romaji-history.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.dampfkraft.com/romaji-history.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I recently created a tool called <a href="https://github.com/polm/cutlet">cutlet</a> for converting Japanese to romaji.
While working on cutlet I was surprised at the difficulty of finding a good
guide to the difference between romaji systems, particularly their history and
usage, so I wrote this up.</p>
<h2 id="a-romaji-refresher"> A Romaji Refresher</h2>
<p>There are three relatively well-defined romaji systems. For a quick overview of
some of their differences:</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Japanese</th>
<th>新橋</th>
<th>お茶漬け</th>
<th>富士山</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Hepburn</td>
<td>Shinbashi (or Shimbashi)</td>
<td>ochazuke</td>
<td>Fujisan</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Kunreisiki</td>
<td>Sinbasi</td>
<td>otyazuke</td>
<td>Huzisan</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Nipponsiki</td>
<td>Sinbasi</td>
<td>otyaduke</td>
<td>Huzisan</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Hepburn is the most widely used outside Japan, Kunreisiki is officially taught
to children in Japan. Nipponsiki is similar to Kunreisiki but older. Technically
Hepburn uses macrons for long vowels while Kunreisiki and Nipponsiki use
circumflexes, but usage isn't consistent and there's no difference in meaning
between them.</p>
<p>In recent years "wapuro" romaji, based on input when typing Japanese, are also
relatively common, but it's not systematized (except in as far as programs
either take or don't take certain sequences) and isn't used in any kind of
formal writing.</p>
<h2 id="particle-comparison"> Particle Comparison</h2>
<p>As another refresher, here's how non-phonetic particles are represented in the
various systems.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Japanese</th>
<th>は</th>
<th>を</th>
<th>へ</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Hepburn</td>
<td>wa</td>
<td>wo</td>
<td>e</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Kunreisiki</td>
<td>wa</td>
<td>o</td>
<td>e</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Nipponsiki</td>
<td>ha</td>
<td>wo</td>
<td>he</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Hepburn is phonetic except for <em>wo</em>, Kunreisiki is strictly phonetic, and
Nipponsiki is strictly orthographic.</p>
<h2 id="early-romaji"> Early Romaji</h2>
<p>Japanese was first written in the Latin alphabet in the 1600s, mainly by
Christian missionaries. It was used by the missionaries for recording and
learning the language, and also used in texts they produced to try to spread
Christianity. Since Christianity was later supressed in Japan, these forms of
romaji never had wide adoption, though they influenced later efforts.</p>
<h2 id="the-origins-of-the-hepburn-system"> The Origins of the Hepburn System</h2>
<p>In 1867, missionary <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Curtis_Hepburn#Missionary_work_in_Japan">James Curtis Hepburn</a> published a
Japanese-English dictionary in Yokohama. Naturally he needed some way to write
Japanese words for people who couldn't read Japanese, so he devised a system of
representing Japanese that reflected the pronunciation of English consonants.
His system wasn't designed from the ground up, but developed based on his
knowledge of existing systems by other missionaries as well as his own
knowledge of Japanese.</p>
<p>Somewhat later, in 1885, an organization known as the
<a href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E3%83%AD%E3%83%BC%E3%83%9E%E5%AD%97%E8%AB%96#%E3%83%AD%E3%83%BC%E3%83%9E%E5%AD%97%E4%BC%9A">羅馬字会</a>
(Romajikai) was established. Mainly a society of Japanese academics, it was
interested in promoting the use of romaji as a replacement for kana and kanji.
Some motivations for getting rid of native writing systems included easier
international communication and improved domestic literacy. The principle
founders were <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ry%C5%8Dkichi_Yatabe">Ryoukichi Yatabe</a>, a botanist and the first Japanese graduate of Cornell, and <a href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E5%A4%96%E5%B1%B1%E6%AD%A3%E4%B8%80">Masakazu Toyama</a>, a <a href="https://ii.umich.edu/cjs/history-of-cjs.html">graduate of the University of Michigan</a> who
later occupied a high post at what would eventually become Tokyo University.</p>
<figure><a href="https://www.dampfkraft.com/by-id/4d041d6a/max-moritz-romaji.jpg"><img src="https://www.dampfkraft.com/by-id/4d041d6a/img/max-moritz-romaji.jpg.l.jpg"></a><figcaption>The Romajikai published books to promote romaji, including this translation of Max and Moritz, titled "Wampaku Monogatari". This edition was reprinted in 1978. via <a href="https://www.wul.waseda.ac.jp/kotenseki/html/he22/he22_07214/index.html">Waseda University</a>
</figcaption></figure>
<p>In 1886 the Romajikai published <a href="https://dl.ndl.go.jp/info:ndljp/pid/862485">a romaji system</a>. Also in 1886
Hepburn published the third edition of his dictionary, which roughly used the
system.  I've had trouble finding the exact nature of the influence between
Hepburn's system and the Romajikai, but they were on friendly terms and
cooperating. Hepburn's dictionary's third edition took off, the romaji system
mainly came to be called by his name, and it became widely established,
particularly among foreigners dealing with Japan.</p>
<p>If you're interested in learning more about Hepburn's dictionaries, a <a href="http://www.meijigakuin.ac.jp/mgda/waei/">wealth
of information</a> is available via Meiji Gakuin University
Library, including a comparison of romaji in all published versions and
manuscripts.</p>
<h2 id="the-origins-of-the-nipponsiki-system"> The Origins of the Nipponsiki System</h2>
<p>Around the time the Romajikai was established, one of the members, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tanakadate_Aikitsu">Aikitu
Tanakadate</a>, developed his
own romaji system, based on some existing informal conventions, that was
specifically designed to mirror the structure of Japanese kana without regard
to foreign pronunciation.</p>
<p>In 1885 Tanakadate proposed this new system to the Romajikai, but they
ultimately rejected his proposal in favor of keeping Hepburn. As a result
Tanakadate left the Romajikai and promoted Nipponsiki on his own. Before
becoming known as "Nipponsiki" this style of Romanization was known as
"Tanakadatesiki".</p>
<p>The disagreement between Tanakadate was only the first in a long series of
arguments between Hepburn and Nipponsiki proponents.</p>
<p>Tanakadate was around 30 when he invented this system, and most of his later
career was in physics. He worked with Lord Kelvin in Scotland and helped bring
about the adoption of the metric system in Japan. He used romaji in personal
writings and promoted it throughout his life. We'll be seeing him again later.</p>
<h2 id="standard-form-and-the-romaji-hirome-kai"> Standard Form and the Romaji Hirome Kai</h2>
<p>In 1905 the ローマ字ひろめ会 (Romaji Hirome Kai, "Society for the Advancement
of Romaji") was established. They published a magazine, called simply "Rômaji",
to create more reading material in romaji and spread its use within Japan.  By
this point Toyama and Yatabe had both passed away, and it's unclear if the
original Romajikai still existed in any capacity. An important early member of
the new society was <a href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E8%97%A4%E5%B2%A1%E5%8B%9D%E4%BA%8C">Katsuji Fujioka</a>, who wrote the
<a href="https://dl.ndl.go.jp/info:ndljp/pid/942994">羅馬字手引</a> (Romaji Tebiki), a kind of romaji dictionary.</p>
<p>Shortly after it was founded the Romaji Hirome Kai proposed a slightly modified
Hepburn and called it 標準式, or "Standard Form". Note that this is "Standard
Form" in general, not "Standard Hepburn", suggesting this was some kind of
official standard romanization system; this may have been a response to
Tanakadatesiki becoming known as "Nipponsiki", which could imply that other
romaji systems were "foreign". As we'll see in a bit, this rhetorical trick
ultimately didn't help official adoption.</p>
<p>I haven't been able to track down the original document with Standard Form, but
the Romaji Tebiki was already using it in 1906.</p>
<p>Standard Form replaced macrons with circumflexes and always romanized ん as
"n", rather than sometimes using "m" depending on the following consonant.</p>
<p>Tanakadate was still around and joined the Romaji Hirome Kai at some point, but
got fed up with their use of Hepburn, left, and founded his own organization in
1914.</p>
<h2 id="the-origins-of-kunreisiki"> The Origins of Kunreisiki</h2>
<p>In 1930 the government formed a committee to evaluate various romaji systems
for official government use. At this point Tanakadate was a member of the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/House_of_Peers_(Japan)">House of Peers</a>, and Romaji Hirome Kai member and Hepburn proponent
Fujioka was not a politician, but had political influence due to his long and
prominent career as a linguist. Both were involved with the government
committee.</p>
<p>While the system used at this point varied considerably by government agency,
Hepburn was more popular, so it seemed slated for official adoption.  However,
in 1935 Fujioka died of illness. In 1937, following a recommendation from the
committee, a slightly modified version of Tanakadate's Nipponsiki, dubbed
Kunreisiki, was established as the official government romaji system.</p>
<p>The main difference between Kunreisiki and Nipponsiki is that kana that are not
pronounced differently in standard modern Japanese are spelled as their more
common counterpart (づ and ず are both <em>zu</em>), though there are other
differences, like how particles are represented, and how ambiguous phonetic
boundaries are written.</p>
<h2 id="the-war"> The War</h2>
<p>Despite the recent official adoption of a government-approved romaji system,
around 1938 a number of more radical romaji proponents were arrested as
potential (or actual) anti-nationalists. One example was Esperantist and
language researcher <a href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E6%96%8E%E8%97%A4%E7%A7%80%E4%B8%80">Hidekatsu Saitou</a>, who contracted tuberculosis in
prison and died in 1940.</p>
<p>Following World War 2, the occupying American forces rescinded the law making
Kunreisiki official and ordered the use of Hepburn for public signage and
documents. During the occupation, an American educational commission
<a href="https://babel.hathitrust.org/cgi/pt?id=pur1.32754081234191&amp;view=1up&amp;seq=28">recommended native Japanese writing be replaced with romaji</a>.
This never happened, though romaji became a standard component of post-war
education.</p>
<p>Post-war the development of romaji became less dramatic, as serious proponents
of replacing Japanese writing systems with romaji mostly disappeared. There
have been a number of laws and rules issued by the government over the years,
as well as a few special systems like the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JSL_romanization">unique system</a> developed for a
textbook called "Japanese: The Spoken Language", but Hepburn and
Nipponsiki/Kunreisiki remain the major systems.</p>
<p>There is also much to be written about interaction of romaji with computers,
but that's best left for another time.</p>
<h2 id="what-about-revised-hepburn%3F"> What About Revised Hepburn?</h2>
<p>Sometimes you'll see references to "Revised Hepburn", but nobody knows what
this is. It is used to mean, variously:</p>
<ul>
<li>Hepburn's system in his third edition, in contrast to earlier editions</li>
<li>the 1905 version by the ローマ字ひろめ会 (properly 標準式 or "standard form")</li>
<li>a version introduced with Kenkyuusha's "New Japanese-English Dictionary" in 1954, subsequently <a href="https://www.loc.gov/catdir/cpso/romanization/japanese.pdf">adopted by the American Library of Congress</a></li>
<li>other minor variants proposed at different times</li>
</ul>
<p>While the Library of Congress is surely consistent in their romaji usage, their
choice of a particular 1954 dictionary is a bit odd, and distinguishing it from
the similar 1905 system is a source of confusion. At one point it seemed like
Hepburn might become an ANSI standard, but instead Kunreisiki was adopted, and
that standard (Z39.11-1972) has since been deprecated. This lack of an official
standard contributes to inconsistency in what "Revised Hepburn" means.</p>
<p>In contrast, "traditional Hepburn" is somewhat reliably used to refer to the
system used in Hepburn's third edition as opposed to later forms.</p>
<p>Another common variant, "passport Hepburn" refers to the system previously
mandated for names on Japanese passports, which included some exceptions to
normal Hepburn, but those requirements are <a href="https://www.mofa.go.jp/mofaj/toko/passport/pass_4.html#q17">no longer strictly in force</a>,
and you can use any romanization you want (such as "George" for what would be
"Jouji" in Hepburn) if you have …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.dampfkraft.com/romaji-history.html">https://www.dampfkraft.com/romaji-history.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.dampfkraft.com/romaji-history.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25108455</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 05:39:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Apple Responds to macOS Privacy Concerns, Explains Why Apps Were Slow to Launch]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 16 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25108108">thread link</a>) | @svrma
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://www.iphoneincanada.ca/mac/apple-responds-to-macos-privacy-concerns-explains-why-apps-were-slow-to-launch/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.iphoneincanada.ca/mac/apple-responds-to-macos-privacy-concerns-explains-why-apps-were-slow-to-launch/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>


<!-- .entry-social-links -->
<div>
	
	
	
		
		
	
<!-- .entry-social-links -->	
		
		
	<div>
	<p><a href="https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Apple_macOS-catalina-available-today_100719_big.jpg.large_.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Apple_macOS-catalina-available-today_100719_big.jpg.large_.jpg" alt="" width="799" height="549" srcset="https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Apple_macOS-catalina-available-today_100719_big.jpg.large_.jpg 799w, https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Apple_macOS-catalina-available-today_100719_big.jpg.large_-350x240.jpg 350w, https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Apple_macOS-catalina-available-today_100719_big.jpg.large_-768x528.jpg 768w, https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Apple_macOS-catalina-available-today_100719_big.jpg.large_-640x440.jpg 640w, https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Apple_macOS-catalina-available-today_100719_big.jpg.large_-660x453.jpg 660w, https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Apple_macOS-catalina-available-today_100719_big.jpg.large_-560x385.jpg 560w" sizes="(max-width: 799px) 100vw, 799px"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.iphoneincanada.ca/news/privacy-concerns-emerge-following-apple-ocsp-server-outage/">Following privacy concerns from Mac users after Apple’s Online Certificate Status Protocol (OCSP) server went down, </a>thus causing third-party applications unable to open on Macs, Apple has now responded to the situation,&nbsp; exacerbated by a recent blog post by Jeffrey Paul.</p>	
	
	
	
<p>An Apple spokesperson told<em> iPhone in Canada</em> it had updated its support document, ‘Safely open apps on your Mac’, to now further detail its privacy protections.</p>
<p>“Gatekeeper performs online checks to verify if an app contains known malware and whether the developer’s signing certificate is revoked,” <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT202491">explains</a> Apple. “We have never&nbsp;combined data from these checks with information about Apple users or their devices. We do not use data from these checks to learn what individual users are&nbsp;launching or running on their devices,” clarified the company.</p>
<p>“Notarization checks if the app contains known malware using an encrypted connection that is resilient to server failures,” says Apple, further emphasizing, “These security checks have never included the user’s Apple ID or the identity of their device. To further protect privacy, we have stopped logging IP addresses&nbsp;associated with Developer ID certificate checks, and we will ensure that any collected IP addresses are removed from logs,” details Apple.</p>
<p>On top of this, Apple says “over the next year we will introduce several changes to our security checks,” specifically:</p>
<ul>
<li>a new encrypted protocol for Developer ID certificate revocation checks</li>
<li>strong protections against server failure</li>
<li>a new preference for users to opt out of these security protections</li>
</ul>
<p>Apple also gave some further technical information on the situation to <em>iPhone in Canada.</em> Certificate revocation checks occur to verify that Developer ID certificates used to sign an app have not been revoked by the company. The move is critical for security since a certificate may be pulled if a developer suspects it has been compromised by third parties, or is being used to sign malicious apps.</p>
<p>The industry-standard online certificate status protocol (OCSP) is used by macOS to verify that the Developer ID code signing certificate issued to an app developer has not been revoked. This OCSP request does not include the Apple ID of the user, or reveal a device or app being launched.</p>
<p>Apple says since OCSP is used to check other certificates, including those used to encrypted web connections, these requests happen over unencrypted HTTP, as normal throughout the industry.</p>
<p>HTTP is used to prevent&nbsp;situations where verifying the validity of the certificate that secures the connection to an OCSP server would potentially depend on the result of a request to that same&nbsp;OCSP server, creating a loop that would make it impossible to resolve the request, according to Apple.</p>
<p>Apple says on macOS Catalina and later, by default, all apps running are notarized by the company to note they have been checked by Apple for known malicious software. When an app launches, macOS will check to verify that the app has not been labeled as malicious by Apple since it was first notarized. These checks happen over an encrypted connection—and are resilient to server failures. Which is what happened the other day and users saw their apps hang and take forever to launch.</p>
<p>What caused the OCSP server problem? Apple says it was due to a server-side misconfiguration that specifically interfered with macOS being able to cache OCSP responses for Developer ID. This configuration error, along with an unrelated content delivery network (CDN) misconfiguration, is what caused the slow performance for apps to launch.</p>
<p>Apple explained to <em>iPhone in Canada</em> it has already fixed this performance issue through a server-side update, that will now allow macOS to cache Developer ID OCSP checks for a longer period. macOS users do not need to do anything to benefit from this Apple update.</p>
<p>App notarization checks are used to verify that apps being launched in macOS have not been found to be malicious by Apple, since they were first notarized. Apple says these checks take place over an encrypted connection and are immune to server failures. Notarization checks were not affected by the server-side issue that caused OCSP requests to fail.</p>

	</div>

</div><!-- .entry-inner -->
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.iphoneincanada.ca/mac/apple-responds-to-macos-privacy-concerns-explains-why-apps-were-slow-to-launch/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25108108</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 04:44:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Laser-Guided Lightning May Help Prevent Wildfires]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 76 | Comments 53 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25103339">thread link</a>) | @kposehn
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://www.breakingasia.com/news/laser-guided-lightning-may-help-prevent-wildfires/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.breakingasia.com/news/laser-guided-lightning-may-help-prevent-wildfires/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
				
				
				<div>
				
				
				<p><h2>Small, portable laser pointers could be used to guide lightning strikes, with a study suggesting the technology may prevent bolts from sparking wildfires, a researcher told AFP Thursday.</h2></p>
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_text --><div>
				
				
				<div><p>A team of international scientists have shown storm clouds could be “short-circuited” by using a hollow laser — like a pipe of light — to deliver particles into the clouds and draw lightning strikes, research co-author Professor Andrey Miroshnichenko from the University of New South Wales in Canberra told AFP.</p>
<p>In lab tests, the team — which also included scientists from the Australian National University (ANU) — successfully used a laser tractor beam to direct the path of an electrical discharge to specific targets, Miroshnichenko said.</p>
<p>In the past, high-powered lasers were needed to achieve similar results, making the technique dangerous, costly and inaccurate.<span>&nbsp;</span></p></div>
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_text --><div>
				
				
				<p><iframe title="Bushfires in Australia: What ignited the deadly crisis" width="1080" height="608" src="about:blank" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-l28KQ8dJDM?feature=oembed" data-no-lazy="1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
				
			</div><div>
				
				
				<div><p>But the new research suggested that small, hand-held lasers could be used in the field within the next decade, he said.</p>
<p>“It turns out that to deliver particles, you do not need high-intensity lasers, even low intensity like your laser pointer will be already enough,” Miroshnichenko said.</p>
<p>Using a tractor beam with a hollow centre, micro-particles in the air could be heated up and delivered to a specific point and trigger an electrical discharge.</p></div>
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_text --><p><span><img src="https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle.jpg" data-src="https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle.jpg" alt="Electrical Discharge Induce by Microparticle" title="Electrical Discharge Induce by Microparticle" height="auto" width="auto" data-srcset="https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle.jpg 800w, https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle-300x167.jpg 300w, https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle-768x427.jpg 768w" data-sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" srcset="https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle.jpg 800w, https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle-300x167.jpg 300w, https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle-768x427.jpg 768w"></span>
			</p><div>
				
				
				<p>The electrical discharge induced by a heated microparticle.</p>
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_text --><div>
				
				
				<div><p>Although it is yet to be tested outside a lab, the technique could potentially be used to control dry lightning strikes, infamous for sparking large blazes including several major <a href="https://www.breakingasia.com/trending/social-media-fakes-australia-bushfire-disinformation/">bushfires in Australia</a> and the western US in the past year, Miroshnichenko added.</p>
<p>“We can imagine a future where this technology may induce electrical discharge from passing lightning, helping to guide it to safe targets and reduce the risk of <a href="https://www.breakingasia.com/trending/makeshift-hospital-saving-dozens-of-koalas-injured-in-bushfires/">catastrophic fires</a>,” co-researcher Vladlen Shvedov, from the ANU Research School of Physics, said.</p>
<p>The research, published in <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-19183-0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nature Communications last month</a>, also involved Texas A&amp;M University in Qatar and the University of California in Los Angeles.<span>&nbsp;</span></p></div>
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_text -->
			</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.breakingasia.com/news/laser-guided-lightning-may-help-prevent-wildfires/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25103339</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 18:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Create Vintage Videos Using FFmpeg in 4 Simple Steps]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 273 | Comments 45 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25102401">thread link</a>) | @ponderingfish
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://ottverse.com/create-vintage-videos-using-ffmpeg/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ottverse.com/create-vintage-videos-using-ffmpeg/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p><strong>It’s time for the holidays and what better way to share love and memories with your family than to create an old-school, vintage movie? You don’t need a time-machine to go back to the 50s or 60s to rmake your homevideo look like a vintage movie. All you need is FFmpeg, some imagination, and perhaps the rest of this guide 🙂 </strong></p>



<p>Let’s take a look at how you can use FFmpeg to make your videos look like old-school/vintage/retro-styled movies, shall we?</p>



<hr>



<h2>What’s Do I Mean By A Vintage Movie?</h2>



<p>Well, good question! </p>



<p><strong>My definition of an old-school movie is a movie with a low frame-rate (like 15 fps), lots of scratches and film-grain to give an aged look, and a sepia tint to it!</strong></p>



<p>Let’s see how we can achieve all of this using FFmpeg.</p>



<p>For this tutorial, I shall be using the “Touchdown Pass” sequence from <a href="https://media.xiph.org/video/derf/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xiph</a> to illustrate the steps. It’s a 20 second video, but for the sake of this tutorial, I’ll be cutting it to 10 seconds using FFmpeg (<a href="https://ottverse.com/trim-cut-video-using-start-endtime-reencoding-ffmpeg/">here’s how to do that</a>).</p>



<p>Let’s get started! </p>



<hr>



<h2>Step 1: Changing the Frame Rate using FFmpeg</h2>



<p>The first step is to “speed” up the video. Let’s take the video back to pre-30fps or pre-60fps days and take it all the way down to 10 fps. This gives the video an old-school look right off the bat! </p>



<pre><code>ffmpeg.exe -i td-10sec.mp4 \
-filter:v fps=fps=10 \
td-fast.mp4</code></pre>



<p>Here is the sped-up video. </p>



<p><iframe frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/479524704" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></iframe></p>



<hr>



<h2>Step 2: Give The Video a Vintage Look using FFmpeg’s filters</h2>



<p>Next, let’s change the rich, wonderful colors and bring a sepia-link tint to the entire video. This can be done using FFmpeg’s in-built <code>curves</code> filter. You can use the <code>curves</code> filter to change the amount of R, G, B in a frame and specify the “curves” that govern the change or shift in colors. </p>



<p>Luckily for us, FFmpeg has a pre-defined <code>vintage</code> filter that works pretty well, I must say! Here is the commandline to convert our sped-up video into a “vintage” looking video. Simple, right?</p>



<pre><code>ffmpeg.exe -i td-fast.mp4 \
-vf curves=vintage \
td-vintage-fast.mp4</code></pre>



<p>Here’s the result of the <code>curves=vintage</code> filter on our footall video.</p>



<p><iframe frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/479525304" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></iframe></p>



<hr>



<h2>Step 3: Getting a Film Grain Overlay and Resizing It</h2>



<p>As the final step, let’s add a lot of film-grain and “scratches” to make our video look like something that was shot on film, stored in a dusty old cupboard, and discovered 40 years later! </p>



<p>I found a fantastic “old school” film overlay on YouTube (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J_MZb7qTenE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">source link</a>) with a download link. </p>



<figure><div>
<p><span><iframe width="1200" height="675" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/J_MZb7qTenE?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;fs=1&amp;hl=en-US&amp;autohide=2&amp;wmode=transparent" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></iframe></span></p>
</div></figure>



<p>The video’s size is <code>1440x1080</code> pixels and so I had to resize it to <code>1920x1080</code> to match the size of my input video. </p>



<p>Here is the command to resize a video using FFmpeg using the the <code>scale</code> filter. I’ve stored the output video as <code>oldFilm1080.mp4</code>.</p>



<pre><code>ffmpeg -i old-film-grain.wmv \
-vf scale=1920:1080,setsar=1:1 \
oldFilm1080.mp4</code></pre>



<hr>



<h2>Step 4: Add the Overlay To Your Video</h2>



<p>Now we have two videos with us – </p>



<ol><li>our old-school film-grain-scratchy video</li><li>our vintage-looking, sped-up football video. </li></ol>



<p>Now all that’s left to do is to overlay them on each other and enjoy the fruits of <s>our</s> FFmpeg’s labor! </p>



<p>Here’s the commandline to achieve that. </p>



<pre><code>ffmpeg.exe \
-i oldFilm1080.mp4 \
-i td-vintage-fast.mp4 \
-filter_complex "[0]format=rgba,colorchannelmixer=aa=0.25[fg];\
[1][fg]overlay[out]" \
-map [out] \
-pix_fmt yuv420p -c:v libx264 -crf 18 \
touchdown-vintage.mp4</code></pre>



<p>So, what’s going on here? </p>



<ul><li>we provide two input videos to FFmpeg </li><li>using <code>filter_complex</code>, we use <code>colorchannelmixer</code> to overlay by modifying the alpha channel of the film-grain video that is referred to as <code>[0]</code> and and let’s call the output <code>[fg]</code>. It’s black and white, so modifying only the alpha is good enough for our use case. The syntax is as follows <code>colorchannelmixer=rr:rg:rb:ra:gr:gg:gb:ga:br:bg:bb:ba:ar:ag:ab:aa</code>. </li><li>we are modifying only the alpha, and so, we modify only the <code>aa</code> (output’s alpha) to <code>0.25</code>.</li><li>then, we use the vintage-looking football video (referred to as <code>[1]</code>) and overlay them both using the <code>overlay</code> filter to create an interim output stored in a variable called <code>[out]</code>. This is shown in the commands –&gt; <code>[1][fg]overlay[out]</code></li><li>then, we encode the interim output to give us the final video using H.264 with <code>crf=18</code> which should give us a good quality video.</li></ul>







<p><strong>Here is what the final output looks like! Cool, isn’t it? </strong></p>



<p><iframe frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/479529512" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></iframe></p>







<p>And, here’s how it looks side-by-side the original video. </p>



<p><iframe frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/479529447" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></iframe></p>







<p>Now you can change the opacity of the alpha channels, use a different film grain video, or use a different <code>curves</code> function, but, the process won’t change much. </p>



<p>Hope you all have a lot of fun making “<strong>vintage</strong>” videos this holiday season and please let me know in the comments how it went! Please create some fun videos, share them with your loved ones, and have a few laughs 🙂 </p>



<p>Thank you! </p>



<p>If you enjoyed this post, do check out the rest of<a href="https://ottverse.com/category/ffmpeg/"> <strong>OTTVerse’s FFmpeg tutorials</strong></a> to learn more about how to use FFmpeg to improve your video editing, compression, and processing skills!</p>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ottverse.com/create-vintage-videos-using-ffmpeg/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25102401</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 16:33:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Case for Properties: Programming Language Design]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 37 | Comments 45 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25102163">thread link</a>) | @WillBAnders
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://blog.willbanders.dev/articles/a-case-for-properties.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.willbanders.dev/articles/a-case-for-properties.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
                <div>
                    
                    <div>
                        <div>
                            <p><span>November 15, 2020</span><br>
                                <span><em>~12m read time</em></span>
                            </p>
                            <p><span>November 15, 2020</span><br>
                                <span><em>~12m read time</em></span>
                            </p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <p>Properties are a really nice feature of modern languages, and I've recently
                    gotten attached to them in Kotlin. For a while
                    I wasn't comfortable with the idea of 'fields' performing arbitrary computation,
                    but having used them for a few months now I'm really enjoying the simplicity -
                    <em>especially</em> when moving back to Java!</p>
                <p>Having given it some thought, I wanted to lay out a case in support of
                    properties which highlights their benefits over directly accessing fields (which
                    is mostly about getters/setters, but nonetheless), and how we can establish some
                    guidelines on when properties should not be used to avoid the issue of
                    arbitrary computation causing side effects or other unexpected behavior.</p>
                
                <p>In short, a property is <abbr title="Features which aid readability or ease of use but do not impact semantics.">syntax sugar</abbr> for getter/setter methods that look
                    like fields. Instead of having to use the methods <code>item.getQuantity()</code> and
                    <code>item.setQuantity()</code>, we can access the property <code>item.quantity</code> and set it
                    using <code>item.quantity = 1</code>, exactly like a field. The compiler transforms property
                    access and assignment to use the appropriate getters/setters (hence, syntax sugar).
                </p>
                <p>The most noteworthy consequence of this is, in my opinion, allowing <em>validation
                    on assigment</em>. For example, <code>item.quantity</code> may be defined as follows (in Kotlin):</p>
<pre><span>class</span> <span>Item</span> {
    <span>var</span> <span>quantity</span>: <span>Int</span> = <span>0</span>
        <span>set</span>(value) {
            require(value &gt;= <span>0</span>) <span>//throws if negative</span>
            <span>field</span> = value
        }
}
</pre>
<pre><span>
  <i onclick="openDemo('item-property', this)"></i>
</span>item.<span>quantity</span> = <span>-10</span>;
</pre>
                
                <p>The largest benefit of properties is replacing field use, which has a massive
                    amount of drawbacks, with methods instead. In languages like C++ and Java that
                    don't have properties, the best practice is to keep all fields private and
                    manually create getters and setters. More modern languages, like C# and Kotlin,
                    use properties for this instead which can do that automatically.</p>
                <p>Most of the following points are also benefits of using getters/setters over
                    fields, and then properties step in to provide the extra bit of syntax sugar icing on
                    the cake.</p>
                <div>
                    <div>
                        <h3 id="api-safety-and-compatibility">
                            <span>
                                <a href="#api-safety-and-compatibility">
                                    <i></i>
                                </a>
                            </span>
                            <span>API Safety and Compatibility</span>
                        </h3>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <ol>
                    <li>Property getters/setters can have different <abbr title="public/private and friends">access modifiers</abbr>, allowing for
                        fields which are read-only for external use but still mutable within the class.
                        <ul>
                            <li>Example: In Kotlin, <code>val&nbsp;counter&nbsp;=&nbsp;0&nbsp;private&nbsp;set</code>
                                defines a <code>counter</code> field that can be publicly accessed but not modified (unless within the class).
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li>Getters/setters can be used to maintain <abbr title="A (mathematical) property which is expected to hold true in all cases

For example, a unit vector (3D) has the invariant x² + y² + z² == 1.">invariants</abbr> and perform other
                        validation work, such as <code>quantity&nbsp;&gt;=&nbsp;0</code> in the opening example.
                    </li>
                    <li>Since getters/setters are methods, the implementation can be changed without
                        breaking either <abbr title="Application Programming Interface

The interface of the *source* code">API</abbr> or <abbr title="Application Binary Interface

The interface of the *compiled* code">ABI</abbr> compatibility.
                        <ul>
                            <li>Example: A <code>Vector</code> class could have <code>x/y/z</code> properties, but
                                change the implementation to use a component array <code>[x, y, z]</code> instead without issue.
                            </li>
                            <li>Additionally, getters/setters can be inlined during optimization to speed up performance at the cost of ABI compatibility.
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                </ol>
                
                <ol>
                    <li>Properties can be used in interfaces since they're backed by methods, while fields require getters/setters to be defined for them. Notably, these getters/setters would still need to have fields defined in the implementing class to handle their values, while a property can handle that automatically.
                    </li>
                    <li>Properties can be used for methods which often behave like fields, but
                        cannot be implemented with one due to subtypes requiring computation or
                        other restrictions.
                        <ul>
                            <li>Example: <code>List#size()</code> generally doesn't need computation and returns the
                                value of a field, but some implementations (such as a <abbr title="A form of linked list which doesn't track its size, comes from Lisp

Honestly google it, this text box can't do it justice">cons list</abbr>) might.
                            </li>
                            <li>Whether <code>List#size()</code> should be a property is certainly debatable, but with how frequently collections are used I think it's almost a necessity.
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                </ol>
                
                <ol>
                    <li>Properties are a <em>single unit</em>. Getters/setters are located in the same
                        location in the source code as the property declaration, making it easier to
                        fully understand a field as opposed to having them defined in separate locations.
                    </li>
                    <li>Properties almost always have syntax sugar for providing default
                        implementations of <code>get/set</code> (if it's not already done automatically). In Kotlin, <code>val property</code> provides a default
                        getter while <code>var property</code> provides both a getter and setter.
                    </li>
                    <li>Debugging properties is possible without a dedicated debugger by using
                        getters/setters. This may be minor for large languages, but if your language
                        doesn't have an IDE or still in development this is <em>extremely</em> useful.
                    </li>
                    <li>Readability is often increased, albeit debatable. I personally find <code>item.quantity&nbsp;=&nbsp;1</code> to
                        be more readable than <code>item.setQuantity(1)</code>, especially in large chains.
                    </li>
                    <li>Generally, properties imply 'simple' behavior, like fields, as opposed to complex
                        computation that some methods may perform. We'll talk about this in detail soon.
                    </li>
                </ol>
                <div>
                    <div>
                        <h2 id="so-what-are-the-downsides">
                            <span>
                                <a href="#so-what-are-the-downsides">
                                    <i></i>
                                </a>
                            </span>
                            <span>So what are the downsides?</span>
                        </h2>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <p>I think there are two notable downsides to having properties. First, the
                    performance difference between field access and method calls can be significant,
                    especially in low level languages. Second, field access has clear, well-defined
                    behavior while a method call could effectively do anything, thus making it
                    harder to reason about code. Let's dig in to both of these.</p>
                
                <p>Field access is almost always language primitive, and is therefore faster than
                    doing the work of a method call (which then has to access <em>something</em> anyways).</p>
                <p>That said, compiler optimizations like <abbr title="Replacing a method call with it's implementation">inlining</abbr> can easily resolve this for
                    simple properties. In more complex cases, this is actually where properties are
                    most useful - a field itself wasn't sufficient, so the alternative would have
                    been a method call or sacrificing validation anyways.</p>
                <p>In low level languages where memory layout is often important, knowing a field
                    access corresponds to a memory lookup (and not arbitrary computation) can be
                    important. In higher level languages, particularly Object Oriented ones that
                    often encapsulate fields behind methods anyways, I don't believe this
                    distinction is as necessary.</p>
                <div>
                    <div>
                        <h3 id="problem-2-arbitrary-computation">
                            <span>
                                <a href="#problem-2-arbitrary-computation">
                                    <i></i>
                                </a>
                            </span>
                            <span>Problem 2: Arbitrary Computation</span>
                        </h3>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <p>Finally, we've made our way to what I believe is the core issue: since
                    properties can perform arbitrary computation, it is unclear what potential
                    behavior getting/setting a property may have. The extreme example here, of
                    course, is deleting the entire file system. Fields on the other hand have
                    clearly defined behavior - get or set the value, nothing more.</p>
                <p>However, these type of assumptions are not unique to properties. We apply the
                    same assumptions to methods (and honestly everything) as well. I often presume
                    that <code>getX()</code> and <code>setX(x)</code> have 'simple' behavior, but they could use lazy
                    initialization, have unexpected validation checks, or cause side-effects and
                    other unexpected behavior
                    like a database <code>getConnection()</code>. Naming is one of the two hard problems in computer science,
                    likely because we carry assumptions with us that may not always fit.</p>
                <p>That said, these assumptions …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.willbanders.dev/articles/a-case-for-properties.html">https://blog.willbanders.dev/articles/a-case-for-properties.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.willbanders.dev/articles/a-case-for-properties.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25102163</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 16:04:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Moving my serverless project to Ruby on Rails]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 329 | Comments 170 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25100397">thread link</a>) | @pcr910303
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://frantic.im/back-to-rails | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://frantic.im/back-to-rails">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
  <header>
    
    
  </header>
  <p>I have a small side project: <a href="https://hacker.gifts/">digital gift cards for hackers</a>. It uses Shopify for all the store-related stuff: frontend, payments, refunds, reports, etc.</p>

<p>But unlike regular digital products (ebooks, videos) I wanted each card that the user purchases from the store to be unique. So I made a  script that generates personalized images and ran it manually for every order.</p>

<p>The next logical step was automating this process. I started with serverless AWS Lambda. At the time it was the hot new tech and I wanted to learn more. It seemed very fitting for my use-case: single-responsibility functions that can run at any time and don’t require server maintenance.</p>

<p><img src="https://frantic.im/assets/back-to-rails/simple-lambda.png" alt=""></p>

<p>It was super easy to get started. I built a JavaScript function and deployed it to AWS Lambda, added Shopify web hook and it all worked!</p>

<p>Early benefits of serverless (for hobby projects):</p>

<ul>
  <li>Easy to get started</li>
  <li>Don’t have to configure or maintain servers</li>
  <li>Free for small loads</li>
</ul>

<p>In reality, writing the simple Lambda functions turned out to be only 10% of the work.</p>

<p>Time passed and my backend started getting more complex: I needed to store some state for each <a href="https://hacker.gifts/products/space-invaders">puzzle</a>, send confirmation emails, show an order details page. What started as a simple function, grew into a bunch of serverless functions, SNS topics, S3 buckets, DynamoDB tables. All bound together with plenty of YAML glue, schema-less JSON objects passed around and random hardcoded configs in AWS console.</p>

<p>I think it’s just a typical software development lifecycle: things grow organically, become a mess, and require some refactoring. Make it run first (discover market fit), then make it right (refactor to integrate the new discoveries).</p>

<p>But this time it was different. I couldn’t refactor things as easily as I used to in traditional monolithic apps. Here’s why:</p>

<p>When the building blocks are too simple, the complexity moves into the interaction between the blocks.</p>

<p>And the interactions between the serverless blocks happen <em>outside</em> my application. A lambda publishes a message to SNS, another one picks it up and writes something to DynamoDB, the third one takes that new record and sends an email…</p>

<p>I could test every single block in that flow, but I didn’t have confidence in the overall process. What if publishing fails, how would I know that? How would system recover? Can I rollback and try again? Where do the logs go?</p>

<p>Another swarm of problems was hiding in my configuration: bad Route 53 record, typos in SNS topics, wrong S3 bucket region. Tracing errors was a challenge, there’s no single log output I can look into.</p>

<p>With serverless, I was no longer dealing with my project's domain, I was dealing with the distributed system's domain.</p>

<p>At this point I felt fooled.</p>

<p>I came for the easy way to deploy code and not think about servers, but in the end had to design my system around the platform’s limitations.</p>

<p>Drawbacks of serverless (for hobby projects):</p>

<ul>
  <li>Hard to follow information flow</li>
  <li>Impossible to replicate production environment locally</li>
  <li>Slow iteration speed</li>
  <li>Lack of end-to-end testing</li>
  <li>Immature documentation (dominated by often outdated Medium posts)</li>
  <li>No conventions (have to make hundreds of unessential decisions)</li>
</ul>

<p>—</p>

<p>I was clearly not enjoying the serverless. So I decided to rewrite it. After all, it is a side project I’m doing for fun. The tech stack of choice — Ruby on Rails.</p>

<p>I haven’t used Rails since 2013, and for the last 8 years at Facebook I’ve been mostly doing JavaScript.</p>

<p><img src="https://frantic.im/assets/back-to-rails/logo.jpg" alt=""></p>

<p>The experience of picking Rails back up was really nice but… uneventful. Not much had really changed. A few things got added, a few small things moved around.</p>

<p>Of course I did <a href="https://github.com/rails/rails/issues/38060">hit some magical Ruby issues</a>. But unlike my typical experience with JavaScript, I was quickly able to find the solution.</p>

<p>Rails comes with so many things built-in and configured. Over the years, without Rails, I used to gluing random JavaScript libraries together to roll my own routing, file storage wrappers, email preview pipeline, managing secrets, test setup with fixtures, database migrations, logging, performance reporting, deployment scripts. With Rails I didn’t have to think about all these details and could simply focus on making product-visible changes.</p>

<p>It was like driving a Tesla after years of making my own scrappy cars. Similar components, but all configured and aligned to work well together.</p>

<p>Benefits of Rails (for hobby projects):</p>

<ul>
  <li>Conventions</li>
  <li>Tooling, libraries</li>
  <li>Documentation</li>
  <li>Monolith is easy to understand and test</li>
</ul>

<p>Drawbacks of Rails (for hobby projects):</p>

<ul>
  <li>Feels heavyweight in the beginning</li>
  <li>Hurts if your opinions differ from Rails conventions</li>
  <li>Have to host on a server</li>
  <li>Doesn’t sound cool in 2020 (anymore and maybe yet)</li>
</ul>

<p>—</p>

<p>Serverless is like a black hole. It promised exciting adventures, but gravity sucked me in and I spent most of my efforts dealing with its complexity, instead of focusing on my product.</p>

  
  






  <div>
  <div>
    <p>Hi! My name is Alex. I’m a software engineer at Facebook, where I work on React&nbsp;Native, Oculus and Messenger. I love thinking about development experience.</p>
    <p>I write about programming, software design and side projects <a href="https://frantic.im/subscribe/" target="_blank"><svg viewBox="0 0 800 800"><path d="M493 652H392c0-134-111-244-244-244V307c189 0 345 156 345 345zm71 0c0-228-188-416-416-416V132c285 0 520 235 520 520z"></path><circle cx="219" cy="581" r="71"></circle></svg> Subscribe</a></p>
  </div>
</div>

</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://frantic.im/back-to-rails</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25100397</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 11:40:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A framework for offline and decentralised web apps]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 33 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25100313">thread link</a>) | @dgellow
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://concords.app/blog/what-is-concords | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://concords.app/blog/what-is-concords">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section><p>Concords is an MVP framework for building offline &amp; decentralised web apps, with a file-based approach to storing data. It has no servers or databases and is a static app built with Javascript and HTML, all code is written to run in a browser and nothing is stored outside of the browser or downloaded files.</p> <p>The full MVP is available to try at <a href="https://alpha.concords.app/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">alpha.concords.app</a></p> <h2 id="why">Why?</h2> <p>SAAS applications run on servers with databases. Each interaction with the UI sends information from the browser to a server, which then likely writes something or fetches something from a centralized database.</p> <p>Maintaining servers and databases is expensive, complex and time-consuming and I'm not really interested in that side of software. I don't want the responsibility to look after data that is depended upon, that's neither my skill-set nor passion. I like to focus my attention on the front-end experience.</p> <p>I set out to build a framework for file-based SAAS apps. Multi-user collaborative apps, with data-driven user flows and advanced UI. But apps that run offline and save state to the filesystem, not send it off to a cloud-based database. Giving users full ownership and visibility of their data, with no dependency on an internet connection. Taking a progressive approach to connectivity, using it to enrich the experience, but not depend on it.</p> <h2 id="technical-steps">Technical Steps</h2> <ul> <li><p>Functional blockchain library in Typescript.</p> </li> <li><p><a href="https://svelte.dev/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Svelte</a> &amp; <a href="https://sapper.svelte.dev/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Sapper</a> for all things UI.</p> </li> <li><p>Blockchain sync with IndexedDB and reactivity hook.</p> </li> <li><p>Created <a href="https://1.0.0.concords.app/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">some mini-apps</a> to refine and test the core functionality.</p> </li> <li><p>User Authentication flow.</p> </li> <li><p><a href="https://alpha.concords.app/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">MVP: Kanban app</a>.</p> </li> </ul> <h2 id="concords-mvp-board-app">Concords MVP: Board App</h2> <p>This MVP serves to demonstrate a basic solution to a truly offline and decentralized experience in a collaborative web app. It's a static app, so just Javascript and HTML, with no servers or databases running in the background. It's a progressive web app with a service worker, that runs entirely in the browser. So once the initial load has been performed, the rest of the experience can work completely offline, where data is stored in files, downloaded and uploaded through the UI.</p> <p>A boards app covers a lot of functionality commonly found in SAAS applications, I figured it's a great benchmark to prove out the technology.</p> <p><img alt="" src="https://concords.app/flows/add-task.gif?raw=true"></p> <hr> <h3 id="authentication">Authentication</h3> <p>With Concords, authentication is all done in the browser, without any communication to a server or external resource.</p> <p>In the Concords authentication system, we issue a downloadable public profile which includes your public key and some basic user info. I keep mine for the MVP on my personal domain. <a href="https://ternent.dev/concords/sam-ternent.profile.concords.json" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">https://ternent.dev/concords/sam-ternent.profile.concords.json</a></p> <p>Anyone with access to my public key is able to encrypt data for me, that only I can read with my private key. I just have that stored on my personal machine. It’s never been online and no-one else knows it.</p> <p>This key is used to log the user into the app and only a valid key combination can login and access the software.</p> <p>For my MVP, this is more than sufficient to complete and decent authentication flow. We can have a recognisable UX of profile/password combination to build a login system, whilst setting us up for an encrypted, multi-user, data flow.</p> <p><img alt="" src="https://concords.app/flows/signup.gif?raw=true"></p> <hr> <p>I know it's a pain to ask users to store both parts of their encryption keys themselves. If the private key is lost, it's unrecoverable and so is any encrypted data to that key. But I couldn't compromise here, it has to be this way to keep things decentralized. But it's a problem that can be fixed through software, it doesn't have to be my software - we're decentralizing things here, but key management software will fix this problem.</p> <h3 id="the-app">The App</h3> <p>Knowing roughly what I needed to build to prove out the concept, and having already implemented User Profile and the authentication flow, the key features I chose to implement were:</p> <ul> <li>Create new and multiple boards</li> <li>Downloadable app files</li> <li>Load any board, from any user</li> <li>Assign tasks to users</li> <li>Editable tasks</li> <li>Timestamped actions</li> <li>Drag to sort columns</li> <li>Draggable tasks across columns</li> <li>Soft delete tasks to the trash, with restore and remove</li> <li>Activity log with an immutable history of the board</li> </ul> <p><img alt="" src="https://concords.app/flows/create-board.gif?raw=true"></p> <hr> <h4 id="multiple-users">Multiple Users</h4> <p>By default, a new user doesn't have edit access to a document. For the purpose of the MVP, we've got a "Join" button in the left-hand sidebar. Clicking this will add the user as an entry to the data store and unlock editing. This covers the concept enough for now, but we are able to achieve direct encryption with the public/private key authentication, so that's going to be an interesting avenue to explore further outside of the MVP context.</p> <p><img alt="" src="https://concords.app/flows/third-user.gif?raw=true"></p> <hr> <h3 id="core-library">Core Library</h3> <p>The core of the framework is written in Typescript. It's a collection of functional utilities which cover the data side of the application. It runs an internal blockchain for writing data, mapped with an IndexDB instance for reading.</p> <h4 id="blockchain">Blockchain</h4> <p>At the heart of the library is the <a href="https://hackernoon.com/merkle-tree-what-is-it-and-why-use-it-8m2a63xjd" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Merkel Tree</a> solution. Our Merkle Tree (as used in Blockchain and git), is a functional library to act as a blockchain node, from a JSON object structure, in the browser.</p> <p>Built on top of that is a CRUD API which the application will interface with. When an action is performed in the app, a timestamped transaction is created for the blockchain. Once commit, all pending transactions are then added to a block on the chain. Once a block has been added to the blockchain, the hash-based data structure ensures the integrity of the app state.</p> <pre><code>{
 "type": "tasks",
 "action": "create",
 "data": {
   "title": "Task Name",
   "description": "Task Description",
   "completed": false,
   "due_date": "2020-11-02",
   "assigned_to": "a72e75a898db9247be59d1aaf9d4c54459e1d24faa43d9f5da0a5a9611a19eb",
   "column": "2bb6a2b737381377fd962b1bda0771d084abd3cab270648c78b7e06566e6b5",
   "id": "d2e25d4d6c77b34fbe87da5f387cf8c3bec25ffc76673e84bf76dbf2aa15754f",
   "timestamp": 1604144654690
 },
 "user": {
   "firstName": "Sam",
   "lastName": "Ternent",
   "avatarUrl": "https://ternent.dev/concords/avatar.jpeg",
   "organisation": "Team Concords",
   "id": "a72e75a898db9247be59d1aaf9d4c54459e1d24faa43d9f5da0a5a9611a19eb"
 },
 "signature": "NOT RELEASED"
}</code></pre><hr> <h4 id="database">Database</h4> <p>Sitting on the other side of the blockchain is the DB layer. When a transaction it accepted onto the blockchain, we parse the event and perform an operation on an IndexedDB instance in the browser. Transactions are recorded as they go in, so we don’t duplicate transactions and minimise the number of write operations to the database.</p> <p>As long as we have the blockchain data object, we have a full picture of our app and data state. We can drop and recreate a database with complete accuracy, based on secured transactional history. This is a <strong>read only</strong> layer.</p> <p><img alt="" src="https://concords.app/flows/recreate-db.gif?raw=true"></p> <hr> <h4 id="architecture-overview">Architecture Overview</h4> <p><img alt="" src="https://concords.app/images/architecture.svg"></p> <hr> <h2 id="next-steps">Next Steps</h2> <h3 id="desktop-app">Desktop App</h3> <p>A quick leap here is to build this out into a desktop app using electron. Little things like saving the hash to a keychain, directly reading and writing to the filesystem. I'm excited to try running the <a href="https://dat.foundation/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">DAT</a> project to enable P2P connectivity to give a realtime collaborative experience.</p> <h3 id="intergrations">Intergrations</h3> <p>My primary goal is decentralization. I'm not against storing data on the cloud, I just want to be able to make my own choice as to where. The initial standout integration I want to try is with Dropbox, syncing a folder in your filesystem to dropbox will give us the ability to introduce the "push/pull" aspect found in git.</p> <h3 id="conflict-resolution">Conflict resolution</h3> <p>I need to do further research around conflict resolution. I have the basics for a complete blockchain, which includes proof of work and consensus to ensure the validity of the underlying data structure, but it doesn't secure or handle in-app data conflicts. Visual diffs and conflicts are problems solved in various other applications, with plenty of research available. I'm not sure how it will look yet, but it should be a fun one to solve.</p> <h3 id="user-roles--permissions">User roles &amp; permissions</h3> <p>Using our data structure user roles and permissions are achievable. With the use of application-level permission keys, we can encrypt the access key for a specific user. They will then have access to any data under that permission level.</p> </section></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://concords.app/blog/what-is-concords</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25100313</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 11:26:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Open Source does not mean “Includes Free Support”]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 295 | Comments 247 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25099862">thread link</a>) | @alexellisuk
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://raccoon.onyxbits.de/blog/bugreport-free-support/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://raccoon.onyxbits.de/blog/bugreport-free-support/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
      We need to talk.
    </p><div>

<p>Here’s a paraphrased conversation I’m having way to often, costing me way too much time, keeping me from doing things that are way more important:</p>

<pre>User: Hi, I'd like to report a bug in your application.
Me:   Great! Please open a support ticket, then.
User: But, it looks like I need to pay for that?
Me:   So?
User: I just want to tell you that your app is broken, so you can fix it.
Me:   Yes, that's a support request, please open a ticket.
User: ...
</pre>

<figure>
  <a href="https://raccoon.onyxbits.de/blog/bugreport-free-support/bugreport.png">
    <img src="https://raccoon.onyxbits.de/blog/bugreport-free-support/bugreport.png">
  </a>
  
</figure><p>
                             
                             
From there it typically derails into a whiny tirade about me being a crappy two bit developer who doesn’t give a shit about his code (which is ridiculous, since, professional pride aside, I have every incentive to fix bugs, to prevent my inbox from getting flooded) and just wants to rip off his users.</p>

<p>In the past, I sometimes gave in (when it sounded like something might be wrong). I looked at the issue and almost always found that nothing was broken, just didn’t work as expected (which is actually to be expected for every reasonably complex piece of software). The user just didn’t bother reading the docs and tried to bypass the fee by masquerading the support request as a bug report. So, nowadays my policy simply is: no support ticket, no service. Any such request goes straight to the trash folder without even being looked at.</p>

<h2 id="why-am-i-such-an-asshole">Why am I such an asshole?</h2>

<p>Here’s the thing: I write open source software to solve <strong>my problem</strong>. I let you use my solutions because that comes at zero cost for me (well, almost, I still have to pay for the website, you are downloading from. You are welcome, by the way). I also provide the source code, so you can fix things yourself, should my solution turn out to be unsuitable. However, once you come to me with a “bugreport” that doesn’t also include a patch (or at least very precisely pinpoints the problem), then you are basically asking me to <strong>look at your problem</strong>. At this point, it is no longer zero cost for me and that’s the reason for why I am charging you money: you are asking me to spent time on your behalf. That is commonly called <strong>work</strong>. And surprisingly enough, work is what people expect to be paid for.</p>

<p>Don’t get me wrong. I’m happy to help. Selling support is what keeps the lights on here (did I mention the cost of running a webserver?). But coming to me under false pretense and/or expecting that I <strong>must</strong> provide free service on top of a software I gave away without charge is not going to win you any favours.</p>

<p>It stops being free, when it starts costing me! My time is valuable. If you want a piece of it, I want money in return. Period.</p>

<p><strong>UPDATE:</strong> Seems like this post has struck a nerve and caused a few misunderstandings. <a href="https://raccoon.onyxbits.de/blog/reactions-bugreport-free-support/">Clarification on my position here</a>.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://raccoon.onyxbits.de/blog/bugreport-free-support/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25099862</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 10:12:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I Ripped Out a £6k Lighting System]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 218 | Comments 286 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25099615">thread link</a>) | @iamflimflam1
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://robdobson.com/2020/11/the-10-reasons-i-ripped-out-a-6k-lighting-system/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://robdobson.com/2020/11/the-10-reasons-i-ripped-out-a-6k-lighting-system/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://robdobson.com/2020/11/the-10-reasons-i-ripped-out-a-6k-lighting-system/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25099615</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 09:24:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[On Taking Criticism]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 63 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25098585">thread link</a>) | @WoodenChair
<br/>
November 14, 2020 | https://www.observationalhazard.com/2020/11/on-taking-criticism_15.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.observationalhazard.com/2020/11/on-taking-criticism_15.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="post-body-4608430843265935994">
<p>I am what I would call a non-famous public person. What do I mean by that? I mean that I have jobs where people publicly review my work. As a college instructor, I receive student reviews. Some of them get read internally at our school, and some of them get posted publicy. And they’re attached to my name. They’re not some product where people might just know my company or my brand. They know <em>me</em>, and they’re reviewing <em>me</em>. As an author, my books get reviewed. Some of those reviews are by editors and official reviewers internal to the publisher. Some of those reviews are by email. But most of those reviews are posted online. As a software developer and hobbyist podcaster I also get public reviews.</p>

<p>To anyone in a personalized creative field who cares deeply about their work, bad reviews hurt. It’s not just about being sensitive (although I am sensitive and that doesn’t help). It’s that when you really pour your heart into something, as I do my teaching for example, then the product is an extension of you. Nobody would deny that the way a class or a book turns out is an extension of the personality, knowledge, and ability of the teacher/author. And when the product is criticized, it’s like you are being criticized. </p>

<p>My dad, who was also a college instructor, and the producer of nine books and nine instructional videos among many other public creative ventures, had a very thin skin. He couldn’t stand me reading him a bad review. That stuck with me. This very accomplished man, couldn’t stand even a little criticism. When I get too sensitive, I try to remember how his inability to accept criticism hurt some of his products. He was much more about getting things done than doing them perfectly. If he had a little bit more of a perfectionist streak in him, he would have done even better. But maybe he would have done less…</p>

<p>It doesn’t matter if I receive eighteen great reviews for a class. It’s the words of the two bad reviews that stick with me. And do you know why? <em>Because almost always there’s a kernel of truth to those reviews.</em> Does that mean we should listen to them? Well if I only listened to the bad reviews, I would never produce anything. I would just stay in bed. The fact is the people who are getting no bad reviews, are the people who are not taking the risk of putting themselves out there. So, we have to not let ourselves get so discouraged that we stop producing. And we have to remember that while we may not have served those two students well, we may have served those other eighteen students better than they would have been served in a world without us teaching them. </p>

<p>We can’t please every student or every customer. Nothing that gets watched/read by more than a few people is going to be liked by all of them. Even Mother Theresa would get a downvote on YouTube. So, if we’re serving the majority, we don’t want to let the critiques of a few steer us in the wrong direction.</p>

<p>On the other hand, being like my dad is dangerous too. <strong>No, the customer is not always right. But usually the customer has a point. We have to always be working to get better.</strong> Because we’re not perfect, and there’s always room for improvement. <strong>And we need to read those bad reviews to find those spaces for improvement.</strong> It doesn’t mean they’re right, but it does mean we need to think about them.</p>

<p>My dad accomplished an amazing amount. If he let those bad reviews slow him down too much, it’s very possible he would have not accomplished as much. But if he could have found a few tweaks, a few changes, to serve a few customers better, well then he could have grown through them. I want to grow, but I also don’t want to stop. So, I can’t let the reviews get me too down, but I have to read them.</p>


</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.observationalhazard.com/2020/11/on-taking-criticism_15.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25098585</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 05:39:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why I teach vim]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 137 | Comments 158 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25097788">thread link</a>) | @amichlin
<br/>
November 14, 2020 | https://blog.ceos.io/2020/11/14/why-i-teach-vim/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.ceos.io/2020/11/14/why-i-teach-vim/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">

	<section id="primary">
		<main id="main">

			
<article id="post-124">

	

	
	<div>
		
<figure><a href="https://xkcd.com/378/"><img data-attachment-id="133" data-permalink="https://blog.ceos.io/real_programmers/" data-orig-file="https://blogceosio.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/real_programmers.png" data-orig-size="740,406" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="real_programmers" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://blogceosio.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/real_programmers.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://blogceosio.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/real_programmers.png?w=740" src="https://blogceosio.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/real_programmers.png?w=740" alt="" srcset="https://blogceosio.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/real_programmers.png 740w, https://blogceosio.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/real_programmers.png?w=150 150w, https://blogceosio.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/real_programmers.png?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 740px) 100vw, 740px"></a></figure>



<p>The why of why people use vim has been <a href="https://dev.to/iggredible/why-i-use-vim-2f40">covered fairly extensively</a>, so I thought I would spend a little time explaining why I <em>teach</em> vim to my high school students, even in 2020.</p>



<p>It all began when I was assigned a mixed class of ninth through twelfth grade students in computer science just after the financial collapse on 2008. Well, the financial collapse first brought me to teach Intro to Programming using VB 6.0 and Windows thin clients, which was an experience unto itself (thanks in part to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conficker">Conficker virus</a>). That experience is worth a separate blog post and is a good part of why one of my specialties is teaching computer security.</p>



<p>So here I am with all levels of student, including AP CS A (read: AP CS Java), and obsolete Windows PCs (at least the thin clients were gone). I couldn’t install any software, wanted to teach C, had to teach Java, and had very few options (these were the days before online web based IDEs).</p>



<p>I had experience with the UNIX command line, primarily Sun Workstations, thanks to my wonderful education at <a href="https://www.soe.ucsc.edu/departments/computer-science-and-engineering">UCSC</a>, so that wasn’t an issue. I had played with Linux in the 1990s to a bit of success, but hadn’t touched it for almost a decade. So I found an old Pentium 2 carcass in the the garbage outside my condo complex, installed a hard drive, and tried this new (to me) flavor of Linux called, strangely, <a href="https://ubuntu.com/">Ubuntu</a>.</p>



<p>I quickly realized this machine could have all the students coding at one, discovered the wonder that is <a href="https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/latest.html">putty.exe</a> (it doesn’t require any installation to run!) to connect the obsolete PCs to the server and soon my students were off and coding.</p>



<p>Why did I teach them vim? I wish I could say I agonized over all the options at the time and decided vim was the best pedagogical solution, but the reality of the situation was that vi was what I used in college because my father taught me vi. You see, I am lucky to have a father who worked in the industry and is even somewhat of a <a href="https://www.bell-labs.com/usr/dmr/www/qed.html">footnote in text editor history</a>. So I taught vi (later vim) because it is what I knew. A running theme in many computer science teacher’s trials by fire… teaching something because it is what they know. I will go as far as to argue that it is more important that the teacher knows the editor, and especially the programming language, rather than assigning any importance to one correct editor or one correct language that all teachers should teach.</p>



<p>Years later, though, I still teach vim and the command line. So here is how I justify my decision, even if only to myself.</p>



<p>It just works. Every time I go to a new school, it takes time to get the software installed necessary to run IDEs. I remember walking into one school in which the AP CS A class was flailing away with Eclipse on Mac OS X because the students needed, and didn’t have, administrator access. I have an amazing tech department at my current job, but even here it took us weeks to figure out how to deploy Visual Studio Code on the student’s MacBook Airs and then we had to figure out how to deploy Python3 and Java. So there’s no confusion, I teach vim along with many IDEs and I fully believe it is my responsibility to teach multiple platforms and multiple IDEs, but the CLI and vim are always my safety net.</p>



<p>My students can program in any number of of languages on a now cloud based CLI Linux machine (thank you <a href="https://www.linode.com/">Linode</a> and <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/">Digital Ocean</a> – both of whom offer a $5/month plan – just. happy customer!). By using the CLI, I can support literally any type of computer connecting (including iPads, although the lack of a virtual esc key drives me batty as a vim user, and <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/secure-shell-app/pnhechapfaindjhompbnflcldabbghjo?hl=en">ChromeBooks</a>). Students can connect from anywhere in the world and things just work. All of this became infinitely important in the remote and hybrid learning experience of the pandemic. And this is all possible because the students use vim.</p>



<p>I keep track of as many of my students that major in CS and a running theme is they all profusely thank me for teaching them vim and the CLI. Too many colleges start CS1 with an IDE and then throw the CS2 students into the deep end with the CLI. Not everyone is as lucky as I was in regards to having a father well versed in the CLI.</p>



<p>And yes, there are online IDEs these days, but I’ve found those to be full of their own pitfalls, privacy issues, and costs and find doing any advanced work using them to be very difficult if not impossible.</p>



<p>Also, to be clear, both nano and Emacs work quite well in the context of CLI Linux and I don’t make any claim that teachers should use vim over those equally acceptable command line text editors except for one small argument. Most people agree, computer security pretty much requires knowledge of the command line and a text editor. I always tell my students that the one editor they are likely to find already installed on a machine is vim and it is a bad day when you have to install another editor. Maybe just an issue for students interested in ethical penetration testing…</p>
	</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->

				
</article><!-- #post-${ID} -->

	<nav role="navigation" aria-label="Posts">
		<h2>Post navigation</h2>
		
	</nav>
<!-- #comments -->

		</main><!-- #main -->
	</section><!-- #primary -->


	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.ceos.io/2020/11/14/why-i-teach-vim/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25097788</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 02:50:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Going Bark: A Furry’s Guide to End-to-End Encryption]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 21 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25097177">thread link</a>) | @ciarannolan
<br/>
November 14, 2020 | https://soatok.blog/2020/11/14/going-bark-a-furrys-guide-to-end-to-end-encryption/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://soatok.blog/2020/11/14/going-bark-a-furrys-guide-to-end-to-end-encryption/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

		<div>

			
<p>Governments are back on their anti-encryption bullshit again.</p>



<p>Between the <a href="https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2020/03/06/earn-it-is-an-attack-on-encryption/">U.S. Senate’s “EARN IT” Act</a>, the <a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/10/orders-top-eus-timetable-dismantling-end-end-encryption">E.U.’s slew of anti-encryption proposals</a>, and <a href="https://fee.org/articles/australia-s-unprecedented-encryption-law-is-a-threat-to-global-privacy/">Australia’s new anti-encryption law</a>, it’s become clear that the authoritarians in office view online privacy as a threat to their existence.</p>



<p>Normally, when the governments increase their anti-privacy sabre-rattling, technologists start talking more loudly about Tor, Signal, and other privacy technologies (usually only to be drowned out by paranoid people who think Tor and Signal are government backdoors or something stupid; conspiracy theories ruin everything!).</p>



<p><strong>I’m not going to do that.</strong></p>



<p>Instead, I’m going to show you how to add end-to-end encryption to any communication software you’re developing. (Hopefully, I’ll avoid making <a href="https://soatok.blog/2020/10/28/bizarre-design-choices-in-zooms-end-to-end-encryption/">any bizarre design decisions</a> along the way.)</p>



<p>But first, some important disclaimers:</p>



<ol><li><strong>Yes, you should absolutely do this.</strong> I don’t care how banal your thing is; if you expect people to use it to communicate with each other, you should make it so that you can never decrypt their communications.</li><li>You should absolutely NOT bill the thing you’re developing as an <em>alternative</em> to Signal or WhatsApp.</li><li>The goal of doing this is to increase the amount of end-to-end encryption deployed on the Internet that the service operator cannot decrypt (even if compelled by court order) and make E2EE normalized. The goal is NOT to compete with highly specialized and peer-reviewed privacy technology.</li><li>I am not a lawyer, I’m some furry who works in cryptography. The contents of this blog post is not legal advice, nor is it endorsed by any company or organization. Ask the <a href="https://eff.org/">EFF</a> for legal questions.</li></ol>



<p>The organization of this blog post is as follows: First, I’ll explain <a href="#symmetric-key-encryption">how to encrypt and decrypt data between users</a>, assuming you have a key. Next, I’ll explain <a href="#key-agreement">how to build an authenticated key exchange</a> and <a href="#session-key-management">a ratcheting protocol to determine the keys used in the first step</a>. Afterwards, I’ll explore <a href="#identity-key-management">techniques for binding authentication keys to identities and managing trust</a>. Finally, I’ll discuss <a href="#backdoor-resistance">strategies for making it impractical to ever backdoor your software (and impossible to silently backdoor it)</a>, just to piss <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Five_Eyes">the creeps and tyrants of the world</a> off even more.</p>



<p>You don’t have to implement the full stack of solutions to protect users, but the further you can afford to go, the safer your users will be from privacy-invasive policing.</p>







<h2 id="preliminaries">Preliminaries</h2>



<h3 id="choosing-a-cryptography-library">Choosing a Cryptography Library</h3>



<p>In the examples contained on this page, I will be using the <a href="https://libsodium.gitbook.io/doc/">Sodium cryptography library</a>. Specifically, my example code will be written with the <a href="https://github.com/paragonie/sodium-plus">Sodium-Plus</a> library for JavaScript, since it strikes a good balance between performance and being cross-platform.</p>


<pre title="">const { SodiumPlus } = require('sodium-plus');

(async function() {
     // Select a backend automatically
     const sodium = await SodiumPlus.auto();
     
     // Do other stuff here
})();
</pre>


<p>Libsodium is <a href="https://latacora.micro.blog/2018/04/03/cryptographic-right-answers.html">generally the correct choice for developing cryptography features in software</a>, and is available in most programming languages,</p>



<p>If you’re prone to choose a different library, you should consult your cryptographer (and yes, you should have one on your payroll if you’re doing things different) about your design choices.</p>



<h3>Threat Modelling</h3>



<p>Remember above when I said, “You don’t have to implement the full stack of solutions to protect users, but the further you can afford to go, the safer your users will be from privacy-invasive policing”?</p>



<p>How far you go in implementing the steps outlined on this blog post should be informed by <a href="https://adamcaudill.com/2016/07/20/threat-modeling-for-applications/">a threat model</a>, not an ad hoc judgment.</p>



<p>For example, if you’re encrypting user data and storing it in the cloud, you probably want to pass <a href="https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2012/04/05/icloud-who-holds-key/">the Mud Puddle Test</a>:</p>



<blockquote><div><p>1. First, drop your device(s) in a mud puddle.<br>2. Next, slip in said puddle and crack yourself on the head. When you regain consciousness you’ll be perfectly fine, but<em>&nbsp;won’t for the life of you&nbsp;</em>be able to&nbsp;recall your device passwords or keys.<br>3. Now try to get your cloud data back.</p><p>Did you succeed? If so, you’re screwed. Or to be a bit less dramatic, I should say: your cloud provider has access to your ‘encrypted’ data, as does the government if they want it, as does any rogue employee who knows their way around your provider’s internal policy checks.</p></div><cite>Matthew Green describes the Mud Puddle Test, which Apple products <a href="https://sneak.berlin/20201112/your-computer-isnt-yours/">definitely don’t pass</a>.</cite></blockquote>



<p>If you must fail the Mud Puddle Test for your users, make sure you’re clear and transparent about this in the documentation for your product or service.</p>







<h2 id="symmetric-key-encryption">I. Symmetric-Key Encryption</h2>



<p>The easiest piece of this puzzle is to encrypt data in transit between both ends (thus, satisfying the loosest definition of end-to-end encryption).</p>



<p>At this layer, you already have some kind of symmetric key to use for encrypting data before you send it, and for decrypting it as you receive it.</p>



<p>For example, the following code will encrypt/decrypt strings and return hexadecimal strings with a version prefix.</p>


<pre title="">const VERSION = "v1";

/**
 * @param {string|Uint8Array} message
 * @param {Uint8Array} key
 * @param {string|null} assocData
 * @returns {string}
 */
async function encryptData(message, key, assocData = null) {
    const nonce = await sodium.randombytes_buf(24);
    const aad = JSON.stringify({
      'version': VERSION,
      'nonce': await sodium.sodium_bin2hex(nonce),
      'extra': assocData
    });

    const encrypted = await sodium.crypto_aead_xchacha20poly1305_ietf_encrypt(
        message,
        nonce,
        key,
        aad
    );
    return (
       VERSION +
       await sodium.sodium_bin2hex(nonce) +
       await sodium.sodium_bin2hex(encrypted)
    );
}

/**
 * @param {string|Uint8Array} message
 * @param {Uint8Array} key
 * @param {string|null} assocData
 * @returns {string}
 */
async function decryptData(encrypted, key, assocData = null) {
    const ver = encrypted.slice(0, 2);
    if (!await sodium.sodium_memcmp(ver, VERSION)) {
        throw new Error("Incorrect version: " + ver);
    }
    const nonce = await sodium.sodium_hex2bin(encrypted.slice(2, 50));
    const ciphertext = await sodium.sodium_hex2bin(encrypted.slice(50));
    const aad = JSON.stringify({
      'version': ver,
      'nonce': encrypted.slice(2, 50),
      'extra': assocData
    });
    
    const plaintext = await sodium.crypto_aead_xchacha20poly1305_ietf_decrypt(
        ciphertext,
        nonce,
        key,
        aad
    );
    return plaintext.toString('utf-8');
}
</pre>


<p>Under-the-hood, this is using <a href="https://soatok.blog/2020/07/12/comparison-of-symmetric-encryption-methods/#aes-gcm-vs-xchacha20poly1305">XChaCha20-Poly1305</a>, which is less sensitive to timing leaks than AES-GCM. However, like AES-GCM, this encryption mode doesn’t provide <a href="https://eprint.iacr.org/2019/016">message- or key-commitment</a>.</p>



<p>If you want key commitment, you should derive two keys from <code>$key</code> using a KDF based on hash functions: One for actual encryption, and the other <a href="https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/1153">as a key commitment value</a>.</p>



<p>If you want message commitment, you can use AES-CTR + HMAC-SHA256 or XChaCha20 + BLAKE2b-MAC.</p>



<p>If you want both, ask <a href="https://mumble.net/~campbell/">Taylor Campbell</a> about his BLAKE3-based design.</p>



<p>A modified version of the above code with key-commitment might look like this:</p>


<pre title="">const VERSION = "v2";

/**
 * Derive an encryption key and a commitment hash.
 * @param {CryptographyKey} key
 * @param {Uint8Array} nonce
 * @returns {{encKey: CryptographyKey, commitment: Uint8Array}}
 */
async function deriveKeys(key, nonce) {
    const encKey = new CryptographyKey(await sodium.crypto_generichash(
        new Uint8Array([0x01].append(nonce)),
        key
    ));
    const commitment = await sodium.crypto_generichash(
        new Uint8Array([0x02].append(nonce)),
        key
    );
    return {encKey, commitment};
}

/**
 * @param {string|Uint8Array} message
 * @param {Uint8Array} key
 * @param {string|null} assocData
 * @returns {string}
 */
async function encryptData(message, key, assocData = null) {
    const nonce = await sodium.randombytes_buf(24);
    const aad = JSON.stringify({
      'version': VERSION,
      'nonce': await sodium.sodium_bin2hex(nonce),
      'extra': assocData
    });
    const {encKey, commitment} = await deriveKeys(key, nonce);

    const encrypted = await sodium.crypto_aead_xchacha20poly1305_ietf_encrypt(
        message,
        nonce,
        encKey,
        aad
    );
    return (
       VERSION +
       await sodium.sodium_bin2hex(nonce) +
       await sodium.sodium_bin2hex(commitment) +
       await sodium.sodium_bin2hex(encrypted)
    );
}

/**
 * @param {string|Uint8Array} message
 * @param {Uint8Array} key
 * @param {string|null} assocData
 * @returns {string}
 */
async function decryptData(encrypted, key, assocData = null) {
    const ver = encrypted.slice(0, 2);
    if (!await sodium.sodium_memcmp(ver, VERSION)) {
        throw new Error("Incorrect version: " + ver);
    }
    const nonce = await sodium.sodium_hex2bin(encrypted.slice(2, 50));
    const ciphertext = await sodium.sodium_hex2bin(encrypted.slice(114));
    const aad = JSON.stringify({
      'version': ver,
      'nonce': encrypted.slice(2, 50),
      'extra': assocData
    });
    const storedCommitment = await sodium.sodium_hex2bin(encrypted.slice(50, 114));
    const {encKey, commitment} = await deriveKeys(key, nonce);
    if (!(await sodium.sodium_memcmp(storedCommitment, commitment))) {
        throw new Error("Incorrect commitment value");
    }
    
    const plaintext = await sodium.crypto_aead_xchacha20poly1305_ietf_decrypt(
        ciphertext,
        nonce,
        encKey,
        aad
    );
    return plaintext.toString('utf-8');
}
</pre>


<p>Another design choice you might make is to encode ciphertext with base64 instead of hexadecimal. That doesn’t significantly alter the design here, but it does mean your decoding logic has to accommodate this.</p>



<p>You SHOULD version your ciphertexts, and include this in the AAD provided to your AEAD encryption mode. I used “v1” and “v2” as a version string above, but you can use your software name for that too.</p>



<h2 id="key-agreement">II. Key Agreement</h2>



<p>If …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://soatok.blog/2020/11/14/going-bark-a-furrys-guide-to-end-to-end-encryption/">https://soatok.blog/2020/11/14/going-bark-a-furrys-guide-to-end-to-end-encryption/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://soatok.blog/2020/11/14/going-bark-a-furrys-guide-to-end-to-end-encryption/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25097177</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 01:12:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Ask HN: Are you depressed?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 395 | Comments 461 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25096877">thread link</a>) | @pcbro141
<br/>
November 14, 2020 | http://www.strawpoll.me/22152225 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.strawpoll.me/22152225">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
        
    
      
    
<section>
    
        <span>Asked</span>
    
    <span>
        <abbr title="11 15 2020 00:09:57 UTC" data-epoch="1605398997">Nov 15, 2020</abbr>
    </span>
    <p>
        <span>IP Duplication Checking</span>
        
    </p>
</section>  
    
   

    


    
   

    
      
    

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.strawpoll.me/22152225</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25096877</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:12:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
