<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 10]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 10. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 12:33:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-10.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 12:33:33 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Dual licensing GPL for fame and profit]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 42 | Comments 38 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24677481">thread link</a>) | @george3d6
<br/>
October 4, 2020 | https://blog.cerebralab.com/Dual_licensing_GPL_for_fame_and_profit | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.cerebralab.com/Dual_licensing_GPL_for_fame_and_profit">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">
        <p>Published on: 2020-10-04</p>
        
<p>Dual licensing with GPL is the idea that if I own a certain piece of GPL code, I can also relicense it as a proprietary library. This is how Oracle licenses Java and how QT licenses QT.</p>
<h2>I - All rights for me but not for thee</h2>
<p>But my general feeling is that there is some stigma associated with this practice, to quote <a href="https://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl-faq.en.html#ReleaseUnderGPLAndNF">gnu.org</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>To release a nonfree program is always ethically tainted, but legally there is no obstacle to your doing this. If you are the copyright holder for the code, you can release it under various different non-exclusive licenses at various times.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The "ethically tainted" doesn't resonate with me, I think this licensing model should be encouraged.</p>
<p>I will admit I am kind of biased on this because I work on a for-profit GPL-license project. But it strikes me as silly that this business model is shunned by the open-source community in favor of licensing under MIT/BSD.</p>
<p>Dual licensing is a way in which the "owner" of the code ends up in an advantageous position compared to other users.</p>
<p>That is to say, a user must abide by the strict rules of the GPL license:</p>
<ul>
<li>Release all modifications.</li>
<li>Potentially (depending on the specifics of the GPL license) have to release other projects that are used "in relation" to the library.</li>
<li>Not ship the code under a different license.</li>
</ul>
<p>The "owner" of the code abides by none of these and can thus benefit in ways that the users can't.</p>
<p>In the open-source utopia, where resources are aplenty for everyone, everything is open source and nothing is for sale, so dual-licensing doesn't fit that particular utopia. But we live in the real world, where money makes things a bit more complicated, and in the long term, dual-licensing might be better than equal-rights open licenses.</p>
<p>Well, developers have to eat.</p>
<p>Even worst, good software is made by good developers, developers which can get six-figure salaries designing skinner boxes. On the contingency that those developers aren't ideal altruists, they have to get way-above-subsistence salaries to work on useful open source projects instead of skinner boxes.</p>
<p>So if dual-licensing provides a middle ground for that which is better than the current situation where a lot of good software is proprietary, what's the harm?</p>
<p>Some would say it's a middle ground that will hamper the development of truly free software. But who release said truly free software anyway?</p>
<h2>II - Who release fully-free projects</h2>
<p>When it comes to license like MIT and BSD, that impose no restrictions upon usage, where the "owner" doesn't exist, it's interesting to look at who release projects under those licenses:</p>
<p>a) Students or hobbyists, people creating software for fun, notoriety, and experience.</p>
<p>b) Very large companies (Facebook, Google, Amazon, Uber) or government &amp; donation founded organizations (Universities, Public Research centers, software foundations such as GNU, Apache, and LSF)</p>
<p>The first group is one I don't wish to dismiss, I think a lot of important programs stem from here. But their end goal is not to work for free for their whole life. Usually, they moonlight for their open-source projects and work a paid gig to earn money. A small minority can be funded by donations, but it's a small minority.</p>
<p>The project I use for allowing comments on this website (<a href="https://github.com/umputun/remark42">remark42</a>), has 2.3k stars on GitHub and <a href="https://www.patreon.com/remark42/posts">earns 9$/month from donations</a>. The <a href="https://github.com/mindsdb/mindsdb">project I work on</a> has 2.9k stars on Github and an operating budget of <a href="https://venturebeat.com/2020/04/16/mindsdb-raises-3-million-for-open-source-automated-machine-learning/">a few million</a> dollars.</p>
<p>You can certainly get to a point where you are funded by donations, but the reality is that it's not a good enough incentive. Doubly so since the developers working on these projects are usually the "creme de la creme", releasing and maintaining truly useful software usually requires expertise only a small fraction of engineers have.</p>
<p>The second group, the corporation and government-funded teams can only exist because of the scale.</p>
<p>Why can Facebook develop PyTorch?</p>
<ul>
<li>Because Facebook hires so many ML engineers that in the cost-benefit analysis it's cheaper to have your internal framework be popular enough such that you can get already-trained people from day 1. The &lt; 100 people working full time on PyTorch save months of training for every single one of the thousands of ML people facebook hires, since it can hire people that already know PyTorch.</li>
<li>Because Facebook doesn't dominate by having better ML models, it dominates by having thousands of times more data than anyone else. It's in facebook's interest to keep research open since it's objective is not to get ahead, but just to stay even, or at least not fall significantly behind.</li>
</ul>
<p>Why can Nvidia assign engineers to dozens of open source ML and game-engine projects?</p>
<ul>
<li>Because Nvidia makes hundreds of billions each year selling GPUs. The little work they put into those libraries to make sure it works ideally with their GPUs is insignificant to the revenue they get from those markets.</li>
</ul>
<p>Why can Google develop TensorFlow?</p>
<ul>
<li>For about the same reasons as Facebook.</li>
<li>Because they can make a lot more money from selling/renting TensorFlow optimized hardware.</li>
</ul>
<p>And that's on the happier side of the spectrum. On the "shadier" end of the scale, one could argue projects like Flutter and Angular might be worth their investment because they make spyware-free browsers like Firefox send-class citizens in the war for the web, not to mention easier integration into internet-monopolizing schemas like AMP.</p>
<p>You've also got, I will admit, projects that seem to be open source purely for flexing. To my knowledge, Yandex might have well never released Clickhouse and the column-store database landscape would have been set back 10+ years for it. Why did they do it? Maybe just because few dozens of people working on it wanted to showcase how good they are.</p>
<p>But at the end of the day, this is not a reliable model</p>
<h2>III - Profit motives</h2>
<p>So would it not be nice for open source if one can bring profit motives into the whole thing?</p>
<p>Even better, profit from the people that don't support or contribute to open source, but not from those that do.</p>
<p>It seems to me like double-licensing with GPL achieves just that. One can release a project and charge large companies for using it, at the risk of breaking the license if they don't pay. Even if a lot of them will use the software illegally, as is the case now, the threat of lawsuits will end up deterring some or most heavy-users from doing so.</p>
<p>On the other hand, people using the project in an open-source project of their own have nothing to worry about.</p>
<p>The only problem that remains here is the fact that you can't chain GPL projects. That is to say, one can't use GPL code in their own double-licensed GPL code, but there are workarounds for that (e.g. isolating the GPL dependency and open-sourcing the changes to that alone). Still, this seems like the kind of problem that could be fixed by an off-shoot of the GPL meant for just this use-case.</p>
<p>This model keeps all the advantages of GPL, in that it incentives your users to open-source their product. It doesn't force them to do so, like a purely-GPL licensed software might, but it's not like GPL is working as intended, outside of a few cases where enough money was at stake to sue (e.g. TiVo), violations of the GPL go unpunished.</p>
<p>Currently, a company that wants to include GPL into their project has two options:</p>
<ul>
<li>Use the code in such a way that GPL won't force you to open source the rest of your code.</li>
<li>Use the code and break the license.</li>
</ul>
<p>Since the wording of GPL is not that clear, it could often be argued that companies go for alternative nr 2. After all, who will ever know?</p>
<p>But what if the "pay the maintainer a small sum" option was available. Wouldn't the liability afraid giants look towards this much more favorably than either of the other 2 options? Wouldn't this, in the long run, give an edge to open source projects which don't have to worry about these fees ?</p>
<hr>
<p>Thus I think I come in squarely on the side of open-source companies dual-licensing GPL on their product[s]. A model that already exists and often enough has great success (see MariaDB and Aerospike).</p>
<p>It's a nice compromise for moving towards a more open world, without having to live in Stallman's utopia. It's an amazingly pragmatic solution and anyone who reads this blog knows I'm a fan of those.</p>

      </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.cerebralab.com/Dual_licensing_GPL_for_fame_and_profit</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24677481</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 09:19:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Formal Models for Ethics]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 30 | Comments 23 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24676411">thread link</a>) | @queueue
<br/>
October 3, 2020 | https://cartesia.link/2020/09/28/the-ethical-question-mk-ii/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://cartesia.link/2020/09/28/the-ethical-question-mk-ii/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<main>
  
<section id="post-the-ethical-question-mk-ii"> 
   
    <div>
      <a href="https://cartesia.link/2020/09/28/the-ethical-question-mk-ii/">
        <h2>The Ethical Question, Mk. II</h2>
      </a> 
      <h3>
        <span>September 28, 2020</span>
        <span>26 minutes</span>
      </h3>
      
    </div>
  
    
  <div>
    
<p>As the reading time estimate crept over 30 minutes, without any end in sight, I was starting to feel like a bit of a blowhard.</p>



<p>The draft I’d originally intended to inaugurate this blog is still sitting there. Maybe I will condense and finish it (eventually), but I think it makes more sense to write <s>briefly</s> less long-windedly about what I mean. Instead of trying to exhaust the subject matter, I’m going to offer a perspective, and present a more intuitive argument for it.</p>



<p>So, more briefly, I’d like to ask you to think, for a moment, about what makes humans <em>ethically</em> important. There are two parts to this question, hidden just under the surface. The first asks you to consider why humans are ethical <em>agents</em>. What makes it possible for them to do, want, or experience things that could fall under the umbrella of ethics? The second (no particular order) asks you to consider why humans are ethical <em>patients</em>. How is it that what happens to them, what is wanted of them, or what is experienced about them might also be part of an ethical problem? (This agent/patient distinction I inherit from Coeckelbergh, whose book, <em>Growing Moral Relations</em>, is worth your time.)</p>



<p>I will add before you start: ethics has been defined in a few different ways, over the millennia. I consider a few definitions interesting. </p>



<p>Charles Taylor, for instance, describes ethics as pertaining not just to moral choices and obligations between people, but questions like “what is the good life?” and “what is good?”. His more expansive account, following Aristotle, moves closer to the Greek root, which refers to one’s <em>character</em>, and can be read to have a slant towards something resembling <em>virtue ethics</em>. Using Taylor, we could ask questions like “what is it good to love?” and not just “what is the right way to act?” </p>



<p>Conversely, followers of Nietzsche contrast <em>ethics</em> with <em>morality</em>, arguing that morality is about passing judgment on what people (or living beings) are and do, whereas ethics can be about <em>affirming</em> life as intrinsically self-justifying. From a (post-) Nietzschean point of view, life’s capacity to want, struggle, and change, <em>is, from the very beginning, what is good</em> (maybe not in those words). Living well means trying to overcome the need to judge, and instead to explore and express what it is to be alive, for all its intensities and tragedies. Nietzsche is often read to be asking his readers to abandon compassion, or to think only of themselves and never of the common good, but I don’t think that is exactly the case. Nietzsche is asking us to live in pursuit of what is good, but not to define it as the enemy of the bad, rather, to live <em>for its own sake, come what may</em>, and to do what is good, <em>defined in itself</em>, rather than as a reaction.</p>



<p>I don’t know Coeckelbergh’s position on ethics broadly, but he considers morality to be embedded in social relationships themselves. Rather than what is right or wrong to do to a <em>patient</em> being about its properties (whether it has consciousness, for instance) and defined in absolute terms, morality is about what relationships exist between an agent and a patient, and what kinds of relationships are good to have, knowing what the agent and patient already are to each other. Do I already mostly act like it’s a person? I should probably treat it like one. Coeckelbergh is interesting in that he tries to legitimate ideas that have, until recently, not had much hearing in the community of western philosophers, although citing him as a source for them over others might, fairly, be challenged. For instance, he would consider our dependence on our ecology grounds to entertain an obligation towards it. I haven’t finished his book yet, so I’m not aware of the extent of the advice he gives for considering problems in these relationships, but it seems fair to say that he doesn’t believe there’s a system of absolute rules out there, or that we should try to find final answers to ethical problems. Relationships are particular, and they evolve. We shouldn’t seek to use the fact that we don’t get hard answers for our convenience; instead, we should consider relationships, for their lumpiness, their particularity, their uncertainty, and live them as best we can.</p>



<p>All of these viewpoints are very different from our ordinary patterns of ethical thought. We are used to thinking that <em>individuals</em>, or sometimes <em>social groups</em> (such as nations) have <em>rights</em> that must be guaranteed to them, but everything else goes. Sometimes, referencing Isaiah Berlin, we might say we believe that this obligation is <em>negative</em> (there are some things that people are fundamentally allowed to do, and our only obligation is to stop people who try to mess with that), or it is <em>positive</em> (there are some things that people should fundamentally be allowed to do, and we need to do our best to make that possible for them). Maybe, for whatever definition of the good, we are utilitarians, who think that we should do the most good for the most people, whatever means that could entail. Perhaps we take the <em>view from afar</em>, and ask “if I had the choice of all reasonably possible societies, which would I like to be born into, knowing that I might be anyone?” Perhaps we see ethics as different versions of the trolley problem, and find reasons, based on our moral intuitions, about what choices we should make when push comes to shove. Some of us, unfashionably, believe in immortal souls and divine law, against which we must not sin, or that her majesty inherits the right to judge from God, and that the highest good is obedience to an Earthly law. A scientist, being familiar with Hume, might read his argument that we cannot derive statements about what <em>ought to be</em> from statements about what <em>is</em>, and see cause to be an anti-realist. Maybe <em>ought</em> statements only express our personal preferences, derived from what we’ve been either (or both) biologically or socially conditioned to think is pleasing. Scientists might say this implies some sort of <em>relativism</em>, or that it’s best to follow whatever is the <em>conventional</em> way to think about ethics (although, if we’re not in the business of assuming the world is already a pretty just place to be in, that last one may not be safe). </p>



<p>So, knowing what you know about what humans are made of, and how they relate to one another, to society, or to other beings, what makes them ethical agents, and what does it mean that they are? What about patients? I think it’s probably a bad idea to try to find an answer too quickly. It might be better to think through what kinds of approaches are better, and what facts could be relevant to the question. For instance, maybe the way people want things matters, as it is defined in terms of elaborations on what’s generated by the default mode network. Maybe there can’t be exactly one right answer, or maybe there must be, or maybe it’s impossible to know. How would you argue that?</p>



<h2>Why it Matters </h2>



<p>I don’t fully agree with Taylor, but, in <em>Sources of the Self</em>, he makes a good case for why we shouldn’t be self-serving, and why we already care about ethics. He says ethics are about what we <em>want to be</em>, how we identify ourselves. This is always done in terms of social groups we identify <em>with</em>. “I am a professional, so I should…” Identity gives us community, people who share something about us (a way of life, perhaps), or maybe it contrasts us against a community (we can identify ourselves as rebels). We rarely, if ever, identify with just one thing, and it’s no use to try to come up with a completely original identity, if it’s possible to do it meaningfully at all, because it doesn’t tell us much about what we’re trying to be, given we’re the only one who would know or care that we’re being it. Identity is critically important to us in interpreting our place in the world, and what we are trying to do with it. So, says he, without identity, we would struggle to come to grips with life. It is a good thing, then, that you and I already have some ideas about <em>who we are</em>, or if we’re struggling to figure that out, generally already acknowledge that it <em>is</em> an important thing to get down. Taylor says that, since it’s all about coming to grips with life, we escape Hume’s is/ought problem, because we don’t have to set up an ethics from scratch. Ethics are already there from the beginning, and have some known properties, so we can argue about them by contrasting them. “Given these two frameworks, which one of them provides the richer set of tools for figuring out how to live a good life?” To Taylor, ethics are certainly <em>real</em>, but not in the sense that they’re an object embedded in a reality perfectly detached from us, rather, they come <em>from</em> the fact that we are social creatures, and relate <em>to</em> how we are trying to live in society. They aren’t just individual, or perfectly culturally relative (as there are no perfectly incommensurable cultures, which share none of the same moral ideas and cannot communicate with each other), but they aren’t exactly objective and final either.</p>



<p>I like Taylor, for how he grounds consciousness of <em>ethics</em> in <em>social consciousness</em>, and I like how good he is at striking down the (usually unanswerable) “why should I care about ethics?” question. I share Coeckelbergh’s complaint that he considers only one kind of relation (between the individual and the community), and I would also gripe that his ethics are unusually centred on the <em>self</em>, for a subject that tends to ask us to think beyond ourselves. But then, that is why the argument against selfishness works so well. It’s difficult to get through to somebody who only thinks of themself unless that’s the place you’re starting from. </p>



<p>Taylor’s other issues, which I will not go too in-depth on here, are first, that he frames the source of ethics as appearing in the fact that one is an <em>ind…</em></p></div></section></main></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://cartesia.link/2020/09/28/the-ethical-question-mk-ii/">https://cartesia.link/2020/09/28/the-ethical-question-mk-ii/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://cartesia.link/2020/09/28/the-ethical-question-mk-ii/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24676411</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 03:50:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Open-source self-hosted comments systems for static websites]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 146 | Comments 34 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24676152">thread link</a>) | @nuker
<br/>
October 3, 2020 | https://lisakov.com/projects/open-source-comments/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://lisakov.com/projects/open-source-comments/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>This comparison table is inspired by
<a href="http://staticsitegenerators.net/">staticsitegenerators.net</a>. Contribute at
<a href="https://github.com/pozitron57/open-source-comments">github</a> —
add the missing data. Github-related data (stars, open issues + PR, etc.)
are updated daily automatically. Want different columns? Noted a bug? Submit
an <a href="https://github.com/pozitron57/open-source-comments/issues/new">issue</a>.</p>
<h2>What’s wrong with Disqus</h2>
<p>Disqus loads absurd amount of tracking services, which exposes your visitors’
personal data and significantly increases loading time. See, e.g., 
<a href="http://donw.io/post/github-comments/#what-s-wrong-with-disqus">this post</a>.</p>
<h2>What’s not covered here</h2>
<p>For a static website, one usually wants a lightweight commenting server with
as little dependencies as possible. Few commenting engines listed on the page
are provided by heavy applications (e.g.,
<a href="https://github.com/discourse/discourse">discourse</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/debiki/talkyard">talkyard</a>), but the majority are
relatively lightweight applications designed specifically to provide 
comments for the static pages.</p>
<p>This page prioritizes information on self-hosted comments. However, there
are other open-source solutions, including implementations of third-party
services (e.g., Github issues, such as
<a href="https://github.com/imsun/gitment">[1]</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/gitalk/gitalk">[2]</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/Blankj/awesome-comment">[3]</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/utterance/utterances">[4]</a>).</p>
<h2>Stars vs. time</h2>
<p>The figure below shows some of the top competitors except for Discourse (as it's not
just a light commenting server like others). The figure is useful to
indirectly estimate how active the project is.</p>
<p><a href="https://lisakov.com/projects/open-source-comments/stars-v-date.png">
<img src="https://lisakov.com/projects/open-source-comments/stars-v-date.png" alt="Plot stars vs. time" width="800px">
</a></p>
<h2>Choose columns to show</h2>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://lisakov.com/projects/open-source-comments/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24676152</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 02:31:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A web of trust for NPM]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 136 | Comments 101 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24673917">thread link</a>) | @tao_oat
<br/>
October 3, 2020 | https://www.btao.org/2020/10/02/npm-trust.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.btao.org/2020/10/02/npm-trust.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>In 1984 the co-inventor of Unix, Ken Thompson, delivered a seminal speech in which he highlighted that <em>you can’t trust code that you did not totally create yourself</em> <sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup>. For a while, this lesson was largely ignored as open-source package registries like RubyGems, PyPI and npm grew rapidly. However, as we’re seeing <a href="https://blog.reversinglabs.com/blog/mining-for-malicious-ruby-gems" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">more</a> <a href="https://blog.npmjs.org/post/185397814280/plot-to-steal-cryptocurrency-foiled-by-the-npm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">and</a> <a href="https://snyk.io/blog/a-post-mortem-of-the-malicious-event-stream-backdoor/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">more</a> supply-chain attacks through software dependencies, the risks of using unvetted dependencies are becoming clearer.</p>

<p>The risks are particularly great for JavaScript applications. Veracode found that the average JavaScript project relies on 377 dependencies – compared with just 16 for Python projects, or 43 in the Java ecosystem<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2">2</a></sup>. Whenever a developer pulls in a new dependency, they are implicitly trusting the maintainers of that dependency. Often, this trust is awarded on the basis of popularity – we assume that a popular library will be more carefully vetted, or that since many others trust the maintainers, we can too. Other times, this trust relationship and the risks involved are not considered at all.</p>

<p><a href="https://sambleckley.com/writing/npm.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Some have argued</a> that the ill health of the npm registry is a social, rather than a technical problem, and suggest a human-compiled set of packages in order to separate the wheat of maintained, healthy packages from the chaff of abandoned toy projects with no documentation. <a href="https://medium.com/@dpc_96143/cargo-crev-and-rust-2019-fearless-code-reuse-b75d58398cb8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Another suggestion from the Rust world</a> involves creating a manual web of trust from maintainers cryptographically signing each other’s projects. Either way, there are challenges: webs of trust have rarely taken off (outside of Debian), and compiling a vetted set of packages from scratch is a massive undertaking. I propose something in the middle: bootstrapping a web of trust using existing npm dependency relationships, and building from that foundation.</p>

<h2 id="existing-trust-relationships-in-npm">Existing trust relationships in npm</h2>

<p>Creating a web of trust from existing npm dependencies is, admittedly, somewhat problematic. As stated earlier, choosing to use a particular dependency is not always a well-considered decision based on researching its code and maintainers, and the trust relationship is merely implied. Similarly, there is no cryptographic verification of this weak trust, nor does npm currently have the infrastructure for such tools<sup id="fnref:3" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:3">3</a></sup>. What I am suggesting is an imperfect starting point to demonstrate the need for, and potential of, stronger trust measures in open source.</p>

<p>To construct this initial web, we can model npm’s maintainerships as a graph. If we let each node be a maintainer, then the edges between them are the trust relationship arising from using a dependency. In other words, if Alice maintains a package A, and A depends on package B maintained by Bob, then there is a directed edge from Alice to Bob. We can even weigh these edges by the number of Alice’s packages in which she implies trust of Bob.</p>

<h2 id="exploring-the-graph">Exploring the graph</h2>

<p>This simple model exhibits a power-law-like pattern in terms of trust: the vast majority of users are trusted by few or no others, and a very small number of users are highly trusted. This type of pattern is common in social networks: you see a similar thing emerge when plotting follower counts on Twitter. Such power laws often lead to a rich-get-richer feedback process in which the inequality (in terms of trust, in this case) gets more pronounced over time<sup id="fnref:4" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:4">4</a></sup>.</p>

<p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/efe1a929e64ebeeb021e79f341b35faa4baf1397/c0643/static/img/maintainer-wot-in-degrees.png" alt="Scatter plot of in-degree vs. number of users. Shows a roughly power-law relationship."></p>

<p>Who are these highly-trusted users? They’re who you’d expect: bots for large projects (e.g. <code>types</code>), corporate accounts (e.g. <code>fb</code>), and the maintainers of extremely popular open-source libraries (e.g. <code>sindresorhus</code>, who maintains e.g. <code>string-length</code>).</p>

<p>Perhaps more interestingly, this web of trust exhibits some useful structures. A number of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strongly_connected_component" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">strongly connected components</a> emerge – groups of users that, roughly speaking, all trust each other according to the web of trust principles (i.e. if I trust Alice, and Alice trusts Bob, then I trust Bob, too). All of these connected components are small, with the exception of a single one that’s home to over 11,000 users<sup id="fnref:5" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:5">5</a></sup>. This core component – we’ll call it the <strong>strong set</strong> – could provide a starting point for a measure of trust in the npm ecosystem.</p>



<p>We can quantify trust in a slightly more nuanced way than simply looking at the in-degree of each npm user. The PageRank algorithm provides such a measure that takes into account the trustworthiness of the people who trust me. For example, I may only be trusted by one user, but if that user is <code>isaacs</code> (the creator of npm) then that trust relationship counts for a lot! After running PageRank, the 10 “most-trusted” users are:</p>

<ol>
  <li><code>types</code></li>
  <li><code>sindresorhus</code></li>
  <li><code>angular</code></li>
  <li><code>m1tk4</code></li>
  <li><code>tjholowaychuk</code></li>
  <li><code>google-wombot</code></li>
  <li><code>fb</code></li>
  <li><code>isaacs</code></li>
  <li><code>gaearon</code></li>
  <li><code>yyx990803</code></li>
</ol>

<p>Many of these are unsurprising. However, <code>m1tk4</code> stands out: they only maintain two rarely-downloaded libraries. Because one of these libraries is used by the BBC, <code>m1tk4</code> is implicitly trusted by a large number of relatively trustworthy BBC employees who maintain other, more popular projects. This demonstrates how PageRank diffuses trust across the social network of npm maintainers. In fact, <code>m1tk4</code> is not a member of the strong set mentioned earlier – but many of the users who trust them <em>are</em>. <code>m1tk4</code> just doesn’t trust those users back!</p>

<p>While PageRank gives a fun measure of trust, it’s a very rough model for the reasons mentioned earlier: it’s based on a pretty weak indication of real trust. However, it might be useful in detecting suspicious behaviours in npm, which is something we – or registry maintainers – need to do proactively if we want to stop supply-chain attacks. For example, it might be a red flag if a highly-trusted user suddenly starts using a library by someone with a PageRank-based-trust of close to 0. And regardless, the strong set comes merely from observing which dependencies people choose to use without applying any complex calculations.</p>

<p>How might we want to use the strong set to create a stricter trust (or reputation) system? I think that formalizing such a system is unlikely if it requires large-scale buy-in from npm users. Instead, we might create a simple wrapper for npm that checks if you’re about to install something from a developer outside of the strong set, similar to Liran Tal’s excellent <a href="https://github.com/lirantal/npq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">npq</a>. Or perhaps security researchers could use the npm web of trust as an additional data point when deciding whether a suspicious package warrants further investigation. Either way, the state of trust within the npm ecosystem is not great. This model gives us a starting point.</p>

<p><em>Do you think I’ve got it all wrong? Or do you have further suggestions on how we can improve the state of trust in open source? <a href="https://www.btao.org/contact">Get in touch</a>.</em></p>

<p><em>A final note: this analysis is based on data from June 2020, which I collected for my Master’s thesis. I believe you’d reach similar numbers if you ran the analysis on data from today.</em></p>

<h3 id="footnotes">Footnotes</h3>



</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.btao.org/2020/10/02/npm-trust.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24673917</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 18:51:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Rust Starter Kit 2020]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 320 | Comments 95 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24671403">thread link</a>) | @psxuaw
<br/>
October 3, 2020 | https://wiki.alopex.li/RustStarterKit2020 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://wiki.alopex.li/RustStarterKit2020">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="wikipage">

<p>People were arguing about Rust’s std lib recently, so I went through the <code>Cargo.toml</code> of all the Rust projects I’ve written since 2015 and picked out the choice tools that get used over and over again. Up to date as of October 2020.</p>
<p>Also see <a href="https://wiki.alopex.li/RustCrates" title="Go to wiki page">RustCrates</a>, though that’s old. There’s also <a href="https://christine.website/blog/rust-crates-go-stdlib-2020-09-27">this</a>, which is narrower but deeper, and <a href="https://github.com/rust-unofficial/awesome-rust">awesome-rust</a>, which is shallower and broader, and the various <a href="https://www.arewewebyet.org/">more</a> <a href="https://arewegameyet.rs/">specific</a> <a href="https://areweasyncyet.rs/">websites</a> <a href="https://www.areweguiyet.com/">for various</a> <a href="https://areweideyet.com/">topics</a>.</p>

<p>I need to set up a new Rust dev environment, what do I install?</p>
<h2 id="linting-clippy">Linting – <code>clippy</code></h2>
<p>The one, the only, the great Rust style and correctness linter. Want to learn how to write “idiomatic” Rust, or just learn more about handy little corners of the language and library? Run <code>clippy</code> regularly. It’s distributed with the compiler via <code>rustup</code> now, so you have no excuse not to.</p>
<h2 id="build-cache-sccache">Build cache – <code>sccache</code></h2>
<p>Or, “how to make a full rebuild 70% faster”. <code>sccache</code> is a build artifact cache similar to <code>icecream</code> or <code>ccache</code>, except it’s actually trivial to just use. <code>cargo install sccache</code>, add a single line in a home dir config file, and you’re ready to go. Pretty much handles most crate and compiler versioning issues for you, so it Just Works if you update crates or install a new version of <code>rustc</code> or something. I think I’ve had to force-clear the cache due to some build weirdness a grand total of once. Looks like it has enough features to use in a professional context as well, at least on a small-to-medium scale.</p>
<h2 id="dependency-viewer-cargo-tree">Dependency viewer – <code>cargo-tree</code></h2>
<p>The best way to view what dependencies you are using, and what dependencies they are using, and so on. Best way to start cracking down on flabby dependencies.</p>
<h2 id="benchmarking-criterion">Benchmarking – <code>criterion</code></h2>
<p>Basically the best benchmark system out there. Incredibly simple to use, informative, and statistically sound. Doesn’t really do profiling, but it’s a good start for understanding your program’s performance, and better for proving that your implementation of X is faster than someone else’s.</p>
<h2 id="other-things">Other things</h2>
<p>Stuff that is less general purpose but occasionally very useful for the meta-programming process of choosing libraries, evaluating them, etc.</p>
<ul>
<li><code>cargo-geiger</code> – Measures how much unsafe code is in a codebase, and its dependencies</li>
<li><code>cargo-crev</code> – A <a href="https://wiki.alopex.li/ActuallyUsingCrev">very neat tool</a> for authoring and verifying distributed code reviews.</li>
<li>Various tools maintained by <a href="https://github.com/EmbarkStudios/rust-ecosystem">Embark Studios</a>, useful for production/company purposes like checking licenses, pinning specific versions of crates, etc.</li>
</ul>

<p>The cool stuff Real Computer Scientists write about.</p>
<h2 id="hashing">Hashing</h2>
<p>No specific crates here. There’s no single crate that provides All The Hash Algorithms, just lots of little ones that generally provide a single algorithm each. Just type the name of the algorithm you want into <code>crates.io</code> and you’ll get at least a couple options, choose the one with 8 million downloads or whatever. <code>sha2</code>, <code>md5</code>, <code>crc</code>, etc. Lots of them are written by the Rust core team.</p>
<h2 id="compression">Compression</h2>
<p>Same as the hashing category. Type <code>zip</code> or <code>bzip2</code> or whatever into crates.io and you’ll get what you need. <code>flate2</code> might be the one crate that’s not quite trivial to find. Again, many of them are written by the Rust core team.</p>
<h2 id="encryption">Encryption</h2>
<p>I have little actual experience or authority on this topic, so I’m going to punt on this one.</p>
<h2 id="pseudorandom-number-generator">Pseudorandom number generator</h2>
<p>Use <code>oorandom</code>. (Disclaimer, I wrote <code>oorandom</code>, but people besides me seem to like it.) More usually you’ll see the <code>rand</code> crate in use. If you’re doing Real Science and need to generate <a href="https://docs.scipy.org/doc/numpy-1.15.0/reference/routines.random.html">fancy probabilities</a>, then <code>rand</code> is the right tool, but most people aren’t doing that. Otherwise <code>rand</code> is complicated and has lots of features, while <code>oorandom</code> is very simple and has about two features, and I expect 80% of code to use at least one of them. <code>rand</code> has had several major breaking changes in its history that the rest of the ecosystem still hasn’t caught up with, while I intend <code>oorandom</code>’s API to change maybe twice in my lifetime. (Its version number, while obeying semver, is mostly a joke.)</p>
<p>There’s other lightweight PRNG crates that are just fine; see <code>oorandom</code>’s readme for a list of some others and choose one you like. Whatever you choose, use the <code>getrandom</code> crate to produce Real Random Seeds for it.</p>

<p>“I just need to solve this ooooooone common problem, but it needs to be solved WELL…”</p>
<h2 id="logging-log">Logging – <code>log</code></h2>
<p>Need to output log messages in your code? Why, use the <code>log</code> crate. Where do the log messages go? <code>log</code> provides only an interface, and that interface compiles to nothing if it isn’t used. You can write your own system for it to actually output the logs to, which is pretty easy, or use one of the small plethora of crates for it. My preferred one is <code>pretty_env_logger</code>, but <code>fern</code>, <code>slog</code> and others are all good too.</p>
<h2 id="parallel-data-crunching-rayon">Parallel data crunching – <code>rayon</code></h2>
<p>Ever have some computation where you have a big list of STUFF and want to process it in parallel, farming out jobs to as many threads as you have CPU’s? That’s what <code>rayon</code> does, and it does it really, really well. You still <a href="https://aspenuwu.me/posts/rust-optimization.html">have to know what you’re doing</a>, but changing a single <code>.iter()</code> into <code>.par_iter()</code> and watching your CPU-bound data-crunching run 8x faster is pretty magical. Now your CPU can help keep you warm this winter!</p>
<p>Please never use it in a library. It’s rude to spawn threads in library code, unless that’s specifically what the library is for.</p>
<h2 id="regexes-regex">Regexes – <code>regex</code></h2>
<p>To quote the inestimable <a href="https://www.jwz.org/blog/">jwz</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Some people, when confronted with a problem, think “I know, I’ll use regular expressions.” Now they have two problems.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>On the other hand, <a href="https://xkcd.com/208/">somebody’s gotta save the day</a>. So, use the <code>regex</code> crate. Also use <a href="https://crates.io/crates/ripgrep">anything else</a> <a href="https://crates.io/crates/xsv">written by BurntSushi</a>. BurntSushi is a paragon of Rust program design, and also just a great <del>human being</del> charred cuisine in general.</p>
<h2 id="threadsafe-globals-lazy_static">Threadsafe globals – <code>lazy_static</code></h2>
<p>“I know globals are evil,” you say, “but I just need one. I’ll only use it for good, I promise.” <code>lazy_static</code> has your back.</p>
<p>May eventually be superseded by <code>once_cell</code>, which looks like its <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs/pull/2788">headed for inclusion into <code>std</code></a>.</p>
<h2 id="serializationdeserialization-serde">Serialization/deserialization – <code>serde</code></h2>
<p>Ever have a struct and just wanted to turn it into JSON, CBOR, XML, or some other engine of woe and devastation designed to be written to an I/O stream? Or had a blob of random JSON and wanted to just stuff it into a struct matching it? Sure you have. <code>serde</code> lets you do this with a single <code>#[derive]</code>. <code>serde</code> is without a doubt one of Rust’s killer libraries. It is better than any other serialization system I have ever used.</p>
<p>What data formats does it support? Anything; the actual reading and writing is done via plugin library. There’s a <a href="https://serde.rs/#data-formats">wide selection of them</a>, of varying quality, and writing your own is a little tedious but not terribly difficult.</p>
<h2 id="error-handling">Error handling</h2>
<p>This spot deliberately left blank.</p>
<p>Rust’s <code>Result&lt;T,E&gt;</code> type is one of the best setups for lightweight, transparent error handling I’ve seen, but it doesn’t do everything. How do you easily write your own error type without a bunch of boilerplate? What if you have multiple different error types from different libraries you want to coalesce together? How do you collect a backtrace of every function an <code>Err</code> is returned through, so you can find the root cause of where it came from? Can we do all this without allocating anything unnecessarily? And so on.</p>
<p>There have been various crates to try to solve these problems. First in 2015 there was <code>error_chain</code>, which was complicated and not very convenient. Then in 2017 there was <code>failure</code>, which was simpler but not very flexible, and which took an irritatingly long time to compile. Then in 2019 there was <code>anyhow</code>, which was about the time I stopped paying attention. Now apparently the new kid on the block is <code>eyre</code>, and I’m sure that in another year or two there will be something else.</p>
<p>So, I just write the boilerplate and make my errors descriptive enough I don’t need a backtrace. When I want to get fancy I implement the built-in <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/error/trait.Error.html"><code>Error</code></a> trait, which used to be kinda useless but is now more helpful. And in another five years it’ll still work just fine.</p>
<h2 id="byte-mucking-bytemuck">Byte mucking – <code>bytemuck</code></h2>
<p>For the rare occasions you need to turn a structure into arbitrary <code>&amp;[u8]</code> or back. Doing this using unsafe pointers is quite easy, and also makes it very easy to screw up horribly with Undefined Behavior galore. (Did you know that changing the value of padding bytes in a struct in UB? You do now.) <code>bytemuck</code> lets you muck around with bytes a little more responsibly.</p>
<h2 id="human-dates-and-times-chrono">Human dates and times – <code>chrono</code></h2>
<p>Rust’s <code>std::time</code> doesn’t really handle calendar or wall-clock times, just arbitrary, monotonic <code>Instant</code>’s and measurable <code>Duration</code>’s between them. Nice, pure, computationally-robust time measurement. For all the nasty human calendar and timezone stuff, you use <code>chrono</code>. (And maybe <code>humantime</code>, but I personally reach for <code>chrono</code> first, just out of habit.)</p>
<h2 id="bit-flags-bitflags">Bit flags – <code>bitflags</code></h2>
<p>Defining type-safe bit-masks in a reasonably convenient way. Not always worth the trouble, but sometimes pretty convenient.</p>

<p>“I have to create or read a…”</p>
<h2 id="pngjpeggifetc-image">PNG/JPEG/GIF/etc – <code>image</code></h2>
<p>General-purpose loading and saving and images, which can handle a lot of formats. Can do some amount of image manipulation as well, such as cropping, smoothing, etc. but that will hopefully be pulled out into its own library at some point soon.</p>
<h2 id="small-data-things-uuid-base64-csv-semver">Small data THINGS – <code>uuid</code>, <code>base64</code>, <code>csv</code>, <code>semver</code>…</h2>
<p>Exactly what it says on the tin.</p>

<p>Not aware of any great encoders, but there’s plenty of <em>decoders</em> for common audio formats. <code>lewton</code> for Ogg Vorbis, <code>hound</code> for .wav, <code>minimp3</code> for MP3, <code>claxon</code> for FLAC. Video, I haven’t used enough to have an opinion on.</p>
<h2 id="config-files-toml">Config files – <code>toml</code></h2>
<p>For all your config file format needs. Works with <code>serde</code>, naturally.</p>
<h2 id="markdown-pulldown-cmark">Markdown – <code>pulldown-cmark</code></h2>
<p>There’s several good Markdown readers and writers, <code>pulldown-cmark</code> is my favorite. It supports CommonMark, it’s simple to use, and it’s pure Rust.</p>
<h2 id="templating-askama">Templating – <code>askama</code></h2>
<p>There’s several quite good text templating engines, but <code>askama</code> IMO rises above them all by compiling your templates into Rust code and type-checking your templates at compile time. Sometimes this isn’t what you want, but it is a great feature surprisingly often. This also makes it super fast, for when you really need to …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://wiki.alopex.li/RustStarterKit2020">https://wiki.alopex.li/RustStarterKit2020</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://wiki.alopex.li/RustStarterKit2020</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24671403</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 12:04:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The case for building a SETI observatory on the moon]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 160 | Comments 70 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24670960">thread link</a>) | @pseudolus
<br/>
October 3, 2020 | https://www.supercluster.com/editorial/the-case-for-building-a-seti-observatory-on-the-moon | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.supercluster.com/editorial/the-case-for-building-a-seti-observatory-on-the-moon">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span>On Monday, a group of researchers sponsored by Breakthrough Listen, the world’s largest SETI program, </span><a href="http://seti.berkeley.edu/lunarseti/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">submitted a paper</a><span> to National Academy of Sciences’ Planetary Science and Astrobiology Decadal Survey that makes the case for establishing a SETI radio observatory on the farside of the moon. The decadal survey establishes scientific priorities for the next ten years and the new paper addresses one of the biggest problems facing the search for extraterrestrial intelligence today: The overwhelming amount of radio interference.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>Our planet has become so “loud” in the part of the radio spectrum observed by SETI that it threatens to drown out any signal sent from an intelligent civilization. Not only would a lunar radio telescope not have to deal with terrestrial radio interference, it could also significantly increase our chances of hearing from ET by opening up parts of the radio spectrum that are blocked by Earth's atmosphere. While the idea of using the moon for radio astronomy is decades old, the researchers make the case that technological advancements have finally made a lunar SETI observatory truly feasible.</span></p></div><div><div><p><span>
says Eric Michaud, an intern at the SETI Berkeley Research Center and the first author of the paper. “Maybe not today, but I think it’s going to get more and more feasible as time goes on.”&nbsp;</span></p></div></div><div><p><span>Radio interference has been a problem for SETI from the very beginning. In the spring of 1960, the planetary scientist Frank Drake trained the massive radio telescope at Green Bank Observatory in West Virginia on Tau Ceti and Epsilon Eridani, two stars a mere 12 light years from Earth. That summer, Drake spent his days studying the signals picked up by Green Bank’s giant mechanical ear in the hopes of receiving a message broadcast by an alien civilization orbiting those stars. Known as Project Ozma, Drake’s experiment marked the beginning of SETI, the scientific search for extraterrestrial intelligence.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>Shortly after Drake started his observations, he was surprised to find what appeared to be a signal of intelligent origin. After days of watching a needle drift lazily over a spool of paper recording the random undulations of cosmic static, Drake and his colleagues were jolted awake when the machine started recording the frantic pulses of a strong radio signal picked up by the telescope. The timing and magnitude of the pulses clearly marked them as artificial; there was nothing in the natural world that could produce such a frenetic radio profile. It would have been an astounding stroke of luck to pick up an alien message after only a few hours of observation, but it was hard to argue with the data.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>“None of us had ever seen anything like it,” Drake recalled in </span><em>Is Anyone Out There?</em><span>, his autobiographical book about the early days of SETI. “We looked at each other wide-eyed. Could discovery be this easy?”</span></p></div><div><div><p><span>

It was a letdown, but the false detection turned out to be a portent for the future of SETI. In the 60 years since Drake’s pioneering experiment, researchers have conducted dozens of SETI searches across thousands of stars and turned up empty-handed. At the same time, the sources of radio interference on Earth—military radars, TV towers, cell phones, and satellites—have exponentially increased, which greatly increases the chances that an extraterrestrial signal will be lost among the noise.&nbsp;</span></p></div></div><div><p><span>Earth was never a particularly great place to do any kind of radio astronomy due to our thick atmosphere blocking a large portion of the radio spectrum. The proliferation of radio communication technologies has only made things harder. The moon, by comparison, has no atmosphere and its nights last for weeks on end, which limits radio noise from the sun. And as&nbsp;NASA discovered through a spate of lunar orbiter missions in the late 1960s, the moon also acts as a natural shield that blocks radio signals emanating from Earth. As the planetary astronomer Phillipe Zarka has put it, “the farside of the moon during the lunar night is the most radio-quiet place in our local universe.” It’s exactly the sort of peace and quiet you want if you’re searching for faint radio signals from solar systems that might be hundreds of light years away.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>The new Breakthrough Listen paper proposed two main approaches to a lunar SETI observatory: an orbiter and a telescope on the surface. The basic idea behind a SETI lunar orbiter would be to scan for signals as it passed over the lunar farside and relay data back to Earth as it passed over the near side. One of the main advantages of an orbiter is cost. The proliferation of small satellites that are capable of accurate tracking combined with low-cost small launch providers like Rocket Lab means that a SETI orbiter could conceivably be sent to the moon </span><a href="https://www.nasa.gov/press-release/nasa-awards-contract-to-launch-cubesat-to-moon-from-virginia/#:~:text=The%20firm%2Dfixed%2Dprice%20launch,Tyvak%20Nano%2DSatellite%20Systems%20Inc." rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">for less than $20 million</a><span>. This would be a valuable pathfinder mission that could pave the way for a more ambitious observatory on the surface, but without the risk and cost.&nbsp; As the </span><a href="https://www.supercluster.com/editorial/the-supercluster-podcast-water-bears-might-now-occupy-the-moon" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">ill-fated Israeli Beresheet lander mission</a><span> reminded us, landing on the moon is extremely challenging even when the mission is backed by $100 million.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>But a SETI lunar orbiter would also come with a lot of compromises. It would only be able to conduct observations during the brief stretches when it was on the lunar farside, which would make a sustained observation campaign more challenging. The upshot is that an orbiter would have access to the full sky, whereas a telescope on the surface would be constrained by the moon’s rotation. The biggest downside of an orbiter is that it might lose a lot of the shielding benefits of the moon and be more vulnerable to radio interference from Earth since it would be orbiting high above the lunar surface.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>“The first SETI observations that are done from the lunar farside will be done from orbit, there’s no question about that,” says Andrew Siemion, the director of the Berkeley SETI Research Center and the second author on the paper. “I think eventually we absolutely want to do something on the surface because we want to build a very large aperture telescope, but even when we’re at that point I don’t think that would negate the utility of doing things from orbit as well.”&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>So what would a SETI observatory on the moon look like? One idea is to use the naturally parabolic lunar crater as a radio dish, much like the Arecibo telescope in Puerto Rico and </span><a href="https://www.supercluster.com/editorial/chinas-massive-telescope-is-the-next-great-seti-hope" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">the FAST telescope in China</a><span>, which are built into natural depressions in the land. This idea was </span><a href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1029/RS012i005p00845" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">first considered</a><span> back in the late 1970s by a group of scientists at the radio physics lab at the Stanford Research Institute. Their idea was to recreate Arecibo on the moon by suspending an antenna from the lip of a crater and using the basin as a reflector. The reduced gravity on the moon would allow for a radio telescope far larger than any on Earth, which could significantly enhance the sensitivity of SETI searches. Ultimately the researchers concluded that a lunar radio observatory was too expensive compared to SETI telescopes that could be built on Earth.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>But 40 years later, Michaud says that building a radio dish in a lunar crater may finally be cheap enough to pull off. One of the main drivers of this cost reduction is the advent of commercial launch providers like SpaceX and Rocket Lab, which have </span><a href="https://www.supercluster.com/editorial/cheaper-rockets-growing-the-human-family-in-space" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">dramatically lowered the cost of space access</a><span>. Another driver is NASA’s push to establish a permanent human presence on the moon, which has subsidized the development of a fleet of commercial lunar exploration vehicles. “There’s so much interest in going back to the moon,” says Michaud, who cited Blue Origin’s lunar lander and Rocket Lab’s Photon Lunar satellite as examples of technologies enabled by </span><a href="https://www.supercluster.com/editorial/nasas-first-puerto-rican-born-director-aims-for-a-moonshot" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">NASA’s Artemis program</a><span>.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>A crux of the original vision for lunar SETI observatories was that it would require a human settlement on the moon to build and operate the radio dish. But robotic systems have improved enough that it may be possible to take humans out of the equation. This was clearly demonstrated in 2019 when China’s Chang’e 4 rover landed autonomously on the farside of the moon. These advancements in autonomous navigation have laid the foundation for a lunar radio observatory that is built entirely by robots.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>It sounds like science fiction, but earlier this year NASA’s Advanced Innovative Concepts program </span><a href="https://www.nasa.gov/directorates/spacetech/niac/2020_Phase_I_Phase_II/lunar_crater_radio_telescope/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">awarded one of it’s prestigious grants to Saptarshi Bandyopadhyay, a researcher at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory, to figure out a way to make it happen</a><span>. His idea is to use rovers to deploy wire mesh in a crater on the lunar farside and suspend a receiver over the dish. NIAC is all about funding high risk, high reward missions, and there’s no guarantee that Bandyopadhyay’s proposal will ever come to fruition. Still, addressing the technical problems associated with building a radio receiver on the farside of the moon is an important first step.</span></p></div><div><p><span>And Bandyopadhyay isn’t the only NASA-backed researcher contemplating a lunar radio observatory. Jack Burns, a radio astronomer at the University of Colorado, has also received a grant to study a mission concept for a radio telescope array called </span><a href="https://www.colorado.edu/project/lunar-farside/dr-jack-burns" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">FARSIDE</a><span>. Instead of using a crater as a dish, FARSIDE would deploy several smaller antennas across the lunar surface that would collectively form a large radio telescope. Both NASA studies are focused on radio astronomy rather than SETI, but Siemion sees the two disciplines as natural allies in the quest to establish an observatory on the lunar farside. SETI has piggybacked on other radio astronomy projects in the past—SERENDIP, for instance, opportunistically searched for ET signals during radio observation campaigns at a variety of telescopes—and it seems plausible that a similar arrangement could be made with an observatory on the moon.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>Siemion acknowledged that there were certain technical challenges that would arise in a collaboration on a lunar radio observatory. The biggest issue, he says, is that a lot of radio astronomy is done at frequencies that don’t really require an observatory on the moon. “Radio …</span></p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.supercluster.com/editorial/the-case-for-building-a-seti-observatory-on-the-moon">https://www.supercluster.com/editorial/the-case-for-building-a-seti-observatory-on-the-moon</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.supercluster.com/editorial/the-case-for-building-a-seti-observatory-on-the-moon</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24670960</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 10:14:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Reverse Engineering a North Korean Sim City Game]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 49 | Comments 9 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24670827">thread link</a>) | @pcr910303
<br/>
October 3, 2020 | https://digitalnk.com/blog/2019/04/21/reverse-engineering-a-north-korean-sim-city-game/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://digitalnk.com/blog/2019/04/21/reverse-engineering-a-north-korean-sim-city-game/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-371">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>
		<p><em>Reverse engineering the North Korean version of a popular Sim City-like game using Ghidra and ndSpy to understand video game monetization strategies in the DPRK and the marketization of the country’s economy. </em></p><p><em>Key takeaways:</em></p><p><em>
<li>Android devices and applications are increasingly common in North Korea. Physical “app stores” can be found on every street corner in Pyongyang.</li>
<li>The game considered in this post is based on a Chinese version of a popular Android game developed in the Netherlands</li>
<li>The game’s monetization strategy was adapted to the country’s infrastructure (low internet/intranet availability, physical app stores)</li>
<li>The North Korean version eschews the original freemium + online microtransaction model for a one-time licence purchase + offline microtransaction model</li>
<li>File integrity checks added by North Korean developers shows that piracy is a concern and suggests the existence a warez/cracking scene in the DPRK</li>
<li>The cryptographic algorithms used for the licence are MD5, SHA1, RSA and AES. The library used by the game included the domestically developed private key algorithms Pilsung and Jipsam, but they were not used as part of the licencing system</li></em></p><p><a href="#intro">0. Introduction</a><br>
<a href="#licence">1. Licensing system</a><br>
<a href="#check">2. File integrity checks</a><br>
<a href="#money">3. In-game monetization strategy and key generation</a><br>
<a href="#end">4. Conclusion</a></p>
<h4 id="intro">0. Introduction </h4><p>During a recent trip to North Korea, I noticed the recent and ubiquitous presence of <em>Information Technology Exchange Rooms</em> (정보기술교류실), physical stores where one can purchase a variety of electronic devices – from laptops and tablets to USB sticks and chargers – as well as software and video games for PC, mobile and tablets (for an in-depth look at what goes on inside those stores as well as what the app selection looks like, <a href="https://www.nknews.org/2019/02/what-to-buy-inside-a-north-korean-app-store/">this article</a> by Alek Sigley provides a an excellent description. There are also a few <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1ujblnigJmM">videos</a> on YouTube). After looking through the catalogue of available games at different stores, I eventually decided to try and buy a Sim City-like game called <em>City Management</em> (도시경경).</p>
<figure id="attachment_426"><a href="http://digitalnk.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/chongbo.png"><img src="http://digitalnk.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/chongbo.png" alt="" width="845" height="760"></a><figcaption>Billboards for various app stores in Pyongyang</figcaption></figure><p>The game only cost 5000 wons (less than 1 USD) which I paid to have the app installed on the phone I had, a Samsung Galaxy A5 running Android 8. The vendor connected the phone to his PC, transferred the APK and tried to install it, but to no avail. After multiple attempts, he eventually informed me that North Korean apps most likely could not run on phones from other countries. </p>
<figure id="attachment_428"><a href="http://digitalnk.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/marrichakyongchu.png"><img src="http://digitalnk.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/marrichakyongchu.png" alt="" width="551" height="827"></a><figcaption>Advertisement for a car racing game inside a North Korean app store</figcaption></figure><p>Fortunately, I was later able to purchase one of the different tablets sold in North Korea. I got the <em>Morning</em> (아침) brand, which is geared towards students and quite affordable. The tablet ran Android 4 (Kit Kat) on an ARM cpu and came loaded with a few educational apps: language learning courses, dictionaries and several e-book libraries containing the complete works of Kim Il Sung, school textbooks and a collection of literary works. No games, but that could now be fixed quite easily.</p>
<figure id="attachment_431"><a href="http://digitalnk.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/achimtablet.png"><img src="http://digitalnk.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/achimtablet.png" alt="" width="800" height="490"></a><figcaption>A North Korean Ach’im (Morning) tablet</figcaption></figure><p>I retrieved the <em>City Management</em> APK from my phone and installed it on the tablet, where it ran perfectly. Unfortunately, after the game’s initial splash screen, I landed on this:</p>
<figure id="attachment_434"><a href="http://digitalnk.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/buyserial.png"><img src="http://digitalnk.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/buyserial.png" alt="" width="1024" height="600"></a><figcaption>Licence key needed</figcaption></figure><p>The screen tells us that there is no “key file” (열쇠화일) and that we should purchase one at a store. There is a “request number” (요청번호) likely used to generate the licence key and make sure it can’t be shared with other devices. Unfortunately, since the APK never installed, the vendor did not put a licence file on my phone when I bought the app. My stay in North Korea was coming to an end too and I did not have time to go back to an app store to buy a new key. So I figured I would take a look inside the app and see if I could get it running nonetheless. </p>
<hr id="licence">
<h4>1. Licensing system </h4><p>To start looking into the APK’s code, I’ll use the standard suite of tools to decompress, decompile and rebuild android apps: <a href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/dex2jar/">dex2jar</a>, <a href="http://java-decompiler.github.io/">jd-gui</a>, <a href="https://ibotpeaches.github.io/Apktool/install/">apktool</a> and <a href="https://github.com/appium/sign">apksign</a>. I’ll also use <a href="https://developer.android.com/studio">Android Studio</a> to run and debug the app. The fact that I couldn’t run the app on my phone may have just come from an Android version compatibility issue: I had no problem running it on an emulated Android 4.4 device with Android Studio. The decompilation of the <code>classes.dex</code> file gives us some interesting information right away:</p>
<figure id="attachment_438"><a href="http://digitalnk.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/dex2jar1.png"><img src="http://digitalnk.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/dex2jar1.png" alt="" width="211" height="326"></a><figcaption>Packages and classes from the decompiled <code>classes.dex</code> file</figcaption></figure><p>The name of the <code>com.bz.cityisland2</code> package actually refers to the original game that <em>City Management</em> is based on: <a href="https://www.sparklingsociety.net/sparkling-games/city-building-games/city-island-2/">City Island 2</a> by the Dutch game studio Sparkling Society. The name of the package <code>com.smartions.appprotected</code> refers to <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/smartions-ag#section-overview">Smartions</a>, a company that offers solutions to “monetize your mobile game or app in China” and are apparently also City Island’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sparkling_Society">distributor in China</a>. There are no mentions of those companies in the game itself however. The game’s loading splash screen only tells us that the game was made by the Ryusong (meteor) Technology Exchange Center (류성기술교류소) and that it is protected by the law for the protection of software (<a href="https://www.kisdi.re.kr/kisdi/common/premium?file=1%7C10360">콤퓨터쏘프트웨어보호법</a>). The law has been in place since 2003 to regulate the sales and distribution of software in the country and guarantees software developers the private ownership of their creation.</p>
<figure id="attachment_502"><a href="http://digitalnk.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/kyongyong-1.png"><img src="http://digitalnk.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/kyongyong-1.png" alt="" width="1000" height="640"></a><figcaption>Loading screen for the game</figcaption></figure><p>It’s hard to tell whether the North Korean version is based on the source code of the original game or if it’s entirely reverse engineered. In any case, the North Korean version does not use Smartions’s monetization system nor Sparkling Society’s but relies on a different system, which is the main difference from the original game. Save for the translation and some minor renames, the game is otherwise similar to the original (from a cursory examination) in its design, gameplay, features… to the original. </p>
<figure id="attachment_442"><a href="http://digitalnk.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/UnityStructure.png"><img src="http://digitalnk.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/UnityStructure.png" alt="" width="339" height="221"></a><figcaption>Structure a Unity APK. From Shim et al., <a href="https://www.hindawi.com/journals/scn/2018/6280768/"><em>Static and Dynamic Analysis of Android Malware and Goodware Written with Unity Framework</em></a> (2018).<br></figcaption></figure><p>There’s not much more we can glean from the Java code for now since, as the classes in <code>unity3dplayer</code> and <code>AndroidManifest.xml</code> file make clear, it is used to run code that was written with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unity_(game_engine)">Unity</a>, a popular cross-plaform video game framework which uses C# as its main programming language. The Unity code is stored in various library with the developer’s C# code being compiled to <code>Assembly-CSharp.dll</code>. C# compiled code is easily decompilable using tools such as <a href="https://github.com/0xd4d/dnSpy">dnSpy</a>. Once the dll is decompiled, we can look for the message we got earlier “열쇠화일이 존재하지 않습니다” (“The key file does not exist”) to find the bits of code we are interested in. The string search takes us to the <code>CIGLoadingScreen</code> class where we find the string among other variables:</p>
<pre title="">
	// Token: 0x0400056A RID: 1386
	private string userKey;

	// Token: 0x0400056B RID: 1387
	private string tapjoyCurrencyIdentifier;

	// Token: 0x0400056C RID: 1388
	private bool bannerVisible;

	// Token: 0x0400056D RID: 1389
	private int _loadingScreenShownCount;

	// Token: 0x0400056E RID: 1390
	private Dictionary&lt;int, bool&gt; m_gameObjectStatus = new Dictionary&lt;int, bool&gt;();

	// Token: 0x0400056F RID: 1391
	private bool m_isVerify;

	// Token: 0x04000570 RID: 1392
	private Font kfont;

	// Token: 0x04000571 RID: 1393
	private string reqMsg = "열쇠화일이 존재하지 않습니다.\r\n열쇠화일을 판매소에서 구입하십시오.";

	// Token: 0x04000572 RID: 1394
	private string reqNumLabel = "요청번호 : ";

	// Token: 0x04000573 RID: 1395
	private string reqNum;

	// Token: 0x04000574 RID: 1396
	private string finishLabel = "끝내기";
</pre><p>Looking for the name of the string variable <code>reqMsg</code> takes us here:</p>
<pre title="">	// Token: 0x06000928 RID: 2344 RVA: 0x00026E60 File Offset: 0x00025060
	private void OnGUI()
	{
		if (!this.m_isVerify &amp;&amp; this.loadingDone)
		{
			GUI.skin.font = this.kfont;
			GUI.DrawTexture(new Rect(0f, 0f, (float)Screen.width, (float)Screen.height), this.blackBg, ScaleMode.StretchToFill);
			GUI.Label(this.GetTextLabelRect(this.reqMsg, 0.5f, 0.3f), this.reqMsg);
			GUI.Label(this.GetTextLabelRect(this.reqNumLabel, 0.3f, 0.5f), this.reqNumLabel);
			GUI.Label(this.GetTextLabelRect(this.reqNum, 0.6f, 0.5f), this.reqNum);
			RectOffset padding = GUI.skin.button.padding;
			GUI.skin.button.padding = new RectOffset(20, 20, 10, 10);
			if (GUI.Button(this.GetButtonRect(this.finishLabel, 0.5f, 0.8f), this.finishLabel))
			{
				Application.Quit();
			}
		}
	}
</pre><p>This is the code used to display the splashscreen we encountered earlier. If the boolean property <code>this.m_isVerify</code>, presumably the result of a call to a function checking the existence and validity of a licence key, is <code>False</code> then, the screen is displayed with the message we saw earlier and the “request number”. The verification function and the generation of the request number are handled in another class <code>GameCus</code>:</p>
<pre title="">using System;
using System.IO;
using System.Runtime.InteropServices;

// Token: 0x02000147 RID: 327
public class GameCus
{
	// Token: 0x06000AA7 RID: 2727
	[DllImport("Game")]
	private static extern int vProcess(byte[] key, int keyLen, byte[] certData, int certDataLen);

	// Token: 0x06000AA9 RID: 2729 RVA: 0x0002E910 File Offset: 0x0002CB10
	public string GetReqNumber()
	{
		string deviceIdString = this.GetDeviceIdString();
		return string.Format("{0:d4} {1:d4} {2:d4} {3:d4}", new object[]
		{
			deviceIdString.Substring(0, 4),
			deviceIdString.Substring(4, 4),
			deviceIdString.Substring(8, 4),
			deviceIdString.Substring(12, 4)
		});
	}

	// Token: 0x06000AAA RID: 2730 RVA: 0x0002E968 File Offset: 0x0002CB68
	public string GetDeviceIdString()
	{
		string text = Utils.GetDeviceModel();
		text = string.Format("{0:d10}", (uint)text.GetHashCode());
		string str = text.Substring(2, 8);
		string text2 = Utils.GetDeviceUid();
		text2 = string.Format("{0:d10}", (uint)text2.GetHashCode());
		string str2 = text2.Substring(2, 8);
		return str + str2;
	}

	// Token: 0x06000AAB RID: 2731 RVA: 0x0002E9CC File Offset: 0x0002CBCC
	public bool checkCertData(byte[] certData)
	{
		if (certData == null || certData.Length == 0)
		{
			return false;
		}
		string text = this.GetDeviceIdString() + …</pre></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://digitalnk.com/blog/2019/04/21/reverse-engineering-a-north-korean-sim-city-game/">https://digitalnk.com/blog/2019/04/21/reverse-engineering-a-north-korean-sim-city-game/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://digitalnk.com/blog/2019/04/21/reverse-engineering-a-north-korean-sim-city-game/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24670827</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 09:39:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why is the market share of Firefox in Germany so much higher?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 17 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24670605">thread link</a>) | @jlelse
<br/>
October 3, 2020 | https://jlelse.blog/posts/firefox-market-share/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jlelse.blog/posts/firefox-market-share/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I recently took a closer look at Cloudflare’s new project <a href="https://radar.cloudflare.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Radar</a>. Besides statistics about internet usage, attacks and popular domains, the site also shows statistics about the market shares of browsers.</p><p>Here is an overview of the global statistics:</p><p><a href="https://media.jlelse.blog/eb2cc6b3a4f116777f08594989bc16b4376a10b159e2c9d9ccc93080fb077631.png"><img src="https://media.jlelse.blog/eb2cc6b3a4f116777f08594989bc16b4376a10b159e2c9d9ccc93080fb077631.png" loading="lazy" alt="Global top browsers" title="Global top browsers"></a></p><p>Here the distribution in the USA:</p><p><a href="https://media.jlelse.blog/172293b33c412050c263e9a5eff0062158c509b58e40c3da31447199e304a871.png"><img src="https://media.jlelse.blog/172293b33c412050c263e9a5eff0062158c509b58e40c3da31447199e304a871.png" loading="lazy" alt="Top browsers in the USA" title="Top browsers in the USA"></a></p><p>And here in Germany:</p><p><a href="https://media.jlelse.blog/fb2e26d1aafda14d14b0affe91b35c6e531669632b3aa7cad1de3276130dd795.png"><img src="https://media.jlelse.blog/fb2e26d1aafda14d14b0affe91b35c6e531669632b3aa7cad1de3276130dd795.png" loading="lazy" alt="Top browsers in Germany" title="Top browsers in Germany"></a></p><p>When comparing the statistics, I notice a few interesting things:</p><ul><li>In the USA as well as in Germany the usage of Firefox is higher than the world average. In Germany, however, it is much higher, instead of only about 7%, the share of Firefox in Germany is almost 21%.</li><li>The use of Safari (iOS and desktop) in the USA is significantly higher than the world average and in Germany.</li><li>However, Chrome (mobile) and Samsung Internet have higher shares in Germany than in the USA. But Chrome (mobile) in Germany still has less than worldwide.</li></ul><p>The higher share of Safari in the USA can probably be explained relatively by the higher market share of Apple in the USA. While many people in Germany tend to rely more on Android smartphones (and Windows PCs), the iPhone (and Mac) share is significantly higher in the USA. Here are <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/461900/android-vs-ios-market-share-in-smartphone-sales-germany/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">some</a> <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/1150677/us-market-share-held-by-leading-smartphone-vendors/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">statistics</a> on this.</p><p>This different distribution naturally also affects the other mobile browsers. In Germany many people seem to use Samsung smartphones and the pre-installed browser Samsung Internet.</p><p>What I can’t quite explain is the high percentage of Firefox in Germany. Are people in Germany more critical of Google? I somehow don’t believe that…</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jlelse.blog/posts/firefox-market-share/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24670605</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 08:53:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Avoiding Worry Driven Development]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 30 | Comments 9 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24670483">thread link</a>) | @gfysfm
<br/>
October 3, 2020 | https://www.seangoedecke.com/worry-driven-development/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.seangoedecke.com/worry-driven-development/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article><header></header><section><p>Sofware dysfunction is more often motivated by anxiety, fear, worry and embarassment than it is by a lack of technical skill. Engineers avoid work that needs doing because they’re afraid of becoming entangled with a nightmarish task, or because they’re afraid of looking stupid, or harming their career by spending time on grungy work. The task itself is rarely that difficult; it just seems so, which is enough of a barrier to discourage anyone from picking it up. One of the highest-leverage things you can do as an engineer is to recognize this emotional reaction in yourself and work to counter it. If you’re working on a single task, doing this can make your implementation significantly cleaner. If you’re a senior engineer with responsibility for a whole system, this can help you address high-impact architectural or operational issues.</p>
<p>You can see this in the common advice to sleep on a problem and come back to it in the morning. A bug that seems impossible when you’re tired and frustrated is far more approachable when you’re well-rested and caffeinated. Tedious investigative tasks (like scanning the logs for a bug or tracing all the possible code paths in a function) are still tedious in the morning, but infinitely more doable. You can knock it out in half an hour while drinking your morning coffee, rather than spending hours the night before avoiding the tedious work and hoping for a flash of inspiration.</p>
<p>Necessary work avoided becomes a haunted forest in the codebase. One engineer’s avoidant emotions turn into dangerous team habits as engineers teach each other to avoid touching certain files, or to pass odd-looking production bugs to the operations team. “This network behaviour is dark magic, let them handle it!” What began as a single engineer’s worry is now a team’s dysfunction, and can eventually metastasize into actively blocking engineers from working on the original technical problems: if you’re avoiding working on a worrying problem, it can feel threatening when someone else comes along and tries to solve it. What if they succeed, or worse still succeed easily? That would reveal that you weren’t good enough to solve the problem.</p>
<p>Just because you’re touching a scary part of the system doesn’t mean you’re facing scary work calmly and rationally. Engineers often approach thorny work like they’re going through a haunted house: either trudging through with eyes half-closed, or rushing through at full speed trying to get out as quickly as possible. Both tactics aim to take in as little of the frightening environment as possible, and neither tactic is a good way of solving real problems in technical systems. If you’ve ever just tweaked setings or frantically moved code around until it worked, you’ve done this.</p>
<p>From the inside, this doesn’t feel like emotionally-driven avoidance. It feels like working on legacy code, sharing friendly complaints about it with other engineers on your team. This is in part because a fear of hard technical problems can be a rational fear. Untangling messy parts of the codebase, identifying and removing dead code, cleaning up build, deploy and monitoring systems - these tasks often feel overwhelming because they can overwhelm you, sucking up days for no real gain. It can harm your career to spend time on this work in an org that mainly values shipping features. (I haven’t seen the other common worry - looking stupid - really be an issue in practice myself.) The trouble comes when you don’t recognise that part of your response is emotional, and therefore overrate the actual difficulty or risk.</p>
<p>How can you distinguish a rational response to a too-difficult task from a learned emotional reaction to a task that is merely worrying? This is a hard problem. I think it is the hardest problem that almost all engineers will regularly face. One approach is to avoid trying to tell the difference at all, and allot a certain amount of time to looking at randomly-chosen neglected parts of the system. Things that reduce stress in general are also good ways to reduce stress and worry about work. Good sleep, eating well, exercise, therapy, and working in an emotionally safe team all have a significant positive effect on the quality of engineering work. Once you start doing this, the difference is usually obvious in hindsight: if the task that worried you for six months took an hour or two of work when you finally mustered up the effort to look at it, you know your worry was unfounded. Dealing with worry is a virtuous cycle. Each difficult task you do makes you less scared of the next one.</p>
<p>Tackling a series of worrying tasks is one of the quickest ways I know to have massive impact in your engineering org. This is because once you understand a thorny piece of code, or a neglected system, you will usually see how to make obvious improvements. In any other part of the system these improvements would have been made already, but since you are the first person to really wrap your head around it in a long time, you get to make them here! Occasionally, you will see the opportunity to completely remove the worrying part of the system, which for me is one of the most satisfying things you can do as a software engineer. Removing things that cause your team stress has compounding benefits to your team, to the systems you work on, and to your engineering org in general.</p></section><hr></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/worry-driven-development/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24670483</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 08:23:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[An Honest Review of Gatsby]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 171 | Comments 113 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24670252">thread link</a>) | @ehfeng
<br/>
October 3, 2020 | https://cra.mr/an-honest-review-of-gatsby/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://cra.mr/an-honest-review-of-gatsby/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>We decided to adopt Gatsby for <a href="https://docs.sentry.io/">Sentry’s customer-facing documentation</a> - well, I should say that <em>I</em> decided. We were already using it successfully for a variety of static marketing content, and I knew it had a lot of hype, so after a brief proof-of-concept it seemed like a safe choice.</p>
<p>To help contextualize everything I’m about to say, it’s important to understand the scope of our usage. Sentry’s documentation is not as straightforward as you might think - in fact, there are over 3,000 pages as of writing. We have a large amount of templated content designed to render language-specific examples, as well as a variety of different types of documentation (user guides, help desk-y articles, code-rich technical docs). Originally we had extended Jekyll to support a lot of this, but Ruby isn’t widely used at Sentry (approximately 0% of the engineering team knows Ruby), and it had become a big mess of spaghetti code with slow build times.</p>
<p>I also want to note that while this blog post is primarily focusing on the flaws of Gatsby as a framework, I’m not here to tell you that it’s not good for your use case. That said, I was not able to discover many of these short comings easily when evaluating Gatsby, and many things you read on the internet don’t stem out of real-world usage. My hope here is that Gatsby continues to improve over time, and that, as a user, you can be more informed about if it’s the right choice for you.</p>
<h2>Adopting Gatsby</h2>
<p>So, enter Gatsby. It seemed fast, was built on React (we’re experts on that here, with our gigabyte-sized Sentry frontend app), and had a huge adoption (assumed future existence and stability). While we didn’t have the desire to use MDX, it also seemed like a positive outcome given we could more easily deal with some of the rich aspects of our docs site, without having to resort to 2010-era JavaScript. We assumed a bunch of the other features of Gatsby had value-add, but we didn’t have an immediate need. These were things like dynamic source data - thus the need for a GraphQL engine at all - as well as the large plug-in ecosystem.</p>
<p>We started by iteratively converting sections of the Jekyll site into Gatsby - running them side by side for a time. At one point we eventually bulk converted pages, and ripped off the band aid. At this point though it was becoming clear build times were a problem. You’d spend at least 5 minutes on image optimization alone, with no way to even disable that. Slowly but surely we were depleting the ozone later on re-optimizing images which had already been pre-optimized. Oh yeah, and we were crippling our iteration speed as well, since the build cache would invalidate under a variety of situations in early development.</p>
<p>Making this worse was how we deployed Gatsby. We started off leveraging what we had already done: deploying Jekyll with Docker onto our own infrastructure - effectively just proxied via a CDN. We continued that for a period of time, but deploy times were far too long - upwards of 30-40 minutes for everything to build. Eventually we moved over to <a href="https://vercel.com/">Vercel</a> which dropped it down closer to 10 minutes, but ultimately it can’t fix what it doesn’t control.</p>
<p>The build and deploy times were the first of many woes, and they represent what would become a continued frustration: a problem without a clear solution.</p>
<h2>Enter MDX</h2>
<p>Rewind time a little bit - this actually wasn’t our first project converting documentation to Gatsby. The proof-of-concept I mentioned earlier was actually our <a href="https://develop.sentry.dev/">developer documentation</a>, which I had migrated out of Notion to make public. While doing that we had gotten our hands dirty with some initial MDX usability and extensions - like our code samples which support toggling between different languages. This was one of the many things we needed to solve for, but MDX made it look like it’d be seemingly easy. No more jQuery DOM manipulation, just clean, encapsulated React components. Or so we thought.</p>
<p>Almost immediately we hit rough spots with MDX. We were coming from Jekyll - which was Liquid-rendered (a template engine) markdown - to MDX - a strange offspring of Markdown and JSX, attempting all of the benefits of both, but missing by a fairly large margin. Let’s illustrate the crux of the issue with what has got to be one of the most common needs in a documentation system: an alert (or callout) component:</p>
<div data-language="markdown"><pre><code><span><span><span>&lt;</span>Alert</span> <span>level</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>info<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span>You should know something important about this!<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>Alert</span><span>&gt;</span></span></code></pre></div>
<p>At face value this looks great. <code>Alert</code> is just a React component, and JSX is close enough to HTML that non-technical folks are able to pick it up fairly easily. Now the problem comes into play when you actually want to do something in the real world. Here’s an example from our API docs:</p>
<div data-language="markdown"><pre><code><span><span><span>&lt;</span>Alert</span> <span>level</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>warning<span>"</span></span> <span>title</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>Note<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span>
    <span><span>**</span><span>PUT/DELETE</span><span>**</span></span> methods only apply to updating/deleting issues.
Events in sentry are immutable and can only be deleted by deleting the whole issue.
<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>Alert</span><span>&gt;</span></span></code></pre></div>
<p>How would you expect this to render? Both as an engineer and a non-engineer, I would expect - given this is markdown - that the “PUT/DELETE” text would be bold. It’s not. Because the MDX interpreter decides that once you enter a component block, it’s no longer markdown. So instead, we’re forced with this monstrosity <em>everywhere</em> in our documentation:</p>
<div data-language="markdown"><pre><code><span><span><span>&lt;</span>Alert</span> <span>level</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>warning<span>"</span></span> <span>title</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>Note<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span><span><span><span>&lt;</span>markdown</span><span>&gt;</span></span>

<span><span>**</span><span>PUT/DELETE</span><span>**</span></span> methods only apply to updating/deleting issues.
Events in sentry are immutable and can only be deleted by deleting the whole issue.

<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>markdown</span><span>&gt;</span></span><span><span><span>&lt;/</span>Alert</span><span>&gt;</span></span></code></pre></div>
<p>There’s two things you should note here: 1) we have to use this <code>&lt;markdown&gt;</code> tag, 2) we have to put empty new-lines to ensure paragraph tags render.</p>
<p>“But David”, you might say, “why don’t you just tell the <code>Alert</code> component to render the text as markdown?“. If only you could, or at least, if only I could have possibly found a way to achieve that as a user with minimal Gatsby or MDX internals knowledge.</p>
<p>To Gatsby, or at least to the MDX team’s credit, they recognize some of these problems and <a href="https://github.com/mdx-js/mdx/issues/1041">there is work underway</a> on a 2.0 of the MDX dialect. While I’m confident they will improve things, I’m not confident MDX can ultimately succeed. It’s likely going to tradeoff one problem for another due to what it’s trying to achieve in the first place. It may get to a good place, but frankly, we need to step back and look at what we’re trying to solve, instead of creating a solution to a problem we don’t have. I don’t need JSX syntax in my markdown, I need a way to include JSX components. That might sound similar, but its quite a different thing.</p>
<p>As an example, there’s no reason I couldn’t simply use markdown syntax, and provide a way to achieve something akin to:</p>
<div data-language="markdown"><pre><code><span><span><span>&lt;</span>a-valid-html-tag-because-markdown-allows-that</span> <span>a-valid-property</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>a-value<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span></code></pre></div>
<p>This wouldn’t force us to work around quirks in a new language (or interpreter even), and could be solved in a much more sustainable way. There are other alternatives as well. A generic way to render extensions in markdown could simply call into a React component, and avoid even trying to hijack HTML in the first place. While I don’t know what this might look like in Markdown, in <a href="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/en/master/usage/restructuredtext/index.html">Sphinx’s use of reStructuredText</a> this was solved early on with Directives:</p>
<div data-language="text"><pre><code>.. my-directive:: some data
   :property-name: property-value</code></pre></div>
<p>I will hold out for MDX 2.0 and hope that finds a nice minimal-compromise place, but if not, we’ll be looking for a way to extend native markdown.</p>
<h2>A Broken DOM</h2>
<p>While we were able to work around the kinks of MDX, there’s been some things not yet solved. One of those is the layer which Gatsby uses to apply diffs to the DOM. I’m going to caveat this section with <em>I don’t know what the technical implementation is</em>, but I can make some assumptions given what I know of the domain. The system itself is intended to apply deltas to the DOM. This is naively also how React works, and I imagine under the hood it’s relying on React at least for part of it. We’ve had issues with this identified in two places already:</p>
<ul>
<li>progressive image loading</li>
<li>dynamic JSX components</li>
</ul>
<p>While they might not be linked to the same issue, they smell like they are, so we’re going to roll with it. The problem exhibits itself when you have a bunch of DOM that to a naive robot might look the same:</p>
<div data-language="text"><pre><code>&lt;div&gt;foo&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;bar&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;baz&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;foobizbar&lt;/div&gt;</code></pre></div>
<p>In React it uses the graph to identify which node is which - effectively creating a unique entity ID based on its location. In cases where that’s difficult, React will warn you to explicitly bind a <code>key</code> attribute on each element to ensure it can more accurately deal with updates. While I would assume Gatsby is at least partially using React’s DOM engine, what we see in production effectively takes the above example, and replaces some of the content with other subsets of content - meaning it’s unable to accurately identify which nodes need updated.</p>
<p>We’ve seen this where a progressive image is replaced with an entirely different image that’s present near it on the page. We’ve also seen this happen for a dynamically loaded section of content (our language-selector include tags). While we’ve yet to identify a fix for the image tags, our other issue was resolved by literally changing a <code>div</code> tag to a different tag, one which is less commonly used (in our case, <code>section</code>).</p>
<p>All of the cases happen after Gatsby’s initial static render and exist only when applying some form of delta.</p>
<h2>Let’s Talk GraphQL</h2>
<p>It’s a static website generator. It literally does not need GraphQL all over the place. While there are few instances in the real world where that is valuable, it shouldn’t require a GraphQL API to read objects that are already in memory.</p>
<p>I don’t want to spend the energy to hammer this in, but take a look at Jared Palmer’s <a href="https://jaredpalmer.com/gatsby-vs-nextjs">Gatsby vs. Next.js</a> as it echoes my thoughts.</p>
<p>So, let’s actually not talk about GraphQL, but all its done is create complexity for us.</p>
<h2>Minor Gripes</h2>
<p>There’s a number of other things we’ve found fairly frustrating at this point, but this post is already getting long, so I’m choosing to summarize them.</p></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://cra.mr/an-honest-review-of-gatsby/">https://cra.mr/an-honest-review-of-gatsby/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://cra.mr/an-honest-review-of-gatsby/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24670252</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 07:18:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
