<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 12:31:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 12:31:53 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Your Move, iPad]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 95 | Comments 114 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25218050">thread link</a>) | @rcarmo
<br/>
November 26, 2020 | https://beckyhansmeyer.com/2020/11/25/your-move-ipad/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://beckyhansmeyer.com/2020/11/25/your-move-ipad/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Hear that? It’s the sound of Mac fans. No, not your shiny new M1 Mac’s fans—chances are, you’ll never hear those—but rather, the sound of <em>excitement</em> rippling through the Mac community. This is something big. Really big. Now, I’m only 33, but someday when I go full fuddy-duddy I will speak of this: the great Intel/Apple Silicon transition. The beginning of a new era at Apple.</p>



<p>All that sounds dramatic, of course, but it’s interesting to trace all of the different paths that led us to this point. The A-Series chips, the introduction of Metal, rapid machine learning gains, the gradually degrading repairability scores as components became more integrated, the Secure Enclave, a new super fast emulation layer, new unified memory architecture, and 5nm process… years and years of work have now come to fruition with the first Apple Silicon chips for Mac. And our minds are blown.</p>



<p>Suddenly, we’re handed a thin, entry-level fanless laptop that performs better than almost every other Mac computer out there, and a low-end MacBook Pro and Mac Mini that make current Mac Pro owners sweat and clutch their wheels. So many questions abound. What new hardware designs will these gains make possible? What on earth does Apple have in store for its high-end Macs? Will anyone else even be able to compete? It’s an exciting time to be a Mac lover, but, surprise: this post isn’t really about the Mac. It’s about the iPad.</p>



<p>There’s no question that Apple has struggled to craft a cohesive, compelling narrative for the iPad. For a long time, there seemed to be a distinct lack of product vision. Everyone likes to speculate over what role Steve Jobs ultimately intended the iPad to have in people’s lives, but not only is that pointless, it’s also irrelevant. We don’t need Steve to tell us what the iPad is good for. We know what it’s good for, and we can easily imagine what it <em>could</em> be good for, if only Apple would set it free.</p>



<p>Just as Apple left us with great expectations for its Pro Mac line-up, the latest iPad Air also raises the bar in new and interesting ways. The Air served as sort of an appetizer for the new M1 chips, while also receiving a generous trickle-down of features from the iPad Pro, including USB-C and support for the latest keyboard and Pencil accessories. There have been rumors of new mini-LED displays for the next-gen iPad Pros, but it’s going to take a lot more than new display tech to set the Pros apart.</p>



<p>Francisco Tolmasky (<a href="https://twitter.com/tolmasky/status/1330033394349125642?s=20">@tolmasky</a>) recently tweeted:</p>



<blockquote><p>“A sad but inescapable conclusion from the impressive launch of the M1 is just how much Apple squandered the potential of the iPad. The iPad has had amazing performance for awhile, so why is the M1 a game changer? Because it’s finally in a machine we can actually <em>do things on</em>.”</p></blockquote>



<p>Francisco is right: Power and performance aren’t the bottleneck for iPad, and haven’t been for some time. So if raw power isn’t enough, and new display tech isn’t enough, where does the iPad go from here? Will it be abandoned once more, lagging behind the Mac in terms of innovation, or will Apple continue to debut its latest tech in this form factor? Is it headed toward functional parity with the Mac or will it always be hamstrung by Apple’s strict App Store policies and seemingly inconsistent investment in iPadOS?</p>



<p>It’s clear that Apple <em>wants</em> the iPad Pro to be a device that a wide variety of professionals can use to get work done. And since so many people use web apps for their work, the introduction of “desktop” Safari for iPad was an important step toward that goal. The Magic Keyboard and trackpad was another step.</p>



<p>Here are ten more steps I believe Apple could and should take to help nudge the iPad into this exciting next era of computing.</p>



<ol><li>Give the iPad Pro another port. Two USB 4.0 ports would be lovely.</li><li>Adopt a landscape-first mindset. Rotate the Apple logo on the back and move the iPad’s front-facing camera on the side beneath the Apple Pencil charger to better reflect how most people actually use their iPad Pros.</li><li>Introduce Gatekeeper and app notarization for iOS. The process of side-loading apps should <em>not</em> be as simple as downloading them from the App Store. Bury it in Settings, make it slightly convoluted, whatever: just have an officially-sanctioned way of doing it.</li><li>Ruthlessly purge the App Store Guidelines of anything that prevents the iPad from serving as a development machine. Every kind of development from web to games should be possible on an iPad. And speaking of games—emulators should be allowed, too.</li><li>Release a suite of professional first-party apps at premium prices. If someone can edit 4K videos in Final Cut on their M1 MacBook Air, they should be able to edit 4K videos in Final Cut on their iPad Pro. I refuse to believe that these pro apps can’t be re-imagined and optimized for a touch experience. If Apple leads the way in developing premium software for iPad, others will follow.</li><li>Make it possible to write, release, and install plug-ins (if appropriate) for the aforementioned first party apps.</li><li>Bring App Library to the iPad and allow widgets to be positioned anywhere on the Home Screen. This isn’t groundbreaking, it just annoys the heck out of me.</li><li>Release a new keyboard + trackpad case accessory that allows the iPad to be used in tablet mode without removing it from the case.</li><li>Introduce Time Machine backups for iPadOS.</li><li>5G, ofc.</li></ol>



<p>In the end, fostering a vibrant community of iPad app developers can only stand to benefit the Mac (and vice-versa).</p>



<p>It’s simple: people love their iPads. They love them so much they wish they could do even more with them. The new M1 Macs should give iPad fans reason to be excited; now that we’ve seen hints of what future Macs can be, it’s time for the iPad to reassert itself—to remind us once again who it’s for, and what makes it special.</p>



<p>In other words: Your move, iPad.</p>
			</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://beckyhansmeyer.com/2020/11/25/your-move-ipad/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25218050</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 08:28:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Discord bans me for using their official client]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 51 | Comments 52 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25214777">thread link</a>) | @jkcclemens
<br/>
November 25, 2020 | https://annaclemens.io/discord | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://annaclemens.io/discord">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
    <section>
      

      <p>
        Quick note: I don't really have a blog, but I wanted to publish this
        on my site, so this just has some quick styles applied.
      </p>

      <hr>

      <p>
	<strong>Resolution</strong>: My Discord account has been unbanned. After posting this page on Hacker News, the head of Discord's anti-abuse team saw it and looked into the issue. It turns out that my use of a third-party Discord client called Ripcord was the reason for my ban. At the time of the ban, I had been using this client for years, but I wasn't actively using it. I was actually using the official client, hence the older title of this page, but the third-party client was open on my laptop in the background. I leave this page here to chronicle how unacceptable Discord's response to this was.
      </p>

      <hr>

      <p>
        It's true: Discord banned me for using their own client. On 1
        November, I was scrolling through my old DMs. It was kind of messy, so
        I started to close some of them (which really just <em>hides</em>
        them). After closing maybe around seven of them, Discord booted me
        back to the login screen. I thought that was weird, but I grabbed my
        phone to scan the QR code to log in, but it didn't work. Annoyed, I
        manually typed in my login details only to find that my account has
        been disabled.
      </p>

      <h2>1 November</h2>

      <p>
        On the same day, 1 November, I opened a ticket (9765093) stating that
        I wasn't sure why my account was disabled and that I would like to
        know. They had sent me an email telling me that my account had been
        disabled, but the email only listed a vague list of reasons that could
        have caused the ban, and I didn't feel that I had done any of them.
      </p>

      <h2>3 November <small>2 days</small></h2>

      <p>
        On 3 November, two days later, Discord got back to me and let me know
        that I had received an email stating why my account was disabled
        (false) and that they had reviewed my ban and would not be reinstating
        my account.
      </p>

      <p>
        The same day, I responded to their email, stating that their
        explanation wasn't good enough and that I hadn't done anything
        wrong. I demanded they give me an actual reason and reinstate my
        account.
      </p>

      <h2>6 November <small>5 days</small></h2>

      <p>
        Three days go by with no response from Discord. On 6 November, I send
        another response to their email, reiterating my desires and asking
        that I at least be able to transfer power of my larger servers if they
        insist on being corrupt.
      </p>

      <h2>12 November <small>11 days</small></h2>

      <p>
        Another six days without a peep from Discord. 12 November: I send yet
        another response, reiterating what I had said in previous emails and
        asking to be put in contact with a GDPR officer to get the data I
        want.
      </p>

      <h2>14 November <small>13 days</small></h2>

      <p>
        After two more days, Discord <em>still</em> has <strong>not</strong> responded outside of
        the initial email I received. On 14 November, I file a new ticket
        (9984772) and mention my previous ticket number and restate that I
        would like a reason why my account was banned and to have my account
        reinstated, considering I hadn't actually done anything besides <em>use
        their official client</em>.
      </p>

      <h2>17 November <small>16 days</small></h2>

      <p>
        After three days, on 17 November, the new ticket gets a
        response. Discord gives me the same list of reasons (a list of bullet
        points that count as "spam and/or platform abuse") and assure me that
        they understand "you may not have malicious intent, [but] we have to
        protect Discord as a whole, and this behavio[u]r can hurt Discord and
        its users." They also go on to mention that as a "one-time gesture",
        they "went ahead" (past tense) and lifted the ban on my account.
      </p>

      <p>
        Hooray, I guess. I go to log in to Discord and it turns out that was a
        lie. My account is still disabled. I figure maybe it needs some time
        to propagate the change, but after hours and then days of trying, my
        account remains disabled. During these initial attempts on 17
        November, I sent a response to Discord, stating that I would like to
        know the real reason I was banned, since what I was doing while I was
        banned wasn't spam or platform abuse, it was closing old DMs manually
        with the official client, a supported use-case. I also made note that my
        account had not been unbanned.
      </p>

      <h2>18 November <small>17 days</small></h2>

      <p>
        On 18 November, my account is still banned despite Discord saying they
        would lift the ban, so I send a quick response asking when the ban
        will be lifted.
      </p>

      <h2>19 November <small>18 days</small></h2>

      <p>
        On 19 November, I ask again, noting that this is the third time I've
        replied to this ticket and still not received a response.
      </p>

      <h2>20 November <small>19 days</small></h2>

      <p>
        On 20 November, I open yet another new ticket (10088193), reference
        the old one, and ask why I haven't been unbanned, demanding that they
        honour their word and lift my ban.
      </p>

      <h2>25 November <small>24 days</small></h2>

      <p>
        On 25 November, <em>eight days</em> after I was told my account would be
        unbanned and <em>twenty-four days</em> after the ban in question, I still
        have not heard from Discord. I was (and am still) banned for doing
        nothing wrong. Discord did not deign to reply to my last ticket at
        all, but I'm filing another one today (25 Nov, 10166788). I will
        continue to update this log of communications as time goes on.
      </p>
    </section>
  

</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://annaclemens.io/discord</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25214777</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 22:01:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[This is how Google will collapse]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 62 | Comments 64 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25213493">thread link</a>) | @partingshots
<br/>
November 25, 2020 | http://www.sfu.ca/olc/blog/engage/how-google-will-collapse | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.sfu.ca/olc/blog/engage/how-google-will-collapse">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p><em>Previously published in&nbsp;<a href="https://hackernoon.com/how-google-collapsed-b6ffa82198ee">HACKERNOON</a>. Originally written by SFU Masters of Digital Media student Daniel Colin James.&nbsp;Re-published with permission of the writer.</em></p>
<p><em>Illustration Credit:&nbsp;</em><a href="https://mandelasmith.artstation.com/">Mandela Smith</a></p>
<hr>
<p>Google made almost all its money from ads. It was a booming business — until it wasn’t. Here’s how things looked right before the most spectacular crash the technology industry had ever seen.</p>
<div>
<h3>The crumbling of Google’s cornerstone</h3>
<p>Search was Google’s only unambiguous win, as well as its&nbsp;<a href="http://www.cnbc.com/2017/01/26/googlealphabet-reports-fourth-quarter-2016-earnings-q4.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.cnbc.com/2017/01/26/googlealphabet-reports-fourth-quarter-2016-earnings-q4.html">primary source of revenue</a>, so when Amazon&nbsp;<a href="http://www.geekwire.com/2017/amazon-continues-grow-lead-google-starting-point-online-shoppers/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.geekwire.com/2017/amazon-continues-grow-lead-google-starting-point-online-shoppers/">rapidly surpassed Google</a>&nbsp;as the top product search destination, Google’s foundations began to falter.&nbsp;As&nbsp;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/08/11/google-isnt-safe-from-yahoos-fate/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/08/11/google-isnt-safe-from-yahoos-fate/">many noted</a>&nbsp;at the time, the online advertising industry experienced a major shift from search to discovery in the mid-2010s.</p>
<p>While Google protected its monopoly on the dying search advertising market, Facebook — Google’s biggest competitor in the online advertising space — got on the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.emarketer.com/Article/Google-Facebook-Increase-Their-Grip-on-Digital-Ad-Market/1015417" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://www.emarketer.com/Article/Google-Facebook-Increase-Their-Grip-on-Digital-Ad-Market/1015417">right side of the trend</a>&nbsp;and dominated online advertising with its in-feed native display advertising.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.sfu.ca/olc/sites/default/files/1.1.jpeg" width="533" height="239"></p>
<p><em><span>The people who turned to Amazon over Google? <a href="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Screen-Shot-2017-01-13-at-10.40.08-AM.png">The 18-29 led the way</a></span></em></p>
<p>In late 2015, Apple — Google’s main competitor in the mobile space — added a feature to their phones and tablets that allowed users to block ads.</p>
<p>Devices running iOS were responsible for an&nbsp;<a href="http://appleinsider.com/articles/15/05/27/apples-ios-drives-75-of-googles-mobile-advertising-revenue" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://appleinsider.com/articles/15/05/27/apples-ios-drives-75-of-googles-mobile-advertising-revenue">estimated 75%</a>&nbsp;of Google’s revenue from mobile search ads, so by making this move, Apple was simultaneously weighing in decisively on the great ad blocking debate of the 2010s and dealing a substantial blow to the&nbsp;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/07/24/apple-lays-the-groundwork-to-kill-online-advertising/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/07/24/apple-lays-the-groundwork-to-kill-online-advertising/">future of online advertising</a>.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.sfu.ca/olc/sites/default/files/1.3.jpeg" width="533" height="196"></p>
<p><em><sub>The rising number of users blocking ads on mobile showed no signs of slowing down</sub></em></p>
</div>
<div>
<p>A year later, as the internet went mobile, so too did ad blocking. The number of people blocking ads on a mobile device grew&nbsp;<a href="https://pagefair.com/blog/2016/mobile-adblocking-report/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://pagefair.com/blog/2016/mobile-adblocking-report/">102% from 2015 to 2016</a>; by the end of 2016, an estimated 16% of smartphone users globally were&nbsp;<a href="https://pagefair.com/blog/2016/mobile-adblocking-report/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://pagefair.com/blog/2016/mobile-adblocking-report/">blocking ads</a>&nbsp;when browsing the internet on a mobile device. The number was&nbsp;<a href="https://www.emarketer.com/Article/Why-More-than-Quarter-of-US-Internet-Users-Block-Ads/1014333" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://www.emarketer.com/Article/Why-More-than-Quarter-of-US-Internet-Users-Block-Ads/1014333">as high as 25%</a>&nbsp;for desktop and laptop users in the United States, a country that accounted for&nbsp;<a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/266250/regional-distribution-of-googles-revenue/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/266250/regional-distribution-of-googles-revenue/">47% of Google’s revenue</a>.</p>
<p>The people most likely to block ads were also the most valuable demographic:&nbsp;<a href="http://marketingland.com/ad-blocker-usage-highest-among-key-advertiser-demos-millennials-and-high-earners-143546" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://marketingland.com/ad-blocker-usage-highest-among-key-advertiser-demos-millennials-and-high-earners-143546"><em>millennials and high earners</em></a><em>.</em></p>
<p><em><img src="http://www.sfu.ca/olc/sites/default/files/1.4.png" width="533" height="300"><br></em></p>
</div>
<div>
<p><em><sub>Young users are a good indicator for the future of technology, and&nbsp;<a href="http://marketingland.com/ad-blocker-usage-highest-among-key-advertiser-demos-millennials-and-high-earners-143546" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://marketingland.com/ad-blocker-usage-highest-among-key-advertiser-demos-millennials-and-high-earners-143546">they were heavy users of ad blocking&nbsp;software</a></sub></em></p>
<p><strong>Internet users had spoken, and they hated ads.</strong></p>
<p>In early 2017, Google announced its plans to build an ad blocker into its popular Google Chrome browser. Google’s ad blocker would only block ads that were deemed unacceptable by the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.thedrum.com/news/2016/09/16/procter-gamble-unilever-google-facebook-and-more-form-coalition-better-ads" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.thedrum.com/news/2016/09/16/procter-gamble-unilever-google-facebook-and-more-form-coalition-better-ads">Coalition For Better Ads</a>, effectively allowing the company to use its dominant web browser to strengthen its already dominant advertising business.</p>
<p>Even after making this desperate and&nbsp;<a href="http://fortune.com/2017/04/20/google-ad-blocker/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://fortune.com/2017/04/20/google-ad-blocker/">legally questionable</a>&nbsp;move, it would quickly become clear to Google that even though ads were getting better, ad blocking numbers would&nbsp;<a href="http://adage.com/article/digital/ad-blocking-increases-consumers-improving/305978/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://adage.com/article/digital/ad-blocking-increases-consumers-improving/305978/">continue to rise</a>. Google had given even more people a small taste of what an ad-free internet experience could look like.&nbsp;<strong>The company discovered that it wasn’t just annoying ads that people didn’t like; it was ads in general.</strong></p>
<p><strong><img src="http://www.sfu.ca/olc/sites/default/files/1.5.png" width="533" height="300"></strong></p>
<p><em><sub>The advertising industry trying to figure out why people hated ads so much</sub></em><strong><br></strong></p>
</div>
<p>A key platform where Google served ads was YouTube, which it bought in 2006 and quickly turned into one of its biggest entities. But even with a&nbsp;<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/youtube-stats_n_2922543.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/youtube-stats_n_2922543.html">sixth of the world</a>&nbsp;visiting this video-sharing behemoth every month, YouTube&nbsp;<a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/viewers-dont-add-up-to-profit-for-youtube-1424897967" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/viewers-dont-add-up-to-profit-for-youtube-1424897967">never became profitable</a>. In an attempt to combat the effect of ad blockers, YouTube launched an ad-free subscription model in late 2015, but the subscription numbers were&nbsp;<a href="http://www.theverge.com/2016/11/2/13498470/youtube-red-subscribers-video-content-music" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.theverge.com/2016/11/2/13498470/youtube-red-subscribers-video-content-music">underwhelming</a>.</p>
<p>YouTube’s already insurmountable problems multiplied in early 2017 as advertisers&nbsp;<a href="http://www.fiercepharma.com/marketing/google-scrambling-for-solutions-after-advertiser-departures-youtube" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.fiercepharma.com/marketing/google-scrambling-for-solutions-after-advertiser-departures-youtube">began to pull out amid ad placement controversies</a>, and huge revenue generators began to&nbsp;<a href="http://www.ibtimes.com/pewdiepie-starts-weekly-twitch-show-uploads-youtube-over-party-video-2523797" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.ibtimes.com/pewdiepie-starts-weekly-twitch-show-uploads-youtube-over-party-video-2523797">leave the site</a>. Even those who weren’t blocking ads had trained themselves to ignore them entirely. Researchers dubbed this phenomenon “<a href="http://www.tobiipro.com/fields-of-use/marketing-consumer-research/advertising/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.tobiipro.com/fields-of-use/marketing-consumer-research/advertising/">banner blindness</a>”. The average banner ad was clicked on by a dismal&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thinkwithgoogle.com/intl/en-gb/planning-tool/display-benchmarks/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://www.thinkwithgoogle.com/intl/en-gb/planning-tool/display-benchmarks/">0.06% of viewers</a>, and of those clicks, roughly&nbsp;<a href="http://www.goldspotmedia.com/fat-finger-report/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.goldspotmedia.com/fat-finger-report/">50% were accidental</a>.</p>
<p>Research showed that&nbsp;<a href="http://www.bannersnack.com/blog/build-trust-display-ads/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.bannersnack.com/blog/build-trust-display-ads/">54% of users</a>&nbsp;reported a lack of trust as their reason for not clicking banner ads and 33% found them completely&nbsp;<a href="http://downloads.pagefair.com/reports/adblocking_goes_mainstream_2014_report.pdf" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://downloads.pagefair.com/reports/adblocking_goes_mainstream_2014_report.pdf">intolerable</a>. These figures painted a pretty grim picture for the sustainability of online advertising, but especially for Google’s position within the industry.</p>
<p><em>Google’s mighty engine had started to sputter.</em></p>
<p><strong>A chance to pivot, and how Google missed&nbsp;it</strong></p>
<p>If losing a major portion of their audience and annoying the rest wasn’t bad enough, Google also failed to get ahead of one of the biggest shifts in technology’s history. They recognized the importance of artificial intelligence but their approach missed the mark. Since Google’s search pillar had become unstable, a lot was riding on the company’s strategy for artificial intelligence.</p>
<p><em>“We will move from mobile first to an AI first&nbsp;world.”</em></p>
<p>Google’s then-CEO Sundar Pichai&nbsp;<a href="https://blog.google/topics/inside-google/this-years-founders-letter/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://blog.google/topics/inside-google/this-years-founders-letter/">famously predicted</a>&nbsp;in 2016 that “<em>the next big step will be for the very concept of the ‘device’ to fade away”&nbsp;</em>and that<em>&nbsp;“over time, the computer itself — whatever its form factor — will be an intelligent assistant helping you through your day. We will move from mobile first to an AI first world.”</em></p>
<p>Google’s ability to acknowledge the coming trend and still fail to land in front of it reminded many observers of its catastrophic failures in the booming industries of social media and instant messaging.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.sfu.ca/olc/sites/default/files/1.6.jpeg" width="533" height="296"></p>
<p><em><sub>Sundar Pichai wondering how to monetize a virtual assistant</sub></em></p>
<p><strong>Google vs.&nbsp;Amazon</strong></p>
<p>Meanwhile, in 2014, Amazon released a product called Amazon Echo, a small speaker that could sit in your home and answer questions, perform tasks, and buy things online for you. The Echo was a&nbsp;<a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/amazon-echo-success-could-spell-big-trouble-for-google-2017-1" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.businessinsider.com/amazon-echo-success-could-spell-big-trouble-for-google-2017-1">smash success</a>. Google released its copycat product, Google Home, two years later, but it was already&nbsp;<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/jan/22/home-battleground-amazon-google-voice-technology" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/jan/22/home-battleground-amazon-google-voice-technology">too late to catch up</a>, and had no clear revenue strategy.</p>
<p>Alexa — the assistant that lived inside the Echo — on the other hand, was quickly integrated into several products and services, and its monetization model was clear, viable, and most importantly future-friendly. The Echo made it easy to order products through Amazon, and every time someone used an Echo to purchase something, Amazon made money.</p>
<p>Google extended the reach of their virtual assistant by building it into Android, but doing so still didn’t provide an answer for how the technology would generate enough revenue to sustain Google’s expanding repertoire of expensive innovations.</p>
<p>Google’s ads relied on screens, yet voice interaction subverted screens entirely. Google briefly tried playing audio ads with the Google Home, but consumers were&nbsp;<a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017/03/17/google-home-ads-bad-precedent/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://www.engadget.com/2017/03/17/google-home-ads-bad-precedent/">far from receptive</a>. Investors&nbsp;<a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/google-ceo-sundar-pichai-responds-to-concerns-over-monetizing-voice-search-2017-1" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.businessinsider.com/google-ceo-sundar-pichai-responds-to-concerns-over-monetizing-voice-search-2017-1">started to voice their concerns in 2017</a>, but Sundar Pichai told them not to worry, leaving them to assume that Google would use their age-old strategy and analyze users’ voice searches so that users could be shown more suitable ads on devices with screens.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.sfu.ca/olc/sites/default/files/1.7.jpeg" width="533" height="336"></p>
<p><em><sub>Alexa celebrating its victory over Google</sub></em></p>
<p>Headlines in early 2017&nbsp;<a href="https://www.wired.com/2017/01/ces-alexa-in-everything/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://www.wired.com/2017/01/ces-alexa-in-everything/">proclaimed</a>&nbsp;that “Alexa Just Conquered CES. The World is Next.” Amazon then made their technology&nbsp;<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/article/amazon-opens-echo-microphone-tech-to-third-party-alexa-devices/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.zdnet.com/article/amazon-opens-echo-microphone-tech-to-third-party-alexa-devices/">available</a>&nbsp;to third party manufacturers, putting even more distance between the two companies. Amazon&nbsp;<a href="http://www.investors.com/news/technology/amazon-confronts-microsoft-google-ibm-in-cloud-computing-wars/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.investors.com/news/technology/amazon-confronts-microsoft-google-ibm-in-cloud-computing-wars/">had already beaten Google once before</a>, holding 54% of the cloud computing market (compared to Google’s 3%) in 2016, and they were just getting started. By early 2017, Amazon&nbsp;<a href="http://www.cnbc.com/2017/03/31/competing-with-amazon-is-crushing-retailers.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.cnbc.com/2017/03/31/competing-with-amazon-is-crushing-retailers.html">had begun closing in</a>&nbsp;on&nbsp;<a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/groupthink/2017/02/03/amazon-go-is-the-future-plus-4-reasons-why-amazon-might-just-win-retail" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/groupthink/2017/02/03/amazon-go-is-the-future-plus-4-reasons-why-amazon-might-just-win-retail">the entire</a>&nbsp;<a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/retailers-are-going-bankrupt-at-a-staggering-rate-2017-4" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.businessinsider.com/retailers-are-going-bankrupt-at-a-staggering-rate-2017-4">retail industry</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Ads weren’t&nbsp;forever</strong></p>
<p>At its peak, Google had a massive and loyal user-base across a staggering number of products, but advertising revenue was the glue that held everything together. As the numbers waned, Google’s core began to buckle under the weight of its vast empire.</p>
<p>Google was a driving force in the technology industry ever since its disruptive entry in 1998. But in a world where people despised ads, Google’s business model was not innovation-friendly, and they missed several opportunities to pivot, ultimately rendering their numerous grand and ambitious projects unsustainable. Innovation costs money, and Google’s main stream of revenue had started to dry up.</p>
<p>In a few short years, Google had gone from a fun, commonplace verb to a reminder of how quickly a giant can fall.</p>
<h2><img src="http://www.sfu.ca/~sfuolc/OLC/Website/Forall/About-Author-Top.png" width="517" height="16"></h2>
<p><em><img src="http://www.sfu.ca/olc/sites/default/files/1.2.jpg" width="90" height="90"></em><em>Daniel is a Master of Digital Media student, currently completing his internship as a product manager at a Vancouver-based blockchain startup called Covalent. Daniel likes writing code and writing words, and he’s not sure what’s next, but he’s excited about it. You can find out what he’s up to now by checking out&nbsp;</em><em><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/danielcolinjames/">his LinkedIn page</a></em><em>.</em></p>
<hr>
<h2><strong>Beyond the Article</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>Check out how Daniel's article led him to get recommended by Google's VP of Design <a href="https://danielcolinjames.com/how-google-collapsed">here</a></li>
<li>See some of his other work on his <a href="https://danielcolinjames.com/">portfolio site</a></li>
</ul>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.sfu.ca/olc/blog/engage/how-google-will-collapse</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25213493</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 19:51:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Libgen Storage Decentralization on IPFS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 269 | Comments 108 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25209246">thread link</a>) | @jerheinze
<br/>
November 25, 2020 | https://freeread.org/ipfs/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://freeread.org/ipfs/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-md-component="container">
      
        
      
      
        
      
      <main data-md-component="main">
        <div>
          
            
              
            
            
              
            
          
          <div>
            <article>
              
                
                
                  
                
                
                
<p>IPFS is here. IPFS is a de-centralized file and webhosting protocol founded on ideals of freedom and openness. The Library Genesis collection is live on IPFS as of today, accessible via <a href="http://libgen.rs/">libgen.rs</a> and <a href="https://libgen.fun/">libgen.fun</a>. IPFS is like BitTorrent but has a single global swarm, and it's accessible on the web. You can learn about the IPFS project from <a href="https://ipfs.io/">IPFS.io</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/InterPlanetary_File_System">Wikipedia</a>.</p>
<p>IPFS is the next technical revolution in peer-to-peer networking, allowing people like you to share books with readers who request them. IPFS is the next best weapon in the fight against domain take-downs and internet censorship.</p>
<p>We can now each become a founding shelf for a free, global library. Let's start.</p>
<h2 id="get-started">Get started</h2>
<p>IPFS is simple. <em>Hosts</em> (you) <em>Pin</em> files (books) using <em>Content Identifiers</em> (CID Hashes) to share them on the IPFS network. CID Hashes can represent individual files or an entire folder. Pinning saves the files to your local computer so you can share them, and others can Pin them from you.</p>
<p>Each CID Hash for Library Genesis represents 1,000 books, or about 5 gigabytes of local file storage. 100 pins = 100,000 books! Who ever told you that you couldn't start your own library?</p>
<h2 id="copyright-warning">Copyright warning</h2>
<p>Before you begin, make sure you understand <a href="https://www.nolo.com/legal-encyclopedia/what-to-do-if-your-named-bit-torrent-lawsuit.html">the legal implications of hosting and sharing copyrighted material.</a></p>
<h2 id="installing-ipfs">Installing IPFS</h2>
<p>Are you a power-user or run a server? Jump to the section on <a href="#docker-for-servers">getting started with Docker.</a></p>
<p>If you're not, just install the <a href="https://ipfs.io/#install">IPFS Desktop client</a>. Make sure to read the <a href="#system-requirements">desktop system requirements.</a></p>
<h2 id="desktop-client">Desktop client</h2>
<h3 id="system-requirements">System requirements</h3>
<p>Note that IPFS Desktop client is an alpha-stage software still in development. The command line version of the software for servers/home servers is more mature.</p>
<ul>
<li>Requires internet serice provider with unlimited bandwidth. Do not install IPFS if you have a monthly bandwidth or data cap.</li>
<li>Recommended at least 16GB RAM and Intel i5 or equivalent processor</li>
<li>Recommended at least 100 mbps, gigabit connection preferred</li>
<li>Recommended <a href="#port-forwarding">port forwarding</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="get-started_1">Get started</h3>
<h4 id="pin-your-first-cid-hash">Pin your first CID Hash</h4>
<p>Click Files &gt; Import &gt; From IPFS</p>
<p>Then copy and paste in your first CID Hash containing 1,000 books (about 6GB). Once it's complete, jump to the <a href="#cid-hash-index">CID Hash index</a>.</p>
<pre><code>
bafykbzaceaeofefgje22l7rhgtcgs22m32f4ysw5nqa3ty5zawfovqam7pj2c

</code></pre>

<p><img alt="Screenshot" src="https://freeread.org/img/ipfs.2.png"></p>
<h2 id="docker-for-servers">Docker for servers</h2>
<p>Previously downloaded the Library Genesis torrents for the Library Genesis Seeding Project? Follow these steps then jump to <a href="#torrents">torrents</a>.</p>
<h3 id="system-requirements_1">System requirements</h3>
<ul>
<li>Docker (<a href="https://docs.docker.com/get-docker/">docker.com/get-docker</a>)</li>
<li>Requires internet serice provider with unlimited bandwidth. Do not install IPFS if you have a monthly bandwidth or data cap.</li>
<li>Requires between 10GB or more of hard-drive space. For more information refer to the <a href="https://cryptpad.fr/sheet/#/2/sheet/view/I5UinPRnv2LNZlMQcNODieaoo7W9L1KDbJMX36OKvdE/">CID Hash index with file sizes.</a></li>
<li>Recommended at least 16GB RAM and Intel i5 or equivalent processor</li>
<li>Recommended at least 100 mbps, gigabit connection preferred</li>
<li>Recommended <a href="#port-forwarding">port forwarding</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="get-started_2">Get started</h3>
<h4 id="create-your-docker-container">Create your docker container</h4>
<p>You can more documentation for the Go-based IPFS Docker container at <a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/ipfs/go-ipfs/">Docker Hub.</a>.</p>
<p>/export will store your downloaded files, while the books from pinned CID Hashes will be located in /ipfs/data/blocks.</p>
<pre><code>docker run -d \
--name go-ipfs \
-v $HOME/ipfs/export:/export \
-v $HOME/ipfs/data:/data/ipfs \
-p 4001:4001 \
-p 127.0.0.1:8080:8080 \
-p 127.0.0.1:5001:5001 \
ipfs/go-ipfs:latest 
</code></pre>

<pre><code>docker start go-ipfs
</code></pre>

<h4 id="pin-your-first-cid-hash_1">Pin your first CID Hash</h4>
<p>This 'docker exec' command runs your 'go-ipfs' container with container command 'ipfs pin add'. This CID Hash contains 1,000 books, to add it run:</p>
<pre><code>docker exec go-ipfs ipfs pin add bafykbzaceaeofefgje22l7rhgtcgs22m32f4ysw5nqa3ty5zawfovqam7pj2c --progress
</code></pre>

<p>Once it's complete, jump to the <a href="#cid-hash-index">CID Hash index</a>.</p>
<p>You can also access the WebUI and add or manage pins from there. Port 5001 is the API port of the IPFS docker container and contains the same UI as IPFS desktop. You can access the webui in your browser at <a href="http://127.0.0.1:5001/webui">http://127.0.0.1:5001/webui</a>.</p>
<h4 id="cid-hash-index">CID Hash index</h4>
<p>Once you've pinned your first 1,000 you can add the next 100,000 books of the Library Genesis Scitech collection here:</p>


<h4 id="port-forwarding">Port forwarding</h4>
<p>The IPFS swarm peer port is 4001. Opening it up will help you connect, but it is optional if you can't do so. To learn how to port forward port 4001 search your <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=ac1750+port+forwarding"><em>router model + port forward.</em></a></p>
<h2 id="torrents">Torrents</h2>
<p>Many volunteers have helped seed the torrents with the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/DataHoarder/comments/ed9byj/library_genesis_project_update_25_million_books/">Library Genesis Seeding Project</a>.</p>
<p>If you already downloaded the torrents you can add torrent folders to IPFS using <code>ipfs add</code></p>
<p>Start go-ipfs normally with <code>docker start go-ipfs</code></p>
<p>Configure go-ipfs to allow you link folders to the Filestore:</p>
<pre><code>docker exec go-ipfs ipfs config --json Experimental.FilestoreEnabled true
</code></pre>

<p>Restart with <code>docker stop go-ipfs &amp;&amp; docker start go-ipfs</code></p>
<p>Add the folders from where you saved them, starting with folder 1000:</p>
<pre><code>docker exec go-ipfs ipfs add $home/books/1000/ -r -w --nocopy --hash=blake2b-256 &gt;&gt;  $home/books/ipfs-add.log
</code></pre>

<p>Watch the log and check out the network activity:</p>
<pre><code>docker exec go-ipfs tail -f $home/books/ipfs-add.log
docker exec go-ipfs ipfs stats bw --poll=true --interval=1s
</code></pre>
                
              
              
                


              
            </article>
          </div>
        </div>
      </main>
      
        

      
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://freeread.org/ipfs/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25209246</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 13:58:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Remember when you could reboot your computer without rebooting your phone first?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 77 | Comments 56 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25205031">thread link</a>) | @mdoms
<br/>
November 24, 2020 | https://annoying.technology/posts/7b574a72da90e5cd/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://annoying.technology/posts/7b574a72da90e5cd/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/31a8603310fa498ae382fe6140ad8db20c277711/6bc2e/media/neustartdoeswell.png"></p><p>Remember when you could reboot your computer without rebooting your phone first?</p><p>I’m not even kidding: I needed to reboot my Mac because I was unable to navigate character by character using the arrow keys when composing new iMessages in Big Sur, but Finder refused to quit during the reboot with the above error message. It was still syncing my iPhone. (Remember when we thought the iTunes rewrite would be a good thing? <a href="https://twitter.com/manu_faktur/status/1260099839511212032">Good Times</a>!) I tried quite a few things on both devices, but was unable to cancel said sync in any other way than to reboot the phone.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://annoying.technology/posts/7b574a72da90e5cd/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25205031</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 01:30:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
