<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 20]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 20. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 08:41:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-20.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 08:41:06 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Virtual Machine Detection in the Browser (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 111 | Comments 54 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25474183">thread link</a>) | @blindm
<br/>
December 18, 2020 | https://bannedit.github.io/Virtual-Machine-Detection-In-The-Browser.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bannedit.github.io/Virtual-Machine-Detection-In-The-Browser.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <h3>Introduction</h3>
<p>Virtual Machine (VM) detection is nothing new. Malware has been doing it for over a decade now. Over time the techniques have advanced as defenders learned new ways of avoiding VM detection.</p>
<p>A while back a friend and I were working on a project related to exploit delivery via a web application for redteaming purposes. I wanted a way to fingerprint visitors of the site and hash the fingerprint data so I could look for potential repeat visitors. While investigating fingerprinting I stumbled upon something pretty interesting. I was looking at some code that collected information about WebGL capabilities. I quickly realized that some of the fingerprinting information could be useful for VM detection because vendor names were exposed. In this particular instance the string "VMWare" was contained within the WebGL information. After some more testing I also discovered that VirtualBox reported the same kind of information. </p>
<p>Once I realized it was potentially possible to detect VMs from the browser I started to dig deeper and began searching for other research related to this discovery. I found a pretty well researched academic paper <a href="http://yinzhicao.org/TrackingFree/crossbrowsertracking_NDSS17.pdf">[1]</a> related to tracking users across multiple browsers. This gave me some other potential techniques that could be applied to VM detection.</p>
<p>The end goal of this research is to have multiple techniques for VM detection. Multiple techniques lead to much more accurate detection. Since some techniques are more false-positive prone than others, a weighting system can be applied to the detection capabilities. This allows us to generate detection confidence scoring. This can help account for inaccuracies of certain detection methods. Given enough testing and data it would then be possible to come up with a reasonable threshold value. If a browser scores above the threshold then it would most likely be within a VM. Alternatively, if the browser scored below the threshold value it could be considered to be running on physical hardware.</p>
<h3>Techniques</h3>
<p>Now that I have covered some of the background information and history leading up to this blog post we can start to dig into the actual techniques.</p>
<p>As mentioned prior in the introduction, WebGL can provide a lot of information about the OpenGL implementation including vendor information. The WEBGL_debug_renderer_info extension <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/WEBGL_debug_renderer_info">[2]</a> can be used to query for debug information such as the WebGL vendor and rendered.</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>var</span> <span>canvas</span> <span>=</span> <span>document</span><span>.</span><span>createElement</span><span>(</span><span>'canvas'</span><span>);</span>
<span>var</span> <span>gl</span> <span>=</span> <span>canvas</span><span>.</span><span>getContext</span><span>(</span><span>'webgl'</span><span>);</span>

<span>var</span> <span>debugInfo</span> <span>=</span> <span>gl</span><span>.</span><span>getExtension</span><span>(</span><span>'WEBGL_debug_renderer_info'</span><span>);</span>
<span>var</span> <span>vendor</span> <span>=</span> <span>gl</span><span>.</span><span>getParameter</span><span>(</span><span>debugInfo</span><span>.</span><span>UNMASKED_VENDOR_WEBGL</span><span>);</span>
<span>var</span> <span>renderer</span> <span>=</span> <span>gl</span><span>.</span><span>getParameter</span><span>(</span><span>debugInfo</span><span>.</span><span>UNMASKED_RENDERER_WEBGL</span><span>);</span>

<span>console</span><span>.</span><span>log</span><span>(</span><span>vendor</span><span>);</span>
<span>console</span><span>.</span><span>log</span><span>(</span><span>renderer</span><span>);</span>
</pre></div>


<p>Additionally, extension availability can be queried using the <strong><em>getExtension</em></strong> method on a WebGL context. I have not fully explored this avenue but it might be possible to detect certain WebGL implementations provided by VMs based on the extensions available. Though this idea is likely very false-positive prone.</p>
<p>Below is a screenshot from <a href="https://webglreport.com/">[3]</a> WebGLReport a website dedicated to fingerprinting WebGL.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><img alt="alt-text" src="https://bannedit.github.io/resources/VirtualBox-VM-Win10-Chrome.png" title="VirtualBox Windows 10 x64 VM Google Chrome Visiting webglreport.com">
<strong><em>VirtualBox Windows 10 x64 VM Google Chrome Visiting webglreport.com</em></strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Now, it is important to note that this depends on how the VM is configured. In Virtual Box for example, setting the graphics controller setting under Display to VMSVGA will report cause WebGL to use CPU based implementations of OpenGL which is browser dependent. However, this could still be a useful indicator that the client machine is running in a VM because most modern hardware has integrated GPUs and can provide access to OpenGL natively. Just keep in mind that CPU based OpenGL implementations do not necessarily mean it is a VM outright.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><img alt="alt-text" src="https://bannedit.github.io/resources/VirtualBox-VM-Win10-Chrome-VMSVGA.png" title="VirtualBox Windows 10 x64 VM Google Chrome Using VMSVGA">
<strong><em>VirtualBox Windows 10 x64 VM Google Chrome Using VMSVGA Visiting webglreport.com</em></strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>This screenshot depicts Google Chrome utilizing the CPU based OpenGL implementation renderer Google SwiftShader <a href="https://github.com/google/swiftshader">[4]</a>.</p>
<p>Another technique seen in normal malware is to determine the screen width and height. This can be achieved in Javascript as well. Additionally, color depth and bits per pixel are other potentially good indicators related to the display.</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>var</span> <span>width</span> <span>=</span> <span>screen</span><span>.</span><span>width</span><span>;</span>
<span>var</span> <span>height</span> <span>=</span> <span>screen</span><span>.</span><span>height</span><span>;</span>
<span>var</span> <span>color_depth</span> <span>=</span> <span>screen</span><span>.</span><span>colorDepth</span><span>;</span>
<span>var</span> <span>bitspp</span> <span>=</span> <span>screen</span><span>.</span><span>pixelDepth</span><span>;</span>
</pre></div>


<p>More details on the screen object can be found at <a href="https://www.w3schools.com/jsref/obj_screen.asp">[5]</a>.</p>
<p>Can we detect the amount of RAM on the client? You bet. Again using Javascript we can determine roughly the amount of RAM available on the browser. One quirk to note here is that the browser will only report RAM values in gigabytes (gb). It also has a quirk where it will only report up to 8gb and as low as 256mb (0.25gb). These ranges of values however, are still enough to use as a VM detection method. Most physical workstations these days come with at least 8gb of RAM. Detecting smaller amounts of RAM such as 2gb or less would be a good indicator the client browser is in a VM. The specification for the Device Memory can be found at <a href="https://www.w3.org/TR/device-memory/">[6]</a></p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>var</span> <span>ram</span> <span>=</span> <span>navigator</span><span>.</span><span>deviceMemory</span><span>;</span>
</pre></div>


<p>Finally, the last technique I will be covering detects the number of CPU cores. This is done by performing timing attacks using multiple web workers running simultaneously. During my testing of this technique I found it to be very accurate. I tested this concept out using the <a href="https://oswg.oftn.org/projects/core-estimator/demo/">[7]</a> Core Estimator Demo site. A small number of CPU cores can be a decent VM indicator and has been used by malware in the past. Core Estimator also provides the Javascript libraries on github <a href="https://github.com/oftn-oswg/core-estimator">[8]</a>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><img alt="alt-text" src="https://bannedit.github.io/resources/VirtualBox-VM-Win10-Chrome-2-Cores.png" title="VirtualBox Windows 10 x64 VM Chrome With 2 CPU Cores">
<strong><em>VirtualBox Windows 10 x64 VM Google Chrome 2 CPU Cores Tested with Core Estimator</em></strong></p>
</blockquote>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p>This blog post covered four unique VM detection capabilities that can be performed from Javascript. When I first discovered these techniques my initial thought was to apply the concepts toward VM detection. Hopefully, both defenders and offensive security professions can find something useful to apply these techniques toward.</p>
<p>It is interesting to see that academics and various other researchers have applied some of the same concepts toward fingerprinting and privacy issues. </p>
<h3>References</h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p>(Cross-)Browser Fingerprinting via OS and
Hardware Level Features <a href="http://yinzhicao.org/TrackingFree/crossbrowsertracking_NDSS17.pdf">http://yinzhicao.org/TrackingFree/crossbrowsertracking_NDSS17.pdf</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>MDN web-docs WEBGL_debug_renderer_info <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/WEBGL_debug_renderer_info">https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/WEBGL_debug_renderer_info</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>WebGL Report <a href="https://webglreport.com/">https://webglreport.com</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Google Swiftshader Github <a href="https://github.com/google/swiftshader">https://github.com/google/swiftshader</a>  </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>W3 Device Memory Specification <a href="https://www.w3.org/TR/device-memory/">https://www.w3.org/TR/device-memory/</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>W3 Schools - The Screen Object <a href="https://www.w3schools.com/jsref/obj_screen.asp">https://www.w3schools.com/jsref/obj_screen.asp</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Core Estimator Demo <a href="https://oswg.oftn.org/projects/core-estimator/demo/">https://oswg.oftn.org/projects/core-estimator/demo/</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Core Estimator Github <a href="https://github.com/oftn-oswg/core-estimator">https://github.com/oftn-oswg/core-estimator</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bannedit.github.io/Virtual-Machine-Detection-In-The-Browser.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25474183</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 01:39:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[That Dothraki Horde, Part III: Horse Fiddles]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 67 | Comments 38 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25473184">thread link</a>) | @parsecs
<br/>
December 18, 2020 | https://acoup.blog/2020/12/18/collections-that-dothraki-horde-part-iii-horse-fiddles/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://acoup.blog/2020/12/18/collections-that-dothraki-horde-part-iii-horse-fiddles/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>This is the third part of a four part (<a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/12/04/collections-that-dothraki-horde-part-i-barbarian-couture/">I</a>, <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/12/11/collections-that-dothraki-horde-part-ii-subsistence-on-the-hoof/">II</a>, IV) look at the Dothraki from George R.R. Martin’s <em>A Song of Ice and Fire</em> and HBO’s <em>Game of Thrones</em>.  We’re looking at, in particular, the degree to which George R.R. Martin’s claim that the Dothraki are “an amalgam of a number of steppe and plains cultures” holds up in the face of research.  <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/12/11/collections-that-dothraki-horde-part-ii-subsistence-on-the-hoof/">Last week</a>, we looked at the subsistence systems of historical Steppe nomads and Great Plains Native Americans and found that the Dothraki subsistence system was less than a pale imitation of them, having stripped out nearly every activity from the daily routine of survival which wasn’t brutal or violent.</p>



<p>This week, we’re going to keep looking at the elements of culture beyond simple subsistence (with the caveat, noted last time, that subsistence systems often dictate over elements of culture).  Necessarily, this is going to make this post a bit more of an <em>omnium gatherum</em> catch-all, with a bunch of discrete topics.  In each case, it is going to make more sense to introduce the Dothraki practice and then contrast it the practices of the Great Plains and the Eurasian Steppe.</p>



<p>I want to note up front, <strong>we’re going to be talking here about slavery, sex, sexual violence, and regular violence</strong>, both as they occur in <em>ASoIaF</em>/<em>GoT</em> and how they occurred in the real world.  I try to keep this blog mostly G-rated, but history itself wasn’t always G-rated and <em>ASoIaF</em> certainly isn’t; reader discretion is advised.  In the interest of keeping clear which section is which, I have dropped my <em>hilarious</em> ‘An X of Ys’ joke section-title format and instead tried to give very descriptive section titles so you can decide if there is one or two you just want to skip.</p>



<p>Also, I want to note before we start that this post is going to be a bit more book-heavy than show-heavy, just because it is generally easier to pin down things which are explicitly said in the book rather than things implied by the visual language of the show.  <strong>That said, I think the show, if anything, magnifies the characterization the book presents on each of today’s topics</strong>, either dialing them up to 11 or (in the cases where the books have oddly excluded things) making that exclusion more intentional and explicit given the different nature of film (since in a book, if an object is not described in a scene, we may assume it is still there and just undescribed; in a visual medium, if it is not seen, it is not there).</p>



<p>And as always, if you like what you are reading here, please share it; if you really like it, you can support me on <a href="https://www.patreon.com/user?u=20122096">Patreon</a>. And if you want updates whenever a new post appears, you can click below for email updates or follow me on twitter (@BretDevereaux) for updates as to new posts as well as my occasional ancient history, foreign policy or military history musings.</p>






<p>Finally, as a reminder that we are not merely unfairly picking on some fantasy author who just wanted to create fictional societies without any tether to, or comment on, real societies which existed in the past or exist today, <strong>the key statement we are really assessing here is <a href="https://www.westeros.org/Citadel/SSM/Entry/6040/">this one by George R.R. Martin</a>:</strong></p>



<blockquote><p>The Dothraki were actually fashioned as an amalgam of a number of steppe and plains cultures… Mongols and Huns, certainly, but also Alans, Sioux, Cheyenne, and various other Amerindian tribes… seasoned with a dash of pure fantasy.</p></blockquote>



<p>A statement which claims, quite directly, that the Dothraki are modeled primarily off of both Eurasian Steppe nomads and Great Plains Native Americans (with a ‘dash’ of fantasy).</p>



<h2>A Collection of Cultures</h2>



<p>(Ok, I had <em>one</em> more too-cute-by-half section title left)</p>



<p>The first thing to touch on here is not a cultural element but rather a fact about Dothraki culture, which is simply that:<strong> there is <em><span>a</span></em> ‘Dothraki culture.’  </strong>The Dothraki have a single language, a single holy city (Vaes Dothrak), a single system of social organization (Khals, etc), apparently a single set of dietary customs, a single religion with a well-understood prophecy of a future leader, and so on.  <strong>In short, there is a <em>single</em> Dothraki culture</strong> which is shared by all of the various <em>khalasars</em> of the Dothraki Sea.  Crucially this is not merely an observation made by characters <em>outside</em> of the Dothraki culture (that would be understandable – significant cultural divides are often invisible to outsiders who cannot mark the significance of ‘small’ differences), but is also a fact observed by the Dothraki themselves, explicit in things like the collective housing of all windowed <em>khaleesi</em> and even in the language the Dothraki use to talk about each other, especially in contrast to the Lhazareen and other non-Dothraki.  <strong>This is a single culture without any real ethnic divisions and is regarded as such by its members</strong>, not just outsiders.</p>



<p>And that is <em>nonsense</em>.</p>



<p>Even if we only take the Eastern <em>third </em>of the Eurasian Steppe (the Eurasian steppe actually divides quite neatly in thirds, broken up by the Ural mountains (dividing the western and central steppe), and the Fergana Valley (dividing the central and eastern steppe)), we have not <em>just</em> the Mongols, but Tatars, Keraites, Naimans, Merkits, Uyghurs, Kyrgyz, Khitans, and (sort of) Jurchen.  <strong>Those are meaningful differences!</strong>  There are, for instance, two entire distinct language <em>families</em> on the Steppe (I should note that there is some dispute here about the lines between language families, but my impression is that the consensus now is that the Mongolic and Turkic languages are not directly related as they were once believed to be), each containing a number of often non-mutually intelligible languages within them (the Turkic language family has some 35 documented languages).  <strong>These groups were often not only linguistically distinct, but culturally and religiously distinct.</strong></p>



<p><strong>The Great Plains were no less varied!</strong>  Isenberg’s chart (<em>op. cit.</em>, 59) – mentioned last week and based on US Government data – lists Assiniboine, Atsina, Comanche, Blackfeet, Koiwa (and Kiowa-Apache), Crow, Sioux, Cheyenne and Arapaho as the nomadic peoples of the Great Plains (it also lists 11 more sedentary Native peoples).  And that understates the variety because – remember – this is a survey from the <em>outside</em> which is going to miss significant variety (like not breaking out the Lakota from the Dakota, etc.)!</p>



<p>This brings us to two crucial points.  <strong>The <em>first</em> problem is that the lack of cultural and lingustic variety is itself an error on Martin’s part</strong>.  This isn’t quite a unique problem for the Dothraki – <a href="https://acoup.blog/2019/06/12/new-acquisitions-how-it-wasnt-game-of-thrones-and-the-middle-ages-part-iii/">as I’ve noted, particularly with The North, many of the regions of Westeros are a lot less varied than they ought to be given their size</a> – but it is more pronounced here.  <strong>The Dothraki Sea is about as large on the map as <em>all six</em> of the Southern parts of the Seven Kingdoms, but has nowhere near the cultural diversity</strong> despite lacking a unifying government or hegemonic religion (as a rule, large nation-states are the <em>product</em> of state-building, not a prerequisite.  To put it bluntly, France is full of French people because the government in Paris saw fit to make it that way.  There is no such homogenizing institution in the Dothraki Sea).  Again, I don’t expect Martin to bring the story to a screeching halt to discuss this, but think about how much the feeling of a real culture could have been enhanced even a little by having Khal Drogo’s army involve multiple ethnicities of Dothraki nomads, or to have him refer to equivalents of the Merkits or Tartars (we may call these non-existent cultures the Nopethraki) occupying other parts of the Dothraki Sea and possibly trading at Vaes Dothrak.  Something just as simple as meeting other nomads either at the wedding or in Vaes Dothrak who spoke a different language (or given the size of Khal Drogo’s <em>khalasaar</em>, have him brag – as many historical rulers were want to do – about all of the many different Nopethraki peoples who also followed him).</p>



<p><strong>The second problem this creates is for this post</strong>.  While we have one fictional culture to compare, we have to compare it with <em>dozens</em> of real historical peoples – an obviously impossible task in this format (or probably any format).  For the sake of keeping this manageable, I am going to reduce my points of comparison specifically to the Mongols (c. 1150-1250) and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_Sioux_Nation">Sioux </a>(also known as the ‘Seven Council Fires’ though note that this is <em>also</em> a diverse grouping, including the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lakota_language">Lakota</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dakota_language">Western and Eastern Dakota</a>).  Fortunately for me, these two sets are peoples <em>specifically</em> cited by Martin as inspirations for the Dothraki.  Where relevant, I will jump to other groups, but we’ll mostly focus on these two.  <strong>We are going to move topically to see how much the Dothraki are rooted in anything we can identify from these real historical cultures that supposedly inspired them.</strong></p>



<h2>Music and Art</h2>



<p><strong>Try as I might, I could not find any clear reference to Dothraki artwork. </strong> Vests are described repeatedly as painted (AGoT, 83, 193), but apart from the exceptional one made for Viserys (AGoT, 329), how they are painted doesn’t seem to ever be mentioned.  One might fairly call Dothraki hair braiding and belling an art (AGoT, 30), but while the number of braids matters, it doesn’t seem like the quality or artistry is ever commented on.  The statues that line the way to Vaes Dothrak are all captured, the “ancient monuments from all the lands the Dothraki have sacked” (AGoT, 324) and Vaes Dothrak itself lacks its own building style, instead being a mix of styles of peoples the Dothraki have enslaved (AGoT, 326-7).  Drogo’s palace has just “rough-hewn timbered walls” and Daenerys smiles to herself at the contrast between the expected grandeur and the actual building (AGoT, 327), apparently devoid of decoration.  It’s possible that the bride-gift weapons (<em>AGoT</em>, 86) were decorated – the materials in question were clearly lavish – but we are not told.  Later, Daario Naharis has a decorated <em>arakh</em> (in the shape of a naked woman, because <em>of course</em>, <em>ASoS</em>, 482), but he is …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/12/18/collections-that-dothraki-horde-part-iii-horse-fiddles/">https://acoup.blog/2020/12/18/collections-that-dothraki-horde-part-iii-horse-fiddles/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://acoup.blog/2020/12/18/collections-that-dothraki-horde-part-iii-horse-fiddles/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25473184</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 23:04:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Surgery, the Ultimate Placebo]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 182 | Comments 140 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25472970">thread link</a>) | @cpncrunch
<br/>
December 18, 2020 | https://www.skepdoc.info/ian-harris-on-surgery-the-ultimate-placebo/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.skepdoc.info/ian-harris-on-surgery-the-ultimate-placebo/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-6449">

				<!-- .entry-header -->
		<div>
			
<p><strong><em>Ian Harris explains that more than half of commonly performed surgical operations may be placebos. Adequate studies using a blinded control group are essential.</em></strong></p>



<div><figure><img src="https://sciencebasedmedicine.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/surgery-surgeon-ongoing-operate.jpg" alt=""></figure></div>



<p><br>Ian Harris, a Professor of Orthopaedic Surgery at the University of New South Wales in Sydney, Australia, wrote a book titled&nbsp;Surgery, The Ultimate Placebo. I haven’t read the book, but I watched his excellent&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IzueFu1cq5U">YouTube video lecture</a>&nbsp;on the subject. It is an eye-opening evaluation of commonly performed surgical operations that have been tested and shown to be no more effective (and arguably worse) than placebo, or that have never even been tested. He covers the history of sham surgery studies, talks about placebo effects, and explains why so many surgeons ignore the evidence and continue to do ineffective operations. In the process, he provides a valuable education in critical thinking.</p>



<p>His introduction to skepticism at age 18 was a documentary on television where dowsers were subjected to an elegant controlled test by James Randi and Dick Smith. They buried ten pipes and challenged dowsers to determine which pipe the water was flowing through. When they knew which pipe was active, the dowsers all identified it correctly; but when they didn’t know, they were only right 12% of the time. He was impressed by how a simple test could easily refute a claim.</p>



<p>When he watched the same documentary again recently, he was impressed by the reaction of dowsers when shown that dowsing didn’t work. He recognized it as the same reaction he was seeing in surgeons when their operations were tested and shown not to work. They made up excuses, hypotheses about why the experiment might not have given the results they expected, and said they wouldn’t give up doing the operation, “because it works”.</p>



<p>In the early 20<sup>th</sup>&nbsp;century, a common operation for heart disease was internal mammary artery ligation. It seemed obvious that it worked: patients felt better. In 1939, a sham surgery experiment showed that an equal number of patients got better if the surgeon just made an incision but didn’t ligate the arteries. Surgeons heeded the evidence and stopped doing that operation.</p>



<p>He takes us on a historical tour of surgical operations that have been tested and shown not to work. Surgeons often reject the evidence and make up rationalizations as to why it might not have worked in those studies, but they remain convinced that it does work&nbsp;<em>in their hands</em>. When they refuse to stop doing that operation, their excuses sound just like those of the dowsers. They insist on continuing to do the operation “because it works” (in their experience). Billions of dollars are being wasted on hundreds of thousands of operations that have been shown not to work or that have never even been tested to see if they work better than doing nothing.</p>



<h2>False analogies and faulty reasoning</h2>



<p>Theory often says an operation&nbsp;<em>should</em>&nbsp;work, but&nbsp;<strong>biological plausibility means absolutely nothing</strong>&nbsp;unless tests can show that it&nbsp;<em>really does work</em>. Dr. Harris says “You can make up a biologically plausible mechanism for&nbsp;<em>anything you want</em>.”</p>



<p><strong>The parachute analogy</strong>&nbsp;says you don’t need a randomized controlled study of parachutes to find out if they work. Dr. Harris says he has seen it frequently invoked, usually for procedures that are later shown to be rubbish.</p>



<p><strong>Comparative effectiveness studies</strong>&nbsp;are done comparing two different methods of something like steroid injections for back pain, but they don’t tell us whether either of them work. They would be better called comparative ineffectiveness studies. The first step should have been to use a control group and compare steroid injections to no injections.</p>



<h2>Perceived effectiveness</h2>



<p>Perceived effectiveness is a combination of two things: the treatment’s specific effects plus its placebo effects.</p>



<p>There are&nbsp;<strong>shortcuts in thinking</strong>&nbsp;that all humans are hard-wired to take. They assume correlation means causation, and they fall for the&nbsp;<em><a href="https://rationalwiki.org/wiki/Post_hoc,_ergo_propter_hoc">post hoc ergo propter hoc</a></em>&nbsp;fallacy (assuming that if B follows A that must mean that A caused B). These shortcuts in thinking often lead to errors. Improvement might be due to something other than the surgery, like the natural history of the disease, regression to the mean, or concomitant treatments.</p>



<p>Improvement can be perceived by the patient (sometimes it is a false perception due to placebo factors or misinterpretations) and/or by the doctor, due to factors like measurement error, reporting bias, confirmation bias, etc. Doctors rate the effectiveness of their treatments higher than their patients do. The perception of the doctors is&nbsp;<em>wrong</em>; they consistently overestimate the benefits and underestimate the harms of their treatments.</p>



<h2>Treatment is not always needed</h2>



<p>He tells the story of Archie Cochrane, for whom the Cochrane Collaboration of systematic analyses was named. As the only doctor in a POW camp in World War II, he was responsible for 10,000 prisoners, many suffering from open wounds, dysentery, typhoid, and other serious diseases. His requests for doctors and medicines were denied by his German captors, who said doctors were superfluous. In six months, only 4 prisoners died, each of them shot while trying to escape. The rest all got better, without treatment.</p>



<p>Harris’ story&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1444794/?page=1">distorts the truth</a>, but it serves as a vivid illustration of an important fact: recovery often occurs without any treatment. Cochrane’s experience led him to question much of what was being done in the name of medicine. Patients were kept in bed for a week after a heart attack not because of any evidence, but just “because it makes sense”. Cochrane did a controlled study and found that bedrest was actually harming people.</p>



<h2><em>Surgery often acts as a placebo</em></h2>



<p>Harris covers the many factors that affect a patient’s response to a placebo. A systematic review found that placebo was just as effective as surgery in over half of the cases studied, and&nbsp;<em>all</em>&nbsp;of the recent trials comparing surgery to placebo have found that surgery was no better than placebo.</p>



<p>He demolishes all the arguments surgeons give for continuing to do these operations that have been tested and shown not to work. The real reason is that they continue to&nbsp;<em>believe the procedure is effective</em>, just as the dowsers continued to believe they could find water with a forked stick. Tradition and personal experience triumph over science and reason.</p>



<p>Science is just a systematic way to reduce error. Imperfect, but better than any other way. Blinded trials are the least biased way to determine effectiveness.</p>



<h2>Ethical concerns</h2>



<p>Some people object that doing sham surgeries is unethical. Placebos are unethical in clinical practice for treating an individual, but not in research where they are essential to finding the truth and balancing harms and benefits for large groups of people and for preventing future harms. Surely, it’s unethical to perform ineffective surgeries. On Science-Based Medicine, we are constantly questioning the ethics of selling dietary supplements with claims that have never been properly tested. Some herbal medicines might be harmless, but surgery always carries a risk of infection, tissue damage, and adverse effects. And it is expensive: millions of dollars are being wasted worldwide on procedures that expose patients to risk for no possible benefit.</p>



<h2>Conclusion: Evidence is essential</h2>



<p>He concludes by saying we should treat new surgical procedures like new drugs, and only pay for those that are part of a trial to find out if they work. Most surgical procedures being done today have not been subjected to blinded trials.</p>



<p>Advice to patients: it’s OK to ask for a second opinion, and you should always ask your surgeon for the evidence showing the benefits and risks of the procedure, and what you can expect to happen if surgery is not done.</p>



<p><em><strong>This article was originally published in the&nbsp;</strong></em><a href="http://www.sciencebasedmedicine.org/"><strong><em>Science-Based Medicine Blog</em></strong></a><em><strong>.</strong></em></p>
<div id="author-bio-box"><h3></h3><p><img alt="" src="https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/bb0b3c417b7e570a2cb126e704577a6a?s=70&amp;d=mm&amp;r=g" srcset="https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/bb0b3c417b7e570a2cb126e704577a6a?s=140&amp;d=mm&amp;r=g 2x" height="70" width="70" loading="lazy"></p><p>Dr. Hall is a contributing editor to both <em>Skeptic</em> magazine and the <em>Skeptical Inquirer.</em> She is a weekly contributor to the <em>Science-Based Medicine Blog</em> and is one of its editors. She has also contributed  to <em>Quackwatch</em> and to a number of other respected journals and publications. She is the author of <em>Women Aren’t Supposed to Fly: The Memoirs of a Female Flight Surgeon</em> and co-author of the textbook, <em>Consumer Health: A Guide to Intelligent Decisions.</em></p></div>					</div><!-- .entry-content -->

		</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.skepdoc.info/ian-harris-on-surgery-the-ultimate-placebo/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25472970</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 22:41:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I Bought Apple Silicon]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 167 | Comments 231 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25472370">thread link</a>) | @honzajavorek
<br/>
December 18, 2020 | https://honzajavorek.cz/blog/i-bought-apple-silicon/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://honzajavorek.cz/blog/i-bought-apple-silicon/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <div><div><div><div><p>I bought the new M1 Apple Silicon MacBook Air, and this is an article about why I did it, what was my decision process, what are my first impressions, and how I've approached the initial setup. The artcile is just a quick brain dump for the purposes of sharing my experiences with my friends and other readers of my blog, so don't expect any benchmarks or anything like that, this is not a serious review.</p>
<figure><img alt="Apple Silicon" src="https://honzajavorek.cz/images/apple-silicon.jpg"><figcaption>
Photo by me</figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="why-i-bought-new-computer">Why I bought new computer<small><a href="#why-i-bought-new-computer" title="Permanent link to this heading">#</a></small></h2>
<p>My computer's display started slowly dying this year, suffering from gradually more and more serious <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sbR2VhHLuW0">ghosting</a>. By November it was so bad that I could barely read any letters after an hour or two of using the machine. It's MacBook 12" early 2015, which I bought a few years ago, second hand, refurbished.</p>
<p>As far as I know, <em>refurbished</em> should mean that the computer was used as a sample machine somewhere, e.g. in an Apple Store. When they didn't need it anymore, it got checked for defects and sold for a cheaper price as a second hand product in a very good shape. My theory is that the computer was almost unused by the time I've bought it, but perhaps it was open with the display shining all the time in the shop, so durability of the pixels suffered a lot.</p>
<p>Anyway, in addition to that, the machine's performance is a total potato these days. I have always appreciated its portability (size and weight of a magazine) and silence (has no fan), but I've spent most of this year at home, so I didn't care about portability, and the world got more bloated, so the minimum requirements for a smooth user experience are higher than in 2015. So by the summer 2020 I found myself wishing a new machine, and it just happened that Apple was about to release something with the new processors. I decided to wait, because I thought that (at the time) the latest machines would get cheaper if Apple releases something new.</p>
<h2 id="how-i-decided-to-buy-apple-silicon">How I decided to buy Apple Silicon<small><a href="#how-i-decided-to-buy-apple-silicon" title="Permanent link to this heading">#</a></small></h2>
<p>When the first reviews were out, I waited for some more, but then it was just obvious this is a big change, a revolutionary machine, which is going to destroy the consumer market. I've enjoyed the following:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://singhkays.com/blog/apple-silicon-m1-black-magic/">Apple Silicon M1: Black. Magic. Fuckery.</a> - compilation of various first impressions</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/yeah-apples-m1-macbook-pro-is-powerful-but-its-the-battery-life-that-will-blow-you-away/">Yeah, Apple’s M1 MacBook Pro is powerful, but it’s the battery life that will blow you away</a> - general review</li>
<li><a href="https://debugger.medium.com/why-is-apples-m1-chip-so-fast-3262b158cba2">Why Is Apple’s M1 Chip So Fast?</a> - how they made it and why competition won't be able to compete</li>
<li><a href="https://jamesallworth.medium.com/intels-disruption-is-now-complete-d4fa771f0f2c">Intel’s Disruption is Now Complete</a> - how Intel failed the same way it won in the beginning</li>
</ul>
<p>After that, I decided I'll buy the new Apple Silicon M1 MacBook Air, because it doesn't make sense to go for anything older if I plan to have the new computer for as many years as possible going forward. It's not <em>cheap</em> cheap, but it's still huge performance for a reasonable price. Honestly, I'm surprised I happen to be buying a freshly released Mac announced just a few weeks ago, when so far I've been buying only second-hand Apple hardware, but it just felt like it makes sense to do this, all things considered.</p>
<p>I decided I don't need more RAM than 8 GB, because nobody from the first reviewers managed to give the RAM a hard time. It seemed to me it's a different beast altogether and it doesn't make sense to just compare numbers and say that more is better. Apple allows you to buy a computer with more than 8 GB RAM, but I think it's just a trap how to satisfy and charge those who don't believe the reviews and just want more RAM whatever it takes.</p>
<p>I also decided I want 512 GB drive, as I'm used to that size and I didn't want to downgrade. Also, I had serious capacity problems with my 16 GB iPhone SE and my wife still has serious capacity problems with her 128 GB old Air, so I really wanted to avoid that in the future.</p>
<p>I decided I don't mind that Docker or any kind of virtualization isn't supported (yet), because I don't use it. I'm self-employed solo enterpreneur now and Docker or Kubernetes play no role in my dev stack, also I use no virtual machines, nothing like that. If I was about to get a regular job somewhere, I assume they'd provide me a dedicated work computer. Also, I think <a href="https://www.docker.com/blog/download-and-try-the-tech-preview-of-docker-desktop-for-m1/">it's gonna be resolved soon</a>.</p>
<h2 id="first-impressions">First impressions<small><a href="#first-impressions" title="Permanent link to this heading">#</a></small></h2>
<p>The new Air arrived this Tuesday, so as of writing this article, I work on it for 4 days. To be honest, upgrading from a years old machine with a dying display and a potato performance, to this shiny new beast, is… It's unbelievable.</p>
<p>The change in responsivity is really significant and I totally love it. I don't think I've ever used anything faster. With my potato machine I got used to going to bloated websites from my phone, as it felt that iPhone X can deal with them much better, but now the phone feels slow. <a href="https://isapplesiliconready.com/">The optimized apps</a> are super snappy. Safari runs smooth and fast like crazy. Firefox the same. Spotify, Slack, Discord, Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, all the annoying bloated websites, which I used to hate so much for the past months, now run like if they were the most optimized websites on the internet. Honestly, I have problems to grasp the speed by my brain. It's just too much of a difference compared to my previous experience. It's like riding on a sloth and then suddenly switching to a super sonic rocket. I feel like I click on a tab in my browser and it happens instantly, and then it takes billion milliseconds until my brain realizes the action has been already performed and I can proceed to whatever else I wanted to do. I can now actually say when something needs network, because everything else is super fast. Whenever there's the slightiest lag, it's because network is involved, and because my network is slow.</p>
<p>I wanted to go with clean installation, so I didn't do any kind of smart restore from backup or anything like that. Just setting up the new system and moving my files, installing a few programs, like in the old days. Thanks to fast USBs and SSDs on both the computers and my external drive, moving the data was very fast, took just a few minutes.</p>
<p>I didn't upgrade to Catalina with my old laptop, because I wanted to play my 32bit Steam games, so macOS Big Sur is a quite a change for me now. A lot of setting up in the beginning, but all quite straightforward. A few surprises, such as zsh being the default shell in macOS now (change by <code>chsh -s /bin/bash</code>). Finally I can set Finder to sort by name AND have folders at the top, at the same time. For me as a person who switched to macOS from other systems, it has always felt so silly that this wasn't possible.</p>
<h3 id="touchid">TouchID<small><a href="#touchid" title="Permanent link to this heading">#</a></small></h3>
<p>Having TouchID as part of the computer is a nice surprise. As a person who has sweaty hands all the time, I didn't believe it's gonna work. But it's actually able to read my fingers without any problems. The iPhone SE couldn't deal with my fingers. It was a source of a lot of frustrations and one of a few major reasons why I switched to iPhone X in Feb 2020, which has FaceID (only if the pandemics didn't bring face masks right after that).</p>
<p>It's very comfortable to use TouchID to login to the operating system, to 1Password, or to confirm a purchase in App Store (although that had to be first set up somewhere deep in the System Preferences, bah). Opening 1Password with a single finger touch is definitely a major productivity win for me.</p>
<h3 id="battery">Battery<small><a href="#battery" title="Permanent link to this heading">#</a></small></h3>
<p>On Wednesday I tested the battery. 9am I unplugged the computer from electricity with 100% battery, and it started complaning about power only around 10pm. That's 13 hours. That said, during that day, I did mostly internet stuff, perhaps played some music, had 1 hour long call over MS Teams, 1 hour long call over Google Meet, and from 7pm to 10pm I attended an online meetup over Zoom. Before I connected to the meetup at 7pm, it still had almost 30 % battery left. Of course, no fan sound, as the machine has no fan, and it was only lukewarm between the keyboard and the display, cold everywhere else. Amazing!</p>
<h3 id="games">Games<small><a href="#games" title="Permanent link to this heading">#</a></small></h3>
<p>On Black Friday I bought <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/435150/Divinity_Original_Sin_2__Definitive_Edition/">Divinity: Original Sin 2</a>, but it would crash on my machine. On the Apple Silicon Air, even though I run the game through Rosetta 2, I've put all the sliders in the performance settings to the highest positions, and it runs so smooth that when moving the game camera I actually experience problems to get my head around so many details happening on my screen. It's beautiful. Of course, the machine makes no sound, as it has no fan.</p>
<p>There is a <a href="https://applesilicongames.com/">list of games which are optimized</a>, but I just installed Steam using Rosetta 2, downloaded the games I wanted through it, and didn't bother further.</p>
<h2 id="setup">Setup<small><a href="#setup" title="Permanent link to this heading">#</a></small></h2>
<h3 id="homebrew">Homebrew<small><a href="#homebrew" title="Permanent link to this heading">#</a></small></h3>
<p>Setting up and figuring up Homebrew was a major drag, especially because my connection isn't very fast and initializing Homebrew downloads a lot of stuff over git, so it's endless. Before I found out the ideal configuration, I had to do it several times. I don't like Apple Store very much, so I only use it for installing apps which are not available as Homebrew casks, e.g. <a href="https://sindresorhus.com/lungo">Lungo</a>. I install everything else using Homebrew.</p>
<p>Homebrew suggests using it through Rosetta 2 (translation layer), which is fine, but I wanted to be able to also install apps which are already native to Apple Silicon. People post <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nv2ylxro7rM">tutorials on how to have two Homebrew installations side by side</a>, but it still took me some time to figure everyhting out. My setup after some trial and error:</p>
<ul>
<li>Don't bother installing CLI apps natively. <a href="https://github.com/Homebrew/brew/issues/7857">It's a mess now</a> and you'll only run into issues. Unless you want to help the Homebrew team with debugging, of course.</li>
<li>I ended up having the default Homebrew installed through Rosetta 2, and I install everything with it, both CLI and GUI apps,</li>
<li>except GUI <a href="https://isapplesiliconready.com/">apps which are already optimized for the new Macs</a>, such as Firefox, Spotify, VS Code, etc.</li>
</ul>
<p>I follow the common advice on how to install Rosetta 2 Homebrew and how to install the native one. I won't repeat the many already existing tutorials:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nv2ylxro7rM">Install Homebrew Natively on an Apple Silicon M1 Mac</a> (see also comments)</li>
<li><a href="https://soffes.blog/homebrew-on-apple-silicon">Homebrew on Apple Silicon</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/mikelxc/Workarounds-for-ARM-mac">Workarounds for ARM-based Apple-Silicon Mac</a></li>
</ul>
<p>The specifics of my setup are that I have this in my <code>.bash_profile</code>:</p>
<pre><code><span></span><code><span>export</span> <span>PATH</span><span>=</span><span>"/us…</span></code></code></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://honzajavorek.cz/blog/i-bought-apple-silicon/">https://honzajavorek.cz/blog/i-bought-apple-silicon/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://honzajavorek.cz/blog/i-bought-apple-silicon/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25472370</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 21:37:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to kill the university]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 34 | Comments 52 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25471974">thread link</a>) | @caminocorner
<br/>
December 18, 2020 | https://thesephist.com/posts/universities/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thesephist.com/posts/universities/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
        <p>Humans are culture creation machines. We stumble on some idea or thought, share it with other humans, and if the idea sticks and spreads faster than we forget about it, it becomes embedded in the way we do things together in the future. These are your inside jokes, your traditions and your cults. Many such ideas disappear as soon as they come, like fashion trends and popular culture. Some great ones stick around for a while and influence history, like Jazz or the Enlightenment. The few most powerful ones, like religion and democracy, embed themselves into the DNA of civilization, and they become <em>institutions</em>, inseparable from the species that conceived of it in the first place. Institutions are much harder to replace than other kinds of culture, because they go beyond simply being a part of life, and take root as an <em>infrastructural</em> piece of the way we navigate the world. They are fabric, more than threads. These institutions are pieces of culture immortalized. There’s nothing inherently inevitable about them – they are immortalized into humanity by virtue of their staying power in the way we live, and by how effectively they spread themselves amongst our communities.</p>
<p>One important invention of civilization is the university – a place with cultural and economic implications so complex I couldn’t possibly do it justice in one blog post. The university is an invention – there’s nothing fundamentally inevitable about it. The university is also an object of culture – universities play different roles in society and economy and life in different parts of the world, and at different points in history. The university is arbitrary in this way, but it’s also fundamental to the way the world works. The four-year research university has weaved itself deep into the fabric of society, from immigration and visa policies to the way science gets done to the coming-of-age culture in most developed countries. If it’s not an <em>institution</em> of civilization today, it’s rapidly becoming one.</p>
<p>But fundamental as it is, the university is still a human invention, and I still think it can be replaced. We can invent other ideas that compete in the same gene pool of culture and the same market for value, that might out-compete it to become a more dominant way we learn and build careers and find relationships. What would that new idea look like?</p>
<p>What would it take to <em>kill the university</em>?</p>
<p>Many smarter minds that I have tried to tackle this question from a problem of pure economic value proposition. When we study the university as a product – something that students pay to reap benefits of education, network, career development, and personal growth – it makes sense to try to invent ideas that compete in providing those values. So we invented better ways to learn, in the modern trade schools and bootcamps. We are inventing better ways to find a network, in cohort-based education products and professional communities. I think we’re still early in the rise of companies offering many other services in the university “package”, but it’s a matter of time.</p>
<p>No matter how competitive the newcomers to the scene, though, I think approaching the university as a bundled package of value propositions like this is only a part of the innovation. The best feature of the four-year research university isn’t career or education or personal development <em>per se</em>, but the <em>ultimate community</em>: a lifelong identity tied to a physical place, with thousands of other people, harboring hundreds of distinct self-sustaining tribes mired in decades and centuries of tradition and stories and identities. The university survives as a core <em>community infrastructure</em> of society, not just a company offering a product.</p>
<p>To kill the university, someone new must beat them at this game. Someone needs to invent a better way to build and grow this super-community of communities.</p>

<p>Universities are some of the richest, most complex communities I’ve studied, due to their place in most people’s lives. Universities claim four years, nearly full-time, of the most formative and socially instrumental period of most of our lives, and generations overlap each other going back decades, often centuries. This makes it something akin to a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Primordial_soup">primordial soup</a> of communities and identities that will last the lifetime of students. All of the best ingredients for forming lasting, powerful communities are present in university campuses: a physical place, people willing to build new relationships, a shared common goal, sufficient diversity, an influx of new community members every year, and numerous activities for people to do together and build a collective identity. I could hardly imagine a more promising hotbed from which communities can spontaneously arise.</p>
<p>But a good university isn’t just one deep and lasting community. It’s a <strong>super-community</strong>, hosting the births of many more infinitely diverse communities every year interlinked by a higher level common identity of the university campus. This aspect of the university community, the <strong>ability to birth and grow new independent communities over time</strong>, is the best feature of universities.</p>
<p>I’ve written before about how <a href="https://thesephist.com/posts/cellular-communities/">communities can scale by growing a hierarchy of smaller “cells” of sub-communities</a>. Many large communities are structured this way to become sustainable (imagine any regional chapter-based organization, as an easy example). The university, though, is one step above this. Because the kinds of communities created within universities are so culturally and topically diverse, many sub-communities brewed within universities grow to become great communities in their own right, creating impact in the world independently of the larger university community.</p>
<p>Included in this category of sub-communities are labs and academic groups, but also less formal kinds of communities like clubs, and the smaller networks of people that might exist within them. These sub-communities can be centered around any number of topics and purpose, from fraternities to career-oriented student organizations. The best of these sub-communities sustain themselves through generations of members who help each other navigate the life outside of the university, building each other’s careers and providing the community with a sense of direction and purpose. Because universities often claim the prime years of students' lives, these communities tend to have outsized impact to their members compared to other communities they’ll join in the future. The communities you join and build during the university years will carry for years and decades.</p>
<p>Even for those students less involved in communities and clubs in college, university communities end up shaping where they go next for work and life, and often determine the way they make sense of the world politically, philosophically, academically, and financially.</p>
<p>Good universities are factories for such communities. Beyond a career prospect or a well-rounded education or even a personal network, universities nurture these communities and provide them with fresh classes of potential new members every year, in a nearly guaranteed, self-sustaining cycle. No other piece of our culture meets the same challenge at the same scale. In this way, universities are a critical piece of the <em>community infrastructure</em> of the modern world.</p>

<p>Many years ago, at the start of my career, at a panel on entrepreneurship, I asked one of the investors gathered on stage:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Most of the productive innovation ecosystems I’ve encountered are built around universities. Do you think this is inevitable?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>To my surprise, they answered, “yes.” They told me it was obvious that great startup ecosystems only form with universities at the hub of the flywheel of capital and network. I took their answer with reluctance at the time, but asking myself the same question now, it’s startlingly obvious. Universities don’t just produce research and new knowledge. Universities also produce communities and networks of optimistic and ambitious people that fuel entrepreneurial communities. These people, pulled up by their predecessors and their alumni, found new ventures. And when the best of them succeed, they’ll pull the successors in their communities to fill their shoes. And the flywheel keeps turning. Universities are <strong>community engines</strong>, attracting students from around the state or the world and producing networks and communities of people vectored towards similar purpose.</p>
<p>Productive engines as they are, universities are flawed. They’re expensive, inefficient bureaucracies that are often inequitable. I have confidence universities can be disrupted, and new, stronger ideas will take their place in society in due time – the imperfections are too fatal in the long term to brush away. There is no shortage of interesting companies and experimental policies trying to find alternatives to universities as a <em>product</em>. But whatever takes the place of universities will also have to fill the role they currently play to the communities that grow around and beyond it, into the rest of the world. And fortunately to those who manage to reinvent this community engine, with a strong and growing community by your side, building great products become much less risky.</p>
<p>Of the many ways universities tie into the fabric of our modern life, I think the most complex, and the most under-appreciated today, is that universities are astonishingly prolific, self-sustaining community factories. The reinvention of the university is inevitable, but a long road stretches ahead, and the job will not be complete until we build ourselves a better community engine.</p>

        <hr>
        <p>
            
            ←
            <a href="https://thesephist.com/posts/software/"><em>Software, the boundless machine</em></a>
            
        </p>
        <p>
            
            <a href="https://thesephist.com/posts/focus/"><em>How to find focus</em></a>
            →
            
        </p>
        <p>
            I share new posts on my <a href="https://thesephist.com/#newsletter">newsletter.</a>
            If you liked this one, you should consider joining the list.
        </p>
        <p>Have a comment or response? You …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://thesephist.com/posts/universities/">https://thesephist.com/posts/universities/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thesephist.com/posts/universities/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25471974</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 21:02:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Equity guide for employees at fast-growing companies]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 85 | Comments 84 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25469435">thread link</a>) | @zt
<br/>
December 18, 2020 | https://withcompound.com/r/equity-guide-to-fast-growing-companies | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://withcompound.com/r/equity-guide-to-fast-growing-companies">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><section>    <p>
      Conventional wisdom says that startup equity is worthless. While most startups fail, there’s a chance your equity will become a life-changing pot of money. This guide explains how to make the most of your equity. 
    </p>
   
</section></div><h3>Let’s start with an example.</h3><div><section>    <p>
Suppose you join a Series A startup as the fifteenth employee. A few months in, and you’re feeling incredibly optimistic. Customer demand is skyrocketing; you can’t seem to build quickly enough to meet their needs. The startup has added six new employees since you joined and is frantically recruiting more—you’re already a “senior employee!” </p>
   
    <p>
You’ve been offered the opportunity to “early exercise” all of the stock options you’ve been granted. This will cost you $40,000. 
</p>
    <p>
It sounds expensive (and it is!) but say that, two years from now, your company reaches a billion dollar valuation—it’ll then cost you upwards of $400,000 to exercise this same tranche of stock options and cover all of the tax obligations. 
</p>
    <p>
Silicon Valley is full of stories where startup employees miss out on material tax savings, on the order of hundreds of thousands, sometimes millions of dollars, because they ignored their equity compensation until it was too late. This guide helps you strategically maximize your upside as an early startup employee at a fast-growing company.
</p>
   
</section></div></div><div><h3>Deciding to exercise</h3><div><section>


    <p>
      Exercising your stock options represents a high-risk, potentially high-reward investment in your company. At a high level, here are the pros and cons of making such an investment: 
    </p>
    <p>
      <b>Pros</b>    </p>

      
      <p>With the 409A rising, you’re incentivized to exercise 
        <span>sooner rather than later.<label for="sn-srtl"></label></span>
        
        <span>Furthermore, your options do expire eventually, so you can’t put off exercising them indefinitely.</span>
        This will kickstart the long-term capital gains clock and break your 
        <span>golden handcuffs.<label for="sn-goldenh"></label></span>
        
        <span>The term golden handcuffs refers to compensation incentives that discourage you from leaving your company. While your equity may pose a large reward, if you cannot afford to exercise it, you’re monetarily encouraged to stay at your company until at least the IPO.</span>
        </p>

    <p>
      <b>Cons</b>    </p>

      <p>Investing capital into stock directly tied to your single source of income greatly increases your overall concentration in a risky, illiquid asset.</p>
     
      <p><b>To answer the question of whether or not you should exercise, consider the following: </b></p>
      
</section></div><h4>1. Your liquidity constraints<br></h4><div><section>
       <p>Your liquidity constraints will limit the number of options that you are able to exercise. To determine these constraints, audit your personal finances. Consider metrics such as your current liquidity, movable assets, near-term liabilities, and financial goals.</p>
       <p>Cash flow timing plays an important role, as startups often take 5-10 years to exit (if ever). Investing in your startup therefore comes with a significant opportunity cost: you could deploy this same capital into other opportunities (e.g., public stocks or real estate) that could generate steady, dependable returns over the course of those 5-10 years. You’re really looking to come up with a projected, probabilistic return on investment for exercising your stock options (and compare that to your broader financial picture).</p>
 
</section></div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5f89a88f5a23982843f8d21f/5fdbcd37dcbef1bb6073e7ce_illustration-op.png" loading="lazy" width="720" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 92vw, (max-width: 991px) 88vw, 53vw" srcset="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5f89a88f5a23982843f8d21f/5fdbcd37dcbef1bb6073e7ce_illustration-op-p-500.png 500w, https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5f89a88f5a23982843f8d21f/5fdbcd37dcbef1bb6073e7ce_illustration-op-p-800.png 800w, https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5f89a88f5a23982843f8d21f/5fdbcd37dcbef1bb6073e7ce_illustration-op-p-1080.png 1080w, https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5f89a88f5a23982843f8d21f/5fdbcd37dcbef1bb6073e7ce_illustration-op.png 1440w" alt=""></p><h4>2. Your view of the company<br></h4><div><section>
        <p>In deciding how much of stock to purchase, you are essentially quantifying your level of optimism in your company. While you’re unlikely to have access to every line-item on your company’s income statement, you do likely have access to key figures (e.g., revenue trends) to inform your analysis. In the end, you need to form your personal investment thesis—Why will your company win? What will prevent you from succeeding? What’s the best case scenario?</p>
        <p>At the same time, keep in mind that even startups with the most seemingly promising trajectories can stumble. WeWork is an obvious example: in early 2019, it was valued at $47 billion and was filing for an IPO. By the end of the year, its valuation had dropped to $8 billion. Pebble went from a $740 million valuation in 2015 to $40 million by 2016. Juul went from $38 billion in 2018 to $12 billion in 2020. Employees who exercised their options at the higher valuations fell out of the money (and overpaid in taxes).</p>

</section></div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5f89a88f5a23982843f8d21f/5fdbdb1f7ac0d8852e9380a8_illustration-val.png" loading="lazy" width="720" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 92vw, (max-width: 991px) 88vw, 53vw" srcset="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5f89a88f5a23982843f8d21f/5fdbdb1f7ac0d8852e9380a8_illustration-val-p-500.png 500w, https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5f89a88f5a23982843f8d21f/5fdbdb1f7ac0d8852e9380a8_illustration-val-p-800.png 800w, https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5f89a88f5a23982843f8d21f/5fdbdb1f7ac0d8852e9380a8_illustration-val-p-1080.png 1080w, https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5f89a88f5a23982843f8d21f/5fdbdb1f7ac0d8852e9380a8_illustration-val.png 1440w" alt=""></p><h3>Deciding</h3><div><section> 
<p>
     To quantify this decision, let’s explore another example. 
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>
        You have 100,000 options, with a strike price of $1
      </li>
      <li>
        The current 409A valuation is $1.20
      </li>
      <li>
        The 409A in 3 years will be $20
      </li>
      <li>
        In 5 years, your company will IPO, and each share will be worth $100
      </li>
    </ul>

    <p>
      Here are the various strategies you can try: 
    </p>
    <ol type="1">
      
      <li>
       Early exercise everything now
      </li>
      <li>
       Exercise all options in 3 years
      </li>
      <li>
        Wait until the IPO to exercise
      </li>
    </ol>
    <p>
      The table below estimates the hypothetical costs of exercising now, in 3 years, and in 5 years.
    </p>
</section></div><p>You can scroll right on the table above →</p><div><section>    
<p>
Importantly, these projections assume a successful outcome for your company and don’t account for relevant factors such as dilution, timing, and liquidation preferences. Early exercising performs worse than doing nothing in the event your startup fails. Exercising your stock options is making an investment in your company. You are betting on its future performance and if it fails, you will lose your principal investment. Consults your financial and tax advisors to make the right decision.
</p>
   
</section></div><h3>Liquidity</h3><div><section>    <p>
Deciding when to exercise is also a matter of timing. How soon do you need liquidity? It’s often possible to sell some of your equity before your company goes public (or gets acquired).    </p>
   
</section></div><h4>Tender offers<br></h4><div><section>
    <p>
From time to time, your company may hold what’s called a tender offer. In a tender offer, some  cohort of shareholders are given the opportunity to sell their shares for a set price per share. Most companies irregularly hold tender offers (once every couple of years), and generally restrict them to current employees who’ve reached some level of tenure. Deciding whether or not to opt-in the tender offer has trade-offs—every share you sell is potentially worth more (or less) in the future.     </p>
</section></div><h4>Secondary markets<br></h4><div><section>
    <p>
A number of secondary markets make it possible to sell shares to independent investors. There are also funds and brokerages designed to help you get financing to exercise your options. It’s not guaranteed that you’ll be able to participate in either of these vehicles; it depends on factors such as transfer restrictions, timing, and demand from investors.
</p></section></div><h3>Conclusion</h3><div><section>
    <p>
No matter what, early-stage startups are inherently risky. You could end up with a life-changing pot of money in five years, or your equity could end up being worthless. Furthermore, along the way, funding rounds and 409A re-evaluations can occur and change your financial situation at any time without warning. In light of this risk and uncertainty, it’s crucial that you take an active role in managing your equity strategically from the start.</p></section></div><div><p>This material presented on Compound’s Resources blog is for informational purposes only and<br>should not be construed as legal, tax, accounting or investment advice. Under no circumstances<br>should any material on this blog be used for or considered as an offer to sell or a solicitation of<br>any offer to buy an interest in any securities or investment fund.&nbsp; The material on this website<br>does not constitute, and may not be used in connection with, an offer or solicitation by anyone in<br>any jurisdiction in which such offer or solicitation is not permitted by law or in which the person<br>making such offer or solicitation is not qualified to do so or to any person to whom it is unlawful<br>to make such offer or solicitation.&nbsp;<br>‍<br>Any analysis or discussion of financial planning matters, investments, sectors or the market<br>generally are based on current information, including from public sources, that we consider<br>reliable, but we do not represent that any research or the information provided is accurate or<br>complete, and it should not be relied on as such. Our views and opinions expressed on this blog<br>or in any post content are current at the time of publication and are subject to change.</p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://withcompound.com/r/equity-guide-to-fast-growing-companies</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25469435</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 17:23:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Selling a Tiny Project]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 73 | Comments 6 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25467912">thread link</a>) | @tinyprojects
<br/>
December 18, 2020 | https://tinyprojects.dev/posts/selling_a_tiny_project | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://tinyprojects.dev/posts/selling_a_tiny_project">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
	
	
	<nav>
		<a href="https://tinyprojects.dev/">Home</a>
		<a href="https://tinyprojects.dev/projects">Projects</a>
		<a href="https://tinyprojects.dev/guides">Guides</a>
		<a href="https://tinyprojects.dev/blog">Blog</a>
	</nav>
	
	<p><i>December 18th 2020</i></p>

	<p>Building tiny projects in my free time is something that I love to do.</p>

	<p>My main goal is to test out ideas that I note down in my phone. Sometimes they work and I make a bit of money, but usually they don’t. Either way, it's a fun hobby.</p>

	<p>Recently I was lucky enough to sell a tiny website I'd built. Although the sale was small, the experience was great.</p>

	<p>The process of selling a website had always been a mystery to me. Therefore, in this post I'll tell you what it was like to sell a tiny project, and how I think anyone can.</p>

	<h3>🛠️ 1. Building a Project</h3>

	<p>Back in June, I built <a href="https://tinyprojects.dev/projects/one_item_store" target="_blank">One Item Store</a>. It's a micro online store builder that lets you create a page to sell a single item on repeat.</p>

	<p>I hacked it together over two weeks, launched it, and wrote about the process. It was a basic MVP with nothing really fancy about it.</p>
	
	<p>To my surprise, a few hundred users created stores, and I even made a staggering £1.64 in revenue through the 1% cut I took on every sale.</p>

	<p>People were selling t-shirts, hats, poems; you name it. One guy even started a store to sell his soul. I saw some very interesting things.</p>

	<h3>👨‍💼 2. Meeting the Buyer</h3>

	<p>My online following is pretty small, but when I type up a blog post like this, people check out the projects I've built.</p>

	<p>One morning I received this email from such a person:</p>

	<div>
		<p>Hi Tiny Projects,</p>
		<p>.. Anyway, it got me thinking about your One Item Store, and actually, I'm wondering if you have any interest in selling it.</p>
		<p>No pressure, but if you are open to it please let me know and I can make you an offer.</p>
	</div>

	<p>Part of me wanted to keep working on this project, but deep down I knew that I didn't have the drive. Besides, I was really interested to know what the offer was:</p>

	<div>
		<p>Hi Buyer,</p>
		<p>I would definitely be open to offers if you were interested in taking it off my hands, especially as you've been following along Tiny Projects for a while.</p>
	</div>

	<p>A few hours later I got an offer.</p>

	<div>
		<p>Hi Tiny Projects,</p>
		<p>Glad to hear you're open to the idea.  Would you consider <b>$4000</b> for it?</p>
	</div>

	<h3>⚔️ 3. Negotiating a Price</h3>

	<p>Was this a good price for a tiny project? How do you even value something like this?</p>

	<p>After doing some back of the envelope math, I sent back a counter-offer:</p>

	<div>
		<p>Hi Buyer,</p>
		<p>.. With a bit of a polish up and some better store designs, One Item Store could have some potential. However, I'd personally be keen to sell and focus on other things. Would you consider <b>$7,500</b> for it?</p>
	</div>

	<p>We went back and forth with offers over the next few days:</p>

	<div>
		<p><b>Buyer:</b> As for the price, how about <b>$4800</b>?</p>
		<p><b>Me:</b> Would you be willing to meet me at <b>$6,500</b>?</p>
		<p><b>Buyer:</b> The upper limit of my budget for this is <b>$5,000</b>.</p>
		<p><b>Me:</b> If you met me at <b>$5,300</b> (£4,000), you have a deal.</p>
		<p><b>Buyer:</b> Ok, you got a deal at <b>$5,300</b> :D</p>
	</div>

	<p>My price dropped, but I was happy and ready to cash out of the e-commerce world.</p> 

	<p>The buyer was also a talented developer &amp; really nice guy, with a good idea of how he wanted to integrate One Item Store into his <a href="https://initialcommit.com/" target="_blank">own website.</a></p>

	<h3>💸 4. Money For Code</h3>

	<p>How do you securely exchange code for cash?</p>

	<p>Although it would've been hilarious to do this transaction through a store on One Item Store, we decided instead to use an escrow service.</p>

	<p>It worked like this:

	</p><ul>
		<li>Buyer transfers $5,300 to the escrow service.</li>
		<li>I transfer the domain name, users, and Github repository to the buyer.</li>
		<li>Brief video call explaining the code.</li>
		<li>Buyer has 7 days to try everything out.</li>
		<li>Escrow service transfers $5,300 to me.</li>
	</ul>

	<p>That was it, the deal was done.</p>

	<h3>🔮 Conclusions</h3>

	<p>I'm aware that I wouldn't have sold this project if I didn't have a small audience.</p>

	<p>It's made me realise there's this really fun strategy for any developer trying to make money on the internet:</p>

	<ol>
		<li>Build things you enjoy</li>
		<li>Write about the process</li>
		<li>Attract a small audience</li>
		<li>Attract opportunities (buyers, customers, job offers)</li>
	</ol>

	<p>It's that simple. Code something for a few weeks, then type up how it went. Maybe publish it on your own blog like this.</p>

	<p>Five people will probably read it, and that's awesome. Next time it might be ten!</p>

	<p>Keep building lots of little things that pique your interest, talk about it, and great things will start happening.</p>

	
	
	
	
	
	

</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://tinyprojects.dev/posts/selling_a_tiny_project</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25467912</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 15:22:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I prepared for a decade to graduate in CS in three months]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 401 | Comments 357 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25467900">thread link</a>) | @miguelrochefort
<br/>
December 18, 2020 | https://miguelrochefort.com/blog/cs-degree/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://miguelrochefort.com/blog/cs-degree/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="article">
  <header>
  

    
    <p><time datetime="2020-12-18T00:00:00Z">December 18, 2020</time> &nbsp; 
    

    
    </p>
  </header>

  <p><em>This is the story of how I prepared for a decade to graduate in 3 months.</em></p>
<p>In 2012, I dropped out of college, where I was studying computer science, after just one semester. I already knew how to program and I thought I’d never need a degree.</p>
<p>Over the years, I found myself complaining a lot about it. I saw many opportunities, especially abroad, that were out of reach because I didn’t have the required papers. I felt ready for graduate school but couldn’t get admitted. I had to work harder to prove myself to employers. Although I never noticed any serious gap in my knowledge, I felt that something was missing. I started to resent my decision.</p>
<p>In June 2020, I attended a virtual <a href="https://slatestarcodex.com/">Slate Star Codex</a> meetup. As usual, I complained about not having a degree. This is when I first heard about <strong><a href="https://www.wgu.edu/">Western Governors University</a></strong> (WGU). Apparently, their online programs had <a href="https://sive.rs/kimo">no speed limit</a> and students could graduate as quickly as they could pass all the exams. I was skeptical, so I did some research.</p>
<p>Here’s what I found:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>It’s accredited</strong>. Their programs are accredited by the <a href="https://www.nwccu.org/">Northwest Commission on Colleges and Universities (NWCCU)</a>, the same accreditation body used by the University of Washington (#24) and the University of Oregon (#94).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>It’s self-paced</strong>. Their competency-based approach allows students to complete courses as quickly as they can show mastery of the material.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>It’s affordable</strong>. Their flat-rate tuition of $3,200 per 6-month term means that the faster you complete the degree, the more money you save.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>It seemed too good to be true. I immediately submitted my application.</p>
<p>The next day, I received a phone call from an enrollment counselor. They confirmed everything I had read and told me that although they didn’t officially accept foreign students (I’m Canadian), they would try to make an exception. After a dozen phone calls, transfer/translation/evaluation of transcripts, proof of English proficiency, and tuition payments, I was officially enrolled in their <a href="https://www.wgu.edu/online-it-degrees/computer-science.html">Bachelor of Science in Computer Science program</a>.</p>
<p>I now had the opportunity to apply everything I had learned from <a href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/myprojects/mit-challenge-2/">Scott H. Young’s MIT Challenge</a>, in which he completed MIT’s 4-year CS curriculum in just 12 months. Of course, my achievement wouldn’t be as impressive, given WGU’s less rigorous program and my prior experience in the field. Indeed, I wrote my first program at 10, I had years of professional experience as a software developer, and I had even studied the subject in college. Still, I would get a real CS degree in just 3 months.</p>

<p>In this post, I will take you through my entire academic journey, describing when, where, and how I completed each of the 34 courses (120 credits) required for this degree. Note that credits awarded for the first 3 courses (9 credits), taken between 2009 and 2012, were excluded from the quoted 3 months and $5000 total. “How I Got a Computer Science Degree in 11 Years for More Than $5000” didn’t sound right.</p>
<p><em>When consulting the tables below, “CUs” stands for “Competency Units”, which is WGU’s time-agnostic equivalent to “Credit Hours”. “Effort” represents the total amount of time (in hours) invested in a given course, from initial research to final assessment.</em></p>
<h2 id="cégep-édouard-montpetit-2009-2012">Cégep Édouard-Montpetit (2009-2012)</h2>
<p>From 2009 to 2012, I studied IT at Cégep Édouard-Montpetit and graduated with a Diploma of College Studies, which is roughly equivalent to an Associate’s degree in the US. From there, a Bachelor’s degree typically requires an additional 3 years of study.</p>
<p>My biggest gripe with the program, other than mandatory class attendance, was its focus on Microsoft technologies: Visual Studio, C#, <span>ASP.NET</span>, SQL Server, IIS, etc. I was a die-hard Linux user who wrote essays about the evil of proprietary software in high school. Despite my initial resistance, I ended up learning quite a bit. Who knew I would later fall in love with Windows Phone, build a bunch of apps for it (including its first Bitcoin wallet), work as a Xamarin developer, and even spend 3 years porting <a href="https://microsoft.github.io/microsoft-ui-xaml/">WinUI</a> to Android and iOS (<a href="https://platform.uno/">Uno</a>).</p>
<p>Out of 39 courses, I only managed to transfer 2 courses' worth of credits (6 credits) to WGU. They wouldn’t transfer any IT course. They wouldn’t take my calculus course because it was over 5 years old. Unlike a US Associate’s degree, which would satisfy all of WGU’s general education requirements, my foreign degree wouldn’t. Also, the subject and level of some of the courses were lost in translation, after going through a translation agency (French → English) and an international credential evaluation service (Québec → USA). If I had a recent (less than 5 years old) Associate’s degree, I could have expected to receive 10 courses' worth of credits.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Start</th>
<th>Course</th>
<th>CUs</th>
<th>Satisfied by</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>2009</td>
<td>C464: Introduction to Communication</td>
<td>3</td>
<td>English Language and Culture</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2009</td>
<td>C100: Introduction to Humanities</td>
<td>3</td>
<td>Québec Literature</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="concordia-university-2012">Concordia University (2012)</h2>
<p>In 2012, I studied computer science at Concordia University and dropped out after 1 semester.</p>
<p>On my first day, I attended 2 lectures. I quickly realized that a 2-hour commute to listen to someone slowly recite a PowerPoint wasn’t the best use of my time. Lectures might exist for good reasons, but I wasn’t sophisticated enough to appreciate them. Instead, I read the PowerPoints myself, at home, and used Wikipedia to fill in the gaps. I only set foot on campus 3 more times, to take the midterm and final exams. Although I passed all 4 courses, I felt very confused about this whole university thing, where you spend a lot of time learning very little. So, I dropped out and gave up my scholarship.</p>
<p>Out of 4 courses, I only managed to transfer 1 courses' worth of credits (3 credits) to WGU.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Start</th>
<th>Course</th>
<th>CUs</th>
<th>Satisfied by</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>2012</td>
<td>C255: Introduction to Geography</td>
<td>3</td>
<td>Introduction to Political Science</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="spanstudycomspan-2020"><span>Study.com</span> (2020)</h2>
<p>In July 2020, as I was going through WGU’s admission process, I decided to get a head-start by taking some courses online for academic credits. At that point, I was still hoping to graduate in 12 months (2 terms of 6 months). I figured that the more credits I transferred, the more likely I would complete the program in 2 terms. I still had no idea that 1 term would be more than enough.</p>
<p>Thankfully, US students have access to a lot of affordable options when it comes to taking online courses for credits. These are just a few of the many websites that offer courses with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/American_Council_on_Education">ACE</a> credits in the $25-$200 per course range:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://study.com/">Study.com</a> ($199/month + $70/course after 2 included courses)</li>
<li><a href="https://sophia.org/">Sophia Learning</a> ($79/month + $0/course)</li>
<li><a href="https://straighterline.com/">StraighterLine</a> ($99/month + $59/course)</li>
<li><a href="https://saylor.org/">Saylor Academy</a> ($0/month + $25/course)</li>
</ul>
<p>I chose <a href="https://study.com/">Study.com</a> because they had the largest course catalog (180+) and the most comprehensive transfer agreements with WGU. Their College Acceleration Edition plan costs $199/month and includes 2 exams, on top of which you can add up to 3 additional exams per month for $70 each.</p>
<p>Their courses are not the best I’ve taken, but they get the job done. They’re split into bite-size units, each with animated lectures and mandatory quizzes. The number of quizzes can be overwhelming, and I recommend looking elsewhere if you already know the material and just want to take the final exam. Some courses have projects, and most courses have a proctored final exam. Proctoring is done using your computer’s webcam, but the footage is only reviewed 7-10 days later, which can be a problem if you need to transfer credits quickly.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, they limit students to 5 courses per month, which is where I stopped.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Start</th>
<th>Course</th>
<th>CUs</th>
<th>Satisfied by</th>
<th>Effort</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>7/11</td>
<td>C958: Calculus I</td>
<td>3</td>
<td><a href="https://study.com/academy/course/calculus.html">Math 104: Calculus 1</a></td>
<td>62:00</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>7/11</td>
<td>C175: Data Management - Foundations</td>
<td>3</td>
<td><a href="https://study.com/academy/course/computer-science-107-database-fundamentals.html">Computer Science 107: Database Fundamentals</a></td>
<td>10:05</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>7/11</td>
<td>C993: Structured Query Language</td>
<td>3</td>
<td><a href="https://study.com/academy/course/computer-science-204-database-programming.html">Computer Science 204: Database Programming</a></td>
<td>8:15</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>7/11</td>
<td>C170: Data Management - Applications</td>
<td>3</td>
<td><a href="https://study.com/academy/course/computer-science-303-database-management.html">Computer Science 303: Database Programming</a></td>
<td>6:30</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>7/26</td>
<td>C963: American Politics and the US Constitution</td>
<td>3</td>
<td><a href="https://study.com/academy/course/american-government-course.html">Political Science 102: American Government</a></td>
<td>16:30</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="sophia-learning-2020">Sophia Learning (2020)</h2>
<p>On July 29<sup>th</sup>, after reaching <span>Study.com</span>’s monthly 5-course limit, I started looking for alternatives. Luckily, <a href="https://sophia.org/">Sophia Learning</a> had made all their courses free until the end of July due to COVID-19.</p>
<p>The quality of their courses is better than average, and you can even choose from multiple lecturers. Courses are broken down into logical units, each with a set of challenges (quizzes) and a milestone (unit exam). Each course ends with a final milestone which is non-proctored (no webcam) and open-book, making them almost too easy.</p>
<p>I managed to complete 3 courses before the promotion ended.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Start</th>
<th>Course</th>
<th>CUs</th>
<th>Satisfied by</th>
<th>Effort</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>7/29</td>
<td>C176: Business of IT - Project Management</td>
<td>3</td>
<td><a href="https://www.sophia.org/online-courses/project-management-2">Project Management</a></td>
<td>3:45</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>7/30</td>
<td>C165: Integrated Physical Sciences</td>
<td>3</td>
<td><a href="https://www.sophia.org/online-courses/environmental-science-2">Environmental Science</a></td>
<td>3:30</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>7/31</td>
<td>C955: Applied Probability and Statistics</td>
<td>3</td>
<td><a href="https://www.sophia.org/online-courses/introduction-to-statistics-2">Introduction to Statistics</a></td>
<td>13:45</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="western-governors-university-2020">Western Governors University (2020)</h2>
<p>On September 1<sup>st</sup>, I finally started my first and only term at WGU, with 23 courses (83 credits) left to go.</p>
<p>By then, I had already passed 9 pre-assessments (practice exams), which unlike course material were already available before the start of the term. On my first day, I completed 4 courses in the span of 4 hours. At a traditional school, it would have taken 4 months.</p>
<p>It made me realize a few things:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>I had underestimated how much knowledge I had gained from previous schools, jobs, projects, books, papers, and talks.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I was much more productive and motivated without an arbitrary speed limit.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I could probably graduate in a single term of 6 months.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Each student at WGU gets assigned a program mentor, who supports them from their first day through graduation. I had a phone call with mine every week, in which we discussed my progress and planned the week ahead. She quickly adapted to my pace of study and made sure I never got stuck waiting for an answer or for the next set of courses to be approved. I never expected that this human point of contact would have such a positive impact on my experience at WGU. Course …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://miguelrochefort.com/blog/cs-degree/">https://miguelrochefort.com/blog/cs-degree/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://miguelrochefort.com/blog/cs-degree/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25467900</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 15:20:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Starting a blog has never been this difficult]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 25 | Comments 62 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25467864">thread link</a>) | @rukshn
<br/>
December 18, 2020 | https://ruky.me/2020/12/18/starting-a-blog-has-never-been-this-difficult/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ruky.me/2020/12/18/starting-a-blog-has-never-been-this-difficult/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-50">

<div>
<p>I feel blogging is making a comeback, why? Because people are starting to realize that they can carve their own brand and be content creators, rather than just sharing your thoughts among few Facebook friends.</p>
<p>And since not all of us are video creators, most people will be selecting blogging as their platform of choice.</p>
<p>I even started my own blog, this one, shifting from Medium, and I hope to have a new year resolution where I will post at least one blog post a week.</p>
<p>However, even if I feel blogging is about to have a come back, a place for bloggers to blog is limited more than ever.</p>
<h2>WordPress</h2>
<p>WordPress is currently the most popular blogging platform that you can self host or use their own free hosting solution.</p>
<p>WordPress is regularly updated, and the eco system is great, however there is limited number of quality themes that is free and focused on bloggers.</p>
<p>Even WordPress’s own free themes are more focused on business, photographers, restaurants etc.</p>
<p>I feel WordPress is more focused on running a CMS company, and blogging is a side niche that users can use their CMS to build a blog.</p>
<h2>Medium</h2>
<p>Medium was a great choice when it was initially released. It is still a great place to blog and you can find lot of eye balls on medium looking for your content. And not to mention Medium blogs have a better SEO if you want to please the Google bot.</p>
<p>However, medium has slowly become a walled garden and paywalls. Most of the content they promote on their homepage are from premium users or paywalled content.</p>
<p>Also medium has shifting priorities and directions, for example once issued domain names where you can have your own domain name for you medium blog for free.</p>
<p>Later they made you pay $80, to have a domain name. Now it seems that they have given up the ability to have your domain name, but medium has now started issuing subdomains instead.</p>
<p>This lack of direction makes it very unpredictable for a regular blogger, because you don’t know what will happen to your blog in another 6 months.</p>
<h2>Blogger</h2>
<p>Google has not made a meaningful update to its blogging platform for years.</p>
<p>It still has the same outdated editor, and the dashboard that blogger currently use has been there for several years without any update. </p>
<p>The third party theme eco system has been also dried up, and google doesn’t seem be to interested in releasing any new themes for the platform.</p>
<p>I believe if it’s not for the ad revenue they are getting from current blogger websites, they would have given up blogger long time ago.</p>
<h2><strong>Stati</strong>c site <strong>generators</strong> </h2>
<p>Static site generators have been there for several years, there are different static site generators using different technologies, some use markdown while some are using WordPress as a CMS but generate a static site that you can easily host.</p>
<p>However, static sites are extremely difficult for a regular blogger to host. You need to have a knowledge on some technology like ruby or node to setup your generator, and web designing to setup your site/blog.</p>
<p>Then you need to have knowledge on git or web hosting to host your static site.</p>
<p>That is too much for an average blogger, who just want to tell their ideas. It maybe cool to have a static site if you are a programmer or a web developer, but for an average blogger it’s just too much.</p>
<p>When are we going to have a free, modern easy to use platform focused only on blogging and nothing else, like the experience Blogger offered when it was initially released?</p>
<h2><strong>Upcoming</strong> platforms </h2>
<p>There are some several upcoming platforms that caught my eyes, including SubStack and Write.as</p>
<p>I’m bit confused about SubStack because they call the publications as newsletters instead of blogs. And is it going to focus on newsletters like MailChimp in the future? or focus on blogs like Medium?</p>
<p>And how are we going to know whether any of these platforms will follow what medium did to their uses or may lack a clear focus or direction?</p>
<h4>Updates</h4>
<p>I initially had a typo which said <strong>statistic site generator, </strong>which I now corrected to static site generators.</p>
<p>Since I’m typing these posts using my iPad I’m bound to make some mistakes. Even though I try to keep them as low as possible.</p>
<p>Also thank you very much for everyone who commented on HackerNews, I enjoyed reading every single comment.</p>
<p><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25467864">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25467864</a></p>

</div>

</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ruky.me/2020/12/18/starting-a-blog-has-never-been-this-difficult/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25467864</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 15:17:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[AWS Lambda is winning, but first it had to die]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 25 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25467190">thread link</a>) | @forrestbrazeal
<br/>
December 18, 2020 | https://acloudguru.com/blog/engineering/aws-lambda-is-winning-but-first-it-had-to-die | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://acloudguru.com/blog/engineering/aws-lambda-is-winning-but-first-it-had-to-die">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-id="8a920a5" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="theme-post-content.default"><div><p><em>Major feature changes have successfully pushed Lambda workloads into the mainstream, even if FaaS purists feel betrayed</em></p><p>Is serverless winning?</p><p>If you ask AWS, they’ll say <em>definitely</em>. Nearly half of all new applications built inside Amazon this year are <a href="https://siliconangle.com/2020/11/30/exclusive-aws-chief-andy-jassy-wakeup-call-cloud-adoption/">running on Lambda</a>. Andy Jassy took time in his re:Invent keynote to call out the thousands of enterprises who now run Lambda workloads in production, but perhaps most interesting was that this year the new serverless feature announcements graduated to Jassy’s keynote — a spot usually reserved for the flashiest, most strategic reveals of the year. AWS, at least, clearly believes that serverless is now one of the primary selling points for its cloud.</p><p>(On the other hand, there’s <a href="https://thenewstack.io/adoption-of-aws-lambda-serverless-stalls/">this odd article</a>, which spends most of its length demonstrating FaaS growth, but ran under the headline “Serverless Adoption Stalls” because … Kubernetes teams say they aren’t using as much Lambda? In other news, cats report eating fewer vegetables.)</p><p>What’s not in debate is that Lambda, still the 900-pound gorilla of FaaS, looks a lot different today than when it went GA in 2015. The <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/forrestbrazeal/">loud, weird niche of engineers</a> who bought into serverless early have always had <a href="https://twitter.com/PaulDJohnston/status/1336765475615879181">very specific ideas</a> about what good serverless systems look like … and lately, Lambda’s been rattling their assumptions.</p><h2 id="h-the-decline-and-fall-of-the-serverless-manifesto">The Decline and Fall of The Serverless Manifesto</h2><p>Those original ideals of FaaS purity didn’t just materialize out of thin air. As recently as 2016, AWS serverless leadership was talking up something they called the Serverless Compute Manifesto. This was a radical vision for how Functions-as-a-Service should, uh, function. The manifesto showed up at <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yCOgc3MRUrs">all sorts of talks</a>, including <a href="https://twitter.com/Serverlessconf/status/735839492431548418">at ACG’s ServerlessConf</a>. Here are its key tenets:</p><p><em><strong>The Serverless Compute Manifesto (circa 2016)</strong></em></p><ul><li><em>Functions are the unit of deployment and scaling</em></li><li><em>No machines, VMs, or containers visible in the programming model</em></li><li><em>Permanent storage lives elsewhere</em></li><li><em>Scales per request; Users cannot over- or under-provision capacity</em></li><li><em>Never pay for idle (no cold servers/containers or their costs)</em></li><li><em>Implicitly fault-tolerant because functions can run anywhere</em></li></ul><p>This manifesto formed a shocking and highly countercultural blueprint for how to build and deploy software. It attracted a small but vibrant community of true believers and a somewhat larger and much louder set of skeptics.&nbsp;</p><p>But in retrospect, the serverless compute manifesto had trouble penetrating beyond that small, engaged nucleus. The bold vision just left out too many existing, legacy workloads and teams.</p><p>So, gradually, like the commandments in Orwell’s <em>Animal Farm, </em>AWS’s non-negotiables of serverless compute began to change. Let’s run through each point of the manifesto and see if Lambda still adheres to it.</p><p><strong>Functions are the unit of deployment and scaling?</strong></p><p><em>Sorta, but not strictly. </em>You can deploy multi-function Lambda Layers to manage large binaries, or (now in preview) Lambda Extensions to plug in third-party agents that I’ve been told should definitely not be thought of as “sidecars for Lambda”.</p><p><strong>No machines, VMs, or containers visible in the programming model?</strong></p><p><em>No longer true. </em>As of re:Invent 2020, Lambda <a href="https://acloudguru.com/blog/engineering/packaging-aws-lambda-functions-as-container-images">now allows you to bring your own containers</a> instead of just shipping a ZIP file of code.</p><p><strong>Permanent storage lives elsewhere?</strong></p><p><em>Not necessarily. </em>Lambda now integrates with EFS, which I guess is technically “elsewhere”, but no more so than any other NFS share attached to a server is “elsewhere”. It’s a persistent filesystem mounted to your compute.</p><p><strong>Scales per request?</strong></p><p><em>Yes!</em> Now that Lambda can run containers, I believe the request model is now the biggest remaining conceptual difference between Lambda and a managed container service like AWS Fargate. Lambda gives you a new execution environment per concurrent request, whereas a Fargate-like service will still process multiple concurrent requests on the same (long-lived) container.</p><p><strong>Users cannot over- or under-provision capacity?</strong></p><p><em>No longer true. </em>Meet Provisioned Capacity, which trades your cold start problem for a hot cost problem. (I snark, but Provisioned Capacity is way better than running your own Lambda pre-warming job, which a LOT of people used to do.)</p><p><strong>Never pay for idle (no cold servers/containers or their costs)?</strong></p><p><em>No longer true – </em>not if you use Provisioned Capacity or EFS, anyway.</p><p><strong>Implicitly fault-tolerant because functions can run anywhere?</strong></p><p><em>Ehhhh. </em>This one is about abstracting away availability zones, which a lot of higher-level AWS services besides Lambda (including Fargate!) now do. That said, we’re starting to hear more guidance from AWS that really, the fault domain you need to be thinking about is regions. That’s right: regions are the new availability zones, and savvy Lambda developers are rolling their own (very un-managed) multi-region architectures as we speak.&nbsp;</p><p>To reinforce the trend, let’s check in with two other defining early features of Lambda:</p><p><strong>Intentional time and space constraints?</strong></p><p><em>Less and less true</em>. Function disk sizes, runtime limits, and CPU and memory sizes have steadily increased over the last 5 years. Today you can run a Lambda function for 15 minutes with 10 GB of memory and 6 vCPUs – a hefty enough blob of compute to make you think seriously about multi-threading, multi-purpose functions, and other things that are against the old ideals of FaaS.</p><p><strong>Zero-trust networking?</strong></p><p><em>Only if you want it. </em>In the old days, Lambda architectures biased heavily toward IAM security rather than using VPCs, partly for ideological reasons but also because attaching functions to custom ENIs added tremendous cold start overhead. Today, innovation from AWS has made customer-managed VPCs much more compatible with Lambda.</p><p>So what we have now is an updated manifesto that looks like this:</p><p><em><strong>The Serverless Compute Manifesto (circa 2020)</strong></em></p><ul><li><em><s>Functions are the unit of deployment and scaling</s></em></li><li><em><s>No machines, VMs, or containers visible in the programming model</s></em></li><li><em><s>Permanent storage lives elsewhere</s></em></li><li><em>Scales per request; </em><em><s>Users cannot over- or under-provision capacity</s></em></li><li><em><s>Never pay for idle (no cold servers/containers or their costs)</s></em></li><li><em><s>Implicitly fault-tolerant because functions can run anywhere</s></em></li><li><em><s>Intentional time and space constraints</s></em></li><li><em><s>Zero-trust networking</s></em></li></ul><p>I feel like Willy Wonka at the end of the chocolate factory tour, looking around to see where all the children went. Of all those ideological principles, those lines in the sand, <em>per-request scaling is the only thing left.&nbsp;</em></p><p>You can still build according to the original serverless manifesto, of course. But the service doesn’t <em>require </em>you to.</p><p>If you had to distill the revised value prop of Lambda down into a single maxim, <em>Animal Farm-</em>style, what would you even say at this point? “<em>All workloads are managed, but some are more managed than others?</em>“</p><h2 id="h-the-rise-of-serverless-for-everyone">The rise of serverless for everyone</h2><p>This seems like the right time to clarify that I mostly like the additions to Lambda. I think they are necessary and in many cases, an unmixed good.</p><p>I wouldn’t have said that four years ago. I was much more of a FaaS purist at that time. What changed my mind was years of hearing a very particular type of statement from engineering teams, repeated over and over in different variations:</p><p><strong><em>I would love to use Lambda, if only it …</em></strong><em> </em>[connected back to my on-prem VPC, was big enough to run my workload, let me use the same language or developer tooling as my other systems, was always warm, supported some form of shared storage, etc, etc]</p><p>My first reaction to these statements was: Why would you want to use Lambda if you can’t or won’t embrace stateless, containerless, scale-to-zero functions? That’s the whole <em>point </em>of Lambda. It sounded to me like those Kubernetes cats from the New Stack survey, saying they’d really like to eat vegetables if they only contained more meat.</p><p>But I’ve since come to understand that the really powerful part of that statement is the beginning part. It’s a statement of longing.</p><p><em>I’d love to use Lambda, if only …</em></p><p>What is it about Lambda, and serverless compute in general, that inspires this reaction in so many people? Why does a brand-new baby computing paradigm spark such compulsive interest everywhere from tiny startups to big ol’ legacy enterprises?</p><p>Because more than any specific technical detail, serverless computing is an idea. An idea expressed in a simple phrase: <em>Own less, build more. </em>All the serverless doctrine, all the technical guidance boils down to this goal. Lambda is an aspirational lifestyle.</p><p>Lambda, circa 2016, was massively ahead of its time, and to some extent still is. But because of the new feature additions, up to and including container support, it’s making the <em>own less, build more </em>identity more accessible to more builders than ever before.&nbsp;</p><p>What AWS is doing is, one by one, taking away the <em>if only</em>s<em>. </em>They’re removing reflexive objections to serverless by providing reassuring options — shared storage, provisioned capacity — for teams that need them. <em>I’d love to use Lambda!</em></p><h2 id="h-guiding-the-future">Guiding the future</h2><p>Will some teams use these features out of confusion or inertia, not realizing that they could build something more radical, more manifesto-like? Yes, and I think this is an area where AWS can do a lot more to help.</p><p>Look, the Lambda console is a mess – you know it, I know it, AWS knows it. It’s got more tacked-on feature creep and incoherent UX paths than a 2001 VCR. And say what you will about infrastructure-as-code, the console is still how people explore new services. It’s how they form feelings about what kind of builders they want to be.</p><p>A console redesign is needed for sure, but not just an arbitrary facelift. We need one that foregrounds the Lambda features that support the original manifesto: code-level programming abstractions, function-level deployments. And then a careful reveal of progressive complexity as you push up against the limits of the manifesto or your own organizational constraints. (Is there such a thing as “regressive complexity”? Because that’s the current console.)</p><p>What you want is for builders to be confronted with the simpler, more managed options every time they start a new …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://acloudguru.com/blog/engineering/aws-lambda-is-winning-but-first-it-had-to-die">https://acloudguru.com/blog/engineering/aws-lambda-is-winning-but-first-it-had-to-die</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://acloudguru.com/blog/engineering/aws-lambda-is-winning-but-first-it-had-to-die</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25467190</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 14:09:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Curl Supports NASA]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 45 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25466877">thread link</a>) | @est31
<br/>
December 18, 2020 | https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/12/17/curl-supports-nasa/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/12/17/curl-supports-nasa/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Not everyone understands how open source is made. I received the following email from NASA a while ago.</p>



<h2>Subject: Curl Country of Origin and NDAA Compliance</h2>



<blockquote><p>Hello, my name is [deleted] and I am a Supply Chain Risk Management Analyst at NASA. As such, I ensure that all NASA acquisitions of Covered Articles comply with Section 208 of the Further Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2020, Public Law 116-94, enacted December 20, 2019. To do so, the Country of Origin (CoO) information must be obtained from the company that develops, produces, manufactures, or assembles the product(s). To do so, please provide an email response or a formal document (a PDF on company letterhead is preferred, but a simple statement is sufficient) specifically identifying the country, or countries, in which Curl <strong>is developed and maintained</strong></p></blockquote>



<blockquote><p>If the country of origin is outside the United States, please provide any information you may have stating that testing is performed in the United States prior to supplying products to customers. Additionally, if available, please identify all authorized resellers of the product in question.</p></blockquote>



<blockquote><p>Lastly, please confirm that Curl <strong>is not developed by, contain components developed by</strong>, or receive substantial influence from entities prohibited by Section 889 of the 2019 NDAA. These entities include the following companies and any of their subsidiaries or affiliates:</p></blockquote>



<blockquote><p>Hytera Communications Corporation<br>Huawei Technologies Company<br>ZTE Corporation<br>Dahua Technology Company<br>Hangzhou Hikvision Digital Technology Company</p><p>Finally, we have a time frame of 5 days for a response.<br>Thank you,</p></blockquote>



<h2>My answer</h2>



<p>Okay, I first considered going with strong sarcasm in my reply due to the complete lack of understanding, and the implied threat in that last line. What would happen if I wouldn’t respond in time?</p>



<p>Then it struck me that this could be my chance to once and for all get a confirmation if curl is already actually used in space or not. So I went with informative and a friendly tone.</p>



<blockquote><p>Hi [name],</p><p>I will answer to these questions below to the best of my ability, and maybe you can answer something for me?</p></blockquote>



<blockquote><p>curl (https://curl.se) is an open source project that creates two products, curl the command line tool and libcurl the library. I am the founder, lead developer and core maintainer of the project. To this date, I have done about 57% of the 26,000 changes in the source code repository. The remaining 43% have been done by 841 different volunteers and contributors from all over the world. Their names can be extracted from our git repository: https://github.com/curl/curl</p></blockquote>



<blockquote><p>You can also see that I own most, but not all, copyrights in the project.</p></blockquote>



<blockquote><p>I am a citizen of Sweden and I’ve been a citizen of Sweden during the entire time I’ve done all and any work on curl. The remaining 841 co-authors are from all over the world, but primarily from western European countries and the US. You could probably say that we live primarily “on the Internet” and not in any particular country.</p></blockquote>



<blockquote><p>We don’t have resellers. I work for an American company (wolfSSL) where we do curl support for customers world-wide.</p></blockquote>



<blockquote><p>Our testing is done universally and is not bound to any specific country or region. We test our code substantially before release.</p></blockquote>



<blockquote><p>Me knowingly, we do not have any components or code authored by people at any of the mentioned companies.</p></blockquote>



<blockquote><p>So finally my question: can you tell me anything about where or for what you use curl? Is it used in anything in space?</p></blockquote>



<blockquote><p>Regards,<br>Daniel</p></blockquote>



<h2>Used in space?</h2>



<p>Of course my attempt was completely in vain and the answer back was very brief and it just said…</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/NASA_logo.png" alt="" width="399" height="334"></figure></div>



<h5>“We are using curl to support NASA’s mission and vision.”</h5>



<h2>Credits</h2>



<p>Space ship image by <a href="https://pixabay.com/users/eliassch-3372715/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=2057420">Elias Sch.</a> from <a href="https://pixabay.com/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=2057420">Pixabay</a></p>
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/12/17/curl-supports-nasa/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25466877</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 13:34:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Find Focus]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 202 | Comments 37 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25466764">thread link</a>) | @mdeira
<br/>
December 18, 2020 | https://thesephist.com/posts/focus/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thesephist.com/posts/focus/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
        <p>I’ve had an easy time being <em>focused</em> lately. I say no to obligations or opportunities that I would have easily accepted before. I have fewer things on my todo list, which means I get to spend more time on the few things that I’ve said yes to when I sit down to be creative. I also have a stronger sense of my values – what’s important to me, and what’s less important – and that’s helped me leave more room in my schedule for myself. I’ve been thinking about why it’s easier for me to focus now, and what might have changed.</p>
<p>The most significant change in my thinking has been that <strong>I have a lot of conviction now that the few things I’m spending my time on – university, writing, side projects – are right for me.</strong> If a stranger had come up to me last year, told me I was doing it all wrong, and suggested I make different choices in my education or my work, I would have been easily swayed. Today, I feel myself standing on much firmer ground. Because I’m sure that I’m spending my time on the right things, it’s easy for me to say no to things that’ll take that time away from me for something else.</p>
<p>There wasn’t a moment in time when I suddenly decided that I was going to become focused, and started <em>having confidence</em> in what I do. Confidence doesn’t work that way – it’s <em>earned</em>, not <em>found</em>. To earn confidence (and the focus that comes with it), we need to explore our options, try things out, open all the different doors in front of us, and then say, “this is the best option for me, so I’m going to do this.” Only that kind of conviction, coming from true belief and not just blunt willpower, can give you the certainty you need to be focused on the few <em>right</em> things. I suspect this is the reason many students who take gap years or gap semesters return with more confidence and perspective. They’ve explored more of their options, and find themselves more focused.</p>
<p>All this has me convinced that <strong>focus isn’t just stubbornly saying “I’m going to say no to more things,” it’s studying all the options you have until you can say with conviction, “this is the right one for me."</strong> Paradoxically, this means attaining focus requires us to become <em>less focused</em> for a little bit, exploring our options enough to develop some conviction around what’s important or what feels right.</p>
<p>At any moment, we are either in a <em>divergent</em> phase of life, or in a <em>convergent</em> phase. During a divergent period, we’re usually focused on broadening our inputs. We go to school, take on internships, travel, try a career switch, and so on, exploring new paths. During a convergent time, we take what we’ve learned thus far to double down on just a handful of goals on which we can spend our energy – we become more focused. We grow fastest not by converging constantly onto some single point set from the start, but over cycles of divergence and convergence that come and go like seasons.</p>
<p>These cycles of divergence and convergence come from the heart, not from circumstance. You can’t force yourself to become focused by picking an option when you aren’t sure that it’s right. If your choice isn’t based on the confidence you have in that decision, your focus ends up pulled apart by the worry that you’ve missed out on the roads not taken.</p>
<p>Focus is a destination, not a path. And the only way to get there is to earn the confidence to feel that what you’re working on is the right one for you, so you can say no to everything else. And the only way to feel right in what you do is to try your chances with the paths that might be wrong, too. That isn’t wasted effort – it’s what’s required of us to earn our focus.</p>
<p>So if you feel lost or directionless, instead of making yourself pick a direction while lost at sea, consider drifting for a bit. Try things out. Open the unopened doors. Say yes to a few more things. And then when you feel the winds turning, set your sail to what feels right, indisputably and confidently right. It might take more time, and you might feel behind sometimes, but when you finally set off, you won’t need to look back.</p>

        <hr>
        <p>
            
            ←
            <a href="https://thesephist.com/posts/universities/"><em>How to kill the university</em></a>
            
        </p>
        <p>
            
            <a href="https://thesephist.com/posts/momentum/"><em>You don't have to be busy to be prolific</em></a>
            →
            
        </p>
        <p>
            I share new posts on my <a href="https://thesephist.com/#newsletter">newsletter.</a>
            If you liked this one, you should consider joining the list.
        </p>
        <p>Have a comment or response? You can <a href="https://thesephist.com/#get-in-touch">email me.</a></p>
    </article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thesephist.com/posts/focus/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25466764</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 13:20:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why Is There So Much Crap Software in the World]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 35 | Comments 19 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25466763">thread link</a>) | @whack
<br/>
December 18, 2020 | https://software.rajivprab.com/2020/12/18/why-is-there-so-much-crap-software-in-the-world/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://software.rajivprab.com/2020/12/18/why-is-there-so-much-crap-software-in-the-world/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>All around us, we are surrounded by crappy software. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://software.rajivprab.com/2020/04/25/preventing-software-rot/" target="_blank">Pension funds that are stumbling along using decades old batch scripts with faulty assumptions</a>. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2017_Equifax_data_breach" target="_blank">Credit agencies leaking over a hundred million social security numbers and other confidential data</a>. And not to even mention the tons of buggy and frustrating software that we see all around us, from smaller vendors and older enterprise software.</p>



<p>Such incompetence would never fly in other engineering disciplines. We would never put up with bridges that are as buggy as your average software system. So why is software engineering so bad? Why is there so much crap software out there?</p>



<hr>



<p>To understand the reason, we need to first understand how developer skill is related to the usefulness of the software they produce for a given task.</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="376" data-permalink="https://software.rajivprab.com/dev-competency-1/" data-orig-file="https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/dev-competency-1.png" data-orig-size="1075,626" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="dev-competency-1" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/dev-competency-1.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/dev-competency-1.png?w=1024" src="https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/dev-competency-1.png?w=1024" alt="" srcset="https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/dev-competency-1.png?w=1024 1024w, https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/dev-competency-1.png?w=150 150w, https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/dev-competency-1.png?w=300 300w, https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/dev-competency-1.png?w=768 768w, https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/dev-competency-1.png 1075w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"></figure>



<p>In the first bucket, you have the “developers” who are effectively incompetent. You might see a wide range of skill levels within this bucket… but they are all similar in that their end-product is functionally useless. Computers are ruthless in that regard – if you can’t figure out how to make your app compile, you might as well have not written it at all. If you can’t figure out how to build the core functionality of your app, absolutely no one will use it. Below a certain skill threshold, you will not produce any usable software. Most “developers” in this bucket may dabble with coding in their free time, but you will rarely find them producing professional software.</p>



<p>Once you go past this threshold however, things change. At the lower end, the developers are now good enough to produce minimally viable software systems. And as these developers get better and better, the usefulness of their software improves rapidly as well. An app that “worked” but was slow, buggy, insecure, and incomprehensible… slowly starts to become less buggy, more performant, more secure, and easier to understand. Unlike the other two buckets, as the developers in this bucket grow their skills, the software they produce becomes significantly better.</p>



<p>And finally, when developers reach a certain threshold of skill, they cross over into the third bucket. A bucket where everyone has reached such a high level of competency (relative to the problem they are solving), that further personal-growth will make minimal difference to the end product. Ie, any random staff engineer at Google can build a CRUD app that is just as good as Jeff Dean’s.</p>



<hr>



<p><strong>In an ideal world</strong>, the only developers in the first and second buckets would be students or entry-level hires. And all professional software systems would be primarily built by developers in the third bucket. Developers who have mastered all the skills needed to solve the assigned problem, and produce solutions that are pretty darn close to the platonic ideal. In such a heavenly world, all the software that we see around us, would be at a similarly high level of quality … performing exactly as expected, at optimal performance, with no security holes. A world where the general public reacts to all software with joy, not frustration.</p>



<p>However, there are two problems standing between us and this utopia.</p>



<p>First, the number of developers in the 3rd bucket is exceedingly small, relative to the second bucket. Programming is a “easy to learn, hard to master” activity. Millions of people can write a functional script, but very few have mastered the art of software engineering. Further, there is no gatekeeping for the software industry whatsoever – no software equivalent to the American Medical Association, or the Bar Association for lawyers. Not surprisingly, you have far more people who are of novice and intermediate competency, as opposed to expert competency.</p>



<p>Second, the demand for developers is immense. There are opportunities for software developers to make huge improvements, in almost every single industry. Compared to more niche professions such as astronomy, where opportunities are severely limited, software development is a talent-constrained field. Ie, the main bottleneck is finding talented software developers, not finding useful work for them to do.</p>



<p>Combine both of these problems, and most companies that want to hire expert developers are locked out from doing so. There aren’t enough expert developers available for them to hire, and the ones that do often have unmatchably high offers from FANG companies or hot startups.</p>



<p>And so, every other company does the next best thing. They hire developers from the second bucket. Developers who can broadly be categorized as “good enough”. Their apps have bugs, security vulnerabilities, and they fail to handle high loads. But at least they are able to build something that “works”. Something that is more useful than the status-quo. Something that can be rolled out into production with minimal regulatory scrutiny.</p>



<hr>



<p><strong>You might be tempted</strong> to think that the above is a natural state of the world, across all professions. But that is actually not the case.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are tons of jobs that fall into the “easy to master” category. Jobs like being a taxi driver, or a construction worker, or a bartender. Jobs where a large fraction of  workers have reached the master-competency bucket, and there are severely diminishing returns to further improvements in skill.</p>



<p>And there are also tons of professions where opportunities are so limited, that employers can choose to hire only those with expert competency. For example, pianists. Amateur pianists abound in every family gathering, but you will never find them playing in a concert hall, given that the number of talented pianists far outstrips the number of scheduled concerts.</p>



<p>And finally, you have the jobs that are hard to master, with plentiful opportunities, but regulatory barriers to entry. For example, medical doctors. In a pre-Obamacare world, there were plenty of people who couldn’t afford health insurance, who would have chosen “some” healthcare over no healthcare at all <em>(whether or not that is advisable, is a whole other can of worms)</em>. And yet, because of strict regulations, only those showing great competency are allowed to offer medical services. Similarly for many other engineering disciplines that face tremendous regulatory oversight, such as building bridges or skyscrapers or medical devices.</p>



<hr>



<p><strong>Software development is a curious cross-section</strong> of all the above. It is easy to learn, so legions of “good enough” developers exist all around the world. Developers who build software solutions that are somewhat useful, but littered with bugs and security vulnerabilities. And at the same time, it is hard to master, so developers who can avoid the above pitfalls, are much harder to find.</p>



<p>Software development is so opportunity-rich, that most employers find it almost impossible to recruit expert-developers. It is so opportunity-rich, that despite the veritable legions of novice developers worldwide, jobs exist for each and every one of them.</p>



<p>And lastly, software engineering has no gatekeeping whatsoever. Anyone can attend a coding bootcamp, take a few online coding classes, and start selling their services on Upwork the next day. And their work product can be rolled out into production immediately, with no regulatory oversight.</p>



<p>Combine all three, and it is easy to see why there’s so much crappy software out there. Software is eating the world, and so too are its bugs and security holes.</p>



<hr>



<p><em><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25466763" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Discussion on HackerNews</a></em></p>



<p><em><strong>Addendum</strong>: As critical as this article may sound, I am not recommending that we gatekeep the software profession, or subject all software systems to regulatory approval. This is meant to be a descriptive essay, not prescriptive. </em></p>



<p><em>This essay also focuses solely on the developer side of the equation. Managers and CEOs not giving developers enough time to build polished software, and preferring to rush out something that is “good enough”, is certainly another major reason that will be explored in a different essay.</em></p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="385" data-permalink="https://software.rajivprab.com/time-quality/" data-orig-file="https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/time-quality.png" data-orig-size="603,572" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="time-quality" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/time-quality.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/time-quality.png?w=603" src="https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/time-quality.png?w=300" alt="" srcset="https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/time-quality.png?w=300 300w, https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/time-quality.png?w=600 600w, https://softwarerajivprab.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/time-quality.png?w=150 150w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px"></figure></div>
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://software.rajivprab.com/2020/12/18/why-is-there-so-much-crap-software-in-the-world/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25466763</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 13:20:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[When important components become scarce: CPUs, GPUs]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 118 | Comments 89 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25466561">thread link</a>) | @monkeydust
<br/>
December 18, 2020 | https://www.igorslab.de/en/if-important-components-will-become-shortage-cpus-gpus-console-chips-and-other-components-as-complex-handle-object/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.igorslab.de/en/if-important-components-will-become-shortage-cpus-gpus-console-chips-and-other-components-as-complex-handle-object/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<article id="post-155125">
<div>
<div>

<div>
<div>
<div>
<p>2020 was actually a first-class year for technological innovation, but it will probably also go down in history as the year of the ultimate frustration of discouraged consumers, when the target group will end up not being able to buy what has been on their wish list for a long time: graphics cards and processors, power supplies and last but not least the ready-made solution in the form of the current consoles such as a PlayStation 5 or Xbox Series X. Why is such a shortage arising in the first place? The big brands that are ultimately at stake (Sony, Microsoft, NVIDIA, AMD) all talk about “demand exceeding supply”. Oh, really?</p>
<p><a href="https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/CPU.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/CPU-1024x491.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="491" srcset="https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/CPU-1024x491.jpg 1024w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/CPU-300x144.jpg 300w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/CPU-768x368.jpg 768w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/CPU-1536x737.jpg 1536w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/CPU-990x475.jpg 990w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/CPU-1320x633.jpg 1320w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/CPU.jpg 1766w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"></a></p>
<p>It is a rather evasive explanation, without any communication about the actual state of their supply and production lines. Every company, regardless of its size, also employs highly experienced specialists who plan production and procurement for the long term and create a so-called forecast, which is nothing more than a complex foresight that takes all factors into account. It is certainly possible for a company to miss the mark, as the example of AMD and Vega shows, where in the end they forgot to plan the packaging in advance with sufficient resources. But that suddenly everyone is supposed to be equally wrong is then rather unlikely.</p>
<p>Of course, one can go in search of causes and traces, exchange ideas with colleagues, tap and evaluate various own sources and also include the findings of other specialized media, which often have incomparably better access to the makers behind the scenes. The first conclusion that could be drawn fairly quickly is the common statement of almost everyone that the situation is really serious at the moment and will continue at least until spring 2021, because its causes are manifold and more complex than many company representatives would like to communicate publicly. In the end it is a causal chain, where all the imponderables and shortcomings also impressively show the negative side of globalisation.</p>
<h3><span><strong>The explosion of demand exists, but is not the only reason</strong></span></h3>
<p>The explosive growth in demand for various IT products is undeniable. First of all because of teleworking in the home office: printers and laptops are sold well and one of the leading providers of webcams even reported a historic sales record. On the gaming side, 2020 will see the most attractive market launch in a long time, driving new customers and upgraders into the shops in equal measure. Consoles like the PS5 or Xbox Series X, graphics cards like NVIDIA’s GeForce RTX 3000 or AMD’s RX 6000, new CPUs like the Ryzen 5000 series and finally, of course, box office hits like Apple’s M1 are fuelling a hype that is leading to a shortage of supply, as many interested parties would like to take the performance leaps (which have not been seen for several years) with them.</p>
<p>One of the largest suppliers of graphics cards explains that orders for the GeForce RTX 3000 from resellers are much higher than last year. Although the cards go out like hot cakes when they arrive, it is also explained that there are no more availability problems in relation to the number of pieces requested than in previous years. The same is also true for manufacturers of stationary gaming PCs and system integrators, who would have RTX 3000 graphics cards at their disposal, for example, but the demand is indeed greater than estimated and more and more mass retailers are entering this market, skimming off large quantities. As a result, even graphics cards of earlier generations are now affected by lack of availability. At AMD, Ryzen 4000 as a notebook CPU is becoming scarce, as is Ryzen 5000, so many manufacturers are now even switching back to Ryzen 3000. And as for AMD’s new RX-6000 series, AMD itself is talking about a transition period of up to eight weeks before it expects to meet the demand for board partner cards.</p>
<figure id="attachment_155106" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-155106"><a href="https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Transsib.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Transsib-1024x486.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="486" srcset="https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Transsib-1024x486.jpg 1024w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Transsib-300x142.jpg 300w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Transsib-768x365.jpg 768w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Transsib-1536x729.jpg 1536w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Transsib-2048x972.jpg 2048w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Transsib-990x470.jpg 990w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Transsib-1320x626.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-155106">The rolling silk road (Image: Pixabay)</figcaption></figure>
<h3><span><strong>Transport problems as a historical crisis that causes additional damage</strong></span></h3>
<p>Since the beginning of the COVID 19 pandemic, traffic has been out of control and panic has been rampant. But now, at the end of 2020, the situation is even worse than in spring. For example, an industry expert working for one of the leading providers of international transport services describes this unprecedented situation as “the biggest crisis ever” in transport between Asia and the rest of the world. Prices for container transport are also skyrocketing through the United States of America, which is attempting to monopolise most sea and air transport in order to import massive amounts of personal protective equipment (PPE) in addition to conventional goods.</p>
<p>Europe must therefore pay an ever higher price for its share in order to recover the lost transport capacity: the price has risen from around 2,000 to over 6,000 dollars for a single container, and only for pure port-to-port delivery. The same applies to air transport. A Chinese exporter explains that chartering a Boeing 747 today costs a whopping million dollars, compared to about 400,000 dollars as used to be the case. This is simply because you have to pay for the return flight of the plane, which is very likely to be empty, since there is currently a very large imbalance in the import-export market between China and Europe.</p>
<p>Incidentally, the price per kilo for air transport has doubled worldwide and Europe is increasingly resorting to the new Silk Road, which China has pushed very hard: conventional road and rail transport, the prices of which have even tripled in the meantime! Especially bulky peripherals, such as PC screens, are also suffering greatly: according to a well-known brand, prices rose by 15 or 25% in France, for example. According to the information, some computer components, sometimes even graphics cards, are now sent to Europe without their packaging as so-called “bulk goods” in order to save volume: they are packed into cartons on arrival later, if at all. Dead on Arrival? Not to be ruled out, which then causes even more frustration.</p>
<figure id="attachment_155103" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-155103"><a href="https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/DOA-scaled.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/DOA-1024x581.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="581" srcset="https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/DOA-1024x581.jpg 1024w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/DOA-300x170.jpg 300w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/DOA-768x436.jpg 768w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/DOA-1536x872.jpg 1536w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/DOA-2048x1163.jpg 2048w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/DOA-130x73.jpg 130w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/DOA-187x105.jpg 187w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/DOA-990x562.jpg 990w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/DOA-1320x749.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-155103">Delivery from the online retailer without any cardboard box (igor’sLAB Forum)</figcaption></figure>
<p>
But on the transport side, even the deadline for technological products, which are often small, light and of high quality, remains a constant issue. Because the real problem at the moment is the lead time: it takes about 4 to 5 weeks to get transport space at all, which is four times longer than normal. By road and rail, crossing certain borders between China and Europe now takes an average of 10 days, whereas it used to take 3 days. This is pretty bad timing in the middle of the Christmas season and this delay will continue until at least next March according to sources.</p>
<h3><span><strong>Production as a taboo subject with serious consequences</strong></span></h3>
<p>The manufacturing industry is also currently in a historically difficult situation. The manufacturers of various products such as processors, motherboards or graphics cards officially do not appear to be overly concerned about this, but unfortunately the reality often looks completely different, as the entire production chain is, for various reasons, sometimes extremely disrupted (broken chain). First of all, the Taiwanese foundry TSMC is completely overwhelmed by the demand. The reason is actually quite simple: With the exception of the current RTX 3000 (Samsung), all market launches of the year 2020 rely on the 7-nm chips from TSMC. ARM-SoC manufacturers such as Qualcomm also use 7 nm and have only recently moved capacity from Samsung to TSMC. TSMC is currently pretty much alone in the market with this technology and the production lines are therefore working at full capacity. A sudden increase in production is therefore not possible.</p>
<p>A special insulating film, the so-called ABF substrate (Ajinomoto Build-up Film), which is indispensable for etching chips in 7 and 5 nm, has also become increasingly scarce and scarce in recent months. The prices for this film are said to have risen by 40% and the waiting time is said to have increased to up to 4 months. If manufacturers are now declaring that the shortage is likely to continue for a long time to come, it is also because the few suppliers of ABF substrate, such as Unimicron, Kinsus or Na Ya, are declaring that they will not be able to increase their production for another three quarters.</p>
<p>Other components make things even more complicated: The small additional chips (controller, supervisor, etc.) from ST Micro, NXP or Infineon are also missing due to another deficiency: silicon wafers with 8 inch diameter. Many products then suffer from this, such as PC power supplies, but also consoles of the PS5 and Xbox series X and the graphics cards. Flash memory and DRAMs, on the other hand, do not seem to be in real short supply, and the consequences of the COVID-19 pandemic are not as drastic as is often claimed, as the unaffected production capacities are now back to full capacity.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/COVID.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/COVID-1024x572.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="572" srcset="https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/COVID-1024x572.jpg 1024w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/COVID-300x168.jpg 300w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/COVID-768x429.jpg 768w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/COVID-1536x858.jpg 1536w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/COVID-470x264.jpg 470w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/COVID-414x232.jpg 414w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/COVID-215x120.jpg 215w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/COVID-130x73.jpg 130w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/COVID-187x105.jpg 187w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/COVID-990x553.jpg 990w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/COVID-1320x737.jpg 1320w, https://www.igorslab.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/COVID.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"></a></p>
<p>The political situation between China and the USA makes the situation even worse. Many Chinese productions are blocked by American trade restrictions, which makes the logistics of component assembly very difficult. Trade between China and Taiwan, which used to be very fluid and easy, is now becoming increasingly delicate and difficult. If some manufacturers are talking about a better situation in February, it is also because they expect a change of the American president and a relaxation of sanctions.</p>
<h3><span>Shortage? Not for all</span></h3>
<p>Not all manufacturers are equally affected. It seems that NVIDIA and Apple have each secured a large amount of ABF substrate thanks to their market position. Apple is on the 5 nm TSMC lines alone with a small chip (119 mm²), which is easier to produce in large quantities. NVIDIA, for its part, avoids bottlenecks at TSMC by producing in 8 nm at Samsung, whose performance remains competitive despite much larger GPUs (392 and 628 mm²). The two giants are doing quite well in this respect. According to our information, the next GeForce RTX 3060 (Ti) …</p></div></div></div></div></div></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.igorslab.de/en/if-important-components-will-become-shortage-cpus-gpus-console-chips-and-other-components-as-complex-handle-object/">https://www.igorslab.de/en/if-important-components-will-become-shortage-cpus-gpus-console-chips-and-other-components-as-complex-handle-object/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.igorslab.de/en/if-important-components-will-become-shortage-cpus-gpus-console-chips-and-other-components-as-complex-handle-object/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25466561</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 12:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: How to make full colour PCB art]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 74 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25466377">thread link</a>) | @tjclement
<br/>
December 18, 2020 | https://pixel.curious.supplies/blog/pcb_art/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://pixel.curious.supplies/blog/pcb_art/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="page">
  <!-- .site-header -->

  <main id="content">
      <article>
    
    <div>
      <div>
        <p>Post by Tom Clement</p>

<p><img src="https://pixel.curious.supplies/images/pixel_badge_back.png" alt="Full colour art on the Pixel Badge"></p>

<p>Beautiful PCB design has thrived in the past few years. With personal projects and event badges alike, hackers have been pushing the limits of the artistic beauty they can put in their circuit boards.</p>

<p>The community of PCB enthusiasts has experimented with combining colours of silkscreen, copper or ENIG, and solder mask to <a href="https://hackaday.com/2017/03/22/making-more-of-me-money/" target="_blank">make sweet graphics</a>. They’ve convinced PCB houses to <a href="https://hackaday.io/project/18508-mr-robot-badge/log/64526-how-i-created-the-mr-robot-badge" target="_blank">use multiple layers of silkscreen</a>, have <a href="https://hackaday.com/2019/05/30/hackaday-superconference-pushing-the-boundaries-of-pcb-artwork-with-brian-benchoff/" target="_blank">stamped colours of their own</a>, and have even <a href="https://hackaday.com/2020/01/13/the-way-of-the-pcb-artist-how-to-make-truly-beautiful-circuit-boards/" target="_blank">gone multidimensional</a>.</p>

<p>I got hooked on event badges after falling in love with <a href="https://hackaday.com/2017/08/14/hands-on-with-the-shacamp-2017-badge/" target="_blank">SHA2017</a>, and have been involved in making badges for a bunch of events ever since. For every new badge we make, we have some innate drive to push the boundary a bit further to what was already done before, both in hardware and what experience it gives its users, and in the aesthetics of the badge.</p>

<p>So naturally, when people asked for the re-production of the ESP32 WiFi LED panel badge a bunch of us had made for CampZone 2019 <a href="https://hackaday.com/2019/07/25/campzone-2019-badge-is-begging-to-become-a-huge-billboard/" target="_blank">that had inkjet printed dithered single-colour graphics</a>, I started thinking about what’s next. Stumbling upon a <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20464215" target="_blank">hacker news post</a> that showed full-colour UV inkjet printed PCBs by an Australian company called <a href="https://www.littlebird.com.au/" target="_blank">Little Bird</a>, I was amazed. Even though the limitations of PCB design had previously resulted in super creative art, having full-colour graphics in your toolbox could open up so many more possibilities.</p>

<p>The comments section of the hacker news article showed that apparently UV printing had already been done on PCBs over a decade ago, but I hadn’t seen anyone in the badge scene use it before. So I got cracking with our (amazing!) production partner Norbert of <a href="https://shop.allnetchina.cn/" target="_blank">ALLNET China</a>, and together we started experimenting with printing on our PCBs. Boy, were we in for a ride! In the remainder of this post, I’ll try to summarise all of the things we learned along the way.</p>

<hr>

<h2 id="first-attempts">First attempts</h2>
<p>We first started thinking about getting to full colour prints by using the same dithering technique we had used for CampZone 2019, but now with many colours, because I had no idea how normal UV printing worked. Luckily, my friend Hans (aka “the maker maker”, whom I got to know via Ian of <a href="http://dangerousprototypes.com/" target="_blank">Dangerous Prototypes</a>) mentioned that industrial UV printers can print on many materials out of the box, including PCBs.</p>

<p>Indeed, after getting some weird looks from a company that normally makes physical store signs with their UV printers, they were happy to put some of our old unpopulated CampZone 2019 PCBs in their printer and turn them into retrowave heaven:</p>

<p><img src="https://pixel.curious.supplies/images/pcbart/1st_try.jpeg" alt="Full colour art printed over scrap CZ19 badges"></p>

<p>This initial print used standard CMYK UV ink, plus a separate white UV ink for the whites.</p>

<p>The result looked great, but we hit the same problem others before us had hit: putting printed PCBs in a reflow oven messes with the colours a lot. You might remark that it makes more sense to print on the PCBs after they have been pick&amp;placed and soldered. However, the print accuracy of inkjet printers is a function of the distance between the print jet and the object. Our printer could only move 3mm above the PCB (which was not enough for our components), and even if it could move higher the print quality would be quite bad. So instead we worked on getting the UV ink handle reflowing better.</p>

<h2 id="lesson-1-making-white-stay-white">Lesson 1: making white stay white</h2>

<p>After reflowing, the boards looked like this:</p>

<p><img src="https://pixel.curious.supplies/images/pcbart/1st_try_baked.png" alt="UV printed boards with white ink after reflowing"></p>

<p>You’ll notice that all colours become a bit more dim. Red seems to lose more of its edge than green and blue. Most importantly though, the white ink is turned into a nasty aged yellow. Most of the colour changes we could live with, so we didn’t correct for them in our designs (you’ll see later that our final art worked nicely with the reflow process). In general one can try to correct for the changes in their source design, of course.</p>

<p>The whites were totally unacceptable though. It made the badge look old and yucky. We considered diving into the world of different UV inks, and finding a white ink that was more heat tolerant. Then we had a simple realisation: the perfect heat resistant white ink we all know already was simply white soldermask or silkscreen. Because we want to keep the front of the badge black to keep nice contrast, we opted for keeping the mask black and experimented with white silkscreen on the back.</p>

<p>So we modified our art such that the white parts were cut out of the design, which meant no ink would be placed there, and made PCBs that were completely covered with white silk outside of the component pads. The result was awesome, even after reflowing:</p>

<p><img src="https://pixel.curious.supplies/images/pcbart/2nd_try_white.jpg" alt="UV ink on white silkscreen after reflowing"></p>

<h2 id="lesson-2-getting-decent-alignment">Lesson 2: getting decent alignment</h2>

<p>At this point we had PCBs that looked nice, but were in no way usable to solder on: many pads were partially printed over.</p>

<p><img src="https://pixel.curious.supplies/images/pcbart/alignment_pads.jpg" alt="Pads were being partially printed over"></p>

<p>We were printing entire panels at a time, and observed that even when we got perfect alignment on one panel, the next would be wildly out of spec again.</p>

<p><img src="https://pixel.curious.supplies/images/pcbart/alignment_panel.jpg" alt="Printing whole panels at a time"></p>

<p>It turned out that even though the <em>contents</em> of a panel are extremely dimensionally accurate, the <em>edge rails</em> width was not. PCB houses use alignment holes and markers on the edge rails to align their processes, and don’t need to care if there was ~0.2mm extra width on the rails after such a mark or not.</p>

<p><img src="https://pixel.curious.supplies/images/pcbart/alignment_rails.jpg" alt="PCB edge rails are not necessarily uniformly cut"></p>

<p>Aside from this, it is in general hard to get sub-mm accuracy on big industrial UV inkjet printers. For future projects, we will at least try to get better repeatability between panels by making a (very thin) jig that is a bit wider and taller than a panel, that has pins on which we slide the alignment holes of the panel. This allows you to fasten the jig to the printbed, and assure that <em>once you have tediously aligned the jig</em> the future panels will print reasonably well.</p>

<h2 id="lesson-3-more-pin-margin--more-better">Lesson 3: more pin margin == more better</h2>

<p>The alignment issue of the previous section was enlarged because we were stubborn. We felt that having close to no whitespace around pads (0.1mm) would look so much better, so literally any misalignment would immediately cause pads to be partially overprinted. It does look incredible in our opinion, but was the cause for a lot of blood, sweat, and tears. We struggled to get our failure rates below 50% (which is ridiculously high; normally we would want &lt;1%).</p>

<p>This makes the <a href="https://pixel.curious.supplies/" target="_blank">Founder’s Edition</a> extra special, as it is highly likely our last project that will have this insanely tight printing margin!
<img src="https://pixel.curious.supplies/images/pixel_badge_back.png" alt="Full colour art on the Pixel Badge"></p>

<p>For future projects, we will probably use a ~1mm margin around pins to make our life easier. For making this margin less apparent, we’ll likely incorporate the underlying mask or silk colour in the design. That way you’re not looking at chunks of white across the board :)</p>

<h2 id="so-what-now">So what now?</h2>

<p>By sharing what we did, we hope to make you all excited about getting full-colour art on your designs. We’d be super psyched especially to see the <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=badgelife" target="_blank">#badgelife</a> community pick up this neat trick for other event badges.</p>



<p>And, if you’re still looking for something to do this Christmas and like WiFi-enabled LEDs you can program in Python: you can still get one of our <a href="https://pixel.curious.supplies/" target="_blank">Pixel Badges here</a>. Happy holidays!</p>
<iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/490463591" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>



<hr>



<p>Do you want to know more, or would you like our help bringing UV inkjet printing into your project? Feel free to reach out <a href="https://pixel.curious.supplies/docs/community" target="_blank">on our Discord</a> or via info@curious.supplies.</p>

      </div><!-- .post-content -->
    </div><!-- .inner-md -->
  </article><!-- .post -->

  <!-- Next/previous post navigation TBD -->
  <!--
  <div class="inner-md outer">
    <nav class="read-next">
      <h2 class="read-next-title line-left">Read Next</h2>
      <div class="nav-links">
        <article class="post">
          <div class="post-meta">
            <time class="published" datetime="">Previous post date</time>
          </div>
          <h3 class="post-title"><a href="#" rel="bookmark">Previous Post Title</a></h3>
        </article>
        <article class="post">
          <div class="post-meta">
            <time class="published" datetime="">Next post date</time>
          </div>
          <h3 class="post-title"><a href="#" rel="bookmark">Next Post Title</a></h3>
        </article>
      </div>
    </nav>
  </div>
  -->

  </main><!-- .site-content -->
  <!-- .site-footer -->

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://pixel.curious.supplies/blog/pcb_art/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25466377</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 12:20:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Adding Composite Video to a Famicom]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 32 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25463627">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
December 17, 2020 | https://www.leadedsolder.com/2020/12/17/famicom-composite-mod-v1.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.leadedsolder.com/2020/12/17/famicom-composite-mod-v1.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
    <p>Since I’ve been reading <a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/i-am-error"><em>I Am Error</em></a>, I’ve been getting more and more interested in the technical aspects of the Famicom. Turns out all you really need to get me interested in your console is prose explanations of how a pattern table works. Also, I get to drip some molten lead into it so I can use a modern TV! Everyone wins.</p>

<p>When I was growing up, a lot of my friends had an NES, but I first had the ColecoVision and then a “Model 2” Sega Genesis when that came out. As a result, I’ve gone the last few decades thinking the NES was full of branded shovelware, because it turns out that’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MzJ0M-erXAM">the exact kind of game that eight year old boys bought a lot of and then subjected their friends to</a>.</p>

<p>Later, when I was getting interested in collecting old videogames, the NES had already started its stratospheric price rise for many games, and with it the skeeziest members of the game-price-speculator community. None of the cool modern “community” stuff existed then (NESRGB, Everdrives, FDSStick) so I gave the entire system a wide berth and decided to wait until this whole fad was over and prices returned to normal. That hasn’t happened yet… however, in Japan, stuff is still really cheap due to the massive popularity of the Famicom, and the Famicom is different enough from the NES that I’m coming at it without the same preconceptions that I had of those childhood NESes.</p>

<p>Out of the box, the original Famicom only has RF output. If you’re not familiar, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8sQF_K9MqpA">this video by Gravis is the best I’ve seen on how RF output works</a>, and a Nintendo is even used to make it relevant to this post.</p>

<p>Not only does the Famicom only have RF output, the Japanese channel frequencies are such that that RF output only appears on channel 95 and 96 on a Western TV, which a lot of TVs simply can’t reach. On some models, you can <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RVyFEMg0Kpg">tweak the pots on the RF can to bring that down to US channel 6</a> to get around this. However, I wanted to play my games on a Commodore 1702 or a PVM, neither of which have an antenna tuner of any kind. Doing a composite mod seemed like the easiest way forward.</p>

<h2 id="giving-it-a-good-squint">Giving It A Good Squint</h2>
<p>The first thing I noticed is that a Famicom is a <em>lot</em> smaller than an NES. They added a bunch of empty space for the American model in order to accommodate the “toaster” mechanism, I guess.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.leadedsolder.com/assets/famicom-vs-nes.jpg" alt="A Famicom is sitting on top of an American front-loading NES, which is a spoiled Western brat and doesn't like loading cartridges."></p>

<p>I thought I would hate the hard-wired controllers, but they’re actually really nice. You’re guaranteed to always get first-party controllers when you buy a used system, which is more than I can say for basically any other machine, that NES included. It would be nice if they were in better condition, but if they work I’ll be happy.</p>

<p>There’s a “Famicom Family” logo on the front sticker that I haven’t seen on most other Famicoms; from what I can tell, this is a good way to tell what machines are later models as it ties into <a href="https://maru-chang.com/hard/hvc/english.htm">some kind of later branding</a>.</p>

<h2 id="opening-it-up">Opening It Up</h2>
<p>When mine arrived from Japan, it looked dirty and pretty beaten up, but that’s okay for a test machine. I can always get a nicer one later; another thing to hoard.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.leadedsolder.com/assets/famicom-case-damage.jpg" alt="The missing chunk of plastic near the player 1 controller slot."></p>

<p>A corner of the plastic near the player-1 controller mount was missing, and there was grit in the textured plastic. I took a few trips to the sink with the plastic and scrubbed, but the yellowing is obviously not going to come out with soap and water.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.leadedsolder.com/assets/famicom-opened.jpg" alt="The Famicom's bottom cover is opened, revealing the underside of the motherboard."></p>

<p>I opened it up - screws were tight, a good sign - and then took a look at the board. It’s a late model, as evidenced by the big power/RF module soldered to the board instead of attached by a ribbon cable.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.leadedsolder.com/assets/famicom-gross-pot.jpg" alt="There is a green potentiometer with some gunk and tree debris (seeds?) on it."></p>

<p>This console has spent some time in an old shed or something, based on how much of Mother Nature had crept inside of it, but at least I didn’t find any stray cigarettes inside it unlike the above NES. The motherboard cleaned up quickly with some spray alcohol and cotton swabs.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.leadedsolder.com/assets/famicom-1989-copyright.jpg" alt="The copyright reads © 1989 Nintendo"></p>

<p>The board is a 1989, which was a pretty good year for Nintendo. <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2013/07/time-to-feel-old-inside-the-nes-on-its-30th-birthday/3/">The Famicom apparently kept getting made until <em>2003</em></a>. It would be cool to track one of those down.</p>

<p>I wanted to deep-clean the dirty, scratched-up controllers as well - the controllers still had their protective plastic wrap on them, but they were scratched anyway! - and make sure that the silicone on the D-pads were in good shape, but I stripped one of the screws on controller 1 pretty severely in a moment of clumsiness. I’ll drill that out later and service it, but in the meantime let’s get back to the composite mod.</p>

<h2 id="motherboard-work">Motherboard Work</h2>
<p>I got sort of lucky in having a late-model board. On the later boards there’s a dedicated “video” pin that is broken out near the RF jack that I could just solder to, rather than lifting pin 21 (<a href="http://wiki.nesdev.com/w/index.php/PPU_pin_out_and_signal_description"><code>VOUT</code></a>) of the PPU. This way, you can keep both the RF and composite. Reportedly, this creates a bunch of ‘jailbar’ interference, so I’ve done what others have and lifted pin 21 of the PPU. Sometimes the hard way is the best way.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.leadedsolder.com/assets/famicom-pin21-lifted.jpg" alt="Pin 21 lifted out of the PPU. Ignore the Sharpie mark telling me which pin is 21, as if I could have forgotten"></p>

<p>This wasn’t too hard to desolder and lift, but the pin would have looked a lot less mangled if I had also desoldered R6 first to get it out of the way. I had to use a little bit too much force on my “prying tweezers” to lift it out, which could have easily broken the leg on a newer chip where the legs are much more fragile. Thanks, 80s technology!</p>

<p><img src="https://www.leadedsolder.com/assets/famicom-decoupling-caps.jpg" alt="The axial decoupling caps are added."></p>

<p>I also added decoupling caps between 5V and GND on the CPU and PPU chips. It’s just good practice! These 0.1µF axial ceramic cuties were lying in my cap pile ever since I used a handful of them for <a href="https://www.leadedsolder.com/tag/tandy1000sx">the cursed Tandy 1000SX</a>, so I was happy to slam two more of them in. The recipe I was following used <code>/RESET</code> as the 5V source, which feels a little sketchy, but it means you don’t have to run long wires all the way to the other end of the chip. Then again, the copper pour on the back of the board <em>is</em> 5V…</p>

<p>I thought 0.1µF might be a little small, but it’s easy to change these out for a 1µF or larger cap if it doesn’t have much effect. You probably shouldn’t pick decoupling caps based on aesthetics.</p>

<h2 id="video-amplification">Video Amplification</h2>
<p>The whole idea behind the composite mod is that you’re building a simple signal amplifier to replace the one that was originally inside the RF can.</p>

<p>As the baseband video signal comes out of PPU pin 21, you need to step it up to a level that the TV can easily understand. The video chip’s output transistors are simply not designed to directly drive a television, and after the weak signal goes all the way through the AV cable into the back of the TV, there’s probably not much left to pick up anyway.</p>

<p>There are a lot of homebrew mods for this, ranging from cutting out and reusing the stock transistors on the motherboard to building a whole protoboard circuit with some new parts.</p>

<p>After doing some more research, I decided I would try a part that I’ve been meaning to try for a while, <a href="https://www.ti.com/product/THS7314">the TI THS7314 video amplifier IC</a>. It’s used a lot for <a href="https://www.retrorgb.com/thsamps.html">the amplification of analogue RGB signals</a>, and it should work really well for my one-channel signal. The part is designed specifically for this application, and should both install cleanly and produce nice-looking video.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.leadedsolder.com/assets/famicom-av-mod-ths7314-board.png" alt="The prototype board as seen from KiCad. It's very simple, with only a 'video in,' 'audio in,' and 'power in' pinout which then goes to the THS7314 chip."></p>

<p>I made a quick, super-simple little board that basically just broke out the pins of the video amp chip, and sent it to fab at OSH Park. They’ve recently added free (if slow - over a month) shipping to Canada, which makes them a really desirable option for running off onesy-twosie little mod boards like this during the current shipping nightmare we find ourselves in.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.leadedsolder.com/assets/famicom-av-mod-boards-osh.jpg" alt="The two variants of the board - one with the traditional &quot;homebrew amp&quot; design, and the other with the TI THS7314 video amplifier chip."></p>

<p>I made boards to do two variants, one with the original “homebrew” amplifier circuit and one with the THS7314. If the THS7314 doesn’t work out for whatever reason, I can just put in the usual circuit that the community prefers. However - spoilers - the THS7314 worked fine, so I never actually constructed the traditional design.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.leadedsolder.com/assets/famicom-av-mod-v0.2-assembled.jpg" alt="The v0.2 board, assembled. A cap leg comes out of the &quot;R&quot; audio hole, and then directly around in a 180 to the &quot;L&quot; audio hole."></p>

<p>I should have added a jumper to the board to solder left and right audio together (the Famicom is monoaural.) This ugly cap leg trick should be fine for awhile. I decided on a 220µF capacitor for audio, because that’s what was on the top of the cap bin when I opened it.</p>

<h2 id="sound">Sound</h2>
<p>The Famicom supports audio coming from the cartridge, which is why Castlevania III on the Famicom has such better music than that on the NES. I definitely want to be able to hear the cartridge audio, so it’s worth pulling the audio from somewhere other than directly out of the CPU (which also contains the sound hardware – lower chip counts = more profit for Nintendo.) The “<a href="https://wiki.nesdev.com/w/index.php/Cartridge_connector">audio output</a>” pin on the cartridge contains the Famicom’s sound after it has been mixed between the expansion audio and the system audio, where it normally then travels immediately to the RF can for output. Since we’re no longer putting that audio into the RF output stream, it needs to get broken out and fed into the TV using the usual RCA jacks as well.</p>

<p>Reportedly, the GPM-02 motherboard has <a href="https://nerdlypleasures.blogspot.com/2018/01/famicom-nes-simple-tweaks-to-restore.html">a different ‘mix’ between the expansion audio and the system audio compared to the original Famicom motherboard</a>. You can revert back to the original model’s amplifier behaviour by removing the 43kΩ resistor at R7 and replacing it with a 100kΩ part.</p>

<p>I also removed the choke at FC1 on the motherboard, so that the sound didn’t go into the RF can where it might pick up other noise. To source audio, I just went from the “expansion audio” pin (#46) on the cartridge port and added a 220µF capacitor.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.leadedsolder.com/assets/famicom-gpm02-audio-mods.jpg" alt="The two audio mods done. R7 is replaced with a 100kΩ resistor that I had on hand (sorry it's so big... and backward) and FC1 is removed entirely."></p>

<p>I only had a giant 100kΩ resistor on hand, so that’s the one that went in. This bugs me more than I thought it would.</p>

<p>These changes <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gD22orMjz48">seem to make a pretty significant impact</a>. I generally don’t have an ear for little tweaks, but this is big enough that even I can pick it out. There’s whole instruments that seem to be missing from the unmodified mix.</p>

<h2 id="getting-the-signal-out">Getting The Signal Out</h2>
<p>There’s a lot of different ways I’ve seen of actually getting the composite signal out of the Famicom and into a way that you can plug it into a TV:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Cut out the RF box’s antenna jack, and <a href="http://8bitplus.co.uk/projects/famicom-av-mod-nintendo/">replace it with a TRRS jack</a>, which carries all four signals for RCA on one jack;</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.boards.ie/vbulletin/showthread.php?t=2056561579">Drill holes in the side</a> and put in some panel-mount RCA connectors;</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ky8rFPbzGMU">Run a female or male RCA cable squid out of the case</a> (usually …</li></ul></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.leadedsolder.com/2020/12/17/famicom-composite-mod-v1.html">https://www.leadedsolder.com/2020/12/17/famicom-composite-mod-v1.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.leadedsolder.com/2020/12/17/famicom-composite-mod-v1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25463627</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 03:54:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Big Sur bug prevents upgrades to the next version]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 130 | Comments 39 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25463521">thread link</a>) | @groobongithub
<br/>
December 17, 2020 | https://micromdm.io/blog/big-sur-softwareupdate/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://micromdm.io/blog/big-sur-softwareupdate/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><br><span>Date: Thu, Dec 17, 2020</span><br><span>Reading Time: 7 minutes</span></p><p>If you work with Apple in some capacity, you know that they’re not very likely to admit mistakes. I’m not aware of Apple publishing postmortems after outages or providing details about known issues. So it’s up to the developer and admin communities at large to help each other learn about outages and potential causes. With the release of macOS 11.1 this week I’ve been debugging a new issue with the Mac software update process, one which will affect most enterprise users. I decided I should write about it and let everyone know what the issue is, workarounds, and how to avoid it. I’ve also been paying close attention to some recent changes to the software update mechanism, so I’ll try to mention them below as well.</p><h2 id="a-macos-11-bug-prevents-upgrades-to-the-next-version">A macOS 11 bug prevents upgrades to the next version</h2><p>After macOS 11.1 was released earlier this week, many users <a href="https://twitter.com/Contains_ENG/status/1339399335298166785">started reporting</a> that they were not able to see the software update. Others reported that they saw it, but were not able to download it. I personally experienced this issue when 11.1 was in beta and filed a case with Apple about it, but then moved on to other problems. When the final release came out this week, there were widespread reports of it on the MacAdmins Slack. Reading through system logs, I as well as other admins were able to find what appears to be the root cause. <strong>Under certain conditions, macOS 11.0.1 and macOS 11.1 hosts are requesting the update server send the 11.0.1 update, instead of requesting the next available one. The server rejects this update as it’s already either installed or older.</strong> This somehow corrupts the state of the software update process, and the update is no longer visible as an option in System Preferences.</p><figure><img src="https://micromdm.io/big_sur_softwareupdate/log.jpg"></figure><h3 id="workarounds">Workarounds</h3><ul><li>The update is visible again immediately after the restart. But it’s unclear if the update can always be installed after it’s visible since the condition that made it fail to download the first time can be triggered again.</li><li>Removing the MDM enrollment profile causes the update to be seen again. I and several others tested this extensively, and it’s definitely the enrollment profile, not some other policy managed by MDM. This is obviously a terrible workaround and I’d hesitate to mention it to users as it could cause security agents to stop working, and countless approval dialogs we’re so familiar with. Not to mention some of you have the MDM enrollment profile as non-removable or users who are not administrators, so they don’t have permission to unenroll. Getting them back enrolled in the MDM might prove to be a challenge too.</li><li>Distributing the full 11.1, and eventually the 11.2 installers.</li></ul><h3 id="can-apple-fix-this-bug-without-manual-intervention">Can Apple fix this bug without manual intervention?</h3><p>Apple is well aware this is a problem now, so I am confident the issue will be addressed in 11.2. Unfortunately, it is a client-side issue affecting both 11.0.1 and 11.1 clients. So there’s not much Apple <em>can</em> do to provide a fix. One potential solution I see is for Apple to detect the wrong request and instead of rejecting the download, offer the right file archive instead. But this is a complex system and it’s unclear if the server-side changes alone are enough.</p><p>Something else Apple could try is to side load a patch through another software update. There’s background configuration and malware removal tools that are likely capable of fixing the issue on the system. But it’s an ugly hack and one I’d personally stay clear of even if the option was available.</p><p>In my opinion, the most likely outcome is that the bug will be fixed in 11.2, but clients that have already upgraded to Big Sur (or any M1 macs you might’ve bought) will have to work around the problem themselves. If we’re lucky Apple will publish a support article and that will be that.</p><h2 id="what-else-you-need-to-know">What else you need to know</h2><p>Big Sur has changed the software update mechanism entirely, especially on Apple Silicon macs. It’s a long time coming and Apple spoke about some of this at WWDC in the MDM and IT sessions, so it shouldn’t be entirely surprising. But a lot was left unsaid for us to discover on our own.</p><ul><li>Combo update packages are <a href="https://eclecticlight.co/2020/12/17/apple-has-stopped-providing-standalone-installers-for-macos-updates/">no longer published</a> on the Apple website. This might surprise many of you who rely on distributing them. The main reason is that the entire format of the updates has changed, and it’s also no longer possible to install updates without the Mac having access to the internet. The updates must come from Apple, and they must be managed by <code>softwareupdate</code> and related processes on the system.</li><li>On Apple Silicon, third party processes are no longer able to script the <code>softwareupdate</code> command. Running the software update command as a root process now prompts for the administrator password, who also needs to be a secure token user. There are only two possible options for OS updates to be applied; either the human user of the device itself or the MDM process <a href="https://support.apple.com/guide/deployment-reference-macos/using-secure-and-bootstrap-tokens-apdff2cf769b/1/web/1.0">which has special permission</a>. It might also be possible for the Mac to update itself with the auto-update mechanism, but there are too many bugs right now to observe how well that works. My personal experience is that it doesn’t and I’m greeted with a password prompt to enter the next day…</li><li>Specifying a custom URL for the <code>softwareupdate</code> process to pull updates from is no longer possible. Apple advertised this deprecation for all of last year, so it should surprise no one but it hurts. <a href="https://github.com/wdas/reposado">Reposado</a> was one of several great tools that made it possible to have unstable/beta/stable tracks within an organization.</li><li>—ignore is gone as a flag. It <a href="https://mrmacintosh.com/10-15-5-2020-003-updates-changes-to-softwareupdate-ignore/">was gone</a> in 10.15.5 briefly too, so you likely know about this one. This time it’s gone for good and never coming back. An MDM server can delay the client from seeing OS updates for up to 90 days only, but that is the absolute maximum going forward. Even for a future major release like macOS 12. If this is important to you, file feedback for Apple to provide a second deferral option, specific to major version numbers.</li></ul><p>I work with the MDM protocol a lot day-to-day and have been <a href="https://micromdm.io/blog/os_update/">testing</a> software updates for a while. I was even <a href="https://micromdm.io/blog/wwdc20-what-s-new-in-managing/">optimistic</a> about what it would look like in Big Sur back in June. Apple had promised it’s an entirely new implementation, closer to what is available on iOS and that everything would work better than before. But we’re not off to a good start, and all the concerns I had for several years now are back. The <a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/devicemanagement/commands_and_queries">design</a> of OS updates in MDM is brittle, requiring multiple remote procedure calls to accomplish something that was previously done by a few lines of shell scripting. And that would be bad on its own, but the bad design is coupled with a buggy implementation; there are many known issues, besides the one I described above. Unless something drastically changes, we’re likely to see many months, if not years of software update bugs that are entirely out of our control.</p><p>Apple was never particularly great at building systems for the enterprise. But, until recently, the Unix components were available for software developers and system administrators to work with. The end result ended up being that if you made an investment within your organization, macOS was a great experience for end-users. It took a lot of work, but it was all achievable. Today, Apple is no better at developing systems that are required in the enterprise. But the ball is entirely in their court. Apple still makes great tools for consumers, and there will be a demand from employees to provide them with Apple gear. But, if Apple can’t start acting on our collective feedback, the experience of using a Mac in the workplace will quickly become unbearable to most.</p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://micromdm.io/blog/big-sur-softwareupdate/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25463521</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 03:35:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Two Hundred Different Misspellings of Schwarzenegger]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 56 | Comments 49 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25462660">thread link</a>) | @cowllin
<br/>
December 17, 2020 | https://www.watercoolertrivia.com/blog/schwarzenegger | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.watercoolertrivia.com/blog/schwarzenegger">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Arnold Alois Schwarzenegger was born in Austria on July 30, 1947. Famously, he reached stratospheric levels of notoriety and success in three wholly distinct professional fields: bodybuilding, acting, and politics, culminating in his eight years as the Governor of California.&nbsp;<br></p><p>For the past 73 years, Schwarzenegger has gone by Arnold, Ahnuld, Governator, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arnold_Schwarzenegger">Austrian Oak</a>, Terminator, Running Man, and dozens of other nicknames. In part because he’s charismatic and there’s nicknames aplomb to describe him, sure.&nbsp;<br></p><p><strong>But also because his last name is hard to spell. Like, really hard.</strong> We would know, because Water Cooler Trivia participants have spelled Schwarzenegger 255 different ways. And we’ve dug deep to explore that data.&nbsp;<br></p><p>255 different spellings. <a href="https://www.watercoolertrivia.com/blog/feature-emojis"><strong>We don’t grade responses based on spellings</strong></a>, so these are the spellings we’ve accepted as correct. We’ve got the full list of them at the end of this article, but we wanted to dig deeper into the data<br></p><h2>First things first: here’s the trivia question<br></h2><blockquote><strong>“What is the name of the Austrian bodybuilder who has been Mr. Universe three times and Mr. Olympia seven times?”</strong><br></blockquote><p>The answer, as you’ve surely guessed by now, is Arnold Schwarzenegger. We first wrote this question in April 2019, and since then…</p><ul role="list"><li><strong>3,019 different participants</strong> across 306 different groups have submitted a response</li><li><strong>2,681</strong> (89%) of folks got the question correct</li><li><strong>1,616</strong> (60%) of correct responses were spelled correctly [editor’s note: we suspect phone and browser autocorrect software lent a helping hand here]</li><li><strong>255</strong> different spellings of Schwarzenegger during that time<br></li></ul><p>And now, let’s look at the different ways in which Schwarzenegger has been spelled by Water Cooler Trivia participants.&nbsp;</p><h2>1. What are the most common misspellings?</h2><p>When you remove the correct spelling, you are left with 1,060 participants who spelled Schwarzenegger in 254 different ways.&nbsp;<br></p><p>The most common misspelling is to simply add a <strong>T </strong>after the <strong>R</strong>, a.k.a <strong>Schwartzenegger</strong>. This makes sense, as Schwartz itself is a fairly common German surname. 116 different respondents, 4% of all correct responses, spelled Arnold’s surname with that bonus <strong>T.</strong><br></p><p>Next up was <strong>Schwarzeneger</strong>, which removes a letter rather than adding one, this time removing one of the two <strong>G</strong>s. Again, this matches intuition. Double letters are hard to remember and frequently don’t add anything phonetically to a word. 88 different participants spelled it with this missing <strong>G</strong>, or 3% of all correct responses.<br></p><p>In third place was <strong>Schwarzenager</strong> with 56 people (2% of correct responses) both dropping that same <strong>G </strong>and then also swapping an <strong>E </strong>with a <strong>G. </strong>We get it, spelling is hard.<br></p><p>Below is a chart of the ten most common misspellings, and for the intrepid, here’s the <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1QqEL1IZvox3Aypi0YDStZ3QJ2_WuMTPwp7pOJ2batPE/edit#gid=756356712">full list</a> of misspellings.</p><figure id="w-node-73dd971f4f5a-e7177fda"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5eb9c1e4771ba53de5f5dbee/5fdbffcf08dd766ee0807d28_YMx1QfTHzO6c61u44T5MnhVihFk7AuJUa3aJXoUvDh8sLDYthwp4CYFclY0sUekxH3MYA1U9T9lu0OY0GBnxEtnBW-jUzNYQfk5iRSXSBP2musv3twFKBiNuMHwAPsVhEvrRVvUz.png" alt=""></p></figure><h2>2. Wait, how many letters is it?</h2><p>It’s 14 letters. S-c-h-w-a-r-z-e-n-e-g-g-e-r. But not everyone realized that.&nbsp;<br></p><p>Of the 255 total different spellings,&nbsp;</p><ul role="list"><li><strong>169</strong> (66%) had fewer than 14 letters</li><li><strong>24</strong> (9%) had more than 14 letters</li><li><strong>61</strong> (24%) correctly had 14 letters but were spelled incorrectly</li><li><strong>1</strong> (0.4%) correctly had 14 letters and was spelled correctly<br></li></ul><p>The most popular length was 13 letters with 31% of distinct spellings and 13% of all correct responses.</p><figure id="w-node-b1be6443de1a-e7177fda"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5eb9c1e4771ba53de5f5dbee/5fdbffcf088a2f4f273d8970_jDn-VaUiTJ_o9aGXBHJpAgFsSNJ4qViTLF0n0X5ZsN1kWQFbC7nS7JO88_K3BwfEaYJEkkT60LeNMN6-x7CwXgXXpJPsO7JLx7fPFXYMxPmM2bmSAaVNS0g1ttJBCkZDVdFqo_jX.png" alt=""></p></figure><h2>3. So it starts with an S... then a C… then...</h2><p>Schwarzenegger starts with the letter S. That’s fairly obvious. In fact, of the 255 distinct spellings that accepted as correct, 100% of them started with the letter <strong>S</strong>. However, once you move on to the second letter, <strong>only 58% of the spellings had C as the second letter.</strong><br></p><p>Unsurprisingly, the share of “correct” letters in terms of positions descends as you get further in the word, with a few noticeable deviations: interestingly, misspellings tend to correctly guess that the 11th letter is a <strong>G</strong> and the 14th letter is an <strong>R</strong>.<strong>&nbsp;</strong></p><figure id="w-node-3153958d4ef7-e7177fda"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5eb9c1e4771ba53de5f5dbee/5fdbffcf6ef4066cb3b8bc5a_SVo29XaQjA6jKuUkHuTPk1t2s967m2NoVPJrmpRPCGKe3Hrzg40C8kdhQvOqWkjw_BH_8noZ2ds0YGXkppq-B22DsD0PZ6auFQTHvSlEjpjzYw7r1Htdz5sFgWl7oAdN6pVAGp-6.png" alt=""></p></figure><h4>Double Letters</h4><p>On that topic, Schwarzenegger has a double letter in it: two G’s as the 11th and 12th letter. This was a common source of misspellings, as 1<strong>47 of the distinct spellings (58%) guessed that there was only one G</strong> in the politician’s surname.<br></p><h4>Edit Distance</h4><p>Known as edit distance or Levenshtein distance, this is a measure of how many changes you need to make to a word or phrase in order to translate it into another word or phrase. <strong>So “bake” has a distance of one from “cake” or “ake” or “baked”.</strong><br></p><p>When you search the internet for <strong>Girrafe</strong> and the search engine asks <strong><em>“Did you mean Giraffe?”</em></strong><em> </em>they are making that guess because your search query only had an edit distance of two from the more common query term <strong>Giraffe</strong>. One deletion (the first <strong>R</strong>) and one insertion (the second <strong>F</strong>) turns your query into the correct word.&nbsp;<br></p><p>So, basically, this is a way to see <strong><em>how bad </em></strong>certain spellings were. Or, more optimistically, how generous we at Water Cooler Trivia are as graders.&nbsp;<br></p><p>Okay, with all that prologue finished, here’s the edit distance stats for the 255 distinct spellings of Schwarzenegger. Note that we are only surfacing the 1,060 responses that were incorrectly spelled.&nbsp;</p><ul role="list"><li><strong>34% had an edit distance of only one</strong>!</li><li>And another 28% were only off by two characters!</li><li>18% of misspellings had an edit distance of at least four</li></ul><figure id="w-node-00b9f866edfc-e7177fda"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5eb9c1e4771ba53de5f5dbee/5fdbffcfee56eb8449ae2563_Qw6LyfdHxuw1-KuhsN3NFHyHzwr-1PnjCWoBqcc6pBTMNmr1DKqO-LmCkjcwMx-wn3K4inzJcTAnSOQCLQokxfe_psFkS6F8YkA4ohbuvw5kcvg7D9ApQtGulyfaG4kXCjRYgV-r.png" alt=""></p></figure><h2>4. What does Schwarzenegger even mean?</h2><p>I was wondering that too. It turns out the name has Germanic roots, divided neatly into two terms.</p><ul role="list"><li>"schwarzen" means "black"</li><li>&nbsp;"egg" refers to a ridge<br></li></ul><p>So the Governator’s surname <strong>translates most literally into English as Black Ridge</strong>, which happens to be the name of a U.S. <a href="https://www.blackridge.us/"><strong>technology services company</strong></a>.</p><h2>Closing thoughts...</h2><p>Looking to learn about more commonly-misspelled names or commonly-mistaken knowledge? Us too! We have a dataset of 2.5 million free text trivia responses. If you want to work with us to mine for fun data-driven stories, email <a href="https://www.watercoolertrivia.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#76121702173601170213041519191a130402041f001f175815191b"><span data-cfemail="7511140114350214011007161a1a19100701071c031c145b161a18">[email&nbsp;protected]</span></a> and we can find a way to work together.<br></p><p>Or if you just want to bring a <a href="https://www.watercoolertrivia.com/blog/how-weekly-trivia-impacts-your-mental-well-being"><strong>weekly trivia ritual</strong></a> to your team, that would make our hearts a-flutter. Get started with a four-week free trial at our <a href="http://watercoolertrivia.com/"><strong>homepage</strong></a>.<br></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.watercoolertrivia.com/blog/schwarzenegger</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25462660</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 01:15:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
