<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 5]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 5. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 12:39:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-5.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 12:39:12 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Road to Rome: Fundraising and Project Goals]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 21 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25342500">thread link</a>) | @terabytest
<br/>
December 7, 2020 | https://rome.tools/funding/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rome.tools/funding/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main-content"> <section>  <section> <h2 id="introduction">Introduction <a href="#introduction" aria-label="introduction"></a></h2>  <p>I’m Sebastian McKenzie, the creator of <a href="https://babeljs.io/">Babel</a> and <a href="https://yarnpkg.com/">Yarn</a>. These tools have both inspired me to create Rome, a new project that aims to simplify and improve JavaScript and web development.</p> <p>Rome consolidates dozens of separate tools into one. Rome can install your dependencies, check your code for errors, run your tests, bundle your code, and more, all via a single CLI. Rome will be able to replace Babel, ESLint, Prettier, Yarn, and webpack. <a href="https://rome.tools/">Learn more</a>.</p> <p>It’s been three months since we announced our initial <a href="https://rome.tools/blog/2020/08/08/introducing-rome.html">beta release</a>. Since then, we’ve received a tremendous amount of enthusiasm from the community. As that enthusiasm has grown, it’s become clear that Rome will require a full-time developer to be successful and deliver on our ambitious goals and release a stable v1.0.</p> <p><strong>I need your help to make it a reality.</strong></p> </section> <section> <h2 id="funding">Funding <a href="#funding" aria-label="funding"></a></h2> <p>I have left my job so I can work independently and focus on what the community needs. This includes a <a href="#allow-users-to-extend-functionality-with-plugins">plugin system</a>, <a href="#add-more-configuration-and-have-less-opinions">more configuration</a>, and <a href="#integrate-with-existing-tools">dedicated integrations for existing tools</a>.</p> <p>We have an initial goal of <strong>$100,000</strong>. This will allow myself to work independently on our first stable release. Additional funding would allow us to expand upon our release goals, fund future maintenance, and compensate other contributors.</p> <p>If you’re passionate about what we’re building, or have otherwise benefited from my work, I would appreciate your financial support.</p>    <section> <h3 id="recent-contributions">Recent Contributions <a href="#recent-contributions" aria-label="recent-contributions"></a></h3> <ul> <li>Loading...</li> </ul> </section> <section> <h3 id="contribute">Contribute <a href="#contribute" aria-label="contribute"></a></h3> <p>Prices are in USD. Includes sales tax and international shipping. Refer to <a href="#questions-and-answers">Questions and Answers</a> for more information.</p> <p> Loading... </p> <div> <h4>Custom</h4> <p>Want to donate under $10? Something else? Select your own amount!</p>  </div> <section> <h4 id="business">Business <a href="#business" aria-label="business"></a></h4> <p>These tiers include dedicated support, migration assistance, and website advertisement. I’ll make sure Rome works well for you and your organization.</p> <p>Migration support is where I personally help your organization adopt and use Rome. This could include porting configuration, integrating with CI, or even adding new features and configuration to Rome.</p> <p>Interested in something else or have questions? Get in touch at <a href="https://rome.tools/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#582b3d3a392b2c313936182a37353d762c3737342b"><span data-cfemail="aeddcbcccfdddac7cfc0eedcc1c3cb80dac1c1c2dd">[email&nbsp;protected]</span></a>!</p> <p> Loading... </p> </section> </section> </section> <section> <h2 id="goals">Goals <a href="#goals" aria-label="goals"></a></h2> <p>Funding will allow us to focus on usage and labor-intensive goals. We can make Rome easier to use and work for more people.</p> <section> <h3 id="add-more-configuration-and-have-less-opinions">Add more configuration and have less opinions <a href="#add-more-configuration-and-have-less-opinions" aria-label="add-more-configuration-and-have-less-opinions"></a></h3> <p>We have deliberately tried to keep configuration to a minimum. While this does produce a minimal API surface, it makes it almost impossible to easily migrate without losing functionality or changing conventions.</p> <p>We should aim to reduce the functional differences between Rome and other tools by introducing additional configuration and supported languages. This could include:</p> <ul> <li>Code formatting options</li> <li>Ability to customize expected filenames and directories</li> <li>Support for other configuration languages such as YAML and TOML</li> <li>More CLI flags</li> <li>Public JavaScript API</li> <li>Dynamic configuration (as opposed to static JSON-only configuration files)</li> <li><a href="#allow-users-to-extend-functionality-with-plugins">Allow extending functionality with plugins</a></li> </ul> <p>We have so far kept configuration light, as by reducing the amount of configuration options supported, we reduce maintenance cost and the potential for internal bugs.</p> <p>While this makes it easier for us as maintainers, it makes it drastically more difficult for users. No matter how persuasive our arguments may be for why you should use hard tabs instead of spaces, they seem like artificial and arbitrary constraints and introduces excessive prerequisites for adoption.</p> <p>Strong defaults and guided documentation for new users can provide the experience we ultimately want to offer, while removing our existing adoption restrictions.</p> </section> <section> <h3 id="integrate-with-existing-tools">Integrate with existing tools <a href="#integrate-with-existing-tools" aria-label="integrate-with-existing-tools"></a></h3> <p>Rome attempts to replace many tools. However we should still strive to support scenarios where another tool is better situated or preferred. This can also help during a migration where Rome is used in conjunction with another tool. We can do this in a couple of ways:</p> <p><strong>Integrating Rome as a first-class plugin in tools such as Babel, eslint, and webpack</strong></p> <p>Rome could be exposed as a plugin for those tools to allow you to adopt the Rome compiler without having to adopt the bundler first. This would reduce adoption prerequisites and allow easier experimentation inside of existing setups.</p> <p><strong>Seamlessly integrate other tools into Rome</strong></p> <p>We can introduce compatibility layers to have ESLint, Babel, and other tools run inside of Rome itself. ESLint errors could be displayed alongside Rome linter errors with the same UI and output format Instantly you could benefit from Rome’s file caching and parallelisation without needing a major migration.</p> </section> <section> <h3 id="assist-in-migrating-from-existing-tools">Assist in migrating from existing tools <a href="#assist-in-migrating-from-existing-tools" aria-label="assist-in-migrating-from-existing-tools"></a></h3> <p>It should be easy to migrate from other tools to Rome. First we need to ensure popular configuration options from other tools are supported. Then, offer automated tools to migrate basic setups without users needing to it manually.</p> <p>This needs to be accompanied with dedicated documentation and guides that can explain the differences between the tools, why you might want to use one over the other, similar concepts, new terminology, and equivalent config options.</p> </section> <section> <h3 id="allow-users-to-extend-functionality-with-plugins">Allow users to extend functionality with plugins <a href="#allow-users-to-extend-functionality-with-plugins" aria-label="allow-users-to-extend-functionality-with-plugins"></a></h3> <p>One of the fears with Rome is creating a monoculture where it’s impossible to innovate and experiment with new ideas. While it’s extremely optimistic to think we’ll ever get into any sort of monopolistic position, not allowing extensions does stiffle innovation regardless of our market position by restricting the viability and adoption of new ideas.</p> <p>Plugins allow us to avoid supporting functionality that we might not want, while still giving users a choice. It reduces our role as an arbiter and allows new languages, non-standard JavaScript features, code conventions, and ideas that interact with Rome to be viable, receive support, and proliferate.</p> <p>We need to be extremely careful not to get into the position where Babel and Webpack are today, where they’re heavily restricted by the usage of internal APIs. We need to be able to maintain our autonomy when it comes to making architectural changes. Balancing this with a powerful plugin API will be a challenge and will likely require several iterations.</p> </section> <section> <h3 id="release-undocumented-features">Release undocumented features <a href="#release-undocumented-features" aria-label="release-undocumented-features"></a></h3> <p>Rome currently does a lot more than linting. It’s a major challenge today to market and explain Rome when so much of the project isn’t officially supported. While we strive to make each individual component of Rome competitive on it’s own, to some the biggest advantage and compelling reason for using Rome might be the reduction in dependencies.</p> <p>We should focus on releasing and maturing basic versions of all core functionality. This would increase user confidence in our architecture and show that Rome is viable as the comprehensive replacement that we want to be.</p> </section> <section> <h3 id="provide-accessible-and-comprehensive-documentation">Provide accessible and comprehensive documentation <a href="#provide-accessible-and-comprehensive-documentation" aria-label="provide-accessible-and-comprehensive-documentation"></a></h3> <p>Documentation for developer tools is generally quite obtuse and relies a lot on prerequisite knowledge. This can make it intimidating and inaccessible for developers new to the ecosystem. Further complicating that is the broad scope of what Rome is trying to do.</p> <p>We have tried to address some of this by making our documentation a single page. This makes it easy to search, and it can be read from top to bottom without needing to jump around to learn about different concepts. However as our supported features grow, it will be more difficult to use this structure without oversimplifcation and doesn’t allow different paths for different demographics.</p> <p>We need to invest in a more scalable approach for our documentation. We can offer dedicated sections that explain features like linting end-to-end without needing to introduce other components like the compiler and bundler that contain significantly more concepts and overwhelm the reader. Separate guides can be offered for new users and those already experienced with other tools to properly cater for multiple audiences.</p> </section> <section> <h3 id="regularly-release-new-versions">Regularly release new versions <a href="#regularly-release-new-versions" aria-label="regularly-release-new-versions"></a></h3> <p>One of the reasons Babel was successful is how quickly I was able to quickly fix bugs and release new versions. I would regularly have releases out within minutes of a bug report. This was critical during the early days when adoption was low. Being able to unblock users quickly would often make them more excited to use Babel even though they ran into a bug.</p> <p>Similarly, we should try and replicate this by building out our release infrastructure to allow the rapid testing and release of versions. We need to maintain momentum as the scope of supported features grow.</p> <p>We can achieve this with automated releases that can be manually triggered or deployed on a schedule. Automatic changelog generation would also take a lot of the manual work out of producing releases. Nightly releases would allow users to test experimental features and provide early feedback.</p> </section> </section> <section> <h2 id="questions-and-answers">Questions and Answers <a href="#questions-and-answers" aria-label="questions-and-answers"></a></h2> <section> <h3 id="when-will-physical-rewards-be-shipped">When will physical rewards be shipped? <a href="#when-will-physical-rewards-be-shipped" aria-label="when-will-physical-rewards-be-shipped"></a></h3> <p>We are tentatively aiming for the end of April 2021, however due to COVID delays or order volume this could be extended. We’ll make sure to keep you updated via email.</p> </section> <section> <h3 id="what-is-my-email-used-for">What is my email used for? <a href="#what-is-my-email-used-for" aria-label="what-is-my-email-used-for"></a></h3> <p>We use your email address to send information about your order such as order questions, shipping status and delays. We may also send a survey to decide on customization options for rewards.</p> <p>Your email address will not be used for any other purpose or be displayed publicly.</p> </section> <section> <h3 id="how-is-payment-information-stored">How is payment information stored? <a href="#how-is-payment-information-stored" aria-label="how-is-payment-information-stored"></a></h3> <p>Payment information is entered and stored via Stripe. We do not have access to full payment details. Your billing address is used if we need to calculate and pay sales tax in your jurisdiction.</p> </section> <section> <h3 id="what-do-tier-prices-include">What do tier prices include? <a href="#what-do-tier-prices-include" aria-label="what-do-tier-prices-include"></a></h3> <p>Prices include processing fees, international shipping, and sales tax. This does mean the effective donation is reduced if you live in a country with import duty or high shipping cost.</p> <p>You have the option to add an additional donation in the order review screen if you would like to cover those costs.</p> </section> <section> <h3 id="why-do-you-need-my-usernames">Why do you need my usernames? <a href="#why-do-you-need-my-usernames" aria-label="why-do-you-need-my-usernames"></a></h3> <p>Usernames are used to allocate tier rewards. They are not required and you can …</p></section></section></section></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://rome.tools/funding/">https://rome.tools/funding/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rome.tools/funding/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25342500</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 06:28:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Alzheimer’s: New protein found in spinal fluid indicates stage of the disease]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 8 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25342434">thread link</a>) | @finphil
<br/>
December 7, 2020 | https://nuadox.com/post/636913398485073920/alzheimers-new-protein-in-spinal-fluid | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nuadox.com/post/636913398485073920/alzheimers-new-protein-in-spinal-fluid">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div> 
                 
                    
                    <article id="636913398485073920">
                        <div>
                            <div>
                                <a href="https://nuadox.com/post/636913398485073920/alzheimers-new-protein-in-spinal-fluid"><h2>Alzheimer’s: New protein found in spinal fluid indicates stage of the disease</h2></a>
                                <figure data-orig-width="1920" data-orig-height="1322"><img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/a98b1861b351c0e344a0b741a8dbb2e4/a732b01a66a4a7cb-bd/s1280x1920/7ada61fe5c6d735e94585f0e12fc1d58f842e15d.jpg" alt="image" data-orig-width="1920" data-orig-height="1322" width="1280" height="881"></figure><p><b>- By <a href="https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fmedicine.wustl.edu%2Fnews%2Fauthor%2Ftbhandari%2F&amp;t=ZDMzNTBmM2M0M2JmMjMxOGIwZGNkZWUwNDE2ODdkOGM2YmQ5ZDBiYyxES3V5WjNqTQ%3D%3D&amp;b=t%3AeWj9QNbkB8x7_Y2XTyPu8A&amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fnuadox.com%2Fpost%2F636913398485073920%2Falzheimers-new-protein-in-spinal-fluid&amp;m=0&amp;ts=1607603956">Tamara Bhandari</a> ,&nbsp;<a href="https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fmedicine.wustl.edu%2F&amp;t=YTI3Yzk5YzNhMTYxYTMwMmUwMTY3YzJlMDViYmQyZWUyMmM2ODY5MSxES3V5WjNqTQ%3D%3D&amp;b=t%3AeWj9QNbkB8x7_Y2XTyPu8A&amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fnuadox.com%2Fpost%2F636913398485073920%2Falzheimers-new-protein-in-spinal-fluid&amp;m=0&amp;ts=1607603956">Washington University School of Medicine</a> -</b></p><p>A novel form of an Alzheimer’s protein found in the fluid that surrounds the brain and spinal cord indicates what stage of the disease a person is in, and tracks with tangles of tau protein in the brain, according to a study from researchers at Washington University School of Medicine in St. Louis.&nbsp;</p><p>Tau tangles are thought to be toxic to neurons, and their spread through the brain foretells the death of brain tissue and cognitive decline. Tangles appear as the early, asymptomatic stage of Alzheimer’s develops into the symptomatic stage.</p><p>The discovery of so-called microtubule binding region tau (MTBR tau) in the cerebrospinal fluid could lead to a way to diagnose people in the earliest stages of Alzheimer’s disease, before they have symptoms or when their symptoms are still mild and easily misdiagnosed. It also could accelerate efforts to find treatments for the devastating disease, by providing a relatively simple way to gauge whether an experimental treatment slows or stops the spread of toxic tangles.</p><p>The study is published Dec. 7 in the journal <i><a href="https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Facademic.oup.com%2Fbrain%2Fadvance-article%2Fdoi%2F10.1093%2Fbrain%2Fawaa373%2F6024973&amp;t=NTVhMWZmMDMxZWE2NWNiNzhkYzAxNmQyOGEwNzJlNTE4NDY1NzdmZCxES3V5WjNqTQ%3D%3D&amp;b=t%3AeWj9QNbkB8x7_Y2XTyPu8A&amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fnuadox.com%2Fpost%2F636913398485073920%2Falzheimers-new-protein-in-spinal-fluid&amp;m=0&amp;ts=1607603956">Brain</a></i>.</p><p>“This MTBR tau fluid biomarker measures tau that makes up tangles and can confirm the stage of Alzheimer’s disease by indicating how much tau pathology is in the brains of Alzheimer’s disease patients,” said senior author <a href="https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fwuphysicians.wustl.edu%2Ffor-patients%2Ffind-a-physician%2Frandall-j-bateman&amp;t=MjQ0NjEyMDVmZjYwZWNiMmU1Y2E1Y2JjMTNhZDRlZjkwNzU5MTgwNCxES3V5WjNqTQ%3D%3D&amp;b=t%3AeWj9QNbkB8x7_Y2XTyPu8A&amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fnuadox.com%2Fpost%2F636913398485073920%2Falzheimers-new-protein-in-spinal-fluid&amp;m=0&amp;ts=1607603956">Randall J. Bateman, MD</a>, the Charles F. and Joanne Knight Distinguished Professor of Neurology. Bateman treats patients with Alzheimer’s disease on the Washington University Medical Campus. “If we can translate this into the clinic, we’d have a way of knowing whether a person’s symptoms are due to tau pathology in Alzheimer’s disease and where they are in the disease course, without needing to do a brain scan. As a physician, this information is invaluable in informing patient care, and in the future, to guide treatment decisions.”</p><figure data-orig-height="467" data-orig-width="700"><img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/fc417759120d05f3ed2b3f3c88456b16/a732b01a66a4a7cb-5b/s1280x1920/833d10cd4ac25b6179bb912ffe11c36eb2e47a6d.jpg" data-orig-height="467" data-orig-width="700" width="700" height="467" alt="image"></figure><p><i>Image:&nbsp;A “heat map” of the brain of a person with mild Alzheimer’s dementia shows where tau protein has accumulated, with areas of higher density in red and orange, and lower density in green and blue. Researchers at Washington University School of Medicine in St. Louis have found a form of tau in spinal fluid that tracks with tau tangles in the brain and indicates what stage of the disease a person is in. Credit: <a href="https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fmedicine.wustl.edu%2Fnews%2Fnovel-form-of-alzheimers-protein-found-in-spinal-fluid-indicates-stage-of-the-disease%2F&amp;t=ZmE5MmZmMmU5ZWY4NjYyNDVjMWE4NDE3YzBiZjE0MDk1NmU1MTU5YSxES3V5WjNqTQ%3D%3D&amp;b=t%3AeWj9QNbkB8x7_Y2XTyPu8A&amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fnuadox.com%2Fpost%2F636913398485073920%2Falzheimers-new-protein-in-spinal-fluid&amp;m=0&amp;ts=1607603956">Tammie Benzinger/Knight ADRC</a>.</i></p><p>Alzheimer’s begins when a brain protein called amyloid starts forming plaques in the brain. During this amyloid stage, which can last two decades or more, people show no signs of cognitive decline. However, soon after tangles of tau begin to spread in the neurons, people start exhibiting confusion and memory loss, and brain scans show increasing atrophy of brain tissue.</p><p>Tau tangles can be detected by positron emission tomography (PET) brain scans, but brain scans are time-consuming, expensive and not available everywhere. Bateman and colleagues are developing diagnostic blood tests for Alzheimer’s disease based on <a href="https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fmedicine.wustl.edu%2Fnews%2Fblood-test-is-94-accurate-at-identifying-early-alzheimers-disease%2F&amp;t=NDczMmVjYjNjMGZiZWRlZTAxNzRiZWIyYmFjYjQ1ZWI3OTRkNTM5YixES3V5WjNqTQ%3D%3D&amp;b=t%3AeWj9QNbkB8x7_Y2XTyPu8A&amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fnuadox.com%2Fpost%2F636913398485073920%2Falzheimers-new-protein-in-spinal-fluid&amp;m=0&amp;ts=1607603956">amyloid</a> or a different <a href="https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fmedicine.wustl.edu%2Fnews%2Falzheimers-protein-in-blood-indicates-early-brain-changes%2F&amp;t=MjJkYWMyNjZhNDY4OTcwNjliNjY5ZDI1NzFiNDk2MTRlZWYzZWZmYixES3V5WjNqTQ%3D%3D&amp;b=t%3AeWj9QNbkB8x7_Y2XTyPu8A&amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fnuadox.com%2Fpost%2F636913398485073920%2Falzheimers-new-protein-in-spinal-fluid&amp;m=0&amp;ts=1607603956">form of tau</a>, but neither test can pin down the amount of tau tangles across the stages of disease.</p><p>MTBR tau is an insoluble piece of the tau protein, and the primary component of tau tangles. Bateman and first author Kanta Horie, PhD, a visiting scientist in Bateman’s lab, realized that specific MTBR tau species were enriched in the brains of people with Alzheimer’s disease, and that measuring levels of the species in the cerebrospinal fluid that bathes the brain might be a way to gauge how broadly the toxic tangles have spread through the brain. Previous researchers using antibodies against tau had failed to detect MTBR tau in the cerebrospinal fluid. But Horie and colleagues developed a new method based on using chemicals to purify tau out of a solution, followed by mass spectrometry.</p><p>Using this technique, Horie, Bateman and colleagues analyzed cerebrospinal fluid from 100 people in their 70s. Thirty had no cognitive impairment and no signs of Alzheimer’s; 58 had amyloid plaques with no cognitive symptoms, or with mild or moderate Alzheimer’s dementia; and 12 had cognitive impairment caused by other conditions. The researchers found that levels of a specific form — MTBR tau 243 — in the cerebrospinal fluid were elevated in the people with Alzheimer’s and that it increased the more advanced a person’s cognitive impairment and dementia were.</p><p>The researchers verified their results by following 28 members of the original group over two to nine years. Half of the participants had some degree of Alzheimer’s at the start of the study. Over time, levels of MTBR tau 243 significantly increased in the Alzheimer’s disease group, in step with a worsening of scores on tests of cognitive function.</p><figure data-orig-height="467" data-orig-width="700"><img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/b80f5e6d9222f0044e0c36a76f464ec8/a732b01a66a4a7cb-da/s1280x1920/353cb72a4ec9acf360e43a1eb0a68bb6998b1887.jpg" data-orig-height="467" data-orig-width="700" width="700" height="467" alt="image"></figure><p><i>Image:&nbsp;Researchers at Washington University School of Medicine in St. Louis have found a novel form of the Alzheimer’s protein tau in the fluid surrounding the brain and spinal cord. This form of tau — known as MTBR tau — indicates what stage of Alzheimer’s a person is in and tracks with tangles of tau protein in the brain. Credit: <a href="https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fmedicine.wustl.edu%2Fnews%2Fnovel-form-of-alzheimers-protein-found-in-spinal-fluid-indicates-stage-of-the-disease%2F&amp;t=ZmE5MmZmMmU5ZWY4NjYyNDVjMWE4NDE3YzBiZjE0MDk1NmU1MTU5YSxES3V5WjNqTQ%3D%3D&amp;b=t%3AeWj9QNbkB8x7_Y2XTyPu8A&amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fnuadox.com%2Fpost%2F636913398485073920%2Falzheimers-new-protein-in-spinal-fluid&amp;m=0&amp;ts=1607603956">Sara Moser</a>.</i></p><p>The gold standard for measuring tau in the living brain is a tau-PET brain scan. The amount of tau visible in a brain scan correlates with cognitive impairment. To see how their technique matched up to the gold standard, the researchers compared the amount of tau visible in brain scans of 35 people — 20 with Alzheimer’s and 15 without — with levels of MTBR tau 243 in the cerebrospinal fluid. MTBR tau 243 levels were highly correlated with the amount of tau identified in the brain scan, suggesting that their technique accurately measured how much tau — and therefore damage — had accumulated in the brain.</p><p>“Right now there is no biomarker that directly reflects brain tau pathology in cerebrospinal fluid or the blood,” Horie said. “What we’ve found here is that a novel form of tau, MTBR tau 243, increases continuously as tau pathology progresses. This could be a way for us to not only diagnose Alzheimer’s disease but tell where people are in the disease. We also found some specific MTBR tau species in the space between neurons in the brain, which suggests that they may be involved in spreading tau tangles from one neuron to another. That finding opens up new windows for novel therapeutics for Alzheimer’s disease based on targeting MTBR tau to stop the spread of tangles.”</p><p>–</p><p><b>Source:&nbsp;<a href="https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fmedicine.wustl.edu%2Fnews%2Fnovel-form-of-alzheimers-protein-found-in-spinal-fluid-indicates-stage-of-the-disease%2F&amp;t=ZmE5MmZmMmU5ZWY4NjYyNDVjMWE4NDE3YzBiZjE0MDk1NmU1MTU5YSxES3V5WjNqTQ%3D%3D&amp;b=t%3AeWj9QNbkB8x7_Y2XTyPu8A&amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fnuadox.com%2Fpost%2F636913398485073920%2Falzheimers-new-protein-in-spinal-fluid&amp;m=0&amp;ts=1607603956">Washington University School of Medicine</a></b></p><p><b>Full study:</b>&nbsp;“CSF tau microtubule binding region identifies tau tangle and clinical stages of Alzheimer’s disease”, <i>Brain</i>.</p><p><a href="https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fdoi.org%2F10.1093%2Fbrain%2Fawaa373&amp;t=MWZkZTM5YjIxMjZiMTc3NzZlNzBlMjIzY2U0NWZjYjRjYjQwYWY2NSxES3V5WjNqTQ%3D%3D&amp;b=t%3AeWj9QNbkB8x7_Y2XTyPu8A&amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fnuadox.com%2Fpost%2F636913398485073920%2Falzheimers-new-protein-in-spinal-fluid&amp;m=0&amp;ts=1607603956">https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awaa373</a><br></p><h2><b>Read Also</b></h2><p><a href="https://nuadox.com/post/625031181195509760/new-blood-test-alzheimers">Novel blood test could greatly improve diagnosis of Alzheimer’s</a></p>
                    
                      
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                                             
                                <p><span>
                                    <p>
                                    
                                        <a href="https://nuadox.com/tagged/alzheimers">alzheimers</a>
                                    
                                        <a href="https://nuadox.com/tagged/neuroscience">neuroscience</a>
                                    
                                        <a href="https://nuadox.com/tagged/brain">brain</a>
                                    
                                        <a href="https://nuadox.com/tagged/medicine">medicine</a>
                                    
                                        <a href="https://nuadox.com/tagged/health">health</a>
                                    
                                        <a href="https://nuadox.com/tagged/biology">biology</a>
                                    
                                        <a href="https://nuadox.com/tagged/aging">aging</a>
                                    
                                    </p>
                                </span></p>
                                
                            </div>
                        </div>
                    </article>
                 
                </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nuadox.com/post/636913398485073920/alzheimers-new-protein-in-spinal-fluid</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25342434</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 06:14:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[DIY Covid-19 Vaccine]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 11 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25341719">thread link</a>) | @alfongj
<br/>
December 7, 2020 | https://radvac.org/vaccine/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://radvac.org/vaccine/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<div id="content">

<div>
	<div id="primary">
		<main id="main" role="main">

			
<article id="post-9" class="page">
	<!-- .entry-header -->
	<div>
		




<ul><li><strong>Intranasally delivered.</strong> Very simple to self administer. No injection, no needles. </li><li><strong>Synthetic peptide epitopes / antigens</strong>. These peptides are small synthetically produced portions of viral sequences. A peptide-based vaccine is not infectious. We have selected these peptides as the basis for our vaccine against SARS-CoV-2. The antigen portion of the vaccine can be substituted by other antigens; for example, recombinant SARS-CoV-2 Spike RBD. By appropriate selection of antigens, the intranasal vaccine design described here can also be adapted for use against other viruses, especially respiratory viruses, such as influenza or non-SARS coronaviruses.</li><li><strong>Chitosan nanoparticle delivery</strong>. Chitosan is a form of chitin, which is found in mushrooms and the shells of crustaceans such as shrimp and crabs (seafood allergies are not allergies to chitin). Chitosan acts as both delivery vehicle and immunostimulatory adjuvant.</li><li><strong>Extremely simple and inexpensive preparation</strong> with easily obtained materials.</li><li><strong>Short-term safety. </strong>This type of vaccine has shown excellent safety in animal studies and human clinical trials. The RaDVaC vaccine has been used repeatedly over several months,  by over 100 self-experimenters, with the most extreme complication in some recipients of stuffy noses. </li></ul>



<p>Protocols for the simple and robust production of chitosan nanoparticle vaccines for intranasal delivery have been published for over two decades. Intranasal delivery of chitosan-based vaccines have shown mild side effects and high levels of efficacy of both mucosal and systemic immunity, when delivered in a prime-boost regimen (in both animal models and human trials). </p>



<p>Click <a href="https://radvac.org/materials-and-equipment/">here to see a list of essential <strong>Materials and equipment</strong></a></p>



<p>Click <a href="https://radvac.org/protocols-for-making-and-taking-the-vaccine">here to access <strong>Protocols for making and taking the vaccine</strong></a></p>



<p>Click <a href="https://radvac.org/white-paper/">here for access to our <strong>White Paper</strong></a>, which contains all relevant scientific details, methods and protocols</p>
	</div><!-- .entry-content -->
</article><!-- #post-9 -->

		</main><!-- #main -->
	</div><!-- #primary -->
</div><!-- .wrap -->


		</div><!-- #content -->

		<!-- #colophon -->
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://radvac.org/vaccine/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25341719</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 04:18:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Drive My Robot]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 8 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25340599">thread link</a>) | @tomjacobs
<br/>
December 7, 2020 | http://teleportconnect.com/teleport.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://teleportconnect.com/teleport.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">

  <div>

    <center>
    <a href="http://teleportconnect.com/"><img src="http://teleportconnect.com/img/teleport_logo.png"></a>
    &nbsp;<a href="http://teleportconnect.com/">About</a> | 
    &nbsp;<a href="https://www.tindie.com/products/teleport/teleport">Buy a Teleport</a>
    </center>

    <!--
    <script>
    	var player = new WSAudioAPI.Player({
        server: {
            host: window.location.hostname,
            port: 5000
	}});
    </script>

    <script>
    	var streamer = new WSAudioAPI.Streamer({
        server: {
            host: window.location.hostname, 
            port: 5000 
	}});
    </script>
    <button onclick="player.start()">Play stream</button>
    <button onclick="player.stop()">Stop playing</button>
    <button onclick="streamer.start()">Start stream</button>
    <button onclick="streamer.stop()">Stop stream</button>
    -->

    <div>

      <!-- Asleep? -->
      

      <div>

        <!-- Video canvas -->
        

      </div>

      <div>
       

    <!-- List of tracks -
    <div id="tracksTitle" style="background:#AAFDCC;">Tracks</div>
    <div id="tracks" style="background:#DDFFDD;"></div><br>-->

    <!-- List of devices online -->
    
    

    </div>

    </div>

    

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://teleportconnect.com/teleport.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25340599</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 01:47:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Cemetery of Soviet Computers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 52 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25340452">thread link</a>) | @detaro
<br/>
December 7, 2020 | https://rusue.com/cemetery-of-soviet-computers/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rusue.com/cemetery-of-soviet-computers/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>The building did not stand out. Unremarkable industrial building, which was built in hundreds of Soviet cities.<span id="more-10215"></span></p>
<p>Non-broken glass, burning lights, live plants inside, modern plastic entrance doors. Except for one floor.</p>
<!-- WP QUADS Content Ad Plugin v. 2.0.17.1 -->


<p>Despite the twilight, the floor remained lifelessly dark. Somewhere in the depths, there was a dim glow of electric light, hardly penetrating through old glass blocks.</p>
<p>Inside the floor was empty and black, but not completely.&nbsp;Inside burned several fluorescent lamps, spotlighting dozens of silhouettes of tall cabinets.</p>
<p>Some of them were covered with darkened translucent film.</p>
<p>The surface of the floor, tables and enclosures covered with black spots of soot, sometimes diluted with white stains of dried extinguishing mixture.</p>
<p>The air felt a persistent, but not strong smell of burning.&nbsp;The fire walked here a few years ago but did not touch the equipment.</p>
<p>Part of the cabinets were antique electronic computers. Others served to measure signals, and computers controlled this process. Dozens of terminals froze on the tables with extinct screens.</p>

<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/2.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/2.jpg?resize=1050%2C788&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="788" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/2.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/2.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/2.jpg?resize=768%2C576&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/2.jpg?resize=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/2.jpg?resize=200%2C150&amp;ssl=1 200w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/2.jpg?resize=360%2C270&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/2.jpg?resize=545%2C409&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/3.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/3.jpg?resize=1050%2C1438&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="1438" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/3.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/3.jpg?resize=219%2C300&amp;ssl=1 219w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/3.jpg?resize=768%2C1052&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/3.jpg?resize=748%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 748w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/3.jpg?resize=360%2C493&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/3.jpg?resize=545%2C746&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/121.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/121.jpg?resize=1050%2C788&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="788" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/121.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/121.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/121.jpg?resize=768%2C576&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/121.jpg?resize=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/121.jpg?resize=200%2C150&amp;ssl=1 200w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/121.jpg?resize=360%2C270&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/121.jpg?resize=545%2C409&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p>Suddenly it became clear that before them the legendary machine “Saratov-2”.&nbsp;The machine, which was massively placed on many enterprises of the Soviet Union in the 70s, but at the same time, not a single high-quality (I’m not talking about color) photos remained. Not on the Internet, not even in the museum of the enterprise developer.</p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/4-1.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/4-1.jpg?resize=1050%2C1400&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="1400" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/4-1.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/4-1.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/4-1.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/4-1.jpg?resize=360%2C480&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/4-1.jpg?resize=545%2C727&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/5.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/5.jpg?resize=1050%2C1400&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="1400" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/5.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/5.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/5.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/5.jpg?resize=360%2C480&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/5.jpg?resize=545%2C727&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p>This computer did not even have a traditional microprocessor. Domestic clone of the popular American PDP-8, Saratov-2 was produced in two versions.</p>
<p>Steel frame, like a chest of drawers, filled with drawers.&nbsp;Different boxes responded to various computer nodes — a twelve-bit computing unit, input-output device interfaces, and RAM.</p>
<p>The memory was ferromagnetic – two boxes of four cubes in each. Reading or writing programs occurred through punched tapes, and to display the results of calculations used electric typewriter CONSUL-260.</p>
<p>The monitor and keyboard in that era were not yet a much-needed</p>
<p>part of the computer. The necessary input of programs into the operative memory was carried out in binary codes, manually using a group of switches on the front panel. Bulbs controlled the correctness of the input.</p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/6.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/6.jpg?resize=1050%2C788&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="788" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/6.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/6.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/6.jpg?resize=768%2C576&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/6.jpg?resize=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/6.jpg?resize=200%2C150&amp;ssl=1 200w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/6.jpg?resize=360%2C270&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/6.jpg?resize=545%2C409&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/7.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/7.jpg?resize=1050%2C773&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="773" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/7.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/7.jpg?resize=300%2C221&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/7.jpg?resize=768%2C565&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/7.jpg?resize=1024%2C754&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/7.jpg?resize=360%2C265&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/7.jpg?resize=545%2C401&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/8.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/8.jpg?resize=1050%2C774&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="774" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/8.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/8.jpg?resize=300%2C221&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/8.jpg?resize=768%2C566&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/8.jpg?resize=1024%2C755&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/8.jpg?resize=360%2C265&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/8.jpg?resize=545%2C402&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/9.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/9.jpg?resize=1050%2C1088&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="1088" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/9.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/9.jpg?resize=290%2C300&amp;ssl=1 290w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/9.jpg?resize=768%2C796&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/9.jpg?resize=988%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 988w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/9.jpg?resize=360%2C373&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/9.jpg?resize=545%2C565&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/10.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/10.jpg?resize=1050%2C828&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="828" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/10.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/10.jpg?resize=300%2C237&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/10.jpg?resize=768%2C606&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/10.jpg?resize=1024%2C807&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/10.jpg?resize=360%2C284&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/10.jpg?resize=545%2C430&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/121-1.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/121-1.jpg?resize=1050%2C788&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="788" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/121-1.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/121-1.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/121-1.jpg?resize=768%2C576&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/121-1.jpg?resize=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/121-1.jpg?resize=200%2C150&amp;ssl=1 200w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/121-1.jpg?resize=360%2C270&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/121-1.jpg?resize=545%2C409&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p>The next generation of computers was Electronics 100/25. These machines were clones of American PDP-11.</p>
<p>They thought faster, had more memory, allowed them to work with magnetic tape drives and punched tapes, but the general principle remained the same.</p>
<p>It was possible to connect a monitor and a keyboard to this computer, while still having the ability to enter programs through the front switches.</p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/11.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/11.jpg?resize=1050%2C778&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="778" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/11.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/11.jpg?resize=300%2C222&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/11.jpg?resize=768%2C569&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/11.jpg?resize=1024%2C759&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/11.jpg?resize=360%2C267&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/11.jpg?resize=545%2C404&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/12.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/12.jpg?resize=1050%2C788&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="788" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/12.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/12.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/12.jpg?resize=768%2C576&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/12.jpg?resize=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/12.jpg?resize=200%2C150&amp;ssl=1 200w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/12.jpg?resize=360%2C270&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/12.jpg?resize=545%2C409&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<!-- WP QUADS Content Ad Plugin v. 2.0.17.1 -->


<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/13.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/13.jpg?resize=1050%2C801&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="801" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/13.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/13.jpg?resize=300%2C229&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/13.jpg?resize=768%2C586&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/13.jpg?resize=1024%2C781&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/13.jpg?resize=360%2C275&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/13.jpg?resize=545%2C416&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p>Electronics-60 – the further development of Electronics 100/25. The same architecture, but bulky tape drives are a thing of the past.</p>
<p>They were replaced by flexible eight-inch floppy disks. The new chipset, allowed to fit the processor module, power supply and control devices, in a very compact size.</p>
<p>I note that all these computers were managers, that is, they worked with a bunch of external equipment. It could be machine tools, laboratory complexes, measuring devices.</p>
<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/16.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/16.jpg?resize=1050%2C779&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="779" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/16.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/16.jpg?resize=300%2C223&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/16.jpg?resize=768%2C570&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/16.jpg?resize=1024%2C760&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/16.jpg?resize=360%2C267&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/16.jpg?resize=545%2C404&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a> <a href="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/17.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/17.jpg?resize=1050%2C1385&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="1385" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/17.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/17.jpg?resize=227%2C300&amp;ssl=1 227w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/17.jpg?resize=768%2C1013&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/17.jpg?resize=776%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 776w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/17.jpg?resize=360%2C475&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/17.jpg?resize=545%2C719&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/18.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/18.jpg?resize=1050%2C1418&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="1418" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/18.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/18.jpg?resize=222%2C300&amp;ssl=1 222w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/18.jpg?resize=768%2C1037&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/18.jpg?resize=758%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 758w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/18.jpg?resize=360%2C486&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/18.jpg?resize=545%2C736&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p>15VM16-1 some early version of Electronics-60, having a control panel of light bulbs and switches. Assembled on the element base of the previous Electronics 100/25. I occupied a small nightstand built into the table on which the controlled equipment was placed.</p>
<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/19.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/19.jpg?resize=1050%2C858&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="858" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/19.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/19.jpg?resize=300%2C245&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/19.jpg?resize=768%2C628&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/19.jpg?resize=1024%2C837&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/19.jpg?resize=360%2C294&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/19.jpg?resize=545%2C445&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a> <a href="https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/20.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/20.jpg?resize=1050%2C814&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="814" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/20.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/20.jpg?resize=300%2C233&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/20.jpg?resize=768%2C595&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/20.jpg?resize=1024%2C794&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/20.jpg?resize=360%2C279&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/20.jpg?resize=545%2C423&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p>DVK-2M or Interactive Computing Complex. Massive, stylish in appearance, the computer of the 80s, which could be considered a personal computer.</p>
<p>It consisted of two desktop blocks – processor and pairing. A set of interchangeable interface cards allowed connecting drives of various types, a monochrome monitor on an openwork leg, and a keyboard.</p>
<p>Back in 1993, when we were studying, one teaching DVK could distribute programs for a couple of dozen Spectrums through the network.</p>
<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21.jpg?resize=1050%2C788&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="788" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21.jpg?resize=768%2C576&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21.jpg?resize=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21.jpg?resize=200%2C150&amp;ssl=1 200w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21.jpg?resize=360%2C270&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21.jpg?resize=545%2C409&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/22.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/22.jpg?resize=1050%2C788&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="788" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/22.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/22.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/22.jpg?resize=768%2C576&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/22.jpg?resize=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/22.jpg?resize=200%2C150&amp;ssl=1 200w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/22.jpg?resize=360%2C270&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/22.jpg?resize=545%2C409&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/23.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/23.jpg?resize=1050%2C788&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="788" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/23.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/23.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/23.jpg?resize=768%2C576&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/23.jpg?resize=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/23.jpg?resize=200%2C150&amp;ssl=1 200w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/23.jpg?resize=360%2C270&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i2.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/23.jpg?resize=545%2C409&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p>The DVK-3 in the monoblock plastic case is the next stage of the DVK-2M.</p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/24.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/24.jpg?resize=1050%2C790&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="790" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/24.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/24.jpg?resize=300%2C226&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/24.jpg?resize=768%2C578&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/24.jpg?resize=1024%2C770&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/24.jpg?resize=200%2C150&amp;ssl=1 200w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/24.jpg?resize=360%2C270&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i0.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/24.jpg?resize=545%2C410&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/25.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/25.jpg?resize=1050%2C811&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="811" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/25.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/25.jpg?resize=300%2C232&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/25.jpg?resize=768%2C593&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/25.jpg?resize=1024%2C791&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/25.jpg?resize=360%2C278&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/25.jpg?resize=545%2C421&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a> <a href="https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/26.jpg?ssl=1"><img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/26.jpg?resize=1050%2C740&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="1050" height="740" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/26.jpg?w=1050&amp;ssl=1 1050w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/26.jpg?resize=300%2C211&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/26.jpg?resize=768%2C541&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/26.jpg?resize=1024%2C722&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/26.jpg?resize=360%2C254&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i1.wp.com/rusue.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/26.jpg?resize=545%2C384&amp;ssl=1 545w" sizes="(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://ralphmirebs.livejournal.com/226286.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Source</a></p>
<div><!--Yasr Visitor Votes Shortcode--><div id="yasr_visitor_votes_10215"><p>Our Reader Score</p><p><span data-postid="10215" id="yasr-total-average-dashicon-10215"></span><span id="yasr-total-average-text-1c1d658ff52d7">Total: <span id="yasr-vv-votes-number-container-1c1d658ff52d7">83</span>  Average: <span id="yasr-vv-average-container-1c1d658ff52d7">4.8</span></span></p></div><!--End Yasr Visitor Votes Shortcode--></div>
<!-- WP QUADS Content Ad Plugin v. 2.0.17.1 -->


</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rusue.com/cemetery-of-soviet-computers/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25340452</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 01:29:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Spend your money where you spend your time]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 7 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25339736">thread link</a>) | @mcrittenden
<br/>
December 7, 2020 | https://critter.blog/2020/12/07/spend-your-money-where-you-spend-your-time/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://critter.blog/2020/12/07/spend-your-money-where-you-spend-your-time/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-content" role="main">

	
<article id="post-4015">

	
<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>

		<div>

			
<p>5 years ago, I bought some new glasses. I found a cheap $60 frame and I was proud. I’ve worn those glasses every waking hour for the last 5 years, which adds up to about 30,000 hours. They’re slightly uncomfortable and I have to push them back up on my nose a few times an hour, but I make do because you can’t argue with that price!</p>



<p>Meanwhile, I recently bought a new minivan to lug the kids around. I could have made do with one for $10,000-ish less, but I wanted a nice shiny one with a DVD player and all that. I use it maybe 30 minutes a day. </p>



<p>I’m realizing lately how backwards that logic is. I saved a couple hundred bucks on glasses and <a href="https://critter.blog/2020/11/06/all-self-help-boils-down-to-choose-long-term-over-short-term/">cursed myself with 30,000 hours</a> of discomfort and annoyance. And I spent an extra $10,000 on something that I barely even use compared to those dang glasses.</p>



<p>I think it makes sense to spend our money where we spend our time. What are the things we spend the most time with? Glasses, shoes, a computer and desk and chair, a bed, a belt, whatever it is. Even if one of those things is <em>slightly</em> worse than it could be, when you multiply that by <a href="https://critter.blog/2020/11/04/what-we-have-left/">a bajillion hours of usage</a>, it explodes.</p>



<p>Say that I had spent $500 on a pair of glasses that felt great. That’s an increase of $440. Divide $440 by 30,000 hours, and it turns out that I’d be paying about 1 penny per hour for that added comfort. No brainer, right? </p>



<p>Now let’s look at the car. If I use that car for 7 years that’s about 1300 hours of driving time. That means that the extra $10,000 comes out to about $7.70 per hour. I’m paying minimum wage to no one in exchange for access to a DVD player we barely use and a van that looks a little nicer.</p>



<p>Never again. Never again will I skimp on glasses and splurge on a car. I don’t even have a commute!</p>





		</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	</div><!-- .post-inner -->

	<!-- .section-inner -->

	
	<!-- .pagination-single -->

	
</article><!-- .post -->

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://critter.blog/2020/12/07/spend-your-money-where-you-spend-your-time/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25339736</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:23:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A database of 400 places where to promote your startup]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25338757">thread link</a>) | @sjohn93
<br/>
December 7, 2020 | https://www.startupjohn.com/companies/SpreadTheWorld | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.startupjohn.com/companies/SpreadTheWorld">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.startupjohn.com/companies/SpreadTheWorld</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25338757</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 22:46:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Librem 5 Evergreen vs. Pinephone]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 145 | Comments 63 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25338633">thread link</a>) | @ThatGeoGuy
<br/>
December 7, 2020 | https://thatgeoguy.ca/blog/2020/12/06/Librem-5-Evergreen-vs-Pinephone/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thatgeoguy.ca/blog/2020/12/06/Librem-5-Evergreen-vs-Pinephone/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="layout">
	 <!-- sidebar -->
	<div>
	
<p>On <em>2020-12-06</em> by <em>ThatGeoGuy</em></p>

<p>Huzzah! I recently received my Librem 5 (Evergreen) from
<a href="https://puri.sm/">Purism</a>. The Librem 5 is a smartphone that runs an otherwise
standard linux kernel. However, unlike Android which also relies on the linux
kernel under the hood, the Librem 5 uses a GNU userspace, adapted for mobile.
This makes it more akin to your typical laptop in some ways, although the form
factor still resembles a modern smartphone (at least, mostly). Here are some
preliminary thoughts about the phone and how it compares to
<a href="https://pine64.org/">Pine64</a>’s Pinephone, which is another phone that uses
neither Android nor iOS, and relies on a GNU / Linux based OS.</p>

<p>This is a bit of a long post, and I’m sorry for that. Brevity is certainly a
hard-earned skill, but going forward without comparing the Librem 5 to the
Pinephone seemed like the wrong choice ;)</p>



<h2 id="purism-librem-5">Purism Librem 5</h2>

<p>Purism touts the Librem 5 as a “Security and Privacy Focused Phone.” This is
not wholly untrue, and there are some features that are unique to the Librem 5
in this respect. For example, there are “kill-switches” on one side of the
phone that allow you to disable:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Mobile network and mobile data</li>
  <li>Wifi &amp; Bluetooth</li>
  <li>Camera &amp; Microphone</li>
</ul>

<p>There’s an additional feature where if you disable all three switches, then
other sensors on the phone such as GPS are all disabled as well. You’d be
better served reading through the <a href="https://puri.sm/products/librem-5">Librem 5 product
page</a> to learn more.</p>

<h2 id="pine64-pinephone">Pine64 Pinephone</h2>

<p>In contrast to the Librem 5, which touts itself as being privacy and security
focused, the <a href="https://www.pine64.org/pinephone/">Pinephone is touted as</a> “An
Open Source Smart Phone Supported by All Major Linux Phone Projects.” It is
considerably different from the Librem 5 in many ways, from the hardware all
the way to the final software. It too has kill-switches, but these are not easy
to access on the side of the phone and instead are inside the case of the
phone. You can access these kill-switches by removing the back plate.</p>

<p>One of the neat things about the Pinephone is the ability to boot and use a
variety of Linux distributions on the hardware itself. It’s as easy as loading
the distro onto an SD card, and then booting the phone. You don’t even have to
flash anything to the internal eMMC in order to run it!</p>

<h2 id="price-">Price $$$</h2>

<h3 id="librem-5">Librem 5</h3>

<p>The Librem 5 starts at $799.00 USD, or can be purchased at $1999.00 USD if you
want your Librem 5 assembled in the good ol’ US of A before they ship it to
you. There’s a lot of talk about anti-interdiction or controlling the supply
chain, but trust me in saying that you’re definitely not in the market for a
$2k phone like the Librem 5. I don’t know anyone who is.</p>

<p>I could probably write an entire post on the economics of this, but quite
frankly, it’s kind of appalling that literally anyone would pay this much. It’s
kind of appalling that Purism would charge this much. I can imagine a scheme
where the parts are shipped from China, and verified and assembled by a
part-time college student in the States and they’d likely still be able to
price it cheaper than $1999.00.</p>

<p>Anyways this post isn’t about Purism’s business practices, of which I will
comment on at some point, but regardless I will drop this matter here. Please
just don’t spend $1999.00 on a Librem 5.</p>

<p>And for that one person who will eventually claim they did purchase the
$1999.00 USA version and it was very necessary for their use case: <em>look buddy,
I get it, you’ve drank the Kool-Aid on this one but I’m sincerely doubtful that
your very specific concerns and use-case apply to even the general nerd who
gets excited about the intersection of FOSS and mobile hardware. Moreover, I’m
doubtful that even if they did apply to such a niche group that $2k is a price
point upon which you still don’t balk at and go look for literally anything
else.</em></p>

<hr>

<p>
<strong>Update (2020-12-08)</strong>:
</p>
<p>
Many wonderful people on Hacker News as well as the
Purism / Librem Matrix channels corrected me on the fact that part of the
reason that the phone is so expensive is due to the fact that the PCB is
fabricated in the States, in addition to the assembly.  I am still inclined to
believe that the price is rather exorbitant. Perhaps had the USA edition been
something that had been launched after Evergreen was completed I would be less
averse to the idea of it. Nonetheless, I still think that for the general
person reading this: you should not purchase it. You might argue that I don't
know your threat vector, but Bayes' theorem would suggest you will be better
served spending your money on a regular Librem 5 and putting the remaining
funds to something more important to you (like maybe an iPhone, so you can use
Signal while it is unavailable on the Librem 5 :-P).
</p>
<hr>

<p>I bought my Librem 5 back during the original crowdfunding campaign, so I ended
up spending a lot less than even the $799 USD. Surprisingly, I’ve been waiting
on this phone since around the end of 2017, and here we are in 2020 and I
finally have it. Purism has been sending out what are effectively <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Engineering_validation_test">DVT and
EVT</a> runs of the
phone that have been going through several phases named Aspen, Birch, Chestnut,
Dogwood, and finally Evergreen. Evergreen is supposed to be the final version
of the hardware, which I opted for. I wanted to get the final, true Librem 5,
not one that could be radically different. While my unit does not have FCC
certification (it is technically what you might consider a PVT unit), it is
representative of the final hardware that Purism will land on for this phone,
as there is ostensibly no more hardware revisions.</p>

<h3 id="pinephone">Pinephone</h3>

<p>The Pinephone starts at $149.99 USD, sold in small batches surrounding a
particular distro / community that is building software for the device (called
<code>&lt;distro-name&gt;</code> Community Edition). Recent batches have made a “convergence
edition” available, for $199.99 USD. The convergence editions have an extra
gigabyte of RAM and a larger eMMC flash storage, and are touted as being useful
for connecting the Pinephone to a full-size monitor and running it as if you
had a full desktop available.</p>

<p>I originally purchased a Pinephone from the UBPorts CE batch. Eventually, I
upgraded my mainboard so that my specs match that of the convergence editions
from later batches. All in all, I’ve managed to spend more than the original
$200, but I’m not disappointed, since I have had a lot of fun with the
Pinephone.</p>



<p>For the vast majority of people, the Librem 5 and Pinephone are probably not
worth even considering. The GNU userspace and associated “mobile” paradigms
within it are very much not ready for daily use.</p>

<p>For the Librem 5, there are some security aspects that this “security and
privacy focused phone” don’t even hit (e.g.  hardware backed security / secure
enclave, device encryption, etc.). That’s not to say that these can’t be made
possible in future updates, but as far as the software story today goes, they
do not yet exist.</p>

<p>
Small note: Hardware-backed features like the secure enclave do not exist on
the base phone today. However, there is a smart card reader and the M.2 slots
used for the SIM And wifi/bluetooth chipsets on board could be replaced as
well. That said, this isn't exactly in "buy an iPhone and guarantee your
physical security" territory, and there's no clear path to "do X steps to
enable this" yet.

Basically, don't be tricked by the marketing to believe this is somehow the
full package at present. It is not.
</p>

<p>Anyways, so why do I, the author, care? I will admit, after my first bout of
usage, neither phone will be a daily driver for me. I will probably continue to
stick to my Pixel 3, and it is very likely that I will eventually get another
Android device at some point in the next two years. Linux phones are definitely
not yet ready to be daily drivers; however, they are interesting for a few key
reasons.</p>

<h2 id="device-longevity">Device longevity</h2>

<p>Digital waste is a blight on our society. I can admit that the year-over-year
hardware cycle provides a vast set of improvements that can change the
smartphone landscape. However, I also acknowledge that the number of phones,
tablets, and other electronics that find their way into landfills or are
otherwise rendered into trash is a growing concern. Linux phones and mobile
hardware present an opportunity to move away from that, and it’s important to
support this in some way.</p>

<h2 id="free-software">Free software</h2>

<p>I’m a fan of free software! While my day job isn’t working on FOSS, I think
that there’s a lot of benefits to having better FOSS software available. The
least of which is because leaps in the mobile space have also attracted others
to work on Linux in the desktop space as well.</p>

<h2 id="a-third-option">A third option</h2>

<p>I care about Linux phones because they present a third option from the Android
/ iOS duopoly. Even if they suck now in (a lot of) ways, they will improve over
time. I want to move towards a future where I don’t have to choose between an
OS that’s built towards data collection and advertising, and another that’s
built on locking you into an ecosystem.</p>



<p>First, before I get into my impressions comparing the two, I should at the very
least mention what I am / am not testing. I did not / will not test:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Phone calls &amp; SMS / MMS functionality
    <ul>
      <li>I do not have a secondary mobile number, and my primary mobile number is
registered to an e-SIM on my Pixel 3. So the best I can do is test how
mobile data works on a data-only SIM.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Convergence features
    <ul>
      <li>I don’t really plan to use these as anything other than a mobile device, so
I haven’t bothered plugging them into a display. Additionally, my display
may be a bit too large and high-resolution for either phone to drive it
effectively.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Email
    <ul>
      <li>This one is still on my TODO list, however I’ve been too lazy to try
setting this up on several of the Pinephone’s possible distros.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Cameras
    <ul>
      <li>The Librem 5 does not yet have a functioning camera. For a phone to ship
with the hardware but no software… Well it’s not typical. So I can’t
compare anything, given that the Librem 5 hasn’t yet made it possible to do
so.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>GPS / location
    <ul>
      <li>Look, I want to do this more than …</li></ul></li></ul></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://thatgeoguy.ca/blog/2020/12/06/Librem-5-Evergreen-vs-Pinephone/">https://thatgeoguy.ca/blog/2020/12/06/Librem-5-Evergreen-vs-Pinephone/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thatgeoguy.ca/blog/2020/12/06/Librem-5-Evergreen-vs-Pinephone/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25338633</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 22:33:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Comp sci students drawn to classes on Sanskrit, a 3,500-year-old language]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25338546">thread link</a>) | @99_00
<br/>
December 7, 2020 | https://www.utoronto.ca/news/it-s-good-coding-computer-science-students-drawn-classes-sanskrit-3500-year-old-language | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.utoronto.ca/news/it-s-good-coding-computer-science-students-drawn-classes-sanskrit-3500-year-old-language">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  
      
  
  <div>
    <p><img height="269" width="268" data-delta="1" typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://www.utoronto.ca/sites/default/files/Libbie-Mills-IMG_1510-1-300s.jpg" alt="Libbie Mills"></p><p><strong>Libbie Mills</strong>, an assistant professor in the department for the study of religion in the University of Toronto’s&nbsp;Faculty of Arts &amp; Science, noticed something interesting this fall in her introductory Sanskrit class: computer science students.

</p>

<p>The course typically attracts students majoring in the study of religion, who are learning the language to further their research into Hinduism, Buddhism and Sikhism. Reading through her class list, however, Mills found that of six of the 40 enrolled students were actually computer science majors.&nbsp;</p>

<p>“I'm always excited when there are students from an unexpected place,” she says.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The lingual connection between Sanskrit and computer science, it turns out, has been the subject of interest for quite some time. The first well-known publication that examined the relationship was in 1985, when NASA scientist&nbsp;Rick Briggs&nbsp;published a research paper in which he argued that the 3,500-year-old language was the best candidate for programming artificial intelligence technology&nbsp;– namely because of its adherence to rigid grammatical rules.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Paul Thomas</strong>, a fourth-year undergraduate student at St. Michael’s College who plans on majoring in computer science next year, says he&nbsp;has a proclivity for learning languages, but ultimately took the course because of its connection to coding.</p>

<p>“Sanskrit is a very computational language,” he explains. “It’s a lot of syntax, which is the structure of programming itself. Classical Sanskrit is an engineered language.”</p>

<p>There are nearly 4,000 rules&nbsp;recorded in the fourth&nbsp;century BCE grammar of Pāṇini, an ancient scholar of the language&nbsp;– and&nbsp;Mill’s approach to teaching it is methodical.</p>

<p>“I'm a nerd” she says. “I like mathy type things, and I teach in a bit of a sciencey way.”</p>

<p>She stresses to her students that this is not a typical language class, where after a few classes they’ll be able to casually practise what they have learned over coffee.&nbsp;</p>

<p>“It’s not conversational, there’s too much to learn at the beginning,” she says. “They must learn the characters&nbsp;and how words get put together. It’s mind-bogglingly awful at first.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>She starts with what she calls the building blocks&nbsp;–&nbsp;“the order of sounds we produce out of our mouths ... from the throat to palate to teeth to lips” –&nbsp;and enthuses over the “tidiness of the language”, where a few root words are the basis of the entire Sanskrit vocabulary.</p>

<p>“It's orderly,” Mills says. “If you know the systems for making words you can work backward&nbsp;to the root to understand the meaning of the word. It’s creative in an organized way. It is kind of amazing.”</p>

<p>Mills adds that she&nbsp;understands the affinity that computer programmers have with the language. “It’s good coding,” she says.&nbsp;</p>

<p>For Thomas, the strict grammatical rules of Sanskrit&nbsp;align well&nbsp;with the goals of computer programmers who are ultimately interested in the “question of how to create interface between computers and human languages.”&nbsp; He maintains that Sanskrit is well positioned to do so because of its algorithmic foundation. “Computers don’t understand linguistics, they understand rules,” he says.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>In addition, the rigidity of Sanskrit makes it less likely that an artificial intelligence algorithm would misinterpret commands. The same can’t&nbsp;be said of a language like English, which is&nbsp;looser with its rules and where words have multiple meanings.</p>

<p>“In English, there are so many influences from different language streams,” Mills says. “It’s kind of a mess.”&nbsp;</p>
  </div>

  
  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.utoronto.ca/news/it-s-good-coding-computer-science-students-drawn-classes-sanskrit-3500-year-old-language</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25338546</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 22:25:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[German court forces mail provider Tutanota to insert a backdoor]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 239 | Comments 72 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25337507">thread link</a>) | @carlesfe
<br/>
December 7, 2020 | https://www.heise.de/news/Gericht-zwingt-Mailprovider-Tutanota-zu-Ueberwachungsfunktion-4972460.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.heise.de/news/Gericht-zwingt-Mailprovider-Tutanota-zu-Ueberwachungsfunktion-4972460.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

      <p>Tutanota gehÃ¶rt zu den wenigen E-Mail-Anbietern, die standardmÃ¤ÃŸig alle eingehenden Mails verschlÃ¼sseln. Ein Urteil des Landgerichts KÃ¶ln zwingt das hannoversche Unternehmen nun jedoch zum Einbau einer Funktion, mit der Ermittler einzelne PostfÃ¤cher Ã¼berwachen und Mails im Klartext lesen kÃ¶nnen.</p>

<a-paternoster height="360" media="(min-width: 320px) and (max-width: 767px)">
  


  


  <a-ad height="600" instant="" layout="fixed" media="(min-width: 320px) and (max-width: 767px)" preload-distance="200" safeframe="" sizes="300x600,300x50,300x75,300x100,300x150,300x250,320x50,320x75,320x100,320x250" targeting="{&quot;kw&quot;:[&quot;E-Mail&quot;,&quot;E-Mail-Provider&quot;,&quot;Gerichtsurteil&quot;,&quot;LKA&quot;,&quot;Tutanota&quot;,&quot;VerschlÃ¼sselung&quot;,&quot;Ãœberwachung&quot;],&quot;mpos&quot;:[&quot;understitial&quot;,&quot;top&quot;],&quot;themenhub&quot;:&quot;yes&quot;}" type="gpt" unit="/6514/www.heise.de/ct/ct-inhalt" width="300"></a-ad>

</a-paternoster>




<figure>
  <a href="https://www.heise.de/ct/" name="meldung.newsticker.inline.branding_ct" title="Mehr von c't Magazin">
    
  <a-img alt="Mehr von c't Magazin" height="693" high-dpi-quality="100" quality="100" src="/Magazin-Banner/ct_mobil.jpg" width="1200">
  </a-img>

  

    
  <a-img alt="Mehr von c't Magazin" height="500" high-dpi-quality="100" quality="100" src="/Magazin-Banner/ct_desktop.jpg" width="1830">
  </a-img>

  

  </a>
</figure>

<p>Tutanota will Beschwerde gegen den Beschluss einlegen, diese hat jedoch keine aufschiebende Wirkung. â€žWir mussten daher bereits mit der Entwicklung der Ãœberwachungsfunktion beginnenâ€œ, erklÃ¤rte eine Sprecherin Mitte November gegenÃ¼ber câ€™t. Sollte die Beschwerde Erfolg haben, werde man die Funktion nicht aktivieren beziehungsweise wieder entfernen.</p>
<h3 id="nav_abweichende__0">Abweichende Rechtssprechung</h3>
<p>Das KÃ¶lner Urteil ist bemerkenswert, weil es von der Rechtsprechung anderer Gerichte abweicht. So hatte im Sommer <a href="https://www.heise.de/news/Mailanbieter-Tutanota-Staatsanwaltschaft-wollte-Chef-in-Beugehaft-nehmen-4908806.html">das Landgericht Hannover entschieden</a>, dass Tutanota im rechtlichen Sinn keine â€žTelekommunikationsdiensteâ€œ erbringt oder daran mitwirkt â€“ und deshalb auch nicht zur TelekommunikationsÃ¼berwachung verpflichtet werden kann. Die hannoverschen Richter verwiesen wiederum auf ein Grundsatzurteil des EuropÃ¤ischen Gerichtshof (EuGH) von 2019. Diesem zufolge sind E-Mail-Dienste keine Kommunikationsdienste.</p>

  <a-script name="132" needs-consent="" src="https://a.teads.tv/page/87298/tag"></a-script>
  


<p>Das KÃ¶lner Gericht sieht Tutanota dennoch als â€žMitwirkendenâ€œ bei der Erbringung von Telekommunikationsdiensten. Folglich mÃ¼sse das Unternehmen die Ãœberwachung ermÃ¶glichen. Das Urteil, das câ€™t vorliegt, nennt allerdings weder den Namen noch den Betreiber des Telekommunikationsdienstes, an dem Tutanota angeblich mitwirkt. Aus Sicht des Unternehmens ist das Urteil deshalb â€žabsurdâ€œ.</p>
<h3 id="nav_lka_will__1">LKA will Postfach Ã¼berwachen</h3>






  


  <a-ad height="250" instant="" layout="responsive" media="(min-width: 320px) and (max-width: 767px)" preload-distance="200" safeframe="" sizes="300x50,300x75,300x100,300x150,300x250,320x50,320x75,320x100,320x250,fluid" targeting="{&quot;kw&quot;:[&quot;E-Mail&quot;,&quot;E-Mail-Provider&quot;,&quot;Gerichtsurteil&quot;,&quot;LKA&quot;,&quot;Tutanota&quot;,&quot;VerschlÃ¼sselung&quot;,&quot;Ãœberwachung&quot;],&quot;mpos&quot;:[&quot;2&quot;],&quot;themenhub&quot;:&quot;yes&quot;}" type="gpt" unit="/6514/www.heise.de/ct/ct-inhalt" width="300"></a-ad>



<p>In dem Fall geht es um eine Erpressungsmail, die von einem Tutanota-Postfach aus an einen Autozulieferer gesendet worden war. Tutanota sieht sich nun gezwungen, bis Jahresende eine Funktion zu programmieren, die es dem Landeskriminalamt Nordrhein-Westfalen ermÃ¶glicht, dieses Postfach zu Ã¼berwachen.</p>





  

<a-lightbox tabindex="1">
  
    

<figure>

  <div>
      <a href="https://www.heise.de/imgs/18/3/0/0/9/6/0/7/Tutonia-9fa96e1a083080c4.jpg">
      

<a-img alt="" height="1137" high-dpi-quality="70" layout="responsive" quality="85" src="/imgs/18/3/0/0/9/6/0/7/Tutonia-9fa96e1a083080c4.jpg" width="1800"></a-img>



      </a>
    

  </div>
    

<figcaption>    <p>Tutanota-Team: Der hannoversche Mailprovider versendet Mails Ende-zu-Ende-verschlÃ¼sselt und speichert auch das Postfach in verschlÃ¼sselter Form.</p>
      
        <p>
      (Bild:Â&nbsp;Tutao GmbH)
    </p>
</figcaption>

</figure>

  
</a-lightbox>




<p>FÃ¼r die anderen Nutzer soll sich dadurch nichts Ã¤ndern, ihre Mails sollen weiter standardmÃ¤ÃŸig verschlÃ¼sselt werden. Gleichwohl sieht Tutanota eine einmalige Umgehung der VerschlÃ¼sselung als Datenschutz- und Sicherheitsrisiko fÃ¼r letztlich alle Kunden an.</p>
<p><strong>[Update, 30.11., 12 Uhr]</strong> Wie Tutanota betonte, betrifft die ÃœberwachungsmaÃŸnahme nur die neu eingehenden unverschlÃ¼sselten E-Mails. Bereits verschlÃ¼sselte Daten sowie Ende-zu-Ende verschlÃ¼sselte E-Mails in Tutanota kann das Unternehmen nicht entschlÃ¼sseln.<strong> [Update]</strong></p>
<p>AuÃŸer Tutanota speichern auch einige andere Anbieter alle eingehenden Mails in verschlÃ¼sselter Form. Bei Protonmail ist das ebenfalls Standard, Posteo und Mailbox.org bieten die VerschlÃ¼sselung als Option an. Einen Ãœberblick Ã¼ber die Zahl der Anfragen von BehÃ¶rden gibt Tutanota in seinem <a href="https://tutanota.com/blog/posts/transparency-report/" rel="external noopener" target="_blank">Transparenzbericht</a>.</p>








<a-collapse media="(min-width: 993px)" sneak-peek="" toggle-class-on-media="a-box--full-bordered">
  
  <div data-collapse-target="">
    <div>
      
  <div data-collapse-content="">
    
      <figure>
        
  <a-img alt="" height="1000" high-dpi-quality="70" quality="85" src="/imgs/18/3/0/0/9/6/0/7/ct-2020-25-e065397de69d9c0b.jpg" width="707">
  </a-img>

  


        
      </figure>
    

    <div>

      
        <h4>c't 25/2020</h4><p>Dieser Artikel stammt aus <a href="https://www.heise.de/select/ct/2020/25">câ€™t 25/2020</a>. Darin liefert die Redaktion Auswahlhilfen fÃ¼r den TV-Kauf sowie einen Test von Smart-TVs. Jede Menge Handreichungen und ein Test aktueller E-Mail-Clients soll Ihnen helfen, in den tÃ¤glichen E-Mail-Fluten Oberwasser zu behalten. Beim Navi-Spezialist TomTom hat c't ein Datenleck aufgedeckt und sie analysiert die ÃœberwachungstÃ¼cken von Office 365. Dazu gibts viele weitere Tests und nicht zu vergessen eine TÃ¼te voller nerdiger Geschenketipps fÃ¼rs bevorstehende Weihnachtsfest. c't 25/2020 ist ab sofort <a href="https://shop.heise.de/c-t-25-2020" rel="external noopener" target="_blank">im Heise-Shop</a> und am gut sortierten Zeitschriftenkiosk erhÃ¤ltlich.</p>
      

      

      

    </div>
  </div>


    </div>
  </div>
  
</a-collapse>



<p>

<!-- RSPEAK_STOP -->
<span>(<a href="mailto:uk@ct.de" title="Ulrike Kuhlmann">uk</a>)</span>
<!-- RSPEAK_START -->
</p>

      <!-- RSPEAK_STOP -->

      

      

     

      

      <!-- RSPEAK_STOP -->

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.heise.de/news/Gericht-zwingt-Mailprovider-Tutanota-zu-Ueberwachungsfunktion-4972460.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25337507</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 21:05:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[FuzzOS – an operating system which is designed specifically for fuzzing]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 108 | Comments 18 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25336540">thread link</a>) | @URfejk
<br/>
December 7, 2020 | https://gamozolabs.github.io/fuzzing/2020/12/06/fuzzos.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://gamozolabs.github.io/fuzzing/2020/12/06/fuzzos.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>

<p>We’re going to work on an <em>operating system</em> which is designed specifically for fuzzing! This is going to be a streaming series for most of December which will cover making a new operating system with a strong focus on fuzzing. This means that things like the memory manager, determinism, and scalability will be the most important parts of the OS, and a lot of effort will go into making them super fast!</p>

<h2 id="when">When</h2>

<p>Streaming will start sometime on Thursday, December 10th, probably around 18:00 UTC, but the streams will be at relatively random times on relatively random days. I can’t really commit to specific times!</p>

<p>Streams will likely be 4-5 days a week (probably M-F), and probably 8-12 hours in length. We’ll see, who knows, depends how much fun we have!</p>

<h2 id="where">Where</h2>

<p>You’ll be able to find the streams live on my <a href="https://twitch.tv/gamozo">Twitch Channel</a>, and if you’re unlucky and miss the streams, you’ll be able to find the recordings on my <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/gamozolabs">YouTube Channel</a>! Don’t forget to like, comment, and subscribe, of course.</p>

<h2 id="what">What</h2>

<p>So… ultimately, I don’t really know what all will happen. But, I can predict a handful of things that we’ll do. First of all, it’s important to note that these streams are not training material. There is no prepared script, materials, flow, etc. If we end up building something totally different, that’s fine and we’re just going with the flow. There is no requirement of completing this project, or committing to certain ways the project will be done. So… with that aside.</p>

<p>We’ll be working on making an operating system, specifically for x86-64 (Intel flavor processors at the start, but AMD should work in non-hypervisor mode). This operating system will be designed for fuzzing, which means we’ll want to focus on making virtual memory management extremely fast. This is the backbone of most performant fuzzing, and we’ll need to be able to map in, unmap, and restore pages as they are modified by a fuzz case.</p>

<p>To keep you on the edge of your toes, I’ll first start with the boring things that we have to do.</p>

<h3 id="os">OS</h3>

<p>We have to make an operating system which boots. We’re gonna make a UEFI kernel, and we might dabble in running it on ARM64 as most of our code will be platform agnostic. But, who knows. It’ll be a pretty generic kernel, I’m mainly going to develop it on bare metal, but of course, we’ll make sure it runs on KVM/Xen/Hyper-V such that it can be used in a cloud environment.</p>

<h3 id="acpi">ACPI</h3>

<p>We’re gonna need to write ACPI table parsers such that we can find the NUMA locality of memory and CPUs on the system. This will be critical to getting a high performance memory manager that scales with cores.</p>

<h3 id="multi-processing">Multi-processing</h3>

<p>Of course, the kernel will support multiple cores, as otherwise it’s kinda useless for compute.</p>

<h3 id="10gbit-networking--tcp-stack">10gbit networking + TCP stack</h3>

<p>Since I never work with disks, I’m going to follow my standard model of just using the network as general purpose whatever. To do this, we’ll need 10gbit network drivers and a TCP stack such that we can communicate with the rest of a network. Nothing too crazy here, we’ll probably borrow some code from <a href="https://github.com/gamozolabs/chocolate_milk">Chocolate Milk</a></p>

<hr>

<h2 id="interesting-stuff">Interesting stuff</h2>

<p>Okay, that stuff was boring, lets talk about the fun parts!</p>

<h3 id="exotic-memory-model">Exotic memory model</h3>

<p>Since we’ll be “snapshotting” memory itself, we need to make sure things like pointers aren’t a problem. The fastest, easiest, and best solution to this, is simply to make sure the memory always gets loaded at the same address. This is no problem for a single core, but it’s difficult for multiple cores, as they need to have copies of the same data mapped at the same location.</p>

<p>What’s the solution? Well of course, we’ll have every single core on the system running it’s own address space. This means there is no shared memory between cores (with some very, very minor execeptions). Not only does this lead to execeptionally high memory access performance (due to caches only being in the exclusive or shared states), but it also means that shared (mutable) memory will not be a thing! This means that we’ll do all of our core synchronization through message passing, which is higher latency in the best case than shared memory models, but with an advantage of scaling much better. As long as our messages can be serialized to TCP streams, that means we can scale across the network without any effort.</p>

<p>This has some awesome properties since we no longer need any locks to our page tables to add and remove entries, nor do we need to perform any TLB shootdowns, which can cost tens thousands of cycles.</p>

<p>I used this model in <a href="https://gamozolabs.github.io/metrology/2019/08/19/sushi_roll.html">Sushi Roll</a>, and I really miss it. It had incredibly good performance properties and forced a bit more thought about sharing information between cores.</p>

<h3 id="scaling">Scaling</h3>

<p>As with most things I write, linear scaling will be required, and scaling across the network is just implied, as it’s required for really any realistic application of fuzzing.</p>

<h3 id="fast-and-differential-memory-snapshotting">Fast and differential memory snapshotting</h3>

<p>So far, none of these things are super interesting. I’ve had many OSes that do these things well, for fuzzing, for quite a long time. However, I’ve never made these memory management techniques into a true data structure, rather I use them as needed manually. I plan to make the core of this operating system, a combination of Rust procedural macros and virtual memory management tricks to allow for arbitrary data structure to be stored in a tree-shaped checkpointed structure.</p>

<p>This will allow for fast transitions between different state of the structure as they were snapshotted. This will be done by leveraging the dirty bits in the page tables, and creating an allocator that will allocate in a pool of memory which will be saved and restored on snapshots. This memory will be treated as an opaque blob internally, and thus it can hold any information you want, device state, guest memory state, register state, something completely unrelated to fuzzing, won’t matter. To handle nested structures (or more specifically, pointers in structures which are to be tracked), we’ll use a Rust procedural macro to disallow untracked pointers within tracked structures.</p>

<p>Effectively, we’re going to heavily leverage the hardware’s MMU to differentally snapshot, teleport between, and restore blobs of memory. For fuzzing, this is necessary as a way to hold guest memory state and register state. By treating this opaquely, we can focus on doing the MMU aspects really well, and stop worrying about special casing all these variables that need to be restored upon resets.</p>

<h3 id="linux-emulator">Linux emulator</h3>

<p>Okay, so all of that is kinda to make room for developing high performance fuzzers. In my case, I want this mainly for a new rewrite of vectorized emulation, but to make it interesting for others, we’re going to implement a Linux emulator capable of running QEMU.</p>

<p>This means that we’ll be able to (probably staticially only) compile QEMU. Then we can take this binary, and load it into our OS and run QEMU in our OS. This means we can control the syscall responses to the requests QEMU makes. If we do this deterministically (we will), this means QEMU will be deterministic. Which thus means, the guest inside of QEMU will also be deterministic. You see? This is a technique I’ve used in the past, and works exceptionally well. We’ll definitely outperform Linux’s handling of syscalls, and we’ll scale better, and we’ll blow Linux away when it comes to memory management.</p>

<h3 id="kvm-emulator--hypervisor">KVM emulator + hypervisor</h3>

<p>So, I have no idea how hard this would be, but from about 5 minutes of skimming the interwebs, it seems that I could pretty easily write a hypervisor in my OS that emulates KVM ioctls. Meaning QEMU would just think KVM is there, and use it!</p>

<p>This will give us full control of QEMU’s determinism, syscalls, performance, and reset speeds… without actually having to modify QEMU code.</p>

<h2 id="thats-it">That’s it</h2>

<p>So that’s the plan. An OS + fast MMU code + hypervisor + Linux emulator, to allow us to deterministically run anything QEMU can run, which is effectively everything. We’ll do this with performance likely into the millions of VM resets per second per core, scaling linearly with cores, including over the network, to allow some of the fastest general purpose fuzzing the world has ever seen :D</p>

<h2 id="faq">FAQ</h2>

<p>Some people have asked questions on the internet, and I’ll post them here:</p>

<h3 id="hackernews-q1">Hackernews Q1</h3>

<p>Q:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Huh. So my initial response was, "why on earth would you need a whole OS for that", but memory snapshotting and improved virtual memory performance might actually be a good justification. Linux does have CRIU which might be made to work for such a purpose, but I could see a reasonable person preferring to do it from a clean slate. On the other hand, if you need qemu to run applications (which I'm really unclear about; I can't tell if the plan is to run stuff natively on this OS or just to provide enough system to run qemu and then run apps on linux on qemu) then I'm surprised that it's not easier to just make qemu do what you want (again, I'm pretty sure qemu already has its own memory snapshotting features to build on).

Of course, writing an OS can be its own reward, too:) 
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>A:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Oooh, wasn't really expecting this to make it to HN cause it was meant to be more of an announcement than a description.

But yes, I've done about 7 or 8 operating systems for fuzzing in the past and it's a massive performance (and cleanliness) cleanup. This one is going to be like an operating system I wrote 2-3 years ago for my vectorized emulation work.

To answer your QEMU questions, the goal is to effectively build QEMU with MUSL (just to make it static so I don't need a dynamic loader), and modify MUSL to turn all syscalls to `call` instructions. This means a "syscall" is just a call to another area, which will by my Rust Linux emulator. I'll implement the bare minimum syscalls (and enum variants to those syscalls) to get QEMU to work, nothing more. The goal is not to run Linux applications, but run a QEMU+MUSL combination which may be modified lightly if it means a lower emulation burden …</code></pre></div></div></div></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://gamozolabs.github.io/fuzzing/2020/12/06/fuzzos.html">https://gamozolabs.github.io/fuzzing/2020/12/06/fuzzos.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://gamozolabs.github.io/fuzzing/2020/12/06/fuzzos.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25336540</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 20:00:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Evolution of my role as a founder CTO]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25336135">thread link</a>) | @coreyrab
<br/>
December 7, 2020 | https://miguelcarranza.es/cto | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://miguelcarranza.es/cto">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
  
  <p>There is a lot written about the importance of scaling as a founder in a fast-growing startup. Most of it focused on the CEO role. The generic advice on leadership also applies to other non-CEO roles, but I could not find a lot of content targeted to technical founders. In fact, after reading a <a href="https://twitter.com/elwatto/status/1230977002192031744?s=20" target="_blank">bunch of S-1 forms</a>, <strong>it was hard to find first-time CTOs going all the way from MVP to IPO</strong> (as opposed to founding CEOs). I found this fact really intriguing, and I wanted to dig deeper to try to understand the reasons. It was also stressing me out to some degree: <em>what if I don’t manage to scale fast enough? What does scaling even mean? I’d rather prepare before it becomes a real problem! I want to be the CTO who makes <a href="https://revenuecat.com/" target="_blank">RevenueCat</a> a public company!</em><sup>1</sup></p>

<p>Is it really much harder for non-CEO founders to scale quickly? Or perhaps it is that CEOs have a stronger support network. These could be the reasons. Or maybe I was asking the wrong question. After talking to a lot of founder CTOs, there was something clear: <strong>there is no standard definition for the CTO role</strong>, responsibilities will totally change <strong>depending on the company and the stage</strong>. At inception, the CTO is probably a glorified individual contributor, but this can escalate very quickly. Everyone’s experiences are different. Unfortunately, I don’t have the answers for other non-CEO founder roles, and maybe I don’t even have it for first-time CTOs either. However, I thought it would be a good self-awareness exercise to reflect on the things I’ve learned and how my responsibilities have changed during the first 3 years at <a href="https://revenuecat.com/" target="_blank">RevenueCat</a>.</p>

<h3 id="the-cto-vs-vp-of-engineering-dilemma">The CTO vs VP of Engineering dilemma</h3>
<p>Simplifying, we could say that the CTO role is closer to architecture and code; whereas the VPE would be in charge of processes and management. A simple analogy could be the Senior/Staff Engineer path versus the Engineering Management career path.</p>

<p>During the early days, you need a CTO to architect and coordinate a small group of ICs hacking the minimum viable product. At this stage, being a founder is extremely helpful to set the vision of the product and the engineering culture. Ideally, the CTO is a domain expert in the problem that the startup is trying to solve.</p>

<p>But what if the product becomes successful? What if you reach product-market fit? You will need to hire a lot more engineers to satisfy customer demands. That’s a great problem to have. You might get lucky and get funding, or you might even be profitable already. But a higher headcount means more polished processes. At some point, somebody will inevitably need to start wearing the VP of Engineering hat. It will happen, and it will become quite obvious as the previous (or lack of) processes start to break. You have a couple of options at this stage. The CTO can start acting as VPE, or you can hire externally. It is probably a matter of personal preference or previous management experience. But <strong>it is a totally different set of skills</strong>, which might be difficult to acquire in a hyper-growth environment. Therefore, most commonly, the VP of Engineering is <a href="https://www.saastr.com/makes-bad-cto/" target="_blank">hired externally</a>.</p>

<p>If you are a founder you have some flexibility. You might have control to decide which way you want to go. Perhaps you hate people management and want to keep using your technical skills and problem knowledge to influence the technology directly. Or maybe you want to improve your management skills. Early employees tend to be more forgiving about founder managerial flaws. They joined because they trusted the founders, believed in the vision, and know they have good intentions. In the beginning, they might even prefer you as a direct manager than an external person. But eventually, there will be several layers of management, so you better learn fast if you want to follow this path and don’t have the experience.</p>

<p>Bryan Helmig, Zapier’s co-founder and CTO, says you need to <a href="https://zapier.com/engineering/startup-cto/" target="_blank"><em>figure out where you get your dopamine hits</em></a>. Personally, I have always been more of a <em>computer person</em> than a <em>people person</em>. 
I was not sure which path I should take, but I would have bet on the one involving computers. I’ve always loved them, and I would say I am a better, more experienced engineer than I am a manager. I feel  more energized after shipping a new feature than during a one-on-one meeting.</p>

<p>However, as a founder, <strong>I get the dopamine hits when the company is doing well</strong>. When a customer recommends our product. When we hit the revenue goal. When we hire engineers that are better than me. When these engineers are happy and successfully shipping ambitious features. When code review is exhaustive but collaborative, not adversarial.</p>

<p>So, ultimately, I’ve taken the approach to not simply follow my personal preference, but to <strong>do whatever is more impactful for the company at each stage</strong>. I am a problem solver after all. That is how I have been thinking about my role. My <strong>founder identity should be more important than my CTO title</strong>. In the long run, as a major shareholder, I need to do whatever is best for the company.</p>

<p>Typically breaking points start happening <strong>somewhere between 8 and 12 engineers</strong>. But it can be different depending on the product and the environment. In our case, as a fully distributed company, we encountered several breaking points as we were adding new time zones. During this <em>no man’s land stage</em> most technical founders are temporarily forced to wear both CTO and VPE hats simultaneously. Being flexible turned out to be very advantageous. I tried to step up and (poorly and temporarily) do work that nobody had the bandwidth to do. This helped me to identify the pain points and tweak the process or hire somebody to take over these tasks.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="https://miguelcarranza.es/assets/posts/notebooks.jpeg" alt="RevenueCat journals">
</figure>

<p>One thing that helped me a lot to navigate my role was to learn how other founders were spending their time at each stage. I have been journaling since we started the company. Based on these notes, I will briefly describe the tasks I’ve been focused on and how my role has evolved.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Metrics (EOY)</th>
      <th>2018</th>
      <th>2019</th>
      <th>2020</th>
      <th>2021</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>Product Engineers</td>
      <td>2</td>
      <td>4</td>
      <td>8</td>
      <td>~18</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Total team size</td>
      <td>5</td>
      <td>9</td>
      <td>19</td>
      <td>~45</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Number of cities</td>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>5</td>
      <td>14</td>
      <td>??</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Number of time zones</td>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>3</td>
      <td>6</td>
      <td>??</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h2 id="2018-yc-mvp-and-first-hires">2018: YC, MVP, and first hires</h2>
<p>When we did Y-Combinator it was only <a href="https://twitter.com/jeiting" target="_blank">Jacob</a> and me. Jacob would write SDK and frontend code and I would focus on the backend and infrastructure. After YC we hired our first two engineers to take over Jacob’s coding responsibilities full time. We were all based in San Francisco and these hires were people we already knew. Easy (almost inexistent) management. <strong>There was no process overhead</strong>, we had one-week sprints and <strong>we were moving really fast</strong>.</p>

<p>These days were stressful but fun. We were setting the foundations of the engineering culture and seeing customers signing up one by one. Most of my time was spent architecting the initial version of features, listening to customers, and building their requests as fast as we humanly could. <strong>We would ship most requests on the same day</strong>.</p>

<p>My biggest concern here was making sure we were building something people wanted and the ability to keep growing to justify our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/24/revenuecat-seed-funding/" target="_blank">$1.5M seed round</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Main learnings</strong>: Too many, impossible to summarize. We learned a lot while doing Y-Combinator. The main thing would be that talking to customers, building what they want, and making them happy was paramount. We even made this and shipping fast two of our <a href="https://www.revenuecat.com/blog/values" target="_blank">core values</a>.</p>

<h2 id="2019-keeping-up-with-customers-and-scaling-the-tech">2019: Keeping up with customers and scaling the tech</h2>
<p>It looks like we had achieved some kind of product-market fit. <strong>Customers were coming to us, support tickets started piling up and our API throughput would increase every day</strong>. We added our first remote engineer, located in Taiwan. The time zone difference was hard initially and we needed to adapt processes. But it all worked out fine. We got better coverage for customer requests and monitoring.</p>

<p><strong>Onboarding was a complete, one-off manual process</strong>. I started doing one-on-ones (not very regularly, maybe once a month), but <strong>management was still pretty light</strong>. Most conversations were still very technical. I was still an individual contributor. I was also on booth duty at a couple of conferences.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="https://miguelcarranza.es/assets/posts/boothduty.JPG" alt="Booth Duty, AltConf 2019">
</figure>

<p>My main concern at this stage was purely technical: <strong>the scalability of our systems</strong>. All of our engineers had a more product-oriented background, and we had some clear single points of failure. Not going down was constantly in my mind. The scale was outgrowing my comfort zone every single day. We did a decent job optimizing the most common scenarios, <a href="https://www.revenuecat.com/blog/aurora-migration-zero-downtime" target="_blank">migrating infrastructure before reaching breaking points</a>, and <strong>paying down the technical debt we took the year before</strong>.</p>

<p>Up until Q4, I was the de-facto on-call engineer. I did not want to disturb other team members outside working hours, and I felt reliability was my ultimate responsibility as a technical founder. I would carry my laptop literally everywhere. Eventually, <strong>we implemented an on-call rotation, and in retrospect, we should have done it earlier</strong>.</p>

<p><strong>Main learnings</strong>: Do not stress over scalability, but monitor as much as possible and always look out for the next bottleneck and single point of failure. Again, these are stressful but great problems to have. Establish an on-call policy as soon as possible, train engineers, and document resolution for known incidents. Rely on your team. <a href="https://miguelcarranza.es/technical-debt" target="_blank">Technical debt is actually good</a> if taken responsibly while trying to find product-market fit.</p>

<h2 id="2020-delegation-and-planning-the-future-organization">2020: Delegation and planning the future organization</h2>
<p>In 2020 we doubled the team again. We added engineers in Europe and Latin America. By the end of the year, we had multiple members in every team (SDK, frontend, backend…). We were able to work on several projects at the same time, and finally tackle more ambitious features. But we needed more coordination. <strong>A little bit of management structure was unavoidable at this stage.</strong></p>

<p>During Q1 and Q2 I spent most of my time reviewing code, providing architectural guidance, and coding a little bit on the side. I was still the person who had more context about our systems. By mid-year, it became very obvious that I was the bottleneck for …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://miguelcarranza.es/cto">https://miguelcarranza.es/cto</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://miguelcarranza.es/cto</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25336135</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 19:33:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Road to Rome: Fundraising and Project Goals]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25335731">thread link</a>) | @bpierre
<br/>
December 7, 2020 | https://rome.tools/funding/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rome.tools/funding/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main-content"> <section>  <section> <h2 id="introduction">Introduction <a href="#introduction" aria-label="introduction"></a></h2>  <p>I’m Sebastian McKenzie, the creator of <a href="https://babeljs.io/">Babel</a> and <a href="https://yarnpkg.com/">Yarn</a>. These tools have both inspired me to create Rome, a new project that aims to simplify and improve JavaScript and web development.</p> <p>Rome consolidates dozens of separate tools into one. Rome can install your dependencies, check your code for errors, run your tests, bundle your code, and more, all via a single CLI. Rome will be able to replace Babel, ESLint, Prettier, Yarn, and webpack. <a href="https://rome.tools/">Learn more</a>.</p> <p>It’s been three months since we announced our initial <a href="https://rome.tools/blog/2020/08/08/introducing-rome.html">beta release</a>. Since then, we’ve received a tremendous amount of enthusiasm from the community. As that enthusiasm has grown, it’s become clear that Rome will require a full-time developer to be successful and deliver on our ambitious goals and release a stable v1.0.</p> <p><strong>I need your help to make it a reality.</strong></p> </section> <section> <h2 id="funding">Funding <a href="#funding" aria-label="funding"></a></h2> <p>I have left my job so I can work independently and focus on what the community needs. This includes a <a href="#allow-users-to-extend-functionality-with-plugins">plugin system</a>, <a href="#add-more-configuration-and-have-less-opinions">more configuration</a>, and <a href="#integrate-with-existing-tools">dedicated integrations for existing tools</a>.</p> <p>We have an initial goal of <strong>$100,000</strong>. This will allow myself to work independently on our first stable release. Additional funding would allow us to expand upon our release goals, fund future maintenance, and compensate other contributors.</p> <p>If you’re passionate about what we’re building, or have otherwise benefited from my work, I would appreciate your financial support.</p>    <section> <h3 id="recent-contributions">Recent Contributions <a href="#recent-contributions" aria-label="recent-contributions"></a></h3> <ul> <li>Loading...</li> </ul> </section> <section> <h3 id="contribute">Contribute <a href="#contribute" aria-label="contribute"></a></h3> <p>Prices are in USD. Includes sales tax and international shipping. Refer to <a href="#questions-and-answers">Questions and Answers</a> for more information.</p> <p> Loading... </p> <div> <h4>Custom</h4> <p>Want to donate under $10? Something else? Select your own amount!</p>  </div> <section> <h4 id="business">Business <a href="#business" aria-label="business"></a></h4> <p>These tiers include dedicated support, migration assistance, and website advertisement. I’ll make sure Rome works well for you and your organization.</p> <p>Migration support is where I personally help your organization adopt and use Rome. This could include porting configuration, integrating with CI, or even adding new features and configuration to Rome.</p> <p>Interested in something else or have questions? Get in touch at <a href="https://rome.tools/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#582b3d3a392b2c313936182a37353d762c3737342b"><span data-cfemail="aeddcbcccfdddac7cfc0eedcc1c3cb80dac1c1c2dd">[email&nbsp;protected]</span></a>!</p> <p> Loading... </p> </section> </section> </section> <section> <h2 id="goals">Goals <a href="#goals" aria-label="goals"></a></h2> <p>Funding will allow us to focus on usage and labor-intensive goals. We can make Rome easier to use and work for more people.</p> <section> <h3 id="add-more-configuration-and-have-less-opinions">Add more configuration and have less opinions <a href="#add-more-configuration-and-have-less-opinions" aria-label="add-more-configuration-and-have-less-opinions"></a></h3> <p>We have deliberately tried to keep configuration to a minimum. While this does produce a minimal API surface, it makes it almost impossible to easily migrate without losing functionality or changing conventions.</p> <p>We should aim to reduce the functional differences between Rome and other tools by introducing additional configuration and supported languages. This could include:</p> <ul> <li>Code formatting options</li> <li>Ability to customize expected filenames and directories</li> <li>Support for other configuration languages such as YAML and TOML</li> <li>More CLI flags</li> <li>Public JavaScript API</li> <li>Dynamic configuration (as opposed to static JSON-only configuration files)</li> <li><a href="#allow-users-to-extend-functionality-with-plugins">Allow extending functionality with plugins</a></li> </ul> <p>We have so far kept configuration light, as by reducing the amount of configuration options supported, we reduce maintenance cost and the potential for internal bugs.</p> <p>While this makes it easier for us as maintainers, it makes it drastically more difficult for users. No matter how persuasive our arguments may be for why you should use hard tabs instead of spaces, they seem like artificial and arbitrary constraints and introduces excessive prerequisites for adoption.</p> <p>Strong defaults and guided documentation for new users can provide the experience we ultimately want to offer, while removing our existing adoption restrictions.</p> </section> <section> <h3 id="integrate-with-existing-tools">Integrate with existing tools <a href="#integrate-with-existing-tools" aria-label="integrate-with-existing-tools"></a></h3> <p>Rome attempts to replace many tools. However we should still strive to support scenarios where another tool is better situated or preferred. This can also help during a migration where Rome is used in conjunction with another tool. We can do this in a couple of ways:</p> <p><strong>Integrating Rome as a first-class plugin in tools such as Babel, eslint, and webpack</strong></p> <p>Rome could be exposed as a plugin for those tools to allow you to adopt the Rome compiler without having to adopt the bundler first. This would reduce adoption prerequisites and allow easier experimentation inside of existing setups.</p> <p><strong>Seamlessly integrate other tools into Rome</strong></p> <p>We can introduce compatibility layers to have ESLint, Babel, and other tools run inside of Rome itself. ESLint errors could be displayed alongside Rome linter errors with the same UI and output format Instantly you could benefit from Rome’s file caching and parallelisation without needing a major migration.</p> </section> <section> <h3 id="assist-in-migrating-from-existing-tools">Assist in migrating from existing tools <a href="#assist-in-migrating-from-existing-tools" aria-label="assist-in-migrating-from-existing-tools"></a></h3> <p>It should be easy to migrate from other tools to Rome. First we need to ensure popular configuration options from other tools are supported. Then, offer automated tools to migrate basic setups without users needing to it manually.</p> <p>This needs to be accompanied with dedicated documentation and guides that can explain the differences between the tools, why you might want to use one over the other, similar concepts, new terminology, and equivalent config options.</p> </section> <section> <h3 id="allow-users-to-extend-functionality-with-plugins">Allow users to extend functionality with plugins <a href="#allow-users-to-extend-functionality-with-plugins" aria-label="allow-users-to-extend-functionality-with-plugins"></a></h3> <p>One of the fears with Rome is creating a monoculture where it’s impossible to innovate and experiment with new ideas. While it’s extremely optimistic to think we’ll ever get into any sort of monopolistic position, not allowing extensions does stiffle innovation regardless of our market position by restricting the viability and adoption of new ideas.</p> <p>Plugins allow us to avoid supporting functionality that we might not want, while still giving users a choice. It reduces our role as an arbiter and allows new languages, non-standard JavaScript features, code conventions, and ideas that interact with Rome to be viable, receive support, and proliferate.</p> <p>We need to be extremely careful not to get into the position where Babel and Webpack are today, where they’re heavily restricted by the usage of internal APIs. We need to be able to maintain our autonomy when it comes to making architectural changes. Balancing this with a powerful plugin API will be a challenge and will likely require several iterations.</p> </section> <section> <h3 id="release-undocumented-features">Release undocumented features <a href="#release-undocumented-features" aria-label="release-undocumented-features"></a></h3> <p>Rome currently does a lot more than linting. It’s a major challenge today to market and explain Rome when so much of the project isn’t officially supported. While we strive to make each individual component of Rome competitive on it’s own, to some the biggest advantage and compelling reason for using Rome might be the reduction in dependencies.</p> <p>We should focus on releasing and maturing basic versions of all core functionality. This would increase user confidence in our architecture and show that Rome is viable as the comprehensive replacement that we want to be.</p> </section> <section> <h3 id="provide-accessible-and-comprehensive-documentation">Provide accessible and comprehensive documentation <a href="#provide-accessible-and-comprehensive-documentation" aria-label="provide-accessible-and-comprehensive-documentation"></a></h3> <p>Documentation for developer tools is generally quite obtuse and relies a lot on prerequisite knowledge. This can make it intimidating and inaccessible for developers new to the ecosystem. Further complicating that is the broad scope of what Rome is trying to do.</p> <p>We have tried to address some of this by making our documentation a single page. This makes it easy to search, and it can be read from top to bottom without needing to jump around to learn about different concepts. However as our supported features grow, it will be more difficult to use this structure without oversimplifcation and doesn’t allow different paths for different demographics.</p> <p>We need to invest in a more scalable approach for our documentation. We can offer dedicated sections that explain features like linting end-to-end without needing to introduce other components like the compiler and bundler that contain significantly more concepts and overwhelm the reader. Separate guides can be offered for new users and those already experienced with other tools to properly cater for multiple audiences.</p> </section> <section> <h3 id="regularly-release-new-versions">Regularly release new versions <a href="#regularly-release-new-versions" aria-label="regularly-release-new-versions"></a></h3> <p>One of the reasons Babel was successful is how quickly I was able to quickly fix bugs and release new versions. I would regularly have releases out within minutes of a bug report. This was critical during the early days when adoption was low. Being able to unblock users quickly would often make them more excited to use Babel even though they ran into a bug.</p> <p>Similarly, we should try and replicate this by building out our release infrastructure to allow the rapid testing and release of versions. We need to maintain momentum as the scope of supported features grow.</p> <p>We can achieve this with automated releases that can be manually triggered or deployed on a schedule. Automatic changelog generation would also take a lot of the manual work out of producing releases. Nightly releases would allow users to test experimental features and provide early feedback.</p> </section> </section> <section> <h2 id="questions-and-answers">Questions and Answers <a href="#questions-and-answers" aria-label="questions-and-answers"></a></h2> <section> <h3 id="when-will-physical-rewards-be-shipped">When will physical rewards be shipped? <a href="#when-will-physical-rewards-be-shipped" aria-label="when-will-physical-rewards-be-shipped"></a></h3> <p>We are tentatively aiming for the end of April 2021, however due to COVID delays or order volume this could be extended. We’ll make sure to keep you updated via email.</p> </section> <section> <h3 id="what-is-my-email-used-for">What is my email used for? <a href="#what-is-my-email-used-for" aria-label="what-is-my-email-used-for"></a></h3> <p>We use your email address to send information about your order such as order questions, shipping status and delays. We may also send a survey to decide on customization options for rewards.</p> <p>Your email address will not be used for any other purpose or be displayed publicly.</p> </section> <section> <h3 id="how-is-payment-information-stored">How is payment information stored? <a href="#how-is-payment-information-stored" aria-label="how-is-payment-information-stored"></a></h3> <p>Payment information is entered and stored via Stripe. We do not have access to full payment details. Your billing address is used if we need to calculate and pay sales tax in your jurisdiction.</p> </section> <section> <h3 id="what-do-tier-prices-include">What do tier prices include? <a href="#what-do-tier-prices-include" aria-label="what-do-tier-prices-include"></a></h3> <p>Prices include processing fees, international shipping, and sales tax. This does mean the effective donation is reduced if you live in a country with import duty or high shipping cost.</p> <p>You have the option to add an additional donation in the order review screen if you would like to cover those costs.</p> </section> <section> <h3 id="why-do-you-need-my-usernames">Why do you need my usernames? <a href="#why-do-you-need-my-usernames" aria-label="why-do-you-need-my-usernames"></a></h3> <p>Usernames are used to allocate tier rewards. They are not required and you can …</p></section></section></section></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://rome.tools/funding/">https://rome.tools/funding/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rome.tools/funding/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25335731</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 19:00:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why I Love Tailwind]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 252 | Comments 276 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25332101">thread link</a>) | @theBashShell
<br/>
December 7, 2020 | https://mxstbr.com/thoughts/tailwind/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://mxstbr.com/thoughts/tailwind/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px"><a target="_blank" rel="noopener" to="https://tailwindcss.com" href="https://tailwindcss.com/" color="blue">Tailwind</a> is an atomic CSS framework that has taken the frontend world by storm. It gives developers without a deep understanding of design the ability to build visually gorgeous, modern user interfaces. </p><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px">If you have not seen it before, here is the canonical Tailwind example from their original homepage:</p><pre font-size="15px"><code font-size="15px"><span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span> <span>class</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>shadow-lg flex bg-white rounded-lg p-6 leading-normal<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>img</span> <span>class</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>h-24 w-24 rounded-full mx-auto mx-0 mr-6<span>"</span></span> <span>src</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>avatar.jpg<span>"</span></span> <span>/&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span> <span>class</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>text-center text-left<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span>
    <span><span><span>&lt;</span>h1</span> <span>class</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>text-lg<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span>Erin Lindford<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>h1</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
    <span><span><span>&lt;</span>h2</span> <span>class</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>text-purple-500<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span>Customer Support<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>h2</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
    <span><span><span>&lt;</span>p</span> <span>class</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>text-gray-600<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span>erinlindford@example.com<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>p</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
    <span><span><span>&lt;</span>p</span> <span>class</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>text-gray-600<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span>(555) 765-4321<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>p</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
</code></pre><div><p><img alt="Avatar of Erin Lindford" src="https://randomuser.me/api/portraits/women/17.jpg"></p><div><p>Erin Lindford</p><p>Customer Support</p><p>erinlindford@example.com</p><p>(555) 765-4321</p></div></div><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px">Many people think Tailwind is cool because it uses atomic CSS. Here is the thing though: <strong>Tailwind is awesome <em>despite</em> using atomic CSS, not because of it</strong>.</p><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px">Hear me out.</p><h3 font-family="system" font-size="4" font-weight="bold">The key to Tailwind</h3><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px">We have had <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" to="https://github.com/basscss/basscss/commit/ed65eec980c4899d930f2c293f70bc619573456f" href="https://github.com/basscss/basscss/commit/ed65eec980c4899d930f2c293f70bc619573456f" color="blue">atomic</a> <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" to="https://github.com/tachyons-css/tachyons/commit/7f27af8d52d8ed03615e23a9db5ff33fc8153729" href="https://github.com/tachyons-css/tachyons/commit/7f27af8d52d8ed03615e23a9db5ff33fc8153729" color="blue">CSS</a> <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" to="https://medium.com/buzzfeed-design/introducing-solid-1c16b1bf4868" href="https://medium.com/buzzfeed-design/introducing-solid-1c16b1bf4868" color="blue">frameworks</a> for almost a decade but none of them have been as critically acclaimed as Tailwind. What makes it different?</p><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px"><strong>The key to Tailwind's popularity is the painstakingly constructed system of design tokens at the core of the framework.</strong> The system's carefully selected constraints give developers <em>just</em> the right guardrails. They make it obvious whether a choice is good or bad by offering only discrete steps.</p><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px">This does require some design <em>taste</em>, but most frontend engineers I know have developed that over the years of building user interfaces. Tailwind's system lets them turn that taste into implementation without requiring a lot of design <em>skill</em> — it helps them cross <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" to="https://vimeo.com/85040589" href="https://vimeo.com/85040589" color="blue">"the gap"</a>.</p><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px">Tailwind's system is a masterpiece of design. I, and many other developers all around the world, feel empowered by and love it.</p><h3 font-family="system" font-size="4" font-weight="bold">The problem with Tailwind</h3><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px">The atomic CSS framework is basically a delivery mechanism that allows developers to apply the system to their UIs. It's undeniable that it has a fantastic developer experience: once you get used to the custom vocabulary you feel like you are flying!</p><ul><li><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px">Users still have to add a separate setup for the <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" to="https://twitter.com/kentcdodds/status/1240868842361913347" href="https://twitter.com/kentcdodds/status/1240868842361913347" color="blue">custom CSS they inevitably need</a> (coined <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" to="https://twitter.com/samselikoff/status/1251637275412357121" href="https://twitter.com/samselikoff/status/1251637275412357121" color="blue">"bailwind"</a>). You cannot get by on <em>just</em> Tailwind in the real world. Not having a dedicated place for custom styles in the same system can cause maintenance issues down the line.</p></li><li><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px">Due to file-size considerations, <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" to="https://tailwindcss.com/docs/hover-focus-and-other-states#default-variants-reference" href="https://tailwindcss.com/docs/hover-focus-and-other-states#default-variants-reference" color="blue">Tailwind does not include all variants</a> (e.g. <code font-size="2">hover:</code>, <code font-size="2">sm:</code>) for all utilities by default. It leaves it to you to manually configure which ones you need for every single CSS property.</p></li><li><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px">Atomic CSS is not ideal for performance. No tooling can extract the <em>per-page</em> critical CSS, so you end up shipping more CSS to the browser than necessary. The bigger and more dynamic the app, the more unnecessary code you will ship.<sup id="fnref-1"><a href="https://mxstbr.com/thoughts/tailwind/#fn-1" color="blue">1</a></sup></p></li></ul><h3 font-family="system" font-size="4" font-weight="bold">Tailwind without the downsides</h3><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px">Brent Jackson, the creator of one of the original atomic CSS libraries, said it best in <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" to="https://jxnblk.com/blog/two-steps-forward/" href="https://jxnblk.com/blog/two-steps-forward/" color="blue">his post on atomic CSS</a>:</p><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px">“This methodology was created before React was released and was intended for use in template-based user interfaces, including Rails and PHP. It was never designed for functional component-based UI and doesn't take advantage of this new paradigm.”</p><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px">Now, here is the thing: you can have your cake and eat it too. You can use Tailwind's marvelous system and fantastic developer experience without the downsides of atomic CSS.</p><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px">Let me illustrate. Here is the canonical Tailwind example built with <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" to="https://github.com/ben-rogerson/twin.macro" href="https://github.com/ben-rogerson/twin.macro" color="blue">twin.macro</a> and React:</p><pre font-size="15px"><code font-size="15px"><span>import</span> <span>"twin.macro"</span>

<span>const</span> <span>Card</span> <span>=</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>(</span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span> <span>tw</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>shadow-lg md:flex bg-white rounded-lg p-6 leading-normal<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span><span>
    </span><span><span><span>&lt;</span>img</span> <span>tw</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>h-16 w-16 md:h-24 md:w-24 rounded-full mx-auto md:mx-0 md:mr-6<span>"</span></span> <span>src</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>avatar.jpg<span>"</span></span> <span>/&gt;</span></span><span>
    </span><span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span> <span>tw</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>text-center md:text-left<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span><span>
      </span><span><span><span>&lt;</span>h1</span> <span>tw</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>text-lg<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span><span>Erin Lindford</span><span><span><span>&lt;/</span>h1</span><span>&gt;</span></span><span>
      </span><span><span><span>&lt;</span>h2</span> <span>tw</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>text-purple-500<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span><span>Customer Support</span><span><span><span>&lt;/</span>h2</span><span>&gt;</span></span><span>
      </span><span><span><span>&lt;</span>p</span> <span>tw</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>text-gray-600<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span><span>erinlindford@example.com</span><span><span><span>&lt;/</span>p</span><span>&gt;</span></span><span>
      </span><span><span><span>&lt;</span>p</span> <span>tw</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>text-gray-600<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span><span>(555) 765-4321</span><span><span><span>&lt;/</span>p</span><span>&gt;</span></span><span>
    </span><span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span><span>
  </span><span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
<span>)</span>
</code></pre><div><p><img alt="Avatar of Erin Lindford" src="https://randomuser.me/api/portraits/women/17.jpg"></p><div><h2>Erin Lindford</h2><p>Customer Support</p><p>erinlindford@example.com</p><p>(555) 765-4321</p></div></div><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px">Unsurprisingly, the result looks identical — we are still using the same system after all. Even the code looks the same, except that we use the <code font-size="2">tw</code> prop instead of the <code font-size="2">class</code> attribute!</p><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px">However, under the hood this automatically compiles the class names to the actual CSS they refer to (with <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" to="https://medium.com/styled-components/announcing-native-support-for-the-css-prop-in-styled-components-245ca5252feb" href="https://medium.com/styled-components/announcing-native-support-for-the-css-prop-in-styled-components-245ca5252feb" color="blue">the css prop</a>):</p><pre font-size="15px"><code font-size="15px"><span>import</span> <span>"twin.macro"</span>

<span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span> <span>tw</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>text-center md:text-left<span>"</span></span> <span>/&gt;</span></span>



<span>import</span> <span>"styled-components/macro"</span>

<span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span> 
  <span>css</span><span><span>=</span><span>{</span><span>{</span>
    textAlign<span>:</span> <span>"center"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"@media (min-width: 768px)"</span><span>:</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>"textAlign"</span><span>:</span><span>"left"</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span><span>}</span></span>
<span>/&gt;</span></span>
</code></pre><ul><li><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px">Extending your elements with custom styles is as simple as using the css prop, no extra separate setup required to "bailwind":</p><pre font-size="15px"><code font-size="15px"><span>import</span> <span>"twin.macro"</span>

<span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span>
  <span>tw</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>text-center md:text-left<span>"</span></span>
  <span>css</span><span><span>=</span><span>{</span><span>{</span><span><span>`
    &amp;:hover { 
      background-image: url("/bg.png");
    }
  `</span></span><span>}</span><span>}</span></span>
<span>/&gt;</span></span>
</code></pre></li><li><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px">You can use all variants in all combinations with all utilities allowing for even more expression within the system. Since twin.macro runs at build-time, you don't have to worry about configuration or file size:</p><pre font-size="15px"><code font-size="15px"><span>import</span> <span>"twin.macro"</span>

<span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span> <span>tw</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>sm:hover:first:bg-black<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span><span>...</span><span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
</code></pre></li><li><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px">You get fully automatic critical CSS extraction and code splitting. Users will only load exactly the styles they need for the page they requested — nothing more and nothing less! CSS performance does not get better.<sup id="fnref-1"><a href="https://mxstbr.com/thoughts/tailwind/#fn-1" color="blue">1</a></sup></p></li></ul><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px">The ideal setup for both developer <em>and</em> user experience!</p><div display="block"><div><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px"><strong>Lesson</strong>: <!-- -->use <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" to="https://github.com/ben-rogerson/twin.macro" href="https://github.com/ben-rogerson/twin.macro" color="blue">twin.macro</a> to leverage Tailwind's marvelous system and developer experience without the downsides of atomic CSS.</p></div></div><p font-family="system" color="#333" font-size="18px">Rather than taking two steps forward with Tailwind's system and one step backward with atomic CSS, let's take five steps forward. Together.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://mxstbr.com/thoughts/tailwind/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25332101</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 13:56:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Is Stencil a Better React?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 81 | Comments 56 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25331909">thread link</a>) | @yoava
<br/>
December 7, 2020 | https://www.wix.engineering/post/is-stencil-a-better-react | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.wix.engineering/post/is-stencil-a-better-react">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-hook="post-description"><article><div><div data-rce-version="8.7.1"><div dir="ltr"><div><div id="viewer-9ud64"><div><div data-hook="imageViewer" role="button" tabindex="0"><div role="img"><p><img data-pin-url="https://www.wix.engineering/post/is-stencil-a-better-react" data-pin-media="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_7ba678e807d947b0a64706b33bc23f72~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000%2Ch_1000%2Cal_c%2Cq_80/file.png" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_7ba678e807d947b0a64706b33bc23f72~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_300,h_300,al_c,q_5/file.jpg"></p></div></div></div></div><p id="viewer-coc16"><span>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@joshcala?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Josh Calabrese</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Unsplash</a></span></p><p id="viewer-8u5rt"><span><span>Recently I went looking for ways to code web components and found this great post - “</span><a href="https://webcomponents.dev/blog/all-the-ways-to-make-a-web-component/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span><u>All the Ways to Make a Web Component - October 2020 Update</u></span></a><span>”. It lists ~30 libraries for creating web components, comparing code style, performance and bundle size. One of the libraries got me intrigued - Stencil - which looks very promising and has lots of stars on GitHub - about 8.6k.</span></span></p><p id="viewer-m0td"><span><a href="https://stenciljs.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span><u>Stencil</u></span></a><span> is a React-inspired web component library. It is using the same JSX as React and some of the same concepts (Render function, props, state). However, Stencil differs as it compiles to an optimal bundle, creating Virtual DOM that is consolidated directly into the DOM itself (no VDOM to VDOM comparison). The result is standard web components with optimal performance.</span></span></p><p id="viewer-876ce"><span><span>On top, Stencil provides good development experience through their template applications - for building a component, a website / app or a PWA. Stencil also supports server-side rendering and hydrations for websites that need to be optimized for indexing.</span></span></p><p id="viewer-4f7v9"><span><span>To learn Stencil, we decided to build yet another version of </span><a href="http://todomvc.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span><u>TodoMVC</u></span></a><span>. TodoMVC is a great platform to compare different javascript libraries - it </span>exposes<span> 54 Javascript UI libraries on one simple use case - a Todo list application. Each application has to look exactly the same, with the same functionality - adding a todo item, marking an item as complete, removing completed items, etc. Every instance of the application needs to be persistent with local storage and feature routing for display all, active or completed todos, and so on. </span></span></p><p id="viewer-5ab1d"><span><span>Here is an example of a TodoMVC application:</span></span></p><div id="viewer-9kpfo"><div><div data-hook="imageViewer" role="button" tabindex="0"><div role="img"><p><img data-pin-url="https://www.wix.engineering/post/is-stencil-a-better-react" data-pin-media="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_451dfe597f8c4a3e99ebd9013facd90f~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000%2Ch_1000%2Cal_c%2Cq_80/file.png" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_451dfe597f8c4a3e99ebd9013facd90f~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_300,h_300,al_c,q_5/file.png"></p></div></div></div></div><p id="viewer-5isi0"><span><span>In this article we share what we’ve learned from building a TodoMVC application using Stencil.</span></span></p><p id="viewer-7pffh"><span><span>Our finished copy of the complete Stencil TodoMVC application is on GithuB: </span></span></p><ul><li id="viewer-2ajfe"><p><span>Github pages - </span><a href="https://yoavaa.github.io/stencil-todo-mvc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span><u>demo</u></span></a> </p></li><li id="viewer-504l8"><p><span>Github </span><a href="https://github.com/yoavaa/stencil-todo-mvc" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span><u>repo</u></span></a> </p></li><li id="viewer-6isa4"><p><span>Pull request for TodoMVC is </span><a href="https://github.com/tastejs/todomvc/pull/2130" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span><u>here</u></span></a><span>.</span></p></li></ul><p id="viewer-df9em"><span><span>Here’s an equivalent React TodoMVC application for reference:</span></span></p><ul><li id="viewer-e9k4l"><p><a href="http://todomvc.com/examples/react/#/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span><u>TodoMVC React Example</u></span></a></p></li></ul><p id="viewer-ce1qk"><span><span>Just for the fun of it, we also added a </span><a href="https://svelte.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span><u>Svelte</u></span></a><span> TodoMVC application for the performance comparison</span></span></p><ul><li id="viewer-acl7k"><p><a href="http://svelte-todomvc.surge.sh/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span><u>Svelte TodoMVC Example</u></span></a></p></li></ul><p id="viewer-8a90"><span><span>A side note on Svelte - that’s another framework we’ve considered in the past and one we’re following closely today. Our Wix Engineering podcast did a whole episode on Svelte, speaking to its creator and Wix devs. You can listen to it </span><a href="https://www.wix.engineering/podcast/episode/8fd2ff59/wix-engineering-podcast-outmatched-how-svelte-beats-the-odds" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span><u>here</u></span></a><span> and read the full podcast transcript </span><a href="https://www.wix.engineering/post/how-svelte-beats-the-odds-e04-full-transcript" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span><u>here</u></span></a><span>. Now back to Stencil.</span></span></p><p id="viewer-b0csu"><span><span>To get started building TodoMVC with Stencil, we first need to create a dev project.</span></span></p><div id="viewer-blmkj"><div><div data-hook="imageViewer" role="button" tabindex="0"><div role="img"><p><img data-pin-url="https://www.wix.engineering/post/is-stencil-a-better-react" data-pin-media="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_ebdf4b650aee451cbe398b706ce36c6b~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000%2Ch_304%2Cal_c%2Cq_80/file.png" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_ebdf4b650aee451cbe398b706ce36c6b~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_300,h_300,al_c,q_5/file.png"></p></div></div></div></div><p id="viewer-okcd"><span><span>Running this command asks us which type of project we want to create - we’re creating a component, so we choose “component”.</span></span></p><p id="viewer-avn2i"><span><span>With the project created, we start working on our TodoMVC application.</span></span></p><p id="viewer-1ho6a"><span><span>First, we define the Todo component as </span></span></p><div id="viewer-5eveb"><div><div data-hook="imageViewer" role="button" tabindex="0"><div role="img"><p><img data-pin-url="https://www.wix.engineering/post/is-stencil-a-better-react" data-pin-media="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_d479219dd8dc4364a0138d36868b1f6c~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000%2Ch_532%2Cal_c%2Cq_80/file.png" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_d479219dd8dc4364a0138d36868b1f6c~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_300,h_300,al_c,q_5/file.png"></p></div></div></div></div><p id="viewer-cfkou"><span><span>There are a few things similar to React, a few that are different.</span></span></p><p id="viewer-9jmdh"><span><span>The first thing we see is the </span><span>@Component</span><span> decorator which tells Stencil to generate a web component named</span><span> `todo-app`</span><span>, include a CSS file and use the shadow DOM.</span></span></p><p id="viewer-fs96p"><span><span>Second, we see the decorators for</span><span> @State</span><span>, </span><span>@Prop</span><span> which are used to declare state and props of the component. Those decorators accept additional parameters to fine-tune the props and state declarations.</span></span></p><p id="viewer-6dh3h"><span><span>In fact, the actual Render functions are very similar - here they are side by side:</span></span></p><div id="viewer-336dk"><div><div data-hook="imageViewer" role="button" tabindex="0"><div role="img"><p><img data-pin-url="https://www.wix.engineering/post/is-stencil-a-better-react" data-pin-media="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_840ce5691517407e8ea9ed8104d9ce76~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000%2Ch_892%2Cal_c%2Cq_80/file.png" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_840ce5691517407e8ea9ed8104d9ce76~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_300,h_300,al_c,q_5/file.png"></p></div></div></div></div><div id="viewer-1n343"><div><div data-hook="imageViewer" role="button" tabindex="0"><div role="img"><p><img data-pin-url="https://www.wix.engineering/post/is-stencil-a-better-react" data-pin-media="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_ceed6aca271c4f1bbd2bf64c3ab53e80~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000%2Ch_1000%2Cal_c%2Cq_80/file.png" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_ceed6aca271c4f1bbd2bf64c3ab53e80~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_300,h_300,al_c,q_5/file.png"></p></div></div></div></div><div id="viewer-c2ish"><div><div data-hook="imageViewer" role="button" tabindex="0"><div role="img"><p><img data-pin-url="https://www.wix.engineering/post/is-stencil-a-better-react" data-pin-media="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_4b6a81c88c76467790404aeeece07fd7~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000%2Ch_996%2Cal_c%2Cq_80/file.png" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_4b6a81c88c76467790404aeeece07fd7~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_300,h_300,al_c,q_5/file.png"></p></div></div></div></div><p id="viewer-1quff"><span><span>While very similar, there are still some important differences between the render functions.</span></span></p><p id="viewer-ch90r"><span><span>First, in React access to props and states is done via </span><span>this.state.newTodo</span><span> and</span><span> this.prop.model</span><span>. With Stencil both the props and state are just members of </span><span>this</span><span> - </span><span>this.newTodo</span><span> and</span><span> this.mode</span><span>l.</span></span></p><p id="viewer-6ojpl"><span><span>The second difference is the use of the </span><span>class</span><span> attribute instead of the </span><span>className</span><span> attribute. The semantics are the same, with Stencil using the more standard naming scheme.</span></span></p><p id="viewer-acdmj"><span><span>The third difference is event binding, where in Stencil they promote using arrow functions while React promotes explicit binding using the</span><span> .bind() </span><span>function. This is obviously a preference and both options can be used in both libraries.</span></span></p><p id="viewer-8hram"><span><span>The last, not so obvious, difference is with using child components. In the React version, we see the use of </span><span>TodoFooter</span><span> and </span><span>TodoItem</span><span> - both are React components which are imported into the module. However, with Stencil, the child components are</span><span> todo-footer</span><span> and</span><span> todo-item</span><span>, and there is no import statement to import those into the module. </span></span></p><p id="viewer-d0h3a"><span><span>While this may seem strange at first glance, it actually makes sense once you remember that both </span><span>todo-footer</span><span> and</span><span> todo-item</span><span> are web components and are supported natively by browsers.</span></span></p><p id="viewer-f06tp"><span><span>When comparing Stencil to React and Svelte in terms of performance, Stencil scores a higher lighthouse score for desktop. For mobile, Svelte takes the lead but is less stable. Stencil on mobile is close behind Svelte and is more stable.</span></span></p><p id="viewer-9o36j"><span><span><strong>Desktop comparison:</strong></span></span></p><div id="viewer-83opl"><div><div data-hook="imageViewer" role="button" tabindex="0"><div role="img"><p><img data-pin-url="https://www.wix.engineering/post/is-stencil-a-better-react" data-pin-media="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_d9cba83a658e4417a9cc3b645d5b8618~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000%2Ch_320%2Cal_c%2Cq_80/file.png" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_d9cba83a658e4417a9cc3b645d5b8618~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_300,h_300,al_c,q_5/file.png"></p></div></div></div></div><p id="viewer-6ong4"><span><span><strong>Mobile Comparison (3 runs):</strong></span></span></p><div id="viewer-b92bd"><div><div data-hook="imageViewer" role="button" tabindex="0"><div role="img"><p><img data-pin-url="https://www.wix.engineering/post/is-stencil-a-better-react" data-pin-media="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_b34e4ab9ba6b4111b98a2e7b44ffcd1d~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000%2Ch_488%2Cal_c%2Cq_80/file.png" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_b34e4ab9ba6b4111b98a2e7b44ffcd1d~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_300,h_300,al_c,q_5/file.png"></p></div></div></div></div><p id="viewer-9gf8n"><span><span>All the libraries score very high grades for the TodoMVC case. For me it was no surprise that Stencil was faster compared to React. What was a surprise is that it is also faster compared to Svelte, at least within this use case. </span></span></p><p id="viewer-pb8o"><span><span><strong>Stencil desktop</strong></span></span></p><div id="viewer-5f41m"><div><div data-hook="imageViewer" role="button" tabindex="0"><div role="img"><p><img data-pin-url="https://www.wix.engineering/post/is-stencil-a-better-react" data-pin-media="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_1c49f2b173cc4326ad16357d32f15069~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_992%2Ch_954%2Cal_c%2Cq_80/file.png" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_1c49f2b173cc4326ad16357d32f15069~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_300,h_300,al_c,q_5/file.png"></p></div></div></div></div><p id="viewer-520fu"><span><span><strong>React desktop</strong></span></span></p><div id="viewer-7b9su"><div><div data-hook="imageViewer" role="button" tabindex="0"><div role="img"><p><img data-pin-url="https://www.wix.engineering/post/is-stencil-a-better-react" data-pin-media="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_b673f1bb8e634d27a1166d7bf04b862e~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_990%2Ch_954%2Cal_c%2Cq_80/file.png" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_b673f1bb8e634d27a1166d7bf04b862e~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_300,h_300,al_c,q_5/file.png"></p></div></div></div></div><p id="viewer-2iv4b"><span><span><strong>Svelte desktop</strong></span></span></p><div id="viewer-6tjb8"><div><div data-hook="imageViewer" role="button" tabindex="0"><div role="img"><p><img data-pin-url="https://www.wix.engineering/post/is-stencil-a-better-react" data-pin-media="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_fd26b273556c4a288164730f2561f829~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_990%2Ch_1000%2Cal_c%2Cq_80/file.png" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_fd26b273556c4a288164730f2561f829~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_300,h_300,al_c,q_5/file.png"></p></div></div></div></div><p id="viewer-2nj6b"><span><span><strong>Stencil Mobile</strong></span></span></p><div id="viewer-99c53"><div><div data-hook="imageViewer" role="button" tabindex="0"><div role="img"><p><img data-pin-url="https://www.wix.engineering/post/is-stencil-a-better-react" data-pin-media="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_13e477762abe42fdb9c0136e211caf25~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_990%2Ch_1000%2Cal_c%2Cq_80/file.png" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_13e477762abe42fdb9c0136e211caf25~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_300,h_300,al_c,q_5/file.png"></p></div></div></div></div><p id="viewer-cenfc"><span><span><strong>React Mobile</strong></span></span></p><div id="viewer-ehele"><div><div data-hook="imageViewer" role="button" tabindex="0"><div role="img"><p><img data-pin-url="https://www.wix.engineering/post/is-stencil-a-better-react" data-pin-media="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_9a6f4718afff41429a3a30a8b57b1c0a~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_988%2Ch_1000%2Cal_c%2Cq_80/file.png" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_9a6f4718afff41429a3a30a8b57b1c0a~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_300,h_300,al_c,q_5/file.png"></p></div></div></div></div><p id="viewer-ckcb3"><span><span><strong>Svelte Mobile</strong></span></span></p><div id="viewer-7glqb"><div><div data-hook="imageViewer" role="button" tabindex="0"><div role="img"><p><img data-pin-url="https://www.wix.engineering/post/is-stencil-a-better-react" data-pin-media="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_0850646adbd3437c9856402387ed9c28~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_990%2Ch_1000%2Cal_c%2Cq_80/file.png" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_0850646adbd3437c9856402387ed9c28~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_300,h_300,al_c,q_5/file.png"></p></div></div></div></div><p id="viewer-c018s"><span><span>I have to admit that coding in Stencil was a quite delightful experience. The coding style is a bit cleaner for me with the use of decorators, the split of CSS to multiple files makes a lot of sense. </span></span></p><p id="viewer-9b5h2"><span><span>Stencil gives a great way to build web components while allowing us to keep using the standard toolset we all like - from SCSS, LESS, PostCSS, Rolloup or Stylus, to integrations with different frameworks like React, Angular, Vue, etc. </span></span></p><p id="viewer-15s6e"><span><span>It enables creating web components, static site generation, server-side rendering with client side dehydration. It even has documentation generation for Stencil components.</span></span></p><p id="viewer-74lkv"><span><span>Overall, Stencil is a great alternative to React and stacks well against Svelte too, which makes it a framework that’s definitely worth looking into.</span></span></p><div id="viewer-cgl09"><div><div data-hook="imageViewer" role="button" tabindex="0"><div role="img"><p><img data-pin-url="https://www.wix.engineering/post/is-stencil-a-better-react" data-pin-media="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_133a1a4778a948db80c6f78b36ae82af~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_722%2Ch_862%2Cal_c%2Cq_80/file.png" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/66bc35_133a1a4778a948db80c6f78b36ae82af~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_300,h_300,al_c,q_5/file.png"></p></div></div></div></div><p id="viewer-3utm6"><span>This post was written by <strong>Yoav Abrahami</strong></span></p><p id="viewer-3jb16"><span>You can <a href="https://twitter.com/yoavabrahami" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>follow him on Twitter</u></a></span></p><p id="viewer-41gj6"><span><strong>For more engineering updates and insights:</strong></span></p><ul><li id="viewer-8pnpr"><p>Follow us on: <a href="https://twitter.com/WixEng" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Twitter</u></a> | <a href="https://www.facebook.com/WixEngineering/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Facebook</u></a> | <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/showcase/wix-engineering/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>LinkedIn</u></a></p></li><li id="viewer-6v46r"><p>Visit us on <a href="https://github.com/wix" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>GitHub</u></a> </p></li><li id="viewer-d33l"><p><a href="https://www.wix.engineering/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Subscribe to our monthly newsletter</u></a> </p></li><li id="viewer-c4bod"><p>Subscribe to our <a href="https://www.youtube.com/WixTechTalks" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>YouTube channel</u></a> </p></li><li id="viewer-13nvn"><p><a href="https://medium.com/wix-engineering" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Follow our Medium publication</u></a></p></li><li id="viewer-3dk0n"><p>Listen to our podcast on <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/il/podcast/wix-engineering-podcast/id1503976848" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Apple</u></a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5CmjtjpdcKkHDnr0601uYS?si=PcOf7Rx_RUmGojFj5n7CEA" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Spotify</u></a> or <a href="https://podcasts.google.com/?feed=aHR0cHM6Ly9yYW5sZXZpLmNvbS9mZWVkL3dpeF9wb2Qv&amp;ved=0CAAQ4aUDahcKEwjY3bLcy7_oAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Google</u></a></p></li></ul></div></div></div></div></article></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.wix.engineering/post/is-stencil-a-better-react</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25331909</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 13:25:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Architecture of IMGZ]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 189 | Comments 88 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25331877">thread link</a>) | @sirodoht
<br/>
December 7, 2020 | https://imgz.org/blog/2020/11/19/look-ma-no-seo/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://imgz.org/blog/2020/11/19/look-ma-no-seo/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
Posted on
<time itemprop="datePublished" datetime="2020-11-19">November 19, 2020</time>.
</p><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>Every day at work, hundreds of customers ask us "can I get a large cappuccino?". Later, we go home and use the money to narrowly avoid starvation while working on IMGZ, the best image host, in true Silicon Valley spirit. We thought that some of the architectural challenges we faced while building the service would interest others, and decided to write about them to help our readers and change the world.</p>
<p>If you aren't familiar with IMGZ, it's an image host with a twist: You pay to host images, thus ensuring that we always have your best interests in mind and won't turn into a social network. In essence, we flip the traditional "startup giving away VC money to users" on its head, and take money <strong>from</strong> users. If that sounds good to you, you can sign up <a href="https://imgz.org/">on our home page</a> and we'll only be mildly surprised.</p>
<p>At IMGZ, we're passionate about two things: Serving images, and speaking about ourself in the plural so it doesn't look like it's the one-man sideproject it is, and we don't even really care about serving images that much. Today, though, we're going to talk about the former, and take a deep dive into the technical details of serving more than one million bytes of images per day while maintaining the elusive "nine fives" reliability guarantee we're loved for and usually uphold.</p>
<h2>Architecture deep-dive</h2>
<p>Our architecture is pretty simple, a fairly run-of-the-mill, scrappy-startup SaaS architecture which you've no doubt seen countless times before:</p>
<p><a href="https://imgz.org/i9hxfgRu/"><img src="https://imgz.org/i9hxfgRu.png" alt="Architecture diagram"></a></p>
<p>While designing the IMGZ storage and serving model, we wanted scalability and reliability to be our foremost concerns.
After months of designs and grueling research, we ended up designing a Kafka-based georeplicated image processing pipeline over a multitenant, distributed, resilient microservices architecture, where metadata about each image is kept in a georeplicated MongoDB instance, and with images themselves stored in DynamoDB on AWS, ensuring scalability and low latency.</p>
<p>When we realized we didn't have investors to impress, we trashed that plan, as it sounded like too much work.
We realize that architecture design nowadays is mostly aspirational, but at some point a startup needs to come to terms with the fact that it doesn't have ten million users right now, it probably won't have ten million users soon, and it'll likely never have ten users.
Instead, we stored the images in a small Postgres database (yes, the actual image data itself), with a small Django app handling the business logic. Sexy.</p>
<p>When the user uploads an image, we process it, create thumbnails for displaying in various views of the website, and store it along with its metadata in the database, at least in theory.
When a user requests the image, the request first goes through our CDN, which fetches the image from our server and then caches it forever, so each image is only served by us at most once.
For our CDN (for serving, caching, georeplication, etc), we use CloudFlare's free tier, which is excellent.
We ensure that we'll always remain in the free tier by providing a paid service nobody would actually ever pay for.</p>
<h2>The hardware</h2>
<p>This is the heart of IMGZ:</p>
<p><a href="https://imgz.org/iABb4tze/"><img src="https://imgz.org/iABb4tze.jpg" alt="Servers"></a></p>
<p>Images, just like the one above, are the heart of our service, but let's not digress.
The hardware is a $5/mo Hetzner VM that serves ~10 other projects, so it's pretty beefy.
As our favorite proverb goes, "you don't need lots of resources when all your content is static and you can get someone else to serve it for free".</p>
<p>We're pretty confident in our ability to scale our infrastructure in the event that more users join the service, as our VPS provider has a button we can press to make the server larger, solving all scalability problems once and for all.</p>
<h2>Moral of the story</h2>
<p>This article was a bit boring, wasn't it? That's by design: Your architecture doesn't have to be exciting to work, especially in the early stages of a company. Doing the easiest thing that works (taking care not to paint yoursellf into a corner) is often the best way to start, since you usually don't even know where you'll end up.</p>
<p>To summarize, our architecture follows the tried-and-true Silicon Valley approach: Build the simplest thing you can, by piggybacking off of everyone's free tier, while they hope you one day become successful and pay them exorbitant amounts of money in return. The strategy to outsmarting them is simple:</p>
<p>Just make sure you never succeed.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://imgz.org/blog/2020/11/19/look-ma-no-seo/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25331877</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 13:21:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The CIA's Deadly Deceits and the Vietnam War, with Ralph McGehee (1986)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 102 | Comments 66 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25329913">thread link</a>) | @AndrewBissell
<br/>
December 6, 2020 | https://ourhiddenhistory.org/entry/the-cia-s-deadly-deceits-and-the-vietnam-war-w-ex-cia-officer-ralph-mcgehee | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ourhiddenhistory.org/entry/the-cia-s-deadly-deceits-and-the-vietnam-war-w-ex-cia-officer-ralph-mcgehee">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-bolt-field="body"><p><iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BDZv57p1Ixk"></iframe></p>



<p><b>Ralph W. McGehee:</b> It's a real honor for me to be here today. I don't often say that, but I really mean it. I like to start off my talk by mentioning two things. One, please don't believe anything I'm going to tell you. The American people are so inundated by misinformation, there's absolutely no reason you should believe anything anybody tells you, particularly the evening news. Of course, with everything there is an exception, and I think in my case, I have a fairly valid exception. Because of the process that I had to go through to clear my book, I had to prove that everything I am saying is in the public domain. I still go down to the Agency about twice a month and turn in new material to let them clear it. And in doing that process, I have to produce or pull out from government documents that particular information, because they inevitably will say, "You can't say it, it's classified." And I will inevitably locate that information in the public domain.</p> 
 
<p>So if you doubt me, and I hope you will, there is a way to check up on me. Go to the library and look in the back of my book, and almost every major conclusion that I will be talking about here today will be documented to an official government document. I've drawn upon the Pentagon Papers. Are you all familiar with the Pentagon Papers? And the Senate and House investigations of the Agency and a variety of other material. So don't believe what I say, but if you want to check up on me, the information is available.</p> 
 
<p>Secondly, I'd like to say my message is basically a real downer. It is real negative, but I don't want to leave you with that impression, because I just returned from a two week speaking trip in Iowa, where I was going to testify at the court case there in Iowa City for the protesters, and in Nebraska. And I've been in Arizona and various other places speaking, and wherever you go, you find concerned groups. So I am encouraged. I know during the Vietnam War for the first ten years, we didn't even know what was going on. And then eleven or twelve years later, people began to protest. But this time in Latin America, the protest was almost instantaneous. The substructure is there. The only reason we got out of Vietnam, of course, is because of the student protests. So I am very encouraged. My message is negative, but I don't want to leave you with that impression. I am very, very encouraged.</p> 
 
<p>I think I should talk in three basic phases. One, walk you very quickly through my career with the Agency up to right now where I am today, and back up and walk you through Vietnam a little bit or walk you through my career in a little more detail, including Vietnam. Now I do that not to talk about Vietnam but because the processes that are followed today in Central America, in the Middle East and in Africa have all been used in Vietnam. I'll take out three or four incidences, and they are documented by the way, and show you that these are sort of typical of what the Agency does around the world since the very beginning in '47, what it's doing today in '86.</p> 
 
<p>Then I'll go back and review the Agency's domestic operations, and I'll do that for one purpose, because everything they were doing up to the mid-seventies they are now doing again. The only difference now is under President Reagan's Executive Order 12333 of December '81, they can do the things legally that they were doing illegally before. It's the only difference. Then I would like to talk, sort of bring it all together in Central America and talk about El Salvador, Grenada, and particularly Nicaragua, and then come to my conclusion. So that's basically the approach I'll take.</p> 
 
<p>I went to the University of Notre Dame. I played on four undefeated football teams, three national championships, and then I tried out with the Green Bay Packers. And to this day, I can't understand what's the matter with the coaches up there. When I was cut, I received a cable, "Would you be interested in an important government position similar to the State Department in function?" My football background was not irrelevant. When I went down to Washington, I found that the class before me, my class, and the class after me were basically rejects from the National Football League, not the standard concept of an intelligent (He does say "intelligent" here, I think as a joke about football players) officer.</p> 
 
<p>Well, I served in the Agency for 25 years. The first 15 or 16 years, I believed that the CIA was sort of like a missionary organization, out saving the world for democracy and religion and gathering good intelligence to help our policymakers make good decisions. When I'd go into work in the morning, I'd feel a real pride that I'm part of the great crusade to stop the international communist conspiracy. All that began to change for me in Vietnam. That's when I began protesting.</p> 
 
<p>I should mention that I served my entire 25 years in the Directorate of Operations. Now, the Agency is broken down to basically four directorates, Administration, Science and Technology, Intelligence, and Operations. Administrators administrate. Science and Technology, they devise the sophisticated collection devices and monitor the results. The Directorate of Intelligence, that's the scholars who sit and read the reports that come in from around the world and then put out the final reports. And the Operators operate. The Directorate of Operations has two basic functions, covert operations and gathering intelligence covertly.</p> 
 
<p>Since it's my contention that the Agency is little more than a covert action agency, I will dwell a little bit on it. Now, covert action operations in broadest context can be described as those operations designed to overthrow or support foreign governments. Overthrow operations have four basic components, economic warfare, political warfare, psychological warfare, and economic warfare. In my 25 years in the Agency, I served overseas in Japan, in the Philippines, in Taiwan, six years or three tours in Thailand, and two years as the chief police adviser to the head of the Vietnamese Special Police. That's the equivalent of our FBI.</p> 
 
<p>As I said, my period of protests began around the Vietnam War. I for the next period within the Agency began protesting, and having no luck with those protests, I finally left the Agency in 1977. Now, in a stroke of real irony at this particular point, because they had assigned me to the CIA’s Siberia. When you escalate your protest, you become persona non grata. In '77 in a stroke of irony, they awarded me the Career Intelligence Medal and the Honorable Service Medal. Of course, I think I know why. They knew they had a loose cannon and they wanted to kind of damp me down, appease me a little bit. And I think that was the purpose of giving them to me.</p> 
 
<p>But I also earlier had won awards, two Vietnam service awards, a commendation from the director for devising a program of counterinsurgency and intelligence, and a variety of other CIA and foreign awards. Well, when I left the Agency, I testified before the Senate and House intelligence committees and before a variety of other Senate and House committees, all related to CIA activities.</p> 
 
<p>I immediately set about writing a book about my experiences. It took me three years to research and write the book, and then like all CIA officers, when you join the Agency, you have to sign a secrecy agreement. And as I said, I must now submit everything to the CIA for pre-publication review. I did, and they came back and they said they have identified approximately 400 security violations in my manuscript. And they returned it in little bits and pieces of paper, because some of these deletions ran up to several pages in length.</p> 
 
<p>Well, to defeat this process, I went through going through the public record and pulling out the identical information. And ultimately with this effort, I got virtually everything reinstated. There are a few little specifics that I didn't get reinstated, but for the most part they were all reinstated. I did in a few cases, they had deleted some very boring information, so I said rather than fight them over this one, let's just leave this comment, "Seven words deleted." It looks a lot sexier than mine. So I didn't fight them on all of them.</p> 
 
<p>Then I went looking for a publisher, a long hard process, and finally one publisher said, "You know, you've written a nice legal brief here. You make your points and then you have your citations to your information. But boy, it's dull as mud. Who would want to read a legal brief? So we will publish it if you'll rewrite it as a autobiography," which I did. I then resubmitted it to the CIA for pre-publication review. I didn't put any more secret details in there. I just added my personal life.</p> 
 
<p>At this time, William Casey had become Director of the CIA, and they in essence told me, "We're not going to let you publish a book." And I said, "Well, you can't stop me. Everything that's in the book, you have not only cleared for other people, it's not only in the public record, but you also cleared for me before. And the laws that you operate under say you may not reclassify information once it's been declassified and released." And their response in essence, "Well, that's tough. We're doing it anyhow. There's nothing you can do about it." Well, this was a very critical period. I just didn't know what to do. I really worried about this, because if they would've stopped me with that, then I would not be able to speak to you here this evening, because everything would have been classified.</p> 
 
<p>So I called <i>The Washington Post</i>, and <i>The Washington Post</i> ran a long exposé of how the CIA was violating the law by reclassifying information that was in the public domain, a violation of the law of the land. This public exposure forced the Agency to relent, and the book was finally released. Subsequent to the release of the book, I then traveled to Cuba, where we stayed about a week, and to Grenada, …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://ourhiddenhistory.org/entry/the-cia-s-deadly-deceits-and-the-vietnam-war-w-ex-cia-officer-ralph-mcgehee">https://ourhiddenhistory.org/entry/the-cia-s-deadly-deceits-and-the-vietnam-war-w-ex-cia-officer-ralph-mcgehee</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ourhiddenhistory.org/entry/the-cia-s-deadly-deceits-and-the-vietnam-war-w-ex-cia-officer-ralph-mcgehee</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25329913</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 06:45:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[TeX: A Tale of Two Worlds]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 28 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25329049">thread link</a>) | @Bella-Xiang
<br/>
December 6, 2020 | https://bitbashing.io/tex.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bitbashing.io/tex.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
    <!-- for XeTeX -->


<p>Best viewed in <del>Internet Explorer 6</del>
<a href="https://assets.bitbashing.io/papers/tex-tale-of-two-worlds.pdf">PDF</a>
because… well… read the damn thing.</p>

<!--
It all started when a college friend told me about a cool program for typesetting
papers. Now typography books litter my apartment and I can't read a menu
without noticing bad kerning. Thanks, Max. This is all your fault.
-->

<hr>

<p>Most serious programmers have heard of Donald Knuth,
the man who coined the term <em>analysis of algorithms</em> in 1968
and pioneered many of the computer science fundamentals we use today.
Knuth is perhaps most famous for his ongoing magnum opus,
<em>The Art of Computer Programming</em>.</p>

<p>When the first volume of TAOCP was released that same year,
it was printed the way most books had been since the turn of the century:
with <em>hot metal</em> type.
Each individual letter was cast from molten lead,
then arranged into its line.</p>

<figure>
<img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/7/72/Matrixcase-bembo-16pts.jpg" alt="Monotype matrix case" height="400">
<figcaption>
A case of letter molds—or <em>matrices</em>—used by the Monotype caster,
the most commonly-used machine for printing books in the days of hot metal type.
Its main contemporary, the Linotype, molded entire lines at a time,
and was often used for printing newspapers.
</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>These lines were clamped together to form pages of the book,
which were finally inked and pressed against paper.
By March of 1977, Knuth was ready for a second run of TAOCP, Volume&nbsp;2,
but he was horrified when he received the proofs.
Hot metal typesetting was an expensive, complicated, and time-consuming process,
so publishers had replaced it with phototypesetting,
which works by projecting characters onto film.
The new technology, while much cheaper and faster,
didn’t provide the same level of quality he had come to expect.</p>

<p>The average author would have resigned themselves to the change and moved on,
but Knuth took great pride in print quality,
especially for the mathematics in his books.
Around this time, he discovered an exciting new technology:
digital typesetting.
Instead of working with metal or film,
letters and shapes were built from tiny dots,
often packed together at over 1,000 per inch.
Inspired by this burgeoning tech and frustrated with the current state of affairs,
Knuth set off on one of the greatest yak shaves of all time.
For years, he paused all work on his books to create his own
digital typesetting system.
When the dust settled in 1978, Knuth had the first version of
<span>T<sub>e</sub>X</span>
.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup></p>

<p>It’s hard to understand how much of a revolution <span>T<sub>e</sub>X</span>
 was,
especially looking back from a time where anybody with a copy
of Word can be their own desktop publisher.
Adobe’s PDF wouldn’t exist for another decade, so Knuth
invented a device-independent format, DVI.
Scalable fonts were uncommon at the time, so Knuth created a system,
<span>METAFONT</span>
, to rasterize his characters into dots on the
page.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2">2</a></sup>
Perhaps most importantly, Knuth and his graduate students designed algorithms
to automatically hyphenate and justify lines of text into
beautifully-typeset paragraphs.</p>

<p>Here is where the timelines diverge.
In one, <span>T<sub>e</sub>X</span>
 was just the beginning.
Computer typography evolves rapidly as the decades go by,
building on Knuth’s prior work and
taking advantage of the million-fold increases we’ve seen in computing power.
Browsers, e-readers, and word processors deliver beautiful type
to every person who looks at a screen, with almost no effort from authors.</p>

<p>In the darker timeline… none of this happens.
<span>T<sub>e</sub>X</span>
 is still some of the best we’ve got for computer typesetting.
It’s seen some impressive improvements,<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3">3</a></sup>
but its core hasn’t changed much in decades.
To this day,
it doesn’t lay out more than one page at a time because 1980s computers didn’t
have enough RAM to do any better.<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4">4</a></sup>
Almost no other software—except for a handful of professional layout
programs like Adobe InDesign—leverages any of the advances
<span>T<sub>e</sub>X</span>
 made in line breaking and hyphenation.
Layout in Word, browsers, and even e-readers is a sad joke.</p>

<figure>
<img src="https://assets.bitbashing.io/images/exa.png" alt="Mobile browser layout example" height="400">
<figcaption>
State of the art text layout in today's browsers. Mind the gaps.
</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>I’m not sure what to make of this.
Maybe most people, outside a small cadre of designers and
enthusiasts, just don’t care about typography very much.
After all, the human brain is incredibly good glossing over minor details and
im<span>p</span>erfections when reading.
But even the design world seems largely unaware or indifferent to Knuth’s work.
Despite collaborations with famous type designers like Hermann Zapf,
you’ll find no mention of him in renowned books and documentaries on
the subject.<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5">5</a></sup>
And parametric font families—just like the ones <span>METAFONT</span>
 offered in 1983—are
heralded in 2017 as “a new era of type design”.<sup id="fnref:6"><a href="#fn:6">6</a></sup>
It’s bizarre.</p>

<p>Good typography can make almost anything more enjoyable to read,
and it feels like such a shame that better layout isn’t
available to the masses
when so much of the groundwork was laid almost forty years ago.
In an age when the average American reads from a screen they keep in their pocket
dozens of times a day,
and where each one of those devices holds more processing power than you could
fit in several rooms back when Donald Knuth
wrote <span>T<sub>e</sub>X</span>
, surely we can—and <em>should</em>—do better.</p>

<hr>



  </article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bitbashing.io/tex.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25329049</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 03:23:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Three Cheers for Solutionism?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 44 | Comments 33 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25328149">thread link</a>) | @panic
<br/>
December 6, 2020 | https://aelkus.github.io/theory/2020/12/03/solu.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://aelkus.github.io/theory/2020/12/03/solu.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>Economist Noah Smith <a href="https://noahpinion.substack.com/p/climate-change-isnt-that-hard">is fed up with</a> generic critiques of technological “solutionism,” specifically what he calls the “2010s consensus that technology is a sideshow compared to social movements.”</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>In the last decade, we’ve basically been taught to deride “solutionism” — while Silicon Valley techbros were bending their genius toward figuring out ways to sell more ads or lower taxi drivers’ wages, inequality was running rampant and parents were struggling to feed their kids. Instead of trusting wizardry to solve the world’s problems, we were supposed to place our faith in politics, in mass action, and in cultural change.</p>

  <p>Except then consider what happened with COVID. Our leaders failed to fight the virus effectively, and the President actively sabotaged containment efforts. Culturally, we screeched our heads off about masks and herd immunity and “just the flu” and beach parties and school closings and bar closings and restaurant closings and dorm closings and so on and so forth. We didn’t implement strict lockdowns and we protested against lockdowns and we didn’t even obey the half-assed lockdowns we did implement. We became one of the planet’s worst-hit countries, despite having the planet’s most expensive health care system. We died in the red states, we died in the blue states. We died in droves, in hundreds of thousands. Collectively, as a society, we wrung our hands and ran in circles and screeched and died and screeched and died and screeched and died until scientists made vaccines against the virus.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Is this correct? In some ways, Smith stacks the deck in his favor. Scientific breakthroughs on vaccines can be produced by small groups of experts insulated from public pressure and the clown show of 21st century American politics. This was never the case with non-pharmaceutical interventions, even if I share Smith’s sense out of outrage and horror over America’s failed response to COVID.</p>

<p>Comparing them is a little akin to comparing World War II’s military-technical research achievements to the great campaigns of Europe and the Pacific War. The latter required extensive political and organizational coordination on a hitherto unprecedented scale, and buy-in from millions of ordinary people. The former were not exactly a bunch of eggheads in a seminar room, but they represent at least crudely processes that are largely autonomous from the need to attain large-scale consensus and cooperation.</p>

<p>Come next year, when we enter into the challenge of rolling out vaccines while preserving basic social distancing measures, we will get a reminder of how different these two kinds of activities are. I’m more optimistic that next year will be significantly better than 2020 was, but only guardedly. However, Smith is also on to something larger when he notes the dubious framing of how the answer to engineering our way to nirvana is supposed to be large-scale political and cultural change driven by mass popular mobilization.</p>

<p>‘Political solution’ in this framing seems to be a euphemism for either a deliberative process that harmonizes competing views or (more often) the imposition of one’s will on the body politic via political struggle. Neither look particularly promising in a polarized society in which merely putting on a piece of cloth held together with string has become a <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/politics/2020/06/25/republicans-democrats-move-even-further-apart-in-coronavirus-concerns/">partisan issue</a>. Moreover, Smith <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-10-17/california-is-back-on-the-brink-of-being-a-failed-state">observes elsewhere</a> that even in my home state of California – where GOP opposition has been virtually eradicated – single-party dominance has failed to resolve basic governance issues.</p>

<p>Certainly most thoughtful critics of techno-determinism likely will say that they aren’t categorically against the use of technology, but rather criticize a particular mindset that uncritically postulates that objective solutions can be discovered to objectively framed problems and then objectively implemented and accepted by a mostly cooperative public. However, it is hard to tell if they are talking about the technologists or themselves when they make this criticism. Statements like “if only we had the political will” to do something of interest are just as naive as “if only we had the right app.”</p>

<p>Technologists are often criticized for wanting to ‘route around’ the US political system, but <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2019/07/22/key-findings-about-americans-declining-trust-in-government-and-each-other/">given</a> low institutional trust and increasingly low interpersonal trust, it is difficult to be entirely critical of that desire. The biggest problem with it is that it often devolves into fantasies of taking one’s toys and exiting into an autonomous space free of the need to gain mass consensus (seasteading!) or instituting impersonal mechanisms that suppress political resistance (make the AI president!) There are idiots. Look around. But we’re all idiots in some shape or form and we’re stuck with each other. What do we do next?</p>

<p>First, somewhat of a meta-point: indirection often is a very underrated way of creating change. Part of what this post is looking to encourage is something I sometimes refer to as the “Andrew Marshall style” of change. For decades, Marshall headed up the Office of Net Assessment (ONA) within the United States Department of Defense. Most people interested in defense and strategy, including yours truly, have in some way directly or indirectly benefited from ONA and its projects. But Marshall did so largely below the radar.</p>

<p>Demanding only autonomy, a tiny (by Pentagon standards) budget, a small office, and the freedom to report directly to the Secretary of Defense, Marshall at first glance took a rather counter-intuitive approach. But this was actually critical to his success. He was not a threat to other people’s bureaucratic rice bowls. But he preserved his own autonomy. And by slowly building up a network of relationships and becoming a hub for innovative work, ONA ended up exercising a profound influence on American national security and defense.</p>

<p>What is remarkable about Marshall’s success is that he propagated his particular institutional relationships forward through decades of changing political, economic, and bureaucratic turmoil while slowly altering the surrounding environment around him. It would be ridiculous to assert that Marshall is singularly responsible for any particular major shift in American national security and defense, but it is also very evident that ONA’s presence and persistence changed the boundary conditions of the US defense and security system.</p>

<p>While many technologists often valorize another Cold War American defense icon – John Boyd – Marshall is also a model worth emulating. Technology is complicated, frustrating, and more often than not disappointing relative to our ambitions. But it can change the boundary conditions of problems. Tweaking the boundary conditions of problems is a big part of how meaningful change can happen overall.</p>

<p>Getting 2-3 promising vaccines in under a year is a great example. Vaccines do not change the massive amount of political and institutional failures America has experienced since the COVID-19 outbreak began. However, consider the alternative world without vaccines that we were in only a short time ago. We had all of those problems but without any kind of roadmap as to how we might escape them. Now we have a <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/carlieporterfield/2020/11/15/heres-when-experts-say-things-could-get-back-to-back-to-normal-after-coronavirus/?sh=3f66c9d936ed">hazy but nonetheless meaningful</a> idea of how long it could take to get back to normal, even if there is no really coherent shared idea of ‘normality.’ This is worth celebrating!</p>

<p>Even without a vaccine, we would be much worse off than we are now if everything from the physical network backbone to distributed work solutions did not perform well under significant stress. The Internet, also created originally in part for the purpose of scientific collaboration, enabled scientific researchers around the world to work together at breakneck speed to learn as much as possible about a novel virus and figure out how to attack it. Outside of the US and most <a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/blogs/new-atlanticist/lessons-from-taiwans-experience-with-covid-19/">successfully in Taiwan</a>, governments have also found success in working together with the private sector to manage information flows during the pandemic.</p>

<p>Beyond COVID, what might this mean? Even in the best of times, the <a href="https://texaspolitics.utexas.edu/archive/html/bur/features/0303_02/muddling.html">most</a> we can often accomplish on the most intractable social problems is to <a href="https://texaspolitics.utexas.edu/archive/html/bur/features/0303_02/muddling.html">muddle through</a>. They have <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/BF01405730">no inherent point</a> at which they officially stop being problems, and often no inherently correct shared framing. It doesn’t mean that action is pointless, but true students of politics often understand that politics is a secular activity instead of a means of bringing about religious salvation.</p>

<p>It seems unwise to stake our hopes on some kind of decisive reckoning at which political solutions will somehow materialize and then be imposed on our friends, neighbors, and co-workers. Much for the same reason that many of us find that we cannot get even members of our own family to take sensible COVID precautions no matter how much we plead, cajole, and threaten them. Still, we have also seen what happens when we simply stand still and do nothing.</p>

<p>“Techno-scientific” changes in the surrounding environment can do a number of salient things. They can provide tools we did not have before to mitigate problems. They can subtly influence or even shift the dynamics of particular interpersonal and institutional relationships and interactions. New frontiers to explore can distract people that otherwise would make trouble, and a bigger pie can make people feel more generous than they otherwise would be. While much has been made of the costs of technological disruption, breaking up established social hierarchies can be necessary for the system as a whole to survive and grow.</p>

<p>Preventing stasis and injecting more slack into the system are both means to the same end: propagating the system forward into the future. So technological “solutionism” (a term I have always disliked due to its imprecision), is both more and less important than ever. It certainly falls short of the hopes of its biggest boosters and the fears of its opponents. But if you are a technologist looking to make a difference now is as good of a …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://aelkus.github.io/theory/2020/12/03/solu.html">https://aelkus.github.io/theory/2020/12/03/solu.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://aelkus.github.io/theory/2020/12/03/solu.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25328149</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:40:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
