<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 08:25:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 08:25:05 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Being Glue]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 82 | Comments 22 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25120504">thread link</a>) | @monsieurpng
<br/>
November 16, 2020 | https://noidea.dog/glue | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://noidea.dog/glue">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="canvas">

      
  
  



    

    

    

    <section id="page" role="main" data-content-field="main-content">
      <!-- CATEGORY NAV -->
      
      <div data-type="page" data-updated-on="1592981380911" id="page-5cc7644e852586000128e46b"><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1556734196837_9137"><div><p>Your job title says "software engineer", but you seem to spend most of your time in meetings. You'd like to have time to code, but nobody else is onboarding the junior engineers, updating the roadmap, talking to the users, noticing the things that got dropped, asking questions on design documents, and making sure that everyone's going roughly in the same direction. If you stop doing those things, the team won't be as successful. But now someone's suggesting that you might be happier in a less technical role. If this describes you, congratulations: you're the glue. If it's not, have you thought about who is filling this role on your team?</p><p>Every senior person in an organisation should be aware of the less glamorous - and often less-promotable - work that needs to happen to make a team successful. Managed deliberately, glue work demonstrates and builds strong technical leadership skills. Left unconscious, it can be career limiting. It can push people into less technical roles and even out of the industry.</p><p>Let's talk about how to allocate glue work deliberately, frame it usefully and make sure that everyone is choosing a career path they actually want to be on.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1556739775888_8389"><p>(💖💖💖Thank so much to the organisers of the amazing <a href="https://theleaddeveloper.com/" target="_blank">Lead Developer conference</a> where I presented this version of these slides. Thank you also to the organizers of the equally amazing<a href="https://www.writespeakcode.com/" target="_blank"> Write/Speak/Code conference </a>who accepted the first iteration of this talk. You are wonderful folks and I so appreciate the work you do. 💖💖💖)</p></div></div><div><div data-block-type="51" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1592980352948_19617"><div>


<div>
  <form data-form-id="5ef2f43280c2046beb659fc7" autocomplete="on" method="POST" onsubmit="return (function (form) {
    Y.use('squarespace-form-submit', 'node', function usingFormSubmit(Y) {
      (new Y.Squarespace.FormSubmit(form)).submit({
        formId: '5ef2f43280c2046beb659fc7',
        collectionId: '5cc7644e852586000128e46b',
        objectName: 'page-5cc7644e852586000128e46b'
      });
    });
    return false;
  })(this);">
    
    
    <p>No spam, I promise.</p>
    <p>Thank you!</p>
    
  </form>
</div>
</div></div><div data-aspect-ratio="90.83333333333333" data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1556734196837_13841"><div>








  

    

      <figure data-scrolled="" data-test="image-block-v2-outer-wrapper">

        <div>
          
            <a href="https://twitter.com/deniseyu21/status/1123313394113753088" data-animation-role="image" data-description="">
            
            <img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a05ececd55b4165f250f032/1556734772289-TZ8L8K9LCIPEQGXSM8LO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKwP5wc_189XiWLTNbaYn7EUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8GRo6ASst2s6pLvNAu_PZdJQr8gHdfuVEBZ6fGgEWibFK9OSZJCsAjo5_hH76asz9_aMLW6xIlFKyCazI6z63-Q/image-asset.jpeg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a05ececd55b4165f250f032/1556734772289-TZ8L8K9LCIPEQGXSM8LO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKwP5wc_189XiWLTNbaYn7EUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8GRo6ASst2s6pLvNAu_PZdJQr8gHdfuVEBZ6fGgEWibFK9OSZJCsAjo5_hH76asz9_aMLW6xIlFKyCazI6z63-Q/image-asset.jpeg" data-image-dimensions="601x1024" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a05ececd55b4165f250f032/1556734772289-TZ8L8K9LCIPEQGXSM8LO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKwP5wc_189XiWLTNbaYn7EUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8GRo6ASst2s6pLvNAu_PZdJQr8gHdfuVEBZ6fGgEWibFK9OSZJCsAjo5_hH76asz9_aMLW6xIlFKyCazI6z63-Q/image-asset.jpeg">
            
          
            </a>
          

        </div>

        
          
          <figcaption data-width-ratio="">
            <div>

              

              
                <div><p>https://twitter.com/deniseyu21/status/1123313394113753088</p></div>
              

              

            </div>
          </figcaption>
        

      </figure>

    

  


</div></div></div></div></div>
    </section>

    

    

    

  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://noidea.dog/glue</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25120504</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 05:18:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Headlamp: a new UI for Kubernetes]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 98 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25118870">thread link</a>) | @aberoham
<br/>
November 16, 2020 | https://kinvolk.io/blog/2020/11/shining-a-light-on-the-kubernetes-user-experience-with-headlamp/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://kinvolk.io/blog/2020/11/shining-a-light-on-the-kubernetes-user-experience-with-headlamp/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <p>If you’ve ever seen a Kubernetes demo, it probably involved a terminal and someone typing commands using kubectl and arcane yaml configuration files. This might be a powerful workflow for experts, but in an age when everything has a slick web interface, it is not the most accessible user experience. It <strong>steepens the learning curve</strong> for those new to Kubernetes, and <strong>presents a barrier</strong> to occasional users.</p>
<p>Of course, there are several graphical user interfaces available for Kubernetes, including the <em>Kubernetes Dashboard</em> project that is part of upstream Kubernetes itself. However, when we researched the landscape, we couldn’t find a solution that covered everything we were looking for. Specifically, our criteria were:</p>
<ul>
<li>100% open source</li>
<li>Actively maintained</li>
<li>Generic, in the sense of not being tied to a specific vendor’s Kubernetes distro</li>
<li>Modular and extensible</li>
<li>Clean, modern user interface</li>
<li>Implemented using a stack that was familiar to our development team (Go, Javascript/Typescript, React)</li>
<li>An interactive UI that allows read-write operations, not just a read-only dashboard</li>
<li>Multi-cluster.</li>
</ul>
<p>Despite the good number of alternatives, the reality is that none of the solutions we tested at the time really matched all the points in our criteria or was a good base to start from. So, in the time-honored tradition, we decided to build one ourselves…</p>

<p>Today, I am <strong>proud to announce the general availability of a new UI for Kubernetes</strong>: <a href="https://github.com/kinvolk/headlamp">Headlamp</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://kinvolk.io/media/headlamp_cluster_overview.png" alt="Headlamp"></p>
<p>Headlamp is a generic and extensible Kubernetes UI that meets the criteria mentioned above. Of course, coming from Kinvolk, it is 100% open source. We hope many Kubernetes community members will not just enjoy using Headlamp, but also contribute back to the project.</p>
<p>Let’s take a quick spin through some of its core features.</p>
<h2 id="extensible-ui">Extensible UI</h2>
<p>We want Headlamp to be used for as many different use-cases as possible. That includes not only novice Kubernetes users, but also experienced operators, as well as Kubernetes vendors with very different needs. Often, particularly for UI projects, such a breadth of use cases can only be addressed by downstream users maintaining their own fork. But keeping forks up to date becomes more challenging the deeper the changes are.</p>
<p>A solution to this problem is to have a plugin system. So Headlamp supports out-of-tree UI plugins: Javascript files that are loaded by Headlamp’s backend and passed to the client which dynamically loads them.</p>
<p>This opens up Headlamp to innovation, <strong>fostering a wealth of new functionality</strong>. For example, if you want to add a button to the Pod details view that will redirect the user to a service showing how much the Pod is costing to operate, that should be easy to implement.</p>
<p>We see Headlamp’s plug-in capabilities as a great opportunity for the community. We are eager to collaborate with others who want to develop new Headlamp plugins, or enhance the plugin system itself to support other use-cases.</p>
<h3 id="traceloop">Traceloop</h3>
<p>As an <strong>example of the power of the plug-in system</strong>, and an incredibly useful tool in its own right, we have developed a <a href="https://github.com/kinvolk/lokomotive-web-ui/tree/master/plugins/ig-traces">Headlamp plugin for the traceloop gadget</a> of our <a href="https://github.com/kinvolk/inspektor-gadget">Inspektor Gadget</a> project.</p>
<p>When Inspektor Gadget is installed in a cluster and the traceloop gadget is enabled, it <strong>records all syscalls from a pod</strong> into a ring buffer. This buffer can be seen in real-time as the pod is running, allowing a lens into what the pod is doing right now, but is also saved for terminated pods. This allows operators to see what caused a crash, after it happens – like a “flight data recorder” for your Kubernetes apps.</p>
<p><img src="https://kinvolk.io/media/traces.gif" alt="Traces plugin for Headlamp"></p>
<h2 id="role-aware-ui">Role-aware UI</h2>
<p>One problem with many read-write (CRUD) user interfaces is that they are not aware of underlying access controls. For example, displaying the update/delete buttons is misleading if the user has actually no permissions to modify the resource. So Headlamp checks Kubernetes RBAC settings and displays only those controls whose actions can be performed. So, if the user does not have permission to edit a resource, the edit button will not be displayed.</p>
<p>This results in a much better UX, because it is obvious to the operator what actions are available based on their permissions at the time. In particular, this is great for situations where time-limited credentials are granted to operators (e.g. temporary deletion permissions on a resource).</p>
<p><img src="https://kinvolk.io/media/headlamp_permissions.png" alt="Pod when the user has update/delete permissions" title="Pod when the user has update/delete permissions">
<sub>Pod when the user has update/delete permissions</sub></p>
<p><img src="https://kinvolk.io/media/headlamp_no_permissions.png" alt="Pod when the user has no update/delete permissions" title="Pod when the user has no update/delete permissions">
<sub>Pod when the user has no update/delete permissions</sub></p>
<h2 id="design--user-interface">Design / User Interface</h2>
<p>We wanted Headlamp’s design to be as <strong>clean and modern</strong> as possible, yet without breaking with a more “traditional” Kubernetes UI or dashboard style. For example, we think that showing a familiar table-based view is very helpful, and we hope other visualizations, such as a graph-based representation of the cluster, can be implemented through plugins.</p>
<p>To implement Headlamp’s frontend, we chose to use React with the <a href="https://material-ui.com/">Material UI</a> library, because it is modern, clean, and is well maintained with a large user community. It also has the advantage that it is the same technology stack that we use in our <a href="https://github.com/kinvolk/nebraska">Nebraska</a> project, enabling sharing of expertise and resources, and supporting a consistent UI across all our products.</p>
<h2 id="desktop-vs-in-cluster">Desktop vs In-cluster</h2>
<p>Most Kubernetes UIs can be categorized as either a hosted (often in-cluster) backend, such as the original Kubernetes Dashboard, or a local desktop application, such as VMware’s <a href="https://github.com/vmware-tanzu/octant">Octant</a> project.</p>
<p>Both approaches have their advantages and disadvantages. For example, when run as a hosted application, it’s very simple to just share a URL with users, and have them log in through OIDC. It’s available “everywhere”, and it’s easy to keep it up-to-date with the cluster version. Conversely, with a desktop application, there’s no need to host the UI application, keeping things more isolated, but the burden of keeping the app up to date falls on the user.</p>
<p>With Headlamp, you <strong>don’t have to choose</strong> between these two approaches, as we support both. It can be easily <strong>hosted in-cluster</strong> by using/adapting the YAML files we provide, or <strong>installed locally</strong> on Linux, Mac, and Windows.</p>
<h2 id="multi-cluster-support">Multi-cluster support</h2>
<p>Most Kubernetes deployments involve multiple clusters, even if that’s just to separate a development from a production environment. Thus, Headlamp <strong>allows you to access all your clusters</strong> - with the exact method depending on whether you’re running as a hosted, or a local (desktop), application.</p>
<p>When run locally, Headlamp will read the kube config and display the contexts available there, allowing the user to change when needed just by setting the local environment variable to the appropriate cluster.</p>
<p>The way the multi-cluster support works is straightforward: it creates a proxy for each configured cluster, and redirects requests from the UI (with the Kubernetes API calls) to the right cluster address. Shout-out here to the <a href="https://github.com/indeedeng/k8dash">K8dash</a> project, whose request/API management modules we reused in the development of Headlamp.</p>
<p>It’s also possible to mix this with running in-cluster, though this does require the cluster running the application to have API access to the other configured clusters.</p>
<p><img src="https://kinvolk.io/media/headlamp_cluster_chooser.png" alt="Cluster Chooser" title="Cluster chooser dialog"></p>

<p>You may be aware that Kinvolk also has a Kubernetes distribution, <a href="https://kinvolk.io/lokomotive">Lokomotive</a>. While Headlamp is of course used within Lokomotive as the basis for its web user interface, it is important to note that these are separate and independent projects. True to our goal of being independent of any particular distro, <strong>Headlamp is designed to support any conformant Kubernetes cluster</strong>.</p>

<p>It’s <strong>easy to try out Headlamp</strong>: just apply the deployment manifest to your cluster and point your browser to the Headlamp service, or download and install the desktop application for Windows, Mac, or Linux. For details, see the <a href="https://kinvolk.io/docs/headlamp/latest/installation">documentation</a>.</p>
<p>Headlamp is fully open source, released under the Apache 2.0 terms and, as mentioned above, we created it to be a generic and vendor-independent Kubernetes UI that we hope can suit many use-cases. So we encourage anyone interested to take part.</p>
<p>If you want to participate, please check out our <a href="https://kinvolk.io/docs/headlamp/latest/contributing">contribution guidelines</a>.</p>
<p><strong>We hope you enjoy Headlamp!</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://kinvolk.io/images/headlamp-logo.svg">
</p>

          </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://kinvolk.io/blog/2020/11/shining-a-light-on-the-kubernetes-user-experience-with-headlamp/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25118870</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:16:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[High Performance Individuals and Teams]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 76 | Comments 54 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25118762">thread link</a>) | @pablasso
<br/>
November 16, 2020 | https://pablasso.com/high-performance-individuals-and-teams/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://pablasso.com/high-performance-individuals-and-teams/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Growing up, the only thing that put me off while learning software development, was the common occurrence of people who cared more about one upping others with their trivia knowledge rather than actually building things.</p>
<p>At the start of my career I had a difficult time differentiating between them and actual top performers because the industry still thought there was a strong correlation between jerks and highly productive people. Employers used to be afraid something will go wrong if they fired a mythical 10x engineer and no one else understood how to fix their systems.</p>
<p>After 15 years what I've learned is that engineers that produce orders of magnitude more than others exist<sup id="fnref-1"><a href="#fn-1">1</a></sup>, but the way they are talked about is overly exaggerated. They’re usually not jerks either, at least not more than the rest of the population.</p>
<p>If you find a project where only one person know what is going on, chances are that person is not good at writing code for humans, not that is a coding god.</p>
<p>One thing we don’t often consider is that you don’t have to hire the very top of the field to find people that are orders better than the industry average. Even more important than finding great engineers is to avoid bad ones<sup id="fnref-2"><a href="#fn-2">2</a></sup>.</p>
<p>Being obsessed with finding a 10x engineer, is to be obsessed with shortcuts and Hail Marys. It will hurt you in the long run if you’re focusing on that instead of building solid fundamentals.</p>
<p>Ultimately I am convinced that focusing on building teams is more important than finding individual outliers. Of course the John Carmacks, the Jeff Deans, the Fabrice Bellards, of the industry exist, but your startup isn’t going to die if you don’t find one. It will die if you don’t build a good team.</p>
<h2>Good reads on individual and team performance</h2>
<ul>
<li>Steve McConnell, has a great summary of existing studies that support the 10x theory in <a href="https://www.construx.com/blog/productivity-variations-among-software-developers-and-teams-the-origin-of-10x/">“Individual Productivity Variation in Software Development”</a>. </li>
<li>McConnell also recognizes the aforementioned studies are not perfect in <a href="https://www.construx.com/blog/the-origins-of-10x-how-valid-is-the-underlying-research/">“Origins of 10X – How Valid is the Underlying Research?”</a>. But the lack of studies contradicting the current findings and the abundance of anecdotal stories signals towards confirmation.</li>
<li>In <a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/10429247.2002.11415178">“Leadership, Team Building, and Team Member Characteristics in High Performance Project Teams”</a> the authors identify 9 themes<sup id="fnref-3"><a href="#fn-3">3</a></sup> as potential predictors of team performance.</li>
<li>In <a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/10429247.2002.11415147">“Linking Project Team Performance with Team Health”</a> the authors emphasize that team building is a long term strategy that does not happen overnight by itself. Organizations must invest if they want to build healthy, high performing teams.</li>
<li>In <a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/10429247.1999.11415013">“An Empirical Study of the Relationship Between Team Performance and Team Maturity”</a> the authors measure the impact of changes in team dynamics, and make a correlation of team maturity with high performance teams. They mention how persistance is required to move to higher performance.</li>
<li>In <a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/10429247.1990.11414554">“Innovative Performance in Research, Development, and Engineering”</a> the authors identify 12 factors<sup id="fnref-4"><a href="#fn-4">4</a></sup> that strongly influence innovative work environments:</li>
</ul>

      </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://pablasso.com/high-performance-individuals-and-teams/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25118762</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:04:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Sweden bans public events of more than eight people]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 79 | Comments 89 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25116451">thread link</a>) | @belltaco
<br/>
November 16, 2020 | https://www.thelocal.se/20201116/breaking-sweden-introduces-limit-of-eight-coronavirus | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.thelocal.se/20201116/breaking-sweden-introduces-limit-of-eight-coronavirus">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.thelocal.se/20201116/breaking-sweden-introduces-limit-of-eight-coronavirus</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25116451</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 20:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What Gödel Discovered]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 656 | Comments 161 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25115746">thread link</a>) | @stopachka
<br/>
November 16, 2020 | https://stopa.io/post/269 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://stopa.io/post/269">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p><span><p>In 1931, a 25-year-old Kurt Gödel wrote a proof that turned mathematics upside down. The implication was so astounding, and his proof so elegant that it was...kind of funny. I wanted to share his discovery with you. Fair warning though, I’m not a mathematician; I’m a programmer. This means my understanding is intuitive and not exact. Hopefully, that will come to our advantage since I have no choice but to avoid formality 🙂. Let’s get to it.</p><p>For the last 300 years, mathematicians and scientists alike made startling discoveries, which led to one great pattern. The pattern was unification: ideas that were previously thought to be disparate and different consistently turned out to be one and the same!</p><p>Newton kicked this off for physicists when he discovered that what kept us rooted on the Earth was also what kept the Earth dancing around the sun. People thought that heat was a special type of energy, but it turned out that it could be explained with mechanics. People thought that electricity, magnetism, and light were different, but Maxwell discovered they could be explained by an electromagnetic field.</p><p>Darwin did the same for biologists. It turned out that our chins, the beautiful feathers of birds, deer antlers, different flowers, male and female sexes, the reason you like sugar so much, the reason whales swim differently...could all be explained by natural selection.</p><p>Mathematicians waged a similar battle for unification. They wanted to find the “core” principles of mathematics, from which they could derive all true theories. This would unite logic, arithmetic, and so on, all under one simple umbrella. To get a sense of what this is about, consider this question: How do we <em>know</em> that 3 is smaller than 5? Or that 1 comes before 2? Is this a “core” principle that we take on faith (the formal name for this is called an “axiom”) or can this be derived from some even more core principle? Are numbers fundamental concepts, or can they be derived from something even more fundamental?</p><p>Mathematicians made great progress in this battle for core principles. For example, a gentleman called Frege discovered that he could craft a theory of sets, which could represent just about everything. For numbers, for example, he could do something like this:</p><p><span><img src="https://stopa.io/api/image/aHR0cHM6Ly91c2VyLWltYWdlcy5naXRodWJ1c2VyY29udGVudC5jb20vOTg0NTc0Lzk5MjkyOTc0LWZhMTE3MjgwLTI4MGYtMTFlYi05MTM1LTVkYjRkZWFlZjgzYy5wbmc" alt="A demonstration of how to represent numbers with sets"></span></p><p>Here, he represents 0 the empty set. 1 as the set which contains the set for 0. 2 as the set that contains the set for 1 and 0. From this he could set a principle to get the “next” number: just wrap all previous numbers in a set. Pretty cool! Frege was able to take that and prove arithmetic rules like “1 + 1”, “numbers are infinite”, etc.</p><p>This looked formidable and cool, but Bertrand Russell came along and broke the theory in one fell swoop. </p><p>He used the rules that Frege laid out to make a valid but <em>nonsensical</em> statement. He proved something analogous to 1 + 1 = 3 <sup>1</sup>. This sounds innocuous; it was after-all just <em>one</em> statement. But nevertheless it was disastrous for a foundational theory of mathematics. If you could prove that 1 + 1 = 3, then you can’t really trust any true statement that results from this foundation. </p><p>This put mathematicians on a tail-spin. They even dubbed this period the “Foundational Crisis of Mathematics” </p><p>In an effort to solve this problem, a mathematician called Hilbert laid down some requirements for what a fundamental theory of mathematics had to look like <sup>2</sup>. He said that this theory must be a new language, with a set of rules that satisfied two primary constraints:</p><p>The theory would need to be able to prove <em>any</em> true mathematical statement. For example, imagine the statement 1 + 1 = 2. If this language can’t prove that statement, then it certainly can’t prove all of mathematics. Hilbert called this quality <strong>completeness.</strong> The language would need to be complete. </p><p>The second hard requirement, as we discussed earlier, was that it <em>could not</em> prove a false mathematical statement. If we could prove 1 + 1 = 3, then all was for naught. Hilbert called this <strong>consistency.</strong> The language would need to be consistent.</p><p>Bertrand Russell, the gentleman who broke Frege’s theory, worked together with Alfred North Whitehead to develop a theory of their own. They labored for years to craft an immense volume of work, called Principia Mathematica <sup>3</sup>.</p><p>They started by writing a new language (let’s call it PM) with a few simple rules. They took those rules,  and proceeded to prove a bunch of things. Russell and Whitehead took almost nothing on faith. For example, let’s look at this almost-impossible-to-read proof over here (don’t worry, you don’t need to understand the syntax for this essay):</p><p><span><img src="https://stopa.io/api/image/aHR0cHM6Ly91c2VyLWltYWdlcy5naXRodWJ1c2VyY29udGVudC5jb20vOTg0NTc0Lzk5MjkzMDA0LTA0Y2MwNzgwLTI4MTAtMTFlYi05ZGJkLTRkMTlmYmQxMDM2My5wbmc" alt="An example, very hard-to-read proof from Principia Mathematica"></span></p><p>This proof showed that “1 + 1”, does indeed equal “2”. It took 2 volumes to get here.</p><p>Their language was dense and the work laborious, but they kept on proving a whole bunch of different truths in mathematics, and so far as anyone could tell at the time, there were no contradictions. It was imagined that at least in theory you could take this foundation and eventually expand it past mathematics: could you encode in pure logic how a dog behaves, or how humans think?</p><p>It certainly looked like Principia Mathematica could serve as the foundational theory for Mathematics. Until Gödel came along. </p><p>He proved that Principia Mathematica <em>did indeed have</em> true mathematical statements which <em>could not be proven</em> in the language. Principia Mathematica was incomplete.</p><p>This was startling, but his proof went even further. He showed that the entire enterprise behind Hilbert’s Program — to find a formal foundation for mathematics — could <em>never</em> work.</p><p>It’s hard to believe that a person could really prove that something can “never” happen — imagine if someone told you that we could never travel farther than our solar system — you’d look at them with suspicion.</p><p>Yet here Gödel was...a 25 year-old who proved beyond a doubt that this enterprise was impossible. He did this by showing that if a language could represent numbers, then unprovable statements would necessarily pop up.</p><p>Let’s think about that for a second: Numbers seem so quaint and easy to prove —  just “1”, “2”, “3”...so on. People thought we could eventually write down how humans think — imagine how shocked they must have been to see that we couldn’t prove all truths about...numbers.</p><p>Let’s see how Gödel did it.</p><p>Now Russel and Whitehead’s language was hard to read. There’s no harm done in changing some of their symbols around. Let’s map their language to something more amenable to programmers: Lisp! </p><p>You can imagine that Russell and Whitehead came up with a lisp-like language. Here’s how their syntax looked:</p><p>First, they had a few symbols for arithmetic.</p><div><table><thead><tr><td><p><strong>Symbol</strong></p></td><td><p><strong>Meaning</strong></p></td><td><p><strong>Example</strong></p></td></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p>0</p></td><td><p>zero</p></td><td><p><code>0</code></p></td></tr><tr><td><p>next</p></td><td><p>the next successor</p></td><td><p><code>(next 0)</code></p></td></tr><tr><td><p>+</p></td><td><p>plus</p></td><td><p><code>(+ 0 (next 0))</code></p></td></tr><tr><td><p>*</p></td><td><p>times</p></td><td><p><code>(* 0 (next 0))</code></p></td></tr><tr><td><p>=</p></td><td><p>equals</p></td><td><p><code>(= 0 (* 0 (next 0)))</code></p></td></tr></tbody></table></div><p>Just from these symbols, they could represent all natural numbers. If they proved that the symbol <code>0</code> worked like 0. and the symbol <code>next</code> worked like a successor function, then <code>(next 0)</code> could represent 1, <code>(next (next 0))</code> could represent 2, and so on. </p><p>Here’s how they could write <code>1 + 1 = 2</code>: </p><pre><code><span>(</span><span>=</span><span> (</span><span>+</span><span> (</span><span>next</span><span> </span><span>0</span><span>) (</span><span>next</span><span> </span><span>0</span><span>)) </span>
<span>   (</span><span>next</span><span> (</span><span>next</span><span> </span><span>0</span><span>)))</span></code></pre><p>Now, for the purpose of this essay, I’ll add one rule. If you ever see me using a natural number inside PM-Lisp other than 0 (i.e “15”), you can imagine it’s shorthand to writing <code>(next (next (next ...))))</code> that many times. In this case, “15” means <code>next</code> applied to 0, 15 times</p><div><table><thead><tr><td><p><strong>Symbol</strong></p></td><td><p><strong>Meaning</strong></p></td><td><p><strong>Example</strong></p></td></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p><code>&lt;natural-number&gt;</code></p></td><td><p><code>(next (next ...))</code> applied to <code>0</code> <code>&lt;natual-number&gt;</code> times</p></td><td><div><p><code>3</code></p><p><em>means</em> <code>(next (next (next 0)))</code></p></div></td></tr></tbody></table></div><p>(Next (pun-intended)), they came up with some symbols to represent logic: </p><div><table><thead><tr><td><p><strong>Symbol</strong></p></td><td><p><strong>Meaning</strong></p></td><td><p><strong>Example</strong></p></td></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p>not</p></td><td><p>not</p></td><td><p><code>(not (= 0 1))</code></p></td></tr><tr><td><p>or</p></td><td><p>or</p></td><td><p><code>(or (= 0 1) (not (= 0 1)))</code></p></td></tr><tr><td><p>when</p></td><td><p>when ... then ..</p></td><td><div><p><code>(when 0 (or 0 1))</code></p><p><em>when 0, then there is either 0 or 1</em></p></div></td></tr><tr><td><p>there-is</p></td><td><p>there is ... such that ...</p></td><td><p><code>(there-is x (= 4 (* x 2))</code></p></td></tr></tbody></table></div><p>These symbols map closely to the logical statements we are used to in programming. The most unusual one is <code>there-is</code>. Let’s see one of those for an example: </p><pre><code><span>(</span><span>there-is</span><span> x (</span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>4</span><span> (</span><span>*</span><span> x </span><span>2</span><span>)))</span></code></pre><p>This is making a statement, that there is some number <code>x</code>, such that <code>(* x 2)</code> equals 4.  Well, that is indeed true: <code>x = 2</code>. That’s pretty cool — we’ve just made a general arithmetic statement. </p><p>Where did the <code>x</code> come from though? Oops, we need to account for that in our language:</p><div><table><thead><tr><td><p><strong>Symbol</strong></p></td><td><p><strong>Meaning</strong></p></td></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p>a...z, A...Z</p></td><td><p>variable</p></td></tr></tbody></table></div><p>In order to represent general truths, Russell and Whitehead introduced variables. Here’s how they could derive <code>and</code> for example: </p><pre><code><span>(</span><span>not</span><span> (</span><span>or</span><span> (</span><span>not</span><span> A) (</span><span>not</span><span> B)))</span></code></pre><p>When this statement is <code>true</code>, both <code>A</code> and <code>B</code> must be true! </p><p>Very cool. One more trick for our essay. To make it a bit easier to read, sometimes I’ll introduce new symbols. They won’t actually be a part of the language, but it can make good shorthand for us in the essay</p><div><table><thead><tr><td><p><strong>Form</strong></p></td><td><p><strong>Meaning</strong></p></td><td><p><strong>example</strong></p></td></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p><code>(def &lt;name&gt; &lt;formula&gt;)</code></p></td><td><p>define <code>&lt;name&gt;</code> to represent <code>&lt;formula&gt;</code></p></td><td><div><p><code>(def and (not (or (not A) (not B)))</code></p><p><em>same as</em> <code>(and &lt;var-a&gt; &lt;var-b&gt;...)</code></p></div></td></tr></tbody></table></div><p>Now we can write <code>(and 1 2)</code> 🙂</p><p>All we saw above were <em>symbols.</em> They had no meaning yet. </p><p>Russell and Whitehead needed to prove that <code>0</code> works like zero, and that <code>=</code> works like equals. In order to breathe life into those symbols, they started off with some core principles — the axioms. </p><p>Here’s what they chose: </p><div><table><thead><tr><td><p><strong>Axiom</strong></p></td><td><p><strong>Example</strong></p></td></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p><code>(when (or p p) p)</code></p></td><td><p>when either apples or apples, then apples</p></td></tr><tr><td><p><code>(when p (or p q))</code></p></td><td><p>when apples, then either apples or bananas</p></td></tr><tr><td><p><code>(when (or p q) (or q p))</code></p></td><td><p>when either apples or bananas, then either bananas or apples</p></td></tr><tr><td><p><code>(when (or p (or q r)) (or q (or p r))</code></p></td><td><p>when either apples, bananas, or pears, then either bananas, apples, or pears</p></td></tr><tr><td><p><code>(when (when q r) (when (or p q) (or p r))</code></p></td><td><p>when apples are a fruit, then bananas or apples implies bananas or fruits</p></td></tr></tbody></table></div><p>That’s it. This is all we needed to take them on faith for. They took these rules and laboriously combined them in intricate ways to derive everything else. </p><p>For example, here’s how they derived <code>=</code>: </p><pre><code><span>(</span><span>def</span><span> = (</span><span>and</span><span> (</span><span>when</span><span> A B) (</span><span>when</span><span> B A)))</span></code></pre><p>If A implies B, and B implies A, they <em>must</em> be equal! Imagine this done for hundreds and hundreds of pages. </p><p>Note something essential here: their rules are so precise that there is no room for human judgement; a computer could run them. This was a key component for …</p></span></p></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://stopa.io/post/269">https://stopa.io/post/269</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://stopa.io/post/269</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25115746</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 19:15:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How and when to acquire SaaS users]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 227 | Comments 94 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25114214">thread link</a>) | @timjones
<br/>
November 16, 2020 | https://www.themvpsprint.com/p/how-and-when-to-acquire-saas-users | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.themvpsprint.com/p/how-and-when-to-acquire-saas-users">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2>My side projects always fail</h2><p><strong>Building stuff has always been the fun part for me.</strong></p><p>It’s why my side projects generally follow this pattern:</p><ol><li><p>Have an idea</p></li><li><p>Build something</p></li><li><p>Try (unsuccessfully) to get users</p></li><li><p>Give up and move on</p></li></ol><p><em><strong>How </strong></em><strong>I’ll acquire users was always an afterthought</strong> - something I did <em>after</em> there was a product for them to use.</p><p><strong>This time, I’m trying a different approach.</strong></p><blockquote><p>If a product ships in the woods, and no users are around to hear it, does it make money? <strong>🤔</strong></p></blockquote><h2>💸 From idea to revenue</h2><p><em><a href="https://www.themvpsprint.com/about">I’m a solo, bootstrapped founder</a> building a SaaS startup in public.</em></p><p>In <a href="https://mvpsprint.substack.com/p/choose-a-problem">Step One</a>, I chose a problem to work on.</p><p>In <a href="https://mvpsprint.substack.com/p/step-2-even-unicorns-walk-before-they-run">Step Two</a>, I chose my niche and my target users.</p><p>In <a href="https://www.themvpsprint.com/p/step-3-seeking-validation">Step Three</a>, I validated the problem for my target users.</p><p><strong>Last week, I created a distribution strategy for <a href="https://www.hellohailey.io/">HelloHailey</a> </strong>- <em>before</em> I wrote any code.</p><div><figure><a target="_blank" href="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F58a5127d-8d53-46e9-a8f0-28b412bc7c13_971x2774.png"><img src="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F58a5127d-8d53-46e9-a8f0-28b412bc7c13_971x2774.png" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/58a5127d-8d53-46e9-a8f0-28b412bc7c13_971x2774.png&quot;,&quot;height&quot;:2774,&quot;width&quot;:971,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:360,&quot;bytes&quot;:272065,&quot;alt&quot;:null,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;image/png&quot;,&quot;href&quot;:null}" alt=""></a></figure></div><p><strong>I’m sharing all my product decisions, metrics, successes, and failures in public.</strong></p><p>Want to get next Monday’s update?</p><p data-attrs="{&quot;url&quot;:&quot;https://www.themvpsprint.com/subscribe&quot;,&quot;text&quot;:&quot;Get my real-time case study&quot;,&quot;class&quot;:null}"><a href="https://www.themvpsprint.com/subscribe"><span>Get my real-time case study</span></a></p><h2>📣 Distribution <em>before</em> product</h2><p>Distribution is how a company gets their product in front of potential users.</p><p>You might think I’m crazy for thinking about how I’m going to sell a thing that doesn’t even exist yet. But when it comes to launching a software product, distribution is <em>at least</em> half the battle.</p><p><em><strong>If a product ships in the woods, and no users are around to hear it, does it make money? </strong></em><strong>🤔</strong><em><strong> </strong></em></p><h3>🚀 Silicon Valley’s biggest success stories are living proof</h3><h4>✉️ <strong>Hotmail (now Outlook)</strong></h4><p>Hotmail launched in 1996 and sold to Microsoft in 1998 for $400 million. They achieved viral growth by piggybacking on their users’ outgoing emails.</p><p>By appending <em>“Get your free email at Hotmail” </em>to every outgoing message, they quickly grew from 0 to 12 million users.</p><h4>🥳 <strong>Eventbrite</strong></h4><p>Events were a natural distribution channel. Attendees became event organizers, who invited more attendees, and so on.</p><h4>☁️ <strong>Dropbox</strong></h4><p>A viral referral program catapulted Dropbox from 100k users in 2008 to 33.9M in 2010.</p><h2>📝 Crafting my distribution strategy</h2><p>First, let’s revisit the problem I’m solving:</p><div><figure><a target="_blank" href="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fcb363612-4e16-499d-8440-7b477862ddc4_1122x688.png"><img src="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fcb363612-4e16-499d-8440-7b477862ddc4_1122x688.png" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/cb363612-4e16-499d-8440-7b477862ddc4_1122x688.png&quot;,&quot;height&quot;:688,&quot;width&quot;:1122,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:422,&quot;bytes&quot;:null,&quot;alt&quot;:null,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:null,&quot;href&quot;:null}" alt=""></a></figure></div><h3>📺 Anatomy of the perfect channel</h3><p>As I described in <a href="https://www.themvpsprint.com/p/step-2-even-unicorns-walk-before-they-run">Step Two</a> when I chose my niche, I want channels that are <strong>free</strong> with <strong>low barriers to entry</strong>.</p><ol><li><p><strong>Free</strong> - I don’t plan on paying to acquire users for a long time. “Cheap” isn’t good enough.</p></li><li><p><strong>Low barriers to entry</strong> - A long-term growth strategy that builds barriers is a wonderful thing. But I’m still in the validation phase and need users now.</p></li></ol><p><strong>My goal is to get in front of product and engineer leaders in tech</strong>.</p><p>Here’s where I think I can reach them:</p><h4>Outbound sales</h4><p>With an estimated Annual Contract Value (ACV) of around $1k, outbound sales won’t be profitable in the long-term.</p><p>For now, though, it’s a great way to hustle my way into the first 10, 20, or 30 customers.</p><h4><strong>The MVP Sprint mailing list</strong></h4><p>If you’re a product or engineering manager, this isn’t an article. It’s a distribution channel. 🙂</p><p>With almost 250 subscribers in its first three weeks giving me feedback and encouragement, <strong>it’s made the pre-product process fun for me.</strong></p><h4>Reddit</h4><p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ProductManagement/">r/ProductManagement</a> has ~40k readers. It’s an engaged community with lots of smart, motivated product people.</p><p>My early successes with posts for <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ProductManagement/comments/jmofq3/every_product_needs_a_niche_heres_the_criteria_i/">Step Two</a> and <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ProductManagement/comments/jqz961/how_i_validated_whether_people_will_use_and_pay/">Step Three</a> show that the community appreciates my content.</p><h4>Twitter</h4><p>Twitter is full of interesting and influential people sharing thoughts and having public conversations. And they’re all accessible - just 280 characters away.</p><h4>LinkedIn</h4><p>LinkedIn is a content-deficient platform - there’s more demand for quality content than supply.</p><p>And pretty much all product and engineering leaders spend time on the platform.</p><p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tjones4413/">Feel free to connect</a> and shoot me a message! 🙂</p><h4>SEO</h4><p>In the early days, I can hustle my way to 20-30% month-over-month growth.</p><p>But when 20% growth requires adding 20+ new companies, I need to be able to rely on more scalable channels.</p><p>I’m optimistic that SEO will be my best sustainable growth driver in the long-term.</p><h4>The product</h4><p>Eventbrite’s product was inherently viral. A product where employees get value by inviting their coworkers has the same potential for (intra-company) virality.</p><h3>🚗 Every channel needs a strategy</h3><p>A channel without a strategy is like a car without gas - it won’t take you anywhere.</p><p>I have two initial growth hypotheses:</p><h4>1. Product managers will engage with “meta” content about HelloHailey metrics and strategy</h4><p>If you’ve made it this far, and you’re a product manager, then you’re supporting my hypothesis.</p><p>I’ll share all my product decisions, metrics, successes, and failures in public. This product meta content will reel PM’s into my funnel. Some of them will convert into users.</p><div><figure><a target="_blank" href="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fbb26c16e-5642-48e7-ac3f-c860ec7037c8_4347x3148.png"><img src="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fbb26c16e-5642-48e7-ac3f-c860ec7037c8_4347x3148.png" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/bb26c16e-5642-48e7-ac3f-c860ec7037c8_4347x3148.png&quot;,&quot;height&quot;:1054,&quot;width&quot;:1456,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:null,&quot;bytes&quot;:752074,&quot;alt&quot;:null,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;image/png&quot;,&quot;href&quot;:null}" alt=""></a><figcaption>The HelloHailey growth funnel</figcaption></figure></div><h4>2. HelloHailey will expand within an organization through product-led growth (PLG)</h4><p>After acquiring the first user inside a new company, <strong>the product itself will drive growth</strong> <strong>within that company.</strong></p><ul><li><p>Hypothesis 1 is how I’ll acquire <strong>new companies.</strong></p></li><li><p>PLG is how I’ll grow <strong>within companies.</strong></p></li></ul><p>Products in my category have strong network effects - users get more value when more  of their coworkers join.</p><p>I can take advantage of this with a pricing structure that increases with user count, usage, or some similar value metric.</p><h4>How can I improve my distribution strategy?</h4><p>I like my strategy, but I know there are holes in it. Have any tips for me? Let me know in my Twitter thread:</p><p><strong>Or just show show me some love with a like or retweet.</strong> 😁</p><p>A little engagement goes a long way with the Twitter gods. 🙏</p><h2>🤔 Reducing uncertainty one week at a time</h2><div><figure><a target="_blank" href="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fcac3da08-e921-4064-b421-eebf46ef563b_920x248.png"><img src="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fcac3da08-e921-4064-b421-eebf46ef563b_920x248.png" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/cac3da08-e921-4064-b421-eebf46ef563b_920x248.png&quot;,&quot;height&quot;:248,&quot;width&quot;:920,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:490,&quot;bytes&quot;:29061,&quot;alt&quot;:null,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;image/png&quot;,&quot;href&quot;:null}" alt=""></a></figure></div><div><figure><a target="_blank" href="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fdb551976-985c-4556-b498-1619dde51c59_469x184.png"><img src="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fdb551976-985c-4556-b498-1619dde51c59_469x184.png" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/db551976-985c-4556-b498-1619dde51c59_469x184.png&quot;,&quot;height&quot;:184,&quot;width&quot;:469,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:509,&quot;bytes&quot;:23009,&quot;alt&quot;:null,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;image/png&quot;,&quot;href&quot;:null}" alt=""></a></figure></div><p>So now I have a good idea how I’ll reach users. <strong>But how will I get them to pay me money?</strong></p><p>This week, I’ll learn about the purchasing process - how companies purchase low-ticket SaaS products like <a href="https://www.hellohailey.io/">HelloHailey</a>.</p><p><strong>Here’s some of the questions I’ll try to answer:</strong></p><ol><li><p>Who can approve purchases?</p></li><li><p>What does the approval process look like?</p></li><li><p>From what budget(s) will companies pay for HelloHailey?</p></li></ol><p><strong>Want to get notified when it’s published?</strong> I’ll tell you what I learn next Monday, whether I succeed or fail.</p><p data-attrs="{&quot;url&quot;:&quot;https://www.themvpsprint.com/subscribe&quot;,&quot;text&quot;:&quot;Send me next week's update&quot;,&quot;class&quot;:null}"><a href="https://www.themvpsprint.com/subscribe"><span>Send me next week's update</span></a></p><p>I’ll be documenting my startup journey from idea to paying users over the coming weeks and months. I’d love to have you along for the ride.</p><p><em>Icons made by&nbsp;<a href="https://www.freepik.com/">Freepik</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.flaticon.com/authors/icongeek26">Icongeek26</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.flaticon.com/authors/pixel-perfect">Pixel perfect</a>&nbsp;from&nbsp;<a href="https://www.flaticon.com/">Flaticon</a></em></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.themvpsprint.com/p/how-and-when-to-acquire-saas-users</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25114214</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 17:15:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Psql command line tutorial and cheat sheet]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 305 | Comments 42 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25113440">thread link</a>) | @tomcam
<br/>
November 16, 2020 | https://tomcam.github.io/postgres/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://tomcam.github.io/postgres/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      
      
      

      

<p>You’ve installed PostgreSQL. Now what? I assume you’ve been given a task that 
uses <code>psql</code> and you want to learn the absolute minimum to
get the job done.</p>

<p>This is both a brief tutorial and a 
quick reference for the absolute least you need to know about <code>psql</code>. 
I assume you’re familiar with the command line and have a rough idea about
what database administration tasks, but aren’t familiar with how to
use <code>psql</code> to do the basics.</p>

<p>View on <a href="https://tomcam.github.io/postgres/">GitHub Pages</a> or directly on <a href="https://github.com/tomcam/postgres/">GitHub</a></p>

<p>The <a href="https://www.postgresql.org/docs/manuals/">PostgreSQL documentation</a> is incredibly 
well written and thorough, but frankly, I didn’t know where to start reading. This
is my answer to that problem.</p>

<p>If you have any complaints or suggestions please let me know by 
sending your feedback to tomcampbell@gmail.com.</p>

<p>It shows how to do the following at the <code>psql</code> prompt:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="#opening-a-connection-locally">Start and quit <code>psql</code></a></li>
  <li><a href="#h-help">Get help</a></li>
  <li><a href="#getting-information-about-databases">Get information about databases</a></li>
  <li><a href="#creating-a-database">Create databases</a></li>
  <li><a href="#creating-a-table-create-table">CREATE TABLEs</a></li>
  <li><a href="#adding-a-record-insert-into">INSERT, or add records to a table</a></li>
  <li><a href="#select">SELECT, to do simple queries</a></li>
  <li><a href="#reference">Reference</a> pointing to the official PostgreSQL documentation</li>
</ul>

<p>If you don’t have access to a live PostgreSQL installation at the moment we still have your back.
You can follow through the examples and the output is shown as if you
did type everything out.</p>

<h2 id="the-psql-command-line-utility">The psql command line utility</h2>

<p>Many administrative tasks can or should be done on your local machine, 
even though if database lives on the cloud.
You can do some of them through a visual user interface, but that’s not covered here. 
Knowing how to perform these operations on the command line means you can script them,
and scripting means you can automate tests, check errors, and do data entry on the command line.</p>

<p>This section isn’t a full cheat sheet for <code>psql</code>.
It covers the most common operations and shows them roughly in sequence, 
as you’d use them in a typical work session.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Starting and quitting the psql interactive terminal</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="#using-psql">Command-line prompts for psql</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="#quitting-pqsql">Quitting psql</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="#opening-a-connection-locally">Opening a connection locally</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="#opening-a-connection-remotely">Opening a connection remotely</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="#looking-at-the-psql-prompt">Using the psql prompt</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Getting information about databases</strong></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="#h-help">\h Help</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="#l-list-databases">\l List databases</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="#c-connect-to-a-database">\c Connect to a database</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="#dt-display-tables">\dt Display tables</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="#d-and-d-display-columns-field-names-of-a-table">\d and \d+ Display columns (field names) of a table</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="#du-display-user-roles">\du Display user roles</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Creating and using tables and records</strong></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="#creating-a-database">Creating a database</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="#creating-a-table-create-table">Creating a table (CREATE TABLE)</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="#adding-a-record-insert-into">Adding a record (INSERT INTO)</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="#adding-inserting-several-records-at-once">Inserting several records at once (INSERT INTO)</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="#adding-only-specific-columns-fields-from-a-record">Adding only specific fields from a record</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="#doing-a-simple-query--get-a-list-of-records-select">Doing a simple query–get a list of records (SELECT)</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Maintenance and operations</strong></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="#timing">Timing</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="#watch">Watch</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="#maintenance">Maintenance</a></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h2 id="what-you-need-to-know">What you need to know</h2>

<p>Before using this section, you’ll need:</p>

<ul>
  <li>The user name and password for your PostgreSQL database</li>
  <li>The IP address of your remote instance</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="command-line-prompts-on-the-operating-system">Command-line prompts on the operating system</h3>

<p>The <code>$</code> starting a command line in the examples below represents your operating system prompt. 
Prompts are configurable so it may well not look like this. 
On Windows it might look like <code>C:\Program Files\PostgreSQL&gt;</code> but Windows prompts are also configurable.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>$ psql -U sampleuser -h localhost
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>A line starting with <code>#</code> represents a comment. Same for everything to the right of a <code>#</code>. 
If you accidentally type it or copy and paste it in, don’t worry. Nothing will happen.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>This worked to connect to Postgres on DigitalOcean
<span># -U is the username (it will appear in the \l command)</span>
<span># -h is the name of the machine where the server is running.</span>
<span># -p is the port where the database listens to connections. Default is 5432.</span>
<span># -d is the name of the database to connect to. I think DO generated this for me, or maybe PostgreSQL.</span>
<span># Password when asked is csizllepewdypieiib</span>
<span>$ </span>psql <span>-U</span> doadmin <span>-h</span> production-sfo-test1-do-user-4866002-0.db.ondigitalocean.com <span>-p</span> 25060 <span>-d</span> mydb

<span># Open a database in a remote location.</span>
<span>$ </span>psql <span>-U</span> sampleuser <span>-h</span> production-sfo-test1-do-user-4866002-0.db.ondigitalocean.com <span>-p</span> 21334
</code></pre></div></div>
<h2 id="using-psql">Using psql</h2>

<p>You’ll use <code>psql</code> (aka the <a href="https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/app-psql.html">PostgreSQL interactive terminal</a>) most of all because it’s used to create databases and tables, show information about tables, and even to enter information (records) into the database.</p>

<h3 id="quitting-pqsql">Quitting pqsql</h3>

<p>Before we learn anything else, here’s how to quit <code>psql</code> and return to the operating system prompt.
You type backslash, the letter <code>q</code>, and then you press the Enter or return key.</p>

<div><div><pre><code># Press enter after typing \q
# Remember this is backslash, not forward slash
postgres=# \q
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This takes you back out to the operating system prompt.</p>

<h3 id="opening-a-connection-locally">Opening a connection locally</h3>

<p>A common case during development is opening a connection to a local database (one on your own machine).
Run <code>psql</code> with <code>-U</code> (for user name) followed by the name of the database, <code>postgres</code> in this example:</p>
<div><div><pre><code># Log into Postgres as the user named postgres
$ psql -U postgres
</code></pre></div></div>

<h3 id="opening-a-connection-remotely">Opening a connection remotely</h3>

<p>To connect your remote PostgreSQL instance from your local machine, use <code>psql</code> at your operating system command line.
Here’s a typical connection.</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span># -U is the username (it will appear in the \l command)</span>
<span># -h is the name of the machine where the server is running.</span>
<span># -p is the port where the database listens to connections. Default is 5432.</span>
<span># -d is the name of the database to connect to. I think DO generated this for me, or maybe PostgreSQL.</span>
<span>$ </span>psql <span>-U</span> doadmin <span>-h</span> production-sfo-test1-do-user-4866002-0.db.ondigitalocean.com <span>-p</span> 25060 <span>-d</span> defaultdb
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Here you’d enter the password. In case someone is peering over your shoulder, the characters are hidden. After you’ve entered your information properly you’ll get this message (truncated for clarity):</p>

<h3 id="looking-at-the-psql-prompt">Looking at the psql prompt</h3>
<p>A few things appear, then the <code>psql</code> prompt is displayed.
The name of the current database appears before the prompt.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>psql (11.1, server 11.0)
Type "help" for help.

postgres=# 
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>At this point you’re expected to type commands and parameters into the command line.</p>

<h3 id="psql-vs-sql-commands">psql vs SQL commands</h3>

<p><code>psql</code> has two different kinds of commands. Those starting with a backslash
are for <code>psql</code> itself, as illustrated by the use of <code>\q</code> to quit.</p>

<p>Those starting with valid SQL are of course interactive SQL used to
create and modify PostgreSQL databases.</p>

<h3 id="warning-sql-commands-end-with-a-semicolon">Warning: SQL commands end with a semicolon!</h3>

<p>One gotcha is that almost all SQL commands you enter into <code>psql</code> must end in a semicolon.</p>

<ul>
  <li>For example,suppose you want to remove a table named <code>sample_property_5</code>. You’d enter this command:</li>
</ul>

<div><div><pre><code>postgres=# DROP TABLE "sample_property_5";
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>It’s easy to forget. If you do forget the semicolon, you’ll see this perplexing prompt.
Note that a <code>[</code> has been inserted before the username portion of the prompt, and another
prompt appears below it:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>[postgres=# DROP TABLE "sample_property_5"
postgres=#

</code></pre></div></div>

<p>When you do, just remember to finish it off with that semicolon:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>[postgres=# DROP TABLE "sample_property_5"
postgres=# ;
</code></pre></div></div>

<h3 id="scrolling-through-the-command-history">Scrolling through the command history</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Use the up and down arrow keys to move backwards and forwards through the command history.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="getting-information-about-databases">Getting information about databases</h2>

<p>These aren’t SQL commands so just press Enter after them. Remember that:</p>

<ul>
  <li>When there’s more output than fits the screen, it pauses. Press space to continue</li>
  <li>If you want to halt the output, press <code>q</code>.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="h-help">\h Help</h3>

<div><div><pre><code># Get help. Note it's a backslash, not a forward slash.
postgres=# \h
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>You’ll get a long list of commands, then output is paused:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Available help:
  ABORT                            CREATE USER
  ...
  ALTER AGGREGATE                  CREATE USER MAPPING
  ALTER PROCEDURE                  DROP INDEX
:
</code></pre></div></div>

<ul>
  <li>Press space to continue, or <code>q</code> to stop the output.</li>
</ul>

<p>You can get help on a particular item by listing it after the <code>\h</code> command.</p>

<ul>
  <li>For example, to get help on <code>DROP TABLE</code>:</li>
</ul>

<pre><code>postgres=# \h drop table
</code></pre>

<p>You’ll get help on just tha item:</p>

<pre><code>Command:     DROP TABLE
Description: remove a table
Syntax:
DROP TABLE [ IF EXISTS ] name [, ...] [ CASCADE | RESTRICT ]
</code></pre>

<h3 id="l-list-databases">\l List databases</h3>

<p>What most people think of as a database (say, a list of customers) is actually a table. A database is a set of tables, information about those tables, information about users and their permissions, and much more. Some of these databases (and the tables within) are updated automatically by PostgreSQL as you use them.</p>

<p>To get a list of all databases:</p>

<pre><code>postgres=# \l
                                  List of databases
   Name    |  Owner   | Encoding |   Collate   |    Ctype    |   Access privileges   
-----------+----------+----------+-------------+-------------+-----------------------
 visitor   | tom      | UTF8     | en_US.UTF-8 | en_US.UTF-8 | 
 markets   | tom      | UTF8     | en_US.UTF-8 | en_US.UTF-8 | 
 postgres  | postgres | UTF8     | en_US.UTF-8 | en_US.UTF-8 | 
 template0 | postgres | UTF8     | en_US.UTF-8 | en_US.UTF-8 | =c/postgres          +
           |          |          |             |             | postgres=CTc/postgres
 template1 | postgres | UTF8     | en_US.UTF-8 | en_US.UTF-8 | =c/postgres          +
           |          |          |             |             | postgres=CTc/postgres
 tom       | tom      | UTF8     | en_US.UTF-8 | en_US.UTF-8 | 

</code></pre>

<p>You can get info on a single database by following the <code>\l</code> prompt with its name.</p>

<ul>
  <li>For example, to view information about the <code>template0</code> database:</li>
</ul>

<pre><code>postgres=# \l template0
</code></pre>

<p>The output would be:</p>

<pre><code>postgres=# \l
                                  List of databases
   Name    |  Owner   | Encoding |   Collate   |    Ctype    |   Access privileges   
-----------+----------+----------+-------------+-------------+-----------------------
 template0 | postgres | UTF8     | en_US.UTF-8 | en_US.UTF-8 | =c/postgres          +
           |          |          |             |             | postgres=CTc/postgres
</code></pre>

<h3 id="l-list-databases-with-size-tablespace-and-description">\l+ List databases with size, tablespace, and description</h3>

<p>To get additional information on the space consumed by database tables
and comments describing those tables, use <code>\l+</code>:</p>

<pre><code>postgres=# \l+
</code></pre>

<h3 id="x-expandnarrow-table-lists">\x Expand/narrow table lists</h3>

<p>Use <code>\x</code> (X for eXpanded listing) to control 
whether table listings use a wide or narrow format.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Command</th>
      <th>Effect</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td><code>\x off</code></td>
      <td>Show table listings in wide format</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><code>\x on</code></td>
      <td>Show table listings in narrow format</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><code>\x</code></td>
      <td>Reverse the previous state</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><code>\x auto</code></td>
      <td>Use terminal to determine format</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p><strong>Example:</strong> Here’s an expanded …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://tomcam.github.io/postgres/">https://tomcam.github.io/postgres/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://tomcam.github.io/postgres/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25113440</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 16:18:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Tools and Services I Use to Run My SaaS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 171 | Comments 34 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25112954">thread link</a>) | @jakelazaroff
<br/>
November 16, 2020 | https://jake.nyc/words/tools-and-services-i-use-to-run-my-saas/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jake.nyc/words/tools-and-services-i-use-to-run-my-saas/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Who doesn’t love a good stack teardown? Ever since I saw <a href="https://cushionapp.com/running-costs/">Cushion’s running costs</a> page, I’ve been low key addicted to reading about how other apps are built.</p>
<p>I work on an app called <a href="https://songrender.com/">SongRender</a> that helps musicians and podcasters make videos for social media. So in the spirit of the teardown, here are the tools and services I use to run it!</p>
<h3 id="languages">Languages</h3>
<p>This isn’t an exhaustive list — I’ve omitted some obvious ones (like HTML) and ones that are implied by other tooling choices (like HCL for Terraform).</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.typescriptlang.org/">TypeScript</a> — A superset of JavaScript with static types. I fell in love with this language when I first tried it a few years ago, and it’s only gotten better since then. I use it for both the frontend and server-side code.</li>
<li><a href="https://sass-lang.com/">SCSS</a> — A superset of CSS with cool features like mixins and nesting. I use it for both the marketing site and — with <a href="https://github.com/css-modules/css-modules">CSS modules</a> — the web app.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="build-systems-and-frameworks">Build Systems and Frameworks</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://reactjs.org/">React</a> — The frontend is a single-page app built with React, which has been a great choice — it gets out of the way and lets me just work on the app. There might be other frameworks out there that are quote unquote better, but the sheer size of the React community means I basically never run into any uncharted territory.</li>
<li><a href="https://create-react-app.dev/">Create React App</a> — A batteries-included build system for React. The first time I made a React app, I cobbled together the configuration for Webpack/Babel/etc myself. Create React App hides all that — with the option to “eject” and get the full configuration if I ever need to do something it doesn’t support.</li>
<li><a href="https://expressjs.com/">Express</a> — A Node.js server-side framework. Just like with React, I chose it because it’s the most popular by far. As for why I chose Node.js rather than another language, it’s because I need to run the same video rendering code in the browser and on the server.</li>
<li><a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo</a> — A fast static site generator written, used to build the marketing site.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="libraries">Libraries</h3>
<p>This list is also not exhaustive, but there are too many libraries to name them all here, so I’ve tried to keep it to the most notable or interesting ones.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://immerjs.github.io/immer/docs/introduction">immer</a> — An intuitive, performant way to do immutability. It can also serialize patches you make to an object, so it’s fairly easy to implement undo functionality as well.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.downshift-js.com/">downshift</a> — A React library for building accessible dropdowns and multi-selects. Easy to style, and you get accessibility for free.</li>
<li><a href="https://popper.js.org/">popper</a> — A nifty little tooltip positioning library.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/Automattic/node-canvas">node-canvas</a> — Node library for using the <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Canvas_API">canvas API</a> on the server.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.ffmpeg.org/">ffmpeg</a> — Swiss army knife audio and video library. I use this to on the server convert audio files to WAV and to combine individual frames into users' videos.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="infrastructure">Infrastructure</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.namecheap.com/">Namecheap</a> — Domain name registrar. Don’t get turned off by the slightly sketchy name — they’re my favorite registrar that I’ve used.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/">Cloudflare</a> — Provides DNS, SSL termination and DDOS protection for the websites and API.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.netlify.com/">Netlify</a> — Hosts static files for the app frontend and marketing site. It’s really easy to use and there’s a generous free tier.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/">DigitalOcean</a> — Cloud infrastructure provider, but with plain Linux servers rather than proprietary services. I use them for servers, databases, and object storage to host users' file uploads and videos. Their web UI and API are both really easy to use; I never want to go back to AWS. <a href="https://m.do.co/c/e506b6f94e20">💰 Affiliate link</a></li>
<li><a href="https://postmarkapp.com/">Postmark</a> — Transactional email provider. I switched from <a href="https://sendgrid.com/">SendGrid</a> when I exceeded their free tier and couldn’t get in touch with support, and boy am I glad I did. Postmark’s delivery rate is better, and the dashboard is faster and easier to use. If you’re a bootstrapped startup, they’ll give you a <a href="https://postmarkapp.com/for/bootstrapped-startups">$75 credit</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="databases">Databases</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.postgresql.org/">PostgreSQL</a> — Relational database for persisting the app’s data. I briefly considered <a href="https://www.mysql.com/">MySQL</a> as well, but PostgreSQL has a bunch of really nice features like <a href="https://www.postgresql.org/docs/9.5/dml-returning.html">returning data from modified rows</a>. I did not consider non-relational databases like <a href="https://www.mongodb.com/">MongoDB</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://redis.io/">Redis</a> — Key/value store, only used for a task queue. Usually I would put this part off and just build a monolith, but CPU-intensive video rendering needs its own server.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.influxdata.com/">InfluxDB</a> — Time-series database for storing metrics. See the section on <a href="#monitoring">monitoring</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="servers">Servers</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://ubuntu.com/">Ubuntu</a> — The Linux distribution that the servers run. Like other parts of the stack, I chose it because it’s one of the most popular.</li>
<li><a href="https://nginx.org/">nginx</a> — A web server and reverse proxy, used here as a load balancer for the API servers.</li>
<li><a href="https://systemd.io/">systemd</a> — A daemon that manages the processes&nbsp;on the server, like Node.js and nginx. <a href="https://pm2.keymetrics.io/">pm2</a> is another popular one, but it’s Node-specific.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="deploying">Deploying</h3>
<p>I’ve previously written about how I deploy SongRender, so you can <a href="https://jake.nyc/words/bluegreen-deploys-and-immutable-infrastructure-with-terraform/">read about it in more depth</a> if you’re interested. If you just want the high level, these are the tools involved.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.terraform.io/">Terraform</a> — An “infrastructure as code” tool, where you describe the infrastructure you want and it diffs with the infrastructure that actually exists. Kind of like React, but for configuration management. I love Terraform, and I use it to manage any infrastructure it supports.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.packer.io/">Packer</a> — A tool for building machine images. This makes it easy to deploy servers with Terraform.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="monitoring">Monitoring</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://sentry.io/organizations/songrender/issues/">Sentry</a> — Error tracking. Picks up any uncaught exceptions in the client- and server-side code.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.statuscake.com/">Statuscake</a> — Uptime monitoring, making sure the website and API don’t go down. Chosen for its generous free tier.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.papertrail.com/">Papertrail</a> — Log management. It forwards system log messages using <code>rsyslog</code>, so I can just use <code>console.log</code> in my server-side code and have it picked up. At some point I might try to switch to a service that supports structured logs, like <a href="https://timber.io/">Timber</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.influxdata.com/time-series-platform/telegraf/">Telegraf</a> — Agent that collects metrics from the servers and forwards them to InfluxDB. It makes it very easy to get metrics on CPU/memory/etc without paying an arm and a leg for something like <a href="https://www.datadoghq.com/">Datadog</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://grafana.com/">Grafana</a> — Metrics dashboard that displays data from InfluxDB and PostgreSQL. It’s easy to set up and use, and its visualizations are pretty.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="analytics">Analytics</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.indicative.com/">Indicative</a> — App analytics. I was using <a href="https://mixpanel.com/">Mixpanel</a>, but I ended up exceeding their free tier — which was a shame, because I liked them a lot more. Might check out <a href="https://amplitude.com/">Amplitude</a> when I have time.</li>
<li><a href="https://usefathom.com/">Fathom</a> — Website visitor stats for the marketing page and app. It’s simpler than Google Analytics and only $15 per month for small sites. <a href="https://usefathom.com/ref/WBX5G9">💰 Affiliate link</a></li>
<li><a href="https://search.google.com/search-console/about">Google Search console</a> — Analytics about Google searches for which SongRender has shown up in the results.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="payments">Payments</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://stripe.com/">Stripe</a> — Credit card processing and subscriptions. I <strong>love</strong> using Stripe. Their APIs are so well thought-out, the developer tooling is great and their documentation and dashboard are beautiful and easy to use. Their support is also responsive and helpful. I had such a positive experience with them that I registered SongRender LLC with Stripe Atlas, even though it cost a bit more than doing it manually.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.paypal.com/">PayPal</a> — Additional payment option. As happy as I am with Stripe, I’m that unhappy with PayPal: their tooling is lackluster, their documentation is not comprehensive and their website is slow. It’s also clearly not meant as a payment option for in-app purchases — for example, if you’re a new merchant, they’ll hold payments for a few weeks unless you upload a shipping label, which I obviously can’t do. People seem to like having it as a payment option, though.</li>
<li><a href="https://mercury.com/">Mercury</a> — My business bank. One of the three options Stripe recommended as part of Atlas.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="design">Design</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.sketch.com/">Sketch</a> — Vector graphics editor. I designed the SongRender logo using this, and I touch up icons with it too. I tend to go back and forth between this and <a href="https://www.figma.com/">Figma</a>, which I also really like — but there’s still an appeal to using a <a href="https://www.sketch.com/blog/2020/10/26/part-of-your-world-why-we-re-proud-to-build-a-truly-native-mac-app/">native app</a> that doesn’t store all my data in the nebulous cloud.</li>
<li><a href="https://nucleoapp.com/">Nucleo</a> — Library of SVG icons. I bought the lifetime package years ago and have used it in basically every project since. <a href="https://nucleoapp.com/?ref=427">💰 Affiliate link</a></li>
<li><a href="https://jakearchibald.github.io/svgomg/">SVGOMG</a> — Nifty web app that cleans up and compresses SVGs. It’s basically a frontend for <a href="https://github.com/svg/svgo">SVGO</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://squoosh.app/">squoosh</a> — Nitfy web app that compresses PNGs and JPGs; the raster image counterpart to SVGOMG.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="development">Development</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/">VS Code</a> — Not quite a text editor, not quite an IDE. Probably the best Electron app I’ve ever used. I keep checking out <a href="https://nova.app/">Nova</a> out of a love for all things Panic, but it’s not quite there yet.</li>
<li><a href="https://postgresapp.com/">Postgres.app</a> — Simple free local PostgreSQL server for macOS.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/amacneil/dbmate">dbmate</a> — Language- and database-agnostic migration tool.</li>
<li><a href="https://gitlab.com/">Gitlab</a> — Source code hosting and versioning.</li>
<li><a href="https://prettier.io/">Prettier</a> — Code formatter for JavaScript, HTML and CSS. If you’ve never used a code formatter before, do it now. It’ll change your life.</li>
<li><a href="https://jestjs.io/">Jest</a> — Test runner for JavaScript. Bundled with Create React App.</li>
<li><a href="https://yarnpkg.com/">Yarn</a> — Alternative package manager for Node.</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Make_(software)">Make</a> — SongRender doesn’t need to be compiled, so this is just a task runner. <a href="https://www.thapaliya.com/en/writings/well-documented-makefiles/">Self-documenting Makefile snippets</a> are super helpful.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="debugging">Debugging</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://eggerapps.at/postico/">Postico</a> — Great indie Mac app for querying Postgres databases.</li>
<li><a href="https://insomnia.rest/">Insomnia</a> — HTTP client. I use this sometimes when I’m working on the API and don’t want to worry about the browser. I also use it as a very crude admin dashboard: the API has a few admin endpoints for things like retrying a failed render, which I hit directly from Insomnia. <a href="https://paw.cloud/">Paw</a> is a non-Electron alternative that I’ll spend the $50 on at some point.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.panic.com/transmit/">Transmit</a> — File transfer app. I use this whenever I need to poke around object storage, since it’s much easier than using DigitalOcean’s web-based file browser.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="support">Support</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://crisp.chat/">Crisp</a> — In-app support chat. It’s the slickest, least obtrusive one I could find with a free tier. I’d like to switch to <a href="https://www.intercom.com/">Intercom</a> but can’t justify the cost.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="organization">Organization</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://trello.com/">Trello</a> — A kanban board for keeping track of bugs and features. A killer feature for me is the ability to add checklists to cards. Before I deploy a feature, I make an exhaustive checklist of cases to test. I’ve caught so many bugs this way; checklists should be a crucial tool in any developer’s QA arsenal. <a href="https://blog.nuclino.com/the-simple-genius-of-checklists-from-b-17-to-the-apollo-missions">Checklists work</a>! <a href="https://trello.com/jakelazaroff/recommend">💰 Affiliate link</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.notion.so/">Notion</a> — A repository for less structured note-taking.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.fastmail.com/">Fastmail</a> — The email provider I use <a href="https://jake.nyc/words/giving-up-google">instead of Gmail</a>. <a href="https://ref.fm/u20086848">💰 Affiliate link</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="marketing">Marketing</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://flyingmeat.com/acorn/">Acorn</a> — Raster&nbsp;image editor. I mostly use it as a lightweight Photoshop alternative when I need to tweak screenshots.</li>
<li><a href="https://ia.net/writer">iA Writer</a> — Markdown …</li></ul></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://jake.nyc/words/tools-and-services-i-use-to-run-my-saas/">https://jake.nyc/words/tools-and-services-i-use-to-run-my-saas/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jake.nyc/words/tools-and-services-i-use-to-run-my-saas/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25112954</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 15:36:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I failed to make LinkedIn fix their broken international domain URL parser]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 210 | Comments 79 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25111142">thread link</a>) | @helstegt
<br/>
November 16, 2020 | https://helmstedt.dk/2020/11/how-i-failed-to-make-linkedin-fix-their-broken-url-parser-for-international-domain-names/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://helmstedt.dk/2020/11/how-i-failed-to-make-linkedin-fix-their-broken-url-parser-for-international-domain-names/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



		<div>



			
<p>In Denmark it is possible to register domains with funny characters such as æ, ø and å. And we do. One prominent example is our national portal for booking Covid-19 tests at <a href="https://xn--coronaprver-ngb.dk/">https://coronaprøver.dk</a>. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internationalized_domain_name">Wikipedia calls these beasts Internationalised domain names</a>, so they must indeed exist.</p>



<p>Recently I quit my job (have a new one now, luckily) and found myself making posts on a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/">social network known as LinkedIn</a> to improve my prospects.</p>



<p>One of these posts was about about a hobby project I made called <a href="https://wishlist.dk/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://wishlist.dk">wishlist.dk</a>, an ad free wish registry. The big player on the Danish wish registry market (what a market: it seems every novice web developer in Denmark has launched one of these) is <a href="https://xn--nskeskyen-k8a.dk/">https://<strong>ø</strong>nskeskyen.dk</a>.</p>



<p>What I wanted to let my network know was something like:</p>



<blockquote><p>“I have launched wishlist.dk – a gratis, ad and surveilance free alternative to evil wish list giant ønskeskyen.dk”</p><cite>– Morten Helmstedt, job seeker</cite></blockquote>



<p>Alas, LinkedIn’s URL parser breaks in many ways when trying to express your career news and feelings through internationalised domain names.</p>



<h3>How do thee fail? Let me count the ways.</h3>



<p>When making a post on LinkedIn with an URL, LinkedIn will try to:</p>



<ul><li>Create a preview of the first URL in the post</li><li>Create a short link for all URLs in the post containing a path (e.g. https://lindkedin.com/<em>path</em>), not for top level domains and subdomains without a path. It will generally look like and point to something like <em>https://lnkd.in/eCTD8Q9</em></li></ul>



<p>Here are the bugs I noticed in action:</p>



<h4>Posting like a sane person</h4>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="545" height="352" src="https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin1.png" alt="" srcset="https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin1.png 545w, https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin1-300x194.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 545px) 100vw, 545px"><figcaption>Trying to post an internationalised domain name like any sane person would. Post preview fails to load. The link in the post itself works as expected, though.</figcaption></figure>



<h4>Posting like a LinkedIn person</h4>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="550" height="648" src="https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin2.png" alt="" srcset="https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin2.png 550w, https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin2-255x300.png 255w" sizes="(max-width: 550px) 100vw, 550px"><figcaption>Whois’ing the “real” domain name and posting it like no true Dane would. Post preview succeeds.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Things go from bad to worse when trying to post an internationalised domain name with a path such as <a href="https://xn--nskeskyen-k8a.dk/text/cookies">https://ønskeskyen.dk/text/cookies</a>.</p>



<p>If I just post that URL, I get a post like this:</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin3.png" alt="" width="540" height="142" srcset="https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin3.png 540w, https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin3-300x79.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 540px) 100vw, 540px"><figcaption>LinkedIn shortens the link to make it more readable and to be able to track our smallest actions on the world wide web.</figcaption></figure>



<p>What happens when I click the link is this:</p>



<h4>INVALID REDIRECT</h4>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="773" height="319" src="https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin4.png" alt="" srcset="https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin4.png 773w, https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin4-300x124.png 300w, https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin4-768x317.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 773px) 100vw, 773px"><figcaption>An error! (Invalid redirect)</figcaption></figure>



<p>My browser (Firefox) tries to GET the URL and is redirected to <em>linkedin.com/slink</em>:</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="374" height="235" src="https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin5.png" alt="" srcset="https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin5.png 374w, https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin5-300x189.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 374px) 100vw, 374px"><figcaption>A 301 redirect in action!</figcaption></figure>



<p>And then:</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="357" height="381" src="https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin6.png" alt="" srcset="https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin6.png 357w, https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin6-281x300.png 281w" sizes="(max-width: 357px) 100vw, 357px"><figcaption>The submitted URL is stored, but the location should probably be <a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://xn--nskeskyen-k8a.dk/text/cookies">https://%C3%B8nskeskyen.dk/text/cookies</a> or maybe even <a href="https://xn--nskeskyen-k8a.dk/text/cookies">https://xn--nskeskyen-k8a.dk/text/cookies</a>. Who knows? It’s complicated. LinkedIn engineers should definitely look into this!</figcaption></figure>



<h2>How I tried to fix this mess</h2>



<p>Well, I contacted LinkedIn on Twitter (WHAT!), tried e-mailing their security e-mail (no reply, of course, but only e-mail I could find) and got in touch with a very understanding Member Support Consultant named Vegard who tried his/her best:</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="797" height="508" src="https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin8.png" alt="" srcset="https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin8.png 797w, https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin8-300x191.png 300w, https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin8-768x490.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 797px) 100vw, 797px"><figcaption>Pretty impressive response after describing the problem.</figcaption></figure>



<h4>If our URL parser doesn’t work, just change your URL</h4>



<p>But then the engineering team told me that I should just stop posting internationalised domain names to LinkedIn:</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin9.png" alt="" width="610" height="471" srcset="https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin9.png 808w, https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin9-300x232.png 300w, https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin9-768x593.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 610px) 100vw, 610px"><figcaption>True for Chrome, not for Firefox, not from a usability perspective</figcaption></figure>



<p>I tried to have Vegard tell the engineers at LinkedIn to read up on internationalised domain names, but no such luck: </p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="793" height="571" src="https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin10.png" alt="" srcset="https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin10.png 793w, https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin10-300x216.png 300w, https://helmstedt.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/linkedin10-768x553.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 793px) 100vw, 793px"><figcaption>The sorry end.</figcaption></figure>



<h2>THE END</h2>



<h2>An aside:</h2>



<p>As another hobby project, I created <a href="https://lnk.dk/">lnk.dk</a>, a very simple short link generator (like wish registries, it seems every aspiring web developer in Denmark has made one of these). Using <a href="https://www.djangoproject.com/">Django</a>‘s built in <code>URLField</code> I can validate, store and correctly redirect internationalised domain names with hardly any work at all on my part.</p>



<p><em>If only tools like that were available for the engineers at LinkedIn to use for their URL parsing and shortening…</em></p>



		</div><!-- .entry-content -->



	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://helmstedt.dk/2020/11/how-i-failed-to-make-linkedin-fix-their-broken-url-parser-for-international-domain-names/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25111142</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 13:07:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Emacs in odd places]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 158 | Comments 46 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25108697">thread link</a>) | @catacombs
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://www.eigenbahn.com/2020/09/02/emacs-in-odd-places | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.eigenbahn.com/2020/09/02/emacs-in-odd-places">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main" role="main"><article role="article"><h2 id="unfamiliar-situations">Unfamiliar situations</h2><p>I find it amusing spotting familiar software in equally unfamiliar situations.</p><p>One of those situations is when it <a href="https://ilikeinterfaces.com/">makes a cameo in fiction</a>, with examples such as <a href="https://nmap.org/movies/">nmap</a> and the <a href="https://boingboing.net/2011/04/06/how-emacs-got-into-t.html">inclusion of Emacs &amp; eshell in Tron Legacy</a>.</p><p>Another unfamiliar situation is when the software runs on an unexpected hardware or OS.</p><blockquote><p>Can it run Doom?</p></blockquote><p>Doom is the king of this category.</p><p>It’s common sense that almost every device with a bare minimum of computing power <a href="https://itrunsdoom.tumblr.com/">can run Doom</a><sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup>.</p><h2 id="emacs-on-odd-hardware--software">Emacs on odd hardware &amp; software</h2><p>Emacs has in essence less potential than Doom due to its comparatively hefty requirements (especially its modern versions).</p><p>But that just forces us to take other approaches:</p><ul><li>Use an early Emacs version compatible with the device</li><li>Use a fork/clone with low system requirements: <a href="https://github.com/torvalds/uemacs">uEmacs</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JOVE">JOVE</a></li><li>Use our odd hardware as a dumb terminal connecting to a remote modern version of Emacs</li></ul><p>The first approach is basically called <a href="https://www.eigenbahn.com/tag/retrocomputing/">retrocomputing</a> and can be painfully cumbersome. It’s only reserved to the most stubborn internet archive dvelvers.</p><p>The third approach works surprisingly well as Emacs kept good support for terminal rendering<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2">2</a></sup>.</p><p>Actually this goes further as the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/notes/daniel-colascione/buttery-smooth-emacs/10155313440066102">GUI rendering is built on top of the TUI codebase</a>.</p><blockquote><p>Whoever made Emacs into a native X11 program […] pretended the GUI was a text terminal. – Daniel Colascione</p></blockquote><h2 id="emacs-on-the-go">Emacs on the Go</h2><p>Another appeal of exploring alternative hardware is the perspective of having an Emacs instance on the go.</p><p>Nowadays the best approach is to have an Android device with Emacs installed through <a href="https://termux.com/">Termux</a> and a bluetooth keyboard.</p><p>Most people use a smartphone. If the screen feels too small, one can use a tablet<sup id="fnref:4" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:4">3</a></sup>.</p><p>As far as Org-mode is concerned, we nowadays have decent applications such as <a href="http://www.orgzly.com/">Orgzly</a> (Android), <a href="https://beorgapp.com/">beorg</a> (iOS), <a href="https://organice.200ok.ch/">organice</a> and <a href="https://org-web.org/">org-web</a> (web, mobile-friendly).</p><p>Back in 2007, smartphones (as we know them) where in their infancy and I was in dire need for a solution.</p><p>At the time, the only possibility was to find an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ultra-mobile_PC">UMPC</a>. Without much money in the bank, I settled for an old (even for the time) HP Jornada 680, bought secondhand for not much.</p><p>It ran a custom version of Windows CE (in German) but a distribution of Linux (<a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20160301064554/http://jlime.com/wiki/home">Jlime</a>) could be run on it.</p><p>Emacs wasn’t available in its repositories but I was able to compile it after fetching all of its dependencies.</p><p>And here I was, with my little <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_island">data island</a> in my backpack.</p><p><img src="https://www.eigenbahn.com/assets/img/emacs_on_hp_jornada_680.jpg" alt="emacs_on_hp_jornada_680"></p><p>My <a href="https://github.com/p3r7/retro-dot-emacs">config from these old days</a> was pretty barebone as compared to the <a href="https://github.com/p3r7/emacs.d">current incarnation</a>.</p><h2 id="emacs-on-a-actual-dumb-terminal">Emacs on a actual dumb terminal</h2><p>Even the most recent versions of Emacs still have <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/html_node/emacs/Terminal-Init.html">stellar support for hardware terminals</a>.</p><p>I don’t know who (apart from a few enthusiasts like me) still access Emacs through those devices.</p><p>There are some configuration specificities (addressed in a later post) but things mostly just work.</p><p><img src="https://www.eigenbahn.com/assets/img/emacs_on_dec_vt320.jpg" alt="emacs_on_dec_vt320"></p><h2 id="other-examples-spotted-in-the-wild">Other examples spotted in the wild</h2><h4 id="esotheric-os">Esotheric OS</h4><p>Emacs under <a href="https://depot.haiku-os.org/#!/pkg/emacs/haikuports/26/2/-/-/1/x86_64?bcguid=bc157-URXX">Haiku</a> (<a href="https://imgur.com/GCa6CFK">screenshot</a>).</p><h3 id="hardware-dumb-terminals">Hardware (dumb) terminals</h3><p>Emacs through a <a href="https://twitter.com/CanalEDTA/status/721345151214465024">Minitel 1B</a>.</p><h4 id="niche-linux-based-smartphones">Niche Linux-based smartphones</h4><p>Emacs on the <a href="https://twitter.com/puri_sm/status/1144394797517402114">Purism Librem 5</a>.</p><p>Emacs on the <a href="https://social.pixie.town/@theonefreeman/103623829020543902">PinePhone</a></p><p>Emacs under <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/unixporn/comments/1wwpe3/gnu_emacs_in_sailfish_os/">Jolla SailfishOS</a>.</p><p>Emacs (GUI version) under <a href="https://imgur.com/ZGWH6Nm">Ubuntu Touch</a>.</p><h4 id="older-phones">Older phones</h4><p>Emacs 23 running natively on the <a href="https://talk.maemo.org/showthread.php?s=c5e3e5b32f8fe6d2a08d76503164c9d5&amp;t=37241">Nokia N900</a> (<a href="https://talk.maemo.org/attachment.php?s=c5e3e5b32f8fe6d2a08d76503164c9d5&amp;attachmentid=7364&amp;stc=1&amp;d=1266616914">screenshot</a>)<sup id="fnref:3" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:3">4</a></sup>.</p><p>Emacs accessed from SSH on an <a href="http://archive.eglug.org/node/27">old Nokia phone</a>.</p><h4 id="pdas-and-umpcs">PDAs and UMPCs</h4><p>Emacs on the <a href="https://twitter.com/komecha/status/1021370513707347969">GeminiPDA</a> (Android-based).</p><p>Emacs on the <a href="http://muru.com/linux/psion/kernel/">Psion 5mx</a>.</p><p>Emacs 21 running natively on the <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20160426190322/http://pda.sukareruhito.com/2007/05/zaurus_slc1000emacshowm.html">Sharp Zaurus SL-C1000</a><sup id="fnref:5" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:5">5</a></sup>.</p><p>uEmacs fork <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20060610210357/http://tillanosoft.com/ce/ngj.html">Ng</a> on the <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20150514125016/http://pda.sukareruhito.com/2007/05/x01htemacsng_for_win32micro_em.html">SoftBank X01HT</a>.</p><p>Emacs accessed from SSH under <a href="http://www.sealiesoftware.com/pssh/">Palm OS 5</a>.</p><h4 id="single-board-computers">Single board computers</h4><p>Emacs on the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/emacs/comments/ajwtcb/emacs_on_the_go/">Pocket C.H.I.P.</a>.</p><p>Emacs on the <a href="https://twitter.com/noodle_pi/status/996427835630747648">Noodle Pi</a>.</p><h4 id="smartwatches">Smartwatches</h4><p>Emacs on a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/emacs/comments/7oqr5s/i_must_have_emacs_on_everything_even_my_smartwatch/">Pebble watch</a> (this one is actually just a “face”, not the real deal).</p><h2 id="hacker-news">Hacker News</h2><p>I was quite surprised to see that this post got submitted to Hacker News and <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25108697#25111009">won the front page lottery</a>.</p><h2 id="notes">Notes</h2><p> Tagged <a href="https://www.eigenbahn.com/tag/emacs">#emacs</a>, <a href="https://www.eigenbahn.com/tag/retrocomputing">#retrocomputing</a>, <a href="https://www.eigenbahn.com/tag/vt320">#vt320</a>.</p><hr> </article></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.eigenbahn.com/2020/09/02/emacs-in-odd-places</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25108697</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 06:22:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Short History of Romaji]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 58 | Comments 43 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25108455">thread link</a>) | @polm23
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://www.dampfkraft.com/romaji-history.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.dampfkraft.com/romaji-history.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I recently created a tool called <a href="https://github.com/polm/cutlet">cutlet</a> for converting Japanese to romaji.
While working on cutlet I was surprised at the difficulty of finding a good
guide to the difference between romaji systems, particularly their history and
usage, so I wrote this up.</p>
<h2 id="a-romaji-refresher"> A Romaji Refresher</h2>
<p>There are three relatively well-defined romaji systems. For a quick overview of
some of their differences:</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Japanese</th>
<th>新橋</th>
<th>お茶漬け</th>
<th>富士山</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Hepburn</td>
<td>Shinbashi (or Shimbashi)</td>
<td>ochazuke</td>
<td>Fujisan</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Kunreisiki</td>
<td>Sinbasi</td>
<td>otyazuke</td>
<td>Huzisan</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Nipponsiki</td>
<td>Sinbasi</td>
<td>otyaduke</td>
<td>Huzisan</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Hepburn is the most widely used outside Japan, Kunreisiki is officially taught
to children in Japan. Nipponsiki is similar to Kunreisiki but older. Technically
Hepburn uses macrons for long vowels while Kunreisiki and Nipponsiki use
circumflexes, but usage isn't consistent and there's no difference in meaning
between them.</p>
<p>In recent years "wapuro" romaji, based on input when typing Japanese, are also
relatively common, but it's not systematized (except in as far as programs
either take or don't take certain sequences) and isn't used in any kind of
formal writing.</p>
<h2 id="particle-comparison"> Particle Comparison</h2>
<p>As another refresher, here's how non-phonetic particles are represented in the
various systems.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Japanese</th>
<th>は</th>
<th>を</th>
<th>へ</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Hepburn</td>
<td>wa</td>
<td>wo</td>
<td>e</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Kunreisiki</td>
<td>wa</td>
<td>o</td>
<td>e</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Nipponsiki</td>
<td>ha</td>
<td>wo</td>
<td>he</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Hepburn is phonetic except for <em>wo</em>, Kunreisiki is strictly phonetic, and
Nipponsiki is strictly orthographic.</p>
<h2 id="early-romaji"> Early Romaji</h2>
<p>Japanese was first written in the Latin alphabet in the 1600s, mainly by
Christian missionaries. It was used by the missionaries for recording and
learning the language, and also used in texts they produced to try to spread
Christianity. Since Christianity was later supressed in Japan, these forms of
romaji never had wide adoption, though they influenced later efforts.</p>
<h2 id="the-origins-of-the-hepburn-system"> The Origins of the Hepburn System</h2>
<p>In 1867, missionary <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Curtis_Hepburn#Missionary_work_in_Japan">James Curtis Hepburn</a> published a
Japanese-English dictionary in Yokohama. Naturally he needed some way to write
Japanese words for people who couldn't read Japanese, so he devised a system of
representing Japanese that reflected the pronunciation of English consonants.
His system wasn't designed from the ground up, but developed based on his
knowledge of existing systems by other missionaries as well as his own
knowledge of Japanese.</p>
<p>Somewhat later, in 1885, an organization known as the
<a href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E3%83%AD%E3%83%BC%E3%83%9E%E5%AD%97%E8%AB%96#%E3%83%AD%E3%83%BC%E3%83%9E%E5%AD%97%E4%BC%9A">羅馬字会</a>
(Romajikai) was established. Mainly a society of Japanese academics, it was
interested in promoting the use of romaji as a replacement for kana and kanji.
Some motivations for getting rid of native writing systems included easier
international communication and improved domestic literacy. The principle
founders were <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ry%C5%8Dkichi_Yatabe">Ryoukichi Yatabe</a>, a botanist and the first Japanese graduate of Cornell, and <a href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E5%A4%96%E5%B1%B1%E6%AD%A3%E4%B8%80">Masakazu Toyama</a>, a <a href="https://ii.umich.edu/cjs/history-of-cjs.html">graduate of the University of Michigan</a> who
later occupied a high post at what would eventually become Tokyo University.</p>
<figure><a href="https://www.dampfkraft.com/by-id/4d041d6a/max-moritz-romaji.jpg"><img src="https://www.dampfkraft.com/by-id/4d041d6a/img/max-moritz-romaji.jpg.l.jpg"></a><figcaption>The Romajikai published books to promote romaji, including this translation of Max and Moritz, titled "Wampaku Monogatari". This edition was reprinted in 1978. via <a href="https://www.wul.waseda.ac.jp/kotenseki/html/he22/he22_07214/index.html">Waseda University</a>
</figcaption></figure>
<p>In 1886 the Romajikai published <a href="https://dl.ndl.go.jp/info:ndljp/pid/862485">a romaji system</a>. Also in 1886
Hepburn published the third edition of his dictionary, which roughly used the
system.  I've had trouble finding the exact nature of the influence between
Hepburn's system and the Romajikai, but they were on friendly terms and
cooperating. Hepburn's dictionary's third edition took off, the romaji system
mainly came to be called by his name, and it became widely established,
particularly among foreigners dealing with Japan.</p>
<p>If you're interested in learning more about Hepburn's dictionaries, a <a href="http://www.meijigakuin.ac.jp/mgda/waei/">wealth
of information</a> is available via Meiji Gakuin University
Library, including a comparison of romaji in all published versions and
manuscripts.</p>
<h2 id="the-origins-of-the-nipponsiki-system"> The Origins of the Nipponsiki System</h2>
<p>Around the time the Romajikai was established, one of the members, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tanakadate_Aikitsu">Aikitu
Tanakadate</a>, developed his
own romaji system, based on some existing informal conventions, that was
specifically designed to mirror the structure of Japanese kana without regard
to foreign pronunciation.</p>
<p>In 1885 Tanakadate proposed this new system to the Romajikai, but they
ultimately rejected his proposal in favor of keeping Hepburn. As a result
Tanakadate left the Romajikai and promoted Nipponsiki on his own. Before
becoming known as "Nipponsiki" this style of Romanization was known as
"Tanakadatesiki".</p>
<p>The disagreement between Tanakadate was only the first in a long series of
arguments between Hepburn and Nipponsiki proponents.</p>
<p>Tanakadate was around 30 when he invented this system, and most of his later
career was in physics. He worked with Lord Kelvin in Scotland and helped bring
about the adoption of the metric system in Japan. He used romaji in personal
writings and promoted it throughout his life. We'll be seeing him again later.</p>
<h2 id="standard-form-and-the-romaji-hirome-kai"> Standard Form and the Romaji Hirome Kai</h2>
<p>In 1905 the ローマ字ひろめ会 (Romaji Hirome Kai, "Society for the Advancement
of Romaji") was established. They published a magazine, called simply "Rômaji",
to create more reading material in romaji and spread its use within Japan.  By
this point Toyama and Yatabe had both passed away, and it's unclear if the
original Romajikai still existed in any capacity. An important early member of
the new society was <a href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E8%97%A4%E5%B2%A1%E5%8B%9D%E4%BA%8C">Katsuji Fujioka</a>, who wrote the
<a href="https://dl.ndl.go.jp/info:ndljp/pid/942994">羅馬字手引</a> (Romaji Tebiki), a kind of romaji dictionary.</p>
<p>Shortly after it was founded the Romaji Hirome Kai proposed a slightly modified
Hepburn and called it 標準式, or "Standard Form". Note that this is "Standard
Form" in general, not "Standard Hepburn", suggesting this was some kind of
official standard romanization system; this may have been a response to
Tanakadatesiki becoming known as "Nipponsiki", which could imply that other
romaji systems were "foreign". As we'll see in a bit, this rhetorical trick
ultimately didn't help official adoption.</p>
<p>I haven't been able to track down the original document with Standard Form, but
the Romaji Tebiki was already using it in 1906.</p>
<p>Standard Form replaced macrons with circumflexes and always romanized ん as
"n", rather than sometimes using "m" depending on the following consonant.</p>
<p>Tanakadate was still around and joined the Romaji Hirome Kai at some point, but
got fed up with their use of Hepburn, left, and founded his own organization in
1914.</p>
<h2 id="the-origins-of-kunreisiki"> The Origins of Kunreisiki</h2>
<p>In 1930 the government formed a committee to evaluate various romaji systems
for official government use. At this point Tanakadate was a member of the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/House_of_Peers_(Japan)">House of Peers</a>, and Romaji Hirome Kai member and Hepburn proponent
Fujioka was not a politician, but had political influence due to his long and
prominent career as a linguist. Both were involved with the government
committee.</p>
<p>While the system used at this point varied considerably by government agency,
Hepburn was more popular, so it seemed slated for official adoption.  However,
in 1935 Fujioka died of illness. In 1937, following a recommendation from the
committee, a slightly modified version of Tanakadate's Nipponsiki, dubbed
Kunreisiki, was established as the official government romaji system.</p>
<p>The main difference between Kunreisiki and Nipponsiki is that kana that are not
pronounced differently in standard modern Japanese are spelled as their more
common counterpart (づ and ず are both <em>zu</em>), though there are other
differences, like how particles are represented, and how ambiguous phonetic
boundaries are written.</p>
<h2 id="the-war"> The War</h2>
<p>Despite the recent official adoption of a government-approved romaji system,
around 1938 a number of more radical romaji proponents were arrested as
potential (or actual) anti-nationalists. One example was Esperantist and
language researcher <a href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E6%96%8E%E8%97%A4%E7%A7%80%E4%B8%80">Hidekatsu Saitou</a>, who contracted tuberculosis in
prison and died in 1940.</p>
<p>Following World War 2, the occupying American forces rescinded the law making
Kunreisiki official and ordered the use of Hepburn for public signage and
documents. During the occupation, an American educational commission
<a href="https://babel.hathitrust.org/cgi/pt?id=pur1.32754081234191&amp;view=1up&amp;seq=28">recommended native Japanese writing be replaced with romaji</a>.
This never happened, though romaji became a standard component of post-war
education.</p>
<p>Post-war the development of romaji became less dramatic, as serious proponents
of replacing Japanese writing systems with romaji mostly disappeared. There
have been a number of laws and rules issued by the government over the years,
as well as a few special systems like the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JSL_romanization">unique system</a> developed for a
textbook called "Japanese: The Spoken Language", but Hepburn and
Nipponsiki/Kunreisiki remain the major systems.</p>
<p>There is also much to be written about interaction of romaji with computers,
but that's best left for another time.</p>
<h2 id="what-about-revised-hepburn%3F"> What About Revised Hepburn?</h2>
<p>Sometimes you'll see references to "Revised Hepburn", but nobody knows what
this is. It is used to mean, variously:</p>
<ul>
<li>Hepburn's system in his third edition, in contrast to earlier editions</li>
<li>the 1905 version by the ローマ字ひろめ会 (properly 標準式 or "standard form")</li>
<li>a version introduced with Kenkyuusha's "New Japanese-English Dictionary" in 1954, subsequently <a href="https://www.loc.gov/catdir/cpso/romanization/japanese.pdf">adopted by the American Library of Congress</a></li>
<li>other minor variants proposed at different times</li>
</ul>
<p>While the Library of Congress is surely consistent in their romaji usage, their
choice of a particular 1954 dictionary is a bit odd, and distinguishing it from
the similar 1905 system is a source of confusion. At one point it seemed like
Hepburn might become an ANSI standard, but instead Kunreisiki was adopted, and
that standard (Z39.11-1972) has since been deprecated. This lack of an official
standard contributes to inconsistency in what "Revised Hepburn" means.</p>
<p>In contrast, "traditional Hepburn" is somewhat reliably used to refer to the
system used in Hepburn's third edition as opposed to later forms.</p>
<p>Another common variant, "passport Hepburn" refers to the system previously
mandated for names on Japanese passports, which included some exceptions to
normal Hepburn, but those requirements are <a href="https://www.mofa.go.jp/mofaj/toko/passport/pass_4.html#q17">no longer strictly in force</a>,
and you can use any romanization you want (such as "George" for what would be
"Jouji" in Hepburn) if you have …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.dampfkraft.com/romaji-history.html">https://www.dampfkraft.com/romaji-history.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.dampfkraft.com/romaji-history.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25108455</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 05:39:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
