<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 08:25:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 08:25:54 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why Privacy Matters]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 88 | Comments 16 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24341079">thread link</a>) | @Clo_S
<br/>
September 1, 2020 | https://thistooshallgrow.com/blog/privacy-security-roundup | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thistooshallgrow.com/blog/privacy-security-roundup">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-block-type="2" id="block-0690890445953831c024"><div><p><em>Trigger warning: authoritarianism, state surveillance, the Holocaust. If you want to avoid these topics, please jump to the last paragraph of this introduction, starting with ‘Enough about the depressing stuff.’</em></p><p>Before we start, I feel like I need to give a bit of background on why I care so deeply about privacy. It’s partly historical. Being Ashkenazi, I learnt from a very young age about the importance of sensitive information, and who you give that information to. My grandfather broke the law by not going to the police station to register himself as a Jew. The Holocaust saw 76,000 Jews deported to death camps from France alone - around 1/4th of the country’s Jewish population at the time. There’s a chance that not being part of the Jewish census saved his life. Lesson: be careful who you give sensitive information to.</p><p>That grandfather and two of his brothers left Paris in the middle of the war, and took a train south with no plan, no luggage, no contact, and no destination other than, well, heading south. They were helped by strangers and survived. Their mother however, along with two other siblings, had a plan. They had a deal with a smuggler to reach unoccupied France. The smuggler informed the Nazis, and all 3 of them died in deportation. Lesson: each person who has information on you represents an additional chance for it to be leaked.</p><p>And yes, we can raise the irony of mentioning my Jewish grandpa to warn you against sharing sensitive information online. There, I just did.&nbsp;</p><p>While this happened in the 1940’s, a data point’s lifespan is drastically different today. It’s possible that you posted something online 10 years ago, and it was fine back then, but 20 years from now you will hope that no one finds it. My message is: the Internet never forgets, cultures change, and retroactive laws exist. People can get screwed over digital data. Let’s take the obvious example: China’s state surveillance has an eye on literally each and every move of its inhabitants, whether physical or digital. The state uses extensive data to allocate social scores, which can have a <a href="https://www.abc.net.au/news/2018-09-18/china-social-credit-a-model-citizen-in-a-digital-dictatorship/10200278?nw=0" target="_blank">drastic impact</a> on Chinese people’s life, including banning them from purchasing train or plane tickets, providing them with lower Internet speed, and denying them visas and loans. China also makes use of this surveillance system <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/interactive/2020/02/asia/xinjiang-china-karakax-document-intl-hnk/" target="_blank">against its Uyghur population</a>, detaining between 1 and 2 million people - the estimates vary - in concentration camps, where prisoners suffer <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Xinjiang_re-education_camps#Testimonies_of_treatment" target="_blank">extensively reported torture, brainwashing and forced labour</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>Apart from governmental issues, there’s also the topic of pervasive <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iFTWM7HV2UI" target="_blank">tracking and ads</a>, championed by Facebook and Google. I’m yet to see the difference between today’s digital advertising and individually-customised mass manipulation. Maybe because there is none. Please try and change my mind if you have any conclusive elements.</p><p>Enough about the depressing stuff. I’ve explained why your privacy matters, and we’re now about to dive into a few security concepts. I wrote this article with <a href="https://twitter.com/lp1eu" target="_blank">lp1</a>, as he knows much more about these concepts than I do. So here’s my first pro tip for you, unrelated to privacy or security: date people you admire. Now, let’s get into the technical aspects.</p><h2>CIA</h2><p>The CIA ‘triad’ is a summary of the main concepts of information security. There are 3 aspects regarding information which are targeted by infosec:</p><ul data-rte-list="default"><li><p><strong>Confidentiality</strong>:<strong> </strong>the assurance that a piece of information can only be observed by authorised third parties.</p></li><li><p><strong>Integrity</strong>:<strong> </strong>the assurance that a piece of information is and stays accurate over time.</p></li><li><p><strong>Availability</strong>: the assurance that a piece of information can be accessed by an authorised user when they need it.</p></li></ul><h2>Encryption: Server-side vs. Client-side</h2><p>Encryption secures data and aims to maintain its confidentiality and integrity.</p><p>We differentiate server-side from client-side encryption. Server-side means that only information stored on said server is encrypted. This means that the company has the encryption key, and therefore can access your communication (yes, including your nudes). However, server-side encryption doesn’t apply to the <strong>transmission </strong>of your communication. The data you share is not necessarily encrypted, only the storage is, which is why you should favour platforms that use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTPS" target="_blank">https</a>.</p><p>Client-side – or end-to-end – encryption means that the transmission of your information is encrypted, and that <strong>only your device</strong> has the key. If you log in from a different device, you won’t be able to see the exchanges. Since the company <strong>does not have the key</strong>,<strong> </strong>they cannot access your messages. As a result, even if they were to store your exchanges, said exchanges would automatically be encrypted. However, this also means that you won’t be able to recover your messages, should you lose the key.</p><p>In the case of a communication service, this means that the nudes you're sending to <strong>someone you trust</strong> are encrypted from your device to the company's server, as well as from their server to your trusted partner's device. Without encryption however, anyone on your network can see and tamper with all your communications. By 'tamper with', we mean any kind of modification by an unauthorised third-party. Examples include someone changing your password and email address on a platform to take over your account, deleting your private files on a cloud file storage service, replacing software in your online backups with malware, etc.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1598877921511_5282"><div><p>A recent example is the July Twitter hack, during which <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1286088135525318656" target="_blank">hackers managed to read users' messages from Twitter's admin control panel</a>. &nbsp;With end-to-end encrypted DMs, no one at Twitter would have been able to access them.</p><h2>Encryption vs. Hashing</h2><p>A distinction has to be made between two important notions: encryption and hashing. Encrypting information means that you turn it into scrambled text which can be decoded with a key. For instance, it's useful to make sure a communication between two peers cannot be read by an unauthorised person.&nbsp;</p><p>Hashing a piece of data on the other hand means that you turn it into a <strong>unique signature</strong> which <strong>cannot be reversed</strong> into its original readable state. The only way for someone to obtain the original input based on the hashing output, is to try inputs themselves until their output matches. Hashing is not intended as a cypher to decrypt, which is why encryption and hashing serve different purposes and are used in different cases. Hashing is noticeably useful to store passwords, because you avoid storing the actual easy-to-steal-and-reuse passwords. Instead, you compare the hashing output that you store to the hashing output of what a user entered while trying to log in. If you get the same hash that you’ve stored, then the password is correct.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1598877921511_7990"><div><h2>100% secure does not exist</h2><p>Flaws and vulnerabilities can always be found. However, the sturdier your tools, the safer you'll be. And contrary to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=djV11Xbc914" target="_blank">what A-ha used to sing</a>, it is better to be safe than sorry.</p><h2>Free vs. Open source</h2><p>Free and open source software are specific philosophies, based on specific values. Free software specifically refers to the notion of users' freedom, which isn't the case in open-source software. As <a href="https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.en.html" target="_blank">the GNU website</a> puts it: 'To understand the concept, you should think of “free” as in “free speech,” not as in “free beer”'.</p><p>There are 4 criteria for software to be free:</p><ul data-rte-list="default"><li><p>Freedom 0: The freedom to run the programme as you wish, for any purpose.</p></li><li><p>Freedom 1: The freedom to study how the programme works, and change it so it does your computing as you wish. This entails having access to the source code.</p></li><li><p>Freedom 2: The freedom to redistribute copies so you can help others.</p></li><li><p>Freedom 3: The freedom to distribute copies of your modified versions to others.</p></li></ul><p>On the other hand, open-source software has a <a href="https://opensource.org/osd" target="_blank">less strict definition</a>, and a different philosophy. You can also see the source code, amongst other things.</p><p>If you want to get into the political aspect of these terminologies, <a href="https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/floss-and-foss.en.html" target="_blank">here</a>’s a good explanation.</p><h2>Credential stuffing attack</h2><p>Credential stuffing is a popular attack whose goal is to automatically test a user’s known credentials on multiple platforms on a large scale. Nowadays, it is widely used by malicious intruders because of the online accessibility of billions of credentials gathered from data leaks (<a href="https://www.troyhunt.com/dating-the-ginormous-myspace-breach/" target="_blank">MySpace</a>, <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/dailymotion-allegedly-hacked-85-million-user-accounts-stolen/" target="_blank">Dailymotion</a>, <a href="https://www.troyhunt.com/the-dropbox-hack-is-real/" target="_blank">Dropbox</a> to name some of the biggest).</p><p>And there you have it, a roundup of the main security concepts. Feel free to reach out to <a href="https://twitter.com/lp1eu" target="_blank">lp1</a> or <a href="https://twitter.com/this2shallgrow" target="_blank">me</a> on Twitter. Part 2 will be available next week, with a list of the privacy and security tools we frequently use and recommend.</p><p>If you’re looking for a UX researcher or UX designer to work in the privacy and security sphere, I’d love to have a chat with you! </p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thistooshallgrow.com/blog/privacy-security-roundup</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24341079</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 12:31:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[First Impressions of GitHub Codespaces]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 89 | Comments 73 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24339118">thread link</a>) | @legostormtroopr
<br/>
August 31, 2020 | https://www.aristotlemetadata.com/blog/2020/08/first-impressions-github-codespaces.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.aristotlemetadata.com/blog/2020/08/first-impressions-github-codespaces.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                                <p>Github recently launched their new <a href="https://github.com/features/codespaces">Github codespaces</a> service - an online, in-browser Integrated Development Environment powered by <a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/">Visual Studio Code</a>. This environment allows someone to quickly load a virtual machine and a complete code editing interface, that is all accessible within the browser without having to install anything on the users machine. If you are familiar with products like <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/cloud9/">Amazon Web Services’s Cloud 9 IDE</a> or its predecessor C9.io this will probably feel very familiar.</p>

<p>As one of the lucky few who were given access to the GitHub Codespaces beta program I had the opportunity to test it out and offer my thoughts on behalf of the Aristotle team below.</p>

<h2 id="first-impressions">First impressions</h2>
<p>There were a few small changes that needed to be done to the <a href="https://www.aristotlemetadata.com/">Aristotle Metadata home page</a>, (including making this blogpost) and it was easy opening a Codespace to start working. Opening a code space for a project is literally as easy as GitHub says - click “Open in Codespace” on a repository and it does the rest - no need to configuring or decommission a server, its all handled for you.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.aristotlemetadata.com/aristotle/images/blog/codespaces/codespaces-opening-project.png" alt="How to open Codespaces" title="How to open Codespaces"></p>

<p><a href="https://www.aristotlemetadata.com/">Our website</a> is a basic <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a> static site, and offers a great basic test of whats available in Codespaces already. Loading a fresh Codespace took less than 2 minutes, which is comparable to AWS Cloud9. As someone who used Cloud9 when it was still C9.io, Codespaces reminded me a lot of that - its a simple way to open an editor and a virtual machine for a GitHub project.</p>

<p>The <a href="https://docs.github.com/en/github/developing-online-with-codespaces/about-codespaces">documentation for Codespaces</a> is also great. What I didn’t know is that GitHub can also <a href="https://docs.github.com/en/github/developing-online-with-codespaces/personalizing-codespaces-for-your-account">load your dotfiles directly into each new Codespace</a>, so your preferences (<code>.bashrc</code> and similar files) will follow you across Codespaces.</p>

<h2 id="editing-files">Editing files</h2>
<p>Being based on Visual Studio Code, <strong>Yes, Codespaces has a Dark Mode</strong>.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.aristotlemetadata.com/aristotle/images/blog/codespaces/codespaces-dark-editor.png" alt="Default Codespaces Editor" title="Default Codespaces Editor"></p>

<p>Although if you are using different browsers to open your workspace (which I had to do for reasons below), your colour scheme preferences won’t follow you across browsers. I’m not a regular user of Visual Studio Code, but it seems to includes all the standard features you expect from a browser, such as syntax highlighting, VIm and Emac keybindings (which work very well in browser), and autosave which is enabled by default, and I promptly disabled.</p>

<p>You can also drag-and-drop files from your local machine into Codespaces filesystem, and preview and edit certain non-text files in the browser, such as images, both of which are really handy for web development.</p>

<h2 id="terminal-emulator">Terminal emulator</h2>
<p>Codespaces includes a powerful terminal editor that seems to be based on a stock Debian image. The only thing I didn’t like is that separate terminals are accessed using a dropdown instead of with tabs, but this is a minor detail.</p>

<p><strong>Big news: Docker is here</strong>, and it works well.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.aristotlemetadata.com/aristotle/images/blog/codespaces/codespaces-docker.png" alt="Docker in Codespaces" title="Docker in Codespaces"></p>

<p>One of my biggest issues with C9.io was the lack of Docker support, which was solved when AWS bought Cloud9 but comes with the extra complexity of configuring your Amazon machine. So being able to simply run Docker in the browser is great. Docker-compose isn’t installed by default, and I haven’t had a chance to see how that works.</p>

<p>The only issue I found with the terminal emulator was you can only paste with right-click into Chromium-based browsers like Chrome or Edge, <em>Firefox users beware</em>.</p>

<h2 id="serving-sites">Serving sites</h2>
<p><a href="https://docs.github.com/en/github/developing-online-with-codespaces/developing-in-a-codespace">Codepsaces does a great job of handling port forwarding for you </a>, so you can simply start you server process (on a non-Port 80 port) and if GitHub detects a <code>localhost:PORT</code> combination it makes it accessible for you by clicking on the URL, as shown below:</p>

<p><img src="https://www.aristotlemetadata.com/aristotle/images/blog/codespaces/codespaces-jekyll.png" alt="Jekyll in Codespaces" title="Jekyll in Codespaces"></p>

<p>Loading and reloading Jekyll was fast, and by the time I clicked the forwarded link or switched tabs to preview changes to the site, it was already refreshed. 
<del><strong>However, this is another Chromium-only feature the clikcable port forward links don’t work in Firefox</strong></del>  this seems to be fixed now in Firefox.</p>

<p>One other minor issue is you can’t open your site in a private window or different browser to view the server without logging into GitHub. This isn’t a huge issue, but if you are trying to view what your site looks like under different browser or when logged out it can be troublesome.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.aristotlemetadata.com/aristotle/images/blog/codespaces/codespaces-final-site.png" alt="Aristotle Home Page in Codespaces" title="Aristotle Home Page in Codespaces"></p>

<h2 id="final-thoughts">Final thoughts</h2>

<p><strong>This is amazing</strong> and may become my default IDE - as a co-founder who is spending less time as a developer, and more time in meetings, writing emails, strategy papers, letters and tenders, <em>this is just amazing</em>! Most of my daily tools are Windows based, so I’ve been spending a lot of time getting Windows Subsystem for Linux working alongside the rest of my daily workflow, which comes with its own headaches. So being able to quickly checkout a branch, make changes and take some load of my local machine seems very promising.</p>

<p>There are a lot of features here to review that I haven’t had a chance to look at, including collaborative workspaces, Git integration and connecting with a local version of Visual Studio, but from a quick glance everything works smoothly.</p>

<p>Overall, it’s an extremely quick way to get started on a project, and I look forward to writing an update after I’ve had a chance getting the Aristotle Metadata Registry software, with all its many dependencies, running in codespaces under Docker-compose.</p>

<p><strong>The Aristotle Metadata Registry is no stranger to cloud innovation</strong>. If you want to learn how to access a cloud-hosted metadata registry as simple as Github’s Codespaces <a href="https://www.aristotlemetadata.com/contact.html">get in contact with us</a>.</p>

<p>Discuss this post on our community forum: https://community.aristotlemetadata.com/</p>

                                                            
                            </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.aristotlemetadata.com/blog/2020/08/first-impressions-github-codespaces.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24339118</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 06:37:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The database I wish I had]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 303 | Comments 169 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24337244">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
August 31, 2020 | https://euandre.org/2020/08/31/the-database-i-wish-i-had.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://euandre.org/2020/08/31/the-database-i-wish-i-had.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
  
  
    
  
  <section>
    <p>I watched the talk
“<a href="https://vimeo.com/230142234">Platform as a Reflection of Values: Joyent, Node.js and beyond</a>”
by Bryan Cantrill, and I think he was able to put into words something I already
felt for some time: if there’s no piece of software out there that reflects your
values, it’s time for you to build that software<sup id="fnref:talk-time" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:talk-time">1</a></sup>.</p>

<p>I kind of agree with what he said, because this is already happening to me. I
long for a database with a certain set of values, and for a few years I was just
waiting for someone to finally write it. After watching his talk, Bryan is
saying to me: “time to stop waiting, and start writing it yourself”.</p>

<p>So let me try to give an overview of such database, and go over its values.</p>



<p>I want a database that allows me to create decentralized client-side
applications that can sync data.</p>

<p>The best one-line description I can give right now is:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It’s sort of like PouchDB, Git, Datomic, SQLite and Mentat.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>A more descriptive version could be:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>An embedded, immutable, syncable relational database.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Let’s go over what I mean by each of those aspects one by one.</p>



<p>I think the server-side database landscape is diverse and mature enough for
my needs (even though I end up choosing SQLite most of the time), and what I’m
after is a database to be embedded on client-side applications itself, be it
desktop, browser, mobile, etc.</p>

<p>The purpose of such database is not to keep some local cache of data in case of
lost connectivity: we have good solutions for that already. It should serve as
the source of truth, and allow the application to work on top of it.</p>

<p><a href="https://sqlite.org/index.html"><strong>SQLite</strong></a> is a great example of that: it is a very powerful
relational database that runs <a href="https://sqlite.org/whentouse.html">almost anywhere</a>. What I miss
from it that SQLite doesn’t provide is the ability to run it on the browser:
even though you could compile it to WebAssembly, it assumes a POSIX filesystem
that would have to be emulated.</p>

<p><a href="https://pouchdb.com/"><strong>PouchDB</strong></a> is another great example: it’s a full reimplementation of
<a href="https://couchdb.apache.org/">CouchDB</a> that targets JavaScript environments, mainly the browser and
Node.js. However I want a tool that can be deployed anywhere, and not limit its
applications to places that already have a JavaScript runtime environment, or
force the developer to bundle a JavaScript runtime environment with their
application. This is true for GTK+ applications, command line programs, Android
apps, etc.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/mozilla/mentat"><strong>Mentat</strong></a> was an interesting project, but its reliance on SQLite
makes it inherit most of the downsides (and benefits too) of SQLite itself.</p>

<p>Having such a requirement imposes a different approach to storage: we have to
decouple the knowledge about the intricacies of storage from the usage of
storage itself, so that a module (say query processing) can access storage
through an API without needing to know about its implementation. This allows
the database to target a POSIX filesystems storage API and an IndexedDB storage
API, and make the rest of the code agnostic about storage. PouchDB has such
mechanism (called <a href="https://pouchdb.com/adapters.html">adapters</a>) and Datomic has them too (called
<a href="https://docs.datomic.com/on-prem/storage.html">storage services</a>).</p>

<p>This would allow the database to adapt to where it is embedded: when targeting
the browser the IndexedDB storage API would provide the persistence layer
that the database requires, and similarly the POSIX filesystem storage API would
provide the persistence layer when targeting POSIX systems (like desktops,
mobile, etc.).</p>

<p>But there’s also an extra restriction that comes from by being embedded: it
needs to provide and embeddable artifact, most likely a binary library object
that exposes a C compatible FFI, similar to
<a href="https://www.sqlite.org/amalgamation.html">how SQLite does</a>. Bundling a full runtime environment is
possible, but doesn’t make it a compelling solution for embedding. This rules
out most languages, and leaves us with C, Rust, Zig, and similar options that
can target POSIX systems and WebAssembly.</p>



<p>Being immutable means that only new information is added, no in-place update
ever happens, and nothing is ever deleted.</p>

<p>Having an immutable database presents us with similar trade-offs found in
persistent data structures, like lack of coordination when doing reads, caches
being always coherent, and more usage of space.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.datomic.com/"><strong>Datomic</strong></a> is the go to database example of this: it will only add
information (datoms) and allows you to query them in a multitude of ways. Stuart
Halloway calls it “accumulate-only” over “append-only”<sup id="fnref:accumulate-only" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:accumulate-only">2</a></sup>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It’s accumulate-only, it is not append-only. So append-only, most people when
they say that they’re implying something physical about what happens.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Also a database can be append-only and overwrite existing information with new
information, by doing clean-ups of “stale” data. I prefer to adopt the
“accumulate-only” naming and approach.</p>

<p><a href="https://git-scm.com/"><strong>Git</strong></a> is another example of this: new commits are always added on top
of the previous data, and it grows by adding commits instead of replacing
existing ones.</p>

<p>Git repositories can only grow in size, and that is not only an acceptable
condition, but also one of the reasons to use it.</p>

<p>All this means that no in-place updates happens on data, and the database will
be much more concerned about how compact and efficiently it stores data than how
fast it does writes to disk. Being embedded, the storage limitation is either a)
how much storage the device has or b) how much storage was designed for the
application to consume. So even though the database could theoretically operate
with hundreds of TBs, a browser page or mobile application wouldn’t have access
to this amount of storage. SQLite even <a href="https://sqlite.org/limits.html">says</a> that it does
support approximately 280 TBs of data, but those limits are untested.</p>

<p>The upside of keeping everything is that you can have historical views of your
data, which is very powerful. This also means that applications should turn this
off when not relevant<sup id="fnref:no-history" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:no-history">3</a></sup>.</p>



<p>This is a frequent topic when talking about offline-first solutions. When
building applications that:</p>

<ul>
  <li>can fully work offline,</li>
  <li>stores data,</li>
  <li>propagates that data to other application instances,</li>
</ul>

<p>then you’ll need a conflict resolution strategy to handle all the situations
where different application instances disagree. Those application instances
could be a desktop and a browser version of the same application, or the same
mobile app in different devices.</p>

<p>A three-way merge seems to be the best approach, on top of which you could add
application specific conflict resolution functions, like:</p>

<ul>
  <li>pick the change with higher timestamp;</li>
  <li>if one change is a delete, pick it;</li>
  <li>present the diff on the screen and allow the user to merge them.</li>
</ul>

<p>Some databases try to make this “easy”, by choosing a strategy for you, but I’ve
found that different applications require different conflict resolution
strategies. Instead, the database should leave this up to the user to decide,
and provide tools for them to do it.</p>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Merge_(version_control)"><strong>Three-way merges in version control</strong></a> are the best example,
performing automatic merges when possible and asking the user to resolve
conflicts when they appear.</p>

<p>The unit of conflict for a version control system is a line of text. The
database equivalent would probably be a single attribute, not a full entity or a
full row.</p>

<p>Making all the conflict resolution logic be local should allow the database to
have encrypted remotes similar to how <a href="https://spwhitton.name/tech/code/git-remote-gcrypt/">git-remote-gcrypt</a>
adds this functionality to Git. This would enable users to sync the application
data across devices using an untrusted intermediary.</p>



<p>I want the power of relational queries on the client applications.</p>

<p>Most of the arguments against traditional table-oriented relational databases
are related to write performance, but those don’t apply here. The bottlenecks
for client applications usually aren’t write throughput. Nobody is interested in
differentiating between 1 MB/s or 10 MB/s when you’re limited to 500 MB total.</p>

<p>The relational model of the database could either be based on SQL and tables
like in SQLite, or maybe <a href="https://docs.datomic.com/on-prem/query.html">datalog</a> and <a href="https://docs.datomic.com/cloud/whatis/data-model.html#datoms">datoms</a> like in
Datomic.</p>



<p>Now let’s try to translate the aspects above into values, as suggested by Bryan
Cantrill.</p>



<p>Being able to target so many different platforms is a bold goal, and the
embedded nature of the database demands portability to be a core value.</p>



<p>When the local database becomes the source of truth of the application, it must
provide consistency guarantees that enables applications to rely on it.</p>



<p>The database should empower applications to slice and dice the data in any way
it wants to.</p>



<p>Since I can’t find any database that fits these requirements, I’ve finally come
to terms with doing it myself.</p>

<p>It’s probably going to take me a few years to do it, and making it portable
between POSIX and IndexedDB will probably be the biggest challenge. I got myself
a few books on databases to start.</p>

<p>I wonder if I’ll ever be able to get this done.</p>



<p>See discussions on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/ijwz5b/the_database_i_wish_i_had/">Reddit</a>, <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/m9vkg4/database_i_wish_i_had">lobsters</a> and <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24337244">HN</a>.</p>



  </section>
  
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://euandre.org/2020/08/31/the-database-i-wish-i-had.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24337244</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:21:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I sold my side-project for $30k]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 197 | Comments 84 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24336925">thread link</a>) | @keesj
<br/>
August 31, 2020 | https://marc.io/tweet-photo-acquired | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://marc.io/tweet-photo-acquired">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p><strong>TL;DR: <a href="https://tweet.photo/">Tweet Photo</a> is a software service to automatically post your Instagram photos to Twitter. It started out as a Medium post, turned into a software product, and eventually got acquired for $30,000.</strong></p>

<p>Continue reading for the full story on how I validated the idea, built a simple product, grew it to thousands of active users, tried monetizing it, and eventually sold it.</p>

<hr>

<h3 id="-blog-post-as-an-mvp">📝 Blog post as an MVP</h3>

<p>People always tell you: start with an MVP, prove there’s demand for your product
before investing all your time into something nobody wants. In my experience
that’s good advice, but it seems many successful products often start out as
accidental MVPs. Tweet Photo is a perfect example of this.</p>

<p>If you’ve ever tried posting an Instagram photo to Twitter, you might have noticed it looks like this:</p>



<p>Just a link. No photo. Useless. I don’t know the politics behind this, but I believe Facebook is the one that disabled the photo previews at some point. So now we’re stuck with useless tweets.</p>

<p>You can find many workarounds using automation services like <a href="https://ifttt.com/">IFTTT</a> and <a href="https://zapier.com/">Zapier</a>. Because I was unhappy with all solutions, I decided to write my own article in May 2017:</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://medium.com/@marckohlbrugge/a-better-way-to-post-your-instagram-photos-to-twitter-7f3a04a37d89">A better way to post your Instagram photos to Twitter</a></strong></p>

<p>Turns out I struck a chord. To this date that post has been read 70,000 times. Over three years later it continues to get over a 1,000 hits per month.</p>

<p><img src="https://marc.io/images/tweet-photo-acquired/medium.png#full" alt=""></p>

<p>If you read the post though, you will notice how complicated the setup is. So I figured there might be an opportunity for a product here. I knew there was an interest, but I didn’t know if I could monetize it.</p>

<p>It wasn’t until <a href="https://hi.yuko.im/">Yuko</a> posted <a href="https://wip.chat/questions/what-is-the-best-way-to-repost-instagram-contents-to-twitter">this question</a> on WIP:</p>

<p><a href="https://wip.chat/questions/what-is-the-best-way-to-repost-instagram-contents-to-twitter"><img src="https://marc.io/images/tweet-photo-acquired/wip.png" alt=""></a></p>

<p>She mentioned she’d happily pay $20/mo for Zapier to tweet her photos. That got me thinking, maybe it’s a product that can be monetized after all. Plus, I already got the leads coming in via the blog post. I could funnel them through to this new service instead.</p>

<p>Rather than further validating the business model, I challenged myself to build a prototype over the next couple of days.</p>

<h3 id="-building-the-product">🛠 Building the Product</h3>

<p>I believe in using the tools you’re familiar with, so I used Ruby on Rails to build the product.</p>

<p>Tweet Photo is technically quite simple. I’m basically glueing together the Instagram and Twitter APIs. I was able to do most of the work with open-source libraries.</p>

<p>I finished the product in just over a week during my spare time.</p>

<p>I initially went with the <strong>tweetphoto.icu</strong> domain name because it was only $1. That’s how much faith I had in the product I guess. But shortly after I decided if I’m going to do this, I might as well do it right and purchased <strong>tweet.photo for $130</strong>. It might not seem like a lot of money, but with all the projects I start things thing start to add up 😅. In hindsight I’m really glad I got this domain name…</p>

<p>I wouldn’t realize it until later, but the key feature I added was appending <em>“via tweet.photo”</em> to every tweet. This single piece of text would prove to be the driving factor of Tweet Photo’s growth.</p>



<h3 id="-time-to-launch">🚀 Time to launch</h3>

<p>December 12th, 2018, 11 days after Yuko’s post, I launched:</p>

<div><blockquote><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>🖼👉🐦 I made a new thing called <a href="https://t.co/LMVsrPNaFV">https://t.co/LMVsrPNaFV</a> ✨</p><p>Automagically post your Instagram photos and videos to your Twitter account. Your media will be embedded in the tweet, unlike Instagram's built-in feature.</p></div>— Marc (@marckohlbrugge) <a href="https://twitter.com/marckohlbrugge/status/1072869470866034688?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 12, 2018</a></blockquote>

</div>

<p>It got featured on <a href="https://betalist.com/startups/tweet-photo">BetaList</a> and
<a href="https://www.producthunt.com/posts/tweet-photo">Product Hunt</a>.</p>

<p>At the end day of the launch over 100 accounts were created with combined total of over 100 published tweets.</p>

<p>The product worked! 🥳</p>

<h3 id="-growth">📈 Growth</h3>

<p>As time went on the userbase continued growing.</p>

<p>Unlike most software services, the retention of Tweet Photo was basically 100%. Meaning that anyone that signed up, was likely to continue using it for a long time. Once signed up, everything was automated after all.</p>

<p>Combine that with the “via tweet.photo” in every tweet and you’ve got steady growth:</p>

<p><img src="https://marc.io/images/tweet-photo-acquired/growth.png" alt=""></p>

<p>Here’s a screenshot of the <a href="https://simpleanalytics.com/">Simple Analytics</a> dashboard showing how tweets are driving new leads to the homepage:</p>

<p><img src="https://marc.io/images/tweet-photo-acquired/tweets.png" alt=""></p>

<p>We even got some major Hollywood celebrities using the service. In fact, Tweet
Photo came a hot topic amongst her fans. Driving even more sign ups.</p>



<h3 id="-monetization">💸 Monetization</h3>

<p>Okay, so we’ve got decent growth. But what about the revenue?</p>

<p>This was a lot harder. When I launched Tweet Photo I included a $19/year PRO subscription that would remove the “via tweet.photo” branding. I figured if people care enough about their Twitter profile to not want to show that link, they might be willing to pay.</p>

<p>People with more Twitter followers would pay more. After all if someone has a million Twitter followers it’s worth a lot more to me if they promote Tweet Photo in every tweet.</p>

<p><img src="https://marc.io/images/tweet-photo-acquired/stripe.png" alt=""></p>

<p>I eventually switched to monthly pricing starting at $5/mo. I figured churn rate would be really low anyway, so it would be better to charge monthly. Paying $5/mo instead $19 for a year upfront is a lower commitment for the customer, but ultimately 3x the revenue for me.</p>

<p>Unfortunately MRR grew very slowly. It’s about $135 MRR right now.</p>

<p>I think the main problem is that the the free plan is already very compelling. So it’s hard to convince people to upgrade.</p>

<h3 id="-now-what">🤔 Now what?</h3>

<p>While I had plenty of ideas for improving monetization, including removing the free plan altogether, it didn’t seem worth my time trying to grow a product that’s only doing $135 MRR. Even if I could 10x that, it’s still a low amount compared to my other products.</p>

<p>So over time I spent less time and attention on Tweet Photo. It continued to grow organically.</p>

<p>Another reason I didn’t want to invest too much time is the inherent platform-risk of building an API-powered product. I was dependent on both Twitter and Facebook continuing to provide me access to their API. They could revoke it at any time and Tweet Photo might be doomed.</p>

<p>Earlier this year Facebook did actually deprecate one of their APIs I was relying on, requiring me to upgrade my integration to use a different API.</p>

<h3 id="-acquisition-offer">💬 Acquisition offer</h3>

<p>In April, <a href="https://twitter.com/kevntz">Kevin</a> reached out to me asking if I was interested in selling Tweet Photo. He had a strategic interest with his other products <a href="https://creatorkit.com/">CreatorKit</a> and <a href="https://topnine.co/">Top Nine</a>.</p>

<p><img src="https://marc.io/images/tweet-photo-acquired/dm.png" alt=""></p>

<p>Of course the question of valuation quickly came up. Typically a SaaS product is sold for 3-4x annual revenue. In Tweet Photo’s case that would be around $5,000. But that didn’t factor in the many free users that required almost zero customer support, but drove continued growth.</p>

<p>If I were to sell it, it would need to be in the $xx,xxx range. Otherwise I’d prefer to just keep the service and see what happens. There’s always the possibility of another celebrity using it and it going viral.</p>

<h3 id="-valuation-of-30000">💰 Valuation of $30,000</h3>

<p>After some negotiation we ultimate settled on a purchase price of $30,000.</p>

<p>The first $10,000 is cash upfront with no strings attached. The remaining $20,000 is contingent on Tweet Photo making that much (or more) in revenue within 24 months of the acquisition.</p>

<p>We both ran the numbers and we believe that with the full weight of <a href="https://creatorkit.com/">CreatorKit</a> behind it, it seems very likely Tweet Photo will cross that revenue goal.</p>

<p>But you never know how things turn out, so this was a way to de-risk the acquisition for the buyer while still allowing for a higher purchase than you’d typically see for a $135 MRR business.</p>

<p>Ask me in a few months how things are going 🙂</p>

<h3 id="-whats-next">👀 What’s next</h3>

<p>The $10,000 is in the bank and we’re now finalizing the asset transfer.</p>

<p>In the coming months CreatorKit will likely start marketing it to their existing userbase and possibly improving the service as well. Since we still have a shared interest in growing Tweet Photo me and the CreatorKit team will keep in touch to see how things are going.</p>

<p>Personally, I will continue to focus on <a href="https://wip.chat/">WIP</a>, <a href="https://betalist.com/">BetaList</a>, and <a href="https://startup.jobs/">Startup Jobs</a>.</p>

<p>If you want to hear how the remaining $20,000 plays out subscribe to my newsletter below 💌</p>


  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://marc.io/tweet-photo-acquired</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24336925</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 23:25:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Understanding How the Time-Based One-Time Password Algorithm Works]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 93 | Comments 25 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24336785">thread link</a>) | @aryamansharda
<br/>
August 31, 2020 | https://blog.digitalbunker.dev/2020/08/27/how-do-time-based-one-time-password-totp-services-work/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.digitalbunker.dev/2020/08/27/how-do-time-based-one-time-password-totp-services-work/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="mainEntityOfPage">
		
<p>Cybersecurity has always been a weak point for me and after setting up Authy for the n-th time, it seemed as good a time as any to take a deep dive and figure out exactly how these time-based one-time password algorithms worked.</p>



<figure><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/L93OYxu_Tn62xRpz0FsJyBeFNl8sp79Q4O-Wq2SPIC8rabc82VqubJNThDYX-vFl8TwOQSZwf7bDVzwyAxSD28jkRq0jiOtmFGmYhULpW8G8_vrGN89Z3NuOUC27z9pgyuQ8OuCT" alt="" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><figcaption>Examples of different time-based one-time password algorithm implementations</figcaption></figure>



<h2>Basic Overview</h2>



<p>At the highest level, the passcodes you see on these apps are created using a TOTP (time-based one-time password) algorithm. The passcode is generated by combining a secret key from the service you’re authenticating with and the current time. That’s why the codes always expire after a few seconds.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you’ve set up these apps yourselves, you’ll probably remember having to scan a QR code somewhere along the way. That was the transfer of the secret key to your device’s secure keychain storage. This algorithm is agnostic of your SIM card, cellular network provider, or the make/model of your phone which makes it preferable to texting the user an authentication code. The algorithm’s only considerations are the current time and the shared secret key.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Whenever you create a new account on a service that supports TOTP, they’ll generate a unique secret code for your user account. Then, the next time you’re logging in, the website will run the same algorithm the client runs to generate a passcode. If the passcode from the client matches the one generated by the server, the user is authenticated and the two-factor authentication process is complete.</p>



<h2>Algorithm Overview</h2>



<p>I’ve always found it easier to understand concepts like this by looking directly at the code. Let’s see what we’d need to do to implement a TOTP service from scratch.&nbsp;</p>



<p>TOTP is built off of a foundational algorithm called the HMAC-based One-time Password algorithm (HOTP), which we’ll need to understand first.&nbsp;</p>



<p>HMAC (hash-based message authentication code) is simply an algorithm that uses</p>



<ul><li>a cryptographic hash function (commonly <code>SHA1</code>)</li><li>a secret cryptographic key</li><li>a counter property (used to keep the client and server TOTP processes in sync)&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>to generate a unique time based authentication code.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If the distinction between TOTP and HOTP/HMAC isn’t totally clear yet, don’t worry. The main difference between TOTP and HOTP implementations involve the counter property. </p>



<p>HOTP’s counter is generally event-driven – for example, a button press would change the counter value. </p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="600" height="298" src="https://i2.wp.com/blog.digitalbunker.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/hardware-token.jpg?resize=600%2C298&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/blog.digitalbunker.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/hardware-token.jpg?w=600&amp;ssl=1 600w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.digitalbunker.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/hardware-token.jpg?resize=300%2C149&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.digitalbunker.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/hardware-token.jpg?resize=370%2C184&amp;ssl=1 370w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i2.wp.com/blog.digitalbunker.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/hardware-token.jpg?w=600&amp;ssl=1 600w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.digitalbunker.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/hardware-token.jpg?resize=300%2C149&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.digitalbunker.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/hardware-token.jpg?resize=370%2C184&amp;ssl=1 370w" data-lazy-src="https://i2.wp.com/blog.digitalbunker.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/hardware-token.jpg?resize=600%2C298&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><figcaption>An example device implementing the HOTP algorithm</figcaption></figure>



<p>Instead, in TOTP, the counter value is set based on the current timestamp. </p>



<p>Let’s take a look at the end to end flow.</p>



<p>First, we’ll create a counter from the timestamp. To avoid any additional complexity, we’ll just use time since epoch which is agnostic of timezones.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/qnUpYNJC6jzwQHRa7fLcOSSX9Np-J4fUQLJujxqQ4SCIY79rLF_1OCVkt4Zv1yjAicMLlNriMRNxzkotqWDNO56eRxudqQvqmmRvxfRLUnUAECK0Lx9nvQY0npKNOObClF6rld0T" alt="" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><figcaption>We need the number of Tx intervals to provide as input into the HOTP algorithm.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Simply put, the result of this calculation is to figure out how many Tx intervals away from the Unix epoch the user is. </p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="924" height="863" src="https://i2.wp.com/blog.digitalbunker.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-27-at-12.16.56-AM-1.png?resize=924%2C863&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/blog.digitalbunker.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-27-at-12.16.56-AM-1.png?w=924&amp;ssl=1 924w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.digitalbunker.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-27-at-12.16.56-AM-1.png?resize=300%2C280&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.digitalbunker.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-27-at-12.16.56-AM-1.png?resize=768%2C717&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.digitalbunker.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-27-at-12.16.56-AM-1.png?resize=370%2C346&amp;ssl=1 370w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.digitalbunker.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-27-at-12.16.56-AM-1.png?resize=760%2C710&amp;ssl=1 760w" sizes="(max-width: 924px) 100vw, 924px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i2.wp.com/blog.digitalbunker.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-27-at-12.16.56-AM-1.png?w=924&amp;ssl=1 924w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.digitalbunker.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-27-at-12.16.56-AM-1.png?resize=300%2C280&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.digitalbunker.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-27-at-12.16.56-AM-1.png?resize=768%2C717&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.digitalbunker.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-27-at-12.16.56-AM-1.png?resize=370%2C346&amp;ssl=1 370w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.digitalbunker.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-27-at-12.16.56-AM-1.png?resize=760%2C710&amp;ssl=1 760w" data-lazy-src="https://i2.wp.com/blog.digitalbunker.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-27-at-12.16.56-AM-1.png?resize=924%2C863&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><figcaption>Full TOTP Flow</figcaption></figure>



<h2>Implementation</h2>



<p>Here’s the Swift code thus far:&nbsp;</p>



<pre><code> let secretKey = "digitalbunker"
 let counter = "53283545"
 let hmacResult: String = secretKey.hmac(algorithm: .SHA1,  counter: counter)</code></pre>



<p>Now, <code>hmacResult</code> is equal to the following hashed value <code>1OyZRjbfhe+8womld8xldXo5V9M=</code>.</p>



<p>Next, Let’s convert this hashed value to a hexadecimal string:&nbsp;</p>



<pre><code>let data = Data(hmacResult.utf8)
let hexString = data.map{String(format:"%02x ", $0)}</code></pre>



<p><code>hexString</code> is now equal to <code>31 4f 79 5a 52 6a 62 66 68 65 2b 38 77 6f 6d 6c 64 38 78 6c 64 58 6f 35 56 39 4d 3d</code>.</p>



<p>This isn’t something we can ask the user to type in every single time they need to authenticate. Let’s see if we can find an easier way of representing this – a 6 digit code would be a great user-friendly alternative. </p>



<p>We’ll convert this hashed value to a shorter code through a process called dynamic truncation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Dynamic truncation involves taking the lower 4 bits of the last byte of the hexadecimal string and using that as an offset into the string to help us create a 6 digit code while still remaining secure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The last byte is <code>3d</code> which means the last 4 bits belong to the hexadecimal value for <code>d</code>  (decimal <code>13</code>).</p>



<p>Starting at an offset of <code>13</code>, we’ll grab the next 4 bytes:&nbsp;</p>



<p><code>31 4f 79 5a 52 6a 62 66 68 65 2b 38 77 <strong>6f 6d 6c 64</strong> 38 78 6c 64 58 6f 35 56 39 4d 3d</code></p>



<p>These bit operations are all part of the dynamic truncation process. We’re doing all of these manipulations to find a 6 digit code that is still as secure as possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, we’ll convert <code>0x6f6d6c64</code> to decimal giving us <code>1869442148</code>. Since we just need a 6 digit code, we can take the last 6 digits <code>442148</code> and return that to the user.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, the server will do the exact same sequence of steps. More accurately, it’ll check the current 30-second interval, the previous one, and the next one to account for clock drift. If the server’s code matches the code the user entered, the user is authenticated.</p>



<h2>Closing Thoughts</h2>



<p>TOPT and HOPT are both well-respected algorithms, but it’s important to mention the limitations. TOTP values can be phished like other passwords, but the attacker would have to be stealing the credentials in near real-time. </p>



<p>If this is a concern, you can shorten the TTL of the code. Standard TTL’s of TOTP codes can range from 10 – 30 seconds to account for latency (both client and server-side), unsynchronized clocks, and for user usability – feel free to tweak the TTL to suit your needs. However, if the attacker was able to find the shared secret key, they’d be able to create valid TOTP codes at will.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Hope you’ve enjoyed this closer look at the TOTP algorithm and its nuances! If you like contact like this, please join our mailing list. If there’s any article requests or comments, please feel free to reach out.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
			
				</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.digitalbunker.dev/2020/08/27/how-do-time-based-one-time-password-totp-services-work/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24336785</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 23:08:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Are apps even that relevant anymore?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 51 | Comments 41 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24335703">thread link</a>) | @stokesyio
<br/>
August 31, 2020 | https://tinyprojects.dev/posts/are_apps_even_that_relevant_anymore | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://tinyprojects.dev/posts/are_apps_even_that_relevant_anymore">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
	
	<nav>
		<a href="https://tinyprojects.dev/">Home</a>
		<a href="https://tinyprojects.dev/projects">Projects</a>
		<a href="https://tinyprojects.dev/guides">Guides</a>
		<a href="https://tinyprojects.dev/blog">Blog</a>
	</nav>
	
	<p><i>August 31st 2020</i></p>

	<p>Are apps even that relevant anymore? This is a question that's been on my mind for a while, but has particularly come to the forefront with the recent Epic vs. Apple saga.</p>

	<p>Sure, video games like Fortnite and software requiring native APIs make sense as an app (for now). But, if you're not a tilt-your-phone rolling-ball maze game, why not just make your software a great mobile-optimised website instead of an app?</p>

	<p>Sometimes I feel that there's a mentality amongst new developers and naive businesses that mobile software must be in the form of an app. I can see why.</p>

	<p>When the iPhone launched in 2007, apps were such a step up from the clunky text-based websites on our tiny manual-buttoned phones, who could blame anyone for wanting to develop a beautiful full-screen app? However, with that excitement, I feel the idea of making great software for the mobile web got left behind.</p>

	<p>Developing an app is so much harder than building software optimised for the mobile web. Not only do you have the monetary cost of developer licenses and equipment (iOS devices) when developing apps, you also have a sigificant time cost involved for maintaining separate iOS and Android codebases, building &amp; deploying to real test devices, and the delay and scrutiny your app goes under before updates go live onto an app store.</p>

	<p>Once your app is live, you have the significant barrier of a user having to find it, then use their precious storage space to install it. Oh, and the app stores take a juicy 30% cut of your profits.</p>

	<p>Who is actually winning here?</p>

	<p>Increasingly, a trend I've caught myself doing is using the mobile website equivalent of an app. Instagram &amp; Facebook's mobile websites for example have almost every feature of their app counterparts, without taking up massive storage space on my phone and draining battery with their background processes.</p>

	<p>Even now with my own <a href="https://tinyprojects.dev/projects" target="_blank">projects</a>, a well optimised mobile website beats an app most times. Who needs push notifications (and the effort they require to set up) when email notifications do the job just fine?</p>

	<p>In most cases, a great mobile website does the trick. You don't need an app, or the app store. We already have a pretty great app store and you're browsing it right now.</p>

	
	
	
	
	
	

</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://tinyprojects.dev/posts/are_apps_even_that_relevant_anymore</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24335703</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 20:39:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Cracking Phobos UUID]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 51 | Comments 14 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24333545">thread link</a>) | @tux1968
<br/>
August 31, 2020 | https://breakpoint.purrfect.fr/article/cracking_phobos_uuid.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://breakpoint.purrfect.fr/article/cracking_phobos_uuid.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <div id="cracking-phobos-uuid">

<div id="tl-dr-for-busy-people">
<h2>tl;dr for busy people</h2>
<ul>
<li><p>Contrary to other languages, D's current standard implementation of UUID4
isn't cryptographically secure and shouldn't be used to generate secrets
This is supported by the RFC which discourages people to use UUIDs for
secrets.</p></li>
<li><p>Of course lots of people, projects and frameworks use them to generate
secrets such as session cookies, password reset token and more because it's
easy, looks like it should work and does work in virtually any other
language.</p></li>
<li><p>Legitimately, people will ask "OK, it's bad in theory, but how hard is it
in practice". I show in this article that it is possible to guess the next
UUID to be generated with a maximum of 8192 requests after having gathered
156 UUIDs: a very practical attack indeed compared to the original 2¹²⁸
possibilities.</p></li>
<li><p>This should be viewed as a call for action: Phobos must provide a secure
random number generator. It's too basic and important a component not to
provide it in a standard way.</p></li>
<li><p>If your project uses <strong>randomUUID()</strong>, make sure its value isn't supposed
to be secret. Otherwise change for a token built from cryptographically
secure randomness.</p></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div id="context">
<h2>Context</h2>
<p>Some time ago I had a nice chat with a library's maintainer about Random
Number Generation and their relation to security. It reminded me that the
topic is not obvious and I decided to have a look at the state of things in
<a href="https://dlang.org/">D</a> since that's become my topic of open-source
research these last years.</p>
<p>In particular, I knew that D's standard library, Phobos, does not currently
propose any standard way to get cryptographically secure random numbers. Not
too many projects use the default and insecure <strong>uniform()</strong> to generate
secrets such as session tokens. However I decided to have a look at UUIDs
since they are often for security purpose. And sure enough, many projects
that I will not list use insecure UUIDs.</p>
<p>The thing is, while they should not do so, I cannot fault them for thinking
that it is correct. In most languages UUIDs are generated from secure
randomness and are a reasonable way to generate secure secrets. But that is
not the case in D and this means that these projects are vulnerable.</p>
<p>In this post we'll see how we can predict future UUIDs from previous
ones. It's a bit of work certainly, but it's not that hard. Here's our
road map:</p>
<ul>
<li><p><a href="#identify">Identify</a>: see how random UUIDs are made in Phobos</p></li>
<li><p><a href="#prepare">Prepare</a>: crack raw MT19937</p></li>
<li><p><a href="#attack">Attack</a>: predict future UUIDs from past ones</p></li>
<li><p><a href="#defend">Defend</a>: see how to fix this in your project and in Phobos</p></li>
</ul>
<p>This will be quite the long and technical post, but come along anyway, it is
sure to be interesting!</p>
<div id="a-word-on-randomness">
<h3>A word on randomness</h3>
<p>Before going further we need to be clear about what we mean by
cryptographically secure randomness and how it differs from regular
randomness.</p>
<p>Normal randomness is generally defined by only one assumption: to have no or
low bias. This means that if you were to generate lots of numbers, the number
of times you see each specific output should be evenly matched. This property
is sufficient for most applications, from a random dog name generator to
Monte-Carlo simulations.</p>
<p>However cryptographic randomness requires more:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>It must not have any bias</p></li>
<li><p>It must not be possible to predict future outputs from old ones</p></li>
<li><p>It must not be possible to recover past outputs from current ones</p></li>
</ul>
<p>(The proper <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cryptographically_secure_pseudorandom_number_generator#Definitions">definition</a> is a bit stronger than this, but this will suffice
in the context of our article.)</p>
<p>If there's a bias, then I have information about what numbers are generated
without having to gather a single number. I do not think I need to explain
how predicting future numbers can be an issue for a system generating secrets
such as session tokens. The last item though can surprise, but consider this:
if it is possible to recover past outputs from current ones and you use these
random numbers for password reset tokens (for example), then I can ask a
reset of another user's password, then ask a reset of mine and determine what
the previous entry was, disclosing that user's password reset token.</p>
<p>Why aren't cryptographically secure pseudo-random number generators (CSPRNG)
used for everything if they're more secure? Because enforcing these
conditions also makes them much slower than conventional PRNGs and many
applications don't need these guarantees.</p>
<p>MT19937 is not a cryptographically secure pseudo-random number generator and
can't be used as one. It's not a matter of choosing the right seed, or
reseeding often (actually, reseeding often would be a benefit to us as we'll
see at the end). It has some bias (not much admittedly), but most importantly
it's both possible to predict the future and recover the past from just a few
outputs.</p>
<p><img alt="../image/chibi_cat_hurry_up.png" src="https://breakpoint.purrfect.fr/image/chibi_cat_hurry_up.png">
</p></div>
</div>
<div id="structure-of-a-uuid">
<h2>Structure of a UUID</h2>
<div id="the-standard">
<h3>The standard</h3>
<p>Universally Unique Identifiers (UUID) are a category of identifiers defined
in <a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc4122.html">RFC 4122</a>. Their goal is, as
the name suggests, to provide a way got generate IDs that are guaranteed to
be different even across systems that can't communicate together. You've
probably seen them, they look like this:
<strong>0d3120f8-f209-43f2-949d-e70dcf228403</strong></p>
<p>There are different types of UUIDs, but the most common one is Type 4: random
UUIDs. These are described in section 4.4 of the RFC as such:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>bits 6 and 7 must be set to 0 and 1</p></li>
<li><p>bits 12 to 15 must be set to the UUID version number: 4 in this case (0100)</p></li>
<li><p>all 122 other bits must be set to random values</p></li>
</ul>
<p>In practice, libraries generally choose 4 32-bit random numbers, concatenate
them and then change bits 6,7 and 12 to 15. This means that some information
about these random numbers is lost in the process, we don't get a clean PRNG
output.</p>
<p>Note that the RFC does not require the use of cryptographically secure random
numbers, but it does warn against using UUIDs for sensitive values if normal
randomness is used.</p>
</div>
<div id="phobos-implementation">
<h3>Phobos implementation</h3>
<p>Phobos' <strong>randomUUID()</strong> follows these lines perfectly, using non-secure
randomness.</p>
<pre><code><span>UUID</span> <span>randomUUID</span><span>(</span><span>RNG</span><span>)(</span><span>ref</span> <span>RNG</span> <span>randomGen</span><span>)</span>
<span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>isInputRange</span><span>!</span><span>RNG</span> <span>&amp;&amp;</span> <span>isIntegral</span><span>!</span><span>(</span><span>ElementType</span><span>!</span><span>RNG</span><span>))</span>
<span>{</span>
    <span>import</span> <span>std.random</span> <span>:</span> <span>isUniformRNG</span><span>;</span>
    <span>static</span> <span>assert</span><span>(</span><span>isUniformRNG</span><span>!</span><span>RNG</span><span>,</span> <span>"randomGen must be a uniform RNG"</span><span>);</span>

    <span>alias</span> <span>E</span> <span>=</span> <span>ElementEncodingType</span><span>!</span><span>RNG</span><span>;</span>
    <span>enum</span> <span>size_t</span> <span>elemSize</span> <span>=</span> <span>E</span><span>.</span><span>sizeof</span><span>;</span>
    <span>static</span> <span>assert</span><span>(</span><span>elemSize</span> <span>&lt;=</span> <span>16</span><span>);</span>
    <span>static</span> <span>assert</span><span>(</span><span>16</span> <span>%</span> <span>elemSize</span> <span>==</span> <span>0</span><span>);</span>

    <span>UUID</span> <span>u</span><span>;</span>
    <span>foreach</span> <span>(</span><span>ref</span> <span>E</span> <span>e</span> <span>;</span> <span>u</span><span>.</span><span>asArrayOf</span><span>!</span><span>E</span><span>())</span>
    <span>{</span>
        <span>e</span> <span>=</span> <span>randomGen</span><span>.</span><span>front</span><span>;</span>
        <span>randomGen</span><span>.</span><span>popFront</span><span>();</span>
    <span>}</span>

    <span>//set variant
</span>    <span>//must be 0b10xxxxxx
</span>    <span>u</span><span>.</span><span>data</span><span>[</span><span>8</span><span>]</span> <span>&amp;=</span> <span>0b10111111</span><span>;</span>
    <span>u</span><span>.</span><span>data</span><span>[</span><span>8</span><span>]</span> <span>|=</span> <span>0b10000000</span><span>;</span>

    <span>//set version
</span>    <span>//must be 0b0100xxxx
</span>    <span>u</span><span>.</span><span>data</span><span>[</span><span>6</span><span>]</span> <span>&amp;=</span> <span>0b01001111</span><span>;</span>
    <span>u</span><span>.</span><span>data</span><span>[</span><span>6</span><span>]</span> <span>|=</span> <span>0b01000000</span><span>;</span>

    <span>return</span> <span>u</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre>
<p>It generates 4 32-bit uint values using the default random number generator
of std.random: MT19937. If that PRNG's state is too small, it falls back on
Xorshift192 (<a href="https://github.com/dlang/phobos/blob/v2.093.0/std/uuid.d#L1200">code here</a>).</p>
<p>So our main target is Mersenne Twister 19937, possibly the most common PRNG
in use.</p>
<p><img alt="../image/chibi_cat_me_want.png" src="https://breakpoint.purrfect.fr/image/chibi_cat_me_want.png">
</p></div>
</div>
<div id="cracking-mt19937">
<h2>Cracking MT19937</h2>
<div id="previous-work">
<h3>Previous work</h3>
<p>So, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mersenne_Twister">MT19937</a> is
well-known, used a lot, and insecure. Surely other people have written about
cracking it in the past?</p>
<p>Indeed, there is a profusion of <a href="https://jazzy.id.au/2010/09/22/cracking_random_number_generators_part_3.html">articles</a>
but the most interesting one was definitely <a href="https://www.ambionics.io/blog/php-mt-rand-prediction">this article</a> by Ambionics that
does something different.</p>
<p>The basic strategy we see in these articles is to recover the internal
624-byte state of the Mersenne Twister by collecting 624 values. From there
it is possible to predict any future value. Of course this isn't immediately
an option for our larger project since some bits are missing from UUIDs due
to how they are built, but it is an important cornerstone.</p>
<p>The Ambionics strategy is very interesting also: they show that since each
output value depends only on two state values, it is possible to recover the
previous value with only two outputs. From there they rebuild the complete
seed by inverting its process. Good stuff. We will not get to use it but it
is definitely worth a read.</p>
<p>In the end all Mersenne Twisters are a bit different so we need to tailor the
approach for Phobos, but we will use two values to predict the next one.</p>
</div>
<div id="how-mt19937-works">
<h3>How MT19937 works</h3>
<p>MT19337's internal state is an array of 624 32-bit integers. That array is
seeded at initialization but we will not discuss seeding in this article. For
all intent and purposes, we start with an array of 624 random integers.</p>
<p>Once seeded, two mechanisms are at play. One outputs a number after
scrambling it (in blue in the figure) while the other updates the next entry
by combining three elements of the state array: the <em>index</em>, the <em>next</em> and
the <em>conjugate</em> (naming is hard). This process is in orange in the figure.</p>
<p><img alt="../image/mt19937_1.png" src="https://breakpoint.purrfect.fr/image/mt19937_1.png"></p><p>The actual values presented are mostly specific to Phobos' implementation,
but let's note the most important ones:</p>
<pre>n = 624    a = 0x9908b0df   c = 0xefc60000
m = 397    b = 0x9d2c5680</pre>
<p>One thing isn't apparent in this diagram, and it is how <em>next</em> and <em>index</em>
are combined to produce <em>y</em>. <em>y</em> is composed of the most significant bit of
<em>index</em> and all bits from <em>next</em> except its most significant one.</p>
<p>Each time a new number is outputted, both of these processes go one step to
the left, walking the state array in reverse order. After <em>n</em> iterations it
loops back to the end of the array.</p>
<p>You can read Phobos's implementation <a href="https://github.com/dlang/phobos/blob/master/std/random.d#L955">here</a> but note
that, in order to improve caching performances, both the blue and orange
processes are interweaved.</p>
<p>And with this we are ready to crack normal MT19937!</p>
</div>
<div id="reversing-the-scrambling">
<h3>Reversing the scrambling</h3>
<p>MT19937 is entirely defined by its internal state. If we can identify all its
624 components then we can just set the state of our own MT19937 PRNG with
these values and it'll output the same numbers. Now, given one output, if we
are able to reverse the scrambling (blue process) then we directly obtain the
corresponding state value. And if we're able to do it once, we can do it for
624 consecutive outputs and have a full internal state. The key part is that
we never need to worry about the updating (orange) process in that scenario.</p>
<p><img alt="../image/mt19937_2.png" src="https://breakpoint.purrfect.fr/image/mt19937_2.png"></p><p>In code, this gives:</p>
<pre><code><span>uint</span> <span>scramble</span><span>(</span><span>uint</span> <span>z</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>immutable</span> <span>b</span> <span>=</span> <span>0x9d2c5680</span><span>;</span>
    <span>immutable</span> <span>c</span> <span>=</span> <span>0xefc60000</span><span>;</span>

    <span>z</span> <span>^=</span>  <span>z</span> <span>&gt;&gt;</span> <span>11</span><span>;</span>
    <span>z</span> <span>^=</span> <span>(</span><span>z</span> <span>&lt;&lt;</span>  <span>7</span><span>)</span> <span>&amp;</span> <span>b</span><span>;</span>
    <span>z</span> <span>^=</span> <span>(</span><span>z</span> <span>&lt;&lt;</span> <span>15</span><span>)</span> <span>&amp;</span> <span>c</span><span>;</span>
    <span>z</span> <span>^=</span> <span>(</span><span>z</span> <span>&gt;&gt;</span> <span>18</span><span>);</span>
    <span>retur…</span></code></pre></div></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://breakpoint.purrfect.fr/article/cracking_phobos_uuid.html">https://breakpoint.purrfect.fr/article/cracking_phobos_uuid.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://breakpoint.purrfect.fr/article/cracking_phobos_uuid.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24333545</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 17:10:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Intel MKL on AMD Zen]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 135 | Comments 47 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24332825">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
August 31, 2020 | https://danieldk.eu/Posts/2020-08-31-MKL-Zen.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://danieldk.eu/Posts/2020-08-31-MKL-Zen.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
    <h2>Intel MKL on AMD Zen</h2>

<p><i>Aug 31, 2020</i></p>


  
  <p>
  <b>Tags:</b>
    
      <a href="https://danieldk.eu/Posts/tag/dev">dev</a>,
    
      <a href="https://danieldk.eu/Posts/tag/linux">linux</a>
    
  </p>


<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<p><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> this post investigates how recent MKL versions behave
on Zen CPUs. You should read the MKL license before using MKL. I shall
not be held responsible for how you use MKL.</p>

<p>Intel MKL has been known to use a SSE code paths on AMD CPUs that
support newer SIMD instructions such as those that use the Zen
microarchitecture. A (by now) well-known trick has been to set the
<code>MKL_DEBUG_CPU_TYPE</code> environment variable to the value <code>5</code> to <a href="https://www.pugetsystems.com/labs/hpc/How-To-Use-MKL-with-AMD-Ryzen-and-Threadripper-CPU-s-Effectively-for-Python-Numpy-And-Other-Applications-1637/">force
the use of AVX2
kernels</a>
on AMD Zen CPUs. Unfortunately, this <a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/matlab/comments/dxn38s/howto_force_matlab_to_use_a_fast_codepath_on_amd/fm2j83e/">variable has been
removed</a>
from Intel MKL 2020 Update 1 and later. This can be confirmed easily
by running a program that uses MKL with <code>ltrace -e getenv</code>.</p>

<h2 id="good-news-intel-seems-to-be-adding-zen-kernels">Good news: Intel seems to be adding Zen kernels</h2>

<p>However, it seems that Intel removed this option because they are
adding Zen kernels to MKL. For instance, if we run the <a href="https://www.lanl.gov/projects/crossroads/benchmarks-performance-analysis.php">ACES
dgemm</a>
benchmark with MKL 2020.2.254 on a Ryzen 3700X, performance is good:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span>./mt-dgemm 4000 | <span>grep </span>GF    
GFLOP/s rate:         382.756063 GF/s
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>A quick inspection with <code>perf</code> shows that most cycles are spent
in a Zen-optimized kernel:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>79.95%  mt-dgemm  libmkl_def.so           [.] mkl_blas_def_dgemm_kernel_zen
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="bad-news-sgemm-is-not-yet-implemented">Bad news: <code>sgemm</code> is not yet implemented</h2>

<p>However, it seems that they have not yet implemented Zen kernels
for every BLAS function yet. I modified the ACES benchmark to
use the <code>sgemm</code> BLAS function and the results aren’t quite as
good:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span>./mt-sgemm 4000 | <span>grep </span>GF
GFLOP/s rate:         237.352720 GF/s
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And indeed, <code>perf</code> reveals that MKL does not use a Zen kernel:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>88.90%  mt-sgemm  libmkl_def.so           [.] LM_LOOPgas_1
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="a-temporary-workaround">A temporary workaround</h2>

<p>Some quick tracing shows that MKL uses a single function
<code>mkl_serv_intel_cpu_true</code> to detect whether it is dealing
with a genuine Intel CPU. Fortunately, the function is
rather trivial, so we can replace it by our own function:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>int</span> <span>mkl_serv_intel_cpu_true</span><span>()</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>return</span> <span>1</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And compile it as a shared library:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span>gcc <span>-shared</span> <span>-fPIC</span> <span>-o</span> libfakeintel.so fakeintel.c
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And ensure that the library gets preloaded:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span><span>export </span><span>LD_PRELOAD</span><span>=</span>libfakeintel.so
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Now the <code>sgemm</code> benchmark shows good performance:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span>./mt-sgemm 4000 | <span>grep </span>GF
GFLOP/s rate:         851.541946 GF/s
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And indeed, an AVX2-optimized code path is used:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>82.73%  mt-sgemm  libmkl_avx2.so          [.] mkl_blas_avx2_sgemm_kernel_0
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The only minor downside is that MKL will also use AVX2 kernels for
other functions such as <code>dgemm</code>. But this does not seem to impact
performance negatively. In fact, for the <code>dgemm</code> benchmark performance
is slightly better on my machine (430 GF/s).</p>

<h2 id="making-it-permanent">Making it permanent</h2>

<p>Setting <code>LD_PRELOAD</code> everytime on a machine can get weary and one can
easily forget it. An easy solution is to add our small library to the
ELF dynamic section of your program using
<a href="https://github.com/NixOS/patchelf">patchelf</a> with the <code>DT_NEEDED</code>
tag. For example:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span>patchelf <span>--add-needed</span> libfakeintel.so yourbinary
</code></pre></div></div>



  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://danieldk.eu/Posts/2020-08-31-MKL-Zen.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24332825</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 16:10:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: ML From Scratch – free online textbook]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 235 | Comments 50 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24332303">thread link</a>) | @dafrdman
<br/>
August 31, 2020 | https://dafriedman97.github.io/mlbook/content/introduction.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dafriedman97.github.io/mlbook/content/introduction.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main-content">
        <div>
        
              <div>
                
  <div id="introduction">

<p><img alt="" src="https://dafriedman97.github.io/mlbook/_images/logo_light.png"></p>
<div id="what-this-book-covers">
<h2>What this Book Covers<a href="#what-this-book-covers" title="Permalink to this headline">¶</a></h2>
<p>This book covers the building blocks of the most common methods in machine learning. This set of methods is like a toolbox for machine learning engineers. Those entering the field of machine learning should feel comfortable with this toolbox so they have the right tool for a variety of tasks. Each chapter in this book corresponds to a single machine learning method or group of methods. In other words, each chapter focuses on a single tool within the ML toolbox.</p>
<p>In my experience, the best way to become comfortable with these methods is to see them derived from scratch, both in theory and in code. The purpose of this book is to provide those derivations. Each chapter is broken into three sections. The <em>concept</em> sections introduce the methods conceptually and derive their results mathematically. The <em>construction</em> sections show how to construct the methods from scratch using Python. The <em>implementation</em> sections demonstrate how to apply the methods using packages in Python like <code><span>scikit-learn</span></code>, <code><span>statsmodels</span></code>, and <code><span>tensorflow</span></code>.</p>
</div>
<div id="why-this-book">
<h2>Why this Book<a href="#why-this-book" title="Permalink to this headline">¶</a></h2>
<p>There are many great books on machine learning written by more knowledgeable authors and covering a broader range of topics. In particular, I would suggest <a href="http://faculty.marshall.usc.edu/gareth-james/ISL/">An Introduction to Statistical Learning</a>, <a href="https://web.stanford.edu/~hastie/ElemStatLearn/">Elements of Statistical Learning</a>, and <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/publication/pattern-recognition-machine-learning/">Pattern Recognition and Machine Learning</a>, all of which are available online for free.</p>
<p>While those books provide a conceptual overview of machine learning and the theory behind its methods, this book focuses on the bare bones of machine learning algorithms. Its main purpose is to provide readers with the ability to construct these algorithms independently. Continuing the toolbox analogy, this book is intended as a user guide: it is not designed to teach users broad practices of the field but rather how each tool works at a micro level.</p>
</div>
<div id="who-this-book-is-for">
<h2>Who this Book is for<a href="#who-this-book-is-for" title="Permalink to this headline">¶</a></h2>
<p>This book is for readers looking to learn new machine learning algorithms or understand algorithms at a deeper level. Specifically, it is intended for readers interested in seeing machine learning algorithms derived from start to finish. Seeing these derivations might help a reader previously unfamiliar with common algorithms understand how they work intuitively. Or, seeing these derivations might help a reader experienced in modeling understand how different algorithms create the models they do and the advantages and disadvantages of each one.</p>
<p>This book will be most helpful for those with practice in basic modeling. It does not review best practices—such as feature engineering or balancing response variables—or discuss in depth when certain models are more appropriate than others. Instead, it focuses on the elements of those models.</p>
</div>
<div id="what-readers-should-know">
<h2>What Readers Should Know<a href="#what-readers-should-know" title="Permalink to this headline">¶</a></h2>
<p>The <em>concept</em> sections of this book primarily require knowledge of calculus, though some require an understanding of probability (think maximum likelihood and Bayes’ Rule) and basic linear algebra (think matrix operations and dot products). The appendix reviews the <a href="https://dafriedman97.github.io/mlbook/content/appendix/methods.html"><span>math</span></a> and <a href="https://dafriedman97.github.io/mlbook/content/appendix/methods.html"><span>probability</span></a>needed to understand this book. The concept sections also reference a few common machine learning <a href="https://dafriedman97.github.io/mlbook/content/appendix/methods.html"><span>methods</span></a>, which are introduced in the appendix as well. The concept sections do not require any knowledge of programming.</p>
<p>The <em>construction</em> and <em>code</em> sections of this book use some basic Python. The construction sections require understanding of the corresponding content sections and familiarity creating functions and classes in Python. The code sections require neither.</p>









</div>
</div>


              </div>
              
        </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dafriedman97.github.io/mlbook/content/introduction.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24332303</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 15:16:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Effective testing for machine learning systems]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 90 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24332202">thread link</a>) | @brzozowski
<br/>
August 31, 2020 | https://www.jeremyjordan.me/testing-ml/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.jeremyjordan.me/testing-ml/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">
    <div>

        <article>

            


            <section>
                <div>
                    <p><em>Working as a core maintainer for <a href="https://github.com/PyTorchLightning/pytorch-lightning">PyTorch Lightning</a>, I've grown a strong appreciation for the value of tests in software development. As I've been spinning up a new project at work, I've been spending a fair amount of time thinking about how we should test machine learning systems. A couple weeks ago, one of my coworkers sent me <a href="https://homes.cs.washington.edu/~marcotcr/acl20_checklist.pdf">a fascinating paper</a> on the topic which inspired me to dig in, collect my thoughts, and write this blog post.</em> </p><p>In this blog post, we'll cover what testing looks like for traditional software development, why testing machine learning systems can be different, and discuss some strategies for writing effective tests for machine learning systems. We'll also clarify the distinction between the closely related roles of evaluation and testing as part of the model development process. By the end of this blog post, I hope you're convinced of both the extra work required to effectively test machine learning systems and the value of doing such work.</p><h2 id="what-s-different-about-testing-machine-learning-systems">What's different about testing machine learning systems?</h2><p>In traditional software systems, humans write the logic which interacts with data to produce a desired behavior. Our software tests help ensure that this <strong>written logic</strong> aligns with the actual expected behavior.</p><figure><img src="https://www.jeremyjordan.me/content/images/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-09-at-4.45.29-PM.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.jeremyjordan.me/content/images/size/w600/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-09-at-4.45.29-PM.png 600w, https://www.jeremyjordan.me/content/images/size/w1000/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-09-at-4.45.29-PM.png 1000w, https://www.jeremyjordan.me/content/images/size/w1600/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-09-at-4.45.29-PM.png 1600w, https://www.jeremyjordan.me/content/images/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-09-at-4.45.29-PM.png 1850w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>However, in machine learning systems, humans provide desired behavior as examples during training and the model optimization process produces the logic of the system. How do we ensure this <strong>learned logic</strong> is going to consistently produce our desired behavior?</p><figure><img src="https://www.jeremyjordan.me/content/images/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-09-at-4.47.06-PM.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.jeremyjordan.me/content/images/size/w600/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-09-at-4.47.06-PM.png 600w, https://www.jeremyjordan.me/content/images/size/w1000/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-09-at-4.47.06-PM.png 1000w, https://www.jeremyjordan.me/content/images/size/w1600/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-09-at-4.47.06-PM.png 1600w, https://www.jeremyjordan.me/content/images/2020/08/Screen-Shot-2020-08-09-at-4.47.06-PM.png 1850w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Let's start by looking at the best practices for testing traditional software systems and developing high-quality software. </p><p>A typical software testing suite will include:</p><ul><li><strong>unit tests</strong> which operate on atomic pieces of the codebase and can be run quickly during development,</li><li><strong>regression tests</strong> replicate bugs that we've previously encountered and fixed,</li><li><strong>integration tests</strong> which are typically longer-running tests that observe higher-level behaviors that leverage multiple components in the codebase,</li></ul><p>and follow conventions such as:</p><ul><li>don't merge code unless all tests are passing,</li><li>always write tests for newly introduced logic when contributing code,</li><li>when contributing a bug fix, be sure to write a test to capture the bug and prevent future regressions.</li></ul><figure><img src="https://www.jeremyjordan.me/content/images/2020/08/Group-5-1.jpg" alt="" srcset="https://www.jeremyjordan.me/content/images/size/w600/2020/08/Group-5-1.jpg 600w, https://www.jeremyjordan.me/content/images/size/w1000/2020/08/Group-5-1.jpg 1000w, https://www.jeremyjordan.me/content/images/size/w1600/2020/08/Group-5-1.jpg 1600w, https://www.jeremyjordan.me/content/images/2020/08/Group-5-1.jpg 2348w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption>A typical workflow for software development.</figcaption></figure><p>When we run our testing suite against the new code, we'll get a report of the specific behaviors that we've written tests around and verify that our code changes don't affect the expected behavior of the system. If a test fails, we'll know which specific behavior is no longer aligned with our expected output. We can also look at this testing report to get an understanding of how extensive our tests are by looking at metrics such as <strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Code_coverage">code coverage</a></strong>.</p><figure><img src="https://www.jeremyjordan.me/content/images/2020/08/Group-1.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.jeremyjordan.me/content/images/size/w600/2020/08/Group-1.png 600w, https://www.jeremyjordan.me/content/images/size/w1000/2020/08/Group-1.png 1000w, https://www.jeremyjordan.me/content/images/2020/08/Group-1.png 1149w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption>An example output from a traditional software testing suite.</figcaption></figure><p>Let's contrast this with a typical workflow for developing machine learning systems. After training a new model, we'll typically produce an evaluation report including:</p><ul><li>performance of an established metric on a validation dataset,</li><li>plots such as precision-recall curves,</li><li>operational statistics such as inference speed,</li><li>examples where the model was most confidently incorrect,</li></ul><p>and follow conventions such as:</p><ul><li>save all of the hyper-parameters used to train the model,</li><li>only promote models which offer an improvement over the existing model (or baseline) when evaluated on the same dataset. </li></ul><figure><img src="https://www.jeremyjordan.me/content/images/2020/08/Group-3-1.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.jeremyjordan.me/content/images/size/w600/2020/08/Group-3-1.png 600w, https://www.jeremyjordan.me/content/images/size/w1000/2020/08/Group-3-1.png 1000w, https://www.jeremyjordan.me/content/images/2020/08/Group-3-1.png 1174w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption>A typical workflow for model development.</figcaption></figure><p>When reviewing a new machine learning model, we'll inspect metrics and plots which summarize model performance over a validation dataset. We're able to compare performance between multiple models and make relative judgements, but we're not immediately able to characterize specific model behaviors. For example, figuring out <em>where</em> the model is failing usually requires additional investigative work; one common practice here is to look through a list of the top most egregious model errors on the validation dataset and manually categorize these failure modes.</p><p>Assuming we write behavioral tests for our models (discussed below), there's also the question of whether or not we have enough tests! While traditional software tests have metrics such as the lines of code covered when running tests, this becomes harder to quantify when you shift your application logic from lines of code to parameters of a machine learning model. Do we want to quantify our test coverage with respect to the input data distribution? Or perhaps the possible activations inside the model?</p><p><a href="http://proceedings.mlr.press/v97/odena19a/odena19a.pdf">Odena et al</a>. introduce one possible metric for coverage where we track the model logits for all of the test examples and quantify the area covered by radial neighborhoods around these activation vectors. However, my perception is that as an industry we don't have a well-established convention here. In fact, it feels like that testing for machine learning systems is in such early days that this question of test coverage isn't really being asked by many people.</p><h2 id="what-s-the-difference-between-model-testing-and-model-evaluation">What's the difference between model testing and model evaluation?</h2><p>While reporting evaluation metrics is certainly a good practice for quality assurance during model development, I don't think it's sufficient. Without a granular report of specific behaviors, we won't be able to immediately understand the nuance of how behavior may change if we switch over to the new model. Additionally, we won't be able to track (and prevent) behavioral regressions for specific failure modes that had been previously addressed.</p><p>This can be especially dangerous for machine learning systems since often times failures happen silently. For example, you might improve the overall evaluation metric but introduce a regression on a critical subset of data. Or you could unknowingly add a gender bias to the model through the inclusion of a new dataset during training. We need more nuanced reports of model behavior to identify such cases, which is exactly where model testing can help.</p><p>For machine learning systems, we should be running model evaluation and model tests in parallel. </p><ul><li><strong>Model evaluation</strong> covers metrics and plots which summarize performance on a validation or test dataset.</li><li><strong>Model testing</strong> involves explicit checks for behaviors that we expect our model to follow.</li></ul><p>Both of these perspectives are instrumental in building high-quality models. </p><p>In practice, most people are doing a combination of the two where evaluation metrics are calculated automatically and some level of model "testing" is done <a href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/machine-learning-projects/lecture/GwViP/carrying-out-error-analysis">manually through error analysis</a> (i.e. classifying failure modes). Developing model tests for machine learning systems can offer a systematic approach towards error analysis.</p><h2 id="how-do-you-write-model-tests">How do you write model tests?</h2><p>In my opinion, there's two general classes of model tests that we'll want to write.</p><ul><li><strong>Pre-train</strong> <strong>tests</strong> allow us to identify some bugs early on and short-circuit a training job.</li><li><strong>Post-train tests</strong> use the trained model artifact to inspect behaviors for a variety of important scenarios that we define.</li></ul><h3 id="pre-train-tests">Pre-train tests</h3><p>There's some tests that we can run without needing trained parameters. These tests include:</p><ul><li>check the shape of your model output and ensure it aligns with the labels in your dataset</li><li>check the output ranges and ensure it aligns with our expectations (eg. the output of a classification model should be a distribution with class probabilities that sum to 1)</li><li>make sure a single gradient step on a batch of data yields a decrease in your loss</li><li>make <a href="https://greatexpectations.io/">assertions about your datasets</a></li><li>check for label leakage between your training and validation datasets</li></ul><p>The main goal here is to identify some errors early so we can avoid a wasted training job.</p><h3 id="post-train-tests">Post-train tests</h3><p>However, in order for us to be able to understand model behaviors we'll need to test against trained model artifacts. These tests aim to <strong>interrogate the logic learned during training</strong> and provide us with a behavioral report of model performance.</p><blockquote><strong>Paper highlight</strong>: <a href="https://homes.cs.washington.edu/~marcotcr/acl20_checklist.pdf">Beyond Accuracy: Behavioral Testing of NLP Models with CheckList</a></blockquote><p>The authors of the above paper present three different types of model tests that we can use to understand behavioral attributes. </p><p><strong>Invariance Tests</strong></p><p>Invariance tests allow us to describe a set of perturbations we should be able to make to the input <em>without</em> affecting the model's output. We can use these perturbations to produce pairs of input examples (original and perturbed) and <strong>check for consistency</strong> in the model predictions. This is closely related to the concept of data augmentation, where we apply perturbations to inputs during training and preserve the original label. </p><p>For example, imagine running a sentiment analysis model on the following two sentences:</p><ul><li><u>Mark</u> was a great instructor.</li><li><u>Samantha</u> was a great instructor.</li></ul><p>We would expect that simply changing the name of the subject doesn't affect the model predictions. </p><p><strong>Directional Expectation Tests</strong></p><p>Directional expectation tests, on the other hand, allow us to define a set of perturbations to the input which <em>should</em> have a <em>predictable</em> effect on the model output. </p><p>For example, if we had a housing price prediction model we might assert:</p><ul><li>Increasing the number of bathrooms (holding all other features constant) should not cause a drop in price.</li><li>Lowering the square footage of the house (holding all other features constant) should not cause an increase in price.</li></ul><p>Let's consider a scenario where a model fails the second test - taking a random row from our validation dataset and decreasing the feature <code>house_sq_ft</code> yields a higher predicted price than the original label. This is surprising as it doesn't match our intuition, so we decide to look further into it. We realize that, without having a feature for the house's neighborhood/location, our model has learned that smaller units tend to be more expensive; this is due to the fact that smaller units from our dataset are more prevalent in cities where prices are generally higher. In this case, the <em>selection</em> of our dataset has influenced the model's logic in unintended ways - this isn't something …</p></div></section></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.jeremyjordan.me/testing-ml/">https://www.jeremyjordan.me/testing-ml/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.jeremyjordan.me/testing-ml/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24332202</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 15:07:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[As above, so below, part 2. Bare metal Rust generics]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 79 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24332187">thread link</a>) | @M2Ys4U
<br/>
August 31, 2020 | https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-2/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-2/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <p>During <a href="https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-1/">last episode</a>, we went on a tour of the
pleasantly boring world of flash memory, drafted some driver interfaces, and
toyed with the idea of generics at both levels of crate visibility. What's
conspicuously absent is, well, <em>working code.</em> It's one thing to lay down data
structures, and another entirely to weave generics between the raw ones and
zeros of bare metal firmware. Today we'll gaze long into the void*, and,
hopefully, the void* won't gaze back into us.</p>

<p>In the <a href="https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-1/#what-is-flash-memory">section about flash
memory</a> we
explored, with the help of a dodgy analogy, how it's possible to directly
overwrite a <code>1</code> with a <code>0</code> but not the reverse. This quirk is what makes
writing efficient flash writers a bit tricky. When asked to write over a memory
range, a naive driver would simply erase every sector overlapped by it, then
write back the original data "merged" with the desired bytes. We want our driver
a bit smarter than that; it should first check whether it's possible to write
the bytes directly. In other words, we want to ensure that every <code>1</code> in our
intended write is also a <code>1</code> in the target space.</p>
<pre><code><span>pub trait </span><span>BitSubset {
    </span><span>/// Check that every '1' bit is a '1' on the right hand side.
</span><span>    </span><span>fn </span><span>is_subset_of</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>self</span><span>, </span><span>rhs</span><span>: </span><span>&amp;</span><span>Self</span><span>) -&gt; </span><span>bool</span><span>;
}
</span></code></pre>
<p>That looks like a straightforward, simple trait to express the condition we want
to check. Here comes the unnecessary part: We're going to implement it
generically. Let's be honest, we <em>both</em> know we want to implement this for
<code>[u8]</code>. There shouldn't be much use for it other than slices of bytes. However,
doing it this way will help flex our generic muscles and illustrate a couple of
important points.</p>
<pre><code><span>impl</span><span>&lt;T: </span><span>Copy </span><span>+ </span><span>Eq </span><span>+ </span><span>BitOr&lt;Output=T&gt;&gt; BitSubset </span><span>for</span><span> [T] {
    </span><span>fn </span><span>is_subset_of</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>self</span><span>, </span><span>rhs</span><span>: </span><span>&amp;</span><span>Self</span><span>) -&gt; </span><span>bool </span><span>{
        </span><span>if </span><span>self.</span><span>len</span><span>() </span><span>&gt;</span><span> rhs.</span><span>len</span><span>() {
            </span><span>false
        </span><span>} </span><span>else </span><span>{
            self.</span><span>iter</span><span>().</span><span>zip</span><span>(rhs.</span><span>iter</span><span>()).</span><span>all</span><span>(|(</span><span>a</span><span>, </span><span>b</span><span>)| (</span><span>*</span><span>a </span><span>| *</span><span>b) </span><span>== *</span><span>b)
        }
    }
}
</span></code></pre>
<p>Yes, I feel that dread too. There are enough sigils up there to summon half
the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lesser_Key_of_Solomon">Lesser Key of
Solomon</a>. We have
<strong>five</strong> types of brackets (<code>&lt;(|[{</code>) and we're barely getting started.
Fortunately symbols are much like ant invasions—live with them long enough and
you'll stop noticing. They can even be endearing.</p>
<p>When I started playing with Rust generics a few years ago, it often helped me to
approach functions by parts; focusing first on the constraints, moving to
the implementation only when I've painted a clear picture of the elements involved.
I find there's a bit of ritual in deciphering constraints, not unlike the
infamous <a href="http://c-faq.com/decl/spiral.anderson.html">spiral rule</a> for C
declarations. For me, it takes the form of describing them in a
manner of plain English pseudocode. For the above it would look like this:</p>
<ul>
<li>We have <em>something</em> that can be copied and compared.</li>
<li>It can be bitwise or'd with itself.</li>
<li>We are implementing over an array of it.</li>
</ul>
<p>For more complex lists I'd sing these conditions in my head a few times until
the abstract types coalesce into something more manageable, at which point it
becomes possible to push the sigil soup away and focus on behaviour.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>All</strong> the behaviour of these type parameters is summarized in these
constraints. Nothing is implicit. That's <em>very cool</em>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In this case, all that's left is a bit of iterator magic and bit wrangling.
<code>self.iter().zip(rhs.iter()).all(Condition)</code> "zips" two iterators together in
pairs, then verifies that every pair satisfies a condition. In our case the
condition is the closure <code>|(a, b)| (*a | *b) == *b</code>. For the condition to hold,
all <code>1</code> bits in element <code>*a</code> must also be <code>1</code> in <code>*b</code>.</p>
<p>We'll use this later to compare, as we anticipated, slices of bytes. What have
we gained from doing it generically?</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Even though <code>T: Copy + Eq + BitOr&lt;Output=T&gt;</code> is certainly a lot wordier
than <code>u8</code>, it's also <strong>purer</strong> in some sense, because it more accurately
summarizes what we care about. Weirdly,
the shorter <code>u8</code> carries a lot more extraneous, distracting baggage:</p>
<ul>
<li>It is 8 bits long, which is a hardware detail we don't care about.</li>
<li>It is unsigned, which is a mathematical detail we don't care about.</li>
</ul>
<p>In contrast, our platonic <code>T</code> is refreshingly simple: only does the things
that the implementation needs. And as such, the implementation <em>will be
correct now and forever after</em>, which leads to the next point:</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>When our constraints match the requirements of the implementation so tightly,
we can resort to blanket implementations, knowing that future users will opt
into this behaviour automatically if they define a type that matches these
requirements. Crates like the impressively elegant
<a href="https://bevyengine.org/">Bevy</a> take this idea further, using their prelude to
bring blanket implementations over a wide range of types without exposing the
user to the trait. This leads, I think, to very ergonomic APIs.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Not that we'd have any reason to suspect otherwise, but the
<a href="https://godbolt.org/z/5abac4">concrete</a> and
<a href="https://godbolt.org/z/nxMW57">generic</a> versions produce identical assembly.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>We've increased our sigil count, getting closer to summoning
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kimaris">Kimaris</a>, Marquis of Hell, ruler of 20
demonic legions, teacher of grammar, logic and rhetoric. Maybe he'll finally
produce an intuitive definition of a
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monad_(functional_programming)">monad</a>.</p>
</li>
</ul>

<p>At <a href="https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-1/#taking-a-step-back">the end of the last
entry</a>, we sketched out the
constraints on our minimal concept of address and region:</p>
<pre><code><span>pub trait </span><span>Address: Ord + Copy + Add&lt;usize, Output = Self&gt; {}
</span><span>pub trait </span><span>Region&lt;A: Address&gt; {
    </span><span>fn </span><span>contains</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>self</span><span>, </span><span>address</span><span>: A) -&gt; </span><span>bool</span><span>;
}
</span></code></pre>
<p><em>But cuervo</em>, you ask, <em>that's not how it looked like last week. You added an</em>
<code>Add</code> <em>constraint.</em> Okay, hypothetical attentive reader, you got me. I may have
forgotten to copy that as I was curating the code examples. Yes, the
<code>core::ops::Add</code> bound will be necessary, as we'll see in a bit. This gives us
an excuse to sing the generics song, which works just as well for supertrait
definitons:</p>
<ul>
<li>An <code>Address</code> is <em>something</em> that can be sorted and copied. It can be added
together with an offset, yielding another address.</li>
<li>A <code>Region</code> is <em>something</em> that may contain an address.</li>
</ul>
<p>What can we build with this? We know that one of the goals of our flash driver
is to smartly negotiate the different write and erase granularities, so that for
any given buffer write, only the required regions are erased. In order to do
this, there's a requirement we can accurately summarize in this way:</p>
<p><strong>For a buffer of given length, and for a base address in the target memory map,
we need to relate each buffer segment to every region it overlaps with.</strong></p>
<p>Here rendered through the power of ASCII:</p>
<pre><code><span>0    5    10   15   20   25   30   35
-----|ooooooooooooooooooooooooooooo|------ : Buffer of length 30 at address 5
----------|====|====|====|====|----------- : Four regions of length 5 at address 10
</span></code></pre>
<p>Given the two inputs above, we need to produce the following four views into the
buffer:</p>
<pre><code><span>
0    5      10      15      20      25      30   35
-----|ooooo [ooooo] [ooooo] [ooooo] [ooooo] ooooo|-----
             view1   view2   view3   view4
</span></code></pre>
<p>Our goal in this section is to <em>define such operation generically</em>, and
<em>implement it generically</em>, in such a way that it will work with
last week's sectors, subsectors and pages from both drivers.</p>
<p>Now, if you're allergic to symbols, be warned: Here be dragons. Henceforth be
dragon turtles, all the way down. We are about to reach <em>ancient Egyptian
shopping in <a href="https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-2/akihabara.jpeg">Akihabara</a></em> levels of symbol overload. Believe me
that after some time none of them will feel superfluous or overwrought. As
with human language, precise definitions lead to better understanding.</p>
<p>Okay, let's take a deep breath.</p>
<pre><code><span>/// Iterator producing block-region pairs,
/// where each memory block maps to each region
</span><span>pub struct </span><span>OverlapIterator&lt;</span><span>'a</span><span>, A, R, I&gt;
where
    A: Address,
    R: Region&lt;A&gt;,
    I: Iterator&lt;Item = R&gt;,
{
    memory: </span><span>&amp;</span><span>'a</span><span> [</span><span>u8</span><span>],
    regions: I,
    base_address: A,
}

</span><span>pub trait </span><span>IterableByOverlaps&lt;'a, A, R, I&gt;
where
    A: Address,
    R: Region&lt;A&gt;,
    I: Iterator&lt;Item = R&gt;,
{
    </span><span>fn </span><span>overlaps</span><span>(</span><span>self</span><span>, </span><span>block</span><span>: </span><span>&amp;</span><span>'a</span><span> [</span><span>u8</span><span>], </span><span>base_address</span><span>: A) -&gt; OverlapIterator&lt;A, R, I&gt;;
}
</span></code></pre>
<p>Hmm. Not too bad thus far. We have the tools necessary to break down the <em>where</em>
clause, which is identical for both the struct and the trait. We are dealing
with:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Some</em> address <code>A</code>.</li>
<li><em>Some</em> region <code>R</code> which contains such addresses.</li>
<li><em>Some</em> iterator <code>I</code> that yields such regions.</li>
</ul>
<p>The explicit lifetime, a requisite of all structs containing references, simply
denotes that the <code>memory</code> field is a reference to data stored elsewhere, and
guarantees said data will exist <strong>at least</strong> as long as our struct.</p>
<p>What we've defined above is an iterator struct, and a trait for types that can
be iterated in a certain way. If you come from C, iterators can be a bit of a
mind bender. They <em>feel</em> heavy, but ultimately they're very
simple. I like to think of iterator structs as bookmarks for physical books;
progress trackers with just enough state to find your position in a sequence.</p>
<p>Looking at our iterator struct above, we see we can track our progress through
the inner <code>regions</code> iterator, until we run out of regions. We also have a means
of producing this kind of iterator—the <code>overlaps</code> function in the
<code>IterableByOverlaps</code> trait—so all that's left is to define the <em>rules</em> of
iteration. The implementation I'm going to show you can do with some manual
optimization, and indeed it doesn't look exactly like this in the final
<code>Loadstone</code> code. I went with the slightly more readable option to better
illustrate the points in this article.</p>
<pre><code><span>impl</span><span>&lt;</span><span>'a</span><span>, A, R, I&gt; Iterator </span><span>for </span><span>OverlapIterator&lt;</span><span>'a</span><span>, A, R, I&gt;
</span><span>where</span><span>
    A: Address,
    R: Region&lt;A&gt;,
    I: </span><span>Iterator</span><span>&lt;Item = R&gt;,
{
    </span><span>type </span><span>Item </span><span>= </span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>'a </span><span>[</span><span>u8</span><span>], R, A);

    </span><span>fn </span><span>next</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>mut </span><span>self</span><span>) -&gt; </span><span>Option</span><span>&lt;</span><span>Self::</span><span>Item&gt; {
        </span><span>while let </span><span>Some</span><span>(region) </span><span>= </span><span>self.regions.</span><span>next</span><span>() {
            </span><span>let mut</span><span> block_range </span><span>= </span><span>(</span><span>0</span><span>..</span><span>self.memory.</span><span>len</span><span>())
                .</span><span>skip_while</span><span>(|</span><span>index</span><span>| </span><span>!</span><span>region.</span><span>contains</span><span>(self.base_address </span><span>+ *</span><span>index))
                .</span><span>take_while</span><span>(|</span><span>index</span><span>| region.</span><span>contains</span><span>(self.base_address </span><span>+ *</span><span>index));
            </span><span>if let </span><span>Some</span><span>(start) </span><span>=</span><span> block_range.</span><span>next</span><span>() {
                </span><span>let</span><span> end </span><span>=</span><span> block_range.</span><span>last</span><span>().</span><span>unwrap_or</span><span>(start) </span><span>+ </span><span>1</span><span>;
                </span><span>return </span><span>Some</span><span>((</span><span>&amp;</span><span>self.memory[start</span><span>..</span><span>end], region, self.base_address </span><span>+</span><span> start));
            }
        }
        </span><span>None
    </span><span>}
}

</span><span>impl</span><span>&lt;</span><span>'a</span><span>, A, R, I&gt; …</span></code></pre></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-2/">https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-2/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-2/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24332187</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 15:06:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Motivation – Keli Language]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 275 | Comments 273 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24331635">thread link</a>) | @azhenley
<br/>
August 31, 2020 | https://keli-language.gitbook.io/doc/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://keli-language.gitbook.io/doc/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div><div data-editioncontainer="true"><div data-slate-editor="true" data-key="4" autocorrect="on" spellcheck="true" data-gramm="false"><p data-key="897a985a86cc4278b06ee2367236de5a"><span><span data-key="18568aa2ade34dcf81ff08476e0b0772"><span data-offset-key="18568aa2ade34dcf81ff08476e0b0772:0">A user from Quora asked: </span></span></span></p><blockquote data-key="69783191aed44c8c99cfcfbbf5fb418b"><p data-key="42fffa898e7d4cfab7bda3c5aa1876fd"><span><span data-key="f2cad49fcd004710a8b79e77417a0f72"><span data-offset-key="f2cad49fcd004710a8b79e77417a0f72:0"><span data-slate-zero-width="z">​</span></span></span><a href="https://www.quora.com/Why-isnt-functional-programming-that-popular-even-though-its-so-beneficial" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-key="24fb50b6b71e452288b87f2ca8e9e707"><span data-key="ab47b806c4a4469a8767843f865b9384"><span data-offset-key="ab47b806c4a4469a8767843f865b9384:0">Why isn't functional programming that popular even though it's so beneficial?</span></span></a><span data-key="27b008a81d68439fa2a11e5f87afb644"><span data-offset-key="27b008a81d68439fa2a11e5f87afb644:0"><span data-slate-zero-width="z">​</span></span></span></span></p></blockquote><p data-key="353e366d50d94fbbb9145756cf92834f"><span><span data-key="ea16ded4dd07432bbb4a736b3243b91c"><span data-offset-key="ea16ded4dd07432bbb4a736b3243b91c:0">One of the top answer says: </span></span></span></p><blockquote data-key="f442b5154acc415790599c554a6f585d"><p data-key="c84fbbd36b62498ab531ba7ad121cddd"><span><span data-key="6bb3bf85692941b3974cba42c816f26c"><span data-offset-key="6bb3bf85692941b3974cba42c816f26c:0">The user experiences of functional programming languages sucks.</span></span></span></p></blockquote><p data-key="df00ff40225c4481ab4b679fba62168b"><span><span data-key="f5da13623e4843768fcae1f7e98c2f4c"><span data-offset-key="f5da13623e4843768fcae1f7e98c2f4c:0">No doubt, this is a sad but true story for most functional programming  (FP) languages. I personally thought that FP languages like Haskell offers a very unified and pure programming concepts (</span><span data-offset-key="f5da13623e4843768fcae1f7e98c2f4c:1"><em data-slate-leaf="true">i.e. everything are functions, and functions and compose well, etc</em></span><span data-offset-key="f5da13623e4843768fcae1f7e98c2f4c:2">). However, Haskell syntax is a mess (</span></span><a href="https://www.haskell.org/onlinereport/syntax-iso.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-key="c2042c06c32c4516a8fd4b5e7e28a162"><span data-key="20d8508c88354fca87c0cbff422512b4"><span data-offset-key="20d8508c88354fca87c0cbff422512b4:0">take a look at the grammar</span></span></a><span data-key="6f6e8f688d734782a153bf5918c51ee0"><span data-offset-key="6f6e8f688d734782a153bf5918c51ee0:0">), there are a lot of edge cases (e.g. </span></span><a href="https://github.com/haskell/haskell-mode/wiki/Why-TAB-cycle-indentation-for-Haskell-is-a-hard-problem" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-key="95044b6c0c574f2d929c7a346f42ec67"><span data-key="5c60b4b35add407bb6273bae9a53e2da"><span data-offset-key="5c60b4b35add407bb6273bae9a53e2da:0">weird indentation rules</span></span></a><span data-key="9da68936fb284fce8190d8fd8b8c5e7f"><span data-offset-key="9da68936fb284fce8190d8fd8b8c5e7f:0">). Of course this problem is not only limited to Haskell, similar problems can also be found in other FP languages like Erlang, F#, OCaml etc.  Thus, I believe that these are also the primal reason that most people felt FP languages are hard. </span></span></span></p><blockquote data-key="444c20d31f07450d82fe4e4a393b5e4b"><p data-key="2e8ede7447e1425a9bf12e51fc60d5c7"><span><span data-key="d0b01956d02e49c6800c1df1af4d6db6"><span data-offset-key="d0b01956d02e49c6800c1df1af4d6db6:0">I wanted more people to adopt FP. </span></span></span></p></blockquote><p data-key="fd022cfd71d1440481cf9b6b342bbd9c"><span><span data-key="be00defcb46b42edb54efcfaf80543d1"><span data-offset-key="be00defcb46b42edb54efcfaf80543d1:0">That is what I wished for, therefore I'm motivated to create a language called Keli (named after my girlfriend), which hopes to an FP language with good user experience (UX). </span></span></span></p><p data-key="734c706e1d9f4669a3453b2582087686"><span><span data-key="d9cd55bdf12447068a38da641de552f8"><span data-offset-key="d9cd55bdf12447068a38da641de552f8:0">In the following section, I will describe the UX problems of FP languages and how they are solved in other programming languages.</span></span></span></p><h2 id="1-ambiguous-functions-argument-positions" data-key="04052a38274f400ea45ec6130d0313ef"><p><span><span data-key="af49270742cc4c589e4b648f1dcf78a1"><span data-offset-key="af49270742cc4c589e4b648f1dcf78a1:0">1. Ambiguous functions argument positions</span></span></span><a href="#1-ambiguous-functions-argument-positions" contenteditable="false"><span><svg preserveAspectRatio="xMidYMid meet" height="1em" width="1em" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke="currentColor"><g><path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71"></path><path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71"></path></g></svg></span></a></p></h2><p data-key="abed90c7e63e4c658ec38c7fa2540ef9"><span><span data-key="e89bcae79a974df4a8061319d18b1d42"><span data-offset-key="e89bcae79a974df4a8061319d18b1d42:0">This is a problem where the user cannot properly tell where to place function arguments properly without looking at documentation. This problem is actually prevalent for every programming languages that favors </span><span data-offset-key="e89bcae79a974df4a8061319d18b1d42:1"><em data-slate-leaf="true">prefix function invocations , </em></span><span data-offset-key="e89bcae79a974df4a8061319d18b1d42:2">for example C, Bash, Assembly, and most FP languages. </span></span></span></p><p data-key="7e8e1f5e25c4488aa0fcb3dff6608361"><span><span data-key="20e9af9b922545caba02b355f10d1a11"><span data-offset-key="20e9af9b922545caba02b355f10d1a11:0">For example, without referring to documentation or previous experiences, a user can never tell which of the following will yield intended result, even though the user have the domain knowledge (in this case, basic English).</span></span></span></p><div><pre data-key="17e021d0bcff41f09ff3ae0a7dfc68ed" spellcheck="false"><p><span data-key="d2e4ddfd2e324dba9b5b78f14850e85e"><span data-offset-key="d2e4ddfd2e324dba9b5b78f14850e85e:0"><span>splitBy</span></span><span data-offset-key="d2e4ddfd2e324dba9b5b78f14850e85e:1"><span> </span></span><span data-offset-key="d2e4ddfd2e324dba9b5b78f14850e85e:2"><span>","</span></span><span data-offset-key="d2e4ddfd2e324dba9b5b78f14850e85e:3"><span>  </span></span><span data-offset-key="d2e4ddfd2e324dba9b5b78f14850e85e:4"><span>"1,2,3,4,5"</span></span></span></p><p><span data-key="91d75d0d9c544b02beab1e287a564158"><span data-offset-key="91d75d0d9c544b02beab1e287a564158:0"><span data-slate-zero-width="n">​</span></span></span></p><p><span data-key="ac60595e4a384c70a69e5ee1361a9511"><span data-offset-key="ac60595e4a384c70a69e5ee1361a9511:0"><span>splitBy</span></span><span data-offset-key="ac60595e4a384c70a69e5ee1361a9511:1"><span> </span></span><span data-offset-key="ac60595e4a384c70a69e5ee1361a9511:2"><span>"1,2,3,4,5"</span></span><span data-offset-key="ac60595e4a384c70a69e5ee1361a9511:3"><span>  </span></span><span data-offset-key="ac60595e4a384c70a69e5ee1361a9511:4"><span>","</span></span></span></p></pre></div><p data-key="819c8ab5145646748f5db7f6bbf6e901"><span><span data-key="86b35daddacd4679a911238ad8c0fe6a"><span data-offset-key="86b35daddacd4679a911238ad8c0fe6a:0">This problem is slightly mitigated in object-oriented programming(OOP) languages due to their </span><span data-offset-key="86b35daddacd4679a911238ad8c0fe6a:1"><em data-slate-leaf="true">infix function invocation</em></span><span data-offset-key="86b35daddacd4679a911238ad8c0fe6a:2"> nature. For example, in Java or Scala, the code above can be rewritten in a more comprehensible manner:</span></span></span></p><div><pre data-key="8b5bbbca43254f9d9e6c898cfb2fd36e" spellcheck="false"><p><span data-key="911153d975fa45f9be7f2dde82e28d43"><span data-offset-key="911153d975fa45f9be7f2dde82e28d43:0"><span>","</span></span><span data-offset-key="911153d975fa45f9be7f2dde82e28d43:1"><span>.</span></span><span data-offset-key="911153d975fa45f9be7f2dde82e28d43:2"><span>splitBy</span></span><span data-offset-key="911153d975fa45f9be7f2dde82e28d43:3"><span>(</span></span><span data-offset-key="911153d975fa45f9be7f2dde82e28d43:4"><span>"1,2,3,4,5"</span></span><span data-offset-key="911153d975fa45f9be7f2dde82e28d43:5"><span>)</span></span></span></p><p><span data-key="9254f3da1727457aa4702cacb885f823"><span data-offset-key="9254f3da1727457aa4702cacb885f823:0"><span data-slate-zero-width="n">​</span></span></span></p><p><span data-key="175af9f4b0714d6f916d135830a59afe"><span data-offset-key="175af9f4b0714d6f916d135830a59afe:0"><span>"1,2,3,4,5"</span></span><span data-offset-key="175af9f4b0714d6f916d135830a59afe:1"><span>.</span></span><span data-offset-key="175af9f4b0714d6f916d135830a59afe:2"><span>splitBy</span></span><span data-offset-key="175af9f4b0714d6f916d135830a59afe:3"><span>(</span></span><span data-offset-key="175af9f4b0714d6f916d135830a59afe:4"><span>","</span></span><span data-offset-key="175af9f4b0714d6f916d135830a59afe:5"><span>)</span></span></span></p></pre></div><p data-key="2379c8bf6fc94665a1cec7bcfaebcf42"><span><span data-key="c1e029fd3029494caedc7fd1d31d09b9"><span data-offset-key="c1e029fd3029494caedc7fd1d31d09b9:0">However, OOP languages also suffers the same problem whenever the number of function/method arguments get more than two, for example:</span></span></span></p><div><pre data-key="550ac5fe769b4b039804506515ba8e4e" spellcheck="false"><p><span data-key="553635cdaf4c4677a94a8fd5158fbf5a"><span data-offset-key="553635cdaf4c4677a94a8fd5158fbf5a:0"><span>"Hello world"</span></span><span data-offset-key="553635cdaf4c4677a94a8fd5158fbf5a:1"><span>.</span></span><span data-offset-key="553635cdaf4c4677a94a8fd5158fbf5a:2"><span>replace</span></span><span data-offset-key="553635cdaf4c4677a94a8fd5158fbf5a:3"><span>(</span></span><span data-offset-key="553635cdaf4c4677a94a8fd5158fbf5a:4"><span>"Hello"</span></span><span data-offset-key="553635cdaf4c4677a94a8fd5158fbf5a:5"><span>,</span></span><span data-offset-key="553635cdaf4c4677a94a8fd5158fbf5a:6"><span> </span></span><span data-offset-key="553635cdaf4c4677a94a8fd5158fbf5a:7"><span>"Bye"</span></span><span data-offset-key="553635cdaf4c4677a94a8fd5158fbf5a:8"><span>)</span></span></span></p><p><span data-key="66a80816accd4c7da6114bdda6743742"><span data-offset-key="66a80816accd4c7da6114bdda6743742:0"><span>"Hello world"</span></span><span data-offset-key="66a80816accd4c7da6114bdda6743742:1"><span>.</span></span><span data-offset-key="66a80816accd4c7da6114bdda6743742:2"><span>replace</span></span><span data-offset-key="66a80816accd4c7da6114bdda6743742:3"><span>(</span></span><span data-offset-key="66a80816accd4c7da6114bdda6743742:4"><span>"Bye"</span></span><span data-offset-key="66a80816accd4c7da6114bdda6743742:5"><span>,</span></span><span data-offset-key="66a80816accd4c7da6114bdda6743742:6"><span> </span></span><span data-offset-key="66a80816accd4c7da6114bdda6743742:7"><span>"Hello"</span></span><span data-offset-key="66a80816accd4c7da6114bdda6743742:8"><span>)</span></span></span></p></pre></div><p data-key="da8e06dea9674ad79879e5faab153880"><span><span data-key="499ec0148d7f46de8e3bc3a3d12ab97f"><span data-offset-key="499ec0148d7f46de8e3bc3a3d12ab97f:0">Fortunately, this problem is actually solved by a languages called Smalltalk, which is designed by Alan Kay and intended to be used by children of all ages. Smalltalk solves this by using its message syntax, for example:</span></span></span></p><div><pre data-key="96cea94a4b604ea7a17043642f4e8d36" spellcheck="false"><p><span data-key="719babccff1c480eb9672c86204a7d3f"><span data-offset-key="719babccff1c480eb9672c86204a7d3f:0"><span>'Hello world'</span></span><span data-offset-key="719babccff1c480eb9672c86204a7d3f:1"><span> replace</span></span><span data-offset-key="719babccff1c480eb9672c86204a7d3f:2"><span>:</span></span><span data-offset-key="719babccff1c480eb9672c86204a7d3f:3"><span> </span></span><span data-offset-key="719babccff1c480eb9672c86204a7d3f:4"><span>'Hello'</span></span><span data-offset-key="719babccff1c480eb9672c86204a7d3f:5"><span> with</span></span><span data-offset-key="719babccff1c480eb9672c86204a7d3f:6"><span>:</span></span><span data-offset-key="719babccff1c480eb9672c86204a7d3f:7"><span> </span></span><span data-offset-key="719babccff1c480eb9672c86204a7d3f:8"><span>'Bye'</span></span></span></p></pre></div><p data-key="5f057424e95c4e658c2392ec1e777227"><span><span data-key="4217098b9cc047989413e787727277a0"><span data-offset-key="4217098b9cc047989413e787727277a0:0">And the good thing of such syntax is that it scales, no matter how many arguments your function is taking, for example:</span></span></span></p><div><pre data-key="0494404f37e642a8a204156efc1d68e6" spellcheck="false"><p><span data-key="036fa5bc8adc4f6a8e74df935207cc73"><span data-offset-key="036fa5bc8adc4f6a8e74df935207cc73:0"><span>'Hello world'</span></span><span data-offset-key="036fa5bc8adc4f6a8e74df935207cc73:1"><span> replaceFromIndex</span></span><span data-offset-key="036fa5bc8adc4f6a8e74df935207cc73:2"><span>:</span></span><span data-offset-key="036fa5bc8adc4f6a8e74df935207cc73:3"><span> </span></span><span data-offset-key="036fa5bc8adc4f6a8e74df935207cc73:4"><span>0</span></span><span data-offset-key="036fa5bc8adc4f6a8e74df935207cc73:5"><span> toIndex</span></span><span data-offset-key="036fa5bc8adc4f6a8e74df935207cc73:6"><span>:</span></span><span data-offset-key="036fa5bc8adc4f6a8e74df935207cc73:7"><span> </span></span><span data-offset-key="036fa5bc8adc4f6a8e74df935207cc73:8"><span>4</span></span><span data-offset-key="036fa5bc8adc4f6a8e74df935207cc73:9"><span> with</span></span><span data-offset-key="036fa5bc8adc4f6a8e74df935207cc73:10"><span>:</span></span><span data-offset-key="036fa5bc8adc4f6a8e74df935207cc73:11"><span> </span></span><span data-offset-key="036fa5bc8adc4f6a8e74df935207cc73:12"><span>'Bye'</span></span></span></p></pre></div><p data-key="6158d699b8644329a044624ede002b4b"><span><span data-key="eb4373b5828f486290c9ebcd91e88a8a"><span data-offset-key="eb4373b5828f486290c9ebcd91e88a8a:0">Therefore, Keli shall adopts the message syntax from Smalltalk.</span></span></span></p><h2 id="2-not-intellisense-friendly" data-key="72733da2d0a749b7ba9e498913a7964a"><p><span><span data-key="a7eaddbb57b84cbbbe61d1f9bdf0bd20"><span data-offset-key="a7eaddbb57b84cbbbe61d1f9bdf0bd20:0">2. Not Intellisense friendly</span></span></span><a href="#2-not-intellisense-friendly" contenteditable="false"><span><svg preserveAspectRatio="xMidYMid meet" height="1em" width="1em" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke="currentColor"><g><path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71"></path><path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71"></path></g></svg></span></a></p></h2><p data-key="3faf2bfe243e460691e58f1aad5b86f3"><span><span data-key="5b7932b0caac483c8203df2cceef48ba"><span data-offset-key="5b7932b0caac483c8203df2cceef48ba:0">The other problem of FP languages is that they are not Intellisense friendly, in another word, they don't integrate well with integrated development environment (IDE). </span></span></span></p><p data-key="9a967c53a5ca4c059ca5cf5fc32dbaca"><span><span data-key="d94b1c8b93db47c98a5cad80f0812464"><span data-offset-key="d94b1c8b93db47c98a5cad80f0812464:0">This is also due to their prefix function invocation nature, which does not allow Intellisense to provide good code completions suggestion. The best they can do is to provide some low-level Intellisense such as:</span></span></span></p><ul data-key="c4475599ccfb4b9a87112ee7652c8158"><li><p data-key="5af8c436307d4dc1ae16e662d4403696"><span><span data-key="283d8096008d4d9d91ca7964f4f19897"><span data-offset-key="283d8096008d4d9d91ca7964f4f19897:0">Naively suggesting variable or function names </span></span></span></p></li><li><p data-key="ef5e25045a014ebc94cb97b20558e286"><span><span data-key="a19f48a4741e44ee8f6671060dfe1940"><span data-offset-key="a19f48a4741e44ee8f6671060dfe1940:0">Suggesting function when typing out a module name</span></span></span></p></li></ul><p data-key="b87b7145461f41068920e5c326709168"><span><span data-key="4217fa8e7fa94686a73764b6a264622a"><span data-offset-key="4217fa8e7fa94686a73764b6a264622a:0">This kind of Intellisense are dwarfed when compared to those of OOP languages, which provide higher-level Intellisense, which is:</span></span></span></p><ul data-key="c9e62d55b6544266bcba1fc1994e7d37"><li><p data-key="9c11af111cac46ea924d902f0e44d239"><span><span data-key="42c30f325ad849d98df1cc3ef0edf2bc"><span data-offset-key="42c30f325ad849d98df1cc3ef0edf2bc:0">Suggesting related method based on type of the object</span></span></span></p></li></ul><div data-slate-void="true" data-key="7b1d87fd083947bf98a79c8695001eca"><div><figure data-key="7b1d87fd083947bf98a79c8695001eca" contenteditable="false"><div><p><img tabindex="0" src="https://gblobscdn.gitbook.com/assets%2F-LVJCs7dNBHSuAiiNeWI%2F-LVMN3Tzu7mlzhwZYNO2%2F-LVMT-n_UoBA86gA2Ob-%2Fintellisense.gif?alt=media&amp;token=0e616f08-ba15-4e90-91e9-c943b7a98a13" loading="lazy"></p></div><p><figcaption><span>Higher-level IntelliSense in action</span></figcaption></p></figure></div></div><p data-key="db7a0a3883f34262b7d239c0a89ab887"><span><span data-key="42cb0c28b23948718f51d9fd22359908"><span data-offset-key="42cb0c28b23948718f51d9fd22359908:0"><span data-slate-zero-width="n">​</span></span></span></span></p><h2 id="conclusion" data-key="e616bbbc45384e34a75638427c0fa586"><p><span><span data-key="54dbac6debdf4bd082c08bfe2ed74e9a"><span data-offset-key="54dbac6debdf4bd082c08bfe2ed74e9a:0">Conclusion</span></span></span><a href="#conclusion" contenteditable="false"><span><svg preserveAspectRatio="xMidYMid meet" height="1em" width="1em" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" stroke="currentColor"><g><path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71"></path><path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71"></path></g></svg></span></a></p></h2><p data-key="183833ba5ba1433fbab9474fb2f24967"><span><span data-key="74d72f18e9044536a0779ee161cf7cba"><span data-offset-key="74d72f18e9044536a0779ee161cf7cba:0">In a nutshell, Keli strives to fill the hole in the table below, which is to be a functional programming language that is IDE-friendly.</span></span></span></p><p data-key="a21a981c68984b78b5dd6f98bc865d6c"><span><span data-key="d733e8c659474fb0831e15020748a233"><span data-offset-key="d733e8c659474fb0831e15020748a233:0"><span data-slate-zero-width="n">​</span></span></span></span></p><p data-key="1d8c4a30542f49ed9c01d98ba9c4b9e2"><span><span data-key="f590b96cf30f4861b7c37bee5b2c3a3f"><span data-offset-key="f590b96cf30f4861b7c37bee5b2c3a3f:0"><span data-slate-zero-width="n">​</span></span></span></span></p></div></div></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://keli-language.gitbook.io/doc/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24331635</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 14:14:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How NASA and ISRO discovered water on the Moon]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 169 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24331408">thread link</a>) | @uncertainquark
<br/>
August 31, 2020 | https://jatan.space/how-nasa-and-chandrayaan-discovered-water-on-the-moon/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jatan.space/how-nasa-and-chandrayaan-discovered-water-on-the-moon/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
		
	<main id="content" role="main">

	<div>
		<div>
						<article id="post-1176">
				<div>
<p>After decades of work, scientists used Chandrayaan 1 and NASA’s LCROSS to finally discover water on the Moon in 2009. In the 10 years since, the next step has been to understand the exact nature of and the amount of water the Moon hosts. This is where NASA’s LRO and <a href="https://jatan.space/chandrayaan-2-is-creating-the-highest-resolution-map-of-the-moon/">ISRO’s Chandrayaan 2 orbiter</a> come in.</p>



<p>For most of the 20th century, scientists argued the Moon’s surface was bone-dry. The 382 kg of rock and soil samples the Apollo missions brought from the Moon to Earth attested to this. When they did find traces of water in the samples, scientists dismissed them as contamination. The Moon has a very thin atmosphere, so any water on its surface is exposed directly to the vacuum of space, and evaporates. And due to the Moon’s low gravity, water vapor quickly escapes into space.</p>



<p>However, there are certain regions on the Moon that haven’t received sunlight for more than a billion years, and where scientists think the water can be. On the lunar poles, the Sun is very close to the local horizon throughout the day so even a small feature, like a rock, can cast very long shadows. Likewise, large craters with terraced edges can easily block sunlight from entering the crater, so sunlight is blocked a full 360°. Such places are eternally dark and are called permanently shadowed regions (PSRs).</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/jatan.space/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/11556-psrs-nasa-lro.gif?resize=600%2C338&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="600" height="338" data-recalc-dims="1"><figcaption>Permanently shadowed regions on the lunar south pole, highlighted in blue. <a href="https://svs.gsfc.nasa.gov/4043">Credit: NASA LRO</a></figcaption></figure></div>



<p>But where could the water have come from?</p>



<p>Scientists know that comets and many types of asteroids contain water. For most of the Solar System’s existence, these objects have been bombarding planets and their moons at a vigorous pace. This is why the Moon is covered in craters, and scientists think the asteroids and comets responsible for them could have deposited water on the Moon. They have proposed that some fraction of this water could have found its way into PSRs, where – like sitting inside a refrigerator – they could’ve been preserved for billions of years.</p>



<p>In 1994, NASA launched the Clementine lunar orbiter. Its <a href="https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1994-004A-09">Bistatic Radar Experiment</a> beamed radio signals straight into the PSRs. The signals bounced off the PSRs and were received by ground stations on Earth. Scientists found the nature of the reflected signals to be consistent with water ice, although they couldn’t be 100% sure.</p>



<p>NASA sent another orbiter in 1998, called the Lunar Prospector, to find out if there was water ice in the PSRs. Its neutron spectrometer found that the number of neutrons in the soil corresponded with the <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/vision/universe/solarsystem/14apr_moonwater.html">presence of hydrogen atoms</a>. Could these hydrogen atoms be part of water molecules?</p>



<p>Armed with Clementine and Lunar Prospector data, scientists were almost certain that there was water on the Moon, but they needed to be absolutely sure.</p>



<h3>Water on the Moon indeed</h3>



<p>In 2008, India forayed into planetary exploration with the Chandrayaan 1 lunar orbiter, for which ISRO <a href="https://www.lpi.usra.edu/meetings/lpsc2006/pdf/1704.pdf">solicited instruments</a> from scientists around the world. NASA pitched and built two of these, named MiniSAR and M3.</p>



<p>The Miniature Synthetic Aperture Radar (Mini-SAR) <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/Mini-RF/multimedia/feature_ice_like_deposits.html">also found</a> that the PSRs reflected signals in patterns consistent with water ice, from more than 40 polar craters. But just like with Clementine, the data wasn’t 100% certain.</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" width="1200" height="1204" src="https://i0.wp.com/jatan.space/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/c2356-mini-sar-finds-water-ice.jpg?resize=1200%2C1204&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-recalc-dims="1"><figcaption>Likely water ice on the Moon’s north pole (marked by green circles) found by Chandrayaan 1 instrument Mini-SAR. <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/Mini-RF/multimedia/feature_ice_like_deposits.html">Credit: NASA</a></figcaption></figure></div>



<p>The Moon Mineralogical Mapper (M3), an infrared spectrometer, would go on to clinch the prize. M3 detected not just water in the PSRs but <a href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/news.php?feature=7218">could also differentiate between ice, liquid water and water vapor</a> based on how the surface absorbed infrared light. M3 confirmed that the Moon hosted water once and for all.</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="1200" height="675" src="https://i0.wp.com/jatan.space/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/3cc0f-water-ice-moon-map-m3.jpg?resize=1200%2C675&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-recalc-dims="1"><figcaption>Distribution of water ice on the lunar poles mapped by Chandrayaan 1 instrument M3. <a href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/news.php?feature=7218">Credit: NASA</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>The Chandrayaan 1 orbiter also carried an impact probe – a craft that intentionally crashed near a PSR on the Moon’s south pole. As it descended, its mass spectrometer instrument <a href="http://www.planetary.org/blogs/emily-lakdawalla/2010/2430.html">detected water molecules</a> in the thin but persistent lunar atmosphere.</p>



<p>However, ISRO didn’t publish the results until NASA announced that Mini-SAR and M3 had discovered lunar water. ISRO then <a href="https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/MIP-detected-water-on-Moon-way-back-in-June-ISRO-Chairman/article16883362.ece">claimed</a> that their instrument had detected water on the Moon first.</p>



<h3>Not that dry</h3>



<p>All this time, scientists had been developing ideas about how the Moon could have water on other parts as well, not just at or near the poles. The Sun emits a constant stream of protons, some of which strike the Moon. Most of these protons are reflected into space but some are absorbed. Scientists thought the oxygen in the soil could interact with the absorbed protons to produce water, and that they should be able to detect the water molecules from orbit.</p>



<p>NASA’s Cassini spacecraft flew by the Moon in 1999, en route to Saturn. Its infrared spectrometer <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/topics/moonmars/features/clark1.html">found water-bearing minerals</a> at most latitudes on the Moon, with a higher concentration at the poles.</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/jatan.space/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/b0d3d-cassini-moon-water.jpg?resize=392%2C295&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="392" height="295" data-recalc-dims="1"><figcaption>Detection of water-bearing and hydroxyl-bearing minerals on the Moon by Cassini’s infrared spectrometer. <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/topics/moonmars/features/clark1.html">Credit: NASA</a></figcaption></figure></div>



<p>The results were in stark contrast to the bone-dry Apollo samples. One reason could be that most Apollo landing sites were near the equator, so high daytime temperatures at these sites might have evaporated the water. However, they didn’t publish the findings for a decade, until Chandrayaan 1 happened.</p>



<p>The European Space Agency’s instrument onboard Chandrayaan 1, SARA, analyzed protons reflected by the lunar surface. Like Cassini, SARA <a href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2009/10/091015091605.htm">found water/hydroxyl groups</a> in the lunar soil. The discovery proved timely for ESA’s BepiColombo mission to study Mercury, which carries two similar instruments for detecting water. Chandrayaan 1’s M3 detected water and hydroxyl molecules almost everywhere on the Moon too.</p>



<p>In addition to water ice in the PSRs and water molecules in the lunar soil, M3 found a third water source, which came as a surprise. M3 had imaged the Bullialdus crater, one of the many large craters that boast central mountains. These mountains contain material excavated from deep within the Moon’s crust.</p>







<p>M3 <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130220235318/http://lunarscience.nasa.gov/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/38_Klima_NLSI_2012.pdf">found water-bearing minerals</a> in the central mountain but not in the area surrounding it. These traces of water provided informed scientists’ ideas about the Moon’s interior.</p>



<p>Scientists now knew that the lunar soil does hold trace amounts of water even in the non-polar regions. Note that it’s still less water than the driest deserts on Earth. However, the PSRs on the lunar poles host appreciably more water.</p>



<h3>LRO and Chandrayaan 2</h3>



<p>In 2009, NASA launched the Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter (LRO). It also <a href="https://svs.gsfc.nasa.gov/4043">detected water ice on the lunar poles</a> using both the onboard radar and the <a href="https://svs.gsfc.nasa.gov/4057">neutron spectrometer</a>. LRO has been orbiting the Moon for over 10 years now, longer than any other orbiter. The LRO team has published an extensive <a href="http://lroc.sese.asu.edu/psr">atlas of PSRs</a>, laying the groundwork for future exploration and settlement on the Moon.</p>



<p>Like Chandrayaan 1’s impact probe, LRO carried an impactor too, called LCROSS. In 2009, its upper stage deliberately impacted one of the PSRs on the lunar south pole. The other half of LCROSS followed and studied the plume of moondust the crash kicked up. It was found to <a href="https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2010Sci...330..463C/abstract">contain 155 kg of water</a>.</p>



<div>
<div>
<figure><img loading="lazy" width="1000" height="683" src="https://i1.wp.com/jatan.space/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/c25e5-lcross-impactor.jpeg?resize=1000%2C683&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-recalc-dims="1"><figcaption>Artist’s rendering of LCROSS observing its upper stage en route to impact the Moon in 2009. <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/LCROSS/main/prelim_water_results.html">Credit: NASA</a></figcaption></figure>
</div>



<div>
<figure><img loading="lazy" width="529" height="378" src="https://i0.wp.com/jatan.space/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/03d58-lcross_results.jpg?resize=529%2C378&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-recalc-dims="1"><figcaption>Right: LCROSS camera showing the ejected plume post-impact, which included water. <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/LCROSS/main/prelim_water_results.html">Credit: NASA</a></figcaption></figure>




</div>
</div>



<p>From this result, scientists estimated all the PSRs together contained <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/Mini-RF/multimedia/feature_ice_like_deposits.html">more than 600 billion kg</a> of water ice, equivalent to at least 240,000 Olympic-sized swimming pools.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://jatan.space/chandrayaan-2-is-creating-the-highest-resolution-map-of-the-moon/">Chandrayaan 2 orbiter</a>’s instruments intend to extend our knowledge of water on the Moon. They include an enhanced infrared spectrometer and an upgraded radar, called the DFSAR.</p>



<p>The infrared spectrometer will build a global, high-resolution map of water concentrations in the lunar soil and determine which water-bearing minerals are present. Chandrayaan 2’s long-term observations aim to discern how the water content in the lunar soil changes in response to the lunar environment.</p>



<p>The DFSAR will map the water ice in the PSRs. With twice as much penetration depth and higher resolution, DFSAR will quantify the amount of water trapped in these cold regions, something no one has adequately done yet.</p>



<h3>What’s next?</h3>



<p>The lunar science and exploration communities agree that we can harness water ice on the Moon for future lunar habitats. Using solar power generated by the habitats, we can also split the water ice into hydrogen and oxygen for use as rocket fuel. To that end, Blue Origin, the spaceflight company owned by Jeff Bezos, has <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/press-release/nasa-announces-new-tipping-point-partnerships-for-moon-and-mars-technologies">snagged a $10 million NASA contract</a> for their lunar lander.</p>



<p>But before we plan habitats at the Moon’s poles, we need to know more about the nature of water ice in these regions. The LRO and the Chandrayaan 2 orbiters are expected to fill these gaps.</p>



<p>ISRO has stated that Chandrayaan 2 will orbit the Moon for seven years and that should be ample time to fully map and quantify water on the lunar surface. However, let’s not forget that Chandrayaan 1 had a design life of two years but failed after only 10 months.</p>



<p>Surface missions that explore PSRs, like NASA’s upcoming <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/new-viper-lunar-rover-to-map-water-ice-on-the-moon">VIPER</a> rover, are the next logical step towards sustainable habitats on the Moon. As we develop technologies that tap into water ice, we can <a href="https://jatan.space/the-moon-as-a-rocket-platform/">settle on not just the Moon but the whole solar system</a>. We should be glad our nearest neighbor has plenty of it; we can’t keep dragging everything out of Earth’s gravitational pull for eternity.</p>



<hr>



<p><em>Originally published at <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://thewire.in/the-sciences/isro-chandrayaan-2-water-moon-dfsar-class-lcross" target="_blank">The Wire</a>.</em></p>

</div>

			</article>
					</div>
	</div>
</main><!--/.neve-main-->




</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jatan.space/how-nasa-and-chandrayaan-discovered-water-on-the-moon/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24331408</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 13:49:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Common Mistakes to Avoid in HTML]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 63 | Comments 75 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24330110">thread link</a>) | @iamshadmirza
<br/>
August 31, 2020 | https://iamshadmirza.com/5-common-mistakes-to-avoid-in-html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://iamshadmirza.com/5-common-mistakes-to-avoid-in-html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section itemprop="articleBody mainEntityOfPage"><meta itemprop="thumbnailUrl image" content="https://cdn.hashnode.com/res/hashnode/image/upload/v1598809849449/ouCF-w_TZ.png?w=1600&amp;h=840&amp;fit=crop&amp;crop=entropy&amp;auto=format&amp;q=60"><div><div itemprop="text"><p>Hello, amazing people. This article will cover few of the common mistakes that we often do while writing HTML. Let's get straight to it.</p>
<h2 id="1-use-of-anchor-elements-lessagreater">1. Use of Anchor Elements: <code>&lt;a&gt;</code></h2>
<p>Anchor elements are used to create a hyperlink to a file or a location of a webpage and should always be used for navigating to a real url. Anchor elements are often misused as fake buttons by setting their <code>href</code> to <code>#</code> to prevent the page from refreshing, then listening for their <code>click</code> events.</p>
<p>When we point <code>href</code> value to <code>#</code>, it breaks the default functionality of a link causing unexpected behavior when opening links in a new tab or window, bookmarking, copying/dragging links, or when JavaScript is loading, errors, or is disabled. They also convey
incorrect semantics to assistive technologies, like screen readers.</p>
<p>If something is supposed to be clickable, it should always be a <code>&lt;button&gt;</code></p>
<p>Using here to add a link is not recommended as it doesn't tell anything about where it's going to navigate. Provide some proper text of where the links point to.</p>
<p>Example:</p>
<p>Read more about anchor tag <a target="_blank" href="https://www.w3schools.com/tags/tag_a.asp">here</a> ❌</p>
<p>Read more about anchor tag on <a target="_blank" href="https://www.w3schools.com/tags/tag_a.asp">w3school guide</a> ✅</p>
<h2 id="2-use-of-break-element-lessbrgreater">2. Use of Break element: <code>&lt;br&gt;</code></h2>
<p><code>&lt;br&gt;</code> element is used to break the text in an address or while writing poems specifically. Creating separate paragraphs of text using <code>&lt;br&gt;</code> is not only bad practice, but it is also problematic for people who navigate with the aid of screen reading technology. Screen readers can miss the content between two break elements while still announcing the presence of the tag. This can be frustrating for a person using a screen reader.</p>
<p>Use CSS <code>margin</code> property with <code>&lt;p&gt;</code> element to add space instead.</p>
<h2 id="3-use-of-heading-elements-lessh1greater">3. Use of Heading elements: <code>&lt;h1&gt;</code></h2>
<ul>
<li>HTML is a semantic language and anything regarding visuals should be done with CSS only. Avoid using heading tags to resize text. Instead, use the CSS <code>font-size</code> property. Headings use size to indicate their relative importance, but CSS is preferred for general-purpose resizing.</li>
<li>Avoid skipping heading levels: always start from <code>&lt;h1&gt;</code>, next use <code>&lt;h2&gt;</code>, and so on.</li>
<li>You should only use one <code>&lt;h1&gt;</code> per page.</li>
</ul>
<p>This is wrong:</p>
<pre><code><span>&lt;<span>h1</span>&gt;</span>Heading level 1<span>&lt;/<span>h1</span>&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;<span>h3</span>&gt;</span>Heading level 3<span>&lt;/<span>h3</span>&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;<span>h4</span>&gt;</span>Heading level 4<span>&lt;/<span>h4</span>&gt;</span>
</code></pre>
<p>This is appropriate:</p>
<pre><code><span>&lt;<span>h1</span>&gt;</span>Heading level 1<span>&lt;/<span>h1</span>&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;<span>h2</span>&gt;</span>Heading level 2<span>&lt;/<span>h2</span>&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;<span>h3</span>&gt;</span>Heading level 3<span>&lt;/<span>h3</span>&gt;</span>
</code></pre>
<h2 id="4-use-of-paragraph-lesspgreater">4. Use of Paragraph: <code>&lt;p&gt;</code></h2>
<p>Do not use empty <code>&lt;p&gt;</code> elements to add space between
paragraphs and it is problematic for people who navigate with screen-reading
technology. Screen readers may announce the paragraph's presence, but
not any content contained within it — because there is none.</p>
<p>If extra space is desired, use CSS properties like <code>margin</code> to create the effect.</p>
<h2 id="5-use-of-aside-lessasidegreater">5. Use of Aside: <code>&lt;aside&gt;</code></h2>
<p>Aside was introduced with HTML5 and represents content that is not directly connected with the main content. Asides are stand-alone, non-essential as part of an article but when used correctly it can be an extra level of information for your content. Example sidebars or call-out boxes.</p>
<p>Do not use aside to tag the parenthesized test as that is part of the main content. Don’t try to force content into an <code>&lt;aside&gt;</code> if it shouldn't be there.</p>
<p>Example:</p>
<pre><code><span>&lt;<span>p</span>&gt;</span>My family and I visited The Epcot center this summer. The weather was nice, and Epcot was amazing! I had a great summer together with my family!<span>&lt;/<span>p</span>&gt;</span>

<span>&lt;<span>aside</span>&gt;</span>
    <span>&lt;<span>h4</span>&gt;</span>Epcot Center<span>&lt;/<span>h4</span>&gt;</span>
    <span>&lt;<span>p</span>&gt;</span>Epcot is a theme park at Walt Disney World Resort featuring exciting attractions, international pavilions, award-winning fireworks and seasonal special events.<span>&lt;/<span>p</span>&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;/<span>aside</span>&gt;</span>
</code></pre>
<p>Writing semantically correct HTML is the responsibility of every developer. I hope you learned something from this article. That's it for now. Take care and stay safe.<br><a target="_blank" href="https://www.twitter.com/iamshadmirza">Shad</a></p>
<h2 id="resources">Resources</h2>
<ul>
<li><a target="_blank" href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML">MDN Documentation</a></li>
<li><a target="_blank" href="https://www.w3schools.com/html/">W3School Documentation</a></li>
</ul>
<p><em>Illustration on the cover is courtesy of <a target="_blank" href="https://undraw.co/">unDraw</a></em></p>
</div></div></section></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://iamshadmirza.com/5-common-mistakes-to-avoid-in-html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24330110</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 10:51:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Visualizing TSNE Maps with Three.js]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 54 | Comments 15 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24328626">thread link</a>) | @polm23
<br/>
August 30, 2020 | https://douglasduhaime.com/posts/visualizing-tsne-maps-with-three-js.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://douglasduhaime.com/posts/visualizing-tsne-maps-with-three-js.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>For the last year or so, Yale’s DHLab has undertaken a series of experiments organized around analysis of visual culture. Some of those experiments have involved <a href="https://douglasduhaime.com/posts/identifying-similar-images-with-tensorflow.html">identifying similar images</a> and visualizing patterns uncovered in this process. In this post, I wanted to discuss how we used the amazing Three.js library to build a WebGL-powered <a href="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/lab-apps/pix-plot/index.html">visualization</a> that can display tens of thousands of images in an interactive 3D environment [click to enter]:</p>

<p><a href="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/lab-apps/pix-plot/index.html">
  <img src="https://douglasduhaime.com/assets/posts/tsne-webgl/images/tsne-webgl-preview.jpg" alt="A preview of the WebGL-powered TSNE maps we will build below">
</a></p>

<p>If you’re interested in creating something similar, feel free to check out the <a href="https://github.com/YaleDHLab/pix-plot">full code</a>.</p>

<h2 id="getting-started-with-threejs">Getting Started with Three.js</h2>

<p>Three.js is a JavaScript library that generates lower-level code for WebGL, the standard API for 3D rendering in a web browser. Using Three.js, one can build complex 3D environments that would take much more code to build in raw WebGL. For a quick sample of the projects others have built with the library, check out the <a href="https://threejs.org/">Three.js homepage</a>.</p>

<p>To get started with Three.js, one needs to provide a bit of boilerplate code with the three essential elements of a Three.js page:</p>

<p><strong>scene</strong>: The scene contains all objects to be rendered:</p>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="javascript"><span>// Create the scene and a camera to view it</span>
<span>var</span> <span>scene</span> <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>THREE</span><span>.</span><span>Scene</span><span>();</span></code></pre></figure>

<p><strong>camera</strong>: The camera determines the position from which viewers see the scene:</p>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="javascript"><span>// Specify the portion of the scene visiable at any time (in degrees)</span>
<span>var</span> <span>fieldOfView</span> <span>=</span> <span>75</span><span>;</span>

<span>// Specify the camera's aspect ratio</span>
<span>var</span> <span>aspectRatio</span> <span>=</span> <span>window</span><span>.</span><span>innerWidth</span> <span>/</span> <span>window</span><span>.</span><span>innerHeight</span><span>;</span>

<span>// Specify the near and far clipping planes. Only objects</span>
<span>// between those planes will be rendered in the scene</span>
<span>// (these values help control the number of items rendered</span>
<span>// at any given time)</span>
<span>var</span> <span>nearPlane</span> <span>=</span> <span>0.1</span><span>;</span>
<span>var</span> <span>farPlane</span> <span>=</span> <span>1000</span><span>;</span>

<span>// Use the values specified above to create a camera</span>
<span>var</span> <span>camera</span> <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>THREE</span><span>.</span><span>PerspectiveCamera</span><span>(</span>
  <span>fieldOfView</span><span>,</span> <span>aspectRatio</span><span>,</span> <span>nearPlane</span><span>,</span> <span>farPlane</span>
<span>);</span>

<span>// Finally, set the camera's position in the z-dimension</span>
<span>camera</span><span>.</span><span>position</span><span>.</span><span>z</span> <span>=</span> <span>5</span><span>;</span></code></pre></figure>

<p><strong>renderer</strong>: The renderer renders the scene to a canvas element on an HTML page:</p>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="javascript"><span>// Create the canvas with a renderer and tell the</span>
<span>// renderer to clean up jagged aliased lines</span>
<span>var</span> <span>renderer</span> <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>THREE</span><span>.</span><span>WebGLRenderer</span><span>({</span><span>antialias</span><span>:</span> <span>true</span><span>});</span>

<span>// Specify the size of the canvas</span>
<span>renderer</span><span>.</span><span>setSize</span><span>(</span> <span>window</span><span>.</span><span>innerWidth</span><span>,</span> <span>window</span><span>.</span><span>innerHeight</span> <span>);</span>

<span>// Add the canvas to the DOM</span>
<span>document</span><span>.</span><span>body</span><span>.</span><span>appendChild</span><span>(</span> <span>renderer</span><span>.</span><span>domElement</span> <span>);</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>The code above creates the scene, adds a camera, and renders the canvas to the DOM. Now all we need to do is add some objects to the scene.</p>

<p>Each item rendered in a Three.js scene has a <strong>geometry</strong> and a <strong>material</strong>. Geometries use vertices (points) and faces (polygons described by vertices) to define the shape of an object, and materials use textures and colors to define the appearance of that shape. A geometry and a material can be combined into a <strong>mesh</strong>, which is a fully composed object ready to be added to a scene.</p>

<p>The example below uses the high-level <a href="https://threejs.org/docs/#api/geometries/BoxGeometry">BoxGeometry</a>, which comes with pre-built vertices and faces:</p>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="javascript"><span>// Create a cube with width, height, and depth set to 1</span>
<span>var</span> <span>geometry</span> <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>THREE</span><span>.</span><span>BoxGeometry</span><span>(</span> <span>1</span><span>,</span> <span>1</span><span>,</span> <span>1</span> <span>);</span>

<span>// Use a simple material with a specified hex color</span>
<span>var</span> <span>material</span> <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>THREE</span><span>.</span><span>MeshBasicMaterial</span><span>({</span> <span>color</span><span>:</span> <span>0xffff00</span> <span>});</span>

<span>// Combine the geometry and material into a mesh</span>
<span>var</span> <span>cube</span> <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>THREE</span><span>.</span><span>Mesh</span><span>(</span> <span>geometry</span><span>,</span> <span>material</span> <span>);</span>

<span>// Add the mesh to the scene</span>
<span>scene</span><span>.</span><span>add</span><span>(</span> <span>cube</span> <span>);</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Finally, to render the scene on the page, one must call the <code>render()</code> method, passing in the scene and the camera as arguments:</p>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="javascript"><span>renderer</span><span>.</span><span>render</span><span>(</span> <span>scene</span><span>,</span> <span>camera</span> <span>);</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Combining the snippets above gives the following result:</p>

<p data-height="265" data-theme-id="0" data-slug-hash="WXdYpx" data-default-tab="result" data-user="duhaime" data-embed-version="2" data-pen-title="The Simplest Three.js Scene">See the Pen <a href="https://codepen.io/duhaime/pen/WXdYpx/">The Simplest Three.js Scene</a> by Douglas Duhaime (<a href="https://codepen.io/duhaime">@duhaime</a>) on <a href="https://codepen.io/">CodePen</a>.</p>

<p>This is great, but the scene is static. To add some <strong>animation</strong> to the scene, one can periodically update the cube’s rotation property, then rerender the scene. To do so, one can replace the <code>renderer.render()</code> line above with a render loop that calls itself recursively. Here is a standard render loop in Three.js:</p>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="javascript"><span>function</span> <span>animate</span><span>()</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>requestAnimationFrame</span><span>(</span> <span>animate</span> <span>);</span>
  <span>renderer</span><span>.</span><span>render</span><span>(</span> <span>scene</span><span>,</span> <span>camera</span> <span>);</span>

  <span>// Rotate the object a bit each animation frame</span>
  <span>cube</span><span>.</span><span>rotation</span><span>.</span><span>y</span> <span>+=</span> <span>0.01</span><span>;</span>
  <span>cube</span><span>.</span><span>rotation</span><span>.</span><span>z</span> <span>+=</span> <span>0.01</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
<span>animate</span><span>();</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Adding this block at the bottom of the script makes the cube slowly rotate:</p>

<p data-height="265" data-theme-id="0" data-slug-hash="vWpvNL" data-default-tab="result" data-user="duhaime" data-embed-version="2" data-pen-title="Animating the Cube">See the Pen <a href="https://codepen.io/duhaime/pen/vWpvNL/">Animating the Cube</a> by Douglas Duhaime (<a href="https://codepen.io/duhaime">@duhaime</a>) on <a href="https://codepen.io/">CodePen</a>.</p>

<p>Adding <strong>lights</strong> to the scene can make it easier to differentiate the faces of the cube. To add lights to the scene above, we’ll first want to change the cube’s material, because as the documentation says the <a href="https://threejs.org/docs/#api/materials/MeshBasicMaterial">MeshBasicMaterial</a> is not affected by lights. Let’s replace the material defined above with a <a href="https://threejs.org/docs/#api/materials/MeshPhongMaterial">MeshPhongMaterial</a>:</p>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="javascript"><span>var</span> <span>material</span> <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>THREE</span><span>.</span><span>MeshPhongMaterial</span><span>({</span><span>color</span><span>:</span> <span>0xffff00</span><span>})</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Next let’s point a light at the cube so that different faces of the cube catch different amounts of light:</p>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="javascript"><span>// Add a point light with #fff color, .7 intensity, and 0 distance</span>
<span>var</span> <span>light</span> <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>THREE</span><span>.</span><span>PointLight</span><span>(</span><span>0xffffff</span><span>,</span> <span>.</span><span>7</span><span>,</span> <span>0</span><span>);</span>

<span>// Specify the light's position in the x, y, and z dimensions</span>
<span>light</span><span>.</span><span>position</span><span>.</span><span>set</span><span>(</span><span>1</span><span>,</span> <span>1</span><span>,</span> <span>100</span><span>);</span>

<span>// Add the light to the scene</span>
<span>scene</span><span>.</span><span>add</span><span>(</span><span>light</span><span>)</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Voila!</p>

<p data-height="265" data-theme-id="0" data-slug-hash="mqparr" data-default-tab="result" data-user="duhaime" data-embed-version="2" data-pen-title="Lighting the Cube">See the Pen <a href="https://codepen.io/duhaime/pen/mqparr/">Lighting the Cube</a> by Douglas Duhaime (<a href="https://codepen.io/duhaime">@duhaime</a>) on <a href="https://codepen.io/">CodePen</a>.</p>

<h2 id="adding-images-to-a-scene">Adding Images to a Scene</h2>

<p>The snippets above give a quick overview of the core elements of a Three.js scene. The following section will build upon those ideas to create a TSNE map of images.</p>

<p>To build an image viewer, we’ll need to load some image files into some Three.js materials. We can do so by using the <a href="https://threejs.org/docs/#api/loaders/TextureLoader">TextureLoader</a>:</p>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="javascript"><span>// Create a texture loader so we can load the image file</span>
<span>var</span> <span>loader</span> <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>THREE</span><span>.</span><span>TextureLoader</span><span>();</span>

<span>// Specify the path to an image</span>
<span>var</span> <span>url</span> <span>=</span> <span>'https://s3.amazonaws.com/duhaime/blog/tsne-webgl/assets/cat.jpg'</span><span>;</span>

<span>// Load an image file into a MeshLambert material</span>
<span>var</span> <span>material</span> <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>THREE</span><span>.</span><span>MeshLambertMaterial</span><span>({</span>
  <span>map</span><span>:</span> <span>loader</span><span>.</span><span>load</span><span>(</span><span>url</span><span>)</span>
<span>});</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Now that the material is ready, the remaining steps are to generate a geometry from the image, combine the material and geoemtry into a mesh, and add the mesh to the scene, just like the cube example above. Because images are two-dimensional planes, we can use a simple <a href="https://threejs.org/docs/#api/geometries/PlaneGeometry">PlaneGeometry</a> for this object’s geometry:</p>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="javascript"><span>// create a plane geometry for the image with a width of 10</span>
<span>// and a height that preserves the image's aspect ratio</span>
<span>var</span> <span>geometry</span> <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>THREE</span><span>.</span><span>PlaneGeometry</span><span>(</span><span>10</span><span>,</span> <span>10</span><span>*</span><span>.</span><span>75</span><span>);</span>

<span>// combine the image geometry and material into a mesh</span>
<span>var</span> <span>mesh</span> <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>THREE</span><span>.</span><span>Mesh</span><span>(</span><span>geometry</span><span>,</span> <span>material</span><span>);</span>

<span>// set the position of the image mesh in the x,y,z dimensions</span>
<span>mesh</span><span>.</span><span>position</span><span>.</span><span>set</span><span>(</span><span>0</span><span>,</span><span>0</span><span>,</span><span>0</span><span>)</span>

<span>// add the image to the scene</span>
<span>scene</span><span>.</span><span>add</span><span>(</span><span>mesh</span><span>);</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>The image will now appear in the scene:</p>

<p data-height="265" data-theme-id="0" data-slug-hash="jaYdLg" data-default-tab="result" data-user="duhaime" data-embed-version="2" data-pen-title="Adding an Image to a Three.js Scene">See the Pen <a href="https://codepen.io/duhaime/pen/jaYdLg/">Adding an Image to a Three.js Scene</a> by Douglas Duhaime (<a href="https://codepen.io/duhaime">@duhaime</a>) on <a href="https://codepen.io/">CodePen</a>.</p>

<p>It’s worth noting that one can swap out the PlanarGeometry for other geometries and Three.js will automatically wrap the material over the new geometry. The example below, for instance, swaps the PlanarGeometry for a more interesting Icosahedron geometry, and rotates the icosahedron inside the render loop:</p>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="javascript"><span>// use an icosahedron geometry instead of the planar geometry</span>
<span>var</span> <span>geometry</span> <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>THREE</span><span>.</span><span>IcosahedronGeometry</span><span>();</span>

<span>// spin the icosahedron each animation frame</span>
<span>function</span> <span>animate</span><span>()</span> <span>{</span>
<span>requestAnimationFrame</span><span>(</span> <span>animate</span> <span>);</span>
  <span>renderer</span><span>.</span><span>render</span><span>(</span> <span>scene</span><span>,</span> <span>camera</span> <span>);</span>
  <span>mesh</span><span>.</span><span>rotation</span><span>.</span><span>x</span> <span>+=</span> <span>0.01</span><span>;</span>
  <span>mesh</span><span>.</span><span>rotation</span><span>.</span><span>y</span> <span>+=</span> <span>0.01</span><span>;</span>
  <span>mesh</span><span>.</span><span>rotation</span><span>.</span><span>z</span> <span>+=</span> <span>0.01</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
<span>animate</span><span>();</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>This produces a strange looking cat indeed:</p>

<p data-height="265" data-theme-id="0" data-slug-hash="NwXeoB" data-default-tab="result" data-user="duhaime" data-embed-version="2" data-pen-title="Icosahedron Cat">See the Pen <a href="https://codepen.io/duhaime/pen/NwXeoB/">Icosahedron Cat</a> by Douglas Duhaime (<a href="https://codepen.io/duhaime">@duhaime</a>) on <a href="https://codepen.io/">CodePen</a>.</p>

<h2 id="building-custom-geometries">Building Custom Geometries</h2>

<p>The examples above use a few different geometries built into Three.js. Those geometries are based on the fundamental <a href="https://threejs.org/docs/#api/core/Geometry">THREE.Geometry</a> class, which is a primitive geometry one can use to create custom geometries. THREE.Geometry is lower-level than the prebuilt geometries used above, but it gives performance gains that make it worth the effort.</p>

<p>Let’s create a custom geometry by calling the THREE.Geometry constructor, which takes no arguments:</p>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="javascript"><span>var</span> <span>geometry</span> <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>THREE</span><span>.</span><span>Geometry</span><span>();</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>This geometry object doesn’t do much yet, because it doesn’t have any vertices with which to ariculate a shape. Let’s add four vertices to the geometry, one for each corner of the image. Each vertex takes three arguments, which define the vertex’s x, y, and z positions respectively:</p>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="javascript"><span>// identify the image width and height</span>
<span>var</span> <span>imageSize</span> <span>=</span> <span>{</span><span>width</span><span>:</span> <span>10</span><span>,</span> <span>height</span><span>:</span> <span>7.5</span><span>};</span>

<span>// identify the x, y, z coords where the image should be placed</span>
<span>// inside the scene</span>
<span>var</span> <span>coords</span> <span>=</span> <span>{</span><span>x</span><span>:</span> <span>-</span><span>5</span><span>,</span> <span>y</span><span>:</span> <span>-</span><span>3.75</span><span>,</span> <span>z</span><span>:</span> <span>0</span><span>};</span>

<span>// add one vertex for each image corner in this order:</span>
<span>// lower left, lower right, upper right, upper left</span>
<span>geometry</span><span>.</span><span>vertices</span><span>.</span><span>push</span><span>(</span>
  <span>new</span> <span>THREE</span><span>.</span><span>Vector3</span><span>(</span>
    <span>coords</span><span>.</span><span>x</span><span>,</span>
    <span>coords</span><span>.</span><span>y</span><span>,</span>
    <span>coords</span><span>.</span><span>z</span>
  <span>),</span>
  <span>new</span> <span>THREE</span><span>.</span><span>Vector3</span><span>(</span>
    <span>coords</span><span>.</span><span>x</span><span>+</span><span>imageSize</span><span>.</span><span>width</span><span>,</span>
    <span>coords</span><span>.</span><span>y</span><span>,</span>
    <span>coords</span><span>.</span><span>z</span>
  <span>),</span>
  <span>new</span> <span>THREE</span><span>.</span><span>Vector3</span><span>(</span>
    <span>coords</span><span>.</span><span>x</span><span>+</span><span>imageSize</span><span>.</span><span>width</span><span>,</span>
    <span>coords</span><span>.</span><span>y</span><span>+</span><span>imageSize</span><span>.</span><span>height</span><span>,</span>
    <span>coords</span><span>.</span><span>z</span>
  <span>),</span>
  <span>new</span> <span>THREE</span><span>.</span><span>Vector3</span><span>(</span>
    <span>coords</span><span>.</span><span>x</span><span>,</span>
    <span>coords</span><span>.</span><span>y</span><span>+</span><span>imageSize</span><span>.</span><span>height</span><span>,</span>
    <span>coords</span><span>.</span><span>z</span>
  <span>)</span>
<span>);</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Now that the vertices are in place, we need to add some faces to the geometry. The code below will model an image as two triangle faces, as triangles are performant primitives in the WebGL world. The first triangle will combine the lower-left, lower-right, and upper-right vertices of the image, and the second will triangulate the lower-left, upper-right, and upper-left vertices of the image:</p>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="javascript"><span>// add the first face (the lower-right triangle)</span>
<span>var</span> <span>faceOne</span> <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>THREE</span><span>.</span><span>Face3</span><span>(</span>
  <span>geometry</span><span>.</span><span>vertices</span><span>.</span><span>length</span><span>-</span><span>4</span><span>,</span>
  <span>geometry</span><span>.</span><span>vertices</span><span>.</span><span>length</span><span>-</span><span>3</span><span>,</span>
  <span>geometry</span><span>.</span><span>vertices</span><span>.</span><span>length</span><span>-</span><span>2</span>
<span>)</span>

<span>// add the second face (the upper-left triangle)</span>
<span>var</span> <span>faceTwo</span> <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>THREE</span><span>.</span><span>Face3</span><span>(</span>
  <span>geometry</span><span>.</span><span>vertices</span><span>.</span><span>length</span><span>-</span><span>4</span><span>,</span>
  <span>geometry</span><span>.</span><span>vertices</span><span>.</span><span>length</span><span>-</span><span>2</span><span>,</span>
  <span>geometry</span><span>.</span><span>vertices</span><span>.</span><span>length</span><span>-</span><span>1</span>
<span>)</span>

<span>// add those faces to the geometry</span>
<span>geometry</span><span>.</span><span>faces</span><span>.</span><span>push</span><span>(</span><span>faceOne</span><span>,</span> <span>faceTwo</span><span>);</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Awesome, we now have a geometry with four vertices that describe the corners of the image, and two faces that describe the lower-right and upper-left-hand triangles of the image. The next step is to describe which portions of the cat image should appear in each of the faces of the geometry. To do so, one …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://douglasduhaime.com/posts/visualizing-tsne-maps-with-three-js.html">https://douglasduhaime.com/posts/visualizing-tsne-maps-with-three-js.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://douglasduhaime.com/posts/visualizing-tsne-maps-with-three-js.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24328626</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 04:58:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Sum Types in Julia and Rust]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 122 | Comments 64 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24328071">thread link</a>) | @xiaodai
<br/>
August 30, 2020 | https://andreaskroepelin.de/blog/sum_types/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://andreaskroepelin.de/blog/sum_types/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <p>As I have mentioned in other posts on this blog (and surely many would agree here), I strongly believe that a great start for designing a program is figuring out good representations for the real world problem one tries to solve, <em>i.e.</em> defining appropriate types.
One helpful technique for that is what one could call <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Julia/comments/ijln21/blog_sum_types_in_julia_and_rust/g3f1gtn/"><em>optionality</em></a> .<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>
Interestingly, it is expressed completely differently in different programming languages which I would like to briefly demonstrate in this article using Rust and Julia as examples.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Remark:</strong>
Julia and Rust are my favourite programming languages and they are particularly suited to demonstrate my point.
That should not stop you from reading if you use neither of these languages, though!
First, both have a rather intuitive syntax and the code shown here is really basic, so you should be able to follow along.
Second, you can probably substitute your inheritance-using language for Julia (<em>e.g.</em> Java) or your tagged-union-using language for Rust (<em>e.g.</em> Haskell).
Even if not, you might learn something anyway!</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="scenario">Scenario</h2>
<p>Suppose, you are creating an intergalactic game where players can inhabit three different star systems: Our sun (the <em>solarians</em>), the polar star (the <em>polarians</em>) and Alpha Centauri (the <em>centaurians</em>).
An obvious first step would be to define types for each of these three classes:</p>
<p>In Julia:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="julia"><span>struct</span> Solarian <span>end</span>
<span>struct</span> Polarian <span>end</span>
<span>struct</span> Centaurian <span>end</span>
</code></pre></div><p>and in Rust (I will stick to this order if not stated otherwise):</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>struct</span> <span>Solarian</span>;
<span>struct</span> <span>Polarian</span>;
<span>struct</span> <span>Centaurian</span>;
</code></pre></div><p>(You would add some fields to those structs, of course, but that’s not the point here.)</p>
<p>Now, let’s say you need to store the player value in another object like a game state:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="julia"><span>struct</span> GameState
    daytime<span>::</span><span>UInt</span>
    player<span>::???</span>
<span>end</span>
</code></pre></div><div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>struct</span> <span>GameState</span> {
    daytime: <span>u64</span>,
    player: <span>???</span>
}
</code></pre></div><p>What type would you use for <code>player</code> in each case?
And what about</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="julia"><span>function</span> homestar(player<span>::???</span>)<span>::</span>String
    <span>...</span>
<span>end</span>
</code></pre></div><div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>fn</span> <span>homestar</span>(player: <span>???</span>) -&gt; <span>String</span> {
    ...
}
</code></pre></div><p>These are the questions we’re here for.</p>
<h2 id="strategy-1-inheritance--subtyping">Strategy 1: Inheritance / subtyping</h2>
<h3 id="julia">Julia</h3>
<p>This is very straightforward in Julia.
Define</p>
<p>and make the structs from above subtypes of that:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="julia"><span>struct</span> Solarian <span>&lt;:</span> Player <span>end</span>
<span>struct</span> Polarian <span>&lt;:</span> Player <span>end</span>
<span>struct</span> Centaurian <span>&lt;:</span> Player <span>end</span>
</code></pre></div><p>Dynamic dispatch then allows you to write:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="julia">homestar(player<span>::</span>Solarian) <span>=</span> <span>"sun"</span>
homestar(player<span>::</span>Polarian) <span>=</span> <span>"polar star"</span>
homestar(player<span>::</span>Centaurian) <span>=</span> <span>"Alpha Centauri"</span>
homestar(player<span>::</span>Player) <span>=</span> <span>"unknown"</span> <span># or `error("Unknown player class")`</span>
</code></pre></div><h3 id="rust">Rust</h3>
<p>Rust does not have subtyping but you can define relations between types via <em>traits</em> (similar to interfaces in other languages).
So, we can try</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>trait</span> Player {
    <span>fn</span> <span>homestar</span>(<span>&amp;</span>self) -&gt; <span>String</span>;
}
</code></pre></div><p>and then</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>impl</span> Player <span>for</span> Solarian {
    <span>fn</span> <span>homestar</span>(<span>&amp;</span>self) -&gt; <span>String</span> {
        <span>String</span>::from(<span>"sun"</span>)
    }
}
</code></pre></div><p>But what about the <code>GameState</code> struct?
We can make use of <em>trait objects</em>, about which we only know that they implement a certain trait.
We especially don’t know the object’s size so we need to reference to it.
If you’re familiar with Rust, you know that this either means using a “normal” reference (<code>&amp;</code> or <code>&amp;mut</code>) and dealing with life time annotations (not my favourite, to be honest) or using a <code>Box</code>ed value.
If you’re not familiar with that, it doesn’t really matter here anyway.
<code>GameState</code> could look like this:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>struct</span> <span>GameState</span> {
    daytime: <span>u64</span>,
    player: <span>Box</span><span>&lt;</span>dyn Player<span>&gt;</span>
}
</code></pre></div><p>This works, but does restrict us in what we can do with the <code>Player</code> trait, as it needs to be <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/reference/items/traits.html#object-safety"><em>object safe</em></a>.
For example, greeting another player of an arbitrary class</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>trait</span> Player {
    <span>fn</span> <span>homestar</span>(<span>&amp;</span>self) -&gt; <span>String</span>;
    <span>fn</span> <span>greet</span><span>&lt;</span>T: <span>Player</span><span>&gt;</span>(<span>&amp;</span>self, other: <span>&amp;</span><span>T</span>);
}
</code></pre></div><p>would not work anymore.</p>
<p>This would be easy in Julia, though:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="julia">greet(self<span>::</span>Polarian, other<span>::</span>Player) <span>=</span> println(<span>"Hi!"</span>)
greet(self<span>::</span>Polarian, other<span>::</span>Solarian) <span>=</span> println(<span>"Your star doesn't even consist of three separate stars? Pathetic!"</span>)
</code></pre></div><h2 id="strategy-1b-constrained-generics">Strategy 1b: Constrained generics</h2>
<p>Both Julia and Rust offer defining generic types with type parameters.
Additionally, one can put constraints on those parameters.
This allows us to do a smiliar thing as in strategy 1 but without hiding the concrete player type in the <code>GameState</code> struct:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="julia"><span>abstract type</span> Player <span>end</span>
<span>struct</span> Solarian <span>&lt;:</span> Player <span>end</span>

<span>struct</span> GameState{P <span>&lt;:</span> Player}
    daytime<span>::</span><span>UInt</span>
    player<span>::</span>P
<span>end</span>
</code></pre></div><p>or</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>trait</span> Player { ... }
<span>struct</span> <span>Solarian</span>;
<span>impl</span> Player <span>for</span> Solarian { ... }

<span>struct</span> <span>GameState</span><span>&lt;</span>P: <span>Player</span><span>&gt;</span> {
    daytime: <span>u64</span>,
    player: <span>P</span>
}
</code></pre></div><p>This approach can be considered more performant in general, as the compiler can emit code for concrete types (<a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/book/ch10-01-syntax.html#performance-of-code-using-generics"><em>monomorphisation</em></a>) instead of carrying around a clumsy super type that keeps track of subtypes and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_method_table">virtual method tables</a>.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup></p>
<p>However, there is a major concern with this approach: <strong>abstraction leaking</strong>.
Users of the <code>GameState</code> struct now have to decide what concrete type to choose for the parameter <code>P</code>, very strictly so in Rust, not so much in Julia.
This can be okay, but often enough <code>GameState</code> is the right place to deal with that question and really should hide that detail.</p>
<p>So as a rule of thumb: Consider generics for this problem “deep down” in your code but don’t miss the abstraction level where it needs to be kept inside.</p>
<h2 id="strategy-2-enumerations">Strategy 2: Enumerations</h2>
<p>So far, the approaches were not really satisfying for Rust.
But enumerations come to the rescue!
Enumerations (or enums) are types that consist of a concrete and explicit list of possible values (so called <em>variants</em>).</p>
<h3 id="rust-1">Rust</h3>
<p>In Rust, those values can even have their own data which is perfect for our situation:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>enum</span> <span>PlayerClass</span> {
    Sol(Solarian),
    Pol(Polarian),
    Cent(Centaurian)
}

<span>struct</span> <span>GameState</span> {
    daytime: <span>u64</span>,
    player: <span>PlayerClass</span>
}

<span>impl</span> PlayerClass {
    <span>fn</span> <span>homestar</span>(<span>&amp;</span>self) -&gt; <span>String</span> {
        <span>use</span> PlayerClass::<span>*</span>;
        <span>match</span> self {
            Sol(_) <span>=&gt;</span> <span>String</span>::from(<span>"sun"</span>),
            ...
        }
    }

    <span>fn</span> <span>greet</span>(<span>&amp;</span>self, other: <span>&amp;</span><span>PlayerClass</span>) {
        <span>use</span> PlayerClass::<span>*</span>;
        <span>match</span> (self, other) {
            (Cent(_), Pol(_)) <span>=&gt;</span> println<span>!</span>(<span>"Hello, fellow three-star-systemer!"</span>),
            ...
        };
    }
}
</code></pre></div><p>This indeed solves all our previous problems and is hence the go-to pattern for this situation.</p>
<h3 id="julia-1">Julia</h3>
<p>Julia does technically have enums, but not really.</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="julia">@enum PlayerClass Sol Pol Cent
</code></pre></div><p>exists and it will give you a type <code>PlayerClass</code> with exactly these three possible values but enums are not a first class citizen.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup>
But that’s not even relevant for us, more importantly, enum variants in Julia are <em>not</em> able to carry additional data with them!
So all the information in the fields of the <code>Solarian</code>, <code>Polarian</code>, and <code>Centaurian</code> struct can not be build into the <code>PlayerClass</code> enum.
There is no way to sensibly implement</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="julia"><span>function</span> takedamage!(player<span>::</span>PlayerClass)
    <span>...</span>
<span>end</span>
</code></pre></div><p>whereas it is trivial in Rust:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>impl</span> PlayerClass {
    <span>fn</span> <span>takedamage</span>(<span>&amp;</span><span>mut</span> self) {
        <span>match</span> <span>&amp;</span><span>mut</span> self {
            PlayerClass::Sol(solarian) <span>=&gt;</span> solarian.health <span>-=</span> <span>42</span>,
            ...
        };
    }
}
</code></pre></div><p>assuming the struct <code>Solarian</code> has a field <code>health: u64</code>.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>You might have guessed it by now, but the general advice is:
<strong>Use subtyping in Julia and enums in Rust.</strong>
One caveat though: Enums can not be extended from the “outside”.
If you plan to let users of your library add new type variants, you will have to use some kind of trait approach.</p>
<p>If you are somewhat familiar with Rust or Julia then a large part of this article is probably very obvious to you.
“Of course I use subtyping, that’s what everybody <em>loves</em> Julia for!” or “Of course I use enums, they’re one of <em>the</em> key features of Rust!” you might say.</p>
<p>However, I find it quite surprising that these two – seemingly rather different – patterns can be used in the same situation.
If you are (without loss of generality) a Julia developer, being aware of the corresponding pattern in Rust might help you design appropriate types faster, should you ever get into that situation; and vice versa.</p>
<section role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
<p>In an earlier version I used the term <em>sum types</em> but as reddit user <code>u/Eigenspace</code> pointed out, that’s technically not correct.  They also suggested this new choice of words. <a href="#fnref:1" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
<p>Instances of type <code>Player</code> in Julia and of type <code>Box&lt;dyn Player&gt;</code> in Rust work quite similiarly, as far as I understand. <a href="#fnref:2" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote">
<p>It is quite interesting to look at <code>@macroexpand @enum Foo A B C</code> though, to see how enums “work” in Julia. <a href="#fnref:3" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>

        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://andreaskroepelin.de/blog/sum_types/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24328071</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 02:47:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why are there 5280 feet in a mile?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 300 | Comments 433 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24327740">thread link</a>) | @ahupp
<br/>
August 30, 2020 | https://petersmagnusson.org/2009/09/15/why-are-there-5280-feet-in-a-mile/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://petersmagnusson.org/2009/09/15/why-are-there-5280-feet-in-a-mile/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="post-393">

			
			
			<p>
				
				♦ <a href="https://petersmagnusson.org/2009/09/15/why-are-there-5280-feet-in-a-mile/" rel="bookmark" title="Why are there 5280 feet in a&nbsp;mile?">September 15, 2009</a>

									♦ <a href="https://petersmagnusson.org/2009/09/15/why-are-there-5280-feet-in-a-mile/#comments">10 Comments</a>							</p>

			<p>The original Roman mile was 1000 paces (<em>milia passuum</em>), or 5000 feet. The modern mile was defined as 5280 feet under Queen Elizabeth at the end of the 16th century in order to reconcile multiple discordant measurement systems already in wide use. In particular, it was convenient to make it an even multiple of the sides of an acre, which since early medieval times was a rectangle 660 feet long and 66 feet wide. 660 divides neatly into 5280, eight ways, allowing a square mile (640 acres or a “section”) to be conveniently quartered three times over: into quarter sections (160 acres), sixteenth sections (40 acres), and finally the 10 acre squares (660 by 660 feet) that remain at the base of all US land surveys to this day.</p>

<p><em>Background: Many years ago, I became curious as to why, exactly, there are 5280 feet in a mile. The explanations I found online at the time weren’t very convincing. At the time I tried to make some fixes to parts of the puzzle in Wikipedia, but they frequently rejected as OR (original research). Eventually I wrote this article, since revised and updated several times. Since then, my “version” of things will occasionally drift to the #1 spot on Google or Bing, or both, when answering the specific question “why are there 5280 feet in a mile”. More often some SEO-optimized version will slip ahead, though it seems this article is holding steady in the top 3 or 4 at least. So hopefully pretty much everybody who cares about the details will find this. If you have any comments or questions (or corrections), please add to the comment section, I do (eventually) read all comments.<br>
</em></p>
<p><em>I have yet to find an answer to the question that’s as thorough and complete as this one is. But I must caution that this article isn’t really up to academic standards and contains a non-trivial amount of speculation. Caveat Emptor, what follows is my theory of how the mile ended up with 5280 feet.</em></p>
<p>The conventional wisdom on this topic goes something like this: the mile was originally 5000 feet. It was changed to 5280 feet in Elizabethan times around the year 1600 (some point to 1592 and some to 1593) to accommodate the furlong, which was 660 feet. It was easier to fix the mile rather than the furlong for various reasons, hence, eight furlongs and 5280 feet in a mile.</p>
<p>That’s the standard story. It’ll be fleshed out with bells and whistles, including odd theories about horses etc, but that’s about it.</p>
<p>The problem with these versions is that they don’t explain why this collision between furlong and mile occurred around 1600, and not centuries before. It implies, therefore, that people suddenly woke up and realized, hey, wait a second, if there’s 660 feet in a furlong … and eight furlongs in a mile … but 5000 feet in a mile …. wait a second !?!</p>
<p>It somewhat implies that four-digit multiplication was invented ca 1600. Like a lot of rear-view-mirror takes on history, the “explanation” boils down to: “before time X people were stupid about topic Y, and at time Z they wizened up.”</p>
<p>Failing to find a good write-up of the origins, I’ve pieced together my own theory over the years. And it’s a fun one because the answer (or rather, hypothesis) is simply this: the number 5280 arises out of a collision between organized religion, the military, and taxation. Three powerful historical forces, to be sure, so the fourth pillar to modern society (rationality) obviously has to be the one to compromise!</p>
<p>But wait, there’s more: naked Greeks are involved, and Jesus, and Vikings. In that order.</p>
<p>Our story starts with the “original” mile, the Roman one (though there is indication the measurement is older still). The Romans were both practical and militant. Their mile was 1000 paces – a pace being a double step (left foot, right foot) by a soldier in full battle gear. That was a “<em>passus</em>“, and a mile was a “<em>milia passuum</em>“, hence the word “mile” (for “thousand”, as in the word <em>millennium)</em>.</p>
<p>If you are a runner or a hiker, you’ll know that we still remember this information in our convention of relating pedometers to miles: about 2000 steps to a mile. But we have forgotten that it’s not a “trick”, it’s the whole point. Language use changes back and forth over time, and today we’re more likely to use the word “step” rather than “pace”, hence, we can think of a mile as being defined as 2000 steps.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the Romans had another convention, that you’ve probably heard of, which was to place stones next to their roads to mark the distance from Rome. Called “<em>milliarium</em>“, these stone obelisks were first erected along the Via Appia, where milestones dating as far back as the second century BC still survive. Naturally, quite a large number of these stones survived along roads throughout Europe, providing a natural reference point, explaining why their particular measure of a “foot” survives with high accuracy. The central stone in Rome, from which the phrase “all roads lead to Rome” derives, wasn’t erected until some two centuries later in 20 BC, but is since lost.</p>
<p>It’s worth injecting that the popular notion that Roman roads all had measures of the distance from Rome is a myth: only central Italy and a few exceptions were marked from central Rome, all other roads were measured from the nearest local significant center. The US’ attempt to replicate this myth with the Zero Mile marker in Washington, DC, in 1792 would have a similar destiny, influencing only measurements nearby. Instead a similar variation (measuring from something local and significant) lives on in the mile markers of the interstate highway system, where the numbering typically starts at either the southern or the western state line and increasing as you drive in the other direction.</p>
<p>Curiously, we know very little of the details of how the Roman army used the mile as a practical tool – not a single significant military treatise has survived from Roman times. The that has, the <em>Epitoma rei militaris,</em> is unfortunately not considered authoritative. Thus its claims cannot be checked against any other contemporary sources, which is particularly irksome since some of them appear highly dubious – such as stating that the army marched 20 miles in 5 summer hours at regular pace and 24 miles at double pace.</p>
<p>You can experiment yourself to realize that the miles per hour measure is practical for a human: casual walking is 2 mph, an easy walk is 3, swift walking is 4. The available number of hours in a day is similarly small, thus making the mental arithmetic simple.</p>
<p>Hence, 5000 feet to the mile, a general measure that survived throughout Europe as roadside reminders of the might of Rome.</p>
<p>Now, switching tracks, about the furlong. It means “a furrow long” (long as a furrow) and is a practical measure in an agrarian society: it is (approximately) the distance an oxen can plow without resting. That distance was standardized to be 40 “rods”, where a rod (or “pole”) is today defined as 5.5 yards (16.5 feet), though it was probably originally 20 feet (we’ll get back to all this).</p>
<p>An “acre” (which means “field”) was 40 rods long and 4 rods wide (4 rods was also called a “chain”, more on that below). An acre was thus the surface area that one man and a team of oxen could till in one day. It was long and narrow because of the development of the heavy plough around the end of the 10th century, which turned the soil over, revolutionizing agriculture in northern Europe where the clay-heavy soil (vs sandier south European soil) went from being a handicap to an asset, in fact contributing significantly to the eventual inversion of economic power in Europe from the south to the north.</p>
<p>At this point, if you’re paying close attention, you’ll see that not only do we have the decimal (base 10) concept in the “mile” (one thousand paces), but also in the acre: the proportions of the sides are exactly 10:1. That’s because “acre” dates back to “10 square chains”, or an area that’s one “chain” wide and ten long. A “chain” in turn is four rods. The word “chain” comes from how this convenient measurement tool was constructed. Organic materials (wood, rope) have obvious problems in retaining precise dimensions, despite efforts to wax or otherwise treat them. A marked improvement therefore came from carrying a set of thin metal rods, that eventually would be “chained” together. Most surveying in the United States was done in the 1700s and 1800s using a standardized 100-link chain of 66 feet in total length.</p>
<p>But this was a more modern innovation. Going much further back in history it seems likely the basic approach was instead to carry a long, thin, metal “rod” that was 16 feet long, seems likely to me that they were in parts. This is still today a common surveying tool – search Amazon for “surveyor rod” and you’ll find the modern version, now made of telescoping aluminum and generally 16 feet long. We’ll get back to why it was 16 feet (and not 10 or 20), and how it later on became 16.5.</p>
<p>This tradition of the furlong (ten chains) took root in England between the fall of Rome and the Norman conquest of 1066, along the aforementioned adoption of heavy ploughs. With the Normans came the re-introduction of the Roman definition of the foot as 12 inches. A reference foot was thusly carved into one of the pier bases of the new nave in St Paul’s cathedral in London in 1104 (by the son of a banker, interestingly enough).</p>
<p>The Saxon tradition of measuring land had been established in terms of rods, and as we alluded above, probably based on 20 “natural” feet – i.e. not Roman standard feet but “real” 9.8-inch feet. The number 20, of course, was the common “decimal” system prior to the invention of shoes (at which point you can’t see your toes). Also, the technique of counting to 20 with one hand may have been prevalent. Vestiges of base-20 remain, notably for our story, in Danish and French. For example, in French you say “soixante-dix” for 70 and in Danish you say …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://petersmagnusson.org/2009/09/15/why-are-there-5280-feet-in-a-mile/">https://petersmagnusson.org/2009/09/15/why-are-there-5280-feet-in-a-mile/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://petersmagnusson.org/2009/09/15/why-are-there-5280-feet-in-a-mile/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24327740</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 01:47:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
