<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 08:20:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 08:20:58 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Fire your bad customers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 172 | Comments 85 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24097420">thread link</a>) | @grwthckrmstr
<br/>
August 8, 2020 | https://www.preetamnath.com/blog/fire-your-bad-customers | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.preetamnath.com/blog/fire-your-bad-customers">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I recently broke up with 2 customers.</p><p>They were a bad fit from the start - needy for excessive support over phone or WhatsApp, demanding discounts, and raising hell at the slightest hiccup.</p><figure id="w-node-c172f3f1a398-2f0d8df6"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e085291ed2a2769a872e587/5f2edb9a856f6e5d6a8cfdb8_sebastian-herrmann-jzTQVxCyKYs-unsplash%20(1).jpg" alt="fire bad customers break up with them"></p><figcaption><em>Photo by </em><a href="https://unsplash.com/@officestock?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText" target="_blank"><em>Sebastian Herrmann</em></a><em> on Unsplash</em></figcaption></figure><h3>Trying to make every customer happy will make you unhappy</h3><p>Past me didn’t want to lose any potential paying customer. Or have a dissatisfied customer who might go write a negative review because I didn’t provide what they demanded.</p><p>At that time during the early days, it felt like the right thing to do.</p><p>Present me knows that bad customers add more pain than value to your business, both in the short term and in the long term. There is no need to appease them.</p><p>A friend of mine serviced an early user of his app during the early days with free customisations. That same user came back asking for more custom features, while being on the FREE plan, and threatened to write a 1 star review if they didn't. </p><p>These are toxic customers. If you couldn't say no to them in the past, do it now.</p><p>Just like you cut out people from your life who are a sap and drain you without giving you much in return, do the same with customers of your business once you have enough customers.</p><p>Fire them.<br></p><h3><strong>When to fire your customer</strong></h3><p>You don’t have to proactively reach out to all the bad customers using your app and get rid of them right away.</p><p>The ideal situation is when they come to you and subject you to the same ridiculousness that past you felt okay to deal with. </p><p>Only this time, don’t give in to their complaints or demands or whining.&nbsp;<br></p><h3><strong>How to fire your customer the right way</strong></h3><p>I know I said fire your customers. That doesn’t mean you need to start a fight with them.</p><p>Talk politely like your usual self, only explain to them directly as if you’re giving radically candid feedback to a woke adult</p><p>Here are some sample scripts on firing customers.<br></p><p><em>“Hey, look this request you made is not feasible. In the past we have done a lot of work for you out of goodwill. Unfortunately, we won’t be able to service you any longer.”</em><br></p><p><em>“I understand that I answered your queries over call a few times, but that was only out of my eagerness to help you. I cannot continue to do that, and I request you to reach out through the available support channels.”</em><br></p><p><strong>It’s not me, it’s you.</strong></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.preetamnath.com/blog/fire-your-bad-customers</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24097420</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 05:10:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[GPT-3 Explorer]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 107 | Comments 26 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24094526">thread link</a>) | @onemind
<br/>
August 8, 2020 | https://belay-labs.github.io/gpt-explorer/introducing-gpt-explorer | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://belay-labs.github.io/gpt-explorer/introducing-gpt-explorer">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <header>
        
        
        

        <p>A power tool for experimenting with GPT-3</p>

        
        <p><a href="https://github.com/belay-labs/gpt-explorer">View the Project on GitHub <small>belay-labs/gpt-explorer</small></a></p>
        

        

        
      </header>
      <section>

      

<p>Explorer is a power tool for GPT-3 experimentation with <strong>full history</strong>, <strong>sharing</strong>, and the community’s <strong>best-practices</strong> built-in. If you’re just getting started with GPT-3 or don’t want to build out your own boilerplate codebase, try the hosted version: <a href="https://gpt-3-explorer.vercel.app/">Explorer</a>. The source is available <a href="https://github.com/belay-labs/gpt-explorer">here</a>.</p>

<p><img src="https://belay-labs.github.io/gpt-explorer/dashboard.gif" width="500" alt="Screenshot of dashboard"></p>

<hr>



<h2 id="a-ui-for-experimentation">A UI for experimentation</h2>

<p>To get good results from GPT-3, you need to experiment. (Despite what the cherry-picked examples on Twitter will have you believe!)</p>

<p>This fundamental insight led to Explorer’s first feature: saved history. They say the difference between tinkering and science is rigor and reproducibility. We codified that transition by making all our prompts and settings automatically saved and shareable. Annotations further allowed us to build and improve upon previous results.</p>

<p>Long term, we envision an environment that enables the development of higher level APIs on top of GPT-3. A system for designing pipelines of prompts, complex scripts, logic to retrieve external information — that can all be published for use in products and research.</p>

<p>Building complex applications requires you to work at a higher level of abstraction than machine code. <strong>How can we build an open source operating system for GPT-3 at the dawn of <a href="https://medium.com/@karpathy/software-2-0-a64152b37c35">Software 2.0</a>?</strong></p>

<h2 id="get-involved">Get involved!</h2>

<p>There’s a long road ahead and we’re thankful for all of your feedback and suggestions so far. We welcome code contributions to Explorer - pop over to <a href="https://github.com/belay-labs/gpt-explorer">the repository</a> to learn how you can get it running locally!</p>

<p>Oh, and try it out <a href="https://gpt-3-explorer.vercel.app/">here</a> :)</p>



<hr>

<h2 id="appendix">Appendix</h2>

<h3 id="building-together">Building together</h3>

<p>The community is continually discovering incredible methods for unlocking GPT-3’s potential. Without the right set of tools, most practitioners struggle to find and implement these new techniques.</p>

<p>That’s where we see the need for an open source project where we can all rapidly experiment and codify what we’ve learned. Here are some of the community’s methods and best practices that we’re excited to incorporate as features in Explorer:</p>

<p><strong>Prompt chaining</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>This method skirts the token limit by “chaining” together prompts and their outputs.</li>
  <li><a href="http://gptprompts.wikidot.com/chaining:chaining">Chaining</a> breaks down larger tasks into component sub-tasks, before composing them back together in a single prompt to get your final result.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Context stuffing</strong></p>

<p>This is a method of iterative prompt improvement that involves:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Running an initial prompt</li>
  <li>Cherrypicking the best GPT-3 outputs,</li>
  <li>Appending them to the original prompt, to provide more examples for GPT-3 to use.</li>
</ol>


<h3 id="the-roadmap">The Roadmap</h3>

<p>In the coming months, with your help, we plan to build these features (and more!). As the private beta comes to an end, let’s enable new GPT-3 users to hit the ground running with the cumulative, collective insights of the community.</p>

<p>As we receive feedback and contributions from the community, this roadmap will continue to change and be reprioritized. You can follow a live version of it <a href="https://github.com/belay-labs/gpt-explorer/projects/1">here</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Sharing and importing prompts</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>“GitHub for Prompts”. Let’s make it easy to share and build on each others’ work!</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Prompt evaluation</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>GPT’s performance is very, very sensitive to prompt design. So iterating on prompt design is our highest priority.</li>
  <li>With built-in tools for prompt evaluation, you can annotate, rank and sort results for the same task across different prompt designs.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Scripting &amp; chaining</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Enable commands which can trigger scripts.</li>
  <li>These scripts can then: <em>i.</em> do computation, or <em>ii.</em> trigger API requests to do actions, get more information, call other prompts, etc.</li>
  <li>In particular, this scripting interface can chain prompts together.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Higher level API interface</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>The OpenAI API is all about simplicity, it is a raw text-in, text-out interface, which is great to build on top of but does not make it easy to best take advantage of the tool.</li>
  <li>We envision a higher level API which you can use to develop higher-level reasoning and operations on top of the low level API. Turn any prompt, which itself can be a pipeline of other prompts, into an API.</li>
  <li>This enables a more broadly useful natural language interface for: chat, question answering, text transformations, multi-step labeling, and other pipelines of natural language operations</li>
</ul>



<p>Try <a href="https://gpt-3-explorer.vercel.app/">Explorer</a>.
Contribute to the <a href="https://github.com/belay-labs/gpt-explorer">open source project</a>.</p>


      </section>
      
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://belay-labs.github.io/gpt-explorer/introducing-gpt-explorer</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24094526</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 19:40:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Rome: A Linter for JavaScript and TypeScript]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 221 | Comments 87 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24094377">thread link</a>) | @acemarke
<br/>
August 8, 2020 | https://romefrontend.dev/blog/2020/08/08/introducing-rome.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://romefrontend.dev/blog/2020/08/08/introducing-rome.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div> <main id="main-content"> <section> <div>   <p>We’re excited to announce the first beta release and general availability of the <strong>Rome</strong> linter for JavaScript and TypeScript.</p> <p>This is the beginning of an entire suite of tools. Rome is not only linter, but also a compiler, bundler, test runner, and <a href="https://romefrontend.dev/#development-status">more</a>, for JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, JSON, Markdown, and CSS. We aim to unify the entire frontend development toolchain.</p> <p>Rome is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monolithic_application">monolithic</a> tool containing functionality that has traditionally been separate tools in the frontend ecosystem. We call this a toolchain. It is <strong>not</strong> a collection of existing tools, but completely custom, built <a href="https://romefrontend.dev/credits">largely</a> from scratch, contained entirely in a single package and codebase.</p> <p>Rome is designed to replace <a href="https://babeljs.io/">Babel</a>, <a href="https://eslint.org/">ESLint</a>, <a href="https://webpack.js.org/">Webpack</a>, <a href="https://prettier.io/">Prettier</a>, <a href="https://jestjs.io/">Jest</a>, and others.</p> <p>We have significant implementations already for most components, including compiling, bundling, and testing, all using the same core abstractions and internal libraries. Rome is even <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-hosting_(compilers)">self-hosted</a> and we use them to <a href="https://github.com/romefrontend/rome/blob/main/CONTRIBUTING.md">build and develop Rome itself</a>! Once usage as a linter has stabilized, we will move onto the unreleased features to prepare and generalize them for public usage.</p> <p>Linting is an excellent low-risk way for us to mature and validate shared functionality like editor integration, configuration, parallelization, caching, parsing, and dependency analysis. It is not in the critical build path for development so is relatively straight forward and safe to adopt.</p> <pre><code><span>$</span> rome check

 <span>src/App.jsx:12:3</span> <strong>lint/jsx-a11y/altText</strong> ━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━

  <strong><span>✖ </span></strong><span>Provide </span><span><strong>alt</strong></span><span> text when using </span><span><strong>img</strong></span><span>, </span><span><strong>area</strong></span><span>, </span><span><strong>input type='image'</strong></span><span>, and </span><span><strong>object</strong></span>
    <span>elements.</span>

  <strong>  10</strong><strong> │ </strong>  <span>return</span> &lt;<span>div</span> <span>className</span><span>=</span><span>"App"</span>&gt;
  <strong>  11</strong><strong> │ </strong>    &lt;<span>header</span> <span>className</span><span>=</span><span>"App-header"</span>&gt;
  <strong><span>&gt;</span></strong><strong> 12</strong><strong> │ </strong>      &lt;<span>img</span> <span>src</span><span>=</span><span>{</span><span>logo2</span><span>}</span> <span>className</span><span>=</span><span>"App-logo"</span> <span>/</span>&gt;
      <strong> │ </strong>      <span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span>
  <strong>  13</strong><strong> │ </strong>      &lt;<span>p</span>&gt;
  <strong>  14</strong><strong> │ </strong>        Edit

  <strong><span>ℹ </span></strong><span>Meaningful alternative text on elements helps users relying on screen</span>
    <span>readers to understand content's purpose within a page.</span>

 <span>src/App.jsx:12:13</span> <strong>lint/js/noUndeclaredVariables</strong> ━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━

  <strong><span>✖ </span></strong><span>The </span><span><strong>logo2</strong></span><span> variable is undeclared</span>

  <strong>  10</strong><strong> │ </strong>  <span>return</span> &lt;<span>div</span> <span>className</span><span>=</span><span>"App"</span>&gt;
  <strong>  11</strong><strong> │ </strong>    &lt;<span>header</span> <span>className</span><span>=</span><span>"App-header"</span>&gt;
  <strong><span>&gt;</span></strong><strong> 12</strong><strong> │ </strong>      &lt;<span>img</span> <span>src</span><span>=</span><span>{</span><span>logo2</span><span>}</span> <span>className</span><span>=</span><span>"App-logo"</span> <span>/</span>&gt;
      <strong> │ </strong>                <span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span>
  <strong>  13</strong><strong> │ </strong>      &lt;<span>p</span>&gt;
  <strong>  14</strong><strong> │ </strong>        Edit

  <strong><span>ℹ </span></strong><span>Did you mean </span><span><strong>logo</strong></span><span>?</span>

  <span>-</span> <span>logo</span><span><strong>2</strong></span>
  <span>+</span> <span>logo</span>

 <span>src/App.jsx:2:7</span> <strong>lint/js/noUnusedVariables</strong> ━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━

  <strong><span>✖ </span></strong><span>The import variable </span><span><strong>logo</strong></span><span> is unused.</span>

  <strong>  1</strong><strong> │ </strong>
  <strong><span>&gt;</span></strong><strong> 2</strong><strong> │ </strong><span>import</span> <span>logo</span> <span>from</span> <span>"./logo.svg"</span><span>;</span>
     <strong> │ </strong>       <span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span><span><strong>^</strong></span>
  <strong>  3</strong><strong> │ </strong><span>import</span> <span>"./App.css"</span><span>;</span>

  <strong><span>ℹ </span></strong><span>Unused variables are dead code and usually the result of incomplete</span>
    <span>refactoring.</span>

━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━

<strong><span>✖ </span></strong><span>Found </span><span><strong>3</strong></span><span> </span><span>problems</span></code></pre> <p>Even though this is a beta, we have support for over 100 lint rules, including the most common rules needed when working with TypeScript and React. See the full <a href="https://romefrontend.dev/docs/lint/rules">list of rules</a>. You can expect a full featured experience, however may still encounter bugs. With most of the feature development out of the way we will be focusing primarily on stability.</p> <p>Most of our rules have been inspired by their ESLint equivalents. This required a complete rewrite to utilize Rome’s API that differ extensively from existing tools. Without the amazing work of the ESLint team and community establishing these recommended patterns, we would not have been able to pull this off. Refer to the <a href="https://romefrontend.dev/docs/lint/rules">lint rule docs</a> for direct references.</p> <p>Since open sourcing, at the beginning of the year, we have received contributions from over <a href="https://github.com/romefrontend/rome/graphs/contributors">70 contributors</a> and <a href="https://github.com/romefrontend/rome/pulls?q=is%3Apr+is%3Amerged">600 pull requests</a>. We have an established <a href="https://romefrontend.dev/credits#team">team</a>, a formal <a href="https://github.com/romefrontend/rome/blob/main/GOVERNANCE.md">governance model</a>, and a <a href="https://github.com/romefrontend/rome/blob/main/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md">code of conduct</a> enforcement policy. This ensures transparency around project decisions, moderation, and direction.</p> <p>You can read more about Rome, including how to get started, in our <a href="https://romefrontend.dev/">documentation</a>. If you would like to get involved, check out our <a href="https://github.com/romefrontend/rome/blob/main/CONTRIBUTING.md">contributing instructions</a>. If you are interested in reading more about the history and rationale for the project, you can continue reading below.</p> <ul> <li> <a href="https://github.com/romefrontend/rome"> <svg data-name="github" viewBox="0 0 32 31.21"><path d="M16 .29a15.72 15.72 0 00-5 30.64c.79.14 1.08-.34 1.08-.76V27.5c-4.38.95-5.3-2.11-5.3-2.11A4.16 4.16 0 005 23.09c-1.42-1 .11-1 .11-1a3.3 3.3 0 012.41 1.62 3.35 3.35 0 004.58 1.31 3.31 3.31 0 011-2.1C9.64 22.56 6 21.21 6 15.19A6.1 6.1 0 017.59 11a5.68 5.68 0 01.15-4.16s1.32-.42 4.33 1.61a14.87 14.87 0 017.87 0c3-2 4.32-1.61 4.32-1.61a5.58 5.58 0 01.15 4.16A6.06 6.06 0 0126 15.19c0 6-3.68 7.37-7.18 7.76a3.72 3.72 0 011.07 2.91v4.31c0 .52.28.91 1.08.76A15.73 15.73 0 0016 .29z"></path></svg> GitHub </a> </li> <li> <a href="https://opencollective.com/romefrontend"> <svg data-name="open collective" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M12 19.57a7.57 7.57 0 010-15.14 7.34 7.34 0 014.1 1.23l3-3A11.9 11.9 0 0012 .27a11.74 11.74 0 100 23.47 11.56 11.56 0 007.12-2.44L16 18.22a6.25 6.25 0 01-4 1.35z"></path><path d="M19.54 12a7.64 7.64 0 01-1.22 4.1l3.07 3.08a11.86 11.86 0 002.38-7.12A11.48 11.48 0 0021.33 5l-3 3a7.26 7.26 0 011.22 4z"></path></svg> Open Collective </a> </li> <li> <a href="https://discord.gg/rome"> <svg viewBox="0 0 245 240"><path d="M100.8,100.7c-6.8,0-12.2,6-12.2,13.3s5.5,13.3,12.2,13.3c6.8,0,12.2-6,12.2-13.3C113.1,106.7,107.6,100.7,100.8,100.7z M144.6,100.7c-6.8,0-12.2,6-12.2,13.3s5.5,13.3,12.2,13.3c6.8,0,12.2-6,12.2-13.3S151.4,100.7,144.6,100.7z"></path><path d="M202.9,0H42.1C28.5,0,17.5,11,17.5,24.7V187c0,13.7,11,24.7,24.6,24.7h136.1l-6.4-22.2l15.4,14.3l14.5,13.4l25.8,22.8V24.7 C227.5,11,216.5,0,202.9,0z M156.6,156.7c0,0-4.3-5.2-7.9-9.7c15.7-4.4,21.7-14.3,21.7-14.3c-4.9,3.2-9.6,5.5-13.8,7.1 c-6,2.5-11.8,4.2-17.4,5.2c-11.5,2.2-22.1,1.6-31.1-0.1c-6.8-1.3-12.7-3.2-17.6-5.2c-2.8-1.1-5.8-2.4-8.8-4.1 c-0.4-0.2-0.7-0.4-1.1-0.6c-0.2-0.1-0.4-0.2-0.5-0.4c-2.2-1.2-3.4-2-3.4-2s5.8,9.6,21,14.2c-3.6,4.6-8,10-8,10 c-26.5-0.8-36.6-18.2-36.6-18.2c0-38.6,17.3-70,17.3-70c17.3-13,33.7-12.6,33.7-12.6l1.2,1.4c-21.6,6.2-31.6,15.7-31.6,15.7 s2.6-1.4,7.1-3.5c12.8-5.6,23-7.2,27.2-7.6c0.7-0.1,1.3-0.2,2-0.2c7.3-1,15.6-1.2,24.2-0.2c11.4,1.3,23.6,4.7,36.1,11.5 c0,0-9.5-9-29.9-15.2l1.7-1.9c0,0,16.4-0.4,33.7,12.6c0,0,17.3,31.3,17.3,70C193.3,138.5,183.1,155.9,156.6,156.7z"></path></svg> Discord </a> </li> <li> <a href="https://twitter.com/romefrontend"> <svg data-name="twitter" viewBox="0 0 32 31.21"><path d="M10.21 28.28c11.77 0 18.21-9.75 18.21-18.21v-.83a12.75 12.75 0 003.2-3.31 12.74 12.74 0 01-3.68 1 6.37 6.37 0 002.79-3.53A12.84 12.84 0 0126.67 5a6.41 6.41 0 00-10.91 5.84A18.15 18.15 0 012.58 4.1a6.39 6.39 0 002 8.54 6.32 6.32 0 01-2.91-.8v.08a6.41 6.41 0 005.12 6.28 6.42 6.42 0 01-2.89.11 6.4 6.4 0 006 4.44 12.89 12.89 0 01-8 2.75 11.23 11.23 0 01-1.5-.1 18.09 18.09 0 009.81 2.87"></path></svg> Twitter </a> </li> </ul> <section> <h2 id="history">History <a href="#history"></a></h2> <p>I created <strong>6to5</strong> in 2014 (now called <a href="https://babeljs.io/">Babel</a>), a JavaScript transpiler that compiled new ES6 code to ES5 that could be run in any browser. At the time I wasn’t trying to solve any particular problem, I was just building and experimenting with existing libraries and teaching myself new concepts. Over time though, as the project exploded in popularity, so did the scope and mission of the project.</p> <p>We renamed <strong>6to5</strong> to <strong>Babel</strong> to take on a new role as a general platform for doing static JavaScript transformation. This meant a plugin system and a new commitment to supporting future JavaScript standards and proposed features.</p> <p>We also planned on expanding Babel to be used as the base for other JavaScript language tooling by using shared public libraries. From the Babel blog post “<a href="https://babeljs.io/blog/2015/10/29/6.0.0">6.0.0 Released</a>” by <a href="https://twitter.com/buildsghost">Jamie Kyle</a>:</p> <blockquote> <p>But we think we can go even further. Babel should be able to power minifiers, linters, formatters, syntax highlighters, code completion tools, type checkers, codemod tools, and every other tool to be using the same foundation to do their job better than ever before.</p> </blockquote> <figure> <img width="600" src="https://romefrontend.dev/img/blog/6to5-to-babel.png" alt="Old 6to5 logo with an arrow pointing to the new Babel logo"> <figcaption>Old 6to5 logo with an arrow pointing to the new Babel logo</figcaption> </figure> <p>In 2016, I left the project, and those plans never materialized. Over time, I learned the Babel would not have been able to successfully adapt to execute on this vision anyway. The solution to plugins was “expose all the internals” which is an extremely large API surface area to maintain and restricts your ability to make any changes.</p> <p>Making the necessary modifications to Babel to allow for it to be a reliable base for other tools would have required changes to absolutely everything. The architecture is bound to the initial design choices I made in 2014 when I was learning about parsers, ASTs, and compilers.</p> <p>There would have been no way to provide backward compatibility, and with expectations already set, any significant changes to the project would have introduced an extremely high amount of ecosystem churn.</p> <p>In an ode to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ship_of_Theseus">Ship of Theseus</a>, if all components of an object are replaced, is it the same object? There is far less confusion and friction to release something entirely new than drastically change something that’s already in widespread usage. I had since moved on from the project, and so any evolution would not have been possible, and would have required complete vision alignment.</p> <p>Even though I wasn’t involved in Babel, I still maintained a presence in the developer tooling ecosystem. I eventually went on to develop other tools like <a href="https://yarnpkg.com/">Yarn</a> and be involved in projects like <a href="https://prepack.io/">Prepack</a> and <a href="https://fbflipper.com/">Flipper</a>. This work continued to develop the ideas that would eventually become Rome and shaped my philosophy on developer experience. A focus on excellent errors, clean user interface, and minimal configuration.</p> <figure> <img width="500" src="https://romefrontend.dev/img/blog/introducing-rome-post-babel-logos.png" alt="The logos of Yarn, Prepack, and Flipper"> <figcaption>The logos of Yarn, Prepack, and Flipper</figcaption> </figure> <p>The original idea behind Babel had always stuck. What sort of capabilities would be possible if a tool did more than one thing? This sort of philosophy has always seemed alien in the JavaScript ecosystem where micropackages and arbitrary separation of concerns are the norms. These tools being independent has never provided the sort of user autonomy and efficiency that most skeptics of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monolithic_application">monolithic</a> tools proclaim.</p> <p>Language tooling maintainers spend so much time working on the same things. Processing source code, whether it’s in a transpiler like Babel, linting it in ESLint, or bundling it in Webpack, is fundamentally the same problem with overlapping responsibilities and technical implementation.</p> <p>A linter in the JavaScript ecosystem is exactly the same as a compiler. They both consume code, then produce compiled code and errors. What the compiled code is varies. In the case of a linter, the compiled code is formatted source code with automatic fixes applied. The more powerful your compilation infrastructure, the more theoretically powerful your linter could be. These commonalities extend to pretty much anything that involves language processing. We can build more powerful tools using a shared base that is easily adaptable.</p> <p>I had always maintained private repos where I would experiment with ideas, but the original code that would become Rome was started at the beginning of 2017 while I was working for Facebook in my free time. I continued iterating and experimenting on the idea and building out all the different pieces, until 2019, when I was given the opportunity to work on and explore using it at Facebook full-time.</p> <p>I eventually left Facebook and the project became open source in February 2020 where I would continue it as an independent community-driven project.</p> <p>Rome is the spiritual successor of Babel. I’ve taken the lessons I learnt, and refined the mission. Rather than exposing a large public API for other tools to be built on, we are building them all in one place, with batteries included. I’m excited to be trying something new that the JavaScript and web ecosystem haven’t seen before.</p> <p>— <a href="https://twitter.com/sebmck">Sebastian McKenzie</a></p> </section>  </div> </section> </main> </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://romefrontend.dev/blog/2020/08/08/introducing-rome.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24094377</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 19:27:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[UPI: India's Unified Payments Interface]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 261 | Comments 137 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24094323">thread link</a>) | @zero_kool
<br/>
August 8, 2020 | https://the-other-side.blog/upi-the-basics/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://the-other-side.blog/upi-the-basics/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
                <div>
                    <p>In this article, we will learn about India's Unified Payments Interface. A four-year-old payment scheme that has been accounting for 40-45% of digital payments across India. In December 2019, Google <a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/SECRS/2019/November/20191113/OP-1670/OP-1670_110719_136981_396266957468_1.pdf">recommended</a> the Federal Reserve to follow the model of UPI for the design of FedNow.</p><p>It is going to be a 3 part series.</p><p><strong>Part 1 </strong>(this article): We will cover the background and basics. We will learn about the different participants and their roles in the UPI ecosystem.</p><p><a href="https://the-other-side.blog/upi-the-transaction-lifecycle"><strong>Part 2:</strong></a> We take a deep-dive into UPI by tracing a UPI transaction from the beginning through the end.</p><p><strong><a href="https://the-other-side.blog/upi-the-settlement">Part 3:</a></strong> We will look at settlements and understand how money exchanges hands.</p><hr><h3 id="background">Background</h3><p>Since its inception in 2016, UPI has grown tremendously over the last 4 years. It has enabled a whole new set of individuals to transact digitally for the first time.</p><p>There were multiple attempts towards making India a cashless society. Earlier solutions were not simple to use and relied heavily on Netbanking facilities provided by the banks. The experience was not standard. Because of all these reasons, it was mostly used only by the tech-savvy population. India being a diverse country needed a system that has a plethora of payment apps that are optimised for different cohorts.</p><figure><img src="https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/2020/06/upi_transaction_growth.png" alt="" width="1468" height="1088" srcset="https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/size/w600/2020/06/upi_transaction_growth.png 600w, https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/size/w1000/2020/06/upi_transaction_growth.png 1000w, https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/2020/06/upi_transaction_growth.png 1468w" sizes="(min-width: 1200px) 1200px"><figcaption>Growth of UPI</figcaption></figure><p>The primary objective of UPI was to build an open payment system that is mobile-first, fast, and interoperable across different banks.</p><p>For a developing country like India, going mobile-first was almost a no brainer. Mobile Phones and Mobile Data were getting cheaper and the trend was clear.</p><p>Interoperability simply puts the user’s needs at the center. The users can opt for any payment app, link it with their bank account to engage in commerce with anyone across India.</p><p>Think about it, all of us want to use payment apps that we like, instead of being limited to a poorly designed app that’s provided by the bank where we keep our money. We should let banks do what they do best (which is managing money) and let tech companies handle building intuitive user interfaces for transacting money.</p><p>UPI was built on this principle to let private players innovate on top of public digital infrastructure.</p><h3 id="so-what-exactly-is-upi">So, What exactly is UPI?</h3><p>UPI is a payment markup language and a standard for interoperable payments in India.</p><p>To make the process of transacting money simple, UPI introduced the concept of human friendly unique IDs called UPI Virtual Payment Addresses (or VPAs). The VPAs are usually of the form <strong><em>&lt;unique_identifier&gt;</em></strong>@<strong><em>&lt;address_provider&gt;</em></strong>.</p><p>The UPI VPAs are similar to email addresses. They are interoperable. A gmail user can send an email to a yahoo user. </p><p>Some simple examples UPI VPAs are <strong><em>alice@ybl </em></strong>and<strong><em> bob@axis</em></strong>. Here, <strong><em>ybl</em></strong> and <strong><em>axis </em></strong>are two banks that provide virtual payment addresses. And, <strong><em>alice </em></strong>and<strong><em> bob </em></strong>are the unique identifiers in respective address providers.</p><figure><img src="https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/2020/06/payment_markup.png" alt="" width="1600" height="1064" srcset="https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/size/w600/2020/06/payment_markup.png 600w, https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/size/w1000/2020/06/payment_markup.png 1000w, https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/2020/06/payment_markup.png 1600w" sizes="(min-width: 1200px) 1200px"></figure><p>Just like how domains get resolved to IP addresses, every VPA needs to be linked to a bank account. The UPI handles get resolved to bank accounts and IFSC during the payment (we will see how).</p><p>In short, a UPI Virtual Payment Address serves as the addressing layer for a bank account.</p><p>There are mainly two types of transactions in the UPI realm.</p><h4 id="direct-payment">Direct Payment</h4><p>The payer (the sender) initiates the transaction. Typical examples would be, you paying a shopkeeper at the checkout by scanning a QR code or you sending money to your friends and family.</p><h4 id="collect-request">Collect Request</h4><p>The payee (the receiver) initiates the transaction. A simple example is a scenario where your landlord creates a collect request asking you to pay the monthly rent.</p><hr><h2 id="the-ecosystem">The Ecosystem</h2><p>There are three types of participants in the UPI ecosystem.</p><h3 id="the-banks">The Banks</h3><p>Banks hold your money. UPI works directly with the bank accounts, unlike Paytm, Venmo, or CashApp. The bank account will be debited from or credited to whenever you send money or receive money.</p><p>The banks that hold your money are also called <em>Issuing Banks</em>.</p><p>Every bank uses a system called Core Banking System (CBS) to manage its user’s accounts. At the core, CBS is a simple <a href="https://www.codecademy.com/articles/what-is-crud" rel="noopener">CRUD</a> system built around user accounts.</p><p>Debit and Credit are the two fundamental operations of core banking software.The debit is when you’re taking money out of your account. The amount involved is subtracted from your balance. On the other hand, when you’re getting paid, its a credit. The money is added to your account.</p><p>Banks also maintain another UPI specific database. We will discuss more on that later.</p><figure><img src="https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/2020/07/banks_intro.png" alt="" width="2328" height="1840" srcset="https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/banks_intro.png 600w, https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/size/w1000/2020/07/banks_intro.png 1000w, https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/size/w1600/2020/07/banks_intro.png 1600w, https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/2020/07/banks_intro.png 2328w" sizes="(min-width: 1200px) 1200px"></figure><h3 id="the-payment-apps">The Payment Apps</h3><p>Payment Apps are consumer-centric products that can be used to link a bank account and transact in the real world. Some major apps are Google Pay, PhonePe, BHIM, etc. Almost all the banks have their own versions of UPI Apps. There is a wide variety of options to chose from.</p><p>Payment Apps allow users to create handles to make everyday transactions easier. However, not everyone can start creating UPI handles. Reserve Bank of India (RBI) regulates who can create UPI handles. Currently, only the member banks of the UPI ecosystem are allowed to do so.</p><p>That’s why all the payment apps will have to tie up with banks. These banks not only allow payment apps to create and manage UPI handles for their users, but they are also the interface to the UPI ecosystem.</p><p>These banks are called <em>Acquiring Banks</em>.</p><p>Google Pay has tied up with HDFC Bank, Axis Bank, and SBI. PhonePe has a tie-up with Yes Bank and ICICI Bank.</p><p>Banks provide separate APIs to allow payment apps to create and manage the UPI handles.</p><figure><img src="https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/2020/07/payment_apps_intro.png" alt="" width="2540" height="1520" srcset="https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/payment_apps_intro.png 600w, https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/size/w1000/2020/07/payment_apps_intro.png 1000w, https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/size/w1600/2020/07/payment_apps_intro.png 1600w, https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/size/w2400/2020/07/payment_apps_intro.png 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 1200px) 1200px"></figure><h3 id="npci">NPCI</h3><p>National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) is a non-profit set up by the Government of India to facilitate digital payments. They facilitate many payment schemes (like IMPS, BBPS, FASTag, etc.)</p><p>If we reflect back on the original objective of UPI, it was to build an interoperable system. An interoperable means anyone could download a payment app, link any bank (that they own), and transact with anyone else from any other bank.</p><p>One primitive way of building such an interoperable network would be to connect every payment app with every bank. As you’re probably guessing, that’s a very inefficient way of doing it, even if we assume something like that is possible. It practically not possible.</p><p>And, the only thing that’s constant in the software realm, is the fact that systems keep changing and breaking. Imagine the pain that everyone has to go through in reaching a consensus when configurations or infrastructures change. It would be chaos.</p><p>This approach is the same as building an Internet where your browser has to remember the IP address of every possible website on the planet, otherwise, you wouldn’t be able to access it.</p><p>Of course, the Internet is not built in this fashion. The job of resolving every web address into an IP address is taken out as a separate protocol called DNS. Our browsers trust the IP address resolved by the DNS servers used by our Internet Service Providers.</p><p>Introducing standardization and a trusted third party will result in a completely different architecture.</p><figure><img src="https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/2020/07/interoperable_systems.png" alt="" width="3000" height="1520" srcset="https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/interoperable_systems.png 600w, https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/size/w1000/2020/07/interoperable_systems.png 1000w, https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/size/w1600/2020/07/interoperable_systems.png 1600w, https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/size/w2400/2020/07/interoperable_systems.png 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 1200px) 1200px"></figure><p>That’s the route UPI creators took, they made NPCI as the trusted switch and they standardized the protocol. NPCI makes sure that data flow between banks and payment apps are routed to the correct and verified destinations.</p><p>The end result, the payment apps, and banks talk just to NPCI and can be assured by NPCI that they are really interacting with who they intend to.</p><p>To make this easy to understand, we made a GIF.</p><figure><img src="https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/2020/07/npci_switch.gif" alt="" width="1200" height="851" srcset="https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/npci_switch.gif 600w, https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/size/w1000/2020/07/npci_switch.gif 1000w, https://the-other-side.blog/content/images/2020/07/npci_switch.gif 1200w" sizes="(min-width: 1200px) 1200px"></figure><p>Apart from being the trusted router, NPCI also hosts non-financial meta APIs to serve everyone in the ecosystem.</p><p>Some examples of meta API are <em>listAccountProviders (returns all details of all banks), validateAddress (helps in validating VPAs), requestOtp (for 2FA), </em>etc.</p><p>NPCI has one more important role to play. It’s something to do with settlement. We will cover in the last part of the series.</p><hr><p>Before we wrap the first series, let's quickly visit authentication.</p><h3 id="authentication">Authentication</h3><p>UPI uses 2-factor authentication. Commonly used factors are the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multi-factor_authentication#Possession_factors" rel="noopener">possession factor</a> and the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multi-factor_authentication#Knowledge_factors" rel="noopener">knowledge factor</a>.</p><p>UPI being mobile-first, the possession factor (“what a user has”) is the user’s phone. It’s validated using the device fingerprint.</p><p>The knowledge factor (“what a user knows”) is the 4 digits or 6 digits UPI PIN.</p><p>The authentication scheme is designed to be flexible and can use different authentication factors in the future.</p><p>We will learn how these authentication factors are verified in the upcoming articles.</p><hr><p>That’s a wrap of the first part of the series.</p><p>We hope you enjoyed it. Share it with the intellectually curious folks in your circle. If you have any questions regarding UPI or anything related to Fintech in general, feel free to post them on our <a href="https://discuss.setu.co/">forum</a>.</p><p>In the <a href="https://the-other-side.blog/upi-the-transaction-lifecycle">next part</a> of the series, we will take a detailed look into how UPI transactions work. </p>
                </div>
            </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://the-other-side.blog/upi-the-basics/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24094323</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 19:20:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Apple takes legal action against small company with pear logo]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 629 | Comments 261 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24094143">thread link</a>) | @lapcatsoftware
<br/>
August 8, 2020 | https://www.iphoneincanada.ca/news/apple-legal-action-pear-logo/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.iphoneincanada.ca/news/apple-legal-action-pear-logo/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>


<!-- .entry-social-links -->
<div>
	
	
	
		
		
	
<!-- .entry-social-links -->	
		
		
	<div>
	<p><img title="prepear vs apple.jpg" src="https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/prepear-vs-apple.jpg" alt="Prepear vs apple" width="800" height="450"></p>
<p><a href="https://www.prepear.com/">Prepear</a> is a meal planner and grocery list app that helps people discover recipes and more. It’s a spin off from the founders of <em><a href="https://www.superhealthykids.com/">Super Healthy Kids</a></em> and right now they saying its logo is under legal attack from Apple.</p>	
	
	
	
<p>It’s funny what Instagram accounts you follow as a parent at some point. Yesterday, we noticed <em>Super Healthy Kids</em> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CDmcFEInZK7/">sharing a post</a> detailing their new legal woes with Apple.</p>
<p>According to the founders, Apple “has opposed the trademark application for our small business, Prepear, demanding that we change our obviously pear shaped logo, used to represent our brand in the recipe management and meal planning business.”</p>
<p><a href="https://www.change.org/p/apple-save-the-pear-from-apple-end-apple-s-aggressive-opposition-of-small-businesses-with-fruit-logos?recruiter=1137882952&amp;recruited_by_id=ebcd47e0-d5d9-11ea-95f3-73a235808f2d&amp;utm_source=share_petition&amp;utm_medium=copylink&amp;utm_campaign=petition_dashboard">In a petition on Change.org</a>, Prepear goes on to say, “before attacking us, Apple has opposed dozens of other trademark applications filed by small businesses with fruit related logos. Many of those logos were changed or abandoned. Most small businesses cannot afford the tens of thousands of dollars it would cost to fight Apple.”</p>
<p>Prepear says they are a small company with only five staff and legal costs have already cost them “many thousands of dollars” plus laying off one team member, in their legal fight against the iPhone maker.</p>
<p>“It is a very terrifying experience to be legally attacked by one of the largest companies in the world, even when we have clearly done nothing wrong, and we understand why most companies just give in and change their logos,” adds Prepear in its plea for support.</p>
<p>Prepear says they “feel a moral obligation to take a stand against Apple’s aggressive legal action against small businesses and fight for the right to keep our logo. We are defending ourselves against Apple not only to keep our logo, but to send a message to big tech companies that bullying small businesses has consequences.”</p>
<p>So far, just over 8,200 signatures have been signed out of a goal of 10,000 on <a href="https://www.change.org/p/apple-save-the-pear-from-apple-end-apple-s-aggressive-opposition-of-small-businesses-with-fruit-logos?recruiter=1137882952&amp;recruited_by_id=ebcd47e0-d5d9-11ea-95f3-73a235808f2d&amp;utm_source=share_petition&amp;utm_medium=copylink&amp;utm_campaign=petition_dashboard">change.org</a>.</p>
<p>Looking at the two logos above, I can’t say the Prepear logo resembles the Apple logo at all. But of course, Apple feels different about that.</p>
<p>Prepear is a free app and available for <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/prepear/id1248495163">download on iOS</a> and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.prepear.android&amp;hl=en_US">Android</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Update</strong>: You can check out Apple’s trademark opposition filed above (via <em><a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2020/08/08/legal-action-against-company-with-pear-logo/">MacRumors</a></em>).</p>
<p><strong>Update August 9</strong>: Prepear’s COO, Russ Monson, told <em>iPhone in Canada</em> in an email more insight in regards to the company’s filing of their trademark for the ‘pear’ logo.</p>
<p>Monson says Prepear filed their trademark for the logo back in January 2017 and eventually was told by the U.S. Trademark office “that it was not in conflict with any other registered trademarks and that they would publish it for opposition.” Everything seemed good to go.</p>
<p>That was until on the “on the last day of the window to oppose the trademark we received notice that Apple had filed for an extension of the window to oppose, and they subsequently filed for additional extensions which put our trademark in legal limbo for an extended period of time.”</p>
<p>According to Monson, Apple filed their actual opposition on the final day they were legally allowed. Subsequent extensions filed result in more legal fees for a company like Prepear to take on, which they said “seemed designed by their legal team to be made as long, difficult, and expensive as possible for us.”</p>
<p>Monson goes on to explain Prepear was “naive enough” to think they could discuss the matter with Apple rationally, as both logos look different. But that wasn’t the case and the opposition has reached the ‘discovery phase’, which the COO says will “be the most expensive part of this case for us.”</p>
<p>After Apple filed to proceed to discovery phase, that’s what Prepear decided to start their petition. “We believe that this case is clearly frivolous, and that once the public is aware of Apple’s position on this that Apple will be more willing to drop the case rather than have the public see how they are clearly harming us for no apparent justifiable reason,” said Monson to <em>iPhone in Canada.</em></p>
<p>Prepear says they aren’t asking for a boycott of Apple products, but they are asking the iPhone maker to “stop attacking small businesses like ours in frivolous cases that seem designed to cause us to spend as much money and time thinking about the case instead of focusing on how to grow our business and ensure we survive the current economic crisis.”</p>
<p>Monson shared with<em> iPhone in Canada</em> some other oppositions Apple had previously filed against, in a similar fashion to what is happening them right now. These companies below gave up when Apple reached out, but Prepear says they are lucky to garner enough media attention “to expose this practice by Apple.”</p>
<p><a href="https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/prepear-apple-logos-fruit.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/prepear-apple-logos-fruit-992x1042.jpg" alt="" width="992" height="1042" srcset="https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/prepear-apple-logos-fruit-992x1042.jpg 992w, https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/prepear-apple-logos-fruit-333x350.jpg 333w, https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/prepear-apple-logos-fruit-457x480.jpg 457w, https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/prepear-apple-logos-fruit-768x807.jpg 768w, https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/prepear-apple-logos-fruit-660x693.jpg 660w, https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/prepear-apple-logos-fruit-560x588.jpg 560w, https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/prepear-apple-logos-fruit.jpg 1124w" sizes="(max-width: 992px) 100vw, 992px"></a></p>
<p>Prepear says it will be handing its petition of signatures–which currently stands at nearly 19,000 signatures–to Apple soon and will be sharing updates on what happens. The company explains to <em>iPhone in Canada</em> it hopes Apple will drop the case before it gets to more expensive discovery and trial phases.</p>

	</div>

</div><!-- .entry-inner -->
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.iphoneincanada.ca/news/apple-legal-action-pear-logo/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24094143</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 18:57:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Audio from Scratch with Go: Extracting Breakpoints]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 135 | Comments 23 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24092371">thread link</a>) | @Insanity
<br/>
August 8, 2020 | https://dylanmeeus.github.io/posts/audio-from-scratch-pt7/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dylanmeeus.github.io/posts/audio-from-scratch-pt7/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            
    
<article>
  <header>
    
    
    



  </header>
  
  
  <div>
    <p>So far everything we’ve done with breakpoints involved us creating a breakpoint file and using this
to automate part of a track. Now we’ll take a look at how we can take an existing track and extract
some breakpoints from this. For this post, we’ll take a look at extracting the amplitudes from the
.wave files, as this is one of the most straightforward properties that we can extract.</p>
<p>There is nothing here that we’ve not seen in the <a href="https://dylanmeeus.github.io/tags/goaudio/">previous
posts</a>, but rather we are going to combine what we’ve
already learned to create a new tool to do this.</p>
<p>In a high level overview, we’ll have to do this:</p>
<ul>
<li>iterate over our frames</li>
<li>record the given amplitude (frame value)</li>
<li>write to breakpoint file</li>
</ul>
<p>In essence this would be simple enough, but we’ll make two small modifications to this
algorithm. First of all, we don’t want to just generate a breakpoint for each frame, this would just
result in a list that is equal to our frame data. We’ll use less space by just taking a snapshot at
a certain interval, e.g every 10ms, and take advantage of
our linear interpolation that happens when looking up the value of a breakpoint at a certain time.</p>
<p>A small extention to our current breakpoint code is that we need to be able to ‘batch’ the samples
into slices of a given time.</p>
<p>If you want to get to the code, everything can be found on
<a href="https://github.com/DylanMeeus/GoAudio/blob/master/cmd/extractbrk/main.go">GitHub</a>.</p>

<p>The BatchSamples function will take a <code>Wave</code> and <code>seconds float64</code> as input, as this gives us enough
data to batch the frames. Given a certain SampleRate, we know how many Samples per Second we are
seeing in the file. With this information, we can find the amount of Frames per Seconds. Although
frames per second is only equal to the samples per second for mono files, but adapting for
multi-channel audio is just a matter of multiplying the SampleSize by the amount of channels.</p>
<p>The SampleSize can thus be expressed as follows: <code>SampleSize = SampleRate * Channels * seconds</code></p>
<p>When we know our sample size, we can split the raw frames into slices of this size.</p>
<div><div>
<table><tbody><tr><td>
<pre><code><span> 1
</span><span> 2
</span><span> 3
</span><span> 4
</span><span> 5
</span><span> 6
</span><span> 7
</span><span> 8
</span><span> 9
</span><span>10
</span><span>11
</span><span>12
</span><span>13
</span><span>14
</span><span>15
</span><span>16
</span><span>17
</span><span>18
</span><span>19
</span><span>20
</span><span>21
</span><span>22
</span><span>23
</span><span>24
</span><span>25
</span><span>26
</span><span>27
</span><span>28
</span><span>29
</span><span>30
</span><span>31
</span></code></pre></td>
<td>
<pre><code data-lang="go"><span>func</span> <span>BatchSamples</span>(<span>data</span> <span>Wave</span>, <span>seconds</span> <span>float64</span>) [][]<span>Frame</span> {
	<span>if</span> <span>seconds</span> <span>==</span> <span>0</span> {
		<span>return</span> [][]<span>Frame</span>{
			<span>data</span>.<span>Frames</span>,
		}
	}

	<span>samples</span> <span>:=</span> <span>data</span>.<span>Frames</span>

	<span>sampleSize</span> <span>:=</span> int(float64(<span>data</span>.<span>SampleRate</span> <span>*</span> <span>data</span>.<span>NumChannels</span>) <span>*</span> float64(<span>seconds</span>))

	<span>batches</span> <span>:=</span> len(<span>samples</span>) <span>/</span> <span>sampleSize</span>
	<span>if</span> len(<span>samples</span>)<span>%</span><span>sampleSize</span> <span>!=</span> <span>0</span> {
		<span>batches</span><span>++</span>
	}

	<span>batched</span> <span>:=</span> make([][]<span>Frame</span>, <span>batches</span>) <span>// this should be round up..
</span><span></span>	<span>for</span> <span>i</span> <span>:=</span> <span>0</span>; <span>i</span> &lt; len(<span>batched</span>); <span>i</span><span>++</span> {
		<span>start</span> <span>:=</span> <span>i</span> <span>*</span> <span>sampleSize</span>
		<span>if</span> <span>start</span> &gt; len(<span>samples</span>) {
			<span>return</span> <span>batched</span>
		}
		<span>maxTake</span> <span>:=</span> <span>i</span><span>*</span><span>sampleSize</span> <span>+</span> <span>sampleSize</span>
		<span>if</span> <span>maxTake</span> <span>&gt;=</span> len(<span>samples</span>)<span>-</span><span>1</span> {
			<span>maxTake</span> = len(<span>samples</span>)
		}
		<span>subs</span> <span>:=</span> <span>samples</span>[<span>start</span>:<span>maxTake</span>]
		<span>batched</span>[<span>i</span>] = <span>subs</span>
	}
	<span>return</span> <span>batched</span>
}
</code></pre></td></tr></tbody></table>
</div>
</div>
<p>Once we can split our frames into batches, we can call <code>BatchSamples(wave,x)</code> to get the requested
batches of a given duration. Then, we can find the max amplitude over all of these and keep
track of this over all batches.</p>
<p>The setup code is the same as usual, where we parse an input file with
<a href="https://github.com/DylanMeeus/GoAudio">GoAudio</a>. Except that now we’ll also send the frames to the
‘BatchSamples’ function. (Error handling ignored for brevity)</p>
<div><div>
<table><tbody><tr><td>
<pre><code><span> 1
</span><span> 2
</span><span> 3
</span><span> 4
</span><span> 5
</span><span> 6
</span><span> 7
</span><span> 8
</span><span> 9
</span><span>10
</span></code></pre></td>
<td>
<pre><code data-lang="go"><span>func</span> <span>main</span>() {
	<span>flag</span>.<span>Parse</span>()
	<span>infile</span> <span>:=</span> <span>*</span><span>input</span>
	<span>outfile</span> <span>:=</span> <span>*</span><span>output</span>
	<span>wave</span>, <span>_</span> <span>:=</span> <span>wav</span>.<span>ReadWaveFile</span>(<span>infile</span>)

        <span>frameDuration</span> <span>:=</span> <span>15.0</span> <span>// 15 ms
</span><span></span>	<span>ticks</span> <span>:=</span> <span>frameDuration</span> <span>/</span> <span>1000.0</span>
	<span>batches</span> <span>:=</span> <span>wav</span>.<span>BatchSamples</span>(<span>wave</span>, <span>ticks</span>)
        <span>...</span>
</code></pre></td></tr></tbody></table>
</div>
</div><p>After doing this, we’ll have our samples batched in 15 ms slices. We’ll continue by iterating over
them and collecting the max amplitude found in each. As we’ll need to write this to an output file
in the end, we’ll store this in a StringBuilder for now.</p>
<p>One more thing we have to keep track of is which time will be inserted in the <code>time:value</code> pair for
the breakpoint file. This time value will be a 15ms increment for each batch.</p>
<p>We continue the main function:</p>
<div><div>
<table><tbody><tr><td>
<pre><code><span> 1
</span><span> 2
</span><span> 3
</span><span> 4
</span><span> 5
</span><span> 6
</span><span> 7
</span><span> 8
</span><span> 9
</span><span>10
</span><span>11
</span><span>12
</span></code></pre></td>
<td>
<pre><code data-lang="go">        <span>...</span>
	<span>strout</span> <span>:=</span> <span>strings</span>.<span>Builder</span>{}
	<span>elapsed</span> <span>:=</span> <span>0.0</span>
	<span>for</span> <span>_</span>, <span>b</span> <span>:=</span> <span>range</span> <span>batches</span> {
		<span>maxa</span> <span>:=</span> <span>maxAmp</span>(<span>b</span>)
		<span>es</span> <span>:=</span> <span>strconv</span>.<span>FormatFloat</span>(<span>elapsed</span>, <span>'f'</span>, <span>8</span>, <span>64</span>)
		<span>fs</span> <span>:=</span> <span>strconv</span>.<span>FormatFloat</span>(<span>maxa</span>, <span>'f'</span>, <span>8</span>, <span>64</span>)
		<span>strout</span>.<span>WriteString</span>(<span>es</span> <span>+</span> <span>":"</span> <span>+</span> <span>fs</span> <span>+</span> <span>"\n"</span>)
		<span>elapsed</span> <span>+=</span> <span>ticks</span>
	}
	<span>ioutil</span>.<span>WriteFile</span>(<span>outfile</span>, []byte(<span>strout</span>.<span>String</span>()), <span>0644</span>)
}
</code></pre></td></tr></tbody></table>
</div>
</div><p>Finally all that is left is to fill our the <code>maxAmp</code> function by iterating over each frame in the
slice and returning the maximum amp.</p>
<div><div>
<table><tbody><tr><td>
<pre><code><span> 1
</span><span> 2
</span><span> 3
</span><span> 4
</span><span> 5
</span><span> 6
</span><span> 7
</span><span> 8
</span><span> 9
</span><span>10
</span><span>11
</span><span>12
</span></code></pre></td>
<td>
<pre><code data-lang="go"><span>func</span> <span>maxAmp</span>(<span>ss</span> []<span>wav</span>.<span>Frame</span>) <span>float64</span> {
	<span>if</span> len(<span>ss</span>) <span>==</span> <span>0</span> {
		<span>return</span> <span>0</span>
	}
	<span>max</span> <span>:=</span> <span>-</span><span>1.0</span> <span>// because they are in range -1 .. 1
</span><span></span>	<span>for</span> <span>_</span>, <span>a</span> <span>:=</span> <span>range</span> <span>ss</span> {
		<span>if</span> float64(<span>a</span>) &gt; <span>max</span> {
			<span>max</span> = float64(<span>a</span>)
		}
	}
	<span>return</span> float64(<span>max</span>)
}
</code></pre></td></tr></tbody></table>
</div>
</div>
<p>When we run this program <code>go run main.go -i input.wav -w 15 -o output.brk</code> we can generate a
breakpoint file. I’ve created a sample waveform (something I’ll write a future blogpost about) with
variable amplitude. You can listen to it <a href="https://dylanmeeus.github.io/audio/part7/input.wav">here</a>.</p>
<p>The extracted breakpoint file can be seen <a href="https://dylanmeeus.github.io/audio/part7/output.brk">here</a>.</p>
<p>Using audacity and your favourite plotting tool you can compare the waveform with what the
breakpoint extractor generated.</p>
<p><img src="https://dylanmeeus.github.io/audio/part7/audacityplot.png" alt="Audacity">
<img src="https://dylanmeeus.github.io/audio/part7/breakpointplot.png" alt="Breakpoint plot"></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/DylanMeeus/GoAudio">GoAudio</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/DylanMeeus/GoAudio/blob/master/cmd/extractbrk/main.go">Breakpoint extraction program</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/DylanMeeus/GoAudio/blob/master/wave/utils.go#L6">Batching Code</a></li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>If you liked this and want to know when I write new posts, the best way to keep up to date is by <a href="https://twitter.com/DylanMeeus">following me on
twitter</a>.</p>

  </div>
  




  

  
    


</article>


        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dylanmeeus.github.io/posts/audio-from-scratch-pt7/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24092371</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 15:29:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Cheap FPGA Development Boards]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 115 | Comments 50 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24091991">thread link</a>) | @homarp
<br/>
August 8, 2020 | https://joelw.id.au/FPGA/CheapFPGADevelopmentBoards | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://joelw.id.au/FPGA/CheapFPGADevelopmentBoards">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="wikitext">

<p>I bought Avnet's $49 Spartan 3A development board but it was discontinued not long afterward - right about the time when I decided I needed a few dozen more. I've since done some extensive research (thanks, Google!) to find a comparable thrifty thrill.
</p>
<p>When choosing a development board, consider what you get with it and what you want to use it for. FPGAs are ideal for use with high speed peripherals, and in general it is much easier to buy a board that contains the part you want, rather than trying to add one on later (and inevitably giving up and upgrading to a more capable board). Examples of things you might want, and are quite difficult to add yourself:
</p>
<ul><li>Gigabit Ethernet
</li><li>HDMI/DVI
</li><li>PCI/PCI Express
</li><li>External non-serial memory (DDR/Flash etc.)
</li></ul><p>Things that are relatively easy to add, and are not so much of a big deal to wire up yourself.
</p>
<ul><li>MMC/SD cards
</li><li>Character (e.g. 16x2) LCDs
</li><li>Anything I2C/SPI and relatively low speed
</li><li>VGA (with low colour depth)
</li></ul><p>I like having a board with many (at least 8) SPST switches and LEDs, and momentary buttons. Unlike a microcontroller where it's relatively easy to spit debug information out of a serial port or to an LCD with a single C function call, debugging FPGA designs is a bit harder. LEDs  provide a zero fuss way to break out internal signals for visualisation - if you're tracking the progress of a complex state machine, you can light up an LED when it gets to a certain point without adding any extra logic. While these are easy enough to add yourself, I find that it's better to get a board that has them so that you don't waste valuable user IOs or waste time investigating failures caused by your terrible soldering skills.
</p>
<p>Some manufacturers promote a standard form factor for add-ons, notably Digilent with their very wide range of <a href="https://store.digilentinc.com/pmod-modules-connectors/">Pmods</a>, the Papilio One's <a href="http://papilio.cc/index.php?n=Papilio.Wings">Wings</a>, and Arduino shields.
</p>
<p>If you would like to connect high speed devices (above 10-20 MHz) to your FPGA, make sure your board has an interface connector that supports the speeds you'll be using. Look for ground wires interspersed regularly between signal wires, high speed connectors (not just 0.1" headers), PCB trace length equalisation, and impedance control. Few of the cheap boards bother with any of these.
</p>
<p>FPGAs can be a bit daunting, so check that the manufacturer provides:
</p>
<ul><li>Schematic diagram
</li><li>A reference manual, describing all of the on-board peripherals
</li><li>A guide to getting started, if you've never used an FPGA before
</li><li>A reference design that exercises all on-board peripherals.
</li></ul><p>Reference designs can either be HDL or microcontroller-based, but in recent boards, most manufacturers seem to be moving to the latter. Bear this in mind if you don't have a license for the microcontroller and environment (e.g. Xilinx EDK/SDK is not free), as the code will be difficult to port to HDL.
</p>
<p>If you're a beginner, you may benefit from buying a board that has a companion textbook which has been written specifically for the board in mind, and describes each of the peripherals and how to interface with them. Popular boards with larger user communities may also be worth considering above cheaper options. The most popular Xilinx boards are those made by Xilinx (none of them cheap enough to be listed here), Digilent and Avnet. Terasic seem to make the most popular Altera boards.
</p>

<p>A long-standing complaint with vendor FPGA design tools is that they are generally enormous, complicated, slow, buggy, closed source, and are either expensive or have annoying license requirements. The open source community has made great progress in recent years to reimplement parts or all of the FPGA design toolchain and to address all of these concerns.
</p>
<p>FPGA devices which are currently either partially or fully supported by open source tools include:
</p>
<ul><li>Xilinx Spartan 6
</li><li>Xilinx Series 7 (Artix 7, Kintex 7, Virtex 7, Zynq with Series 7 Fabric)
</li><li>Xilinx Ultrascale(+)
</li><li>Lattice iCE40
</li><li>Lattice ECP5
</li><li>QuickLogic EOS S3 and PolarPro3
</li></ul><p>Some tools to check out include:
</p>
<ul><li><a href="https://github.com/enjoy-digital/litex">LiteX</a> - A Python-based SoC builder
<ul><li><a href="https://github.com/litex-hub">LiteX Hub</a> - collaborative FPGA projects based on LiteX
</li><li><a href="https://github.com/timvideos/litex-buildenv">LiteX-BuildEnv</a> - An environment for building LiteX-based FPGA designs
</li></ul></li><li><a href="http://www.clifford.at/yosys/">Yosys</a> - Verilog synthesis tool
</li><li><a href="https://github.com/YosysHQ/nextpnr">nextpnr</a> - a vendor neutral, timing driven place and route tool
</li><li><a href="https://symbiflow.github.io/">SymbiFlow</a> - an umbrella project for FPGA architecture definitions
</li></ul><p><a href="https://twitter.com/mithro">Tim 'mithro' Ansell</a> has an open offer to send FPGA hardware to anyone who has time to to contribute to open source FPGA projects but doesn't have any hardware.
</p>

<h4>Xilinx</h4>
<h5>Zynq</h5>
<p>Xilinx's Zynq parts are supported by their Vivado high level synthesis design suite and include a dual-core ARM Cortex-A9, USB 2.0, and Gigabit Ethernet.
</p>

<table><tbody><tr><th>Name</th><th>Price</th><th>Device</th><th>Notes</th></tr>
<tr><td><a href="https://www.aliexpress.com/item/4000042572307.html">Zynq 7000 ZYNQ7010 development board</a></td><td>$42</td><td>Zynq 7010</td><td>A no-name board, apparently pulled from some equipment, which provides 256MB DDR, 128M NAND flash, SD card, optocoupled inputs, 1 button, 2 LEDs, and 42 I/Os. Some more information is available in this <a href="https://www.eevblog.com/forum/fpga/anyone-played-with-these-cheap-$50-zynq-boards/">EEVBlog thread</a>.</td></tr>
<tr><td><a href="https://www.aliexpress.com/item/4000323573953.html">QMTECH Zynq7000 Starter Kit</a></td><td>$56</td><td>Zynq 7010</td><td>512MB DDR3, micro SD slot, 100 Mbit Ethernet, two LEDs, 62 length-matched and paired FPGA I/Os and 15 processor I/Os. Some documentation is available at <a href="http://www.chinaqmtech.com/xilinx_zynq_soc">QMTech's site</a> and there are some observations in this <a href="https://www.eevblog.com/forum/fpga/anyone-played-with-these-cheap-$50-zynq-boards/">EEVBlog thread</a>, where there are some complaints about a lack of decoupling.</td></tr>
<tr><td><a href="http://shop.trenz-electronic.de/en/TE0722-01-DIPFORTy1-Soft-Propeller">DIPFORTy1 "Soft Propeller"</a></td><td>EUR 59</td><td>Zynq 7010</td><td>A DIP-40 sized board that is designed to be pin-compatible with the Parallax Propeller chip. It has 16MB of flash, 46 I/Os, one RGB LED, one user LED, micro SD socket, and a proximity/light sensor.</td></tr>
<tr><td><a href="https://world.taobao.com/item/607165559105.htm?spm=a21wu.11804641-tw.0.0.4263253ekAFbba">Sipeed Tang Hex</a></td><td>$70-90</td><td>Zynq 7020</td><td>1 GB LPDDR3, 2Gb Flash NAND, 100Mbit Ethernet, four USB 2.0 ports, a TF slot, and 15 GPIOs.</td></tr>
<tr><td><a href="http://zedboard.org/product/minized">MiniZed</a></td><td>$89</td><td>Zynq 7Z007S</td><td>Includes a single ARM A9, 512MB DDR3L, 128Mb flash and 8GB eMMC, USB host, USB-JTAG, and USB-UART, 802.11b/g/n Wi-Fi, Bluetooth 4.1, and BLE, Arduino shield connector and two PMODs (38 total I/Os), accelerometer, temperature, and MEMS microphone sensors, one button, one switch, and two bi-color LEDs</td></tr>
<tr><td><a href="http://www.myirtech.com/list.asp?id=502">MYIR Z-turn Board</a></td><td>$99/$119</td><td>Zynq 7010/ 7020</td><td>1GB DDR, 16MB flash, TF socket, gigabit Ethernet, CAN, USB2.0 OTG, USB-UART, HDMI output, 90 or 106 user I/Os (with 39 LVDS pairs), accelerometer and temperature sensor, JTGA, two buttons, 4 switches, four LEDs, and a buzzer. An "IO Cape" breakout board ($35) provides three Pmod connectors, camera and LCD connectors, and 0.1" header I/O pins.</td></tr>
<tr><td><a href="https://www.crowdsupply.com/krtkl/snickerdoodle">snickerdoodle</a></td><td>$115/$245</td><td>Zynq 7010/7020</td><td>A Zynq board with 155-180 I/Os, 512MB-1GB DDR, 16MB flash, micro SD, 802.11n WiFi, and Bluetooth 4.0. A range of base-boards and add-on boards are also available, providing gigabit Ethernet, HDMI in/out, USB, JTAG, 0.1" I/Os, and more.</td></tr>
<tr><td><a href="http://www.tul.com.tw/ProductsPYNQ-Z2.html">PYNQ Z2</a></td><td>$119</td><td>Zynq 7020</td><td>512MB DDR3, 128 Mb flash, microSD, gigabit Ethernet, HDMI source and sink, USB for JTAG, UART and OTG host, I2S audio I/O, 4 SPST buttons, 2 SPDT switches, 4 LEDs and 2 RGB LEDs, two PMODs, and Arduino and Raspberry Pi connectors (around 60 I/Os, plus 6 analog inputs)</td></tr>
<tr><td><a href="http://www.parallella.org/buy/">Parallella-16 Micro-Server</a></td><td>$126</td><td>Zynq 7010</td><td>Includes a dual ARM A9. Also available on the board are the Epiphany 16-core CPU Accelerator, 1GB RAM, 126 Mb flash, micro SD, and gigabit Ethernet.</td></tr>
<tr><td><a href="http://www.parallella.org/buy/">Parallella-16 Desktop</a></td><td>$158</td><td>Zynq 7010</td><td>Expands on the Micro-Server and adds high speed expansion ports with 24 GPIOs (and other Epiphany signals), HDMI, and USB 2.0 host.</td></tr>
<tr><td><a href="https://store.digilentinc.com/zybo-z7-zynq-7000-arm-fpga-soc-development-board/">Digilent ZYBO Z7</a></td><td>$199/299</td><td>Zynq 7010/7020</td><td>1GB DDR3 RAM, HDMI source/sink with CEC, VGA, gigabit Ethernet, USB JTAG, UART and 2.0 host/OTG, MIPI CSI-2, audio I/O, 6 buttons, 4 switches, 6 or 7 LEDs, and 40 I/Os (5 PMODs), including analogue inputs, and microSD</td></tr>
<tr><td><a href="http://www.zedboard.org/product/microzed">MicroZed</a></td><td>$199</td><td>Zynq 7010</td><td>1GB, 128 Mb flash, SD card, gigabit Ethernet, USB 2.0, 100 I/Os (48 LVDS pairs) and 2 PMODs, 1 LED and 1 switch</td></tr>
<tr><td><a href="https://allaboutfpga.com/product/edge-zynq-soc-fpga-development-board/">EDGE ZYNQ</a></td><td>$214</td><td>Zynq 7010</td><td>512MB, 128 Mb flash, micro SD, gigabit Ethernet, 802.11/b/g/n WiFi and Bluetooth 4.2/LE, USB for JTAG, UART, and OTG, HDMI Tx/Rx, VGA, stereo audio output, light and temperature sensors, 4*7 Seg LEDs, 5 LEDs, 4 slide switches, 31 PL I/Os and 4 PS I/Os. A 2x16 LCD module is included, and camera and TFT LCD modules are available.</td></tr>
</tbody></table>
<h5>Artix-7</h5>
<p>Artix parts are becoming increasingly common in inexpensive development boards, taking the position previously occupied by the Spartan-6 in Xilinx's lineup, though they are only supplied in BGA packages.
</p>

<table><tbody><tr><th>Name</th><th>Price</th><th>Device</th><th>Notes</th></tr>
<tr><td>QMTECH Artix 7 DDR3 Core Board</td><td>$50/80</td><td><a href="https://www.aliexpress.com/item/1000006630084.html">Artix 35T</a>/<a href="https://www.aliexpress.com/item/4000170003461.html">100T</a></td><td>256MB DDR3, 16MB SPI flash, 2 switches, 3 LEDs, JTAG header, and 108 length-matched I/Os. It's also compatible with a daughterboard which provides PMODs, USB-UART, camera interface, VGA, gigabit Ethernet, and more. There are reports that decoupling is insufficient, so beware.</td></tr>
<tr><td><a href="http://store.digilentinc.com/cmod-a7-breadboardable-artix-7-fpga-module/">Digilent Cmod A7</a></td><td>$75/89</td><td>Artix 15T/45T</td><td>A breadboardable module with 512KB SRAM, 4MB SPI flash, USB-JTAG and USB-Serial, 3 LEDs, 2 buttons, 52 digital I/Os, and 2 analog inputs.</td></tr>
<tr><td><a href="https://perfv.org/">Perf-V</a></td><td>$79</td><td>Artix 35T</td><td>4 switches, 5 buttons, 7 LEDs, JTAG 256MB DDR3, 16MB flash, Arduino shield connector, one PMOD, and some sort of high speed connector which supports expansion boards with HDMI and VGA. Larger FPGA sizes will apparently be available too.</td></tr>
<tr><td><a href="https://rhsresearch.com/collections/all/products/litefury">LiteFury</a></td><td>$99</td><td>Artix 100T</td><td>A PCIe x4 gen 2 development board with an NVMe (2280 Key M) connector. It has 256MB DDR3, 128 Mb flash, 4 LEDs, and 12 I/Os (including four LVDS pairs).</td></tr>
<tr><td><a href="https://alchitry.com/collections/all/products/alchitry-au-fpga-development-board">Alchitry Au</a></td><td>$99.99</td><td>Artix 35T</td><td>256MB DDR3, 102 digital I/Os, 9 differential analog inputs (8 shared with digital I/O), 8 LEDs, 1 button, USB-UART, and USB-C for power and programming. It has high density I/O connectors, but companion prototype/breaking ($10) and I/O with switches, LEDs, 7-Segs ($25) boards.</td></tr>
<tr><td><a href="https://www.aliexpress.com/item/4000170042795.html">QMTECH Artix-7 Wukong Board</a></td><td>$100</td><td>Artix 100T</td><td>16MB flash, 256MB DDR3, 3 switches, 4 LEDs, gigabit Ethernet, HDMI output, USB-UART, GTP transceiver interface, 2 PMODs, and 40 I/IOs. There are reports that decoupling is insufficient, so beware.</td></tr>
<tr><td><a href="https://store.digilentinc.com/arty-a7-artix-7-fpga-development-board-for-makers-and-hobbyists/">Arty A7</a></td><td>$129/249</td><td>Artix 35T/100T</td><td>An inexpensive way to get into the Artix parts. It provides 256 MB DDR, 16MB flash, 10/100 Ethernet, USB-UART/JTAG, four PMODs, an Arduino shield connector (a total of 62 I/Os?), 4 switches, 4 buttons, 8 LEDs (4 of them RGB), and a one year licence for Vivado Design Edition.</td></tr>
<tr><td><a href="https://numato.com/product/mimas-a7-artix-7-fpga-development-board-with-ddr-sdram-and-gigabit-ethernet">Numato Mimas A7</a></td><td>$149</td><td>Artix 50T</td><td>128 Mb flash, 2Gb DDR, …</td></tr></tbody></table></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://joelw.id.au/FPGA/CheapFPGADevelopmentBoards">https://joelw.id.au/FPGA/CheapFPGADevelopmentBoards</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://joelw.id.au/FPGA/CheapFPGADevelopmentBoards</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24091991</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 14:49:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Smartphone Hardening non-root Guide 2.0 (for normal people)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 99 | Comments 24 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24091709">thread link</a>) | @URfejk
<br/>
August 8, 2020 | https://dev.lemmy.ml/post/38770 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dev.lemmy.ml/post/38770">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dev.lemmy.ml/post/38770</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24091709</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 14:08:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A website to make 3D geometry shapes out of paper]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 99 | Comments 9 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24091297">thread link</a>) | @bilinualcom
<br/>
August 8, 2020 | https://felixboiii.github.io/paper-plotter/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://felixboiii.github.io/paper-plotter/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                
                <p>This website is a hobby project of mine. I don't track you or make use of any cookies. </p>

            </div><div>
                
                <p>Made a cool function?
                    found bugs, have cool ideas, any questions or just want to say something. Please email me:
                    thebluecodecat@gmail.com</p>
            </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://felixboiii.github.io/paper-plotter/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24091297</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 12:57:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Formulog: ML + Datalog + SMT]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 123 | Comments 19 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24091096">thread link</a>) | @matt_d
<br/>
August 8, 2020 | http://www.weaselhat.com/2020/08/07/formulog-ml-datalog-smt/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.weaselhat.com/2020/08/07/formulog-ml-datalog-smt/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-835">	
		<!-- .entry-header -->

		<div>
		
<p>If you read a description of a static analysis in a paper, what might you find? There’ll be some cute model of a language. Maybe some inference rules describing the analysis itself, but those rules probably rely on a variety of helper functions. These days, the analysis likely involves some logical reasoning: about the terms in the language, the branches conditionals might take, and so on.</p>



<p>What makes a language good for implementing such an analysis? You’d want a variety of features:</p>



<ul><li>Algebraic data types to model the language AST.</li><li>Logic programming for cleanly specifying inference rules.</li><li>Pure functional code for writing the helper functions.</li><li>An SMT solver for answering logical queries.</li></ul>



<p><a href="https://people.seas.harvard.edu/~bembenek/">Aaron Bembenek</a>, <a href="https://people.seas.harvard.edu/~chong/">Steve Chong</a>, and I have developed a design that hits the sweet spot of those four points: given Datalog as a core, you add constructors, pure ML, and a type-safe interface to SMT. If you set things up just right, the system is a powerful and ergonomic way to write static analyses.</p>



<p><a href="https://github.com/HarvardPL/formulog">Formulog</a> is our prototype implementation of our design; our <a href="https://cs.pomona.edu/~michael/papers/formulog_sub2020.pdf">paper on Formulog and its design</a> was just conditionally accepted to <a href="https://2020.splashcon.org/track/splash-2020-oopsla">OOPSLA 2020</a>. To give a sense of why I’m excited, let me excerpt from our <a href="https://github.com/HarvardPL/formulog/blob/master/examples/liquid_types.flg">simple liquid type checker</a>. Weighing in under 400 very short lines, it’s a nice showcase of how expressive Formulog is. (Our paper discusses substantially more complex examples.)</p>



<pre>type base =
&nbsp;&nbsp;| base_bool

type typ = 
&nbsp;&nbsp;| typ_tvar(tvar)
&nbsp;&nbsp;| typ_fun(var, typ, typ)
&nbsp;&nbsp;| typ_forall(tvar, typ)
&nbsp;&nbsp;| typ_ref(var, base, exp)

and exp = 
&nbsp;&nbsp;| exp_var(var)
&nbsp;&nbsp;| exp_bool(bool)
&nbsp;&nbsp;| exp_op(op)
&nbsp;&nbsp;| exp_lam(var, typ, exp)
&nbsp;&nbsp;| exp_tlam(tvar, exp)
&nbsp;&nbsp;| exp_app(exp, exp)
&nbsp;&nbsp;| exp_tapp(exp, typ)
</pre>



<p>ADTs let you define your AST in a straightforward way. Here, <code>bool</code> is our only base type, but we could add more. Let’s look at some of the inference rules:</p>



<pre>(* subtyping *)
output sub(ctx, typ, typ)

(* bidirectional typing rules *)
output synth(ctx, exp, typ)
output check(ctx, exp, typ)

(* subtyping between refinement types is implication *)
sub(G, typ_ref(X, B, E1), typ_ref(Y, B, E2)) :-
&nbsp;&nbsp;wf_ctx(G),
&nbsp;&nbsp;exp_subst(Y, exp_var(X), E2) = E2prime,
&nbsp;&nbsp;encode_ctx(G, PhiG),
&nbsp;&nbsp;encode_exp(E1, Phi1),
&nbsp;&nbsp;encode_exp(E2prime, Phi2),
&nbsp;&nbsp;is_valid(`PhiG /\ Phi1 ==&gt; Phi2`).

(* lambda and application synth rules *)
synth(G, exp_lam(X, T1, E), T) :-
&nbsp;&nbsp;wf_typ(G, T1),
&nbsp;&nbsp;synth(ctx_var(G, X, T1), E, T2),
&nbsp;&nbsp;typ_fun(X, T1, T2) = T.

synth(G, exp_app(E1, E2), T) :-
&nbsp;&nbsp;synth(G, E1, typ_fun(X, T1, T2)),
&nbsp;&nbsp;check(G, E2, T1),
&nbsp;&nbsp;typ_subst(X, E2, T2) = T.

(* the only checking rule *)
check(G, E, T) :-
&nbsp;&nbsp;synth(G, E, Tprime),
&nbsp;&nbsp;sub(G, Tprime, T).</pre>



<p>First, we declare our relations—that is, the (typed) inference rules we’ll be using. We show the most interesting case of subtyping: refinement implication. Several helper relations (<code>wf_ctx</code>, <code>encode_*</code>) and helper functions (<code>exp_subst</code>) patch things together. The typing rules below follow a similar pattern, mixing the <code>synth</code> and <code>check</code> bidirectional typing relations with calls to helper functions like <code>typ_subst</code>.</p>



<pre>fun exp_subst(X: var, E : exp, Etgt : exp) : exp =
&nbsp;&nbsp;match Etgt with
&nbsp;&nbsp;| exp_var(Y) =&gt; if X = Y then E else Etgt
&nbsp;&nbsp;| exp_bool(_) =&gt; Etgt
&nbsp;&nbsp;| exp_op(_) =&gt; Etgt
&nbsp;&nbsp;| exp_lam(Y, Tlam, Elam) =&gt;
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;let Yfresh = 
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;fresh_for(Y, X::append(typ_freevars(Tlam), exp_freevars(Elam)))
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;in
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;let Elamfresh = 
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;if Y = Yfresh
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;then Elam
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;else exp_subst(Y, exp_var(Yfresh), Elam)
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;in
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;exp_lam(Yfresh,
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;typ_subst(X, E, Tlam),
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Elamfresh)
&nbsp;&nbsp;| exp_tlam(A, Etlam) =&gt;
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;exp_tlam(A, exp_subst(X, E, Etlam))
&nbsp;&nbsp;| exp_app(E1, E2) =&gt; 
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;exp_app(exp_subst(X, E, E1), exp_subst(X, E, E2))
&nbsp;&nbsp;| exp_tapp(Etapp, T) =&gt; 
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;exp_tapp(exp_subst(X, E, Etapp), typ_subst(X, E, T))
&nbsp;&nbsp;end</pre>



<p>Expression substitution might be boring, but it shows the ML fragment well enough. It’s more or less the usual ML, though functions need to have pure interfaces, and we have a few restrictions in place to keep typing simple in our prototype.</p>



<p>There’s lots of fun stuff that doesn’t make it into this example: not only can relations call functions, but functions can examine relations (so long as everything is stratified). Hiding inside <code>fresh_for</code> is a clever approach to name generation that guarantees freshness… but is also deterministic and won’t interfere with parallel execution. The <a href="https://cs.pomona.edu/~michael/papers/formulog_sub2020.pdf">draft paper</a> has more substantial examples.</p>



<p>We’re not the first to combine logic programming and SMT. What makes our design a sweet spot is that it doesn’t let SMT get in the way of Datalog’s straightforward and powerful execution model. Datalog execution is readily parallelizable; the magic sets transformation can turn Datalog’s exhaustive, bottom-up search into a goal-directed one. It’s not news that Datalog can turn these tricks—<a href="https://bitbucket.org/yanniss/doop/src/master/">Yiannis Smaragdakis has been saying it for years</a>!—but integrating Datalog cleanly with ML functions and SMT is new. Check out the <a href="https://cs.pomona.edu/~michael/papers/formulog_sub2020.pdf">draft paper</a> for a detailed related work comparison. While our design is, in the end, not so complicated, getting there was hard.</p>



<p>Relatedly, we have also have an <a href="https://cs.pomona.edu/~michael/papers/iclp2020_extabs.pdf">extended abstract at ICLP 2020</a>, detailing some experiments in using incremental solving modes from Formulog. You might worry that Datalog’s BFS (or heuristic) strategy wouldn’t work with an SMT solver’s push/pop (i.e., DFS) assertion stack—but a few implementation tricks and <code>check-sat-assuming</code> indeed provide speedups.</p>
			</div><!-- .entry-content -->
		
	<!-- .entry-footer -->
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.weaselhat.com/2020/08/07/formulog-ml-datalog-smt/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24091096</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 12:23:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Bootstrap finance and the cost of other people's money [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 104 | Comments 33 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24090104">thread link</a>) | @sturza
<br/>
August 8, 2020 | http://library.cust.edu.pk/teacher_resources/Cases&Articles/Entrepreneurship/BootstrapFinance-TheArtofStart-Ups.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://library.cust.edu.pk/teacher_resources/Cases&Articles/Entrepreneurship/BootstrapFinance-TheArtofStart-Ups.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://library.cust.edu.pk/teacher_resources/Cases&amp;Articles/Entrepreneurship/BootstrapFinance-TheArtofStart-Ups.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24090104</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 08:43:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Alcohol as a social technology to check the trustworthiness of others (2014)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 346 | Comments 386 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24088202">thread link</a>) | @searchableguy
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://hndex.org/7798063 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://hndex.org/7798063">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
<header>

<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=7798063" target="_blank">comments</a> <a href="https://plus.google.com/+KajSotala/posts/hofuxyXz78j" target="_blank">original article</a></header>
<p>Ohhh, never thought of this hypothesis: that the act of getting
drunk together might be a social technology that helps us verify
the trustworthiness of others by inhibiting their higher cognitive
functions and thus making it harder to consciously fake things.
That would make sense.</p>
<p>&gt; To enhance our natural thin-slicing abilities, humans have
therefore also developed various cultural practices that make these
instant assessments more reliable. These techniques take advantage
of the fact that deception is fundamentally a cold-cognition act
and relies on cognitive control centers. This means that if we can
impair the cognitive control abilities of people we're trying to
judge, we’ll do a better job of sussing them out: they will
be less able to confuse our cheater-detection systems.</p>
<p>&gt; In one study that has proven enormously useful to law
enforcement agencies, researchers found that police officers could
significantly improve their ability to detect false statements if
suspects were asked to give their alibis in reverse order, starting
with the most recent event and working their way back. This is not
the way we normally tell stories, so being forced to do it
increases cognitive load. Dishonest suspects, it turns out, are
less effective liars if you handicap their conscious minds in this
way.</p>
<p>&gt; This reverse-order alibi technique is a great tool for law
enforcement but not terribly practical when evaluating a potential
business partner or deciding if the people you’re about to
make a peace treaty with are being sincere. There are other ways to
achieve the same effect, though. The police study aimed to reduce
subjects’ cognitive control ability by increasing the
load-adding more weight, as it were. Alternately, you can keep the
load constant but decrease cognitive control ability-weaken the
mental muscles-by suppressing cognitive control centers. One way to
do this is transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS), which involves
applying a powerful magnetic force to the appropriate region of the
skull. TMS, however, is a very recent technology and not exactly
widely available. Also, in most cultures it’s considered bad
form to shock the heads of new acquaintances with huge magnets.</p>
<p>&gt; A much more low-tech and socially acceptable way to produce
the same effect is to get someone completely wasted. As we
discussed in chapter 6, one of the primary effects of alcohol and
other intoxicants is to "downregulate," or temporarily paralyze,
areas of the prefrontal cortex associated with cognitive control. A
couple shots of tequila is the liquid equivalent of a nice jolt of
TMS. It’s therefore no accident that intoxicants of various
sorts are frequently employed by human beings as social lubricants.
Alcohol, kava, cannabis, magic mushrooms, you name it: any
intoxicant that people can get their hands on quickly comes to play
a central role in social occasions, both formal and informal. In
ancient China, no major treaty was signed without first bringing
everyone together in an extended, alcohol-soaked banquet. In fact,
this is one feature of Chinese culture that has not changed a bit
in over four thousand years. Any modern businessperson hoping to
ink a deal with Chinese partners had better get his or her liver in
shape first.</p>
<p>&gt; On a less formal level, this is no doubt why intoxicants
are a universal feature of all sorts of human social gatherings,
from casual cocktail parties to fraternity mixers. Not only is
getting drunk pleasant, it also typically causes people to get
along more freely and easily (at least to a certain point, after
which the drunken fights break out). Intoxication enhances
cooperation in at least two ways. First of all, it reduces social
faking by inhibiting cognitive control centers. Second, if we all
get drunk together, we create a situation of mutual vulnerability
that makes trust easier to establish. Getting drunk is essentially
an act of mental disarmament. In the same way that shaking right
hands with someone assures them that you’re not holding a
weapon, downing a few tequila shots is like checking your
prefrontal cortex at the door. See? No cognitive control. You can
trust me.</p>
<p>Excerpt From: Slingerland, Edward. "Trying Not to Try." Crown
Publishing Group, 2014-03-04. ﻿</p>
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://hndex.org/7798063</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24088202</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 01:32:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
