<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 16:35:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 16:35:32 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Chaos Ink]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 312 | Comments 66 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24813921">thread link</a>) | @parisianka
<br/>
October 17, 2020 | https://dev.scottdarby.com/chaos-ink/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dev.scottdarby.com/chaos-ink/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dev.scottdarby.com/chaos-ink/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24813921</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 22:27:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[We deleted the production database by accident]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 272 | Comments 279 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24813795">thread link</a>) | @caspii
<br/>
October 17, 2020 | https://keepthescore.co/blog/posts/deleting_the_production_database/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://keepthescore.co/blog/posts/deleting_the_production_database/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <div>
        <div>

          


<article>
  <header>
    <h2 dir="auto"><a href="https://keepthescore.co/blog/posts/deleting_the_production_database/">We deleted the production database by accident 💥</a></h2>
    <p><time datetime="2020-10-17T00:00:00+02:00">Sat Oct 17, 2020</time> by Caspar</p>
  </header>
  

<p>Today at around 10:45pm CET, after a couple of glasses of red wine, we deleted the production database by accident 😨. Over 300.00 scoreboards and their associated data were vaporised in an instant.</p>

<p>Thankfully our database is a managed database from DigitalOcean, which means that DigitalOcean automatically do backups once a day. After 5 minutes of hand-wringing and panic, we took the website into maintenance mode and worked on restoring a backup. At around 11:15pm CET, 30 minutes after the disaster, we went back online, however 7 hours of scoreboard data was gone forever 😵.</p>

<p>To be precise, any scoreboards created or scores added on the 17th October 2020 between 15:47 CET and 23:21 CET have been lost. We are extremely sorry about this.</p>

<p><img src="https://keepthescore.co/blog/disaster.jpg" alt="Blue green tennis"></p>

<h2 id="what-happened">What happened?</h2>

<p>It’s tempting to blame the disaster on the couple of glasses of red wine. However, the function that wiped the database was written whilst sober. It’s a function that deletes the local database and creates all the required tables from scratch. This evening, whilst doing some late evening coding, the function connected to the production database and wiped it. Why? This is something we’re still trying to figure out.</p>

<p>Here is the code that caused the disaster:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="python"><span>def</span> <span>database_model_create</span>():
    <span>"""Only works on localhost to prevent catastrophe"""</span>
    database <span>=</span> config<span>.</span>DevelopmentConfig<span>.</span>DB_DATABASE
    user <span>=</span> config<span>.</span>DevelopmentConfig<span>.</span>DB_USERNAME
    password <span>=</span> config<span>.</span>DevelopmentConfig<span>.</span>DB_PASSWORD
    port <span>=</span> config<span>.</span>DevelopmentConfig<span>.</span>DB_PORT
    local_db <span>=</span> PostgresqlDatabase(database<span>=</span>database, user<span>=</span>user, password<span>=</span>password, host<span>=</span><span>'localhost'</span>, port<span>=</span>port)
    local_db<span>.</span>drop_tables([Game, Player, Round, Score, Order])
    local_db<span>.</span>create_tables([Game, Player, Round, Score, Order])
    <span>print</span>(<span>'Initialized the local database.'</span>)</code></pre></div>
<p>Note that <code>host</code> is hardcoded to <code>localhost</code>. This means it should <strong>never connect to any machine other than the developer machine</strong>.  Also: <strong>of course</strong> we use different passwords and users for development and production. We’re too tired to figure it out right now.</p>

<h2 id="what-have-we-learned-why-won-t-this-happen-again">What have we learned? Why won’t this happen again?</h2>

<p>We’ve learned that having a function that deletes your database is too dangerous to have lying around. The problem is, you can never really test the safety mechanisms properly, because testing it would mean pointing a gun at the production database.</p>

<p>We’ve learned that having a backup which allows a quick recovery is absolutely essential. Thanks DigitalOcean, for making this part reliable and simple.</p>

<p>We’ve learned that even a disaster can have some up-sides. This blog post generated a lot of interest. When life gives you citrus fruits, and so on.</p>

<p>The truth is, we can never be 100% sure that something like this won’t happen again. Computers are just too complex and there are days when the complexity gremlins win. However, we will figure out what went wrong and ensure that this <em>particular</em> error doesn’t happen again.</p>

<h2 id="some-perspective">Some perspective</h2>

<p>Thankfully nobody’s job is at risk due to this disaster. The founder is not going to fire the developer – because they are one and the same person.</p>

<p>Also, this webapp is just a side-project. It’s not the software that’s running a power-plant. Nonetheless, we have many users, some of them paying customers, and we try our very best to make them happy. Today we let those users down and that hurts.</p>

<p>The wonderful irony is that not 4 days earlier we tweeted a <em>hilarious</em> meme about deleting your production database:
</p><blockquote><p lang="und" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/mOlFqWal08">pic.twitter.com/mOlFqWal08</a></p>— Keepthescore.co (@keep_the_score) <a href="https://twitter.com/keep_the_score/status/1315552102299598851?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 12, 2020</a></blockquote>



<p>Again, we are very sorry. Good night.</p>

<p>PS This generated some <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24813795">great discussion on Hackernews</a>.</p>

<p><span>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@darmfield?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Dawn Armfield</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/disaster?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Unsplash</a></span></p>


  

  
  <hr>
  
  

</article> 



        </div> <!-- /.blog-main -->

        


      </div> <!-- /.row -->
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://keepthescore.co/blog/posts/deleting_the_production_database/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24813795</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 22:09:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Themed days, Timeboxing and why you should use them]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 55 | Comments 36 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24813440">thread link</a>) | @jamalx31
<br/>
October 17, 2020 | https://www.jamalx31.com/post/themed-days-timeboxing-and-why-you-should-use-them | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.jamalx31.com/post/themed-days-timeboxing-and-why-you-should-use-them">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Have you ever wondered how Elon Musk is running two billion-dollar companies at once? Musk is an interesting example of someone who manages his time so well that he can work 100 hours a week and still manage to take time out for his hobbies, family, and even Twitter! So, how does he do it?<br></p><p>Musk is known for using timeboxing methods to manage his time effectively. He uses timeboxing from the moment he wakes up in the morning where he assigns each time block to a certain task that he needs to accomplish on a given day. This timeboxing method can be used for any tasks ranging from writing emails, scheduling meetings, meditating or anything that you would like to do on a particular day.<br></p><p>Before I began using timeboxing, I learned about another technique called <strong>Themed days</strong>. I decided to combine both to maximize productivity. Themed days are <strong>strategically planned days in your calendar, which are entirely dedicated to one single thing or tasks from the same category</strong>. While timeboxing is <strong>to allocate a certain amount of time to a task in advance and then complete it within that time frame</strong>. The idea behind these two techniques is to eliminate context switching or minimize it.<br></p><p>How to use them? Very simple.<br></p><p>Make a list of 4-5 things you want to focus on this week. For example:</p><ol role="list"><li>☎️ Talk to 5 customers</li><li>💻️ Implement features X,Y &amp; Z</li><li>🎨 Redesign landing page</li><li>✍️ Write a blog post about productivity<br></li></ol><p>These are going to be your “themes”. Now open your calendar and assign a day for each one. Let’s say you want to work Monday and Tuesday on coding the missing features. Use Wednesday to interview customers, etc, you got the idea. (Tip: give each theme a color or an emoji 😉️)<br></p><p>Themed days could be super useful if you already have a day job and are trying to make time for your side hustle. Instead of trying to work on it one hour each day after your day job when you already feel exhausted, you dedicate a whole day for your side project.</p><p>With the one hour a day approach, the chance you could skip the scheduled hour is higher; <strong>with themed days, maintaining self-discipline is much easier.</strong></p><h2>Timeboxing</h2><p>To spice things up a little bit, you should use time timeboxing. Once you finished assigning themes and each day has one:</p><ol role="list"><li>Zoom in on each day</li><li>Add sub-tasks for that day’s theme</li><li>Add a time estimate to each task, and frame it with a start and end time.<br>‍<br></li></ol><p>You want to avoid any tasks without a clear deadline, even if the deadline is not accurate. According to Parkinson’s Law, if you have more time to finish a task, the overall time that you will take to finish the task will also expand. This holds true for many people and timeboxing greatly helps in dealing with that as well.<br></p><p>It’s important that as much as possible in Step 3 above, you avoid the <strong>mental optimistic bias</strong> of underestimating how long the completion of a task would require. When we’re too optimistic about how long a given task is going to take, we fail to completely follow through on what we set out to do.This bias, can be avoided by simply using a <strong>feedback loop, </strong>where you're constantly thinking about what you've done and how you could be doing it better. At the end of each day or at least once a week, reflect on your progress and review the things you worked on that week and think to yourself how you could improve.&nbsp;<br></p><p>Timeboxing is amazing if you learn to do it effectively. In simple words, it is a process to merge your to-do list with your calendar. Another benefit of timeboxing is that it reduces the number of choices you’d have to make in any given moment — boosting your willpower for peak productivity.</p><h2>Productivity as an indie hacker</h2><p>To maximize your productivity, you must set your priorities straight. For me as a developer, I find myself investing the majority of my time coding, but as an indie hacker who wants to build a profitable business, I must focus on other stuff too; marketing, promoting, writing, and talking to customers. Themed days made me realize that <a href="https://www.jamalx31.com/post/is-coding-a-procrastination-trap">coding could be a procrastination trap</a>.<br></p><p>Applying theme days helped me break out of the dev-hamster-wheel (aka coding) and forced me to do more of what needed to be done. So I decided to structure my themed days to look like this:<br></p><p><strong>Monday</strong>: Coding <br>‍<strong>Tuesday</strong>: Coding<strong><br>Wednesday</strong>: Writing / Learning<strong><br>Thursday</strong>: Coding&nbsp;<strong><br>Friday</strong>: Housekeeping / Reflecting&nbsp;<strong><br>Saturday</strong>: Marketing / SEO&nbsp;<strong><br>Sunday</strong>: Writing&nbsp;</p><p>As you see, I only code three days a week, so I can focus on other equally or sometimes even more important things.</p><p>I also found themed days to be very effective when it comes to dealing with new or unexpected tasks. Depending on the task’s "theme", I know precisely on which day it should be scheduled. It takes me a fraction of the time to add it to my system.<br></p><h2>Themed Inbox</h2><p>I took themed days an extra step and applied it to my Gmail inbox. With a <a href="https://www.axllent.org/docs/gmail-snooze-script/">super cool trick using Google Apps Script</a>, I have control over when emails hit my inbox. Instead of checking my email everyday and having dozens of unrelated emails, now emails show up in my inbox on the right day. For example, all unimportant emails are scheduled for Friday (my Housekeeping day), while all marketing &amp; SEO related emails come in on Saturday, and so on. This way I make sure I read the right email at the right time when I’m ready to act on it. So cool, right?<br></p><figure id="w-node-01d3452ce5a9-4885bece"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5eed2ff36d85f3277043492b/5f8b5b8eb994e7219ad5c7a6_aacavebgfxMyaKY5fTJeYgq5iGSUGD-5kW-_E5b-80Oo0IdiLDzEmok9W3WkT5_U-_woBP59Bk2TJg2xCFos_w3fsecvjQiGpCcArpMwuSTAgkbBQkGZUL0fY1dDm_AIU3Vs5NiL.png" alt=""></p><figcaption>The script automatically label emails</figcaption></figure><h2>Building a system: find a tool that works for you.</h2><p>When it comes to productivity in general, it’s important to have an efficient and flexible system that can adapt as your needs change without investing countless hours rebuilding everything from scratch.<br></p><p>Notion has been the core part of my system for the last five months. I’ve been experimenting a lot with different productivity techniques and approaches and it would have been so hard to do that without a super flexible and elegant tool like Notion. It's my second brain and where I store everything, so I’m using it to implement themed days, with Notion build-in templates.<br></p><p>I have a database where I have designed a template for each day and theme. Every morning, after preparing my coffee, I create a new page for that day using the proper template. The new page gets populated with everything I need to be as productive as possible on that day.<br></p><p>For example, on Saturday, which is a marketing/SEO day, I have a page with all the resources and reminders related to that subject.<br></p><figure id="w-node-5a939054f819-4885bece"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5eed2ff36d85f3277043492b/5f8b5b8e51775d3896dd2ca8_IR7wRnLd7_xn6THm_98T9fff1sIPhOhPUMI39ZsvQZckACxBvIC6BGD4oOj2ke_tcSEynYyETcdgfdGl_6kFQibk_no8hh-5oawKs_-YBQTp8GeLS8dstn5kCNhbzySBkC7BNe7X.png" alt="my Notion templates"></p><figcaption>Notion template for each day of the week</figcaption></figure><figure id="w-node-fb4ef460147c-4885bece"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5eed2ff36d85f3277043492b/5f8b5b8e1cd4becfc1e46ca2_RaH23NZlbiaNZOdoL6Pg-aIbRYxrnuE3L3A2-ttTweWCPEe_vbzW6XUu0d-Ycspa372e7ZdciYXHQsFhw_3jadOX_Soqdvqd_ohmn1ikovesCXtAMPrdljxuWiv9Gt15cxeWtB9x.png" alt="Saturday template"></p><figcaption>Saturday's template, focus on marketing &amp;&nbsp;SEO</figcaption></figure><p>What I found really nice about this approach is that my templates are not static, and as I keep updating them, they keep evolving and improving.</p><h2>Next level: Themed weeks</h2><p>If you really want to level up your game and accelerate your progress even further, you can implement themed weeks.</p><p>One of my favourite indie makers, <a href="https://twitter.com/yongfook">Jon Yongfook</a>, has implemented themed weeks for his workflow. Jon works in a 2 weeks sprint, one week of coding, followed by one week of marking, and then wraps it up by writing a newsletter and changelog. When I asked him if he tried shorter sprints, he said that he did but found shorter sprints lead to too much context switching, and two weeks sprint works very well for him.<br></p><p>You can also use the same concept to devote the whole week to a single project, and really make huge advancements, or to a certain business function, and today, with all the rapid prototyping tools available, you could take a week to build an MVP/prototype and test your idea on the market.</p><h2>Give it a try and see for yourself.&nbsp;&nbsp;</h2><p>The best way to see what themed days can do for your productivity is merely trying it out. Here's your homework:</p><ul role="list"><li>Make a list of 3-4 categories/themes you want to focus on (e.g writing, coding, marketing)</li><li>Break them down to atomic tasks, ideally each sub-task should take one hour or less</li><li>Map each theme to a day of the week</li><li>If you can’t find time on working days, try to do it on a Saturday.</li><li>Open your calendar</li><li>Timebox the sub-tasks by scheduling them on their dedicated day</li><li>Get excited -message me to hold you accountable- and do it!&nbsp;<br></li></ul><p>I promise that afterwards, you will feel a sense of achievement and see the progress that can</p><p>be made with this approach. It’s time to make room in your calendar for what matters!</p><p>‍<br></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.jamalx31.com/post/themed-days-timeboxing-and-why-you-should-use-them</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24813440</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 21:15:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Banks help scammers with their bad UI]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 95 | Comments 75 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24810870">thread link</a>) | @ZainRiz
<br/>
October 17, 2020 | https://www.zainrizvi.io/blog/how-banks-help-scammers-with-their-bad-ui/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.zainrizvi.io/blog/how-banks-help-scammers-with-their-bad-ui/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
			<!-- .cover -->


				<div>
					<p>My sister Sana just wanted to earn some money before returning to college. She was looking for a covid-friendly job on craigslist, something to cut down on the student loans she'd have to take out for the year. After searching and scrounging, Sana found someone who needed logistical help taking care of their pets. She applied and was excited to get hired.</p><p>First, they needed help buying pet food. They had ordered $1,800 worth of pet food (they bought high quality stuff in bulk apparently) but the seller would only accept payments via Zelle. Her employer was a bit old fashioned and didn't know how to use that service, so they offered a different arrangement: “I’ll mail you a check for $2,000” they said, “please deposit it in your own bank account, and then use $1,800 of it to Zelle the payment to the sellers. The remaining $200 is your fee.”</p><p>Sana was a bit suspicious, but she deposited the check into her Chase bank account and it cleared a few days later. Chase’s site showed that the money had been deposited successfully and was available to use, no strings attached. </p><p>Seemed like it was legit. So she did the honest thing and Zelle'd the money &nbsp;to the seller.</p><p>Happy with the job well done, her "employer" sent her another $2,000 check to deposit and transfer. This person really liked their pets. The same process happened again, and her employer was happy with the job well done.</p><p>Two weeks later, Sana’s debit card stopped working. Confused, she checked her account to see what was wrong. </p><p>Her heart sank. </p><p>Chase showed it as overdrawn.</p><p>By more than three thousand dollars.</p><p>The checks had bounced, two weeks after Chase’s site had indicated they had “cleared”. Before this whole thing had started, Sana had $300 in her bank account. Now she had negative $3,300.</p><p>She had just been scammed out of $3,600.</p><h2 id="what-happened">What happened?</h2><p>Turns out checks can bounce weeks after they're deposited. It can take that long for the bank to verify they’re legitimate.</p><p>Why does it take so long? Here’s a peek behind the scenes:</p><ol><li>You deposit your check, and it shows up as pending in your account.</li><li>Your bank sends the check to the check-writer’s bank to request the funds.</li><li>Their bank verifies if the check is legitimate and the account actually contains the funds. At small or international banks this step is often manual and could take <em>weeks</em>.</li><li>Their bank lets your bank know it's legit. That's when the check has "cleared".</li></ol><figure><img src="https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/2020/10/Check-lifecycle-large.jpeg" alt="" srcset="https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/size/w600/2020/10/Check-lifecycle-large.jpeg 600w, https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/size/w1000/2020/10/Check-lifecycle-large.jpeg 1000w, https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/size/w1600/2020/10/Check-lifecycle-large.jpeg 1600w, https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/size/w2400/2020/10/Check-lifecycle-large.jpeg 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption>The life cycle of a check</figcaption></figure><p>I skipped one step though: </p><p>It take can than more than <strong>six months</strong> for a check to clear, but banks remove that “pending” status just a couple days after it's deposited and allow people to spend the money. This might sound a bit iffy, but it's actually a good thing. Most checks are legitimate and people might need the money quickly. But that assumption breaks down with fraudulent checks.</p><p>By removing the “pending” status before fully verifying the check’s legitimacy, Chase gave the illusion that the check had already cleared. <em>This is what the scammers count on.</em> &nbsp;</p><p>Today there is <em>no way</em> for a Chase customer to be sure that a check has fully cleared. But unless you have the inside scoop on how banks work, or a finely honed sense of when someone is trying to swindle you, you won’t catch it.</p><p>When Sana called up Chase, the bank heard her out. But instead of stopping the scammers, their only concern was making sure she pays up the remaining $3,000 that they claimed she owed them.</p><p><em>Edit: Chase customer support had one clarification to make. I'd originally said it might take weeks for the check to clear, but they explained it could actually take more than six months. And you'll have no idea when that magic moment occurs.</em></p><!--kg-card-begin: html--><p><img src="https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/2020/10/IMG_1399.jpg" alt="" srcset="https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/size/w600/2020/10/IMG_1399.jpg 600w, https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/2020/10/IMG_1399.jpg 828w" sizes="(min-width: 525px) 525px"></p><!--kg-card-end: html--><h2 id="and-she-s-not-the-only-one-who-s-been-hit-by-this-scam-">And she's not the only one who's been hit by this scam.</h2><p>My friend David Vargas was caught by <a href="https://davidvargas.me/blog/i-got-scammed-out-of-5k/">pretty much the exact same scam</a>. He was sent checks which included his fee and payment that was supposed to be made to someone else. And they only accepted Zelle.</p><p>In fact, similar<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/16/zelle-users-are-finding-out-the-hard-way-theres-no-fraud-protection/?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly9uZXdzLnljb21iaW5hdG9yLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAEVQ_LYXhqL8UBL2vmnP9kphsW_QtokZbglthvs6MgR-ZvqTSF7pcgQMl05VmPjal00O9pBtatU8paO6pmmAYyt91oRIxVEX7L32zEu7v3WKlKOYDV-RVDEHjYe3Co_ugzyWZPRq3oFD-D2giDL1H-Dvj7jmdSbg6NLoAjBnnyWt"> scams</a> <a href="https://news.cardnotpresent.com/news/zelle-scam-emerging">have</a> <a href="https://chicago.cbslocal.com/2019/11/19/how-to-avoid-zelle-scams-and-fraud/">been</a> <a href="https://medium.com/@eirurueta/i-was-scammed-by-using-zelle-for-ethereum-crypto-online-2fa3a38d1817">going on</a> <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/you-accidentally-venmoed-149-to-a-stranger-good-luck-getting-it-back-1531411133">for years</a>, yet most banks don’t seem to care as long as they're not the ones losing money.</p><h2 id="what-should-chase-have-done-here">What should Chase have done here?</h2><h3 id="-1-take-responsibility-their-system-is-broken">#1 Take responsibility: their system is broken</h3><p>Is Chase bank directly responsible for scamming people? Of course not. Did they create an environment where scammers could thrive? Absolutely.</p><p>The harm was unintentional, but they played a hand in it. </p><p>Involuntary manslaughter.</p><p>What have other companies done when someone abused their products to deliberately cause harm? They took responsibility for it and fixed the problem at a systematic level.</p><p><strong>The Tylenol murders: </strong>In 1982, someone started <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/health/tylenol-murders-1982">spiking bottles of Tylenol</a> with poison, killing seven people. This was clearly not Tylenol’s fault, but they still immediately paid to recalled all bottles in the stores, offered anyone who had already purchased the pills free replacements. They took it a step further and <strong>developed tamper-proof packaging </strong>to prevent anyone from contaminating the medicine again in the future.</p><p><strong>Credit Card fraud services</strong>: Online payments are inherently risky. Credit card companies know this, and they’ve committed to helping their customers when the inevitable fraud occurs. If you pay someone with your Discover card and the product turns out to be a scam, <em>Discover will accept responsibility and refund you the money</em>, taking a loss if necessary. This dynamic keeps Discover on their toes working to prevent scams before they even happen.</p><h3 id="-2-how-should-they-fix-it">#2 How should they fix it?</h3><p>Make the status of the deposited check abundantly clear. This is how Chase can tamper-proof their bottles.</p><p>If a check has been deposited but not fully cleared, if it hasn't had the actual funds transferred over to the bank, then Chase needs to make that fact clear to customers! This missing piece of UX is what scammers depend on. That’s the systemic flaw here.</p><p>If the bank actually made the status of the funds clear to its customers, then it would have a much stronger leg to stand on when claiming innocence.</p><p>But as things stand right now, the only way a person could know the check was still at risk is if they already knew about the long clearing time and how banks hide it. Before the results come back from the external bank, Chase itself doesn’t know if the check is valid. Yet they offer customers no hint of that uncertainty.</p><p>And instead of taking responsibility, what did Chase actually do?</p><h3 id="chase-took-option-3-shakedown-their-customers">Chase took option #3: Shakedown their customers</h3><figure><img src="https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/2020/09/Ya340FffaeszEwIQ0ZPdxC9WQbRbN4kGKmcgTWiXLUiifzyqYvwzQSr4nwR3-jR--TS_Z-WrSDyVCcx4G37knBt171ds1zqYgfJ9hB4m-rUHKsDrCMG_N_2u6uTVCOreTRlc32iw.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/Ya340FffaeszEwIQ0ZPdxC9WQbRbN4kGKmcgTWiXLUiifzyqYvwzQSr4nwR3-jR--TS_Z-WrSDyVCcx4G37knBt171ds1zqYgfJ9hB4m-rUHKsDrCMG_N_2u6uTVCOreTRlc32iw.png 600w, https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/size/w1000/2020/09/Ya340FffaeszEwIQ0ZPdxC9WQbRbN4kGKmcgTWiXLUiifzyqYvwzQSr4nwR3-jR--TS_Z-WrSDyVCcx4G37knBt171ds1zqYgfJ9hB4m-rUHKsDrCMG_N_2u6uTVCOreTRlc32iw.png 1000w, https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/2020/09/Ya340FffaeszEwIQ0ZPdxC9WQbRbN4kGKmcgTWiXLUiifzyqYvwzQSr4nwR3-jR--TS_Z-WrSDyVCcx4G37knBt171ds1zqYgfJ9hB4m-rUHKsDrCMG_N_2u6uTVCOreTRlc32iw.png 1192w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Chase acted like the mafia, shaking down whoever they could to get their money back.</p><p>My sister had created this bank account back when she was in high school. For minors, Chase requires a guarantor, someone who would make sure her debts are paid. My dad had listed himself, he was also a Chase customer.</p><p>And now Chase came after him for the remaining three grand.</p><p>He spent hours on the phone with Chase’s customer support trying to get the scam resolved. The reps may have been empathetic, they weren’t empowered to help.</p><p>From the bank's perspective, the money they had already pulled from Sana's account was theirs. Sorry, no negotiation possible. The computer won't let us. And Chase did their darned best to not have to take a hair cut on the rest of the amount they enabled scammers to steal.</p><p>The most those reps could share was to suggest my dad could try not paying the remaining three thousand and wait until the debt goes to collections. And then pray that the collections department has more leniency. It might hurt his credit rating though, they warned. How much? They didn’t know. &nbsp;The account was scheduled to go to collections at the end of September.</p><p>But a month before that date, my dad noticed his own account was now three thousand dollars lighter. Chase had just helped itself to those funds without warning.</p><p>And now that Chase is no longer losing money on this scam, customer support tells him “Sorry, there’s nothing we can do.”</p><p>With every step Chase made sure it got paid, one way or another. Vito Corleone would be proud.</p><figure><img src="https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/2020/09/image-3-1.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-3-1.png 600w, https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/2020/09/image-3-1.png 669w"></figure><p>And if the bank has no skin in the game, why worry about fixing some misleading UI? They seem to think people don’t bother switching banks, and that it can treat its customers as captive users.</p><h2 id="how-widespread-must-this-be">How widespread must this be?</h2><p>When a person gets scammed they’re usually hesitant to speak up about it. </p><p>They're ashamed of having been duped, afraid of being scorned for their foolishness, and so their story rarely gets told. </p><p>Yet I know two people who’ve admitted to being hurt by this scam. What does that imply about the scale of this problem?</p><p>And Chase allows it to continue happening, punishing their customers for not having intimate knowledge of how banking works.</p><h2 id="is-your-blood-boiling-yet">Is your blood boiling yet?</h2><p>I get furious every time I think about it. David Vargas tried to pass his situation off as his own fault, but I was outraged on his behalf.</p><p>I want everyone at Chase to see this story. I want every other bank that’s enabling scammers to see this. And I want them to fix their system to let people know when shady checks have not yet been deposited.</p><p>When I showed this article to a friend, he got restless, he wanted to take action. “How can I help?” he asked, “Tell me what to do!” At the time I wasn’t sure what could be done, but there is one thing:</p><p><strong>My ask to you:</strong> Can you help spread the word and make Chase notice this problem? Maybe the internet outrage machine can turn this into a priority and protect the thousands of other people who are being scammed by this.</p><p>You could share this article (<a href="https://twitter.com/ZainRzv/status/1311701855148236800">retweet the Tweet</a>, or post on FB, Reddit, HN, whatever your usual channels are). Get this shared widely. And maybe, just maybe, some executive at Chase will notice and take the lead in transforming the banking industry. My sincerest thank you to everyone who helps.</p><p>So far, Chase hasn’t been interested in accepting an ounce of responsibility for their part in this scheme. Why bother fixing the system when you can just pull money from your customer’s bank accounts? But maybe they can change. Who wants to be known as an unwitting accomplice to scammers?</p><p>And even if they don't change, remember Chase's missteps and …</p></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.zainrizvi.io/blog/how-banks-help-scammers-with-their-bad-ui/">https://www.zainrizvi.io/blog/how-banks-help-scammers-with-their-bad-ui/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.zainrizvi.io/blog/how-banks-help-scammers-with-their-bad-ui/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24810870</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 15:52:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Lisp from Nothing]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 140 | Comments 18 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24809293">thread link</a>) | @nils-m-holm
<br/>
October 17, 2020 | http://t3x.org/lfn/index.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://t3x.org/lfn/index.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Lulu Press, 2020 - 301 pages - 17 figures - 6"&nbsp;x&nbsp;9" format - <a href="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">CC0</a> code</p></div><p>
This text plays with the theme of minimal LISP by providing
several implementations from a simple metacircular evaluator to
a full compiler that emits a single, self-contained C program.
The discussion is embedded in reflections on what hacking looked
like in the early days of LISP.
</p></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://t3x.org/lfn/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24809293</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 11:48:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Building a 10BASE5 “Thick Ethernet” Network (2012)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 65 | Comments 23 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24807542">thread link</a>) | @RicardoLuis0
<br/>
October 16, 2020 | http://tech.mattmillman.com/projects/10base5/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://tech.mattmillman.com/projects/10base5/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>I can hardly claim to have worked professionally with 10BASE5 as when I first started building my own 10BASE2 networks in 1997, 10BASE5 was long obsolete. Back then, I knew about 10BASE5, but it wasn’t practical, affordable or interesting enough for me to attempt building one.</p>
<p>Fast forward to 2012, and 10BASE5 is now truly a vintage technology. Anyone studying something&nbsp;I.T. related likely will at some point have been told about this stuff, because it’s very important in the history of computing. This was the first standardised, commercially used form of Ethernet, and today, almost the entire Internet is Ethernet, but heck, who’s ever actually seen a working 10BASE5 setup? Not me, that’s for sure, nor or anyone I’ve ever met.</p>
<p>So… can I build a working setup in 2012? Read on…</p>

<p>I’ve written this page primarily for people like myself, who came into the computing scene just a bit too late to have ever seen this technology in use. A 1980s network engineer can safely skip this page.</p>

<p>In order to connect to a true 10BASE5 network, network adapters with AUI are required. AUI stands for Attachment Unit Interface. It is in effect, a media independent form of all of the physical 10Mbit ethernet variants, which I shall call 10BASE-X. AUI was to 10BASE-X what MII is to 100BASE-X, with the exception that MII is rarely found as an external connector.</p>
<p>Unfortunately for this project, networking equipment with external AUI connectors is becoming rather difficult to find.</p>
<p>As I see it, there’s 2 options:</p>
<ul>
<li>Build true 10BASE5 nodes using equipment natively supporting AUI</li>
<li>Bridge to something else i.e. 10BASE-T</li>
</ul>
<h2>Building true 10BASE5 nodes</h2>
<p>Not many options remain for connecting to modern PCs. Here’s a few:</p>
<h3>ISA Cards</h3>
<p>While this can be done, modern mainboards with ISA slots are niche and very expensive. I ruled out this option.</p>
<p><a href="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c509.jpg"><img src="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c509.jpg" alt="3c509" width="717" height="453" srcset="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c509.jpg 717w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c509-150x95.jpg 150w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c509-300x190.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 717px) 100vw, 717px"></a></p>

<h3>PCI Cards</h3>
<p>Fortunately, some modern PCs still have 32-Bit/5 volt parallel PCI slots, also, PCI and 10BASE5 had enough overlap that a small number of products were manufactured. A couple of examples are the 3Com 3C900B-COMBO, and 3C905B-COMBO. At the time of writing there were a fair few of these on eBay, but often for outrageous sums of money. Fortunately I managed to pick up a couple for a few quid. 64-Bit Windows drivers do not exist, making Windows 7 32-bit likely the last version of Windows able to make use of them, short of writing some new drivers. All versions of Linux will work OK with these.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1354" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1354"><a href="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c900-cmb.jpg"><img src="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c900-cmb.jpg" alt="3Com 3c900-COMBO NIC" width="2575" height="1615" srcset="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c900-cmb.jpg 2575w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c900-cmb-150x94.jpg 150w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c900-cmb-300x188.jpg 300w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c900-cmb-768x482.jpg 768w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c900-cmb-800x502.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 2575px) 100vw, 2575px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1354">3Com 3c900-COMBO NIC With AUI Connector</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_32" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-32"><a href="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/10BASE5Node.jpg"><img src="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/10BASE5Node-800x600.jpg" alt="10BASE5 Node" width="474" height="356" srcset="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/10BASE5Node-800x600.jpg 800w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/10BASE5Node-150x113.jpg 150w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/10BASE5Node-300x225.jpg 300w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/10BASE5Node.jpg 1113w" sizes="(max-width: 474px) 100vw, 474px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-32">A true 10BASE5 node. Using a 3Com 3c905B-COMBO NIC with AUI</figcaption></figure>
<h3>USB or other solutions</h3>
<p>As far as I can tell no USB product was ever made. With 10BASE5 MAU’s requiring 12 volts and some 5 or more watts of power, over and above what USB can provide, this would be a problematic proposition. Also, no single chip “USB with AUI” solutions exist. From my research, it seems theoretically possible to create a 2-chip adapter, with external power supply, but apparently there is no market for such as a thing.</p>
<figure id="attachment_71" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71"><a href="http://tech.mattmillman.com/projects/usbaui/"><img src="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/axaui_proto_tn-800x534.jpg" alt="USB AUI Ethernet adapter proof of concept, based on a D-Link DUB-E100, NQ8502 connected to MII" width="474" height="316" srcset="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/axaui_proto_tn-800x534.jpg 800w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/axaui_proto_tn-150x100.jpg 150w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/axaui_proto_tn-300x200.jpg 300w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/axaui_proto_tn.jpg 880w" sizes="(max-width: 474px) 100vw, 474px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-71">A D-Link DUB-E100 with its 100BASE-TX PHY removed, and an NQ8502 frankensteined in its place.<br> This image illustrates my key design objective: To give an AUI interface to a USB Ethernet MAC, instead of converting from 10BASE-T.</figcaption></figure>
<p>But that didn’t stop me from building one. Above is what is quite possibly one of the worlds only USB Ethernet Adapters with AUI interface. I have a seperate project page for this&nbsp;<a href="http://tech.mattmillman.com/usbaui/">here</a>.</p>
<h3>Routers</h3>
<p>A Cisco NM-1E2W module could be used if one has a large ISR kicking around.</p>
<h2>Bridging 10BASE5 to modern twisted pair networks</h2>
<h3>10BASE-T Hubs equipped with AUI</h3>
<p>Using a 10BASE-T hub with AUI to bridge to a twisted pair network is probably the easiest approach. There’s thousands of these for sale on eBay for peanuts, but in my case, having one of these on each node would make the setup rather clunky.</p>
<h3>10BASE-T to AUI Media converters</h3>
<p>What I was really looking for was a few of these little boxes. Easily mistaken for a 10BASE-T MAU, these (unlike the former which tend to be spilling out of every I.T. junk box in the land) are fairly uncommon.</p>
<figure id="attachment_17" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17"><a href="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/MC12T.jpg"><img src="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/MC12T-800x475.jpg" alt="Allied Telesis MC12T" width="474" height="281" srcset="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/MC12T-800x475.jpg 800w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/MC12T-150x89.jpg 150w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/MC12T-300x178.jpg 300w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/MC12T.jpg 872w" sizes="(max-width: 474px) 100vw, 474px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17">An Allied Telesis MC12T next to an ordinary 10BASE-T MAU. Spot the difference?</figcaption></figure>

<p>To keep the cost of this project to a minimum, I decided my network would only have 3-4 nodes as this was sufficient to demonstrate a proper shared media network as opposed to a 2 node effective “point to point” link. For this I sourced the following components:</p>
<ul>
<li>2x 3Com 3C900B-COMBO PCI NICs with AUI</li>
<li>3x MiLAN MIL-130A AUI-to-10BASE-T bridges</li>
<li>1x MiLAN MIL-10P 10BASE-T Transceiver (for testing AUI nodes)</li>
<li>1x Allied Telesis MC12T</li>
<li>6x Cabletron ST-500 MAU’s</li>
<li>3x AMP 228752-1 Vampire taps</li>
<li>2x AMP 221914-1 Intrusive N connector taps</li>
<li>5x AUI Drop cables</li>
<li>15M of Belden #9880 cable</li>
<li>2x 50ohm N terminators</li>
<li>2x N female to female couplers</li>
<li>10x UNC 4-40 x 1.1/2″ countersunk screws (to replace missing ones on my MAUs)</li>
</ul>

<p>A common belief persists that 10BASE5 used RG-8/U cable. This, for the most part, appears to be untrue. The cable used was purpose designed for 10BASE5 and manufactured by Belden under the part number 9880 (A few other compatible cables may exist). The reason #9880 cable was specified is that several variants of RG-8 exist with varying dimensions and manufacturing standards. Given that the main form of connection of MAU’s to 10BASE5 networks was by the precisely designed prongs in “Vampire taps”, cable dimensions and dielectric consistency had to be spot on.</p>
<p>A network designed using only intrusive N connector taps such as AMP 221914-1 could get away with using pretty much any 50 ohm coax, but then the sum total of insertion losses created by each node may prevent the full 500M segment length from being achieved. Also, this approach wouldn’t permit addition of new nodes without bringing down the network. After an evening of wrestling with RG-8/U cable (why oh why didn’t I just buy RG-58) while attempting to make a short test lead, I think I’ll stick with the Vampire Taps.</p>
<p>For someone like me who hadn’t encountered it before, no amount of looking at pictures could prepare for how big this stuff is. Short of high power transmission cables, it’s the largest coaxial cable I’ve ever seen. It is also very heavy, rigid and the bend radius is absurdly large.</p>
<p>Another interesting feature of this cable is the black bands which appear every 2.5M. In 10BASE5 networks, MAUs can only be attached at 2.5M intervals, this is to ensure that signal reflections generated by taps stay out of phase, which stops them compounding across the whole segment. In a small network such as mine, it’s probably not so important to respect this tap placement rule, but I’ll respect it anyway.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1325" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1325"><a href="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/BELDEN_9880.jpg"><img src="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/BELDEN_9880-800x423.jpg" alt="Belden 9880" width="474" height="251" srcset="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/BELDEN_9880-800x423.jpg 800w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/BELDEN_9880-150x79.jpg 150w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/BELDEN_9880-300x159.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 474px) 100vw, 474px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1325">Belden 9880 next to standard CAT5E cable. Either side of this frame is 10 kilos of steel, about the minimum required to hold this stuff down for the photo</figcaption></figure>

<p>Unlike the BNC connectors found on 10BASE2, the official connector used by 10BASE5 (where connectors are required) is the N connector. While still used extensively in lab/specialist environments, this large coaxial connector isn’t something the average ‘tech dude’ is likely to encounter these days. They perform exceptionally, have an intrinsic impedance of 50 ohms, are fairly common/inexpensive and easily handle the large sized #9880 cable.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1324" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1324"><a href="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/N.jpg"><img src="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/N-800x449.jpg" alt="10BASE5 N connectors" width="474" height="266" srcset="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/N-800x449.jpg 800w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/N-150x84.jpg 150w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/N-300x169.jpg 300w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/N.jpg 1789w" sizes="(max-width: 474px) 100vw, 474px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1324">N Connector and joiner with CAT5E patch cable for comparison</figcaption></figure>

<p>These cables sporting male and female 15-pin D-sub connectors, connect a node to the MAU. Since the MAU is bolted to a rigid behemoth piece of coax, it wasn’t exactly convenient to try and drag that lot down to the back of a PC, so these cables bridged that gap. With a maximum length of 50 metres, that gap can be very large indeed. Also, given that taps could only be placed at 2.5M intervals, a world without drop cables would lend its self to much humour around the office, at the expense of well-intended PC and desk placement considerations.</p>
<p>One notable feature is the slide locking mechanism used in place of the usual UNC 4-40 screws. It is my personal opinion that the design of this mechanism is a bit daft. In theory it’s a good idea but in practice I think it was implemented too flimsily. AUI drop cables are often very large and rigid (likely thanks to a half a dozen layers of shielding), so much so that a mild sideways nudge on a cable can easily rip a latched connector straight out of the socket, bending/breaking the mechanism. They also have a feature that the screws in the female end often work their way out over time, inevitably to be lost forever. Even during this small scale project, I have suffered some grief over these locking mechanisms. I can imagine they were a source of many support calls in the 80s and early 90s.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1322" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1322"><a href="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/AUI_DROP.jpg"><img src="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/AUI_DROP-800x447.jpg" alt="1M AUI drop cable" width="474" height="265" srcset="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/AUI_DROP-800x447.jpg 800w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/AUI_DROP-150x84.jpg 150w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/AUI_DROP-300x168.jpg 300w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/AUI_DROP.jpg 1605w" sizes="(max-width: 474px) 100vw, 474px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1322">AUI drop cable, with a one-up-from-useless slide locking mechanism</figcaption></figure>

<p>These metal boxes are one of the key defining pieces of kit in a 10BASE5 network. They function as the transceiver, converting the primitive signals from the AUI interface to what’s required on the physical media, as well as performing collision detection. They came in 4 flavours:</p>
<ul>
<li>With a tap for 10BASE5 networks, using a Vampire Tap</li>
<li>With a tap for 10BASE5 networks, using N connectors (Rare)</li>
<li>With a tap for 10BASE2 networks, using BNC connectors</li>
<li>Without a tap (Buy your own)</li>
</ul>
<p>I chose Cabletron ST-500’s, because they have blinky lights. The ST-500 (90 Series) would have been one of the last and most modern 10BASE5 MAUs manufactured. The internal component count (when compared with, say, a DEC h4000) is low.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1314" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1314"><a href="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/ST500-01.jpg"><img src="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/ST500-01-800x542.jpg" alt="Cabletron ST500-01" width="474" height="321" srcset="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/ST500-01-800x542.jpg 800w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/ST500-01-150x102.jpg 150w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/ST500-01-300x203.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 474px) 100vw, 474px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1314">Cabletron ST500-01</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_1315" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1315"><a href="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/ST500-02a.jpg"><img src="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/ST500-02a-800x659.jpg" alt="" width="474" height="390" srcset="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/ST500-02a-800x659.jpg 800w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/ST500-02a-150x124.jpg 150w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/ST500-02a-300x247.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 474px) 100vw, 474px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1315">Cabletron ST500-02</figcaption></figure>

<p>By far the most common means of connection to the coax segment. The bottom half is plastic, I assume to eliminate ground loops by ensuring the braid remains electrically isolated from the metal case of the MAU. The top half is extruded aluminium. Each contains three prongs (two to connect to the braid, and one to the centre conductor). To me, the idea of using this style of connection to coaxial cable is ambitious, but it has to be said that a few spikes in a coaxial cable will equate to significantly less reflection and insertion loss …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://tech.mattmillman.com/projects/10base5/">http://tech.mattmillman.com/projects/10base5/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://tech.mattmillman.com/projects/10base5/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24807542</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 04:47:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What they don’t tell you about demand paging in school]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 69 | Comments 22 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24806246">thread link</a>) | @luu
<br/>
October 16, 2020 | https://offlinemark.com/2020/10/14/demand-paging/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://offlinemark.com/2020/10/14/demand-paging/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			
<p>This post details my adventures with the Linux virtual memory subsystem, and my discovery of a creative way to taunt the OOM (out of memory) killer by accumulating memory in the kernel, rather than in userspace.</p>



<p>Keep reading and you’ll learn:</p>



<ul><li>Internal details of the Linux kernel’s demand paging implementation</li><li>How to exploit virtual memory to implement highly efficient sparse data structures</li><li>What page tables are and how to calculate the memory overhead incurred by them</li><li>A cute way to get killed by the OOM killer while appearing to consume very little memory (great for parties)</li></ul>



<h2>Part 1: Demand paging is nuanced</h2>



<p>As usual, the story begins with me asking questions about implementation details. This time, about the Linux kernel’s demand paging implementation.</p>



<p>In Operating Systems 101 we learn that operating systems are “lazy” when they allocate memory to processes. When you mmap() an anonymous page, the kernel slyly returns a pointer immediately. It then waits until you trigger a page fault by “touching” that memory before doing the real memory allocation work. This is called “demand paging”.</p>



<p>This is efficient — if the memory is never touched, no physical memory is ever allocated. This also means you can allocate virtual memory in vast excess of what is physically available (“overcommit”), which can be useful.<span id="easy-footnote-1-496"></span><span><a href="#easy-footnote-bottom-1-496" title="Some examples of applications that allocate immense virtual memory are Address Sanitizer and Webkit."><sup>1</sup></a></span>. You just can’t touch it all.</p>



<p>Let’s dive deeper. Barring execution, “touching” memory means reading or writing. Writes to a new mmap’d region require the kernel to perform a full memory allocation. You need memory, you need it <em>now</em>, and the kernel can’t push it off any longer.</p>



<p>Now, the question: <strong>What about reads?</strong></p>



<p>Unlike writes, reads to a new mmap’d region do <em>not</em> trigger a memory allocation. The kernel continues to push off the allocation by exploiting how new anonymous mappings must be zero initialized. Instead of allocating memory, the kernel services the page fault using the “zero page”: a pre-allocated page of physical memory, completely filled with zeros. In theory this is “free” — a single physical frame can back all zero-initialized pages.</p>



<p>The point? <strong>Demand paging is nuanced — not all ways of accessing a new mapping require the kernel to allocate memory</strong>.</p>



<p>Let’s see what this looks like in the <a href="https://elixir.bootlin.com/linux/v5.8.12/source/mm/memory.c#L4191">source</a>. The core page fault handler, <code>handle_mm_fault</code> is in <code>mm/memory.c</code>. A few calls deep via <code>__handle_mm_fault</code> and <code>handle_pte_fault</code>, we hit this block:</p>



<div><pre data-lang="C"><code>static vm_fault_t handle_pte_fault(struct vm_fault *vmf)
{
	// ...

	if (!vmf-&gt;pte) {
		if (vma_is_anonymous(vmf-&gt;vma))
			return do_anonymous_page(vmf);
		else
			// ...
	}

	// ...
}</code></pre></div>



<p>Which leads us to <code>do_anonymous_page</code> — the core page fault handler for anonymous pages. </p>



<div><pre data-lang="C"><code>static vm_fault_t do_anonymous_page(struct vm_fault *vmf)
{
	// ...
	
	if (pte_alloc(vma-&gt;vm_mm, vmf-&gt;pmd))
		return VM_FAULT_OOM;
	// ...

	/* Use the zero-page for reads */
	if (!(vmf-&gt;flags &amp; FAULT_FLAG_WRITE) &amp;&amp; // (1)
			!mm_forbids_zeropage(vma-&gt;vm_mm)) {
		entry = pte_mkspecial(pfn_pte(my_zero_pfn(vmf-&gt;address), // (2)
						vma-&gt;vm_page_prot));
		vmf-&gt;pte = pte_offset_map_lock(vma-&gt;vm_mm, vmf-&gt;pmd,
				vmf-&gt;address, &amp;vmf-&gt;ptl);
		// ...
		goto setpte;
	}
	// ...
setpte:
	set_pte_at(vma-&gt;vm_mm, vmf-&gt;address, vmf-&gt;pte, entry); // (3)
	// ...
	return ret;

	// ...
}</code></pre></div>



<p>Bingo. It checks whether a read caused the fault (1), then maps the virtual page to the zero page (2 and 3).</p>



<p>Note that this all happens in the page fault handler, which is an implementation choice. The mmap <a href="https://elixir.bootlin.com/linux/v5.8.12/source/mm/mmap.c#L1687">core logic</a> does not touch the page tables at all, and only records the presence of the new mapping. It leaves the mapping’s page table entry non-present (present bit = 0) which will trigger a page fault on access.</p>



<p>Alternatively, mmap could proactively allocate the page table entry, and initialize it to the zero page. This would avoid a page fault on the first read, but at the cost of initializing (potentially many) page table entries up front. Given that it’s most efficient to be maximally lazy, the current implementation is best.</p>



<h2>Part 2: Allocating infinite memory, and touching it too</h2>



<p>This led me to another question. Since reads from anonymous mappings are “free”, in addition to allocating excessive virtual memory, can’t you actually touch all of it? As long as that “touch” is a read?</p>



<p>Time for an experiment. Here’s some code that allocates 100 GB of linear memory, and tries to read from the first byte of each page. It allocates 512 MB at a time because I <a href="https://twitter.com/damageboy/status/1317676450393300994">incorrectly thought</a> you couldn’t mmap 100GB at once <s>you can’t directly ask mmap for 100 GB 🙂</s>.<span id="easy-footnote-2-496"></span><span><a href="#easy-footnote-bottom-2-496" title="Thanks to <a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/damageboy&quot;>@damageboy</a> for pointing this out."><sup>2</sup></a></span><span id="easy-footnote-3-496"></span><span><a href="#easy-footnote-bottom-3-496" title="This is lazy, dirty research code :) It is not sound or portable, and only just works because Linux happens to place the mmaps contiguously, growing down in memory."><sup>3</sup></a></span> My test system was a x64 Ubuntu 20.04 VPS.</p>



<div><pre data-lang="C++"><code>#include &lt;sys/mman.h&gt;
#include &lt;iostream&gt;

const size_t MB = 1024 * 1024;
const size_t GB = MB * 1024;

int main() {
  size_t alloc_size = 512 * MB;
  size_t total_alloc = 100 * GB;
  size_t num_allocs = total_alloc / alloc_size;

  // std::cout &lt;&lt; "alloc_size (MB)" &lt;&lt; alloc_size / (1024*1024)&lt;&lt; "\n";
  // std::cout &lt;&lt; "total_alloc " &lt;&lt; total_alloc &lt;&lt; "\n";
  // std::cout &lt;&lt; "num_allocs " &lt;&lt; num_allocs &lt;&lt; "\n";

  std::cout &lt;&lt; "Allocating mem...\n";

  char* base = nullptr;

  // Allocate a ton of memory
  for (size_t i = 0; i &lt; num_allocs; i++) {
    // Unsound alert - assuming allocations are contiguous and grow down.
    base = (char*)mmap(NULL, alloc_size, PROT_READ, MAP_PRIVATE | MAP_ANONYMOUS, -1, 0);
    if (base == MAP_FAILED) {
      perror(NULL);
      throw std::runtime_error("Fail");
    }
    std::cout &lt;&lt; (void*)base &lt;&lt; " " &lt;&lt; i &lt;&lt; "\n";
  }

  std::cout &lt;&lt; "Allocated Virtual Mem (GB): " &lt;&lt; total_alloc / GB &lt;&lt; "\n";
  std::cout &lt;&lt; "Base Addr: " &lt;&lt; (void*)base &lt;&lt; "\n";
  std::cout &lt;&lt; "Press enter to start reading.\n";
  getchar();
  std::cout &lt;&lt; "Reading each page...\n";

  // Read the first byte of each page
  for (size_t i = 0; i &lt; total_alloc; i += 0x1000) {
    auto x = base[i];
  }

  std::cout &lt;&lt; "Done!\n";
  getchar();
}</code></pre></div>



<p>When we run it, here’s what we see:</p>



<div><pre data-lang="Bash"><code>$ ./demo
Allocating mem...
0x7f3f6d300000 1
0x7f3f4d300000 2
0x7f3f2d300000 3
...
0x7f26cd300000 198
0x7f26ad300000 199
0x7f268d300000 200
Allocated Virtual Mem (GB): 100
Base Addr: 0x7f268d300000
Press enter to start reading.</code></pre></div>



<p>It successfully allocated 100 GB of linear virtual memory in 512 MB chunks. We can confirm this with <code>pmap</code>, which shows a 100GB region of anonymous virtual memory at the base address printed.</p>



<div><pre><code>$ pmap `pidof demo`
485209:   ./demo
00005600e1d0c000      4K r---- demo
00005600e1d0d000      4K r-x-- demo
00005600e1d0e000      4K r---- demo
00005600e1d0f000      4K r---- demo
00005600e1d10000      4K rw--- demo
00005600e2a47000    132K rw---   [ anon ]
00007f268d300000 104857600K r----   [ anon ] &lt;&lt;&lt;&lt; 100 GB region
00007f3f8d300000     16K rw---   [ anon ]
00007f3f8d304000     60K r---- libm-2.31.so
00007f3f8d313000    668K r-x-- libm-2.31.so
...</code></pre></div>



<p>What does htop say?</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="625" height="87" src="https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=625%2C87&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=1024%2C142&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=300%2C42&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=768%2C107&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=1536%2C213&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=624%2C87&amp;ssl=1 624w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?w=1916&amp;ssl=1 1916w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?w=1250&amp;ssl=1 1250w" sizes="(max-width: 625px) 100vw, 625px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=1024%2C142&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=300%2C42&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=768%2C107&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=1536%2C213&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=624%2C87&amp;ssl=1 624w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?w=1916&amp;ssl=1 1916w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?w=1250&amp;ssl=1 1250w" data-lazy-src="https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=625%2C87&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure>



<p>htop confirms that 100 GB of virtual memory is allocated (VIRT column), but a much more reasonable 1540 KB of resident memory (RES) is actually occupying RAM. Note the MINFLT column — this is the number of “minor” page faults that have occurred. A minor page fault is one that does not require loading from disk. We will be triggering lots of these and should expect to see this number grow dramatically.</p>



<p>Here’s what happens after I press enter to trigger reading.</p>



<div><pre><code>0x7f26cd300000 198
0x7f26ad300000 199
0x7f268d300000 200
Allocated Virtual Mem (GB): 100
Base Addr: 0x7f268d300000
Press enter to start reading.

Reading each page...
Done!</code></pre></div>



<p>The process hits the “Done!” print. This means it successfully touched every page of the 100 GB allocation!</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="625" height="79" src="https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=625%2C79&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=1024%2C130&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=300%2C38&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=768%2C98&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=1536%2C195&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=624%2C79&amp;ssl=1 624w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?w=1888&amp;ssl=1 1888w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?w=1250&amp;ssl=1 1250w" sizes="(max-width: 625px) 100vw, 625px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=1024%2C130&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=300%2C38&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=768%2C98&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=1536%2C195&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=624%2C79&amp;ssl=1 624w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?w=1888&amp;ssl=1 1888w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?w=1250&amp;ssl=1 1250w" data-lazy-src="https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=625%2C79&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure>



<p>htop confirms that many minor faults have occurred. We would expect it to cause exactly 26214400 faults (100 GB / 4 KB), and indeed, 26214552 – 26214400 = 152, the number we started with. Intriguingly, the resident memory appears to have also increased, which should not have happened. See the <a href="#rss-spike">Appendix A</a> for discussion of this.</p>



<p>Here’s a video to see it all in action:</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Allocating 100 GB and touching it all (Demand Paging Pt 1)" width="625" height="469" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HYNMt6FWsI4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p><strong>So the theory is confirmed! You can apparently “Allocate your memory, and touch it too” (as long as that touch is a read).</strong><span id="easy-footnote-4-496"></span><span><a href="#easy-footnote-bottom-4-496" title="Or if you prefer, the famous Henry Ford <a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/23494-any-customer-can-have-a-car-painted-any-colour-that&quot;>quote</a>:  &amp;#8220;You can touch as much memory as you want, as long as you are only reading&amp;#8221;."><sup>4</sup></a></span></p>



<p>If your application, for some reason, benefits from the ability to have a 100 GB array of zeros then this is perfect for you. What about the rest of us?</p>



<p>A closer-to-real-life application is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sparse_matrix">sparse array</a>. A sparse array is a (typically very large) array, whose elements are mostly zero. By exploiting demand paging, you can implement a memory efficient sparse array, where the majority of the array is backed by the zero page (or not even mapped). You get the fast indexing benefits of an array while avoiding the memory overhead.</p>



<h2>Part 3: Playing with a killer</h2>



<p>I have a confession. Remember when I said not all ways of accessing memory require the kernel to allocate memory? Yeah, that’s a lie.</p>



<p>Even though a read can be serviced by the shared zero page, that doesn’t mean no memory is allocated. Even the process of mapping a zero page requires allocating  memory. And here’s where we get into the nitty gritty.</p>



<h3>The hidden overhead of page tables</h3>



<p>The overhead comes from the virtual memory infrastructure itself — the page tables. Page tables are data structures that power the virtual memory subsystem. Like regular data structures, they occupy memory, only their overhead is easy to overlook, since it’s hidden from userspace.</p>



<p>This is what page tables on x86_64 look like:</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="625" height="463" src="https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?resize=625%2C463&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?resize=1024%2C758&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?resize=300%2C222&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?resize=768%2C568&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?resize=624%2C462&amp;ssl=1 624w, https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?w=1276&amp;ssl=1 1276w" sizes="(max-width: 625px) 100vw, 625px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?resize=1024%2C758&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?resize=300%2C222&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?resize=768%2C568&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?resize=624%2C462&amp;ssl=1 624w, https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?w=1276&amp;ssl=1 1276w" data-lazy-src="https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?resize=625%2C463&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><figcaption>x86_64 Page Tables: Intel Manual Vol 3A Chapter 4.5</figcaption></figure>



<p>They’re a tree data structure that is 4 levels deep, with each node (table) being an array of 512 8-byte entries. Together these tables offer an efficient way to represent a mapping between every virtual page in the address space and a physical frame.</p>



<p>Here’s where the overhead comes from. Each page touched requires 1 Page Table Entry (PTE) to be allocated. However, PTEs aren’t allocated individually. They’re allocated in blocks of 512 called Page Tables. Each Page Table requires 1 Page Directory Entry to be allocated. But …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://offlinemark.com/2020/10/14/demand-paging/">https://offlinemark.com/2020/10/14/demand-paging/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://offlinemark.com/2020/10/14/demand-paging/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24806246</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 00:09:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Porn, Zen, and .vimrc]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 197 | Comments 121 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24804899">thread link</a>) | @kkoncevicius
<br/>
October 16, 2020 | http://karolis.koncevicius.lt/posts/porn_zen_and_vimrc/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://karolis.koncevicius.lt/posts/porn_zen_and_vimrc/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">




<p>Vim is a highly customizable text editor geared towards writing code.
But open-ended configuration possibilities often lure users into wasting time while chasing after perceived minute gains in productivity.
This article describes my Vim journey, starting from heavy personal customization and ending with a renewed love for defaults.</p>

<h2 id="porn">Porn</h2>

<p>As a rule, new users, right after introduction to a few basic commands, start indulging in Vim configuration porn.
Such porn has various different flavours.
There is the “exhibitionist” variety which includes dressing Vim up in status lines, colorschemes, and font decorations in order to impress others.
It often leads to Vim being displayed on videos and, nomen omen, “vim-porn” screenshots.
There is an “integrated” category where people plug and stretch their Vim until it resembles an IDE.
Git integration, autocompletion, language servers, refactoring, and debugging are the tools of trade in this version.
And then there are a few more variants, including “fuzzy”, “packaged”, “conveniently re-mapped”, and I am sure anyone could think up some of their own.</p>

<p>My particular genre was “consistency” - I wanted my Vim to be intuitive and predictable.
While working I would constantly keep an eye for digressions in Vim’s behaviour and then spend my time trying to adjust them.
In my fantasy Vim had to feel intuitive and smooth so I tried to correct every little detail.
And, despite “consistency” porn being quite vanilla, I managed to construct a <code>vimrc</code> file exceeding one thousand lines of code.</p>

<h2 id="consistentvimrc">Consistent vimrc</h2>

<p>No point in sharing the entire collection, but here are a few illustrative examples and the rationale behind them.
Feel free to try them out, if that is your thing.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Y</p>

<p>As is widely known <code>Y</code> is not consistent with other uppercase commands.
It copies the whole line while <code>D</code> and <code>C</code> operates from the cursor position to the end of line.
Simple remap fixes the issue.</p>

<pre><code>" make Y consistent with C and D.
nnoremap Y y$
</code></pre></li>
<li><p><code>n</code> and <code>N</code></p>

<p>Having the same characters always go in the same direction would be a lot easier.
So this map makes <code>n</code> always go forwards and <code>N</code> always go backwards<a href="#fn:1" id="fnref:1" title="see footnote"><sup>○</sup></a>.
Same for <code>;</code> and <code>,</code><a href="#fn:2" id="fnref:2" title="see footnote"><sup>○</sup></a>.</p>

<pre><code>" make n always search forward and N backward
nnoremap &lt;expr&gt; n 'Nn'[v:searchforward]
nnoremap &lt;expr&gt; N 'nN'[v:searchforward]

" make ; always "find" forward and , backward
nnoremap &lt;expr&gt; ; getcharsearch().forward ? ';' : ','
nnoremap &lt;expr&gt; , getcharsearch().forward ? ',' : ';'
</code></pre></li>
<li><p><code>;</code> and <code>,</code></p>

<p>I disliked the forward and backward <code>f</code> repetition being under different characters: <code>;</code> and <code>,</code>.
This set of remaps puts them under the same key and moves away the colon command over to backtick.
The original backtick behaviour is transferred to a single quote.</p>

<pre><code>" make ; and , be on the same key
nnoremap : ,
nnoremap ` :
nnoremap ' `
</code></pre></li>
<li><p><code>j</code>, <code>k</code>, <code>h</code>, <code>l</code></p>

<p>This set of mappings makes the <code>j</code>, <code>k</code>, <code>h</code>, and <code>l</code> keys perform consistent direction-related action in various circumstances: scrolling, changing and creating windows, moving across paragraphs.</p>

<pre><code>" make J, K, L, and H move the cursor MORE.
nnoremap J }
nnoremap K {
nnoremap L g_
nnoremap H ^

" make &lt;c-j&gt;, &lt;c-k&gt;, &lt;c-l&gt;, and &lt;c-h&gt; scroll the screen.
nnoremap &lt;c-j&gt; &lt;c-e&gt;
nnoremap &lt;c-k&gt; &lt;c-y&gt;
nnoremap &lt;c-l&gt; zl
nnoremap &lt;c-h&gt; zh

" make &lt;a-j&gt;, &lt;a-k&gt;, &lt;a-l&gt;, and &lt;a-h&gt; move to window.
nnoremap &lt;a-j&gt; &lt;c-w&gt;j
nnoremap &lt;a-k&gt; &lt;c-w&gt;k
nnoremap &lt;a-l&gt; &lt;c-w&gt;l
nnoremap &lt;a-h&gt; &lt;c-w&gt;h

" make &lt;a-J&gt;, &lt;a-K&gt;, &lt;a-L&gt;, and &lt;a-H&gt; create windows.
nnoremap &lt;a-J&gt; &lt;c-w&gt;s&lt;c-w&gt;k
nnoremap &lt;a-K&gt; &lt;c-w&gt;s
nnoremap &lt;a-H&gt; &lt;c-w&gt;v
nnoremap &lt;a-L&gt; &lt;c-w&gt;v&lt;c-w&gt;h
</code></pre></li>
<li><p><code>J</code> and <code>K</code>.</p>

<p>If you think about how Vim moves across sentences and words you will notice that it doesn’t place the cursor on the empty space between them, but rather on the first and last characters.
Similarly this bad boy makes <code>J</code> and <code>K</code> commands place the cursor on the outermost lines while moving from paragraph to paragraph.
Consistent.</p>

<pre><code>" move to the edge of a paragraph.
function! s:Move(isUp, isInVisual)
  if a:isInVisual
    normal! gv
  end
  let curpos = getcurpos()
  let firstline='\(^\s*\n\)\zs\s*\S\+'
  let lastline ='\s*\S\+\ze\n\s*$'
  let flags = 'Wn'. (a:isUp ? 'b' : '')
  " Move to first or last line of paragraph, or to the beginning/end of file
  let pat = '\('.firstline.'\|'.lastline.'\)\|\%^\|\%$'
  " make sure cursor moves and search does not get stuck on current line
  call cursor(line('.'), a:isUp ? 1 : col('$'))
  let target=search(pat, flags)
  if target &gt; 0
    let curpos[1]=target
    let curpos[2]=curpos[4]
  end
  call setpos('.',curpos)
endfu

" H K L J for moving to paragraph edge
nnoremap &lt;silent&gt; J :&lt;c-u&gt;call &lt;sid&gt;Move(0, 0)&lt;cr&gt;
nnoremap &lt;silent&gt; K :&lt;c-u&gt;call &lt;sid&gt;Move(1, 0)&lt;cr&gt;
vnoremap &lt;silent&gt; J :&lt;c-u&gt;call &lt;sid&gt;Move(0, 1)&lt;cr&gt;
vnoremap &lt;silent&gt; K :&lt;c-u&gt;call &lt;sid&gt;Move(1, 1)&lt;cr&gt;
onoremap J V:call &lt;sid&gt;Move(0, 0)&lt;cr&gt;
onoremap K V:call &lt;sid&gt;Move(1, 0)&lt;cr&gt;
</code></pre></li>
<li><p><code>ge</code></p>

<p>To understand the inconsistency with <code>ge</code> consider how Vim behaves across 4 distinct commands:</p>

<pre><code>Cursor position       Command        Result
------------------------------------------------
word1 word2           de             wo word2
  ^                   dw             woword2

word1 word2           db             word1 rd2
        ^             dge            wordd2
</code></pre>

<p>Note that <code>dge</code> is inconsistent in two ways: first, unlike <code>db</code>, it deletes the character under the cursor; second, unlike <code>dw</code>, it deletes the last character of the word it moves towards.
Remap below made it more consistent.</p>

<pre><code>" make commands with ge consistent with b and w
onoremap ge :execute "normal! " . v:count1 . "ge&lt;space&gt;"&lt;cr&gt;
</code></pre></li>
<li><p><code>&amp;</code></p>

<p>Here remap makes the substitution repeat command reuse the flags of the previous invocation.</p>

<pre><code>" make substitution repeat to reuse last flags
nnoremap &amp; :&amp;&amp;&lt;cr&gt;
xnoremap &amp; :&amp;&amp;&lt;cr&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>Let that be the end of examples.
I had many more but you probably get the point by now.
The simple truth is that my thousand line vimrc file didn’t give me any comfort.
The feeling I had when I opened it up is best described as a kind of anxiety.
I often felt a weird push to improve it, organize it better, make it more consistent.
Until one day I had enough and pressed delete.</p></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="afreshstart">A fresh start</h2>

<p>So, no more vimrc.
It did feel sloppy, at first.
But I quickly found a new way to get around.</p>

<p>Some of the issues with highly customized configuration files are known to everyone.
You have to use a plugin to manage your plugins; have to transfer dotfiles across different servers; lose the ability to work on machines without your configuration files; others cannot use your computer without disabling your setup first.
Removing the heavy configuration got rid of those downsides.
But in addition I noticed a few additional less talked about benefits which are listed below.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Reduced confusion</p>

<p>When my vimrc grew, it became harder to remember all the maps and remaps that were in there.
So when adjusting configuration sometimes I would overwrite my previous mappings and other times I would apply the same “consistency fix” twice, in two slightly different ways, ending up with two different keys being remapped to the same operation.
In general changing things or reading and searching the help pages became cumbersome.</p>

<p>And proper fixes are often hard, harder than you might think.
Take even the simplest example: making <code>cw</code> consistent with <code>dw</code>.
Maybe some haven’t noticed but in Vim <code>cw</code> behaves like <code>ce</code>: it changes text to the end of the current word, not to the beginning of the next word.
It looks like an easy thing to change but the best known implementation is close to 20 lines of vimscript<a href="#fn:3" id="fnref:3" title="see footnote"><sup>○</sup></a>, and there is no guarantee that it is perfect.
You always have to track various edge cases and add checks for different modes, empty lines, end of file situations.
Without such careful treatment the fix will be inconsistent itself.</p>

<p>In addition some consistency bandages themselves introduced inconsistencies in other places.
As an example take the remap between colon and comma.
Remember - I remapped colon to be consistent with semicolon and transferred the original command-line operation to backtick.
But this left <code>g;</code> and <code>g,</code> unadjusted which is, you guessed it, still inconsistent.
Even if we adjust them the <code>":</code> register is still there.
So, to redo the last command-line operation I still have to call <code>@:</code> even if my command-line operation itself is now under backtick.
Those inconsistencies never end.</p></li>
<li><p>Increased flexibility</p>

<p>I became accustomed to my simplified mappings and slowly but surely lost the ability to control more complex commands.
A good example is my <code>&lt;leader&gt;R</code> map:</p>

<pre><code>nnoremap &lt;leader&gt;R :belowright 20split | terminal R --no-save --no-restore&lt;cr&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>It opened up a <code>:terminal</code> buffer below the current window, set it to 20 lines in height, and launched R in it.
Sweet little command, right?
Well yes.
But it only allowed me to open R in a fixed size window.
It somehow took away my knowledge of opening a window anywhere, in any size, and running any command in it.
I got used to this simplicity so much I was no longer able to open python in a 30 line height window without checking the syntax of my R remap in the vimrc first.</p>

<p>Using registers is another good example.
One map I had was <code>&lt;leader&gt;y</code> which copied the text into the system clipboard.
Simple, convenient, and fast.
When it was no longer there I was forced to issue the full command, which is <code>"+y</code>.
It may be slightly less convenient but seeing and using this syntax makes it clear what is going on and it naturally encourages the use of different registers.
When I got in the habit of yanking text into the <code>+</code> register my usage of custom registers became much more frequent as a side effect.
A new side of Vim, previously layered by my custom remaps, opened up and expanded.</p>

<p>Similar thing happened with yanking text and using it to replace another piece of text.
It is a common enough procedure and so I turned to plugins for help.
Using a plugin<a href="#fn:4" id="fnref:4" title="see footnote"><sup>○</sup></a> was convenient.
It was so convenient that I didn’t have to think about it, just yank text, issue an operator, define a motion, and bam - the replacement took place.
After I …</p></li></ul></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://karolis.koncevicius.lt/posts/porn_zen_and_vimrc/">http://karolis.koncevicius.lt/posts/porn_zen_and_vimrc/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://karolis.koncevicius.lt/posts/porn_zen_and_vimrc/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24804899</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 20:47:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Polyform Licenses]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 62 | Comments 20 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24804223">thread link</a>) | @GordonS
<br/>
October 16, 2020 | https://polyformproject.org/licenses/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://polyformproject.org/licenses/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure><img loading="lazy" width="191" height="191" src="https://polyformproject.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Strict-PNG-1.png" alt="" srcset="https://polyformproject.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Strict-PNG-1.png 191w, https://polyformproject.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Strict-PNG-1-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 191px) 100vw, 191px"></figure><p><a href="https://polyformproject.org/licenses/strict/1.0.0">PolyForm Strict</a> removes permission to distribute copies and make changes, leaving only permission to use for noncommercial purposes.  

</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://polyformproject.org/licenses/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24804223</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 19:35:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Zeptoseconds: New world record in short time measurement]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 208 | Comments 84 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24804165">thread link</a>) | @Tomte
<br/>
October 16, 2020 | https://www.goethe-university-frankfurt.de/93203693/Zeptoseconds__New_world_record_in_short_time_measurement?locale=en | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.goethe-university-frankfurt.de/93203693/Zeptoseconds__New_world_record_in_short_time_measurement?locale=en">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.goethe-university-frankfurt.de/93203693/Zeptoseconds__New_world_record_in_short_time_measurement?locale=en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24804165</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 19:30:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[GDPR watchdog: tracking and consent popups unlawful]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 97 | Comments 62 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24803904">thread link</a>) | @gingerlime
<br/>
October 16, 2020 | https://www.iccl.ie/news/gdpr-watchdogs-investigation-finds-that-tracking-and-consent-pop-ups-used-by-google-and-other-major-websites-and-apps-are-unlawful/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.iccl.ie/news/gdpr-watchdogs-investigation-finds-that-tracking-and-consent-pop-ups-used-by-google-and-other-major-websites-and-apps-are-unlawful/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div><main id="main-content-container"><article aria-label="GDPR watchdog’s investigation finds that tracking and consent pop-ups used by Google and other major websites and apps are unlawful."><div>
<p>The Belgian Data Protection Authority (APD-GBA) has found serious GDPR infringements in the system Google and others use to legitimise online tracking. The system behind nearly all of the consent messages that pop up on screens in Europe has been found to infringe the GDPR. The APD-GBA is the lead enforcer on this issue for the EU.</p>



<p>The system is known as the “Transparency &amp; Consent Framework (TCF)”. It was introduced by the tracking industry’s standards body, the Interactive Advertising Bureau (IAB) as an attempt to convince enforcers that online advertising’s controversial “Real-Time Bidding” (RTB) system was compliant with the GDPR. Google started to use the TCF this year.</p>



<p>But the IAB’s system allows companies to swap sensitive information about people, even when this has not been authorised. According to the Belgian Data Protection Authority’s Inspectorate Service, </p>



<blockquote><p><em>“IAB Europe’s approach demonstrates that it neglects the risks that would impact on the rights and freedoms of data subjects”. &nbsp;</em></p></blockquote>



<p>RTB operates behind the scenes on websites and apps. It constantly broadcasts the private things that people do and watch online to tracking companies. It also tells them where we are in the real world. There is no way of limiting what then happens to any of these data.</p>



<p>Europe’s RTB advertising market was worth €6.7bn in 2019. There is no estimate of the market value of personal data gathered through the RTB system. However, publishers have been increasingly worried about the theft of their audiences through the RTB system.</p>



<p>According to the Belgian Data Protection Authority’s Inspectorate Service, the IAB does not provide adequate controls for the processing of the most intimate data, which the GDPR calls “special category” data. &nbsp;Last month the Irish Council for Civil Liberties <a href="https://www.iccl.ie/human-rights/info-privacy/rtb-data-breach-2-years-on/">revealed that RTB data was used to profile LGBT+ people to influence a national election</a>, and that RTB data had been used to profile victims of incest and sexual abuse.</p>



<p>The Belgian findings come as part of a campaign of GDPR complaints against the RTB data breach launched two years ago by <a href="https://www.iccl.ie/staff/dr-johnny-ryan/">Dr Johnny Ryan</a> of the Irish Council for Civil Liberties, who was then a tech executive. He said: </p>



<blockquote><p><em>“the pop-ups that plague us tens of times a day were an attempt to paint a thin legal veneer over the vast data breach at the heart of the behavioural advertising system. The Belgian Data Protection Authority is rightly peeling this veneer off, and exposing massive illegality in online behavioural advertising”</em>.</p></blockquote>



<p><strong>United States</strong></p>



<p>The IAB offers legal guidance to the global tracking industry. In October it began to market a system based on the TCF for California’s new privacy law, the CCPA. In August, it launched the IAB Privacy Lab, to lobby lawmakers and produce variants of the TCF for regional laws.</p>



<p>But the Belgian privacy watchdog has now found that even the privacy policy on the IAB’s own website infringes the GDPR, and that the IAB has failed to appoint a data protection officer. </p>



<p>Pierre Dewitte, of the University of Leuven, a complainant, said</p>



<blockquote><p><em>“the findings about the IAB’s poor internal GDPR compliance show its lack of expertise, or interest, in the most elementary aspects of data protection and privacy law”</em>. &nbsp;</p></blockquote>



<p>The Belgian authority’s report says <em>“the Inspection Service believes that IAB Europe is trying to avoid its liability to the GDPR, constituting an aggravating circumstance”</em>. </p>



<p>Ravi Naik, solicitor who worked on the original complaints, said </p>



<blockquote><p><em>“These findings are damning and overdue. As the standard setters, the IAB is responsible for breaches of the GDPR. Their supervisory authority has rightly found that the IAB “neglects” the risks to data subjects. The IAB’s responsibility now is to stop these&nbsp;breaches”</em>.</p></blockquote>



<p>The Belgian Data Protection Authority’s Inspectorate Service has forwarded its findings to the Litigation Chamber, and action will be taken in early 2021. </p>



<p>Dr Jef Ausloos, of University of Amsterdam, a complaint, said </p>



<blockquote><p><em>“I am happy to see a data protection authority resolve to take on the tracking industry. This may be the first step in taking down surveillance capitalism”. </em></p></blockquote>



<p><strong>Who is involved in the RTB campaign?</strong></p>



<p>There are 22 RTB complainants, individuals and organisations, in 16 EU Member States. They are Dr Johnny Ryan, Senior Fellow of the Irish Council for Civil Liberties; Jim Killock Executive Director of the Open Rights Group; Dr Michael Veale of the Turing Institute; Katarzyna Szymielewicz, CEO of the Panoptykon Foundation; Evelyn Austin, Director of Bits of Freedom; Gemma Galdon Clavell, CEO of the Eticas Foundation; Jose Belo; Dr Jef Ausloos of the University of Amsterdam; Pierre Dewitte of the University of Leuven; Liberties.eu; the Society for Civil Rights; Digitale courage; Ligue des droits humains; Digitale Gesellschaft; Netzwerk Datenschutzexpertise; Deutsche Vereinigung für Datenschutz; the Italian Coalition for Civil Rights and Freedoms; the Bulgarian Helsinki Committee; the Association for the Defense of Human Rights in Romania; the Italian Coalition for Civil Rights and Freedoms; the Estonian Human Rights Centre; the Peace Institute.</p>
</div></article></main></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.iccl.ie/news/gdpr-watchdogs-investigation-finds-that-tracking-and-consent-pop-ups-used-by-google-and-other-major-websites-and-apps-are-unlawful/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24803904</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 19:00:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Uninstall Nano Defender]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 300 | Comments 77 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24803740">thread link</a>) | @resynth1943
<br/>
October 16, 2020 | https://resynth1943.net/articles/uninstall-nano-defender-immediately/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://resynth1943.net/articles/uninstall-nano-defender-immediately/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="content">
		
<p>On the 3rd of October, 2020, Hugo Xu (a.k.a. "jspenguin2017") <a href="https://github.com/NanoAdblocker/NanoCore/issues/362">announced</a> he had sold Nano to "a team of Turkish developers". No further information was posted.</p>
<p>This immediately aroused suspicion. Who <em>are</em> these "Turkish developers"? Who controls the code? Why has the Privacy Policy been removed?</p>
<p>Fast forward 12 days later, Raymond Hill (developer of uBlock Origin) started to <a href="https://github.com/NanoAdblocker/NanoCore/issues/362#issuecomment-709428210">dig deeper</a>. Raymond inspected the modifications added by the new developers (which was not published to GitHub), revealing their dubious intentions.</p>
<p>The extension transmits your data to an <a href="https://def.dev-nano.com/">unknown server</a>, sending information about web requests (which may contain confidential information). This is a backdoor, and presents a <em>major</em> privacy risk to users of the Nano suite.</p>
<hr>
<p>Shortly after, these same "Turkish developers" published a <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/nano-dev">Privacy Policy</a>.</p>
<p>Despite working <em>without</em> collecting data, the new Nano developers have chosen to collect the following data:</p>
<ol>
<li>Your IP Address,</li>
<li>Your Country,</li>
<li>URL's,</li>
<li>Time of your web requests,</li>
<li>HTTP Methods <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Methods">(POST, GET, HEAD, etc.)</a></li>
<li>Size of HTTP Responses,</li>
<li><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Response_codes">(HTTP Status Response Codes)</a></li>
<li>Your Operating System and "other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User's IT environment",</li>
<li>Time spent on each web page,</li>
<li>URL's navigated in the application.</li>
</ol>
<p>If that's not enough, the new developers have not released an official statement.</p>
<hr>
<p>So, what can you do? Remove this extension <strong>immediately!</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/gorhill/uBlock/#installation">uBlock Origin</a> is a fine alternative to Nano.</p>
<p>It comes with greater stability, many more contributors, and no data collection.</p>
<hr>
<p>Remember to audit your extensions frequently, and remove any unused extensions.</p>
<p>In the case of Nano Defender, users were not notified before control of the extension was transferred to a third-party. That's not the right way to handle this.</p>
<p>Hopefully, we can learn from this and move forward.</p>
<p>UPDATE: I've just been told that LiCybora, the author of the Firefox Nano extensions, has full control over the Firefox extensions. <a href="https://github.com/LiCybora/NanoDefenderFirefox/issues/187">They're safe for now.</a></p>


		<!-- Doing a little experiment here. -->
		<p aria-disabled="true">resynth1943.article</p>
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://resynth1943.net/articles/uninstall-nano-defender-immediately/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24803740</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 18:42:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Where Are All the Successful Rationalists?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 90 | Comments 122 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24803540">thread link</a>) | @jeffreyrogers
<br/>
October 16, 2020 | https://applieddivinitystudies.com/2020/09/05/rationality-winning/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://applieddivinitystudies.com/2020/09/05/rationality-winning/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
       <p>It’s been 13 years since Yudkowsky published the sequences, and 11 years since he wrote “<a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/4ARtkT3EYox3THYjF/rationality-is-systematized-winning">Rationality is Systematized Winning</a>“.</p>
<p>So where are all the winners?</p>
<p>The people that jump to mind are Nick Bostrom (Oxford Professor of Philosophy, author), Holden Karnofsky and Elie Hassenfeld (run OpenPhil and GiveWell, directing ~300M in annual donations) and Will MacAskill (Oxford Professor of Philosophy, author).</p>
<p>But somehow that feels like cheating. We know rationalism is a good meme, so it doesn’t seem fair to cite people whose accomplishments are largely built off of convincing someone else that rationalism is important. They’re successful, but at a meta-level, only in the same way Steve Bannon is successful, and to a much lesser extent.</p>
<p>By comparison, Miyamoto Musashi, who Yudkowsky quotes extensively in the post, and who coined the phrase “the Ichi school is the spirit of winning”, appears to have been one of the greatest swordsmen of his era. According to <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miyamoto_Musashi#First_duel">Wikipedia</a>, he:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fought duels against the most famous schools in Kyoto, and never lost</li>
<li>Defeated an “adept” at age 13</li>
<li>Was granted the title “Unrivaled Under Heaven” by the shogun at 21</li>
<li>Single handedly ended the Yoshioka School by defeating 3 masters, and then a <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yoshioka-ry%C5%AB">70 person ambush</a> of followers</li>
</ul>
<p>One explanation is that rationalism entails a particular value system that guides rationalists away from becoming prominent politicians or entrepreneurs. This isn’t obviously absurd. Very successful people are often described as ambitious, smart and hardworking, but rarely as intellectually honest. Analogously, Ecclesiastical orders often had the highest literacy rates, but had philosophical objections to using that leverage to gain influence in other spheres.</p>
<p>Except that they totally did anyway. Pope Urban II initiated the crusades, a holy war of massive proportions. Pope Clement VII was so influential that King Henry VIII had to leave the church and invent in Anglicanism just to escape. And Pope Innocent III claimed influence over all the kings of Europe, single handedly annulled the Magna Carta, and in an act of nominative anti-determinism, directed the sack of Constantiple.</p>
<p>Even today, churches are enormously powerful and wealthy. The <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Finances_of_The_Church_of_Jesus_Christ_of_Latter-day_Saints#:~:text=After%20the%20Time%20article%20was,at%20%2425%20to%20%2430%20billion.">LDS</a> has an estimated $5B in annual revenue, with <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-mormon-church-amassed-100-billion-it-was-the-best-kept-secret-in-the-investment-world-11581138011">an estimated $100B</a> in funds, and <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Religious_affiliations_of_presidents_of_the_United_States#:~:text=Almost%20all%20of%20the%20presidents,Presbyterians%20being%20the%20most%20prevalent.">protestants can make claims to nearly every US president</a>.</p>
<p>Even if you think rationalism is genuinely rooted in altruism, they strongly recommend “earning to give”, which ought to result in rationalists leading hedge funds, startups and so on.</p>
<p>Tyler Cowen once <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://www.vox.com/2017/3/30/15122162/tyler-cowen-ezra-klein-interview-podcast">called rationalism</a> “just another kind of religion”, but if so, it seems to be a fairly unsuccessful one.</p>
<hr>
<p>Still, no one can deny that <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://slatestarcodex.com/2017/04/07/yes-we-have-noticed-the-skulls/">they have noticed the skulls</a>. Whatever criticism one makes of rationalists, they have likely made of themselves many times over.</p>
<p>Immediately after the Systematised Winning, Scott Alexander wrote <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/LgavAYtzFQZKg95WC/extreme-rationality-it-s-not-that-great">Extreme Rationality: It’s Not That Great</a> claiming that there is “approximately zero empirical evidence that x-rationality has a large effect on your practical success”, and giving several possible explanations:</p>
<ul>
<li>Weakness of will: Even with good ideas, rationalists can’t execute</li>
<li>Specific knowledge beats out generalized theoretical knowledge</li>
<li>Noise</li>
</ul>
<p>The second is particularly interesting, Scott goes on to say that “people in finance tend to know this and use specially developed x-rationalist techniques on the job already without making it a lifestyle commitment.” In addition to specialization, practitioners have the benefit of learning a system of practice built by <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://scholars-stage.blogspot.com/2018/08/tradition-is-smarter-than-you-are.html">tradition smarter than you</a>. A person can compete against their own irrational self, but they shouldn’t expect to win against a centuries old practice.</p>
<p>What about dynamic fields, or new fields without precedent?</p>
<p>Many startup CEOs are young generalists who did not learn their craft through a career at McKinsey or an MBA program at Harvard. It’s not clear that tech entrepreneurship has a storied tradition of practice, aside from maybe the abundance of podcasts free to all.</p>
<p>A better excuse is that startup founders are just totally insane, in a way that precludes any rational or even rationalist person from joining their ranks. Elon Musk famously compared entrepreneurship to “chewing glass and staring into the abyss”; Paul Graham warned “If you start a startup, it will take over your life to a degree you cannot imagine”.</p>
<p>That’s the best case scenario where things go according to plan. The much more likely outcome is that you stagnate for years, raise money from, hire or alienate all your friends, are resented by every employee you sold on a billion dollar exit, who by the way, are the only people you ever see, all while sacrificing your physical and emotional health.</p>
<p>This should also be considered against a very high baseline quality of life. The alternative to running a tech company isn’t the median human existence, it’s being an incredibly well paid engineer or tech executive and retiring in your 30s.</p>
<hr>
<p>Speaking of baselines, what exactly should we expect from the rationalist community?</p>
<p>If it was a bunch of uneducated basement dwellers, we shouldn’t be shocked to learn that rationalism was unable to transform them into heads of state and captains of industry.</p>
<p>But the <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/2019%20SSC%20Survey.html">SCC survey results</a> paint a different picture. Over 40% of readers work in software engineering, IT, and computer science, with another 4.7% in finance and 3% in physics, 6.7% in engineering, and 3.8% in law. 12% have PhDs, another 25% have Master’s degrees, and another 40% have Bachelor’s.</p>
<p>All else equal, we should expect these people to do fairly well, or at least have the potential to once imbued with some kind of cognitive superpower.</p>
<hr>
<p>There are two possible conspiratorial views:</p>
<ol>
<li><p>The world is run by rationalists, but you haven’t heard of them. From an <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://slatestarcodex.com/2013/04/15/things-i-learned-by-spending-five-thousand-years-in-an-alternate-universe/">earlier SSC post</a>:&nbsp; “large organizations tend to have a position that pretty much controls everything from behind the scenes but doesn’t have to cope with the appearance of power”</p>
</li>
<li><p>The world is run by rationalists, but they haven’t outed themselves.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>As with all conspiracies, these views are not only crazy, but also unfalsifiable. I could just as easily claim that the world is secretly run by freemasons. From a Bayesian perspective, the evidence is equally well explained by the both hypotheses, so we should stick with our prior that there is not a conspiracy.</p>
<p>Instead, I propose the weak conspiracy, which is that many successful people have read rationalist blogs, but do not make it part of their identity. For example:</p>
<ul>
<li>Tyler Cowen: “<a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://www.vox.com/2017/3/30/15122162/tyler-cowen-ezra-klein-interview-podcast">I enjoy all those sources, and I read them. That’s obviously a kind of endorsement.</a>“</li>
<li>Paul Graham: “<a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://twitter.com/paulg/status/909070952465600512">There’s no one writing now that I admire more than Scott Alexander</a>“</li>
<li>Matt Levine: “<a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://twitter.com/matt_levine/status/795743276036923392">Does anyone else think about this [SSC] article every day?</a>“</li>
<li>Patrick Collison: “<a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://twitter.com/patrickc/status/1005903040115814400">…Scott Alexander’s deservedly famous Meditations on Moloch</a>“</li>
<li>Steven Pinker: “<a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://twitter.com/sapinker/status/1275406500492697601?lang=en">Tragedy in the blogosphere: One of the best [SSC] is being taken down.</a>“</li>
</ul>
<p>Of course, now the question is: “do rationalists become successful, or do successful people just like blogs on the internet?” We might try to infer causality from timing. As of 2009, every one of those people was already successful, which points in favor of the latter hypothesis.</p>
<hr>
<p>Instead of more theorizing, I’ll end by offering my own testimony.</p>
<p>The primary impacts of reading rationalist blogs are that 1) I have been frequently distracted at work, and 2) my conversations have gotten much worse. Talking to non-rationalists, I am perpetually holding myself back from saying “oh yes, that’s just the thing where <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://slatestarcodex.com/2017/08/01/is-it-possible-to-have-coherent-principles-around-free-speech-norms/">no one has coherent</a> <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://slatestarcodex.com/2014/09/30/i-can-tolerate-anything-except-the-outgroup/">meta-principles</a>“ or “that’s the thing where <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://meaningness.com/eggplant/refrigerator">facts are purpose-dependent</a>“. Talking to rationalists is not much better, since it feels less like a free exchange of ideas, and more like an exchange of “have you read <x> post?”</x></p>
<p>There are some specific areas where rationality might help, like using Yudkowsky’s <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://equilibriabook.com/">Inadequate Equilibria</a> to know when it’s plausible to think I have an original insight that is not already “priced into the market”, but even here, I’m not convinced these beat out specific knowledge. If you want to start a defensible monopoly, reading about <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://florentcrivello.com/index.php/2018/07/29/mind-the-moat-a-7-powers-review/">business strategy</a> or <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://blakemasters.com/peter-thiels-cs183-startup">startup-specific strategy</a> will probably be more useful than trying to reason about “efficiency” in a totally abstract sense.</p>
<p>And yet, I will continue reading these blogs, and if Slate Star Codex ever releases a new post, I will likely drop whatever I am doing to read it. This has nothing to do with self-improvement or “systematized winning”.</p>
<p>It’s solely because weird blogs on the internet make me feel less alone.</p>
<p>Before reading <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://wiki.lesswrong.com/wiki/A_Human's_Guide_to_Words">A Human’s Guide to Words</a> and <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://slatestarcodex.com/2014/11/21/the-categories-were-made-for-man-not-man-for-the-categories/">The Categories Were Made For Man</a>, I went around thinking “oh god, no one is using language coherently, and I seem to be the only one seeing it, but I cannot even express my horror in a comprehensible way.” This felt like a hellish combination of being trapped in an illusion, questioning my own sanity, and simultaneously being unable to scream. For years, I wondered if I was just uniquely broken, and living in a reality that no one else seemed to see or understand.</p>
<p>So the defense of “rationality as systematized winning” is not even a causal one. I don’t claim to have benefited in any real way from rationality, nor can I really recommend it to anyone who isn’t already inclined to read these blogs. The point of winning is not to make money, or gain influence, or even to altruistically produce more QALYs. The point is that for my reality to even feel legitimate, it needs to have bearing on the consensus shared reality.</p>
<hr>
<p>Now that Slate Star Codex is gone, this project feels more necessary than ever. Substack promised to fund independent writing, but instead, has largely replaced eclectic blogs with rapid-fire newsletters that follow the news-cycle. The kinds of people who would have been rationalist writers are instead mass-producing insight-porn on Twitter, or starting Progress Studies blogs to share historical trivia.</p>
<p>A smart person would take this …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://applieddivinitystudies.com/2020/09/05/rationality-winning/">https://applieddivinitystudies.com/2020/09/05/rationality-winning/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://applieddivinitystudies.com/2020/09/05/rationality-winning/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24803540</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 18:23:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[So you want to build an embedded Linux system?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 519 | Comments 103 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24800037">thread link</a>) | @cushychicken
<br/>
October 16, 2020 | https://jaycarlson.net/embedded-linux/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jaycarlson.net/embedded-linux/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p>After I published my $1 MCU write-up, several readers suggested I look at application processors — the MMU-endowed chips necessary to run real operating systems like Linux. Massive shifts over the last few years have seen internet-connected devices become more featureful (and hopefully, more secure), and I’m finding myself putting Linux into more and more places.</p><p>Among beginner engineers, application processors supplicate reverence: one minor PCB bug and your $10,000 prototype becomes a paperweight. There’s an occult consortium of engineering pros who drop these chips into designs with utter confidence, while the uninitiated cower for their Raspberry Pis and overpriced industrial SOMs.</p><p>This article is targeted at embedded engineers who are familiar with microcontrollers but not with microprocessors or Linux, so I wanted to put together something with a quick primer on why you’d want to run embedded Linux, a broad overview of what’s involved in designing around application processors, and then a dive into some specific parts you should check out — and others you should avoid — for entry-level embedded Linux systems.</p><p>Just like my microcontroller article, the parts I picked range from the well-worn horses that have pulled along products for the better part of this decade, to fresh-faced ICs with intriguing capabilities that you can keep up your sleeve.</p><p>If my mantra for the microcontroller article was that you should pick the right part for the job and not be afraid to learn new software ecosystems, my argument for this post is even simpler: once you’re booted into Linux on basically <em>any</em> of these parts, they become identical development environments.</p><p>That makes chips running embedded Linux almost a commodity product: as long as your processor checks off the right boxes, your application code won’t know if it’s running on an ST or a Microchip part — even if one of those is a brand-new dual-core Cortex-A7 and the other is an old ARM9. Your I2C drivers, your GPIO calls — even your V4L-based image processing code — will all work seamlessly.</p><p>At least, that’s the sales pitch. Getting a part booted is an entirely different ordeal altogether — that’s what we’ll be focused on. Except for some minor benchmarking at the end, once we get to a shell prompt, we’ll consider the job completed.</p><p>As a departure from my microcontroller review, this time I’m focusing heavily on hardware design: unlike the microcontrollers I reviewed, these chips vary considerably in PCB design difficulty — a discussion I would be in error to omit. To this end, I designed a dev board from scratch for each application processor reviewed. Well, actually, <em>many</em> dev boards for each processor: roughly 25 different designs in total. This allowed me to try out different DDR layout and power management strategies — as well as fix some bugs along the way.</p><p>I intentionally designed these boards from scratch rather than starting with someone else’s CAD files. This helped me discover little “gotchas” that each CPU has, as well as optimize the design for cost and hand-assembly. Each of these boards was designed across one or two days’ worth of time and used JLC’s low-cost 4-layer PCB manufacturing service.</p><p>These boards won’t win any awards for power consumption or EMC: to keep things easy, I often cheated by combining power rails together that would typically be powered (and sequenced!) separately. Also, I limited the on-board peripherals to the bare minimum required to boot, so there are no audio CODECs, little I2C sensors, or Ethernet PHYs on these boards.</p><p id="differences">As a result, the boards I built for this review are akin to the notes from your high school history class or a recording you made of yourself practicing a piece of music to study later. So while I’ll post pictures of the boards and screenshots of layouts to illustrate specific points, these aren’t intended to serve as reference designs or anything; the whole point of the review is to get you to a spot where you’ll want to go off and design <em>your own</em> little Linux boards. Teach a person to fish, you know?</p><h2>Microcontroller vs Microprocessor: Differences</h2><p>Coming from microcontrollers, the first thing you’ll notice is that Linux doesn’t usually run on Cortex-M, 8051, AVR, or other popular microcontroller architectures. Instead, we use <em>application processors</em> — popular ones are the Arm Cortex-A, ARM926EJ-S, and several MIPS iterations.</p><p>The biggest difference between these application processors and a microcontroller is quite simple: microprocessors have a memory management unit (MMU), and microcontrollers don’t. Yes, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%CE%9CClinux">you can run Linux without an MMU</a>, but you usually shouldn’t: Cortex-M7 parts that can barely hit 500 MHz routinely go for double or quadruple the price of faster Cortex-A7s. They’re power-hungry: microcontrollers are built on larger processes than application processors to reduce their leakage current. And without an MMU and generally-low clock speeds, they’re downright slow.</p><p id="why">Other than the MMU, the lines between MCUs and MPUs are getting blurred. Modern application processors often feature a similar peripheral complement as microcontrollers, and high-end Cortex-M7 microcontrollers often have similar clock speeds as entry-level application processors.</p><h2>Why would you want to Linux?</h2><p>When your microcontroller project outgrows its super loop and the random ISRs you’ve sprinkled throughout your code with care, there are many bare-metal tasking kernels to turn to — <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/freertos/">FreeRTOS</a>, ThreadX (now <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/rtos/">Azure RTOS</a>), <a href="https://www.rt-thread.io/">RT-Thread</a>, <a href="https://www.micrium.com/rtos/kernels/">μC/OS</a>, etc. By an academic definition, these are operating systems. However, compared to Linux, it’s more useful to think of these as a framework you use to write your bare-metal application inside. They provide the core components of an operating system: threads (and obviously a scheduler), semaphores, message-passing, and events. Some of these also have networking, filesystems, and other libraries.</p><p>Comparing bare-metal RTOSs to Linux simply comes down to the fundamental difference <em>between </em>these and Linux: memory management and protection. This one technical difference makes Linux running on an application processor behave quite differently from your microcontroller running an RTOS.<sup id="footnote_plugin_tooltip_1" onclick="footnote_moveToAnchor('footnote_plugin_reference_1');">1</sup><span id="footnote_plugin_tooltip_text_1">Before the RTOS snobs attack with pitchforks, yes, there are large-scale, well-tested RTOSes that are usually run on application processors with memory management units. Look at <a href="https://www.rtems.org/">RTEMS</a> as an example. They don’t have some of the limitations discussed below, and have many advantages over Linux for safety-critical real-time applications.</span></p><h4>Dynamic memory allocation</h4><p>Small microcontroller applications can usually get by with static allocations for everything, but as your application grows, you’ll find yourself calling malloc() more and more, and that’s when weird bugs will start creeping up in your application. With complex, long-running systems, you’ll notice things working 95% of the time — only to crash at random (and usually inopportune) times. These bugs evade the most javertian developers, and in my experience, they almost always stem from memory allocation issues: usually either memory leaks (that can be fixed with appropriate free() calls), or more serious problems like memory fragmentation (when the allocator runs out of appropriately-sized free blocks).</p><p>Because Linux-capable application processors have a memory management unit, *alloc() calls execute swiftly and reliably. Physical memory is only reserved (<em>faulted in</em>) when you actually access a memory location. Memory fragmentation is much less an issue since Linux frees and reorganizes pages behind the scenes. Plus, switching to Linux provides easier-to-use diagnostic tools (like <a href="https://valgrind.org/">valgrind</a>) to catch bugs in your application code in the first place. And finally, because applications run in virtual memory, if your app <em>does</em> have memory bugs in it, Linux will kill it — leaving the rest of your system running. <sup id="footnote_plugin_tooltip_2" onclick="footnote_moveToAnchor('footnote_plugin_reference_2');">2</sup><span id="footnote_plugin_tooltip_text_2">As a last-ditch kludge, it’s not uncommon to call your app in a superloop shell script to automatically restart it if it crashes without having to restart the entire system.</span></p><h4>Networking &amp; Interoperability</h4><p>Running something like lwIP under FreeRTOS on a bare-metal microcontroller is acceptable for a lot of simple applications, but application-level network services like HTTP can burden you to implement in a reliable fashion. Stuff that seems simple to a desktop programmer — like a WebSockets server that can accept multiple simultaneous connections — can be tricky to implement in bare-metal network stacks. Because C doesn’t have good programming constructs for asynchronous calls or exceptions, code tends to contain either a lot of weird state machines or tons of nested branches. It’s horrible to debug problems that occur. In Linux, you get a first-class network stack, plus tons of rock-solid userspace libraries that sit on top of that stack and provide application-level network connectivity. Plus, you can use a variety of high-level programming languages that are easier to handle the asynchronous nature of networking.</p><p>Somewhat related is the rest of the standards-based communication / interface frameworks built into the kernel. I2S, parallel camera interfaces, RGB LCDs, SDIO, and basically all those other scary high-bandwidth interfaces seem to come together much faster when you’re in Linux. But the big one is USB host capabilities. On Linux, USB devices <em>just work</em>. If your touchscreen drivers are glitching out and you have a client demo to show off in a half-hour, just plug in a USB mouse until you can fix it (I’ve been there before). Product requirements change and now you need audio? Grab a $20 USB dongle until you can respin the board with a proper audio codec. On many boards without Ethernet, I just use a USB-to-Ethernet adapter to allow remote file transfer and GDB debugging. Don’t forget that, at the end of the day, an embedded Linux system is shockingly similar to your computer.</p><h4>Security</h4><p>When thinking about embedded device security, there are usually two things we’re talking about: device …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://jaycarlson.net/embedded-linux/">https://jaycarlson.net/embedded-linux/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jaycarlson.net/embedded-linux/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24800037</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 12:16:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[NixCon Live]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 146 | Comments 48 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24799659">thread link</a>) | @FRidh
<br/>
October 16, 2020 | https://2020.nixcon.org/live.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://2020.nixcon.org/live.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <p>To watch the stream from VLC on your computer, run:</p><p>
            <code>nix-shell --packages vlc --run "vlc https://dash.nixcon.net/dash/master.m3u8"</code>
            </p><p>or (macOS users try this one):</p><p>
            <code>nix-shell --packages mpv --run "mpv https://dash.nixcon.net/dash/master.m3u8"</code>
            </p><p>The stream will be broadcast <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCjqkNrQ8F3OhKSCfCgagWLg">to YouTube</a> as well, for devices where watching this version does not work.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://2020.nixcon.org/live.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24799659</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 11:23:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Singularity is Near: How Kurzweil's Predictions Are Faring (2017)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 69 | Comments 117 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24799258">thread link</a>) | @segfaultbuserr
<br/>
October 16, 2020 | https://www.antropy.co.uk/blog/the-singularity-is-near-how-kurzweils-predictions-are-faring/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.antropy.co.uk/blog/the-singularity-is-near-how-kurzweils-predictions-are-faring/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        			
					        			<p>Posted by Paul on January 29, 2017</p>		
        		</div><div>
        			<p><strong>Back in 2007 I was very excited to start reading <em>The Singularity is Near</em> by Ray Kurzweil which had been published 2 years earlier in 2005. As someone who'd always been fascinated by computers and technology since I started programming my first ZX Spectrum as a child, through to my teenage years programming in QBASIC, to my work as a Web Developer, I was well aware of Moore's law and very conscious of the accelerating progress in technology.</strong></p>
<p>As I started to read, it became clear that this was an exceptional book. The clarity of Kurzweil's writing, the level of detail he went in to about each concept he discussed and the content itself were entirely captivating, not least because the predictions were set to happen in the near future and would change the world in to an unrecognisable utopia. In fact, although Kurzweil says early on in the book that his view of the future is neither utopian nor dystopian, the future described is so rosy that the Singularity has also been called "the Geeks' Rapture".</p>
<p>Indeed, if Kurzweil's predictions do come true, they are comparible in their size and implications to the Second Coming of Jesus - the conquering of death and the unification of all consciousness in to one computational substrate that is to become more powerful than anything in the Universe and spreads outward from the Earth at the speed of light ... or faster!</p>
<p>The book quickly became an absolute page-turner for me and as incredulous as it sounded, Kurzweil backed up every prediction with thorough research, logic, and his own impressive credentials - Kurzweil was something of a child prodigy who programmed computers and wrote scientific papers at an early age and became the inventor of OCR (Optical Character Recognition) and the Kurzweil digital pianos and keyboards that bear his name. Kurzweil now works at Google where his job description is "to bring natural language understanding to Google" - a goal not too distant from developing an AI capable of passing the Turing test.</p>
<p>During my time as a software developer, discussions often arose about the future of technology and I would occasionally lend the book to other developers. Unfortunately, at some point the book wasn't returned and I wasn't too fussed as I'd already read it thoroughly. Recently, I decided to buy another copy and re-read it - after all, I still consider it to be one of the best books I've ever read. This time though, 12 years after the initial publication, it would be possible to see how Kurzweil's predictions had done.</p>
<p>Incidentally, Kurzweil himself has released a document describing how his predictions are faring which can be downloaded here: <a href="http://www.kurzweilai.net/images/How-My-Predictions-Are-Faring.pdf" target="_blank">http://www.kurzweilai.net/images/How-My-Predictions-Are-Faring.pdf</a></p>
<p>Unfortunately though, he doesn't always seem to be intellectually honest with himself:</p>
<div><p>"PREDICTION<br>Displays will be built into our eyeglasses and contact lenses and images projected directly onto our retinas.</p><p>ACCURACY <br>Essentially correct</p></div>
<p>In The Singularity is Near, the wording could be interpreted to mean that it is commonly <br>used, which is not yet the case, but this is likely to become the case over the next couple <br>of years."</p>
<p>Well that was 2010, it's now 2017 - where are these eyeglasses and contact lenses? What about Google Glass? Well it may still be being developed, but it certainly isn't in common use. Kurzweil also tends to mark many of his other predictions as "correct", when really they're not, even now in 2017.</p>
<p>So, let's get on to my re-reading of <em>The Singularity is Near</em>, which even for the second time I thoroughly enjoyed and took away a load more fascinating information that I may have missed on the first reading. This time I noted any predictions as I went through that we can now verify and what I found is below.</p>
<h2>On pages 11 and 12 we have:</h2>
<p>"James Watson, the codiscoverer of DNA, said that in fifty years we will have drugs that will allow us to eat as much as we want without gaining weight.<br>I replied, 'Fifty years?' We have accomplished this already in mice by blocking the fat insulin receptor gene that controls the storage of fat in the fat cells. Drugs for human use ... are in development now and will be in FDA tests in several years. These will be available in five to ten years, not fifty."</p>
<p>Well, <em>The Singularity is Near</em> was published in 2005, so Kurzweil's deadline for this was 2015. According to the NHS website however, 1,316 gastrc band operations were performed in 2012 and today we still don't have a pill that you can take and then eat what you want. It would be unfair of me not to mention an article on Kurzweil's site: <a href="http://www.kurzweilai.net/imaginary-meal-tricks-the-body-into-losing-weight" target="_blank">http://www.kurzweilai.net/imaginary-meal-tricks-the-body-into-losing-weight</a> but this has only been tested in mice which Kurzweil even says on p11 had already been achieved. I'm sure Kurzweil would disagree, but if we're being honest, there is still no magic pill available that lets us eat what we want and not gain weight.</p>
<p>Prediction: False</p>
<h2>Page 105</h2>
<p>"By the end of this decade, computers will disappear as distinct physical objects, with displays built in our eyeglasses, and electronics woven in our clothing, providing full-immersion visual virtual reality. Thus, 'going to a Web site' will mean entering a virtual-reality environment - at least for the visual and auditory senses - where we can directly interact with products and people, both real and simulated. Although simulated people will not be up to human standards - at least not by 2009 - they will be quite satisfactory as sales agents, reservation clerks, and research assistants. Haptic (tactile) interfaces will enable us to touch products and people. It is difficult to identify any lasting advantage of the old brick-and-mortar world that will not ultimately be overcome by the rich interactive interfaces that are soon to come."</p>
<p>Did the above sound anything like your experience of 2009? Because it doesn't seem anything like my experience of 2017. There are a few separate claims here, let's break them down:</p>
<ul>
<li>"Computers will disappear in to clothes and eyeglasses."<br>Nope. Computers have become our smart phones though and we're no longer tied to desktops.<p>Prediction: False</p></li>
<li>"Going to a website will mean entering virtual reality."<br>In 2009, no. In 2017, it is possible that a tiny percentage (and we're talking &lt; 0.0001%) of websites use VR and probably a similar percentage of people have an Oculus, Vive, Google Cardboard, Gear VR or similar VR headset. There is a framework to allow developers to make VR websites called <a href="https://aframe.io/" target="_blank">A-Frame</a> but it's definitely not in common use yet.<p>Prediction: False</p></li>
<li>"Virtual assistants will be satisfactory sales agents."<br>Nope, not in 2009 and not now in 2017. The closest we get is a live chat that is a bot, but as soon as the user realises they're not speaking to a real person, and that is pretty much after the very first question, they would usually rather just use a search or browse an FAQ.<p>Prediction: False</p></li>
<li>"Touch interfaces will allow us to touch products and people."<br>Sure this has existed in labs for a long time, but do we use this even in 2017? Nope, not even close. Yet another fail for Kurzweil, if we're honest.<p>Prediction: False</p></li>
</ul>
<h2>Page 312</h2>
<p>"Computers arriving at the beginning of the next decade will become essentially invisible: woven into our clothing, embedded in our furniture and environment. They will tap into the worldwide mesh (what the World Wide Web will become once all of its linked devices become communicating Web servers, thereby forming vast supercomputers and memory banks) of high-speed communications and computational resources. We'll have very high-bandwidth, wireless communication to the Internet at all times. Displays will be built into our eyeglasses and contact lenses and images projected directly onto our retinas."</p>
<ul>
<li>"Computers in clothing, furniture and the environment."<br>Well I have a Christmas jumper with flashing LEDs but I don't think that's what Kurzweil meant, and none of my furniture has a computer in it unless you count the Raspberry Pi on the shelf of my coffee table. As above, this one doesn't seem correct even in 2017. <p>Prediction: False</p></li>
<li>"A worldwide mesh will link all devices"<br>Many devices do connect to wifi and you can connect to their IP address to access a config page served by their web server, so this seems to be correct. <p>Prediction: True</p></li>
<li>"forming vast supercomputers and memory banks"<br>In the PDF linked to above, Kurzweil tries to claim he meant the Cloud, but actually I think it's clear from the text that he meant all devices that connect to the Internet will share their resources in terms of memory and processing power. While this probably will happen fairly soon in my opinion and I run the "<a href="http://folding.stanford.edu/" target="_blank">Folding @ Home</a>" software which donates spare processor time to scientists who are trying to solve cancer and Alzheimer's, and can run on a mobile device, this isn't in common use yet in 2017.<p>Prediction: False</p><p>[Update 2017-12-22]<br>Rather than a single standard for devices to share their computing resources, it might be that blockchain technology allows these resources to be shared safely and anonymously in return for a reward such as cash, cryptocurrency or the use of other resources. Some technologies now exist that share processing such as <a href="https://golem.network/" target="_blank">Golem</a> and storage such as <a href="https://sia.tech/" target="_blank">Sia</a>. If these became ubiquitous and ran on the majority of devices, the amount of computing power available would probably be many orders of magnitude greater than even the most powerful supercomputers in existence today. </p></li>
<li>"We'll have very high-bandwidth, wireless communication to the Internet at all times."<br>Correct! Indeed we do, and we use it so much that it's hard to remember that in 2005, we didn't have this.<p>Prediction: True</p></li>
<li>"Displays will be built into our eyeglasses and contact lenses and images projected directly onto our retinas."<br>Also discussed above, this one seems way off.<p>Prediction: False</p></li>
</ul>
<h2>Still talking about "The 2010 Scenario", Kurzweil continues on page 313:</h2>
<p>"These resources will …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.antropy.co.uk/blog/the-singularity-is-near-how-kurzweils-predictions-are-faring/">https://www.antropy.co.uk/blog/the-singularity-is-near-how-kurzweils-predictions-are-faring/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.antropy.co.uk/blog/the-singularity-is-near-how-kurzweils-predictions-are-faring/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24799258</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 09:57:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Elroy Lamp: A transparent LCD lamp (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 163 | Comments 40 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24798764">thread link</a>) | @schappim
<br/>
October 16, 2020 | https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/the-elroy-lamp/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/the-elroy-lamp/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-677">
		<!-- .entry-header -->

	
	<div>
		<p><iframe width="525" height="295" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/90s7JjoEIBQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><span>Elroy is a table lamp with a unique feature — the shade can dynamically change, at the swipe of a finger, to a new style or pattern to complement your mood, the time of day, or an event, all from your phone or web browser.</span></p>
<p><span>Elroy is a concept and personal DIY project. I’ll share some learnings and details on how I built it. These aren’t step-by-step instructions, but I hope they’ll be helpful to anyone that’s inspired to build their own design.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.kylescholz.com/wp/the-elroy-lamp/elroy-lamp-4c_moment-5/"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Elroy-Lamp-4c_Moment-5-1024x576.jpg" alt="" width="525" height="295" srcset="https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Elroy-Lamp-4c_Moment-5-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Elroy-Lamp-4c_Moment-5-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Elroy-Lamp-4c_Moment-5-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Elroy-Lamp-4c_Moment-5.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 525px) 100vw, 525px"></a></p>
<h3><strong>Overview</strong></h3>
<p><span>Elroy is essentially a computer with a 4-way display, backlit by a bright LED bulb. The four sides of the lamp shade are made from translucent LCD displays, and acrylic and paper diffusion layers. The light source is a very bright 35W LED bulb. The displays are driven by a single board computer running Linux and custom software to display and manage images. The lamp is controllable over wifi via a simple web app.</span></p>
<h3><strong>Translucent LCDs</strong></h3>
<p><span>I salvaged some 13” LCD displays from old laptops and found additional matching displays on ebay. I disassembled each display, removing the frame, backing layer, diffusion film, and backlight. This took some practice to get right. The LCD glass is quite fragile. I broke 2 panels during disassembly and had to find replacements. The trick is to remove the electrical tape that holds the display together without flexing the LCD glass so much that it cracks.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_712" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-712"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_184217-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="525" height="394" srcset="https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_184217-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_184217-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_184217-768x576.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 525px) 100vw, 525px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-712">What’s inside? From top: 1) A shiny white paper layer to reflect the back light 2) a transparent polycarbonate sheet with a film to scatter the back light 3) a stack of different diffusion films 4) metal frame 5) the LCD glass panel with circuit board.</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_711" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-711"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_184315-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="525" height="394" srcset="https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_184315-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_184315-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_184315-768x576.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 525px) 100vw, 525px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-711">The backlight is a row of super bright LEDs tucked into a channel in the metal frame. Some other LCD panels use a cold florescent tube instead of LEDs.</figcaption></figure>
<p><span>The remaining LCD panel is translucent: LCD displays are a sandwich of transparent glass embedded with liquid crystals and tiny transistors, surrounded by layers of polarizing film. In the photo below, I wrote a message on a piece of letter paper, placed it on a clear piece of acrylic, on top of a bright backlight. You can see the LCD display on the right is translucent, but similar to a pair of sunglasses, the polarizing film only permits a fraction of the backlight to emit through the panel.</span></p>

<p><span>Polarizing film is </span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liquid-crystal_display"><span>necessary for the function of an LCD display</span></a><span>.</span></p>
<h3><strong>Lamp Light &amp; Diffusion</strong></h3>
<p><span>Given the low amount of light emitted through the display, to create a sufficiently bright lamp, a very bright light source is needed. Also, though an LCD display is typically backlit by a light with a cold color temperature (around 5000K), lamp light is typically a warm color temperature (like 2700K). So the ideal bulb must be bright and warm.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_714" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-714"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_165238-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="525" height="394" srcset="https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_165238-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_165238-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_165238-768x576.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 525px) 100vw, 525px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-714">A 4-bulb array I experimented with.</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_713" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-713"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_165342-1024x576.jpg" alt="" width="525" height="295" srcset="https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_165342-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_165342-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_165342-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 525px) 100vw, 525px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-713">The gigantic 9″ long 35W LED bulb I chose beside an ordinary LED lamp bulb.</figcaption></figure>
<p><span>I experimented with multi-bulb arrays, and different bulb options, but settled on this 35W (300W equiv) LED bulb. This bulb is giant and takes up quite a bit of space within the shade. It’s bright enough that it shouldn’t be directly exposed — it would be uncomfortable (maybe dangerous?) to look at directly.</span></p>
<p><span>Next, without some work, the light from the bulb, when viewed through the LCD panels, would be a harsh point-light concentrated in the center. </span><span>I wanted to diffuse the light evenly across the surface and produce a textured, fabric-like aesthetic. I experimented with different acrylic and polycarbonate sheets and paper materials.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_688" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-688"><a href="http://www.kylescholz.com/wp/the-elroy-lamp/img_20190523_214720/" rel="attachment wp-att-688"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20190523_214720-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="525" height="394" srcset="https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20190523_214720-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20190523_214720-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20190523_214720-768x576.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 525px) 100vw, 525px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-688">Diffusion through mulberry paper.</figcaption></figure>
<p><span>Here’s one experiment result I really liked, but didn’t end up using. This is mulberry paper, which has a unique texture that’s simultaneously woody and linen-like, has nice diffusion properties, and transmits a lot of light. This looked great with black and white patterns and particularly complemented a Japanese lantern aesthetic. I felt like the large and non-uniform fibers didn’t work as well with a diverse set of patterns.</span></p>
<p><span>I found the best combination was this sandwich (starting from the inside):</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span>Frosted acrylic 1/8″ 90% emission (film facing out)</span></li>
<li><span>Vellum tracing paper</span></li>
<li><span>LCD</span></li>
<li><span>Rice paper</span></li>
<li><span>Clear anti-glare polycarbonate 3/32”</span></li>
</ul>
<figure id="attachment_700" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-700"><a href="http://www.kylescholz.com/wp/the-elroy-lamp/elroy-lamp-4c_moment-2a/"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Elroy-Lamp-4c_Moment-2a-1024x576.jpg" alt="" width="525" height="295" srcset="https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Elroy-Lamp-4c_Moment-2a-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Elroy-Lamp-4c_Moment-2a-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Elroy-Lamp-4c_Moment-2a-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Elroy-Lamp-4c_Moment-2a.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 525px) 100vw, 525px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-700">Close up of lamp where texture is visible.</figcaption></figure>
<p><span>The acrylic and polycarbonate sheets also add some structure to protect the LCD glass from flexing and breaking. I wrapped the edges of each sandwich in acetate cloth electrical tape to keep the sheets together.</span></p>
<h3><strong>Controlling</strong></h3>
<p><span>I needed a small SBC (single-board computer), capable of driving 4 displays. I happened to have an Nvidia Jetson Nano, which has DisplayPort 1.2 output with support for MST (multi-stream transport), which means it’s able to drive multiple displays. The Jetson Nano is a powerful, tiny computer that operates on 5V power and can run a standard Linux distribution like Ubuntu.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Screenshot_20191102-204056-576x1024.png" alt="" width="400" height="711" srcset="https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Screenshot_20191102-204056-576x1024.png 576w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Screenshot_20191102-204056-169x300.png 169w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Screenshot_20191102-204056-768x1365.png 768w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Screenshot_20191102-204056.png 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px"></p>
<p><span>I wrote some custom software based on </span><a href="https://www.pygame.org/"><span>Pygame</span></a><span> to display images, with a simple web app and server to give me control over the images.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/71ID5ujheuL._AC_SL1500_-294x300.jpg" alt="" width="400" height="409" srcset="https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/71ID5ujheuL._AC_SL1500_-294x300.jpg 294w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/71ID5ujheuL._AC_SL1500_-768x785.jpg 768w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/71ID5ujheuL._AC_SL1500_-1002x1024.jpg 1002w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/71ID5ujheuL._AC_SL1500_.jpg 1468w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px"></p>
<p><span>The LCD panels take EDP (Embedded DisplayPort) video input. Each display required an adapter from DisplayPort to EDP. These adapters are bulky and have a lot of functionality I didn’t actually need, like 12V power and brightness control for a backlight (which I removed from each panel) and a control interface for display settings. I also needed an MST Hub to break out 4 DP ports from the 1 DP port on the Nvidia Jetson Nano. This configuration is something I think I could make cheaper and more compact in a future revision, but it worked great for this concept.</span></p>
<h3><strong>Woodwork</strong></h3>
<p><span>I designed the lamp structure in Rhino3D and chose to make wooden parts from walnut. This makes the shade rather heavy, but the lamp is stable with the walnut base.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_692" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-692"><a href="http://www.kylescholz.com/wp/the-elroy-lamp/img_20190608_172549/" rel="attachment wp-att-692"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20190608_172549-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="525" height="394" srcset="https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20190608_172549-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20190608_172549-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20190608_172549-768x576.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 525px) 100vw, 525px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-692">The shade frame, glued-up, sanded, and ready to stain.</figcaption></figure>
<p><span>I cut all parts for the shade and base, then shaped them on a router table. I’m not an experienced woodworker, but this came together pretty easily. I had an adventure making tongue-and-groove joints for the first time. This is the 3rd time I’ve used walnut for a project and I always like the result.</span></p>
<p><span>The side-edges of the frame have brass threaded inserts that enable the top and bottom to attach via M2 machine screws.</span></p>
<h3><strong>3D Printed Parts</strong></h3>
<p><span>Most of the electronic components, including the power supply, SBC, MST Hub, switches, and wiring are mounted in a 4.5” square 3D printed “sleeve” that fits inside the walnut base. There is also a vented platform that connects the sleeve to the bottom of the shade.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_696" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-696"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/sleeves-and-platform-1024x780.jpg" alt="" width="525" height="400" srcset="https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/sleeves-and-platform-1024x780.jpg 1024w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/sleeves-and-platform-300x228.jpg 300w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/sleeves-and-platform-768x585.jpg 768w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/sleeves-and-platform.jpg 1334w" sizes="(max-width: 525px) 100vw, 525px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-696">Drawing of sleeve and vented platform. The sleeve was printed in 6 parts. The top of the sleeve peeks out 2 inches above the walnut base and houses the toggle switches.</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_715" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-715"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_175603-1-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="525" height="394" srcset="https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_175603-1-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_175603-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_175603-1-768x576.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 525px) 100vw, 525px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-715">The sleeve in 2 parts that fit inside the walnut base. In this photo you can see most of the main components. From the right: The DisplayPort hub, Nvidia Jetson Nano, and 5V / 12V power supply. The white cylinder on the left is a ceramic E26 light bulb socket.</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_716" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-716"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_180712-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="525" height="394" srcset="https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_180712-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_180712-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_20191106_180712-768x576.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 525px) 100vw, 525px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-716">The sleeve, ready to insert into the walnut base. I primed and painted the 3D printed sleeve. Only the top 2 inches is visible when the lamp is assembled, so the rough spots here aren’t a problem.</figcaption></figure>
<p><span>If I were building this lamp for production … or if I had access to the right tools, I’d want to make the sleeve and platform out of sheet metal to improve heat dissipation.</span></p>
<p><span>On top of the shade, I added a louvered cover. This enables the shade to emit additional light from the top, while obscuring the bulb, which is too bright to look at directly. This also permits heat to escape. I printed these parts out of translucent PETG, which has a higher plasticization temperature than some other common 3D printing filament materials. This isn’t strictly necessary because the surface temperature of the bulb doesn’t really get that hot. Even after hours of continuous use, the temperate is &lt;130 degrees Fahrenheit.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_697" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-697"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/shade-with-louvers-1024x857.jpg" alt="" width="525" height="439" srcset="https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/shade-with-louvers-1024x857.jpg 1024w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/shade-with-louvers-300x251.jpg 300w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/shade-with-louvers-768x643.jpg 768w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/shade-with-louvers.jpg 1348w" sizes="(max-width: 525px) 100vw, 525px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-697">Drawing of shade with louvers and vented platform.</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_717" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-717"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/00100dPORTRAIT_00100_BURST20191106165519731_COVER-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="525" height="394" srcset="https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/00100dPORTRAIT_00100_BURST20191106165519731_COVER-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/00100dPORTRAIT_00100_BURST20191106165519731_COVER-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/00100dPORTRAIT_00100_BURST20191106165519731_COVER-768x576.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 525px) 100vw, 525px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-717">The 3D printed louvered vent while the interior bulb is off.</figcaption></figure>
<h3><strong>Making it better</strong></h3>
<p><span>This lamp is mostly a proof of concept, but it works and looks good enough that I plan to keep it and use it. If I make another, I have a few ideas for improvement.</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span>Sheet metal. Replace the 3D printed sleeve and vented platform with sheet metal to help dissipate heat.</span></li>
<li><span>Replace the DisplayPort MST hub and adapters. These take up a lot of space and add significant expense (~$250 for the hub and 4 adapters). One theoretical alternative is a DisplayLink adapter based on the </span><a href="https://www.displaylink.com/integrated-chipsets/dl-4000"><span>DL-4100</span></a><span>, which would drive displays over USB and support EDP. I haven’t been able to find such a device on the market yet. Another option to drive displays from USB3 would be to use an SBC with Displayport Alt Mode. I would still need to adapt Displayport to eDP. Adapter boards that do this are bulky and have a lot of components because they provide power and control to the backlight. Since I’m not using a backlight, I could make a simpler adapter that just maps pins for the different connectors.</span></li>
<li><span>Finally, reconsider the closed frame design. Elroy’s shade is basically a closed box. I made this choice&nbsp; to obscure the bulb and hide some electronic components like the EDP ribbon cables and adapters. An open frame design might be possible. One idea is to backlight the panels with edge lighting so I can reduce or eliminate the high wattage bulb.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>BOM</strong></h3>
<p>Display</p>
<ul>
<li><span>4 X </span><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00ZSUCMH6/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1"><span>13.3” LCD Display. (1366 x 768)</span></a></li>
<li><span>4 X </span><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B06XC6SJF7/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1"><span>HDMI Controller for M133NWN1 (1366 x 768, 30 Pin EDP)</span></a>
<ul>
<li><span>(Note these adapters take HDMI input rather than DisplayPort, so we need to convert DP&gt;HDMI)</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><span>4 X DisplayPort to HDMI Cable (12”)</span></li>
<li><span>1 X </span><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00XXPYTAG/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_asin_title_o03_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1"><span>StarTech 4-Port MST Hub</span></a></li>
</ul>
<p>SBC</p>
<ul>
<li><span>1 X Nvidia Jetson Nano w/ SD Card</span></li>
</ul>
<p>DC Power</p>
<ul>
<li><span>1 X </span><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Enclosed-RD-65A-MEAN-WELL-Switching/dp/B01MS5JV0Q/ref=sr_1_1?keywords=meanwell+rd-65a&amp;qid=1563736666&amp;s=industrial&amp;sr=1-1-catcorr"><span>MEAN WELL RD-65A AC-DC Power Supply Dual Output 5V 12V</span></a></li>
</ul>
<p>Lights</p>
<ul>
<li><span>1 x </span><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B06XGD91KN/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1"><span>35W (300w equiv) LED Bulb</span></a></li>
<li><span>1 X Ceramic E26 Socket</span></li>
</ul>
<p>Diffusion</p>
<ul>
<li><span>1 X </span><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0006PYKFK/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_asin_title_o07_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1"><span>Yasutomo Sulphite Pulp Unryu Paper Roll</span></a><span>, Cut</span></li>
<li><span>4 x Sheets, vellum paper</span></li>
<li><span>4 X Frosted Acrylic 11 7/8″ X 6 7/8″, 1/8″, “90%”</span></li>
<li><span>4 X Clear, anti-glare Polycarbonate, 11 7/8″ X 6 7/8″, 3/32”</span></li>
</ul>
<p>Other</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01E8W9XK8/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1"><span>Acetate cloth electronic tape</span></a><span>, 15MM</span></li>
<li><span>2X </span><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B078KBC5VH/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1"><span>Rocker Switches</span></a></li>
<li><span>1X </span><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07MKLYD2N/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1"><span>Inlet Plug w/ Fuse</span></a></li>
<li><span>5X </span><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B072BXB2Y8/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1"><span>5.5MM Wire Connectors</span></a></li>
<li><span>1X </span><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07D49F3TW/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1"><span>5.5MM inner diameter adapter (for Starlink MST Hub)</span></a></li>
<li><span>1 X Cord</span></li>
</ul></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/the-elroy-lamp/">https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/the-elroy-lamp/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.kylescholz.com/wp/the-elroy-lamp/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24798764</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 08:20:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Iron, How Did They Make It, Part IVb: Work Hardening, or Hardly Working?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 106 | Comments 23 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24797376">thread link</a>) | @shalmanese
<br/>
October 15, 2020 | https://acoup.blog/2020/10/16/collections-iron-how-did-they-make-it-part-ivb-work-hardening-or-hardly-working/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://acoup.blog/2020/10/16/collections-iron-how-did-they-make-it-part-ivb-work-hardening-or-hardly-working/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>This week, we close out our four(and a half)-part (<a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/09/18/collections-iron-how-did-they-make-it-part-i-mining/">I</a>, <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/09/25/collections-iron-how-did-they-make-it-part-ii-trees-for-blooms/">II</a>, <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/10/02/collections-iron-how-did-they-make-it-part-iii-hammer-time/">III</a>, <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/10/09/collections-iron-how-did-they-make-it-part-iva-steel-yourself/">IVa</a>, IVb) look at pre-modern iron and steel production, although I ought to note that there will be at least one addendum discussing pre-modern cast iron and crucible steel (Wootz) production.  Last week, we looked at the processes used to create steel from iron by introducing carbon (rather than the modern method of producing steel from pig iron by <em>removing</em> carbon).  That process changes the characteristics of the metal, since steel is harder and more elastic (bending and springing back, rather than bending and staying bent) than iron.</p>



<p>But the chemical composition of the iron or steel isn’t the only factor in determining its hardness and ductility: mechanical processes and heat treatment also alter the internal structure of the metal.  Since the pre-modern blacksmith works with both of these – mechanical processes through hammer and heat through the ‘heats’ of forging – he cannot afford to disregard the changes that both bring.  As we noted in part III, the blacksmith’s job is not merely to bring the metal into the necessary <em>shape</em> for its final application, he also has to get it there with the right <em>characteristics</em> – the correct balance of hardness, strength, ductility and elasticity to get the job done, whatever that job might be.</p>



<p>And I should note again that different tools – and indeed, different parts of the same tool – might have very different demands in this regard.  Metal files needed to be prodigiously hard so that they could abrade already quite hard materials.  The tips of chisels and picks also needed to be very hard, to keep their shape under repeated impacts, but not so hard that they broke; some ductility to absorb the energy of impact was needed.  Armor needed typically to only be somewhat hardened (though demands of this sort get higher with gunpowder) and can be fairly malleable; the armor plate that deforms elastically on impact still absorbs the strike.  Swords made varied demands: their significant length demanded strong steel with good elasticity to be able to spring back into proper shape after absorbing the forces of swings and impacts, while keeping a good cutting edge demanded a high degree of hardness (hardness being the characteristic that determines how sharp an edge can be and also how well that sharpness can be held during use).</p>



<p>So a blacksmith couldn’t simply maximize one trait at the expense of the others. Nor could they have just one kind of steel, with just one set of characteristics for every application.  Rather the learned techniques – copied and practiced during their apprenticeship – were developed, probably over generations, by experimentation to produce tools, weapons and armor each with its own unique ‘right blend’ of characteristics, though two major methods we will discuss today (along with, of course, carbon content, which we discussed last week).</p>



<p>As always, if you like what you are reading here, please share it; if you really like it, you can support me on <a href="https://www.patreon.com/user?u=20122096">Patreon</a>. And if you want updates whenever a new post appears, you can click below for email updates or follow me on twitter (@BretDevereaux) for updates as to new posts as well as my occasional ancient history, foreign policy or military history musings.</p>





<h2>Work Hardening</h2>



<p><strong>Work hardening</strong> refers to the tendency of metals, when hammered (or strained into any kind of plastic deformation) to become harder.  In its pristine state, the atoms of a metal are generally arranged in a crystal structure, joined by metallic bonds.  These lattices of atoms are neat and regular.  When that neat, regular lattice of atoms is strained, resulting in plastic (rather than elastic) deformation, those neat regular lattices get scrunched and bent and otherwise dislocated.  This happens in iron, but also in most metals – indeed, work hardening is <em>much more</em> important in bronze-work than it is in iron-work, though it cannot be neglected in either.</p>



<p>That dislocation makes the metal resistant to further deformation (plastic <em>or</em> elastic), both increasing the hardness of the metal and its yield strength (the amount of energy you need to apply for plastic, rather than elastic deformation to take place), but at the same time makes the metal less malleable and more brittle (that is, more likely to break than bend).  This is a property that must have been apparent to the earliest copper-smiths: as they hammered their copper into shape, each blow made the metal slightly more resistant to hammering, until eventually it would refuse to budge almost completely (and possibly break instead).  But the same process works for iron, though because of the different production process for iron, it has to be a touch more intentional.</p>



<p>It is possible to reset this process through a process called <strong>annealing</strong>.  When a work hardened metal is heated up, the energy provided by the heat allows the atoms to break and reform their bonds, causing the crystal structure to return to its normal lattice and removing the various dislocations (while retaining its new shape).  To completely anneal iron, it is heated up to its annealing temperature (which varies based on the carbon content, as you can see in the chart below) and held there for an extended period, which will cause it to get a soft as possible for the given iron and carbon content.  This can be very handy if the iron needs to be cold worked (see below).</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="4840" data-permalink="https://acoup.blog/full_annealing_temp_range/" data-orig-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/full_annealing_temp_range.png" data-orig-size="314,206" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="full_annealing_temp_range" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/full_annealing_temp_range.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/full_annealing_temp_range.png?w=314" src="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/full_annealing_temp_range.png?w=314" alt="" width="485" height="318" srcset="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/full_annealing_temp_range.png 314w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/full_annealing_temp_range.png?w=150 150w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/full_annealing_temp_range.png?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 485px) 100vw, 485px"><figcaption><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annealing_(metallurgy)#/media/File:Full_annealing_temp_range.PNG">Via Wikipedia</a>, a chart of the temperature ranges for annealing, which vary based on the carbon content of the iron.</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>If the iron is not held at the high temperature, but is allowed to cool slowly in the air, it is said to be <em>normalized</em> (this process, <em><strong>normalization</strong></em>, is a subset of annealing).  As with full annealing, the heating process works out all of the little strains in metal (heats for this process range from 700 to 900°C), but by cooling it slowly afterwards (rather than holding it at a high temperature), it causes the actual size of the atomic lattice of the metal to shrink (the technical term is ‘grain refinement’ as the individual grains of the lattice are ‘refined’ – meaning ‘get smaller’), which results in a metal <em>somewhat</em> harder than in a fully annealed state.  Normalization is an important step for metal that is going to be subsequently heat treated as well.</p>



<p>Now the attentive reader will be thinking, “but wait, if heating the metal up to forging heat and letting it cool in the air resets the work hardening process – well, we’re doing that every time we heat the metal for forging.”  Indeed!  <strong>Hot</strong> <strong>working </strong>(which is what we’ve been describing so far with forging) generally does not meaningfully work harden metal for this very reason.  And for a smith working with good steel that is going to be <em>heat treated</em> (which we’ll discuss in a minute) this doesn’t matter a whole lot.  </p>



<p>But – for reasons which we’ll discuss – iron with very low carbon contents <em>cannot</em> be heat treated for hardness.  <strong>For a smith working with nearly pure (no carbon) iron, work hardening is his best option for increasing hardness and yield strength.</strong>  In this case, the iron object would typically be brought essentially to its final shape and then finished by being hammered <em>cold</em> (‘<strong>cold working</strong>‘).  While copper and bronze are generally soft enough to be almost entirely cold worked, iron really isn’t, except in fairly thin sheets, so the bulk of the actual <em>shaping</em> will still be done with hot forging, but with a final phase of cold hammering which will induce work hardening (and also, incidentally, can remove tool marks from the hot working, which might be cosmetically desirable).</p>



<h2>Heat Treatment Basics</h2>



<p>The changes steel undergoes when it is heated and cools can also alter its characteristics.  Because, as we’ll see, a big part of the effect of heat treatment has to do with the carbon atoms diffused within the crystalline iron structure of steel, pure iron and low carbon steel cannot be effectively heat treated and has to instead be work hardened in order to achieve similar results.  Heat treatment allows the blacksmith fairly fine control over the hardness, strength and ductility of the steel and can even allow for different parts of a single steel object to be hardened to different degrees.</p>



<p>For high-carbon steel, the heat treatment cycle is often called ‘tempering and quenching’ although as we’ll see it would perhaps be more accurate to call the process <em><strong>hardening, quenching and tempering</strong></em> (and then quenching one more time) to get the correct order.  It is something of an irony that first, intense <em>quenching</em> of raw, red-hot steel (the second quenching is much less dramatic as it occurs at much lower temperatures) – almost always shown as the <em>final</em> step in blacksmithing in film or video games – is essentially never the final step, for reasons that will soon become apparent.</p>



<p>First, some complicated metallurgy and then we’ll get to the actual real world processes a blacksmith would use.  High carbon steel is initially a mix of two kinds of iron, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Allotropes_of_iron"><strong>ferrite</strong> </a>and <strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cementite">cementite</a></strong>, the former being a cubic atomic structure of pure iron, whereas the later is an iron-carbide (Fe<sub>3</sub>C for the curious).  If that steel is heated above 912°C (but not melted), something interesting starts to happen: the ferrite structure changes into <strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Austenite">austenite</a></strong>.  Avoiding the deep weeds of metallurgy here, all we need to know is that austenite is a <em>different</em> cube of iron that is able to absorb carbon atoms, pulling them out of the cementite and trapping them inside the individual austentite structures.</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="4836" data-permalink="https://acoup.blog/1920px-ironalfairongamma-svg_/" data-orig-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/1920px-ironalfairongamma.svg_.png" data-orig-size="1920,960" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="1920px-ironalfairongamma.svg_" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/1920px-ironalfairongamma.svg_.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/1920px-ironalfairongamma.svg_.png?w=1024" src="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/1920px-ironalfairongamma.svg_.png?w=1024" alt="" srcset="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/1920px-ironalfairongamma.svg_.png?w=1024 1024w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/1920px-ironalfairongamma.svg_.png?w=150 150w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/1920px-ironalfairongamma.svg_.png?w=300 300w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/1920px-ironalfairongamma.svg_.png?w=768 768w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/1920px-ironalfairongamma.svg_.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Austenite#/media/File:IronAlfa&amp;IronGamma.svg">Via Wikipedia</a>, the structure of ferrite (left, also called α-iron) vs. austenite (right, also called γ-iron).</figcaption></figure>



<p>Austenite is neat but unstable at room temperature without the addition of alloys (particularly nickel in stainless steel) that our blacksmith doesn’t have.  If the austenite is allowed to cool slowly, it will slowly reorder itself, forming back into cementite and ferrite, often in a layering pattern called <strong>pearlit…</strong></p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/10/16/collections-iron-how-did-they-make-it-part-ivb-work-hardening-or-hardly-working/">https://acoup.blog/2020/10/16/collections-iron-how-did-they-make-it-part-ivb-work-hardening-or-hardly-working/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://acoup.blog/2020/10/16/collections-iron-how-did-they-make-it-part-ivb-work-hardening-or-hardly-working/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24797376</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 04:10:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The UNIX Time-Sharing System (1974)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 89 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24797312">thread link</a>) | @chsasank
<br/>
October 15, 2020 | https://chsasank.github.io/classic_papers/unix-time-sharing-system.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://chsasank.github.io/classic_papers/unix-time-sharing-system.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>

  

  <p><span>Dennis M. Ritchie and Ken Thompson</span> |
    <time datetime="
      
        1974 July
      
    ">
      
        1974 July
      
    </time> |
    
    
      
          56
      
           minutes to read.
      
    
   
  </p>

  <section>
    <blockquote>
  <p><strong>NOTE</strong>: This is <em>not</em> my article. This is a classic paper originally published in <em>Communications of the ACM</em>, 1974 by Dennis M. Ritchie and Ken Thompson. Yellow highlights/annotations are my own. <a onclick="disableHighlight()" href="#">Disable them.</a></p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="abstract">Abstract</h2>

<p>UNIX is a general-purpose, multi-user, interactive operating system for the Digital Equipment Corporation PDP-11/40 and 11/45 computers. It offers a number of features seldom found even in larger operating systems, including: (1) a hierarchical file system incorporating demountable volumes; (2) compatible file, device, and inter-process I/O; (3) the ability to initiate asynchronous processes; (4) system command language select-able on a per-user basis; and (5) over 100 subsystems including a dozen languages. This paper discusses the nature and implementation of the file system and of the user command interface.</p>

<h2 id="1-introduction">1. Introduction</h2>

<p>There have been three versions of UNIX. The earliest version (circa 1969–70) ran on the Digital Equipment Corporation PDP-7 and -9 computers. The second version ran on the unprotected PDP-11/20 computer. This paper describes only the PDP-11/40 and /45 [l] system since it is more modern and many of the differences between it and older UNIX systems result from redesign of features found to be deficient or lacking.</p>

<p>Since PDP-11 UNIX became operational in February 1971, about 40 installations have been put into service; they are generally smaller than the system described here. Most of them are engaged in applications such as the preparation and formatting of patent applications and other textual material, the collection and processing of trouble data from various switching machines within the Bell System, and recording and checking telephone service orders. Our own installation is used mainly for research in operating systems, languages, computer networks, and other topics in computer science, and also for document preparation.</p>

<p>Perhaps <mark>the most important achievement of UNIX is to demonstrate that a powerful operating system for interactive use need not be expensive either in equipment or in human effort</mark>: UNIX can run on hardware costing as little as $40,000, and less than two man years were spent on the main system software. Yet UNIX contains a number of features seldom offered even in much larger systems. <mark>It is hoped, however, the users of UNIX will find that the most important characteristics of the system are its simplicity, elegance, and ease of use.</mark></p>

<p>Besides the system proper, the major programs available under UNIX are: assembler, text editor based on QED[2], linking loader, symbolic debugger, compiler for a language resembling BCPL[3] with types and structures (C), interpreter for a dialect of BASIC, text formatting program, Fortran compiler, Snobol interpreter, top-down compiler-compiler (TMG) [4], bottom-up compiler-compiler (YACC), form letter generator, macro processor (M6) [5], and permuted index program.</p>

<p>There is also a host of maintenance, utility, recreation, and novelty programs. All of these programs were written locally. It is worth noting that the system is totally self-supporting. All UNIX software is maintained under UNIX; likewise, UNIX documents are generated and formatted by the UNIX editor and text formatting program.</p>

<h2 id="2-hardware-and-software-environment">2. Hardware and Software Environment</h2>

<p>The PDP-11/45 on which our UNIX installation is implemented is a 16-bit word (8-bit byte) computer with 144 Kbytes of core memory; UNIX occupies 42K bytes. This system, however, includes a very large number of device drivers and enjoys a generous allotment of space for I/O buffers and system tables; a minimal system capable of running the software mentioned above can require as little as 50K bytes of core altogether.</p>

<p>The PDP-11 has a 1M byte fixed-head disk, used for filesystem storage and swapping, four moving-head disk drives which each provide 2.5M bytes on removable disk cartridges, and a single moving-head disk drive which uses removable 40M byte disk packs. There are also a high-speed paper tape reader-punch, nine-track magnetic tape,and D-tape (a variety of magnetic tape facility in which individual records may be addressed and rewritten). Besides the console typewriter, there are 14 variable-speed communications interfaces attached to 100-series datasets and a 201 dataset interface used primarily for spooling printout to a communal line printer. There are also several one-of-a-kind devices including a Picturephone® interface,a voice response unit, a voice synthesizer, a phototypesetter, a digital switching network, and a satellite PDP-11/20 which generates vectors, curves, and characters on a Tektronix 611 storage-tube display.</p>

<p>The greater part of UNIX software is written in the above-mentioned C language [6]. Early versions of the operating system were written in assembly language, but during the summer of 1973, it was rewritten in C. The size of the new system is about one third greater than the old. Since the new system is not only much easier to understand and to modify but also includes many functional improvements, including multiprogramming and the ability to share reentrant code among several user programs, we considered this increase in size quite acceptable.</p>

<h2 id="3-the-file-system">3. The File System</h2>

<p>The most important job of UNIX is to provide a file system.
<label for="mn-1">⊕</label>
<span>
 S: Note how the paper considers files important. Unix exposes all the functionality through files.
</span>
From the point of view of the user, there are three kinds of files: ordinary disk files, directories, and special files</p>

<h3 id="31-ordinary-files">3.1 Ordinary Files</h3>

<p><mark>A file contains whatever information the user places on it, for example symbolic or binary (object) programs. No particular structuring is expected by the system.</mark> Files of text consist simply of a string of characters, with lines demarcated by the new-line character. Binary programs are sequences of words as they will appear in core memory when the program starts executing. A few user programs manipulate files with more structure: the assembler generates and the loader expects an object file in a particular format. However, the structure of files is controlled by the programs which use them, not by the system.</p>

<h3 id="32-directories">3.2 Directories</h3>

<p><mark>Directories provide the mapping between the names of files and the files themselves, and thus induce a structure on the file system as a whole.</mark> Each user has a directory of his own files; he may also create subdirectories to contain groups of files conveniently treated together. A directory behaves exactly like an ordinary file except that it cannot be written on by unprivileged programs, so that the system controls the contents of directories. However, anyone with appropriate permission may read a directory just like any other file.</p>

<p>The system maintains several directories for its own use. One of these is the <em>root</em> directory. All files in the system can be found by tracing a path through a chain of directories until the desired file is reached. The starting point for such searches is often the root. Another system directory contains all the programs provided for general use; that is, all the <em>commands</em>. As will be seen however, it is by no means necessary that a program reside in this directory for it to be executed.</p>

<p><label for="mn-2">⊕</label>
<span>
 S: This is a succinct description of path system of unix and Linux
</span>
Files are named by sequences of 14 or fewer characters. When the name of a file is specified to the system, it may be in the form of a <em>path name</em>, which is a sequence of directory names separated by slashes <code>/</code> and ending in a file name. If the sequence begins with a slash, the search begins in the root directory. The name <code>/alpha/beta/gamma</code> causes the system to search the root for directory <code>alpha</code>, then to search <code>alpha</code> for <code>beta</code>, finally to find <code>gamma</code> in <code>beta</code>. <code>gamma</code> may be an ordinary file, a directory, or a special file. As a limiting case, the name <code>/</code> refers to the root itself.</p>

<p>A path name not starting with <code>/</code> causes the system to begin the search in the user’s current directory. Thus, the name <code>alpha/beta</code> specifies the file named <code>beta</code> in subdirectory <code>alpha</code> of the current directory. The simplest kind of name, for example <code>alpha</code>, refers to a file which itself is found in the current directory. As another limiting case, the null file name refers to the current directory.</p>

<p>The same nondirectory file may appear in several directories under possibly different names. This feature is called <em>linking</em>; a directory entry for a file is sometimes called a link. <mark>UNIX differs from other systems in which linking is permitted in that all links to a file have equal status.</mark> That is, a file does not exist within a particular directory; the directory entry for a file consists merely of its name and a pointer to the information actually describing the file. Thus a file exists independently of any directory entry, although in practice a file is made to disappear along with the last link to it.</p>

<p>Each directory always has at least two entries. The name in each directory refers to the directory itself. Thus a program may read the current directory under the name <code>.</code> without knowing its complete path name. The name <code>..</code> by convention refers to the parent of the directory in which it appears, that is, to the directory in which it was created.</p>

<p><mark>The directory structure is constrained to have the form of a rooted tree.</mark> Except for the special entries <code>.</code> and <code>..</code>, each directory must appear as an entry in exactly one other,which is its parent. Te reason for this is to simplify the writing of programs which visit subtrees of the directory structure, and more important, to avoid the separation of portions of the hierarchy. If arbitrary links to directories were permitted, it would be quite difficult to detect when the last connection from the root to a directory was severed.</p>

<h3 id="33-special-files">3.3 Special Files</h3>

<p><mark>Special files constitute the most unusual feature of the UNIX file …</mark></p></section></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://chsasank.github.io/classic_papers/unix-time-sharing-system.html">https://chsasank.github.io/classic_papers/unix-time-sharing-system.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://chsasank.github.io/classic_papers/unix-time-sharing-system.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24797312</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 04:00:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
