<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 08:50:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 08:50:22 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[TabFS: Mount your Browser Tabs as a Filesystem]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 524 | Comments 68 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25600338">thread link</a>) | @thesephist
<br/>
December 31, 2020 | https://omar.website/tabfs/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://omar.website/tabfs/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      

<!-- I'm setting this page in Verdana-on-gray so I feel more comfortable -->

<!-- jotting random notes and stuff down. -->



<p><a href="https://github.com/osnr/TabFS">TabFS</a> is a browser extension that
mounts your browser tabs as a filesystem on your computer.</p>

<p>Out of the box, it supports Chrome and (to a lesser extent<sup id="fnref:firefox"><a rel="footnote" href="#fn:firefox">1</a></sup>)
Firefox, on macOS and Linux.<sup id="fnref:otherbrowsers"><a rel="footnote" href="#fn:otherbrowsers">2</a></sup></p>

<p>Each of your open tabs is mapped to a folder.</p>

<div>
<p><a href="https://omar.website/tabfs/doc/00-browser.png"><img src="https://omar.website/tabfs/doc/00-browser.png"></a>
<a href="https://omar.website/tabfs/doc/00-finder.png"><img src="https://omar.website/tabfs/doc/00-finder.png"></a></p><p>I have 3 tabs open, and
they map to 3 folders in TabFS</p>
</div>

<p>The files inside a tab's folder directly reflect (and can control) the
state of that tab in your browser. (TODO: update as I add more)</p>

<div>
<video autoplay="" loop="" muted="">
  <source src="https://omar.website/tabfs/doc/finder-contents.mp4" type="video/mp4">
</video>
<p>Example: the url.txt, text.txt, and title.txt
files inside a tab's folder, which tell me those live properties
for that tab</p>
</div>

<p>This gives you a <em>ton</em> of power, because now you can apply <a href="https://twitter.com/rsnous/status/1018570020324962305">all the
existing tools</a>
on your computer that already know how to deal with files -- terminal
commands, scripting languages, etc -- and use them to control and
communicate with your browser.</p>

<p>Now you don't need to <a href="https://twitter.com/rsnous/status/1261392522485526528">code up a browser extension from
scratch</a> every
time you want to do anything. You can write a script that talks to
your browser in, like, a melange of Python and bash, and you can save
it as <a href="https://twitter.com/rsnous/status/1308588645872435202">a single ordinary
file</a> that you
can run whenever, and it's no different from scripting any other part
of your computer.</p>

<h3 id="table-of-contents">table of contents</h3>




<h2 id="examples-of-stuff-you-can-do-examples">Examples of stuff you can do!<sup id="fnref:examples"><a rel="footnote" href="#fn:examples">3</a></sup></h2>

<p>(assuming your current directory is the <code>fs</code> subdirectory of the git
repo and you have the extension running)</p>

<h3 id="list-the-titles-of-all-the-tabs-you-have-open">List the titles of all the tabs you have open</h3>

<pre><code>$ cat mnt/tabs/by-id/*/title.txt
GitHub
Extensions
TabFS/install.sh at master · osnr/TabFS
Alternative Extension Distribution Options - Google Chrome
Web Store Hosting and Updating - Google Chrome
Home / Twitter
...
</code></pre>

<h3 id="cull-tabs-like-any-other-files">Cull tabs like any other files</h3>

<div>
<video autoplay="" loop="" muted="">
  <source src="https://omar.website/tabfs/doc/delete.mp4" type="video/mp4">
</video>
<p>Selecting and deleting a bunch of tabs in my file manager</p>
</div>

<p>I'm using Dired in Emacs here, but you could use whatever tools you
already feel comfortable managing your files with.</p>

<h3 id="close-all-stack-overflow-tabs">Close all Stack Overflow tabs</h3>

<pre><code>$ rm mnt/tabs/by-title/*Stack_Overflow*
</code></pre>

<p>or (older / more explicit)</p>

<pre><code>$ echo remove | tee -a mnt/tabs/by-title/*Stack_Overflow*/control
</code></pre>

<h4 id="btw">btw</h4>

<p>(this task, removing all tabs whose titles contain some string, is a
little contrived, but it's not that unrealistic, right?)</p>

<p>(now... how would you do this <em>without</em> TabFS?  I honestly have no
idea, off the top of my head. like, how do you even get the titles of
tabs? how do you tell the browser to close them?)</p>

<p>(I looked up the APIs, and, OK, if you're already in a browser
extension, in a 'background script' inside the extension, <em>and</em> your
extension has the <code>tabs</code> permission -- this already requires you to
make 2 separate files and hop between your browser and your text
editor to set it all up! -- you can do
<a href="https://developer.chrome.com/docs/extensions/reference/tabs/#method-query">this</a>:
<code>chrome.tabs.query({}, tabs =&gt; chrome.tabs.remove(tabs.filter(tab =&gt;
tab.title.includes('Stack Overflow')).map(tab =&gt; tab.id)))</code>)</p>

<p>(not <em>terrible</em>, but look at all that upfront overhead to get it set
up. and it's not all that discoverable. and what if you want to reuse
this later, or plug it into some larger pipeline of tools on your
computer, or give it a visual interface? the jump in complexity once
you need to communicate with anything -- possibly setting up a
WebSocket, setting up handlers and a state machine -- is pretty
horrifying)</p>

<p>(but to be honest, I wouldn't even have conceived of this as a thing I
could do in the first place)</p>

<h3 id="save-text-of-all-tabs-to-a-file">Save text of all tabs to a file</h3>

<pre><code>$ cat mnt/tabs/by-id/*/text.txt &gt; text-of-all-tabs.txt
</code></pre>

<h3 id="run-script">Run script</h3>

<pre><code>$ echo 'document.body.style.background = "green"' &gt; mnt/tabs/last-focused/execute-script
$ echo 'alert("hi!")' &gt; mnt/tabs/last-focused/execute-script
</code></pre>

<h3 id="get-images-scripts-etc-on-page">Get images / scripts / etc on page</h3>

<p>(TODO: <a href="https://github.com/osnr/TabFS/issues/5">document better</a>, put in screenshots)</p>

<p>The <a href="https://github.com/osnr/TabFS/blob/fef9289e3a7f82cda6319d5f19d5a5f13f3cc44b/extension/background.js#L355"><code>debugger/</code>
subdirectory</a>
in each tab folder has synthetic files that let you access loaded
resources (in <code>debugger/resources/</code>) and scripts (in
<code>debugger/scripts/</code>). (this is experimental)</p>

<h3 id="retrieve-what-s-playing-on-youtube-music-youtube-music-tabfs-https-github-com-junhoyeo-youtube-music-tabfs">Retrieve what's playing on YouTube Music: <a href="https://github.com/junhoyeo/youtube-music-tabfs">youtube-music-tabfs</a></h3>

<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/kok4dw/tabfs_mount_your_browser_tabs_as_a_filesystem/ghtbgw1/">thanks</a> to <a href="https://github.com/junhoyeo">Junho Yeo</a>!</p>

<h3 id="reload-an-extension-when-you-edit-its-source-code">Reload an extension when you edit its source code</h3>

<p>Suppose you're working on a Chrome extension (apart from this
one). It's a pain to reload the extension (and possibly affected Web
pages) every time you change its code. There's a <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/2963260/how-do-i-auto-reload-a-chrome-extension-im-developing">Stack Overflow
post</a>
with ways to automate this, but they're all sort of hacky. You need
yet another extension, or you need to tack weird permissions onto your
work-in-progress extension, and you don't just get a command you can
trigger from your editor or shell to refresh the extension.</p>

<p>TabFS lets you do all this in <a href="https://github.com/osnr/playgroundize-devtools-protocol/blob/main/go.sh">an ordinary shell
script</a>.
You don't have to write any browser-side code at all.</p>

<p>This script turns an extension (this one's title is "Playgroundize
DevTools Protocol") off, then turns it back on, then reloads any tabs
that have the relevant pages open (in this case, I decided it's tabs
whose titles start with "Chrome Dev"):</p>

<pre><code>#!/bin/bash -eux
echo false &gt; mnt/extensions/Playg*/enabled
echo true &gt; mnt/extensions/Playg*/enabled
echo reload | tee mnt/tabs/by-title/Chrome_Dev*/control
</code></pre>

<p>I mapped this script to Ctrl-. in my text editor, and now I just hit
that every time I want to reload my extension code.</p>

<h3 id="todo-live-edit-a-running-web-page">TODO: Live edit a running Web page</h3>

<p>edit <code>page.html</code> in the tab folder. I guess it could just stomp
outerHTML at first, eventually could do something more sophisticated</p>

<p>(it would be cool to have a persistent storage story here
also. I like the idea of being able to put arbitrary files anywhere in
the subtree, actually, because then you could use git and emacs
autosave and stuff for free... hmm)</p>

<h3 id="todo-watch-expressions">TODO: Watch expressions</h3>

<pre><code>$ touch mnt/tabs/last-focused/watches/window.scrollY
</code></pre>

<p>Now you can <code>cat window.scrollY</code> and see where you are scrolled on the
page at any time.</p>

<p>Could make an <a href="https://twitter.com/rsnous/status/1080878682275803137">ad-hoc
dashboard</a>
around a Web page: a bunch of terminal windows floating around your
screen, each sitting in a loop and using <code>cat</code> to monitor a different
variable.</p>

<h3 id="todo-import-data-json-xls-js">TODO: Import data (JSON? XLS? JS?)</h3>

<p>drag a JSON file <code>foo.json</code> into the <code>imports</code> subfolder of the tab
and it shows up as the object <code>imports.foo</code> in JS. (modify
<code>imports.foo</code> in JS and then read <code>imports/foo.json</code> and you read the
changes back?)</p>

<p>import a plotting library or whatever the same way? dragging
<code>plotlib.js</code> into <code>imports/plotlib.js</code> and then calling
<code>imports.plotlib()</code> to invoke that JS file</p>

<p>the browser has a lot of potential power as an interactive programming
environment, one where graphics come <a href="https://twitter.com/rsnous/status/1295828978477932544">as
naturally</a> as
console I/O do in most programming languages. i think something that
holds it back that is underexplored is lack of ability to just... drag
files in and manage them with decent tools. many Web-based 'IDEs' have
to reinvent file management, etc from scratch, and it's like a
separate universe from the rest of your computer, and migrating
between one and the other is a real pain (if you want to use some
Python library to munge some data and then have a Web-based
visualization of it, for instance, or if you want to version files
inside it, or make snapshots so you <a href="https://twitter.com/rsnous/status/1288725175895068673">feel
comfortable</a>
trying stuff, etc).</p>

<p>(what would the persistent storage story here be? localStorage? it's
interesting because I almost want each tab to be <a href="https://twitter.com/rsnous/status/1344753559007420416">less of a
commodity</a>,
less
<a href="https://twitter.com/rsnous/status/1270192308772691968">disposable</a>,
since now it's the site I'm dragging stuff to and it might have some
persistent state attached. like, if I'm programming and editing stuff
and saving inside a tab's folder, that tab suddenly really
<a href="https://twitter.com/rsnous/status/1251863115022491653">matters</a>; I
want it to survive as long as a normal file would, unlike most browser
tabs today)</p>

<h2 id="setup">Setup</h2>

<p><strong>disclaimer</strong>: this extension is an experiment. I think it's cool and
useful and provocative, and I usually leave it on, but I make no
promises about functionality or, especially, security. applications
may freeze, your browser may freeze, there may be ways for Web pages
to use the extension to escape and hurt your computer ... In some
sense, the <a href="https://twitter.com/rsnous/status/1338932056743546880">whole
point</a> of this
extension is to create a gigantic new surface area of communication
between stuff inside your browser and software on the rest of your
computer.</p>

<p>Before doing anything, clone <a href="https://github.com/osnr/TabFS">this repository</a>:</p>

<pre><code>$ git clone https://github.com/osnr/TabFS.git
</code></pre>

<p>First, install the browser extension.</p>

<p>Then, install the C filesystem.</p>

<h3 id="1-install-the-browser-extension">1. Install the browser extension</h3>

<p>(I think for Opera or whatever other Chromium-based browser, you could
get it to work, but you'd need to change the native messaging path in
install.sh. Not sure about Safari. maybe Edge too? if you also got
everything to compile for Windows)</p>

<h4 id="in-chrome">in Chrome</h4>

<p>Go to the <a href="chrome://extensions">Chrome extensions page</a>. Enable
Developer mode (top-right corner).</p>

<p>Load-unpacked the <code>extension/</code> folder in this repo.</p>

<p><strong>Make a note of the extension ID Chrome assigns.</strong> Mine is
<code>jimpolemfaeckpjijgapgkmolankohgj</code>. We'll use this later.</p>

<h4 id="in-firefox">in Firefox</h4>

<p>You'll need to install as a "temporary extension", so it'll only last
in your current FF session. (TODO: is this fixable? signature stuff?)</p>

<p>Go to <a href="about:debugging#/runtime/this-firefox">about:debugging#/runtime/this-firefox</a>.</p>

<p>Load Temporary Add-on...</p>

<p>Choose manifest.json in the extension subfolder of this repo.</p>

<h3 id="2-install-the-c-filesystem">2. Install the C filesystem</h3>

<p>First, make sure you have FUSE and FUSE headers. On Linux, for example,
<code>sudo apt install libfuse-dev</code> or equivalent. On macOS, get <a href="https://osxfuse.github.io/">FUSE for
macOS</a>. (on macOS, also check <a href="https://github.com/osnr/TabFS/issues/11">this
bug</a> -- TODO work out the
best path to explain here.)</p>

<p>Then compile the C filesystem:</p>

<pre><code>$ cd fs
$ mkdir mnt
$ make
</code></pre>

<p>(GNU Make is required, so use gmake on FreeBSD)</p>

<p>Now install the native messaging host into your browser, so the
extension can launch and talk to the filesystem:</p>

<h4 id="chrome-and-chromium">Chrome and Chromium</h4>

<p>Substitute the extension ID you copied earlier for
<code>jimpolemfaeckpjijgapgkmolankohgj</code> in the command below.</p>

<pre><code>$ ./install.sh chrome jimpolemfaeckpjijgapgkmolankohgj
</code></pre>

<p>or</p>

<pre><code>$ ./install.sh chromium jimpolemfaeckpjijgapgkmolankohgj
</code></pre>

<h4 id="firefox">Firefox</h4>

<pre><code>$ ./install.sh firefox
</code></pre>

<h3 id="3-ready">3. Ready!</h3>

<p>Go back to <code>chrome://extensions</code> or
<code>about:debugging#/runtime/this-firefox</code> and reload the extension.</p>

<p>Now your browser tabs should be mounted in <code>fs/mnt</code>!</p>

<p>Open the background page inspector to see the filesystem operations
stream in. (in Chrome, click "background page" next to "Inspect views"
in the extension's entry in the Chrome extensions page; in Firefox,
click "Inspect")</p>

<p><a href="https://omar.website/tabfs/doc/inspector.png"><img src="https://omar.website/tabfs/doc/inspector.png"></a>
</p>

<p>This console is …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://omar.website/tabfs/">https://omar.website/tabfs/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://omar.website/tabfs/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25600338</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 02:48:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Design of the Roland Juno Syntheziser's Oscillators]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 163 | Comments 55 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25598656">thread link</a>) | @cushychicken
<br/>
December 31, 2020 | https://blog.thea.codes/the-design-of-the-juno-dco/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.thea.codes/the-design-of-the-juno-dco/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p>This article is a comprehensive guide to the <a href="http://www.vintagesynth.com/roland/juno106.php">Roland Juno</a>'s <strong>digitally-controlled analog oscillators</strong> (<em>DCOs</em>). I fell in love with the Juno early in my synthesizer journey and I've spent the last year or so doing research on its design so that I could create my own Juno-inspired DCO, <a href="https://winterbloom.com/store/winterbloom-castor-and-pollux">Winterbloom's <em>Castor &amp; Pollux</em></a>.</p>
<p><img alt="Juno logo" src="https://blog.thea.codes/static/juno/juno-logo.png"></p>
<p>This article will cover a little history of the Juno, discuss the theory of operation behind digital-controlled oscillators, analyze the circuit designs for the Juno 6/60 &amp; the Juno 106, and discuss practical aspects of using DCOs. This article is somewhat lengthy and there is a <em>lot</em> of information here. I've tried my best to make this approachable for anyone with <a href="https://www.sparkfun.com/engineering_essentials">basic electronics knowledge</a>, so if you feel confused or overwhelmed please <a href="mailto:me@thea.codes">reach out</a> and I'll be more than happy to include more details or change something so that it's easier to understand.</p>
<h2 id="a-little-history">A little history</h2>
<p>Roland introduced the incredible <a href="http://www.vintagesynth.com/roland/juno6.php">Juno-6</a> and nearly identical <a href="http://www.vintagesynth.com/roland/juno60.php">Juno-60</a> in 1982. The Juno was a 6-voice polyphonic synthesizer that was an incredible value considering its array of features.</p>
<p><img alt="A photo of the Juno-60" src="https://blog.thea.codes/static/juno/juno-60.jpg"></p>
<p>The Juno notably featured <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digitally_controlled_oscillator"><em>digitally-controlled analog oscillators</em></a>. The DCO was designed to overcome the tuning instability of the usual <strong>voltage-controlled oscillators</strong> (<em>VCOs</em>) in contemporary polyphonic synthesizers. The DCOs operate with the same fundamental analog circuitry but differ in that they are controlled by a microcontroller. This imparted a unique sound to the Juno series and one that's become a favorite of many musicians.</p>
<p><img alt="A photo of the Juno 106" src="https://blog.thea.codes/static/juno/juno-106.jpg"></p>
<p>Roland followed with the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roland_Juno-106">Juno-106</a> in 1984. It offered some feature upgrades over its predecessor such as pitch bend, modulation, and support for a new thing called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MIDI">MIDI</a>. It still used the same digitally-controlled oscillator concept from the 6 &amp; 60, but its implementation is a little bit different.</p>
<p>This article will discuss and analyze both designs, but before getting into the nitty-gritty details let's take a look at the overall sound generation design of the Juno. Also, this article will refer to these three synthesizers - the 6, 60, and 106 - as <strong>the Juno</strong>, but note that this isn't necessarily applicable to later models.</p>
<h2 id="an-overview-of-the-junos-sound-generation">An overview of the Juno's sound generation</h2>
<p>The Juno has six voices. Each voice has a single oscillator that can generate three different <em>waveforms</em>. These oscillators are controlled by the microcontroller. Here's a block diagram that should help visualize the different parts at play:</p>
<p><img alt="A block diagram of a DCO-based synth" src="https://blog.thea.codes/static/juno/dco-block.png"></p>
<p>Sound generation starts with a <em>square</em> wave controlled by the microntroller and then goes through a series of <em>waveshapers</em> which generates a <em>ramp/sawtooth</em> waveform, a <em>sub</em> waveform (which is a square wave at half the frequency), and a <em>pulse</em> waveform. The frequency of the clock determines the frequency/note that the oscillator plays.</p>
<p>This is in contrast to a common design for a voltage-controlled oscillator (<em>VCO</em>) where a CPU isn't required. Instead, it uses analog circuitry to create a <em>control voltage</em> which determines the oscillator's frequency:</p>
<p><img alt="A block diagram of a VCO-based synth" src="https://blog.thea.codes/static/juno/vco-block.png"></p>
<p>Now that you've got a high-level overview of the sound generation inside of these synthesizers, let's take a deeper look at the components involved in sound generation.</p>
<h2 id="the-ramp-generator">The ramp generator</h2>
<p>Before jumping into the difference between DCOs and VCOs it's useful to discuss the similarities. As shown in the block diagrams above several designs for VCOs <strong>and</strong> the Juno DCOs are designed around a <strong>ramp generator</strong> (sometimes referred to as a <em>ramp core</em>) which creates a <em>sawtooth</em> (ramp) waveform:</p>
<p><img alt="A sawtooth waveform" src="https://blog.thea.codes/static/juno/ramp.png"></p>
<p>The ramp generator is the beginning of how an oscillator turns a <em>frequency input signal</em> into the various useful waveforms that are used to make musical sounds. For a VCO, the frequency input signal is a <strong>control voltage</strong>, hence "voltage-controlled". For a DCO, the frequency input signal is a <strong>digital clock</strong>, hence "digitally-controlled".</p>
<p>The difference in the type of input signal has a significant impact on the circuit design. Before getting into those differences, let's look at the heart of the ramp generator that's shared between both designs: the <strong>integrator</strong>.</p>
<h2 id="the-integrator">The integrator</h2>
<p>An integrator is a electronic circuit that performs the mathematical operation of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Integral"><em>Integration</em></a>. This is a fancy word from calculus but don't be afraid- it's actually pretty straightforward in practice.</p>
<p>The purpose of an integrator is to produce an output signal that changes (increase or decreases) at a rate that corresponds to the magnitude and duration of the input signal. In this case the input and output signals are both voltage. If you apply a <strong>constant</strong> voltage to an integrator, it will create a consistent increase or decrease in the output voltage over time (a <em>ramp</em>):</p>
<p><img alt="An ideal integrator" src="https://blog.thea.codes/static/juno/integrator-ramp.png"></p>
<p>More voltage means that the ramp will have a steeper slope. This is going to be helpful in generating a sawtooth waveform- the integrator ramp produces exactly one cycle of a sawtooth waveform. The trick is getting it to restart so that it creates a repeating (or <em>periodic</em>) sawtooth waveform.</p>
<p>You can create an integrator using an <a href="https://www.electronics-tutorials.ws/opamp/opamp_6.html">op-amp integrator circuit</a>:</p>
<p><img alt="A basic op-amp integrator circuit" src="https://blog.thea.codes/static/juno/op-amp-integrator.png"></p>
<p>The op-amp integrator is based on the idea that if you apply a voltage to a capacitor it <a href="http://hyperphysics.phy-astr.gsu.edu/hbase/electric/capchg.html">takes some time to charge</a>, in fact, it will charge at a rate that is proportional to the input voltage which sounds a <em>lot</em> like integration! Without going into too much op-amp theory, you can just assume that the integrator circuit will produce a voltage that increases or decreases at a rate determined by the input voltage and the values of <code>R</code> and <code>C</code>. The values of <code>R</code> and <code>C</code> determine the <a href="https://www.electronics-tutorials.ws/rc/rc_1.html"><strong>RC constant</strong></a> of the integrator - or put more simply, <em>how long it takes the circuit to charge up</em>. Remember this concept because it comes into play a <em>lot</em> in this article.</p>
<p>You can play around this with interactive illustration to see how changing the voltage, resistance, or capacitance changes the output of the integrator:</p>
<canvas id="integrator" width="1000" height="600"></canvas>


<p>The formula used to determine the output voltage of an integrator with a constant input voltage at a given time is:</p>
<pre><span>Vout</span> <span>=</span> <span>-</span><span>(</span><span>Vin</span> <span>/</span> <span>(</span><span>R</span> <span>*</span> <span>C</span><span>))</span> <span>*</span> <span>time</span>
</pre>
<p>Before going further, there are some interesting and noteworthy properties of the integrator's behavior to be aware of:</p>
<ul>
<li>First, notice that there are three ways of changing the steepness of the output's slope: changing the capacitance, changing the resistance, or changing the voltage. Making the voltage higher will charge the capacitor more quickly and increase the steepness of the slope. Making the resistance or capacitance lower will also cause the capacitor to charge more quickly and will increase the steepness of the slope.</li>
<li>Second, the output is <strong>inverted</strong> - a positive input voltage creates a downward slope and a negative input voltage creates an upward slope. This will come into play when we look at the difference between the Juno-6/60 design and the Juno-106 design.</li>
<li>Third, notice that with steeper slopes the output will <em>saturate</em> (stop increasing or decreasing). This is because a real op amp doesn't have an infinite amount of voltage to output and the capacitor can't hold an infinite amount of charge, so when either the output voltage is beyond the op amp's power supply or the capacitor can't hold any more charge the output voltage will saturate.</li>
</ul>
<p>At this point you should hopefully have a good grasp on how an op-amp integrator forms a ramp from a constant input voltage. So now we'll see how to change the circuit so that instead of a single slope it generates a repeating (periodic) sawtooth waveform.</p>
<p>A straightforward solution is to just start the circuit over - <strong>reset</strong> it. That'll start the ramp back at zero and let it start rising (or falling) again. If you keep resetting at regular intervals the circuit will keep generating ramps and which form cycles of the sawtooth waveform.</p>
<p>But what does it mean to reset a circuit? Well, it means to put it back into its initial state. Think about what <em>changes</em> in the integrator circuit over time: the <strong>charge</strong> of the capacitor. When the circuit first starts the capacitor has no charge and the output voltage is zero, but, as time goes on the capacitor charges more and more. So resetting the circuit means <em>discharging</em> the capacitor.</p>
<p>The easiest way to discharge a capacitor is to <em>short</em> it: connect its two leads together so there's nothing blocking it from discharging. You can do that by putting a little switch in the circuit:</p>
<p><img alt="An op-amp integrator with a switch to discharge the capacitor" src="https://blog.thea.codes/static/juno/integrator-with-switch.png"></p>
<p>When the switch is open the integrator behaves the same as before - its output goes up or down depending on the input voltage. When the switch is closed, it creates a circuit that connects the capacitor's leads and allows it to discharge:</p>
<p><img alt="An op-amp integrator with a switch to discharge the capacitor" src="https://blog.thea.codes/static/juno/integrator-with-switch-closed.png"></p>
<p>Once the switch is opened again the integrator starts over and begins ramping its output again.</p>
<p>Try out the little simulation below - press <code>start</code> to let the capacitor charge for a little bit and then press <code>close switch</code> to reset it:</p>
<canvas id="discharge" width="1000" height="600"></canvas>


<p>Take notice that when you press the button at consistent intervals the output is a sawtooth waveform and its frequency is determined by how often you press the button and reset the capacitor.</p>
<p>Obviously there aren't any synthesizers out there that require you to manually tap a switch at the desired note's frequency!<sup id="fnref:fast"><a href="#fn:fast">1</a></sup> So instead of requiring a person to press a switch this circuit should take some form of <strong>frequency input signal</strong> and use it to electronically close the switch.</p>
<p>The switch is the easy part - there's a well-known component that can act as an <em>electronically-controlled switch</em>: the <a href="https://learn.sparkfun.com/tutorials/transistors/all">transistor</a>. So, the ramp generator will use a transistor in place of the switch:</p>
<p><img alt="An op-amp integrator with a transistor to discharge the capacitor" src="https://blog.thea.codes/static/juno/integrator-with-transistor.png"></p>
<p>Note that I am explicitly not specifying which kind of transistor (PNP, NPN etc)- which one you choose depends on a few other factors so for now I'll keep it abstract. Notice that there's also a new resistor there between the capacitor and the transistor. This is generally a low-value resistor and it's just there to limit the current that goes through the transistor when the capacitor discharges as too much current could damage the transistor.</p>
<p>So now the circuit has a means of electronically resetting the capacitor. The next step is to create a circuit that takes a frequency input signal …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.thea.codes/the-design-of-the-juno-dco/">https://blog.thea.codes/the-design-of-the-juno-dco/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.thea.codes/the-design-of-the-juno-dco/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25598656</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 23:42:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[UK formally leaves European Union after 48 years]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 100 | Comments 209 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25598606">thread link</a>) | @mhh__
<br/>
December 31, 2020 | https://www.rte.ie/news/brexit/2020/1231/1187075-brexit-transition-end/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.rte.ie/news/brexit/2020/1231/1187075-brexit-transition-end/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section itemprop="articleBody" data-epic-field="content">
<p>The United Kingdom's Brexit transition period expired at 11pm last night, ending a 48-year history with the European project.</p>
<p>New <a href="https://www.rte.ie/news/2020/1228/1186705-brexit-eu/" target="_blank">trading rules now apply</a> between Britain and the EU.</p>
<p>Speaking on Wednesday, British Prime Minister Boris Johnson said the destiny of the UK now lies firmly in its people's hands.</p>
<p>He said his government would take on the duty "with a sense of purpose and with the interests of the British public at the heart of everything" it&nbsp;does.</p>
<p>Mr Johnson spoke of wanting a new relationship with the EU as its biggest ally, after <a href="https://www.rte.ie/news/2020/1230/1186933-brexit/" target="_blank">MPs approved the Brexit Withdrawal Agreement yesterday with an overwhelming majority in a House of Commons vote</a>.</p>
<p>17.4 million voters, or 52%&nbsp;opted to leave the EU in a referendum on 23 June 2016.&nbsp;16.1 million, or 48%, voted to remain.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The result of that referendum has dominated British politics ever since and seen the departure of two Prime Ministers,&nbsp;David Cameron and Theresa May,&nbsp;as debate raged about whether another referendum should be called, and how the result of the 2016 vote should be implemented.</p>
<p>The referendum showed a United Kingdom divided about much more than the European Union, and has fuelled soul-searching about everything from secession and immigration to capitalism, empire and modern Britishness.</p>
<p>After the United Kingdom leaves the Single Market and&nbsp;the Customs Union tonight, there is almost certain to be some disruption at borders. More red tape means more cost for those importing and exporting goods across the EU-UK border.</p>
<p>The English Port of Dover expects volumes to drop off in early January. The most worrisome period, it says, will be in mid&nbsp;to late January when volumes pick up again.</p>
<p>Walking away from almost half a century of membership means change to everything from pet passports and driving licence rules for the British in Europe to data rules.</p><hr>
<p><b><a href="https://www.rte.ie/news/brexit/" target="_blank">Latest Brexit stories</a></b></p>
<hr>
<p>After clinching a Christmas Eve trade deal intended to smooth out the worst disruption, European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen quoted both William Shakespeare and TS&nbsp;Eliot.</p>
<p>"Parting is such sweet sorrow," she said. "What we call the beginning is often the end. And to make an end is to make a beginning."</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://img.rasset.ie/00110cec-614.jpg?ratio=1.78"></p>
<p><b>Deal reached to keep Gibraltar border open</b></p>
<p>Gibraltar's border with Spain will remain open following the end of the Brexit transition period,&nbsp;after the UK and European Union agreed a draft deal.</p>
<p>The Rock's status was not covered in the trade agreement reached by Boris Johnson on Christmas Eve, prompting concerns about what would happen when the transition period ends at 11pm tonight.</p>
<p>Gibraltar, whose sovereignty is disputed by Spain and Britain, will remain subject to the rule of the free-travel Schengen area, Spain's foreign minister said.</p>
<p>Arancha Gonzalez Laya announced that the "agreement in principle" means people in Gibraltar "can breathe a sigh of relief".</p>
<p>She said that further details on the agreement would be published in the New Year.</p>
<p>Foreign Secretary Dominic Raab said: "Today, working side by side with the chief minister of Gibraltar, and following intensive discussions with the Spanish government, we reached agreement on a political framework to form the basis of a separate treaty between the UK and the EU regarding Gibraltar.</p>
<p>"We will now send this to the European Commission, in order to initiate negotiations on the formal treaty.</p>
<p>"In the meantime, all sides are committed to mitigating the effects of the end of the transition period on Gibraltar, and in particular ensure border fluidity, which is clearly in the best interests of the people living on both sides.</p>
<p>"We remain steadfast in our support for Gibraltar and its sovereignty. I am grateful to foreign minister Laya and her team for their positive and constructive approach.</p>
<p>"We have a warm and strong relationship with Spain, and we look forward to building on it in 2021."&nbsp;</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://img.rasset.ie/0015eea2-614.jpg?ratio=1.78"></p>
<p><b>Minister updates Cabinet of impact on fishing</b></p>
<p>The Minister for Agriculture has&nbsp;said that&nbsp;while trade can continue tariff-free, he updated the cabinet on the potential impacts on the agri-food and fishing sectors earlier this week.&nbsp;</p>
<p>"The main impacts in relation to administrative costs in doing trade with Britain and also health certification and SPS checks which agri-food products have to undergo," Charlie McConalogue said.</p>
<p>"There is differing assessments in what that might mean," he added.</p>
<p>Speaking on RTÉ's Today with Philip Boucher Hayes, he said there has been significant support assured already in advance of Brexit for the agri-food sector in terms of grant aid and financial support.</p>
<p>He also said post-Brexit he will be going to Brussels to fight the Irish case as strongly as possible for the fisheries sector.</p>
<p>"The Brexit adjustment reserve, we will be looking for our significant share of that in terms of the compensation.</p>
<p>"Also, in terms of working with my European colleagues to ensure we have a strong allocation of quota as we possibly can."&nbsp;</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Revenue has confirmed that its specialised Customs Service is already operating in advance of the Brexit transition period ending tonight</p>
<p>From 11pm a valid Pre-Boarding Notification (PBN) is required for all goods carried by commercial vehicles to and from Britain by ferry.</p>
<p>Revenue says its Customs Roll on-Roll off (RoRo) Service is up and running and a transport company, haulier, importer, exporter or customs agent can create a PBN for any ferry due to sail after 11pm.</p>
<p>The Customs RoRo Service was designed to help efficiently move goods and vehicles between Ireland and Great Britain.</p>
<p>The service also allows truck drivers to check, prior to disembarking a ferry in Ireland, if a vehicle can exit the port or if it is required to call to Customs.</p>
<p><i><b>Additional reporting Mícheál Lehane&nbsp;&nbsp;</b></i></p>
</section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.rte.ie/news/brexit/2020/1231/1187075-brexit-transition-end/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25598606</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 23:38:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[When Nintendo fought a device that gave Mario 'new superpowers']]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 88 | Comments 47 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25596587">thread link</a>) | @avery42
<br/>
December 31, 2020 | https://www.cbc.ca/archives/super-mario-enhancer-1990-1.5799393 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/archives/super-mario-enhancer-1990-1.5799393">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>The Game Genie could make Super Mario jump higher. But Nintendo didn't want him to, and in 1990 the game maker sued a Canadian company over the product.</p><div><p><span><span><div><div title="Game Genie's battle with Nintendo" role="button" tabindex="0"><div><div aria-labelledby="1817989699690-metadata-" title="Game Genie's battle with Nintendo"><div><p><img src="https://thumbnails.cbc.ca/maven_legacy/thumbnails/139/87/game_genie_1391x691.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p></div></div></div></div></div><span>The Game Genie was supposed to make Super Mario jump higher. But in 1990 Nintendo said the console add-on amounted to copyright infringement.<!-- --> <!-- -->2:30</span></span></span></p><p><span><p>The Game Genie could make Super Mario jump higher. But Nintendo wanted to keep him just the way he was.</p>  <p>On Nov. 18, 1990, the CBC business program <em>Venture </em>took viewers inside Nintendo's U.S. headquarters, where frustrated gamers could call for support when playing the video game <em>Super Mario Brothers</em>&nbsp;and others.</p>  <p>"<em>Crystalis</em>," said a caller on the phone with a customer service representative, with an inquiry about the role-playing game of the same name. "I can't defeat the general."</p>  <p>But, as correspondent Nora Pratt explained, the "army of kids" working Nintendo's hotline might not have to field calls about such games for much longer.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>  <h2>'New superpowers'</h2>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799671.1605209899!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/nintendo-help-line.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799671.1605209899!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/nintendo-help-line.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799671.1605209899!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/nintendo-help-line.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799671.1605209899!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/nintendo-help-line.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799671.1605209899!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/nintendo-help-line.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799671.1605209899!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/nintendo-help-line.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>"Did you use the sword of thunder?" asked a troubleshooting customer service representative at Nintendo's American headquarters.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Venture/CBC Archives)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>The reason was a product called the Game Genie, which was distributed in Canada by a company called Camerica.</p>  <p>"Game Genie is an electronic device that lets you give new superpowers to the battling heroes of Nintendo's games," explained Pratt.</p>  <p>According to the Globe and Mail, it was&nbsp;a cartridge that could be attached to a Nintendo game cartridge before being inserted into the game console.&nbsp;</p>  <p>But Nintendo —&nbsp;a Japanese company that had sold $4 billion in games that year —&nbsp;said the Game Genie was "riding on our coattails."&nbsp;</p>  <p>"They are taking our copyrighted work and changing it," said Howard Lincoln, a vice president at Nintendo. "There's no difference between what's happening here and if I were to write <em>Gone With the Wind</em> and change the characters, change the story, change the ending."</p>  <h2>'Mutilating' Mario</h2>  <p><span><span><div><div title="Trouble for the Game Genie" role="button" tabindex="0"><div><div aria-labelledby="1820732483767-metadata-" title="Trouble for the Game Genie"><div><p><img src="https://thumbnails.cbc.ca/maven_legacy/thumbnails/706/827/jump_higher_1383x788.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p></div></div></div></div></div><span>A Canadian company marketing a device to enhance Nintendo game play gets legal pushback from the video game giant.<!-- --> <!-- -->5:05</span></span></span></p>  <p>Pratt said Camerica's David Harding viewed it differently, comparing&nbsp;the device he sold for $50 wholesale to retailers to&nbsp;"any other software add-on."</p>  <p>His company&nbsp;had purchased the "world distribution rights" from Game Genie's&nbsp;British inventors 18 months earlier, and was expecting the Game Genie to generate up to 30 per cent of Camerica's revenues.</p>  <p>"Half a million plus," he said. "That's how many I plan on selling."</p>  <p>An excerpt from a TV commercial for the Game Genie "enhancer" touted its powers to make&nbsp;gamers&nbsp;"run faster" and "jump higher" with a list of retailers already selling it, including Toys R Us, <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/archives/the-240m-deal-that-meant-a-fast-farewell-for-kmart-in-canada-1.5443333">Kmart</a>, Woolco and <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/archives/the-days-when-tough-times-provided-good-times-for-zellers-1.5417584">Zellers</a>.</p>  <p>In August 1990, explained Pratt, Nintendo had filed a lawsuit charging Camerica&nbsp;with "violating their copyright, mutilating an artistic work ... and just plain stealing the fun out of their game."&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>  <p>"It makes our game boring," said Lincoln.</p>  <h2>Legal head-to-head</h2>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799765.1605626142!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/warehouse-boxes.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799765.1605626142!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/warehouse-boxes.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799765.1605626142!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/warehouse-boxes.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799765.1605626142!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/warehouse-boxes.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799765.1605626142!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/warehouse-boxes.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799765.1605626142!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/warehouse-boxes.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Without a victory in court, Camerica faced being stuck with a warehouse full of Game Genies it couldn't sell.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Venture/CBC Archives)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>"Their opinion is, it's harmful to the industry," Harding was seen telling his team after Nintendo filed a second lawsuit.</p>  <p>Both companies had hired PR firms and many lawyers in their fight to control the powers of, "the man in the red hat," as Pratt called Mario.</p>  <p>"That hat's worth billions in sales," said the reporter.</p>  <p>In February&nbsp;1991, according to the Associated Press, Nintendo lost its bid to halt sales of the Game Genie.</p>  <p>"Nintendo, the judge said, had produced 'not&nbsp;one scintilla of proof' that it had&nbsp;suffered&nbsp;irreparable harm from the sale of Camerica's device,"&nbsp;said an AP report in the Globe and Mail.&nbsp;</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799928.1605216746!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/duck-hunt.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799928.1605216746!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/duck-hunt.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799928.1605216746!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/duck-hunt.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799928.1605216746!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/duck-hunt.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799928.1605216746!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/duck-hunt.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799928.1605216746!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/duck-hunt.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>"In this business, there's no buzzword more deadly than boring," said reporter Nora Pratt as a girl was seen playing Nintendo's Duck Hunt. <!-- --> <!-- -->(Venture/CBC Archives)</figcaption></figure></span></p></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/archives/super-mario-enhancer-1990-1.5799393</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25596587</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 20:08:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pure Digital CSS, Swiss Made, Clock – No JavaScript, almost no HTML]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 133 | Comments 81 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25595439">thread link</a>) | @IceWreck
<br/>
December 31, 2020 | https://www.quaxio.com/pure_css_digital_clock.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.quaxio.com/pure_css_digital_clock.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.quaxio.com/pure_css_digital_clock.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25595439</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 18:26:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Autofocus for the 16mm Telephoto Lens Mounted on the Raspberry Pi HQ Camera]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 90 | Comments 42 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25594894">thread link</a>) | @lemariva
<br/>
December 31, 2020 | https://lemariva.com/blog/2020/12/raspberry-pi-hq-camera-autofocus-telephoto-lens | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://lemariva.com/blog/2020/12/raspberry-pi-hq-camera-autofocus-telephoto-lens">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

<p>This tutorial opens the series of articles about "Project JiJi" and describes how to add autofocus to the 16 mm Telephoto Lens mounted on the Raspberry Pi HQ Camera. In the past months, I've been working on a project to add autofocus to the lens and this is the result:</p><div><p><iframe width="100%" height="315" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PrbyPmq_Z7Q" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div><p>Adding some background to this: The Raspberry Pi Foundation offers different Raspberry Pi Camera modules since 2013. The first module (5-megapixel) was produced in 2013, and an 8-megapixel module upgrade (v2) was released in 2016. Both models have visible light and infrared versions. This year (2020), the Foundation launched the HQ Camera. This is a 12-megapixel High Quality (thus HQ) camera (Sony IMX477), which adds the possibility to use a lens with CS-mount. It is a great upgrade, but the lens and the camera lack autofocus up to now.</p><p>If you are impatient, you can find the hardware design, firmware and software on the <a href="https://github.com/lemariva/rPIFocus">lemariva/rPIFocus</a> and <a href="https://github.com/lemariva/uPyFocus">lemariva/uPyFocus</a> repositories. But, you should come back and read the tutorial until the end, so that you can understand how it works, and if you want to, you can also cooperate on this project!</p><h2><span id="software-and-hardware-657181">Software and Hardware</span></h2><p>This section includes the software and hardware needed for this tutorial.</p><h2><span id="diy-project-jiji-657181">DIY: Project JiJi</span></h2><p>In this article, I will explain how to build the project yourself. I won't go deeper in detail. These will be covered in future articles.</p><h2><span id="hardware-pcb-ordering-soldering-and-mounting-657181">Hardware: PCB ordering, soldering, and mounting</span></h2><p>As you may have already noticed, to add autofocus to the camera, you will need to order a PCB and solder and mount some parts. In the Github repository, under the folder <a href="https://github.com/lemariva/rPIFocus/tree/main/pcb">`pcb</a>`, you'll find the schematic as well as the board files for the PCB. To open those files, you'll need <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.autodesk.de/products/eagle/overview">Eagle</a>. Eagle is still free for hobbyists, thus, download and install it to open the files. You can export Gerber files using <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://support.jlcpcb.com/article/137-how-to-generate-gerber-and-drill-files-in-autodesk-eagle">this export-to-gerber tutorial</a>.</p><p>To simplify the process for you, I also added the Gerber files that you can directly send to your PCB provider. I use and recommend <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://jlcpcb.com/">jlcpcb</a>. They are fast, cheap, reliable and the quality of the boards is pretty good. Check out the setting and costs for this project in Fig. 1. Don't forget to select the LeadFree HASL-RoHS surface finish!</p><div uk-grid=""><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/70d/d54/c63/5fe8fb550b22d311339148__1285.jpg" alt="jlcpcb settings" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/70d/d54/c63/5fe8fb550b22d311339148__1285.jpg 1285w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/70d/d54/c63/5fe8fb550b22d311339148__400.jpg 400w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/70d/d54/c63/5fe8fb550b22d311339148__768.jpg 768w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/70d/d54/c63/5fe8fb550b22d311339148__1024.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1285px) 100vw, 1285px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/70d/d54/c63/5fe8fb550b22d311339148__1285.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/70d/d54/c63/5fe8fb550b22d311339148__1285.jpg 1285w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/70d/d54/c63/5fe8fb550b22d311339148__400.jpg 400w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/70d/d54/c63/5fe8fb550b22d311339148__768.jpg 768w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/70d/d54/c63/5fe8fb550b22d311339148__1024.jpg 1024w"><br><span>Fig. 1: jlcpcb settings for this project.</span></p></div><p>I designed the PCB for people with two types of skills: advanced and basic. So, if you're a pro, grab your solder and solder every element (ICs) for yourself, or, if your skills are basic, don't worry, grab your solder and solder the small hobbies boards that you can buy from the selection above. Two steppers rotate the focus and aperture rings. They are controlled by the M5Stack ATOM, which also measures the steppers' currents and offers an RestAPI to send the commands (see Fig. 2 for an basic PCB schematic).</p><div uk-grid=""><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/625/29e/b52/5feca3f70da50778861950__899.jpg" alt="Simple PCB schematic" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/625/29e/b52/5feca3f70da50778861950__899.jpg 899w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/625/29e/b52/5feca3f70da50778861950__400.jpg 400w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/625/29e/b52/5feca3f70da50778861950__768.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 899px) 100vw, 899px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/625/29e/b52/5feca3f70da50778861950__899.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/625/29e/b52/5feca3f70da50778861950__899.jpg 899w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/625/29e/b52/5feca3f70da50778861950__400.jpg 400w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/625/29e/b52/5feca3f70da50778861950__768.jpg 768w"><br><span>Fig. 2: Simple PCB schematic.</span></p></div><p>Fig. 3 to Fig. 8 show you some close photos of the design to help you to mount the elements. Fig. 3 shows you how to mount the aperture and focus belt rings. They usually have a standard of 0.8 mm pitch. So the motor pinions should be compatible with that. Fig. 4 shows the mounted motor. Check the cable color - or the order! They are connected to the A4988 drivers (Fig. 5) and that's the right connection. Otherwise, the driver won't be able to switch the electromagnets in the right sequence and the motor won't rotate. I planned a cut on the PCB so that the pinion distance to the belt ring can be modified and the motor can be fixed as shown in Fig. 6 (using a 2.5 mm screw) - not the best way, but it works ;). To fix the camera to the board, I used a 3/8 inch screw and an adapter to mount that to a tripod (see Fig. 7). The screw fixes the camera to the board. The camera tends to rotate, and it releases the screw. If that's the case, you can fix it using the two 3mm holes on the left of the camera base (see Fig. 8) with an e.g. rectangular piece of wood over the board. Finally, you need to mount the INA219 and two pinheads for the M5Stack ATOM Matrix. The INA219 measures the current of the steppers, which are used to identify the rotational limits of the focus and aperture rings. Therefore, after booting, the system calibrates itself and it doesn't require encoders to measure the steppers positions.</p><div uk-grid=""><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/028/bde/13d/5fe90f321ecc9579624920__300.jpg" alt="Focus and aperture ring belts" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/028/bde/13d/5fe90f321ecc9579624920__300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/028/bde/13d/5fe90f321ecc9579624920__300.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/028/bde/13d/5fe90f321ecc9579624920__300.jpg 300w"><br><span>Fig. 3: Focus and aperture ring belts.</span></p><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/df5/25f/3b1/5fe90f2482bd7006993442__300.jpg" alt="Motor connection and gear mouting" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/df5/25f/3b1/5fe90f2482bd7006993442__300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/df5/25f/3b1/5fe90f2482bd7006993442__300.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/df5/25f/3b1/5fe90f2482bd7006993442__300.jpg 300w"><br><span>Fig. 4: Motor connection and gear mouting.</span></p><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/4bc/2a4/32c/5fe910d944bfb013963036__300.jpg" alt="A4988 Motor stepper driver" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/4bc/2a4/32c/5fe910d944bfb013963036__300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/4bc/2a4/32c/5fe910d944bfb013963036__300.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/4bc/2a4/32c/5fe910d944bfb013963036__300.jpg 300w"><br><span>Fig. 5: A4988 Motor stepper driver.</span></p><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/b09/476/b07/5fe90f2b34a72694523645__300.jpg" alt="Motor fixing" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/b09/476/b07/5fe90f2b34a72694523645__300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/b09/476/b07/5fe90f2b34a72694523645__300.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/b09/476/b07/5fe90f2b34a72694523645__300.jpg 300w"><br><span>Fig. 6: Motor fixing.</span></p><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/b6f/13c/272/5fe90f3b8a223189023619__300.jpg" alt="Camera fixing / tripod adapter" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/b6f/13c/272/5fe90f3b8a223189023619__300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/b6f/13c/272/5fe90f3b8a223189023619__300.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/b6f/13c/272/5fe90f3b8a223189023619__300.jpg 300w"><br><span>Fig. 7: Camera fixing / tripod adapter.</span></p><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/0cd/6a5/977/5feb9cc4b3ea3328038215__300.jpg" alt="INA219 and M5Stack ATOM matrix" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/0cd/6a5/977/5feb9cc4b3ea3328038215__300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/0cd/6a5/977/5feb9cc4b3ea3328038215__300.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/0cd/6a5/977/5feb9cc4b3ea3328038215__300.jpg 300w"><br><span>Fig. 8: Camera rotate fix option.</span></p><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/2f2/8ca/74e/5fe90f2f2e446168683514__300.jpg" alt="INA219 and M5Stack ATOM matrix" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/2f2/8ca/74e/5fe90f2f2e446168683514__300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/2f2/8ca/74e/5fe90f2f2e446168683514__300.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/2f2/8ca/74e/5fe90f2f2e446168683514__300.jpg 300w"><br><span>Fig. 9: INA219 and M5Stack ATOM matrix.</span></p></div><p>As you can see in Fig. 9, there are some ICs, capacitors, and resistors that aren't assembled and also two cables (red and black). The cables supply 7.5V for the motors. The ICs, capacitors, and resistors are planned to provide 5V and 3.3V to the M5Stack, A4988 drivers, and the INA219. Currently (in that Fig. 9), they are supplied via the USB cable connected, on one end, to the M5Stack, on the other, to the Raspberry Pi. So, you have two ways to supply the system :). But, yes, you need two power suppliers: one for the steppers (7.5V) and one for the Raspberry Pi (5V). The 5V on the board (via ICs) won't be able to supply the Raspberry Pi. Sorry, but I didn't want to use bigger ICs for that.</p><h2><span id="m5stack-application-657181">M5Stack Application</span></h2><p>As I described before, the M5Stack ATOM Matrix controls the motors and offers a RestAPI to receive the commands. The M5Stack application is programmed in MicroPython. If you haven't heard about MicroPython, you can check this tutorial: <a href="https://lemariva.com/blog/2020/03/tutorial-getting-started-micropython-v20">Getting Started with MicroPython on ESP32, M5Stack, and ESP8266</a>. MicroPython is a lean and efficient implementation of the Python 3 programming language that includes a small subset of the Python standard library and is optimized to run on microcontrollers and in "constrained environments".
The application is located <a href="https://github.com/lemariva/uPyFocus">lemariva/uPyFocus</a>.</p><p>So, follow these steps to upload the application to the M5Stack:</p><ol><li>Flash MicroPython to the M5Stack as described in <a href="https://lemariva.com/blog/2020/03/tutorial-getting-started-micropython-v20">this tutorial</a>.</li><li>Clone the <a href="https://github.com/lemariva/uPyFocus">lemariva/uPyFocus</a> repository:
<pre><code>git clone https://github.com/lemariva/uPyFocus.git</code></pre></li><li>Open the folder <code>uPyFocus</code> with <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://code.visualstudio.com/">VSCode</a> and rename the <code>config.py.sample</code> to <code>config.py</code>.</li><li>Open the file and add your Wi-Fi credentials in this section:
<pre><code>wifi = {
    'ssid':'',
    'password':''
}</code></pre>
<p>The M5Stack needs to connect to your Wi-Fi so that the Raspberry Pi (also connected to your Wi-Fi/LAN) can find it and sends the commands to control the steppers.</p></li><li>Upload the application to the M5Stack.</li></ol><p>After uploading the code, the M5Stack resets and starts with the calibration routine (check video section: nnn). Take note of the IP that the M5Stack reports while connecting to your Wi-Fi. You'll need that to configure the Microservices Application.</p><h2><span id="docker-and-docker-compose-on-raspberry-pi-657181">Docker and docker-compose on Raspberry Pi</span></h2><p>The application that runs on the Raspberry Pi is a microservices application. That means different services are orchestrated to offer an application. The orchestration is performed by docker-compose and the services are containerized using Docker.</p><p>To install Docker on the Raspberry Pi, just type the following on a Terminal:</p>
<pre><code>curl -sSL https://get.docker.com | sh
sudo usermod -aG docker pi</code></pre>
<p>If you want to learn more about Docker on Embedded System, just read this tutorial: <a href="https://lemariva.com/blog/2018/05/tutorial-docker-on-embedded-systems-raspberry-pi-beagleboard">Tutorial: Docker on Embedded Systems (Raspberry Pi &amp; Beagleboard)</a></p><p>To orchestrate the services, you need to install <code>docker-compose</code>. This can be done by typing:</p>
<pre><code>sudo pip3 -v install docker-compose</code></pre>
<p>Usually, you need to install these dependencies:</p>
<pre><code>sudo apt-get install -y libffi-dev libssl-dev
sudo apt-get install -y python3 python3-pip
sudo apt-get remove python-configparser</code></pre>
<h2><span id="memory-disk-optional-657181">Memory Disk (optional)</span></h2><p>To take photos faster, you can create a disk on RAM. A RAM disk offers faster access to the data compared to an SD card or a connected USB disk. Thus, this allows the application to reduce the time between photos. To do that, you need to create a folder by typing on a Terminal:</p>
<pre><code>sudo mkdir /mnt/ramdisk</code></pre>
<p>Then, you need to modify the <code>/etc/fstab</code> file and add a line at the end of the file:</p>
<pre><code>sudo nano /etc/fstab
### add the following line at the file's end:
tmpfs /mnt/ramdisk tmpfs nodev,nosuid,size=50M 0 0</code></pre>
<p>Then, you can mount it using:</p>
<pre><code>sudo mount -a</code></pre>
<p>To ensure that everything is working, just reboot your Raspberry Pi using:</p>
<pre><code>sudo reboot</code></pre>
<p>To display the newly created drive and check it use the following command.</p>
<pre><code>df -h</code></pre>
<h2><span id="microservices-application-657181">Microservices Application</span></h2><p>The services of the microservices application are the following:</p><ul><li><strong>webapp</strong>: it provides the frontend application (webserver). It is programmed in Angular.</li><li><strong>backend</strong>: it communicates with the frontend via a RestAPI (Flask server), controls the camera, sends the signals to the M5Stack to control the motors, sends the signals and data to the other services to identify objects and take photos. Basically, it is the core service. It is programmed in Python.</li><li><strong>obj-detector</strong>: it receives an image over UDP and identifies the object on it and returns a JSON message. It is programmed in Python. It uses TensorFlow and connects to the Coral USB Accelerator to process the data in real-time.</li><li><strong>photo-service</strong>: it receives a signal via RestAPI (Flask server) to take photos and it processes them to create HDR photos. It is programmed in Python and it uses Celery for multitasking/non-blocking response to the RestAPI.</li><li><strong>redis</strong>: Celery uses this service to schedule the tasks.</li></ul><div uk-grid=""><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/828/27f/a52/5fec60ad052fc228241834__800.jpg" alt="Webservice Microservices Application" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/828/27f/a52/5fec60ad052fc228241834__800.jpg 800w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/828/27f/a52/5fec60ad052fc228241834__400.jpg 400w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/828/27f/a52/5fec60ad052fc228241834__768.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/828/27f/a52/5fec60ad052fc228241834__800.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/828/27f/a52/5fec60ad052fc228241834__800.jpg 800w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/828/27f/a52/5fec60ad052fc228241834__400.jpg 400w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/828/27f/a52/5fec60ad052fc228241834__768.jpg 768w"><br><span>Fig. 10: Webservice Microservices Application.</span></p></div><p>To start the Microservices application, follow these steps:</p><ol><li>Download the <code>docker-compose.yml</code> file or just clone the complete <a href="https://github.com/lemariva/rPIFocus">lemariva/rPIFocus</a> repository:
<pre><code>git clone https://github.com/lemariva/rPIFocus.git</code></pre></li><li>Open the <code>docker-compose.yml</code> file and change the <code>HOST_M5STACK=&lt;ip-address&gt;</code> with the IP of your M5Stack.</li><li>Start the application by typing inside the <code>rPiFocus</code> folder:
<pre><code>docker-compose up -d</code></pre></li><li>Open a browser and visit the URL address: <code>http://&lt;ip-raspberrypi&gt;:4200</code>, you'll see an interface like in Fig. 9. (shhhh... I've just noticed that I wrote Raspberry HD camera and not HQ camera... :()</li><li>To stop the application, type:
<pre><code>docker-compose down</code></pre></li></ol><div uk-grid=""><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/f5a/b64/244/5fec63443a76c981023585__300.jpg" alt="Focus Type: Box - Background focused" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/f5a/b64/244/5fec63443a76c981023585__300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/f5a/b64/244/5fec63443a76c981023585__300.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/f5a/b64/244/5fec63443a76c981023585__300.jpg 300w"><br><span>Fig. 11: Focus Type: Box - Background focused (<a href="https://lemariva.com/storage/app/media/blog_imgs/hqcamera/hq_camera_background_focused.jpg">download</a>).</span></p><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/24c/bc0/434/5fec6339224b0320000410__300.jpg" alt="Focus Type: Box - Nanoblock bird focused" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/24c/bc0/434/5fec6339224b0320000410__300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/24c/bc0/434/5fec6339224b0320000410__300.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/24c/bc0/434/5fec6339224b0320000410__300.jpg 300w"><br><span>Fig. 12: Focus Type: Box - Nanoblock bird focused (<a href="https://lemariva.com/storage/app/media/blog_imgs/hqcamera/hq_camera_nanoblock_bird_focused.jpg">download</a>).</span></p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://lemariva.com/blog/2020/12/raspberry-pi-hq-camera-autofocus-telephoto-lens">https://lemariva.com/blog/2020/12/raspberry-pi-hq-camera-autofocus-telephoto-lens</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://lemariva.com/blog/2020/12/raspberry-pi-hq-camera-autofocus-telephoto-lens</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25594894</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 17:41:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Probabilistic Machine Learning: An Introduction]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 263 | Comments 37 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25593262">thread link</a>) | @joaorico
<br/>
December 31, 2020 | https://probml.github.io/pml-book/book1.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://probml.github.io/pml-book/book1.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
by Kevin Patrick Murphy.
<br>
MIT Press, 2021.


<h2>Key links</h2>

<ul>

  <li> <a href="https://probml.github.io/pml-book/pml1/pml1-toc-short-2020-12-26.pdf">Short table of
      contents</a>

  </li><li> <a href="https://probml.github.io/pml-book/pml1/pml1-toc-long-2020-12-26.pdf">Long table of
      contents</a>

  </li><li> <a href="https://probml.github.io/pml-book/pml1/pml1-preface-2020-12-26.pdf">Preface</a>

  </li><li> <a href="https://github.com/probml/pml-book/releases/latest/download/pml1.pdf">Draft pdf file</a>,  CC-BY-NC-ND license. (Please cite the official reference below.)

    </li><li> <a href="https://somsubhra.com/github-release-stats/?username=probml&amp;repository=pml-book&amp;page=1&amp;per_page=5">Book download statistics</a>
    
    </li><li> <a href="https://github.com/probml/pyprobml">Python code</a>
      
  </li><li> <a href="https://github.com/probml/pml-book/issues">Issue tracker</a>. Use this to report problems with the book and/or code. Be sure to specify which 
    release (date stamp) of the book you are using. Please specify pdf and print page number (which sometimes differ). For reporting small typos, please collect
    a batch of errors into a doc, and create a single issue (or add to an existing open issue list).
</li></ul>

If you use this book, please be sure to cite
<pre><code>
 @book{pml1Book,
 author = "Kevin P. Murphy",
 title = "Probabilistic Machine Learning: An introduction",
 publisher = "MIT Press",
 year = 2021,
 url = "http://mlbayes.ai"
}
</code></pre>

<h2> Endorsements</h2>

<ul>

  <li> "My favorite machine learning book just received a face-lift!
    'Probabilistic Machine Learning: An Introduction' is the most
    comprehensive and accessible book on modern machine learning by a
    large margin.  
    It now also covers the latest developments in deep learning and
    causal discovery. With this upgrade it will remain the reference
    book for our field that every respected researcher needs to have
    on their desk."  -- <a href="https://staff.fnwi.uva.nl/m.welling/">Max Welling</a>,
    U. Amsterdam 

    </li><li> "There are many books on machine learning out there, but none gives
    such a well-rounded, up-to-date, and comprehensive view of the
    field as this one. We use this book as reference reading for our
    students taking the advanced machine learning course at Oxford to
    introduce them to fundamental as well as current topics in the
    field. I'm amazed at the amount of work that went into this
    book---which will surely be used by many to train the next
      generation of machine learning experts."
      -- <a href="http://www.cs.ox.ac.uk/people/yarin.gal/website/">Yarin    Gal</a>, U. Oxford
    

    </li></ul>

<h2>Table of contents</h2>

<br>
    <img src="https://probml.github.io/pml-book/pml1/pml1-toc-short-2col-2020-12-27.png" alt="TOC 2020-12-26">
<h2><a id="ack"></a>Acknowledgements</h2>

I would like to thank the following people for helping with this book.

<ul>

<li> People who helped write some sections:
  Krzysztof Choromanski,
  Justin Gilmer,
  Zico Kolter,
  Frederick Kunster,
  Lihong Li,
  Si Yi Meng,
  Aaron Mishkin,
  Byran Perozzi,
  Colin Raffel,
  Mark Schmidt,
  Sharan Vaswani,
  Andrew Wilson.
  
      </li><li> Proof reader: John Fearns.

      </li><li> People who have provided feedback on parts of the book:
Sebastien Bratieres,
	Kai Brodersen,
	Peter Cerno,
Daniel Galvez,
Abhishek Kumar,
Max Lepikhin,
Aaron Michelony,
	      Horst StÃ¼hler.
Hal Varian.

      </li><li> People who have helped with the code:
	Andrew Carr,
	Aurelien Geron,
	Osvaldo Martin,
	Duane Rich,
	Mahmoud Soliman,
	Theodore Vasiloudis,
	Oscar Wahltinez.

      </li><li> People who have helped with the figures:
	Sandeep Choudhary, and others who are credited in the figure captions.
    </li></ul>
    

</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://probml.github.io/pml-book/book1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25593262</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 15:03:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Spirulina Algae Photobioreactor (2017)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 59 | Comments 16 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25593247">thread link</a>) | @seesawtron
<br/>
December 31, 2020 | https://www.mikechatzidakis.com/home/2017/7/29/spirulina-algae-photobioreactor | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.mikechatzidakis.com/home/2017/7/29/spirulina-algae-photobioreactor">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <article id="article-597d365603596eab18a33f7f">
      
      <div>
        <p><time datetime="2016-07-28" pubdate="">
          <p><span>Jul </span><span>28</span>
          </p>
        </time></p><h2 itemprop="headline" data-content-field="title"><time itemprop="datePublished" datetime="2016-07-28" pubdate="">Jul 28 </time>Spirulina Algae Photobioreactor</h2>

        
      </div>
      
      <div data-controller="BlogProgressBar">
        
        
        <div><div data-layout-label="Post Body" data-type="item" data-updated-on="1501378473772" id="item-597d365603596eab18a33f7f"><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-5b388869c77c096f4e8c"><div><p>I first heard about <em>Arthospira platensis</em> (Spirulina) when I saw a NASA mission featuring the growth of these microbes onboard the ISS. Why grow a cyanobacteria in space you might say? Well what these little guys can do is convert carbon dioxide into oxygen gas for one, and secondly they can also be ingested as a protein substitute. It contains<a target="_blank" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spirulina_(dietary_supplement)#Food_and_nutrition"> 50-70% protein </a>by dry weight for starters, high in iron, and is nearly 300 cals / 100 g to boot. So in terms of a great symbiotic friend for a closed biome (i.e. a sealed steel ball in orbit), Spirulina is a pretty darn perfect room mate.</p><p>Okay I was hooked after a few videos from Youtube and Reddit. How do I get a sample of this West African extremophile? Turns out Amazon, among a myraid of products, also carries this...</p><p>So I ordered this from <a target="_blank" href="http://www.algaelab.org/">AlgaeLab</a> back when they had a Amazon store, it appears they don't have it anymore (July 2017). But they still do ship from their website. So take this in, I purchased a biological sample, shipping from California to Toronto, and it arrived in a little over a week with a bunch of Alkali salts without any major delay at customs. Are you kidding me? A biological sample and miscellaneous white powder can pass through the borders that easy, but I have had books delayed?!</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1501375207629_153452"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501381077828-VKSVEYADYJIT9Y4URHOU/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kA9MJP8G-Te-KF6G_txWkV1Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWEtT5uBSRWt4vQZAgTJucoTqqXjS3CfNDSuuf31e0tVHz1OCtlxDsjXY12tun39jAhdGVKUGCmpVBBjfR2L-Oc8E8-vZB1rw5b7FMBZGIOl4/image-asset.jpeg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501381077828-VKSVEYADYJIT9Y4URHOU/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kA9MJP8G-Te-KF6G_txWkV1Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWEtT5uBSRWt4vQZAgTJucoTqqXjS3CfNDSuuf31e0tVHz1OCtlxDsjXY12tun39jAhdGVKUGCmpVBBjfR2L-Oc8E8-vZB1rw5b7FMBZGIOl4/image-asset.jpeg" data-image-dimensions="400x711" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Spirulina sample sent from AlgaeLab" data-load="false" data-image-id="597d379d3e00bed8e5d33b4d" data-type="image" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501381077828-VKSVEYADYJIT9Y4URHOU/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kA9MJP8G-Te-KF6G_txWkV1Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWEtT5uBSRWt4vQZAgTJucoTqqXjS3CfNDSuuf31e0tVHz1OCtlxDsjXY12tun39jAhdGVKUGCmpVBBjfR2L-Oc8E8-vZB1rw5b7FMBZGIOl4/image-asset.jpeg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
          
          <figcaption>
            <p>Spirulina sample sent from AlgaeLab</p>
          </figcaption>
        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1501381010248_13798"><p>I was so fascinated when I got the sample. It could photosynthesize before your eyes! I recorded a timelapse to see it in direct sunlight. Pretty dope right. The timelapse was over half an hour and condensed into about 5 seconds.</p></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1501381010248_22505"><div><p>The kit from AlgaeLab came with alkali salts and nutrients with directions and ratios for dilution to the volume of water. I took the starter vial and added it into a large Voss glass water bottle.</p><p>Using aquarium air pumps, air was piped through plastic tubing. First into a water percolator to catch dust, then into the glass bottles. One tube was connected to an airstone which creates small air bubbles which will allow greater oxygen dissolution into the medium, and the second tube causes stirring from the bottom to the top of the water column by means of entraining liquid in a bubble tea straw similar to an <a target="_blank" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Airlift_pump">airlift pump</a> or geyser pump. The effect of the air pump is then two fold, greater carbon dioxide diffusion and stirring of the algae.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1501381010248_27504"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501382433389-XTE9RHMTZODM1Z7DY6EQ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPTrHXgsMrSIMwe6YW3w1AZ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fKTrY37saURwPBw8fO2esROAxn-RKSrlQamlL27g22X2A/image-asset.jpeg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501382433389-XTE9RHMTZODM1Z7DY6EQ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPTrHXgsMrSIMwe6YW3w1AZ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fKTrY37saURwPBw8fO2esROAxn-RKSrlQamlL27g22X2A/image-asset.jpeg" data-image-dimensions="2500x1406" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Spirulina reactor underneath the window with a DIY hydroponic garden above it." data-load="false" data-image-id="597d470a4402438918214587" data-type="image" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501382433389-XTE9RHMTZODM1Z7DY6EQ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPTrHXgsMrSIMwe6YW3w1AZ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fKTrY37saURwPBw8fO2esROAxn-RKSrlQamlL27g22X2A/image-asset.jpeg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
          
          <figcaption>
            <p>Spirulina reactor underneath the window with a DIY hydroponic garden above it.</p>
          </figcaption>
        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1501381010248_30812"><p>Below is a short video of the pump system in action. The third tube at the top of the reactors is just for air outflow to avoid pressure building. It would frequently sputter out water and salt everywhere. I will touch on the hydroponic garden in a later blog post.</p></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1501381010248_32831"><div><p>Around one week later we have hit the first exponential bloom phase! Here is another great thing about autotropic microbes, they are so freaking efficient. No photons wasted! Well, I guess thats not entirely true, many photons wasted, but they make trees look like slackers.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1501381010248_34530"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501382904391-J9202TDVO03SJCCBJ9LZ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPTrHXgsMrSIMwe6YW3w1AZ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fKTrY37saURwPBw8fO2esROAxn-RKSrlQamlL27g22X2A/image-asset.jpeg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501382904391-J9202TDVO03SJCCBJ9LZ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPTrHXgsMrSIMwe6YW3w1AZ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fKTrY37saURwPBw8fO2esROAxn-RKSrlQamlL27g22X2A/image-asset.jpeg" data-image-dimensions="2500x1406" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="" data-load="false" data-image-id="597d48f6d2b8570b18c96491" data-type="image" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501382904391-J9202TDVO03SJCCBJ9LZ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPTrHXgsMrSIMwe6YW3w1AZ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fKTrY37saURwPBw8fO2esROAxn-RKSrlQamlL27g22X2A/image-asset.jpeg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1501381010248_35744"><div><p>I think however my favourite thing about Spirulina is their defense mechanism towards getting too much light. Ever wonder why its called Spirlina? The cyanobacteria form a spiral-like shape when they get too much sunlight. Since sunlight is always going to come from one direction at a time (applied to one face), by rearranging into a spiral, only a fraction of total surface area is exposed. And what if the amount of light is too low and not ideal? They straighten out into a line to increase available surface area! How neat is that?</p><p>I bought a cheap $60 chinese microscope on Amazon (most of my projects start at amazon tbh) capable of 800x magnification and I took a cell phone picture through the cheap crappy plastic lenses. As you can see, spirals! Look at that!</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1501381010248_38600"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501383118830-BZR0QQY1JFXL7T3BGT0I/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPTrHXgsMrSIMwe6YW3w1AZ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fKTrY37saURwPBw8fO2esROAxn-RKSrlQamlL27g22X2A/image-asset.jpeg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501383118830-BZR0QQY1JFXL7T3BGT0I/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPTrHXgsMrSIMwe6YW3w1AZ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fKTrY37saURwPBw8fO2esROAxn-RKSrlQamlL27g22X2A/image-asset.jpeg" data-image-dimensions="2500x1406" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="" data-load="false" data-image-id="597d49cd197aea062b6f648b" data-type="image" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501383118830-BZR0QQY1JFXL7T3BGT0I/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPTrHXgsMrSIMwe6YW3w1AZ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fKTrY37saURwPBw8fO2esROAxn-RKSrlQamlL27g22X2A/image-asset.jpeg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1501381010248_61733"><div><p>It was at this point in the project where I realized I should never step foot in a casino. I had a nice batch of algae, now should I do double or nothing? Because of this whole exponential growth business, if my principal amount of algae is higher than before, I should get a ton more algae if I throw in a new batch of nutrients. Or maybe I should harvest these in a 5 micron cloth for consumption and grow a fraction of them again?</p><p>I decided to scale up the operation, and I was at this (below) amount of algae after another 10 days. I put an aquarium heater in the large sack of algae to maintain its temperature at ~32 C.</p><p>I also made this sack of plastic by buying a roll of vacuum pack freezer bag. Typically the vacuum pack machines use this uncut freezer bag material and they singe it closed to the correct size using a heated metal wire. I reproduced this and sealed the bags using a soldering iron. I should note all of these vials are hanging precariously above where I sleep... I sure have a lot of faith in a DIY sealed plastic bag eh??</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1501381010248_63989"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501383866718-SN6I2ATQOEWRB21P8HKO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPTrHXgsMrSIMwe6YW3w1AZ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fKTrY37saURwPBw8fO2esROAxn-RKSrlQamlL27g22X2A/image-5883.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501383866718-SN6I2ATQOEWRB21P8HKO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPTrHXgsMrSIMwe6YW3w1AZ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fKTrY37saURwPBw8fO2esROAxn-RKSrlQamlL27g22X2A/image-5883.jpg" data-image-dimensions="2500x1406" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="image-5883.jpg" data-load="false" data-image-id="597d4cb8d482e9f4cc74af7a" data-type="image" src="https://www.mikechatzidakis.com/home/2017/7/29/image-5883.jpg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1501381010248_66437"><div><p>I'm sure you are wondering, "But Mike, you said you shouldn't gamble at a casino, wasn't this a good gamble? Thats a great yield in the picture above?!" Well, you are indeed correct, its a great yield, but what happened next was quite traumatic for me (no the sack did not fall on my head while I slept). I left for a long weekend, and over that weekend we had one of the hottest heat waves in a while. Between the aquarium heater, tne additional heat and photon flux, the algae overheated and turned yellow. I tried to shade them and I took out the heater but they died.</p><p>I know, there is no happy ending, I'm sorry if you got emotionally invested through this journey. Yes they died, they are very fickle and although they are extremophiles that live in Eastern African salt lakes, they are not invincible.</p><p>I will add more to this blog post as I get along, a few other topics I want to hit (because i researched them during construction) are the following:</p><p>&nbsp;- Fresh vs dried spirulina</p></div></div></div></div></div></div>

        

        

        
      </div>
      

    </article>
  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.mikechatzidakis.com/home/2017/7/29/spirulina-algae-photobioreactor</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25593247</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 15:01:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Big Little Guide to Message Queues]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 266 | Comments 107 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25591492">thread link</a>) | @sudhirj
<br/>
December 31, 2020 | https://sudhir.io/the-big-little-guide-to-message-queues/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://sudhir.io/the-big-little-guide-to-message-queues/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            
<div>
    <main>
            <article>
    
    <div>
                <p>Message Queues are now fairly prevalent—there are so many of them showing up so fast you'd think they were <a href="https://www.rabbitmq.com/">rabbits</a> with an unlimited supply of <a href="https://docs.celeryproject.org/en/stable/">celery</a>, resulting in an <a href="https://kafka.apache.org/">kafkaesque</a> situation where making a decision is like trying to catch a <a href="https://redis.io/topics/streams-intro">stream</a> in your hands. If only there were fewer <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/sns">simple</a> <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/sqs/">services</a> that could help with <a href="https://cloud.google.com/pubsub">publishing and subscribing</a>, it would be so much easier to make a <a href="https://zeromq.org/">zero-effort</a> choice 😕</p><p>Whether we use them by themselves as-is to move data between parts of our application, or as an integral part of the architecture (like event driven systems), message queues are here to stay. In a way, they've been here all along—just without as many names. But what are they? Why are they useful? And how do we use them effectively? Which implementation do we pick? Does it even matter which one we use? And do we need to learn each of them individually, or are there more general concepts that apply to all message queues?</p><p>In this guide, we'll talk about:</p><ul><li>What message queues are and their history.</li><li>Why they're useful and what mental models to use when reasoning about them.</li><li>Delivery guarantees that the queuing systems make (at-least-once, at-most-once, and exactly-once semantics).</li><li>Ordering and FIFO guarantees and how they effect sequencing, parallelism and performance.</li><li>Patterns for fan-out and fan-in: delivering one message to many systems or messages from many systems into one.</li><li>Notes on the pros and cons of many popular systems available today.</li></ul><h2 id="what-are-message-queues">What are message queues?</h2><p>Message Queues are a way to transfer information between two systems. This information—a message—can be data, metadata, signals, or a combination of all three. The systems that are sending and receiving messages could be processes on the same computer, modules of the same application, services that might but running on different computers or technology stacks, or entirely different kinds of systems altogether—like transferring information from your software into an email or an SMS on the cellphone network.</p><p>The idea of a messaging system has been around a very long time, from the message boxes used for moving information between people or office departments (literally where the words <em>inbox </em>and <em>outbox</em> come from), to telegrams, to your local postal or courier service. The messaging systems in the physical world that come closest to what we have in computing are probably the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pneumatic_tube">pnuematic</a> <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=pneumatic+tubes&amp;source=lnms&amp;tbm=isch&amp;sa=X&amp;biw=2560&amp;bih=1366">tubes</a> that moved messages through buildings and cities using compressed air until a few decades ago (and are still used in some places today).</p><p>The kinds of messages we transfer today might be a note that something technical happened, like CPU usage exceeding a limit; or a business event of interest, like a customer placing an order; or a signal, like a command that tells another service to do something. The contents of each message will be driven entirely by the architecture of your application and its purposes—so for the rest of this guide, we don't need to be concerned about what's inside a message—we're more concerned with how the message gets from the system where it originates (the <em>producer</em>, <em>source, publisher</em> or <em>sender</em>) to the system where's it's supposed to go (the <em>consumer</em>, <em>subscriber</em>, <em>destination</em> or <em>receiver</em>).</p><h2 id="and-why-do-we-need-them">And Why Do We Need Them?</h2><p>We need message queues because no system exists or works in isolation—all systems need to communicate with other systems in structured ways that they both can understand, and at a controlled speed that they both can handle. Any non-trivial process needs a way to move information between each stage of the process; any workflow needs a way to move the intermediate product between the stages of that workflow. Message queues are a great way to handle this movement. There are plenty of ways of getting these messages around using API calls, file systems, or many other abuses of the natural order of things; but all of these are ad-hoc implementations of the message queue that we sometimes refuse to acknowledge we need.</p><p>The simplest mental model for a message queue is a very long tube that you can roll a ball into. You write your message on a ball, roll it into the tube, and someone or something else receives it at the other end. There are a lot of interesting benefits with this model, some of which are:</p><ul><li>We don't need to worry about <em>who or what</em> is going to receive the message – that's one less responsibility for the sender to be concerned about.</li><li>We don't need to worry about <em>when</em> the receiver is going to pick up the message.</li><li>We can put <em>as many</em> messages as we want into the tube (let's assume we have a infinitely long tube) at whatever <em>speed</em> is comfortable to us.</li><li>The receiver will <em>never be impacted</em> by our actions—they will pull out as many messages as they want at whatever rate is comfortable to them.</li><li>Neither the sender nor the receiver are concerned with <em>how</em> the other works.</li><li>Neither the sender nor the receiver are concerned with the <em>capacity or load</em> of the other.</li><li>Neither system is concerned with <em>where</em> the other one is – they may or many not reside on the same computer, network, continent or even the same planet.</li></ul><p>Each of these advantages (and this isn't even an exhaustive list) has very important benefits in software development—what they all have in common is <em>decoupling</em>. One system is decoupled from the other in terms of responsibility, time, bandwidth, internal workings, load and geography. And decoupling is a very desirable part of any distributed or complex system—the more decoupled the parts of the system are, the easier it is to independently build, test, run, maintain and scale them.</p><p>Most systems interact with other outside or third-party systems as well—if we build a shopping site we might interact with a payment processor, and let’s say we attempt to directly communicate with the payment processor on each user click. If our system is under heavy load, we're also subjecting the other system to the same load. And vice versa—if our payment provider needs to send us millions of pieces of information about our past payment statues, our system better be ready. The two systems are now <em>coupled</em>. The decisions and actions made by one system have a significant impact on the other, so the needs of both need to be taken into account while making every decision. Add enough other systems into the mix, like logistics or delivery systems, and we quickly have a paralysing mess that makes it difficult to decide anything at all. If one system goes down, the other systems have effectively gone down as well, for no fault of their own.</p><p>We’re also in trouble if we want to switch out any one of these systems for another one, like a new payment processor or delivery system. We’d have to make deep changes in multiple places in our application, and it’s even more difficult to build code to split our messages between multiple providers—we may want to use a ratio to load balance them or split them by geography; or dynamically switch between them based on each provider’s availability or cost.</p><p>Message queues offer the decoupling that solves a lot of these problems. If we set up a queue between two systems that need to communicate with each other, they can now go about their work without having to worry about each other at all—we put our messages aimed at any system into a queue, and we expect information from the other system to come to us through another queue as well. We now have clear points at which we can add rules or make the changes we require, without either system knowing or caring about what's different.</p><h3 id="so-what-s-the-catch">So what's the catch?</h3><p>Are message queues the holy grail of computing, though? Do they solve all the world's problems? No, of course not. There are plenty of situations where we might not want to use them. And we certainly don't want to use a queue just because we have one easily available and think it might be fun. There are some systems that are really simple that just don't require it—a message queue is a way to reduce to complexity of communicating systems, but two communicating systems will always be more complex than one system that doesn't have to communicate. If you have a system that’s simple enough to not require communication with any others, there simply isn't any reason to reach for a queue.</p><p>There are also systems that communicate with each other, but where the complexity added by that communication added is insignificant and not worth worrying about. Or more often the systems are already coupled, in the sense that they all need to work together to function. A really common example is an application server and a data service (in an <em>OLTP</em> system). There's not much point in decoupling them with a queue, because neither can do anything useful without the direct involvement of the other.</p><p>Then there's performance to consider as well—the whole point of decoupling two systems with regards to time and load is so that they can each process information at their own pace—but we certainly would <em>not</em> want this to happen in performance sensitive applications or real-time systems. A queue might help us process more work at the same time (the receiver might have many processes working in parallel on the messages you send) but will remove any guarantees we need about the exact time taken for each piece of work. If predictability is more important than throughput, we're better off without a queue.</p><p>Using a queue might increase the time taken to process each <em>individual</em> message, but will allow you process many more messages at the same time across different computers—so your total number of messages processed per minute or hour, or <em>throughput</em>, will increase.</p><p>If we do have multiple systems that need to communicate, and that communication needs to be <em>durable </em>(if we’ve put a message into a queue, we want to be sure that the messaging system isn’t going to ‘forget’ about it) and decoupled, a message queue is indispensable.</p><h2 id="arguing-semantics">Arguing Semantics</h2><p>There's simply no way to learn about message queues without reading and/or arguing about delivery guarantees …</p></div></article></main></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://sudhir.io/the-big-little-guide-to-message-queues/">https://sudhir.io/the-big-little-guide-to-message-queues/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://sudhir.io/the-big-little-guide-to-message-queues/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25591492</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 10:38:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Shamelessness as a Strategy (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 186 | Comments 202 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25591066">thread link</a>) | @etherio
<br/>
December 31, 2020 | https://nadiaeghbal.com/shameless | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nadiaeghbal.com/shameless">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div ?="">
        <p>I’ve enjoyed playing a game called Avalon recently. I won’t go too far into the rules, but it’s a <a href="https://www.bestplay.co/ultimate-guide-hidden-role-board-games/">hidden role game</a> in the vein of Secret Hitler or Werewolf, where one team is “good”, trying to uncover who among them is “evil”, before the evil team wins.</p>

<p>One of the characters you can play is Merlin. Merlin knows who the evil players are, but can’t reveal what he knows, because the evil team can kill Merlin and win the game. So Merlin relies on another character, Percival, to be his decoy.</p>

<p>Percival’s only power is that he knows who Merlin is. So he secretly watches Merlin’s actions throughout the game and amplifies those signals to the rest of the group. The typical strategy is for Percival to attract attention away from Merlin and towards himself.</p>

<p>But another, riskier strategy is for <em>Merlin</em> to play as though <em>he</em> is Percival. In this case, Merlin displays what he knows so shamelessly that he throws everyone off. The evil team, believing that no Merlin would be stupid enough to put himself out there like that, figures he must be Percival, and writes him off.</p>

<p>The Merlin-as-Percival strategy is bold, because it blatantly defies our expectations about how the game is won. To pull it off, Merlin must create confusion around his actions. He needs the other players to feel unsure about whether he’s being incredibly stupid or incredibly smart.</p>

<p>Increasingly, I think the “shameless” approach is becoming a dominant strategy today. It was first popularized in modern canon by Paris Hilton, who played the “dumb blonde heiress” stereotype so smoothly that everyone assumed she really was as stupid as she seemed.</p>

<p>Paris didn’t play by the “obvious” rules for famous people. She was widely derided by both media and her peers as at best, a train wreck, and at worst, a self-serving aggrandizer. And yet, people couldn’t stop talking about her. A decade later, Paris is now remembered as the mastermind behind the playbook that’s made the Kardashians, Jenners, and other celebrity socialites so successful.</p>

<p>It’s important to note that people were dismissive of Paris because validating her playbook would mean admitting that <em>they</em> were playing an inferior game. Everyone else had invested years into optimizing for the most legible version of the rules. They’d look silly if they were to admit she had found a better way of doing things.</p>

<p>Without getting into tiresome politics, the “shameless” strategy also defined the 2016 U.S. presidential elections. It was shouted down by people in both established political parties, because they were used to playing by the “obvious” rules, but I suspect that in a decade’s time, we’ll look back on that election and realize that it marked the beginning of an entirely new style of politics.</p>

<p>Ditto to, perhaps, the leadership styles of Mark Zuckerberg, who’s followed the “obvious” playbook for years, versus Jack Dorsey, who employs tactics that seem so obviously stupid (tweeting about fasting and meditation!) that we’re quick to write them off. And yet, I’d guess that Zuckerberg’s strategy makes him increasingly unlikeable and untrustworthy, in the same way that any major politician sticking to a pre-2016 playbook today is almost certainly not going to win.</p>

<p>The shameless strategy feels counterintuitive, because our first instinct is to want to punish that sort of behavior. And historically, those sanctions have been effective. Punishing outlandish behavior is an important aspect of cooperative governance: it preserves social order by ensuring that we all play by the same rules.</p>

<p>Today, it seems like punishing shamelessness only <em>increases</em> social rewards to the transgressor. What’s changed?</p>

<p>One explanation might be that it’s an expected effect of the blurring of social boundaries today. In the past, if the size of your community was finitely bounded (like a village, or an aristocratic social class), people didn’t enter or exit these communities as frequently. Under these conditions, sanctions are probably still effective, because members of the community want to be liked and accepted.</p>

<p>But the borders to online communities are much more fluid - perhaps even nonexistent. Under open borders, sanctions will backfire, because they just serve as a signaling boost for the transgressor, attracting outsiders who resonate with that person’s message. What’s meant to be punishment instead becomes a flare shot straight into the night sky.</p>

<p>The “establishment” mistakenly assumes that a shameless person wants the approval of their community, when it turns out that, much like any cult or counterculture, that person’s goal was to attract a following, regardless of who the members are. The disgust of one’s peers doesn’t matter anymore, because that disgust forms the basis for an entirely new community.</p>

<p>A common critique of shameless people is questioning their intelligence. But one of the most bizarre aspects here is it doesn’t actually matter how aware that person is of what they’re doing. The concept of a “genius mastermind” is itself outdated, because it assumes that someone needs to be in control. The shameless person is simply a host for a set of ideas, which, like any virus, will continue to propagate as long as there are willing hosts to receive it.</p>

<p>I’m not really sure what the long-term implications of shamelessness will be. I also don’t think that everybody has to employ this strategy to win (at least, I hope not!). But what I do know is when I see my peers rolling their eyes at someone or deriding them for being “shameless”, there’s a good chance that, instead of writing them off, we should examine their actions a bit more closely.</p>

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nadiaeghbal.com/shameless</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25591066</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 09:26:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[RC3 talk: How to survive in spacecraft [video]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 77 | Comments 13 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25590724">thread link</a>) | @hurlga
<br/>
December 31, 2020 | https://media.ccc.de/v/rc3-158638-how_to_survive_in_spacecraft | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://media.ccc.de/v/rc3-158638-how_to_survive_in_spacecraft">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">



<div>

<p>
<span></span>
<a href="https://media.ccc.de/search?p=urs">urs</a>

</p>

<p><a href="https://media.ccc.de/c/rc3/Chaos-West" rel="tag">Chaos-West</a>
<a href="https://media.ccc.de/c/rc3/CWTV" rel="tag">CWTV</a>
Playlists:
<a href="https://media.ccc.de/v/rc3-158638-how_to_survive_in_spacecraft/playlist">'rc3' videos starting here</a>
/
<a data-method="get" href="https://media.ccc.de/v/rc3-158638-how_to_survive_in_spacecraft/audio">audio</a></p>
<!-- %h3 About -->
<p>If you pop out into space, you die. No oxygen to breathe, no ambient pressure makes your bodily fluids boil, UV radiation burns your skin to a crisp. It's not a good place to be for humans. So in order to survive, you need to bring a number of things along, commonly called the "life support system". This talk explains how this works!</p>

<p>How do oxygen generators and CO_2 scrubbers work? Do you need to heat or cool your craft? If you eat beans and fart a lot, do you ever get rid of the smell? Can you just fill your spacecraft with plants and live off them? <br> This talk goes through historic, present and future ways that life support is managed in spacecraft, spacesuits and future planetary outposts. It also explains why you have to breathe your own pee on the International Space Station. <br> (This is the logical followup to the two previous, german talks about how to fly spaceships and how to build them, from the GulaschProgrammierNacht 13 and 16)</p>

<p>Slides: http://urs.nerd2nerd.org/rC3-talk.svg</p>

<h3>Download</h3>

<!-- %h3 Embed/Share -->

<h3>Tags</h3>

</div>





</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://media.ccc.de/v/rc3-158638-how_to_survive_in_spacecraft</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25590724</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 08:26:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Linux Hardening Guide]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 441 | Comments 272 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25590079">thread link</a>) | @FlyMoreRockets
<br/>
December 30, 2020 | https://madaidans-insecurities.github.io/guides/linux-hardening.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://madaidans-insecurities.github.io/guides/linux-hardening.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
    

    <p><i><time datetime="2020-12-25">Last edited: December 25, 2020</time></i></p>

    <div>
      <p><a href="https://madaidans-insecurities.github.io/linux.html">Linux is not a secure operating system</a>. However, there are steps you can take to improve it. This guide aims to explain
      how to harden Linux as much as possible for security and privacy. This guide attempts to be distribution-agnostic and is not tied to any specific one. </p><p>
      
      DISCLAIMER: Do not attempt to apply anything in this article if you do not know exactly what you are doing. This guide is focused purely on security and privacy,
      not performance, usability, or anything else. </p><p>
      
      All commands listed in this guide will require root privileges. Words beginning with "$" sign indicate a variable that may differ between users as to suit their
      setup.
    </p></div>

    <h2>Contents</h2>

    

    <h2 id="choosing-the-right-distro"><a href="#choosing-the-right-distro">1. Choosing the right Linux distribution</a></h2>

    <p>
      There are many factors that go into choosing a good Linux distribution.
    </p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        Avoid distributions that freeze packages as <a href="https://madaidans-insecurities.github.io/linux.html#debian">they are often quite behind on security updates</a>.
      </li>

      <li>
        Use a distribution with an init system other than <a href="https://systemd.io/">systemd</a>. systemd contains a lot of unnecessary
        attack surface; <a href="https://ewontfix.com/14/">it attempts to do far more things than necessary</a> and goes beyond what an
        init system should do. An init system should not need many lines of code to function properly.
      </li>

      <li>
        Use <a href="https://musl.libc.org/">musl</a> as the default C library. musl is heavily focused on minimality which <a href="https://github.com/NixOS/nixpkgs/issues/90147#issuecomment-643473182">results in very small attack surface</a> whereas other C libraries
        such as glibc are overly complex and prone to vulnerabilities. For example, <a href="https://www.cvedetails.com/vulnerability-list/vendor_id-72/product_id-767/GNU-Glibc.html">
        over a hundred vulnerabilities in glibc have been publicly disclosed</a> compared to the <a href="https://www.cvedetails.com/vulnerability-list/vendor_id-16859/product_id-39652/Musl-libc-Musl.html">
        very few in musl</a>. While counting CVEs by itself is often an inaccurate statistic, it can sometimes be used to represent an overaching issue such as
        in this case. musl also has <a href="https://www.dustri.org/b/security-features-of-musl.html"> decent exploit mitigations</a>, particularly its
        <a href="https://www.openwall.com/lists/musl/2020/05/13/1">new hardened memory allocator</a>.
      </li>

      <li>
        Preferably use a distribution that utilizes <a href="https://www.libressl.org/">LibreSSL</a> by default rather than <a href="https://www.openssl.org/">
        OpenSSL</a>. <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2014/04/openssl-code-beyond-repair-claims-creator-of-libressl-fork/">OpenSSL contains
        tremendous amounts of totally unnecessary attack surface and follows poor security practices</a>. For example, it still maintains OS/2 and VMS support —
        ancient operating systems that are multiple decades old. These abhorrent security practices are what led to the dreaded <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heartbleed">Heartbleed vulnerability</a>. LibreSSL is a fork of OpenSSL by the OpenBSD team that applies
        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LibreSSL#Changes">superior programming practices</a> and <a href="https://opensslrampage.org/">eradicates
        a lot of attack surface</a>. Within LibreSSL's first year, <a href="https://www.openbsd.org/papers/libtls-fsec-2015/mgp00005.html">it mitigated a
        large number of vulnerabilities, including a few high severity ones</a>.
      </li>
    </ul>

    <div><p>
      The best distribution to use as a base for your hardened operating system would be <a href="https://www.gentoo.org/">Gentoo Linux</a> as it allows you to configure
      your system exactly how you want it to be which will be extremely useful, especially when we come to <a href="#hardened-compilation-flags">more secure compilation
      flags</a> later in the guide. </p><p>
      
      However, Gentoo may not be feasible for many people due to its significant usability pitfalls. In this case, <a href="https://voidlinux.org/">Void Linux</a>'s musl
      build is a good compromise.
    </p></div>

    <h2 id="kernel"><a href="#kernel">2. Kernels</a></h2>

    <p>
      The kernel is the core of the operating system and is unfortunately very prone to attacks. As Brad Spengler has once said, <a href="https://grsecurity.net/huawei_hksp_introduces_trivially_exploitable_vulnerability">it can be thought of as the largest,
      most vulnerable setuid root binary on the system</a>. Thus, it is very important for the kernel to be hardened as much as possible.
    </p>

    <h3 id="stable-vs-lts"><a href="#stable-vs-lts">2.1 Stable vs. LTS kernels</a></h3>

    <div><p>
      The Linux kernel is released under two main forms: stable and long-term support (LTS). Stable releases are more recent whereas LTS
      releases are an older stable release that is being supported for a long time. <a href="https://www.grsecurity.net/the_truth_about_linux_4_6">
      There are many consequences to choosing either of the aforementioned releases</a>. </p><p>
      
      The Linux kernel <a href="https://grsecurity.net/reports_of_cves_death_greatly_exaggerated">does not use CVEs to identify security
      vulnerabilities properly</a>. This means that fixes for most security vulnerabilities are not able to be backported to LTS kernels;
      but stable releases contain all security fixes made so far. </p><p>
      
      With those fixes however, a stable kernel includes a lot more new features, therefore vastly increasing the attack surface of the
      kernel and introducing a large amount of new bugs. On the contrary, LTS kernels have less attack surface because these features are
      not being constantly added. </p><p>
      
      Additionally, stable kernels include newer hardening features to mitigate certain exploits which LTS kernels do not. A few examples
      of such features are the <a href="https://mjg59.dreamwidth.org/55105.html">Lockdown LSM</a> and <a href="https://a13xp0p0v.github.io/2018/11/04/stackleak.html">STACKLEAK GCC plugin</a>. </p><p>
      
      To conclude, there is a trade-off when choosing a stable or LTS kernel. LTS kernels have less hardening features and not all public bug fixes
      at that point have been backported, but it generally has less attack surface and potentially a smaller chance of introducing unknown bugs.
      Stable kernels have more hardening features and all known bug fixes are included but it also has more attack surface and greater chances of
      introducing more unknown bugs. In the end though, a more recent LTS branch such as the 4.19 kernel would be preferred due to the much smaller
      attack surface.
    </p></div>

    <h3 id="sysctl"><a href="#sysctl">2.2 Sysctl</a></h3>

    <p>
      Sysctl is a tool that allows the user to configure certain kernel settings and enable various security features or disable dangerous
      features to reduce attack surface. To change settings temporarily you can execute:
    </p>

    <pre><code>sysctl -w $tunable = $value</code></pre>

    <div><p>
      To change sysctls permanently you can add the one you want to change to <code>/etc/sysctl.conf</code> or the corresponding files within
      <code>/etc/sysctl.d</code>, depending on your Linux distribution. </p><p>
      
      The following are the recommended sysctl settings that you should change.
    </p></div>

    <h4 id="sysctl-kernel"><a href="#sysctl-kernel">2.2.1 Kernel self-protection</a></h4>

    <pre><code>kernel.kptr_restrict=2</code></pre>

    <p>
      A kernel pointer points to a specific location in kernel memory. <a href="https://kernsec.org/wiki/index.php/Bug_Classes/Kernel_pointer_leak">
      These can be very useful in exploiting the kernel</a> but kernel pointers are not hidden by default — it is easy to uncover them by, for example,
      reading the contents of <code>/proc/kallsyms</code>. This setting aims to mitigate kernel pointer leaks. Alternatively, you can set
      <code>kernel.kptr_restrict=1</code> to only hide kernel pointers from processes without the <code>CAP_SYSLOG</code> <a href="#capabilities">capability</a>.
    </p>

    <pre><code>kernel.dmesg_restrict=1</code></pre>

    <p>
      <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dmesg">dmesg</a> is the kernel log. It exposes a large amount of useful kernel debugging information but this
      can often leak sensitive information such as kernel pointers. Changing the above sysctl restricts the kernel log to the <code>CAP_SYSLOG</code>
      <a href="#capabilities">capability</a>.
    </p>

    <pre><code>kernel.printk=3 3 3 3</code></pre>

    <p>
      Despite the value of <code>dmesg_restrict</code>, the kernel log will still be displayed in the console during boot. Malware that is
      able to record the screen during boot may be able to abuse this to gain higher privileges. This option prevents those information
      leaks. This must be used in combination with certain boot parameters <a href="#boot-kernel">described below</a> to be fully effective.
    </p>

    <pre><code>kernel.unprivileged_bpf_disabled=1
net.core.bpf_jit_harden=2</code></pre>

    <p>
      <a href="https://madaidans-insecurities.github.io/linux.html#kernel">eBPF exposes quite large attack surface</a>. As such, it must be restricted. These sysctls restrict eBPF
      to the <code>CAP_BPF</code> <a href="#capabilities">capability</a> (<code>CAP_SYS_ADMIN</code> on kernel versions prior to 5.8) and enable
      JIT hardening techniques such as <a href="https://github.com/torvalds/linux/blob/9e4b0d55d84a66dbfede56890501dc96e696059c/include/linux/filter.h#L1039-L1070">constant blinding</a>.
    </p>

    <pre><code>dev.tty.ldisc_autoload=0</code></pre>

    <p>
      This <a href="https://lkml.org/lkml/2019/4/15/890">restricts loading TTY line disciplines</a> to the <code>CAP_SYS_MODULE</code>
      <a href="#capabilities">capability</a> to prevent unprivileged attackers from loading vulnerable line disciplines with the <code>TIOCSETD</code>
      ioctl which <a href="https://a13xp0p0v.github.io/2017/03/24/CVE-2017-2636.html">has been abused in a number of exploits before</a>.
    </p>

    <pre><code>vm.unprivileged_userfaultfd=0</code></pre>

    <p>
      The <code><a href="https://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man2/userfaultfd.2.html">userfaultfd()</a></code> syscall is <a href="https://git.kernel.org/pub/scm/linux/kernel/git/torvalds/linux.git/commit/?id=cefdca0a86be517bc390fc4541e3674b8e7803b0">often</a> <a href="https://duasynt.com/blog/linux-kernel-heap-spray">abused</a> to exploit use-after-free flaws. Due to this, this sysctl is used to restrict
      this syscall to the <code>CAP_SYS_PTRACE</code> <a href="#capabilities">capability</a>.
    </p>

    <pre><code>kernel.kexec_load_disabled=1</code></pre>

    <p>
      <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kexec">kexec is a system call that is used to boot another kernel during runtime</a>. This functionality can
      be abused to load a malicious kernel and gain arbitrary code execution in kernel mode so this sysctl disables it.
    </p>

    <pre><code>kernel.sysrq=4</code></pre>

    <p>
      The <a href="https://www.kernel.org/doc/html/latest/admin-guide/sysrq.html">SysRq key</a> exposes a lot of potentially dangerous debugging functionality
      to unprivileged users. Contrary to common assumptions, SysRq is not only an issue for physical attacks as <a href="https://github.com/xairy/unlockdown">
      it can also be triggered remotely</a>. The value of this sysctl makes it so that a user can only use the <a href="https://www.kernel.org/doc/Documentation/SAK.txt">
      secure attention key</a> which will be necessary for <a href="#accessing-root-securely">accessing root securely</a>. Alternatively, you can simply set the
      value to <code>0</code> to disable SysRq completely.
    </p>

    <pre><code>kernel.unprivileged_userns_clone=0</code></pre>

    <div><p>
      User namespaces are a feature in the kernel which aim to improve sandboxing and make it easily accessible for unprivileged users however, <a href="https://madaidans-insecurities.github.io/linux.html#kernel">this feature exposes significant kernel attack surface for privilege escalation</a> so this sysctl restricts the
      usage of user namespaces to the <code>CAP_SYS_ADMIN</code> <a href="#capabilities">capability</a>. For unprivileged sandboxing,
      it is instead recommended to use a setuid binary with little attack surface to minimize the potential for privilege escalation. This topic is
      covered further in the <a href="#application-sandboxing">sandboxing section</a>. </p><p>
      
      Be aware though that this sysctl only exists on certain Linux distributions as it requires a kernel patch. If your kernel does not include
      this patch, you can alternatively disable user namespaces completely (including for root) by setting <code>user.max_user_namespaces=0</code>.
    </p></div>

    <pre><code>kernel.perf_event_paranoid=3</code></pre>

    

    <h4 id="sysctl-network"><a href="#sysctl-network">2.2.2 Network</a></h4>

    <pre><code>net.ipv4.tcp_syncookies=1</code></pre>

    <p>
      This helps protect against <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SYN_flood">SYN flood attacks</a> which are a form of denial of service attack
      in which an attacker sends a large amount of bogus SYN requests in an attempt to consume enough resources to make the system unresponsive to
      legitimate traffic.
    </p>

    <pre><code>net.ipv4.tcp_rfc1337=1</code></pre>

    <p>
      This protects against <a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc1337">time-wait assassination</a>…</p></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://madaidans-insecurities.github.io/guides/linux-hardening.html">https://madaidans-insecurities.github.io/guides/linux-hardening.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://madaidans-insecurities.github.io/guides/linux-hardening.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25590079</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 06:14:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Interview Transcript – Donald Knuth [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 162 | Comments 36 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25589619">thread link</a>) | @asicsp
<br/>
December 30, 2020 | https://philipkiely.com/assets/files/WfSD_Bonus_Interview_-_Donald_Knuth.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://philipkiely.com/assets/files/WfSD_Bonus_Interview_-_Donald_Knuth.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://philipkiely.com/assets/files/WfSD_Bonus_Interview_-_Donald_Knuth.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25589619</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 04:30:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Shortformer: Better Language Modeling using Shorter Inputs [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 63 | Comments 6 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25588675">thread link</a>) | @blast
<br/>
December 30, 2020 | https://ofir.io/shortformer.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ofir.io/shortformer.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ofir.io/shortformer.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25588675</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 01:51:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
