<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 01:19:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 01:19:26 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[We Crush, Poison, and Destroy Insects at Our Own Peril]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 65 | Comments 11 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25901384">thread link</a>) | @CapitalistCartr
<br/>
January 25, 2021 | http://m.nautil.us/issue/95/escape/we-crush-poison-and-destroy-insects-at-our-own-peril | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://m.nautil.us/issue/95/escape/we-crush-poison-and-destroy-insects-at-our-own-peril">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
			<p><span>T</span>his past summer, my wife and I ventured to an area near Mount Adams in southwestern Washington state to census bumblebees. We camped there over the weekend as we took part in the Pacific Northwest Bumblebee Atlas survey. Scientists want to fill gaps in their knowledge about the bees. Learning about the relative number of different species, and their floral resources over a broad area, provides invaluable information, particularly when some species are in decline. I was helping to determine where conservation efforts may be needed. Survey participants choose a territory where they capture and photograph bumblebees on two occasions. I still marvel at the variety in the photos we took—bees with coloration incorporating rusty bands of hair, black stubby hairs, white patches, orange bands, and a brilliant, lemon-yellow covering of long hairs. <a href="https://nautil.us/issue/90/something-green/the-fungal-evangelist-who-would-save-the-bees" target="_blank">Bumblebees</a> are really quite beautiful when observed more closely.</p><figure data-alt="Hainze_BREAKER"><img src="http://static.nautil.us/18113_ca9eac0c76de0cab71d5b50951fe4c5f.png" width="733" alt=""><figcaption><span><strong>FIGHT OF THE BUMBLEBEE:</strong> A 2017 global study found that one-third of assessed bumblebee species were in decline. The U.S. is studying whether to place the western bumblebee on the endangered species list.</span><span>Stephen Ausmus, USDA ARS / Wikimedia</span></figcaption></figure><p>There is some risk involved, of course. Bumblebees have a painful sting and, unlike the honeybee, with its barbed stinger, the sharp, smooth bumblebee stinger can sting multiple times. Insect stings may serve two purposes. The first is to incapacitate prey. The second is to ward off predators. Bumblebees feed solely on pollen and flower nectar. So they would not sting to subdue prey. A bumblebee nest full of honey and nearly immobile larvae, though, is highly attractive to predators. The bumblebee sting is a weapon used for defense—a mechanism to escape predation from animals that may be 50,000 to 100,000 times their size.<sup>1</sup> And judging by the way most people respond, it works pretty well. The sting of the honeybee has been used as a reference point by sting pain connoisseur, Justin Schmidt. He rates the bumblebee and <a href="https://nautil.us/issue/3/in-transit/tracking-honeybees-to-save-them" target="_blank">honeybee</a> stings as a pedestrian 2 on his scale of 1-4.<sup>2</sup> But that’s a sufficient wallop for people to keep their distance from these bees—and that’s the way the bees like it.<br></p><p>The unparalleled success of insects as a group of organisms results from their ability to escape existential threats. They’re escape artists. They’ve evolved multiple means of eluding the larger animals that endanger them—by stinging, biting, flying, jumping, running, startling, hiding in crevices, and using camouflage as well as chemical defenses. Yet these masters at evading far larger animals face a threat more pernicious than predation today. The resulting decline in the number of insects and in the number of insect species is increasingly well documented. Why should this be alarming? Insects play significant roles as food or in the growth of food for many organisms, including human beings. Insects are also recyclers, decomposing plant matter and animal dung and contributing to the organic content of soils.</p><blockquote><p>It’s not all honey and butterflies in our relationship with insects.</p> </blockquote><p>It’s been said that if human beings disappeared, we would not be missed. Insects and other organisms would thrive. Yet we and many other animals <a href="https://nautil.us/issue/73/play/we-need-insects-more-than-they-need-us" target="_blank">would not survive were insects to disappear</a>. The plight of the island marble butterfly (<i>Euchloe ausonides insulanis</i>) and the western bumblebee (<i>Bombus occidentalis</i>) exemplify the multiple stressors on insect survival in the <a href="https://nautil.us/issue/90/something-green/dawn-of-the-heliocene" target="_blank">Anthropocene</a>, the proposed name for a new epoch in which human-generated change outstrips the effect of natural forces on the Earth. What responsibilities, if any, do we bear toward these insects? And what can each of us do to stem the tide of global insect decline?<br></p><p>In my recent book, <i>Nature Underfoot</i>, I argue that we crush, poison, and destroy insects and their habitat at our own peril. Yet reasons for acting to prevent insect decline run much deeper than self-interest. Humans cause habitat loss, produce pesticides, and import non-native species. We bear, according to certain strands of philosophical and religious thought, responsibility for the catastrophic losses insects experience today. Some say that insects have moral value since they strive to achieve their ends, just as we and other animals do. Others argue that insects have <a href="https://nautil.us/issue/72/quandary/human-exceptionalism-stifles-progress" target="_blank">moral value as a part of God’s creation</a>. Scientists point to the value of insects in global ecosystems, or the value implied by tens or hundreds of thousands of years involved in the evolution of an insect species.</p><p><span>T</span>he insect apocalypse has captured headlines, but the situation is more nuanced than that. Scientists find an increase in the overall numbers of arthropods in the Arctic, but a decline in diversity. Certain habitats in the Arctic are also affected more than others.<sup>3</sup> In Puerto Rico, insect declines initially attributed to climate change may have resulted instead from hurricanes.<sup>4</sup> Some insect species have even increased in numbers—mainly those that are tolerant of human activities or that benefit from associating with humans or from <a href="https://nautil.us/issue/78/atmospheres/is-net-zero-emissions-an-impossible-goal" target="_blank">climate change</a>.</p><p>Despite that, the general trend is negative as climate change, habitat destruction (in the form of deforestation, urbanization, and <a href="https://nautil.us/issue/66/clockwork/herbicide-is-whats-for-dinner" target="_blank">intensification of agriculture</a>), and pesticides take their toll. These forces are overtaking the insects. They are coming so quickly that even these spectacularly successful evolutionary improvisers do not have time to escape. It’s often difficult for scientists to identify a single contributing factor. A new paper, introducing a special issue on the plight of insects, published in the <i>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</i>, referred to the decline of these tiny creatures as “death by a thousand cuts.”<sup>5</sup></p><figure data-alt="Hainze_BREAKER-2"><img src="http://static.nautil.us/18112_d05c25e6e6c5d4898161e0aaf700d9c7.png" width="733" alt=""><figcaption><strong>EDGE OF EXTINCTION:</strong> The Lazarus-like return of the island marble butterfly is remarkable, but the pressures that endanger its prairie habitats remain.</figcaption></figure><p>There is a paucity of long-term records for insect populations. The best historical records are for moths and butterflies in Europe and North America. The story of the island marble butterfly, a grassland species, illustrates the myriad forces arrayed against insects. It was declared endangered in the United States in May of 2020. It is charmingly small—mostly white on the tops of the wings and mottled green, yellow, and white on the undersides. Perhaps its colorful camouflage is a way of escaping predation. This little butterfly was thought to be extinct since 1908, when it was last collected on Gabriola Island, British Columbia. Quite by accident 90 years later, while conducting a survey of butterflies in Puget Sound prairie habitats, a Washington state biologist, John Fleckenstein, collected two of these butterflies on San Juan Island. Neither Fleckenstein, nor his colleague, Ann Potter, could identify the butterflies as they reviewed his collection. So, Potter took the butterflies to a butterfly conference in Corvallis, Oregon, where experts were ecstatic to see the butterfly once thought extinct!<sup>6</sup><br></p><p>The Lazarus-like return of the island marble butterfly is remarkable, but the pressures that endanger it remain. The prairie habitats where the butterfly is found have been farmed, used for pasture, and developed for housing, destroying much of its original habitat. The butterfly caterpillars feed and develop on plants in the mustard family. The native mustard, Menzies’ pepperweed (<i>Lepidium virginicum</i> var. <i>menziesii</i>), that must have originally supported the butterfly, is often found surrounding lagoons on San Juan Island. These plants and the island marble butterfly are damaged by winter storm surges, which will become more serious as climate change causes sea levels to rise. Fortunately, the butterfly has adapted to feeding on two non-native plants, field mustard (<i>Brassica rapa</i>) and tumble mustard (<i>Sisymbrium altissimum</i>) that grow elsewhere on the island.</p><blockquote><p>We and many animals wouldn’t survive if insects disappeared.</p> </blockquote><p>Other invasive species have had a more deleterious effect on the island marble butterfly. The brown garden snail (<i>Cornu aspersum</i>), brought from Europe to the west coast as a source of escargot, competes with the island marble butterfly in consuming field mustard and tumble mustard. The European rabbit (<i>Oryctolagus cuniculus</i>) develops large populations in the San Juan Islands and also feeds on butterfly host plants. Deer, though native in the San Juans, are destructive of prairie habitat. Deer numbers are very high there because their predators, such as wolves, cougars, and bears, were eliminated by European settlers. Deer not only destroy island marble butterfly habitat, but they may ingest eggs and caterpillars in the process. Island marble butterflies also suffer from predation by native spiders and by a European paper wasp (<i>Polistes dominula</i>).<sup>7</sup><br></p><p>A vigorous and widely distributed population of butterflies could withstand the <a href="https://nautil.us/blog/fear-is-good-for-the-forest" target="_blank">pressure of predation</a>, but it poses a significant risk for the tiny, localized population of island marble butterflies. Death by a thousand cuts. Habitat destruction, loss of food plants, invasive species, climate change, and predation are primarily human-driven problems. Fortunately, what is believed to be the last island marble butterfly population falls within the boundaries of the San Juan National Historic Park. Here, the park service is actively rearing and releasing butterflies and making a significant effort to preserve their habitat. The island marble butterfly is in a fragile state but hopefully its new endangered status will yield another amazing recovery.</p><div>
<article>
<p><a href="http://m.nautil.us/issue/16/Nothingness/the-woods-that-time-forgot" data-trval="the-woods-that-time-forgot" data-trlbl="foc_rec" data-tract="internal_art">
<img src="http://static.nautil.us/4013_fbfe5ba2ce3309f522c335e949435612.png" alt="Sapolsky_TH-F1" width="314" height="177">
</a>
</p>
<div>
<p><span>
<span>

<span><a href="http://m.nautil.us/term/f/Environment">Also in Environment</a></span>&nbsp;&nbsp;</span>
</span></p><h4><a href="http://m.nautil.us/issue/16/Nothingness/the-woods-that-time-forgot" data-trval="the-woods-that-time-forgot" data-trlbl="foc_rec" data-tract="internal_art">The Woods That Time Forgot</a></h4>
<p>By Christopher Wharton</p>
<p>
 View Video To view the video, click the “play” icon above. Deep in the woods”: The opening line of narration is perhaps a little unnerving, a Grimm way to begin a wildlife documentary, especially considering it is filmed on...<strong><a href="http://m.nautil.us/issue/16/Nothingness/the-woods-that-time-forgot" data-trval="the-woods-that-time-forgot" data-trlbl="foc_rec" data-tract="internal_art">READ MORE</a></strong>
</p>

</div>

</article>
</div><p>Bumblebees experience similar problems, and the citizen-science survey I described endeavored to generate information about wild bumblebee status—where they occur and what …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://m.nautil.us/issue/95/escape/we-crush-poison-and-destroy-insects-at-our-own-peril">http://m.nautil.us/issue/95/escape/we-crush-poison-and-destroy-insects-at-our-own-peril</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://m.nautil.us/issue/95/escape/we-crush-poison-and-destroy-insects-at-our-own-peril</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25901384</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 09:52:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Papercraft Models of Computers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 177 | Comments 26 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25898063">thread link</a>) | @laurex
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | http://rockybergen.com/papercraft | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://rockybergen.com/papercraft">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section id="page" role="main" data-content-field="main-content">
      <!-- CATEGORY NAV -->
      
      <div data-type="page" data-updated-on="1592534389753" id="page-5c40ced8575d1f4191811561"><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-0348a58188a4ef2cb7ff"><div><p>Construct the computer from your childhood or build an entire computer museum at home with these paper models, free to download and share.<br>Print, Cut, Score, Fold and Glue.</p></div></div></div></div><div><div><div data-aspect-ratio="75" data-block-type="5" id="block-7348027484c80743e6ed"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547751317778-HWMYNDK2JW0LTOB6EBZP/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kN_ZoNdj1kv_gIvm4zjH76N7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0n54Bn8e90W9qBf-smZxzROWPWatu8N4myd8qBOjLXoKr7eLilP27nxMq5hFavDR2g/IMG_3082.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547751317778-HWMYNDK2JW0LTOB6EBZP/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kN_ZoNdj1kv_gIvm4zjH76N7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0n54Bn8e90W9qBf-smZxzROWPWatu8N4myd8qBOjLXoKr7eLilP27nxMq5hFavDR2g/IMG_3082.png" data-image-dimensions="2500x1786" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="IMG_3082.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c40cf83352f5396d76f7ac3" data-type="image" src="http://rockybergen.com/IMG_3082.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-3fa377625522c866e7f3"><div><h3>AMIGA 500</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="https://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/1/15/amiga-500-papercraft-design">here</a>.                                                              German New Art Edition <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/8/8/amiga-500-new-art-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1547751162669_11811"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547751729623-C59CLX1IAXB7W7VT5Y32/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/front-oregon-trail-alt.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547751729623-C59CLX1IAXB7W7VT5Y32/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/front-oregon-trail-alt.png" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="front-oregon-trail-alt.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c40d12442bfc12f9674aa5a" data-type="image" src="http://rockybergen.com/front-oregon-trail-alt.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1590324703951_24581"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1590325638875-4KWH1QV0IOF6T55KOG17/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kGJPosOZKJ_5bTt_aoKLXvV7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmNO4gLeMELCxgbq9ZwIFBqyNnwMzbLyu6EqVFxy448Ac96U4dydQe93OYlnDwKBkA/Apple+Macintosh+128K+Model" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1590325638875-4KWH1QV0IOF6T55KOG17/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kGJPosOZKJ_5bTt_aoKLXvV7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmNO4gLeMELCxgbq9ZwIFBqyNnwMzbLyu6EqVFxy448Ac96U4dydQe93OYlnDwKBkA/Apple+Macintosh+128K+Model" data-image-dimensions="1126x1126" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Apple Macintosh 128K Model" data-load="false" data-image-id="5eca7180250a6a0b1a797f88" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1590324703951_28199"><div><h3>Apple Macintosh 128K</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2020/5/22/apple-macintosh-128k-papercraft-design">here</a>.                                                                             </p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1592415789136_26033"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1592415990253-RN2H94KYOJUE65PPBML4/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKAIkQk1kT2ThXQe37c2Cyd7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1Ub-K2BP0W1-5FW-m4FzjPBuXfWKGAAA0gU_rp4yEhj2SOpYghpI-Ha_TwZsqqmJXng/BBC+Microcomputer+Papercraft+Model" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1592415990253-RN2H94KYOJUE65PPBML4/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKAIkQk1kT2ThXQe37c2Cyd7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1Ub-K2BP0W1-5FW-m4FzjPBuXfWKGAAA0gU_rp4yEhj2SOpYghpI-Ha_TwZsqqmJXng/BBC+Microcomputer+Papercraft+Model" data-image-dimensions="2332x2332" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="BBC Microcomputer Papercraft Model" data-load="false" data-image-id="5eea56aac4488718b636214d" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1592416156070_26814"><div><h3>BBC MicrocompUteR</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2020/6/17/bbc-microcomputer-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1588440149019_23238"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1588440199899-VSNOEOMJTK66IJ6W9RB4/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kGYKcJaEz4vNz2pgt2fQSqlZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpzBgejzEWRPSQ4sX_EGpmnNOvTH6DYc2wKq80NTw9ecR6Vk-vvLi9jwd_7VQTLTqao/Commodore+VIC-20" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1588440199899-VSNOEOMJTK66IJ6W9RB4/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kGYKcJaEz4vNz2pgt2fQSqlZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpzBgejzEWRPSQ4sX_EGpmnNOvTH6DYc2wKq80NTw9ecR6Vk-vvLi9jwd_7VQTLTqao/Commodore+VIC-20" data-image-dimensions="695x695" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Commodore VIC-20" data-load="false" data-image-id="5eadac7d0ef55d3237cb1ad4" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1588440149019_29173"><div><h3>CoMMODORE VIC-20</h3><p>Link to the latest model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2020/5/2/commodore-vic-20-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1547775615568_46583"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547777663528-ODP80GVLTUA3SJ8S6CD2/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/IBM-5100-Front-v003.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547777663528-ODP80GVLTUA3SJ8S6CD2/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/IBM-5100-Front-v003.png" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="IBM-5100-Front-v003.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c4136514ae237dd786a3b4e" data-type="image" src="http://rockybergen.com/IBM-5100-Front-v003.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1563325615886_43244"><div><h3>IBM 5100 Portable computer</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/12/19/ibm-5100-portable-computer">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1553908991580_15079"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1553909419711-DLINHA95G40WJTJ6B94E/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIuDfvWaFR2Iqed7asMOKyt7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmT9vpqXpgR-5jHl5KNyQ_vOUsaE--K8qAsnBiQUVvocXgZXG9SlBsDZM_BtsjcH9x/IMSAI+8080-+Model" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1553909419711-DLINHA95G40WJTJ6B94E/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIuDfvWaFR2Iqed7asMOKyt7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmT9vpqXpgR-5jHl5KNyQ_vOUsaE--K8qAsnBiQUVvocXgZXG9SlBsDZM_BtsjcH9x/IMSAI+8080-+Model" data-image-dimensions="1483x1483" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="IMSAI 8080- Model" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c9ec6990d92972348b97907" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1571765454448_164008"><div><h3>IMSAI 8080 (PCS-80 SYSTEM)</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="https://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/3/27/imsai-8080">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1547775615568_30953"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547777301331-LA12J4F2DIEBFGMU9166/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/IMG_2254.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547777301331-LA12J4F2DIEBFGMU9166/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/IMG_2254.png" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="IMG_2254.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c4134f1352f53176e89c64d" data-type="image" src="http://rockybergen.com/IMG_2254.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1571765454448_179064"><div><h3>Nintendo GAMECUBE</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/7/21/nintendo-gamecube-papercraft">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1558838880993_46488"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1558839026356-XPE1RQDGOLE6PZAL1UAC/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/Sharp+X68000+Papercraft+Model+Pattern" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1558839026356-XPE1RQDGOLE6PZAL1UAC/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/Sharp+X68000+Papercraft+Model+Pattern" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Sharp X68000 Papercraft Model Pattern" data-load="false" data-image-id="5ce9fecce79c7041acbdfad7" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1574732675505_142131"><div><h3>SHARP X68000</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/5/25/sharp-x68000-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1574732675505_151289"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1574733683491-TX601XVQ4LT92TVKUWTO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/TRS-80+Model+III+Papercraft+Model" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1574733683491-TX601XVQ4LT92TVKUWTO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/TRS-80+Model+III+Papercraft+Model" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="TRS-80 Model III Papercraft Model" data-load="false" data-image-id="5ddc872ee9c9ef3d618bdab0" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1590324703951_73296"><div><h3>TRS-80 Model III</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/11/12/trs-80-model-iii-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div></div><div><div data-aspect-ratio="75" data-block-type="5" id="block-8b4182343a2e489b8831"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547751560304-UUUZ08G6JUN0O58IM2G7/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/front-1.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547751560304-UUUZ08G6JUN0O58IM2G7/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/front-1.png" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="front-1.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c40d0751ae6cf0259ec0e75" data-type="image" src="http://rockybergen.com/front-1.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-3aba1e0c24085fad1534"><div><h3>AmSTRAD CPC 464</h3><p>Link to the latest model <a href="https://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/11/30/amstrad-cpc-464-papercraft-20">here</a>.                                                                                 Prev: <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2017/1/21/amstradcpc">v1</a></p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1571765454448_147172"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1571765716167-0UFNI66U7DBDC1LIEGNS/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/Apple+-+Lisa+1" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1571765716167-0UFNI66U7DBDC1LIEGNS/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/Apple+-+Lisa+1" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Apple - Lisa 1" data-load="false" data-image-id="5daf3dc5a50ae018ef6f1f2f" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1571765454448_149636"><div><h3>APPLE - LISA 1</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="https://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/10/17/apple-lisa-1-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1549746001726_22861"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1549746395018-JW1I4T79NKIQLXYGD2SP/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0s0XaMNjCqAzRibjnE_wBlkZ2axuMlPfqFLWy-3Tjp4nKScCHg1XF4aLsQJlo6oYbA/Atari+520+ST" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1549746395018-JW1I4T79NKIQLXYGD2SP/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0s0XaMNjCqAzRibjnE_wBlkZ2axuMlPfqFLWy-3Tjp4nKScCHg1XF4aLsQJlo6oYbA/Atari+520+ST" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Atari 520 ST" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c5f40bf8165f527b770bddb" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1590324703951_68471"><div><h3>ATARI 520ST</h3><p>Link to the latest model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/2/9/atari-520-st-papercraft-design">here</a>.    </p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1547775615568_7710"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547775762408-DNREFI406UJMGRBUDYAZ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kH7bcx_p807l_7aJvGUB_uN7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0moOD8BDhkEvmr_flZVBtwIChsuiQhyTIkjVQ5JuE40aqe9Md01nIM06lR7f9JJmiQ/C64_Mini_Computer_Papercraft-Basic-2.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547775762408-DNREFI406UJMGRBUDYAZ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kH7bcx_p807l_7aJvGUB_uN7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0moOD8BDhkEvmr_flZVBtwIChsuiQhyTIkjVQ5JuE40aqe9Md01nIM06lR7f9JJmiQ/C64_Mini_Computer_Papercraft-Basic-2.png" data-image-dimensions="2500x2499" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="C64_Mini_Computer_Papercraft-Basic-2.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c412ecf4ae237dd7869e612" data-type="image" src="http://rockybergen.com/C64_Mini_Computer_Papercraft-Basic-2.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1549746001726_26611"><div><h3>COMMODORE 64</h3><p>Link to the latest model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/6/28/commodore-64-papercraft-v3">here</a>.                                                                             Prev: <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/3/30/c64minimonitor">v1</a>, <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/4/5/commodore-64-paper-craft">v2</a>, <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/6/14/commodore-1541-disk-drive-papercraft">v3</a> </p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1563325615886_42967"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1563325867306-T0QGQTZZW2IN3FPM5NH6/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/IBM+5150+Personal+Computer" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1563325867306-T0QGQTZZW2IN3FPM5NH6/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/IBM+5150+Personal+Computer" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="IBM 5150 Personal Computer" data-load="false" data-image-id="5d2e754e8f2287000141be63" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1571765454448_182957"><div><h3>IBM 5150 PERSONAL Computer</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/7/16/ibm-5150-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1553262122748_51565"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1553262699056-FOSE3WO4IMXPUM9GEBK0/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kJNqsDNR92Zm0lZEzPpS63h7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UaQfK7iYtFaG3VRabrZaB72zP5b12zwkFkkazYM2Ml-E3WUfc_ZsVm9Mi1E6FasEnQ/Nintendo+Advanced+Video+System" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1553262699056-FOSE3WO4IMXPUM9GEBK0/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kJNqsDNR92Zm0lZEzPpS63h7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UaQfK7iYtFaG3VRabrZaB72zP5b12zwkFkkazYM2Ml-E3WUfc_ZsVm9Mi1E6FasEnQ/Nintendo+Advanced+Video+System" data-image-dimensions="2375x2375" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Nintendo Advanced Video System" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c94e85b085229d4d73c7e67" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1563325615886_54104"><div><h3>Nintendo ADVANCED VIDEO SYSTEM (PROTOTYPE)</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="https://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/3/2/nintendo-avs-prototype-1983">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1574732675505_143092"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1574733462182-PO1EQFO7VFZMCXO4TERQ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/Sega+Master+System+Papercraft+Model" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1574733462182-PO1EQFO7VFZMCXO4TERQ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/Sega+Master+System+Papercraft+Model" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Sega Master System Papercraft Model" data-load="false" data-image-id="5ddc864af95aa874645141f9" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1574732675505_145992"><div><h3>SEGA MASTER SYSTEM</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/11/14/sega-master-system-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1568075226922_49660"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1568075967367-ZG7V8Q7F3YITXZPQ2TJG/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0s0XaMNjCqAzRibjnE_wBlkZ2axuMlPfqFLWy-3Tjp4nKScCHg1XF4aLsQJlo6oYbA/Sinclair+ZX+Spectrum" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1568075967367-ZG7V8Q7F3YITXZPQ2TJG/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0s0XaMNjCqAzRibjnE_wBlkZ2axuMlPfqFLWy-3Tjp4nKScCHg1XF4aLsQJlo6oYbA/Sinclair+ZX+Spectrum" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Sinclair ZX Spectrum" data-load="false" data-image-id="5d76f0ab4daeac2b978c3f92" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1574732675505_134908"><div><h3>Sinclair ZX Spectrum</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/8/17/sinclair-zx-spectrum-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1547775615568_28037"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547776357981-CB2AMVR04ZPDOBNLYJPM/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/front-2.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547776357981-CB2AMVR04ZPDOBNLYJPM/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/front-2.png" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="front-2.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c41313e03ce6448e4275b88" data-type="image" src="http://rockybergen.com/front-2.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1574732675505_149608"><div><h3>CONION C-100F</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/8/11/conion-c-100f-papercraft">here</a>.</p></div></div></div></div></div>
    </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://rockybergen.com/papercraft</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25898063</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 01:33:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The RustyHermit Unikernel]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 101 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25897117">thread link</a>) | @adamnemecek
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://rust-osdev.com/showcase/rusty-hermit/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rust-osdev.com/showcase/rusty-hermit/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <main>
    

    

    <p><a href="https://github.com/hermitcore/rusty-hermit">RustyHermit</a> is a unikernel, which is completely written Rust. <a href="http://unikernel.org/">Unikernels</a> are application images that directly contain the kernel as a library, so they do not require an installed operating system (OS).&nbsp;They are typical used in virtualized environments, which build the backbone of typical cloud / edge infrastructures.</p>
<span id="continue-reading"></span>


<h2 id="virtualization-designs">Virtualization Designs</h2>
<p>Common virtualized environments are based on classical <strong><em>virtual machines</em></strong>. In this case, complete machines are emulated or virtualized and common operating systems are running on both host and guest site:</p>
<p><img src="https://rust-osdev.com/showcase/rusty-hermit/common_vm.png" alt="Structure of a common virtualitation environment"></p>
<p>This technique is established (VMware, Hyper-V, etc.) and widely used. However, it introduces additional overhead especially regarding memory consumption and performance.</p>
<p>An alternative approach to common virtual machines is <strong><em>OS-level
virtualization</em></strong>, where the&nbsp;kernel&nbsp;allows the existence of multiple
isolated&nbsp;user space&nbsp;instances. These isolated instances are also known
as container. A typical representative is LXC or Docker and promise less
overhead in comparison to common virtual machines. However, the
isolation between the processes is weaker and may provide less security.</p>
<h2 id="unikernels">Unikernels</h2>
<p>Often only one application (e.g. a web server) is running in the container or the virtual machine. In this case, a <em>unikernel</em> is an attractive solution. The kernel is provided as static library and linked to the application. As the images directly contain the OS kernel, unikernels can directly be booted inside a virtual machine and do not require the typical software stack containing a Linux kernel and its userland within the VM.</p>
<p>Unikernels do not provide system calls in the classical sense, as everything is running with the privilege level of a kernel and what is typically done via system calls is provided via a common function call. At first glance, this sounds more insecure than previous approaches. However, these kernels are expected to run within a virtual machine, which isolates the application from the real system. In addition, common compiler analysis is used to check the complete software stack and unneeded components can even be removed, which can reduce the attack surface of the application.</p>
<p><img src="https://rust-osdev.com/showcase/rusty-hermit/libos.png" alt="Structure of a library operating system"></p>
<p>Well known unikernels are kernels such as <a href="https://mirage.io/">MirageOS</a>
and <a href="http://www.unikraft.org/">Unikraft</a>. MirageOS is written in OCaml,
while Unikraft still uses C as programming language. In contrast to these
kernels, RustyHermit is completely written in Rust to benefit from
Rust's performance and security behavior.</p>
<h2 id="rustyhermit">RustyHermit</h2>
<p>In principle, every existing
Rust application can be built on top of RustyHermit. However, unikernels
are a single tasking operating system. Consequently, the support of the
system call <code>fork</code> and inter-process communication are missing. In
addition, a classical C library is missing, which is typical used as
interface to the operating system. Every crate, which bypasses the
standard runtime and tries to communicate directly to operating system
does not work without modifications. However, many applications do not
depend on these features and work on RustyHermit.</p>
<h3 id="performance">Performance</h3>
<p>Unikernels can be highly optimized. For instance, we optimized the
network stack of RustyHermit. RustyHermit uses
<a href="https://github.com/smoltcp-rs/smoltcp">smoltcp</a> as network stack, which
is completely written in Rust. As interface between guest and host
operating system, we use
<a href="https://www.linux-kvm.org/page/Virtio">Virtio</a>, which is in a
para-virtualized driver for KVM and widely used in virtualized Linux
environments.</p>
<p>The following figure compares Linux with RustyHermit,
where both are running as guests inside a virtual machine running on top
of a Linux-based host system:</p>
<p><img src="https://rust-osdev.com/showcase/rusty-hermit/bandwidth.png" alt="Bandwidth of the RustyHermit's exerimental network interface"></p>
<p>Especially for small messages RustHermit
is faster in than Linux.</p>
<h3 id="research">Research</h3>
<p>RustyHermit is also a research project to evaluate new operating
system designs, which improves the scalability and the security of operating systems in cloud environments. For instance, RustyHermit provides classical
techniques to improve the security behavior like stack guards and
separating the application stack from the libOS stack. However, a
library operating system typically uses a common function call to enter
the kernel. A classical separation of user- and kernel space by
entering a higher privilege level is missing.</p>
<p>We presented in a
<a href="https://www.ssrg.ece.vt.edu/papers/vee20-mpk.pdf">paper</a> a modified
version of RustyHermit, which provides an intra-unikernel isolation with
<em>Intel Memory Protection Keys</em> (MPK). MPK is a relatively new hardware
primitive that provides per-thread permission control over groups of
pages in a single address space with <a href="https://www.usenix.org/conference/atc19/presentation/park-soyeon">negligible switching overhead</a>,
making it a compelling candidate for use in unikernels.</p>
<p>MPK is requiring modification of page tables at a small performance cost. Four previously-unused bits of each page table entry (the 62nd to the 59th on x86-64) are exploited by MPK. Since MPK exploits four bits of the page table entry, it supports up to 15 protection keys.
MPK controls per-thread permission on groups of pages. Each core has a PKRU register (32 bits) containing a permission value. The value of the PKRU register defines the permission of the thread currently running on that core for each group of pages containing a protection key in their page table entries. Unlike page-table-level permission, MPK provides thread-local memory permission.</p>
<p>We provide user / kernel separation so we simply see the entire application as an untrusted component, independently of application-specific characteristics such as the language it is written in or the level of skill of the application’s programmer. In addition, we divide the kernel code into trusted and untrusted components. Trusted kernel components represent pieces of code written with a memory-safe language, i.e., offering strong security guarantees. Untrusted kernel components correspond to code written either in memory-unsafe languages or in unsafe Rust code blocks.</p>
<p>By entering the library operating system through the application binary interface the protection keys will be automatically changed, which allows access to the kernel stack and the kernel heap. Unauthorized access from within the application will trigger a pagefault, which will be handled by the library operating system.</p>
<h3 id="example-project">Example Project</h3>
<p>To give you an example on how to build an RustyHermit application, lets create a new cargo project:</p>
<pre><code><span>cargo</span><span> new hello_world
</span><span>cd</span><span> hello_world
</span></code></pre>
<p>RustyHermit currently requires the nightly versions of the Rust toolchain.
To simplify the workflow, we recommend to create the configuration
<em>rust-toolchain</em> as follows to define the required components and to
tested version of nightly compiler:</p>
<pre><code><span>[toolchain]
</span><span>channel </span><span>= "</span><span>nightly-2020-12-23</span><span>"
</span><span>components </span><span>= [ "</span><span>rustfmt</span><span>", "</span><span>rust-src</span><span>", "</span><span>llvm-tools-preview</span><span>"]
</span><span>targets </span><span>= [ "</span><span>x86_64-unknown-hermit</span><span>" ]
</span></code></pre>
<p>The configuration file specifies the required components and the version of the nightly compiler to use.</p>
<p>The RustyHermit's target <code>x86_64-unknown-hermit</code> is part of Rust
supported platforms, but doesn't belong to the <em>tier 1</em> platforms,
which means that official binary releases aren't available and the
standard runtime must be build from scratch.
To simplify this build process, we recommend to create the configuration
file <code>.cargo/config</code> as follows:</p>
<pre><code><span>[unstable]
</span><span>build-std </span><span>= ["</span><span>std</span><span>", "</span><span>core</span><span>", "</span><span>alloc</span><span>", "</span><span>panic_abort</span><span>"]

[build]
</span><span>target </span><span>= "</span><span>x86_64-unknown-hermit</span><span>"
</span></code></pre>
<p>To bind the library operating system to the application, we have to add the crate <a href="https://crates.io/crates/hermit-sys"><code>hermit-sys</code></a> to the dependencies in the file <code>Cargo.toml</code>:</p>
<pre><code><span># Cargo.toml

</span><span>[target.'</span><span>cfg(target_os = "hermit")</span><span>'.dependencies]
</span><span>hermit-sys </span><span>= "</span><span>0.1.*</span><span>"
</span><span>features </span><span>= ["</span><span>smoltcp</span><span>"]
</span></code></pre>
<p>The feature <code>smoltcp</code> is required if your application tries
to establish a TCP connection. In this case, the library operating systems
includes the TCP/stack <a href="https://github.com/smoltcp-rs/smoltcp">smoltcp</a>.
In addition <em>hermit-sys</em> depends on the tool <a href="https://crates.io/crates/cargo-download">cargo-download</a> to download required components and must be installed with the command <code>cargo install cargo-download</code>.
Finally, the application can be build with the common command <code>cargo build</code>.</p>
<p>The result is a 64-bit excutable in the <a href="https://refspecs.linuxfoundation.org/elf/elf.pdf">executable link format</a> (ELF).
To start the application within a common virtual machine, a loader is required, which initialize the processor and start the applications.
We provide a simple loader on <a href="https://github.com/hermitcore/rusty-loader">GitHub</a>.
A makefile to build the loader is part of the project.
After that, Qemu can be used to start RustyHermit in a VM as follows:</p>
<pre><code><span>qemu-system-x86_64 -display</span><span> none</span><span> -smp</span><span> 1</span><span> -m</span><span> 64M</span><span> -serial</span><span> stdio</span><span>  -kernel</span><span> path_to_loader/rusty-loader</span><span> -initrd</span><span> path_to_app/app</span><span> -cpu</span><span> qemu64,apic,fsgsbase,rdtscp,xsave,fxsr
</span></code></pre>
<p>To improve the performance, KVM can be used to use the virtualization extension of modern processors.</p>
<pre><code><span>qemu-system-x86_64 -display</span><span> none</span><span> -smp</span><span> 1</span><span> -m</span><span> 64M</span><span> -serial</span><span> stdio</span><span>  -kernel</span><span> path_to_loader/rusty-loader</span><span> -initrd</span><span> path_to_hello_world/hello_world</span><span> -enable-kvm -cpu</span><span> host
</span></code></pre><h3 id="roadmap">Roadmap</h3>
<p>For the near future, we plan to stabilize the interface to the hardware.
For instance, the support of <a href="https://virtio-fs.gitlab.io/">Virtio-fs</a>
is in an early stage. In addition, the integration into Rust standard
library isn't finalized yet and the current version runs only on x86. In the
future, we want to also support aarch64 as processor architecture.</p>


    

    
</main>

            
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rust-osdev.com/showcase/rusty-hermit/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25897117</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 23:01:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Proof of X]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 159 | Comments 59 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25895996">thread link</a>) | @dguo
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://julian.digital/2020/08/06/proof-of-x/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://julian.digital/2020/08/06/proof-of-x/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
 		
<p><span>01</span> Intro</p>



<p>Sparked by <a href="https://twitter.com/dwr/status/1273307320911450112">an interesting Twitter discussion</a>, I’ve spent a lot of time recently thinking about different proof-of-work mechanisms. </p>



<p>When I say proof-of-work, I’m not talking about consensus algorithms like the ones that some crypto currencies use. I’m talking about social networks.</p>



<p>At their core, social networks are primarily about one thing: Building social capital through signaling. As I wrote in <a href="http://julian.digital/2020/03/28/signaling-as-a-service/">Signaling as a Service</a>, signaling can be broken down into three different components:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Signaling Message</strong><br>A hidden status subtext you’re trying to convey about yourself</li><li><strong>Signaling Distribution</strong><br>The channel through which you’re communicating your signaling message</li><li><strong>Signaling Amplification</strong><br>Ways to boost your signaling message to compete against status rivals</li></ul>



<p>For example: A Patagonia vest signals both a prosocial attitude (<em>“I care about the environment</em>“) as well as wealth (“<em>I can afford to spend $500 on a jacket</em>“). Depending on where you live, it might also signal something about <a href="https://vcstarterkit.com/">your occupation</a>.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/patagucci.png"></p><p>In order to signal these messages to others and build actual social capital you need a signaling distribution channel. One option would be to wear the vest in public where others can see it – but there are obvious physical constraints to the size of the audience you’d be able to reach.</p>



<p>This is where social networks come in.</p>



<p>Their primary role is to distribute signaling messages at scale and transform them into quantifiable social capital (in the form of likes and followers).</p>



<p>As social networks grow, they increase the potential reach of your signaling messages – but they also get crowded with status rivals. This is why social networks typically provide you with a set of signaling amplification tools. These tools help you boost your signaling messages and stand out from the crowd.</p>



<p>In <a href="http://julian.digital/2020/03/28/signaling-as-a-service/">Signaling as a Service</a> I compared signaling amplification to <a href="https://www.eugenewei.com/blog/2019/2/19/status-as-a-service">Eugene Wei’s idea of proof-of-work hurdles</a>, which he describes as follows:</p>



<p><i>Almost every social network of note had an early signature proof of work hurdle. For Facebook it was posting some witty text-based status update. For Instagram, it was posting an interesting square photo. For Vine, an entertaining 6-second video. For Twitter, it was writing an amusing bit of text of 140 characters or fewer. Pinterest? Pinning a compelling photo. You can likely derive the proof of work for other networks like Quora and Reddit and Twitch and so on. Successful social networks don’t pose trick questions at the start, it’s usually clear what they want from you.</i></p>



<p>But the more I think about it, the less I like the comparison. I actually think that Eugene’s proof-of-work theory only scratches the surface of what social networks actually do.</p>



<p>Let me explain.</p>



<p><span>02</span> A closer look at proof mechanisms</p>



<p>Take a look at this very cliché Instagram picture. The photographer clearly put a lot of thought and effort into its composition and applied different filters and editing tools to make it look nicer.</p>



<figure>
<img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/creativework.png">
<figcaption><span>Full disclosure: I actually took this picture from Unsplash. No influencers were harmed during the production of this blog post.<br></span>
</figcaption></figure>



<p>It’s a perfect example of Eugene’s definition of proof-of-work. <br>Proof-of-<strong><em>creative</em></strong>-work, to be more exact. </p>



<p>Editing your photo helps to amplify your signaling message and sets you apart within Instagram’s status arena (aka the newsfeed). It also adds additional signaling messages to your post: <em>“Look how great a photographer I am”</em> or <em>“I’m a creative person”</em>.</p>



<p>But those are not the main signaling messages you are communicating here. What you really want to tell your followers with this photo is something along the lines of <em>“I’m a world-traveler”</em> and <em>“I’m in a happy relationship”</em> <span>(which in turn are also just signaling proxies for wealth and mating worthiness)</span>. </p>



<p>The photo and the location tag are your proof points.</p>



<figure><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/igexample02-1.png">
<figcaption><span>If you look closely, you’ll notice additional hidden signaling messages in the form of Allbirds sneakers and what’s most likely a Patagonia vest → proof-of-ownership<br></span>
</figcaption></figure>



<p>Social networks are therefore not only signaling distribution (and amplification) networks – they also allow users to prove their signaling messages. </p>



<p>The creative proof-of-work is just pretext and helps to boost your post. What’s more important are the additional proof mechanisms that social networks provide. In the case of Instagram those are photos and location tags.</p>



<p>Instagram is essentially “pics or it didn’t happen”-as-a-service.</p>



<p><span>03</span> Implications for new social networks</p>



<p>When new social networks emerge they have to introduce new proof mechanisms to differentiate themselves from existing incumbents. These can either be novel proof-of-creative-work hurdles or completely new proof-of-x mechanisms.</p>



<p>TikTok is a good example for proof-of-<em>creative</em>-work innovation. The app provides creators with a powerful set of video editing tools that have opened a whole new level of creativity. </p>



<p>The cost to participate in TikTok’s status game is a lot higher than Instagram’s <span>(compare a well-made dance choreography on TikTok to your median Instagram travel post)</span> – but its powerful feed algorithms also make discovery easier and thus reward users faster and with more social capital. </p>



<p>TikTok doesn’t add any new proof points beyond its novel creative work hurdle though. You can signal and prove your creativity but you could achieve the same by uploading your video to Instagram.</p>



<p>Strava, on the other hand, introduced an entirely new proof mechanism: Proof-of-physical-activity. By using your phone’s GPS sensor (or a 3rd-party fitness tracker), users can actually prove how much and fast they ran or cycled. In contrast to <a href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2017/10/20/grounded-private-jet-hire-helps-russians-fake-lavish-lifestyles/">Instagram</a> <a href="https://www.vice.com/da/article/wdaqgw/instagrams-ballers-discount-private-jets-324">photos</a>, Strava’s proof mechanism is a lot harder to fake <span>(though there are <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=fake+strava+5k+downhill&amp;oq=fake+strava+5k+downhill">exceptions</a>)</span>.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/stravaproof.png"></p><p>What’s great about Strava is that it reinforces a behavior that’s actually good for you: While the status game that initially got you into the app might be zero sum, the actual physical exercise you have to put in to compete has a very positive, compounding effect.</p>



<p>The question is: What other social networks should we build that could have similar positive feedback loops? And what are their proof mechanisms?</p>



<p><span>04</span> Strava for X</p>



<p>Let’s start with the two examples in <a href="https://twitter.com/dwr/status/1273307320911450112">this tweet</a>.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/tweetstrava.png"></p><p>I love the idea of a <strong>Strava for Cooking</strong> – but I’m very skeptical that it can be built. Why? Because the necessary proof mechanisms don’t exist.</p>



<p>The primary metric you optimize on when cooking is taste. But how would you measure or quantify taste? The closest proxy to taste that we have is optics: How good does the meal that you cooked look? This can easily be proved with a photo .. but that’s a proof-of-work mechanism that Instagram already offers (including filters to make your food look nicer). As long as no one comes up with a better proof mechanism for cooking, I think it’s unlikely that we will see a successful social network in the space.</p>



<p>I’m more optimistic about <strong>Strava for Learning</strong>.</p>



<p>While the activity of learning itself might be hard to quantify, you can measure the outcome of learning: knowledge. Has anyone built a multiplayer version of <a href="https://apps.ankiweb.net/">Anki</a> yet? Flash cards would be a perfect proof-of-knowledge mechanism and could easily be turned into a game where you compete against friends.</p>



<p>Similar to physical activity in the Strava example, learning is not something that most people enjoy doing. As TikTok founder <a href="https://youtu.be/wTyg2E44pBA?t=245">Alex Zhu points out</a>, education goes a little against human nature. In combination with a strong enough signaling mechanism however, you can get users to participate. It’s kind of the opposite of <a href="https://cdixon.org/2015/01/31/come-for-the-tool-stay-for-the-network">Chris Dixon’s famous “Come for the tool, stay for the network” strategy</a>. Come for the status, stay for the tool.</p>



<p>A related product I’d love to see is <strong>Strava for Reading</strong>. Imagine an eBook reader that not only tracks how much time you spend reading but also *what* you are reading. Based on these proof-of-(reading)-work mechanisms you could build streaks or GitHub-contributions-like visualizations that incentivize users to read more (and more regularly).</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/githubforreading.png"></p><p>You could even build leaderboards for different topics based on the content of the books and articles you read. Or think about a score that indicated how balanced your reading behavior per topic was (to incentivize users to read takes on political topics from different perspectives).</p>



<p>Unfortunately, I think it’s unlikely that we will see a product like I described anytime soon. <a href="https://twitter.com/lehrjulian/status/1086659965719404544">The world’s largest bookstore, most popular eBook reader, and biggest social network for books</a> are all owned by a company that has very little competency in design and user-facing product innovation.</p>



<p>(Side note: Amazon’s monopoly on books might be the most underrated sub-optimal equilibrium in tech.)</p>



<p>Another app that would be interesting is a social investing app. Think “Robinhood but as a social network”. It seems like investing is already quite a social activity – just look at <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-02-26/reddit-s-profane-greedy-traders-are-shaking-up-the-stock-market">communities like r/wallstreetbets</a>. As <a href="https://twitter.com/patio11/status/1250703738634829824">patio11 pointed out</a>, Robinhood already feels more like a game than a finance app.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/robinhood.png"></p><p>So why not build an investing app that opens with a feed of all your friends’ investments and their returns over time? Instead of sharing screenshots on Reddit and Instagram you could prove your investments right in the app.</p>



<p><strong>Note that an app like this would not be about signaling wealth. It’s about signaling <em>being right</em> and the ability to prove it</strong>. This is probably an even stronger and more engaging mechanism than signaling wealth – and the reason why I’m still bullish on prediction markets.</p>



<p>Perhaps a well-designed, consumer-friendly prediction market app would be the ultimate proof-of-x social network. <strong>Strava for being right.</strong></p>



<p><span>05</span> A Closing Ask</p>



<p>While we are on the topic of being right: Do you agree with my thoughts in this post? What other social networks and proof-of-x mechanisms would you like to see?</p>



<p>Please leave <a href="https://twitter.com/lehrjulian/status/1291397928788135942">your comments here</a>.</p>







<p><em>Thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/dwr">Dan Romero</a>, <em><a href="https://twitter.com/destraynor">Des Traynor</a>,</em></em> <em><a href="https://twitter.com/einkoenig">Jan König</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/cutler_max">Max …</a></em></p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://julian.digital/2020/08/06/proof-of-x/">https://julian.digital/2020/08/06/proof-of-x/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://julian.digital/2020/08/06/proof-of-x/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25895996</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 21:02:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Our experience with the Fediverse, and why we left]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 202 | Comments 193 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25894414">thread link</a>) | @dsego
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-12-05-leaving-the-fediverse/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-12-05-leaving-the-fediverse/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>The “Fediverse” is a loose aggregation of federated servers that mainly speak the ActivityPub protocol. One of the most famous services in the Fediverse is “Mastodon.” We joined the Fediverse in the early days of Mastodon to share short-lived information that didn’t fit into a separate article on our website.</p><h2 id="the-issues-that-we-discussed-earlier-this-year">The issues that we discussed earlier this year</h2><p>In May, <a href="https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-05-31-monthly-review/#fediverse">we reconsidered our presence in the Fediverse</a>. Back then, the main issues for us were:</p><ol><li>You can’t migrate your posts if you need to migrate to another Mastodon server.</li><li>You can’t update your posts without losing shares and comments.</li><li>All posts have a character limit, so we can’t say everything we want in a single post.</li><li>Many Fediverse users claim to be the “better and open-minded alternative to Twitter.” We think that this doesn’t reflect reality, as explained below.</li></ol><p>In June, we addressed issues 1 to 3 by introducing a “News” section on our website.</p><h2 id="further-issues-in-the-fediverse-and-other-social-networks">Further issues in the Fediverse and other social networks</h2><p>We also participated in discussions and tried to encourage dialogs in the Fediverse and other forums instead of only posting information. However, these discussions revealed consistent issues:</p><h3 id="the-toxic-us-vs-them-ideology">The toxic “us vs. them” ideology</h3><p>For some groups, it is vital to make a bogeyman out of opposing parties. In the Fediverse, some individuals and groups continuously spread misinformation about “the others” to gain likes and followers. While most of the toxic behavior targets the big tech companies in the USA, some individuals targetting us.</p><h3 id="the-reverse-burden-of-proof">The “reverse burden of proof”</h3><p>When discussing with others, we often encountered the “reverse burden of proof.” Somebody posts negative claims about a product or service. Instead of providing (technical) proof for the claim, the only supporting “fact” is, “everybody knows that this is true.” On the contrary, this person doesn’t accept any (technical) proof that debunks their initial claim. For us, it looks like you don’t need to provide any real facts as long as you satisfy the ideology of some people.</p><h3 id="the-i-read-headlines-only-problem">The “I read headlines only” problem</h3><p>Many people read the headlines of a post and then guess what is written in the remaining article. Such behavior results in misinterpreted information and persistent myths. On the other hand, it became a standard tool for some blogs to gain more readers: Writing, “Critical security vulnerability could leak all of your data” results in more clicks and shares than, “Company fixed potential security vulnerability months ago, which could have leaked some of your data if ever exploited.” This problem kills meaningful discussions instantly.</p><h3 id="the-security-and-privacy-by-assumption-problem">The “security and privacy by assumption” problem</h3><p>Most of you know “security by obscurity,” when security relies on keeping the implementation secret. We see another common issue: “security and privacy by assumption.” Many people share security and privacy tips without ever checking whether these tips work. They just assume that somebody else checked it before.</p><h3 id="and-finally-comparing-apples-to-oranges">And finally, “comparing apples to oranges”</h3><p>For instance, some people claim the Signal messenger became insecure after introducing the Signal PIN because a server-side attacker could now access your data. The base for this claim is the assumption that a server-side party extracts encrypted information from the volatile main memory of a server, exploits an unpatched security vulnerability in Intel CPUs to extract a key, and successfully guesses a user-provided password.</p><p>While the attack looks anything but trivial as these people describe it, they then argue that their favorite messenger is far more secure due to being decentralized. They compare the encryption mechanism of instant messenger A with something else. Suppose you look at the same feature of their favorite messenger. In that case, you see that their messenger doesn’t offer any server-side protection. In their case, a server-side party can directly access your data in cleartext—this is trivial.</p><h3 id="im-privacy-friendly-please-donate">“I’m privacy-friendly; please donate”</h3><p>The issues mentioned above are also prevalent on other social networks like Twitter. Just like on Twitter, you see “privacy-friendly” companies trying to gain more paying customers or some bloggers heavily involved in influencer marketing. While most of them claim that this is for a “good cause,” it is ultimately all about money.</p><h3 id="decentralization-still-isnt-a-privacy-feature">Decentralization still isn’t a privacy feature</h3><p>Now, some people may insist that at least security and privacy are far better “due to the decentralized nature” of the Fediverse. As we wrote several times before, “decentralization” isn’t a privacy feature.</p><p>Search engines like Google can discover and index all of your public posts in the Fediverse. By default, you can see the social graphs of all accounts, as followers are public. Especially Mastodon servers come with privacy policies that don’t meet the European GDPR requirements. Many (Mastodon) servers seem to run an outdated version, indicating inadequate security practices.</p><h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2><p>Should you become part of the Fediverse by creating an account? It isn’t up to us to decide this, of course.</p><p>If you only want to read the content of others, we recommend subscribing to their RSS feeds. Your RSS subscriptions are private and more decentralized than any Fediverse account. And you need to manage one account less on the internet.</p><p>If you want to be an active part of the Fediverse, be prepared for the same problems as on any other social network. We decided to leave the Fediverse for now.</p><h2>Read also</h2><ul><li><a href="https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-12-20-contact-and-feed/">On contacting us, and subscribing to our RSS feed</a></li><li><a href="https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-11-08-rss-update/">Update of our RSS/Atom feed</a></li><li><a href="https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-08-02-tls-insights/">TLS usage of InfoSec Handbook readers</a></li><li><a href="https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-08-01-introducing-the-news-section/">Introducing the 'News' section</a></li></ul></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-12-05-leaving-the-fediverse/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25894414</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 18:33:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A 10B Pixel Scan of Vermeer’s Masterpiece]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 112 | Comments 44 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25892840">thread link</a>) | @parisianka
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://www.micro-pano.com/pearl/index.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.micro-pano.com/pearl/index.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.micro-pano.com/pearl/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25892840</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 15:35:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Jeff Bezos and Amazon do not want their workers voting by mail on unionization]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 51 | Comments 40 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25889838">thread link</a>) | @jimmy2020
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://www.outkick.com/jeff-bezos-amazon-mail-in-votes/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.outkick.com/jeff-bezos-amazon-mail-in-votes/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
		

		
		<div itemprop="articleBody">
			



<p>Jeff Bezos — a strong Democratic supporter — and Amazon are aiming to postpone a unionization vote at one of its warehouses in Alabama, the <em>Wall Street Journal</em> <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/amazon-seeks-to-postpone-alabama-unionization-vote-11611339250?mod=e2tw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reports</a>. Interestingly, Amazon has requested that the National Labor Relations Board reconsider allowing mail-in voting, claiming that the mail-in voting process has “serious and systemic flaws.”</p>
<p>Got that? Bezos and Amazon are doing all they can to prevent any shady activity when workers cast their ballots for unionization, and they are particularly concerned about the integrity of mail-in ballots.</p>
<p>You are likely trying to figure out how that adds up, right? The <em>Washington Post</em>, owned by Bezos, called any claims of mail-in voter fraud by Donald Trump and his supporters dangerous and inexcusable. Amazon even banned Parler from its servers, in part to ensure no one could claim voter fraud occurred from mail-in ballots back in November.</p>
<p>But stop trying to make it make sense. It is not supposed to add up.</p>
<p>In this case, mail-in voting is disadvantageous for Bezos and his e-commerce behemoth. Therefore, they now consider mail-in voting seriously flawed.</p>
<p>An Amazon spokesperson <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/01/22/tech/amazon-nlrb-union-election/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tells</a> CNN the company is seeking a “valid, fair and successful election” and suggests that only in-person voting can ensure that. Hmm, interesting perspective.</p>
<p>Amazon has, thus far, fended off unions in the United States. If a majority of ballots vote in favor of unionization, hourly Amazon workers would send an L right up to Bezos’ office.</p>
<p>Bamazonunion.com explains that a union at Amazon would “give us the right to collectively bargain over our working conditions including items such as safety standards, training, breaks, pay, benefits, and other important issues that would make our workplace better.”</p>
<p>The NLRB says, “A mail ballot election will enfranchise employees who cannot enter the voting location for health reasons or due to positive COVID tests.” Fearing an unfavorable outcome, however, Amazon now insists that current COVID outbreaks aren’t dangerous enough to warrant this NLRB decision.</p>
<p>Amazon says that Lisa Henderson, NLRB’s Acting Regional Director “reached the remarkable conclusion that any level of infection or potential infection among employees counts as an ‘outbreak.'” <em>O</em><em>nly</em> 218 people employees, 2.88%, at its Bessemer facility tested positive during the 14-day period ending on January 7, which Amazon does not consider an “outbreak” apparently. This is quite the change of perspective. Imagine the coverage from the <em>Washington Post</em> if similar questions had been asked before November.</p>
<p>Mail-in voting has never been about the health of Americans or ensuring that each voice counts. As always, our country’s most powerful figures in both Washington and Silicon Valley base their opinions solely on the outcomes that increase their own power, finances, and flexibility.</p>
<p>Hypocritical, but sadly, all too predictable.</p>
		</div>
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.outkick.com/jeff-bezos-amazon-mail-in-votes/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25889838</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 06:30:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pip has dropped support for Python 2]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 755 | Comments 644 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25888249">thread link</a>) | @groodt
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://pip.pypa.io/en/stable/news/#id1 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://pip.pypa.io/en/stable/news/#id1">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<li><p><strong>PROCESS</strong> Version numbers are now simply <code><span>X.Y</span></code> where the leading <code><span>1</span></code>
has been dropped.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>BACKWARD INCOMPATIBLE</strong> Dropped support for Python 3.1.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>BACKWARD INCOMPATIBLE</strong> Removed the bundle support which was deprecated in
1.4. (#1806)</p></li>
<li><p><strong>BACKWARD INCOMPATIBLE</strong> File lists generated by <cite>pip show -f</cite> are now
rooted at the location reported by show, rather than one (unstated)
directory lower. (#1933)</p></li>
<li><p><strong>BACKWARD INCOMPATIBLE</strong> The ability to install files over the FTP protocol
was accidentally lost in pip 1.5 and it has now been decided to not restore
that ability.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>BACKWARD INCOMPATIBLE</strong> PEP 440 is now fully implemented, this means that
in some cases versions will sort differently or version specifiers will be
interpreted differently than previously. The common cases should all function
similarly to before.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>DEPRECATION</strong> <code><span>pip</span> <span>install</span> <span>--download-cache</span></code> and
<code><span>pip</span> <span>wheel</span> <span>--download-cache</span></code> command line flags have been deprecated and
the functionality removed. Since pip now automatically configures and uses
it’s internal HTTP cache which supplants the <code><span>--download-cache</span></code> the
existing options have been made non functional but will still be accepted
until their removal in pip v8.0. For more information please see
<a href="https://pip.pypa.io/en/stable/reference/pip_install.html#caching">https://pip.pypa.io/en/stable/reference/pip_install.html#caching</a></p></li>
<li><p><strong>DEPRECATION</strong> <code><span>pip</span> <span>install</span> <span>--build</span></code> and <code><span>pip</span> <span>install</span> <span>--no-clean</span></code> are now
<em>NOT</em> deprecated.  This reverses the deprecation that occurred in v1.5.3.
(#906)</p></li>
<li><p><strong>DEPRECATION</strong> Implicitly accessing URLs which point to an origin which is
not a secure origin, instead requiring an opt-in for each host using the new
<code><span>--trusted-host</span></code> flag (<code><span>pip</span> <span>install</span> <span>--trusted-host</span> <span>example.com</span> <span>foo</span></code>).</p></li>
<li><p>Allow the new <code><span>--trusted-host</span></code> flag to also disable TLS verification for
a particular hostname.</p></li>
<li><p>Added a <code><span>--user</span></code> flag to <code><span>pip</span> <span>freeze</span></code> and <code><span>pip</span> <span>list</span></code> to check the
user site directory only.</p></li>
<li><p>Silence byte compile errors when installation succeed. (#1873)</p></li>
<li><p>Added a virtualenv-specific configuration file. (#1364)</p></li>
<li><p>Added site-wide configuration files. (1978)</p></li>
<li><p>Added an automatic check to warn if there is an updated version of pip
available. (#2049)</p></li>
<li><p><cite>wsgiref</cite> and <cite>argparse</cite> (for &gt;py26) are now excluded from <cite>pip list</cite> and
<cite>pip freeze</cite>. (#1606, #1369)</p></li>
<li><p>Add <code><span>--client-cert</span></code> option for SSL client certificates. (#1424)</p></li>
<li><p><cite>pip show --files</cite> was broken for wheel installs. (#1635, #1484)</p></li>
<li><p>install_lib should take precedence when reading distutils config.
(#1642, #1641)</p></li>
<li><p>Send <cite>Accept-Encoding: identity</cite> when downloading files in an attempt to
convince some servers who double compress the downloaded file to stop doing
so. (#1688)</p></li>
<li><p>Stop breaking when given pip commands in uppercase (#1559, #1725)</p></li>
<li><p>pip no longer adds duplicate logging consumers, so it won’t create duplicate
output when being called multiple times. (#1618, #1723)</p></li>
<li><p><cite>pip wheel</cite> now returns an error code if any wheels fail to build. (#1769)</p></li>
<li><p><cite>pip wheel</cite> wasn’t building wheels for dependencies of editable requirements.
(#1775)</p></li>
<li><p>Allow the use of <code><span>--no-use-wheel</span></code> within a requirements file. (#1859)</p></li>
<li><p>Attempt to locate system TLS certificates to use instead of the included
CA Bundle if possible. (#1680, #1866)</p></li>
<li><p>Allow use of Zip64 extension in Wheels and other zip files. (#1319, #1868)</p></li>
<li><p>Properly handle an index or --find-links target which has a &lt;base&gt; without a
href attribute. (#1101, #1869)</p></li>
<li><p>Properly handle extras when a project is installed via Wheel. (#1885, #1896)</p></li>
<li><p>Added support to respect proxies in <code><span>pip</span> <span>search</span></code>.
(#1180, #932, #1104, #1902)</p></li>
<li><p><cite>pip install --download</cite> works with vcs links. (#798, #1060, #1926)</p></li>
<li><p>Disabled warning about insecure index host when using localhost. Based off of
Guy Rozendorn’s work in #1718. (#1456, #1967)</p></li>
<li><p>Allow the use of OS standard user configuration files instead of ones simply
based around <code><span>$HOME</span></code>. (#2021)</p></li>
<li><p>When installing directly from wheel paths or urls, previous versions were not
uninstalled. (#1825, #804, #1838)</p></li>
<li><p>Detect the location of the <code><span>.egg-info</span></code> directory by looking for any file
located inside of it instead of relying on the record file listing a
directory. (#2075, #2076)</p></li>
<li><p>Use a randomized and secure default build directory when possible.
(#1964, #1935, #676, #2122, CVE-2014-8991)</p></li>
<li><p>Support environment markers in requirements.txt files. (#1433, #2134)</p></li>
<li><p>Automatically retry failed HTTP requests by default. (#1444, #2147)</p></li>
<li><p>Handle HTML Encoding better using a method that is more similar to how
browsers handle it. (#1100, #1874)</p></li>
<li><p>Reduce the verbosity of the pip command by default. (#2175, #2177, #2178)</p></li>
<li><p>Fixed <a href="https://github.com/pypa/pip/issues/2031">#2031</a> - Respect sys.executable on OSX when installing from
Wheels.</p></li>
<li><p>Display the entire URL of the file that is being downloaded when downloading
from a non PyPI repository. (#2183)</p></li>
<li><p>Support setuptools style environment markers in a source distribution. (#2153)</p></li>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://pip.pypa.io/en/stable/news/#id1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25888249</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 02:01:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Software engineering topics I changed my mind on]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 1093 | Comments 657 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25887373">thread link</a>) | @goostavos
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://chriskiehl.com/article/thoughts-after-6-years | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://chriskiehl.com/article/thoughts-after-6-years">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div><article><p><img alt="image" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/awsblogstore/articles/162da1cd/5cfd8e9f-image-1440px.jpeg" srcset="https://s3.amazonaws.com/awsblogstore/articles/162da1cd/5cfd8e9f-image-1440px.jpeg 1440w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/awsblogstore/articles/162da1cd/5cfd8e9f-image-1200px.jpeg 1200w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/awsblogstore/articles/162da1cd/5cfd8e9f-image-960px.jpeg 960w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/awsblogstore/articles/162da1cd/5cfd8e9f-image-720px.jpeg 720w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/awsblogstore/articles/162da1cd/5cfd8e9f-image-480px.jpeg 480w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/awsblogstore/articles/162da1cd/5cfd8e9f-image-240px.jpeg 240w"></p><p><sup>Published: 2021-01-23</sup></p><h2>Things I've changed my mind on:</h2><p>Things I now believe, which past me would've squabbled with:</p><ul><li>Typed languages are better when you're working on a team of people with various experience levels</li><li>Standups are actually useful for keeping an eye on the newbies.</li><li>Sprint retrospectives have their place so long as they're for actual course correction (i.e. "holy shit, <i>that</i> went poorly!") and not some god awful&nbsp; 'agile' / 'scum master' driven waste of everyone's time</li><li>Software architecture probably matters more than anything else. A shitty implementation of a good abstraction causes no net harm to the code base. A bad abstraction or missing layer causes everything to rot. &nbsp;</li><li>Java isn't that terrible of a language.</li><li>Clever code isn't usually good code. Clarity trumps all other concerns.</li><li>Bad code can be written in any paradigm</li><li>So called "best practices" are contextual and not broadly applicable. Blindly following them makes you an idiot</li><li>Designing scalable systems when you don't need to makes you a <i>bad engineer</i>.</li><li>Static analysis is useful</li><li>DRY is about avoiding a specific problem, not an end goal unto itself.</li><li>In general, RDBMS &gt; NoSql</li><li>Functional programming is another tool, not a panacea.</li></ul><h2>Opinions I've picked up along the way</h2><ul><li>YAGNI, SOLID, DRY. In that order.</li><li>Pencil and paper are the best programming tools and vastly under used</li><li>Trading purity in exchange for practicality is usually a good call</li><li>Adding more technology is rarely a good call</li><li>Talking directly to the customer always reveals more about the problem, in less time, and with higher accuracy</li><li>The word "scalable" has a mystical and stupefying power over the mind of the software engineer. Its mere utterance can whip them into a depraved frenzy. Grim actions have been justified using this word</li><li>Despite being called "engineers," most decision are pure cargo-cult with no backing analysis, data, or numbers</li><li>90% – <i>maybe</i> 93% – of project managers, could probably disappear tomorrow to either no effect or a net gain in efficiency.</li><li>After performing over 100 interviews: interviewing is thoroughly broken. I also have no idea how to actually make it better.</li></ul><h2>Old opinions unchanged:</h2><ul><li>People who stress over code style, linting rules, or other minutia are insane weirdos</li><li>Code coverage has absolutely nothing to do with code quality</li><li>Monoliths are pretty good in most circumstances</li><li>TDD purists are just <i>the worst</i>. Their frail little minds can't process the existence of different workflows.</li></ul><p>&nbsp; We'll see which of these have flipped or changed at year 10.</p></article></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://chriskiehl.com/article/thoughts-after-6-years</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25887373</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:02:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Filmulator – a streamlined, open-source raw photo editor]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 279 | Comments 48 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25885760">thread link</a>) | @CarVac
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://filmulator.org/v0-11-0/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://filmulator.org/v0-11-0/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            
<div>
  
  <p><span>2021-01-23</span></p><p>Now announcing Filmulator version 0.11.0!</p>
<h2 id="filmulate">Filmulate</h2>
<ul>
<li>Filmulator now properly handles cameras where whitepoint varies according to the set ISO. To benefit from this, go to the Settings tab and tell Filmulator to download the latest camera constants.</li>
<li>The auto CA correction now loads properly for manual lenses on selecting an image.</li>
<li>Reduce Memory Usage now works correctly when quick preview is on.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="import">Import</h2>
<ul>
<li>The file selection for import no longer needs the text box cleared in between uses.</li>
<li>Files that match the name filters but cannot be processed (weird DNGs especially) are now properly ignored when importing.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="organize">Organize</h2>
<ul>
<li>The Organize view now defaults to the current day upon opening.</li>
<li>When on the Organize tab, pressing left/right switches the currently selected day, and holding shift will let you select multiple days.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="queue">Queue</h2>
<ul>
<li>Double-clicking on an image in the queue now brings you directly to the Filmulate tab if you weren't already there.</li>
<li>When an image is right-clicked, the rating shortcuts apply to that image instead of the image currently open for editing.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="general">General</h2>
<ul>
<li>ARM AArch64 builds are now possible, but no premade builds are available at this time.</li>
<li>The version number can now be seen at the bottom right corner of the Settings tab.</li>
</ul>
<p>Builds are available for Linux and Windows, but still no MacOS builds are available at this time. Please get in touch if you can help set up CI for MacOS builds.</p>
<p>Downloads:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/CarVac/filmulator-gui/releases/download/v0.11.0/Filmulator_v0.11.0.AppImage">Filmulator v0.11.0 Linux AppImage</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/CarVac/filmulator-gui/releases/download/v0.11.0/Filmulator_v0.11.0.exe">Filmulator v0.11.0 Windows Installer</a></li>
</ul>
<p>You can discuss the release <a href="https://discuss.pixls.us/t/filmulator-v0-11-0-released/22944">here on our official forum</a> or <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Filmulator/">on our subreddit</a>.</p>

</div>


        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://filmulator.org/v0-11-0/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25885760</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 20:30:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[2 times 3 can sometimes equal 7 with Android's Neural Network API]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 67 | Comments 85 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25885524">thread link</a>) | @aga_ml
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | http://alexanderganderson.github.io/engineering/2021/01/23/integer_indeterminism.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://alexanderganderson.github.io/engineering/2021/01/23/integer_indeterminism.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p><img src="http://alexanderganderson.github.io/static/img/indeterminism.png" alt="two_times_three"></p>

<p>Two times three equals six or at least that’s what I naively expected.</p>

<p>It is well-known that floating point matrix multiplication can result in a variety of <a href="https://developer.download.nvidia.com/video/gputechconf/gtc/2019/presentation/s9911-determinism-in-deep-learning.pdf">surprises</a>.
But did you know that quantized neural networks are not deterministic as well?
A quantized neural network uses integers to
multiply weights and activations in a neural network.
Thus, the naive logic goes, two and three represented and multiplied as integers should always give the exact same result,
namely six.</p>

<p>However, according to the <a href="https://source.android.com/devices/neural-networks#validation">Android NNAPI Driver Validation</a> documentation, a
driver is valid if multiplication of quantized tensors is within plus or minus
one bit.</p>



<p>The non-determinism of quantized multiplication is a result of optimizing for
the most common neural network deployment use cases.  Neural networks used for
classification and detection generally work well with small amounts of
non-determinism due to the nature of the mathematical operations involved in
<a href="https://openreview.net/forum?id=B1IDRdeCW">neural networks</a>. Furthermore, such networks often benefit from training with
some noise (e.g. batch normalization). Likewise, the input to many neural
networks comes from a camera that generates inherently variable images.</p>

<p>The main challenge associated with neural network deployment on the phone
is creating models that are sufficiently fast, power friendly, and small on
disk. Quantizing a neural network helps one improve in all of these categories.
Quantized weights take up less space on disk, take less energy to transfer, and
can be moved more quickly between different levels of memory.</p>

<p>The last issue at play is that it is much cheaper (both in terms of computing
cost and engineering effort) to quantize a pre-trained model than to train an
existing model from scratch. Consequently, the method developed in this
<a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1712.05877">Integer Inference</a> paper
targets quantizing existing models. The key idea is that a floating point
value can be approximated as a scale times a quantized value minus a zero
point. (Also take a look at the <a href="https://www.tensorflow.org/lite/performance/quantization_spec">Tensorflow Quantization Spec</a>).
The scale and zero point can be chosen relatively easily by, for
instance, looking at the
range of the weights and activations when evaluating the model on a number of
representative inputs.</p>

<p>The loss in predictive performance due to quantization in many practical use cases is
small and this abstraction is widely implemented and baked into hardware,
for instance, by Qualcomm’ <a href="https://developer.qualcomm.com/docs/snpe/quantized_models.html">Snapdragon Neural Processing Engine SDK</a>.
[Strictly speaking, the drivers for this hardware could be
changed to ensure determinism, but that may result in a significant loss in
speed at inference time.]
The SNPE was developed and subsequently, Android sought to simplify the process
of deploying neural networks given the wide variety of available
accelerators. The restrictions on the driver tests were relaxed after pushback from
chip manufacturers whose hardware and drivers did not produce deterministic
quantized math.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, the NN API off by at most 1 (or 3 for a larger network) leaves a
lot of room for funny business that can change the results by small amounts.
The hardware and driver vendors want to produce fast times and low energy
usage numbers on
various neural network benchmarks and are less concerned about reproducibility.
This can lead to unexpected changes in neural network outputs.
For instance, the zero point or scale of the
weights might be changed for some reason by the hardware, and the quantized
values are then recomputed. Another thing that can happen is that the range might
be slightly shifted to make zero exactly representable (see Case 3: Inputs are
both negative and positive in the <a href="https://developer.qualcomm.com/docs/snpe/quantized_models.html">Snapdragon Neural Processing Engine SDK</a>).
Likewise, as the off by one error bound is on a per layer basis, larger
networks generate accumulating error. Practically speaking, the error bound is
increased to three for mobilenet in the NN API driver validation tests. Other
networks could produce larger errors.</p>



<p>The lack of determinism for quantized neural networks touches on the broader
issue of cross platform reproducibility and performance optimization for neural networks.
As the neural networks get deployed more and more widely, these issues will grow in importance.</p>

<p>The first major issue is that if you want to deploy a neural network across
many platforms, you don’t have any guarantees that you are going to get the
same results.
Even if you manage to assemble a large team to test your networks on many
different platforms, the problem isn’t solved.
<em>The lack of determinism means that even if you test your network
on every platform, a driver update may unexpectedly change your results</em>.
This creates an ongoing engineering cost beyond the initial fixed cost of
validating the deployment on existing hardware.</p>

<p>The next major issue is that some application areas have more stringent
standards in terms of reproducibility and auditability. Suppose that a neural
network is used in a self-driving car that gets in an accident. For auditing
purposes, it is important to be able to replay the decisions made by the car’s
control system exactly. In the best case, this requires a significant
engineering effort to keep track of all of the driver versions and internal
testing to verify reproducibility for any deployment.</p>

<p>The final issue is that while classification and detection are not particularly
sensitive to small changes in output, the lack of determinism makes it more
challenging to deploy neural network models which are deeper or more sensitive to
changes.  For instance, imagine a language model that is unrolled over many
iterations to parse or generate a sentence. In that case, accumulating errors
could cause unexpected results.</p>



<p>In the past couple years, there has been an explosion of experimentation in
neural network deployment from software frameworks to hardware
accelerators.  As the field matures, questions about best practices will slowly
be answered. The ability to <em>train once, deploy anywhere</em> will become easier
and easier. In the particular case of determinism, the most reasonable next
step is to have a driver test that ensures determinism and publish a list of
vendors that implement a deterministic API.</p>

<p>The question of determinism is only one small part of the puzzle of being able
to deploy anywhere. Another subtle but important issue is that different
operations will run faster on different hardware. Even if a network can deploy
anywhere in a reproducible manner, an even more fundamental issue is whether
or not a network will be fast and power efficient on any platform. Indeed, while there
has been a great amount of progress in the field of neural network
deployment, there is much to be done to make the ecosystem easier to use and
more mature.</p>

<p>If you are interested in learning more about issues surrounding neural network
deployment or how to be a better machine learning engineer,
connect with me on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexanderganderson/">LinkedIn</a> to see my future <a href="http://alexanderganderson.github.io/blog">blog</a> posts!  If you think that I
can help you grow professionally, check out my <a href="http://alexanderganderson.github.io/coaching">coaching</a> page.</p>

<!-- [zero exactly representable] -->

  </div>

</article>

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://alexanderganderson.github.io/engineering/2021/01/23/integer_indeterminism.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25885524</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 19:58:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[DrScheme in Space]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 137 | Comments 34 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25885430">thread link</a>) | @azhenley
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://parentheticallyspeaking.org/articles/drscheme-in-space/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://parentheticallyspeaking.org/articles/drscheme-in-space/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span>This was initially written for my regular column in the
Brown Computer Science departmental magazine, <span>conduit!</span>,
for the
<a href="https://cs.brown.edu/about/conduit/conduit_v12n2.pdf">Fall 2003
issue</a>. I think it’s far too much fun to leave hidden in such an obscure place.
The prose is unchanged since then (so some of the classification information
may well be incorrect); only the marginal notes are new.</span></p><p>The sender’s name was in all-upper-case, and the subject
line read, “Not exactly...”.</p><p>Spam.</p><p>But I’m glad I opened it anyway. “This is not exactly your
normal query...”, the message
body began. It was from an upstanding citizen at the NASA
Johnson Space Center, asking
for... the Export Control Classification Number (ECCN) for
DrScheme<span><span><span>Now <a href="https://www.drracket.org/">DrRacket</a>.</span></span></span>, a Scheme programming environment I
helped develop.</p><p>The what for what?!?</p><p>It transpires that a tasteful astronaut (name withheld to protect the innocent) had loaded
DrScheme on his laptop for use during his free
time in space.<span><span><span>Turns out he was working through <span><a href="https://htdp.org/">How to Design Programs</a></span>.</span></span></span>
He was (a) going to be on the International Space Station (ISS) and (b) launching a
hard drive image from Russia. The ISS is a multinational enterprise and Russia is, well, another
country, so the act of sending software in both instances involves an export. Both, consequently,
need an ECCN. (I wonder if there is some tacit assumption here that outer space, or at least the ISS,
is a foreign land. I wonder if there isn’t some
group squirreled away trying to determine the
equivalent of nautical limits in space.)</p><p>The US government does a remarkably good job
of publishing documents on the Web; anyone
who’s had to deal with the IRS or the lucky few
who’ve had to contend with the INS will grudgingly admit this. These are sometimes no more
than OCR-scanned copies, but the scanning yields
enough clarity that Google can find the documents. I can’t begin to imagine what this process
must have been like ten years ago. (Probably a lot
simpler: I’d have written off for an official document, then returned to my regularly scheduled
work.)</p><p>Anyway, accessing prose is not the same as understanding it. The second paragraph of the first document I read began “The CCL is contained in
Supplement No. 1 to part 774 of the EAR.”</p><p>It was going to be that kind of day.</p><p>I have some layman’s thoughts about such prose.
It doesn’t look like natural language at all. I conjecture it’s because natural language is rife with
anaphoric references. Letting context and a rich
language of reference “do the talking” leads to
higher communication bandwidth, but it’s hell on
disjointed documents.... But this is beginning to
read like one of Eugene’s<span><span><span>That would be natural-language processing maestro
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eugene_Charniak">Eugene Charniak</a>, who had a regular column in <span>conduit!</span> that was
the inspiration for mine.</span></span></span> articles, so I should stop
this digression now.</p><p>The ECCN system is quite simple once you get
the hang of it. Numerous artifacts, from nuclear to
software, are given codes such as 14D993. These
codes determine the range of permitted distribution and the licensing demands on those who wish
to acquire them. Everything else is assigned the
default code EAR99, sometimes designated NLR
(No License Required). So it’s simply a matter of
reading enough documentation, slotting your
product, and finding a code. This is a bit like saying that feeding your pet octopus is simply a matter of pulling aside the arms, placing the food in
the middle, then retracting your limb. Easily done,
but you may lose an organ or two getting the hang
of it.</p><p>Reading these documents was not without its rewards. I discovered, for instance, that EAR 740.13
(d) (3) (ii) (A) differs from EAR 774 Supplement
No. 2 (2) (a), though they describe the same thing.
The former document is dated later, yet leaves out
a key provision included in the latter, the recognition that software may be sold electronically! Better still, I found that ECCN category 14D993
specifically restricts the export of “program”
proof and validation “software” using mathematical and analytical techniques and designed or
modified for “programs” having more than
500,000 “source code” instructions. Beware, all
you verification researchers—don’t get too ambitious!</p><p>Having done my research, I determined that we
fall under License Exception TSU (Technology
and Software — Unrestricted), though it all gets a
bit sketchy here because our software is not specifically sold. (The concept of free software
doesn’t seem to be in the ECCN vocabulary.
Cheap political crack omitted here.) This didn’t
necessarily mean we were EAR99, and EAR99 is
an ECCN, whereas TSU isn’t, and NASA had
asked for an ECCN. Mustering great courage, I
called the encouragingly named Outeach and Educational Services Division of the US Commerce
Department. After only a few minutes, I was connected to a gruff counselor.</p><p>“Can I help you?”</p><p>“Ah, yes, I was hoping to get a quick clarification
on an ECCN classification.”</p><p>(gruffer still) “Yes?”</p><p>(deep breath) “If I find that my product falls under
License Exception TSU under part 774 of the
EAR, can I assume it has the ECCN of EAR99?”</p><p>I believe I did this without inhaling.</p><p>These are the moments that test the mettle of great
men. Like Major Major’s father, my counselor
was made of stern stuff. He paused for just a moment, just long enough to
accord respect to someone he clearly perceived to be a fellow numbers-and-policy wonk. And then, in a voice rich in
cameraderie, he said, “You know, I’ve been trying
to determine that for five years myself!”</p><p>Being excepted from a license was not the same as
not requiring a license? In the logic of the US government, did the Law of the Excluded Middle not
apply? What was the difference between the two?</p><p>Syria.</p><p>No, seriously. The difference really is Syria. TSU
permits export to Syria, but EAR99 does not.</p><p>My counselor told me this with glee. Apparently I
had hit on one of his favorite trivia questions, because, now really warming to the topic, he informed me that he had asked this very question of
many of his colleagues. Some had incorrectly
identified the two; others, quicker on the draw,
had said that they were indeed different but had
recommended the use of ECCN 4D994. As everyone knows — shucks, by this point even I knew —
this was a contemptible response, because 4D994
permits the export of only specific software products. And so on.</p><p>Anyway, this story has a happy ending. We appear
to meet EAR99. NASA Johnson has acknowledged receipt of our ECCN. I’ve been in touch
with the fine astronaut. DrScheme will soon be
happily beta-v-cs-reducing expressions in outer
space.</p><p>Where has your programming language been today?</p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://parentheticallyspeaking.org/articles/drscheme-in-space/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25885430</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 19:47:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I bought 200 Raspberry Pi Model B’s and I’m going to fix them]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 463 | Comments 155 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25885348">thread link</a>) | @stedaniels
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/i-bought-200-raspberry-pi-model-bs-and-im-going-to-fix-them-part-1/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/i-bought-200-raspberry-pi-model-bs-and-im-going-to-fix-them-part-1/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-3571">

	

	<div>
		
<h2>Introduction</h2>



<p>I’m sure some of my followers have seen my recent social media posts regarding the 200+ Raspberry Pi Model B’s I purchased on ebay – if you have not then follow my <a href="https://twitter.com/jmdawson_blog" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">twitter</a> for sneak peaks and updates!</p>



<div><p>I purchased the job lot of Pi’s for just £61 although there was a catch – they were listed as broken and I believe they are customer returns. They are all Model B’s with with either 256MB or 512MB of RAM and are in various conditions. </p><p>The first step in repairing these is to diagnose the issues, I created some tooling to assist with this which I will cover now.</p></div>



<h2>Pi Diagnostics</h2>



<p>So how do you go around diagnosing 200+ faulty Raspberry Pi’s? Regardless of how clever I get around this its not going to be a fast process but I needed a plan. </p>



<div><p>I will be categorising the Pi’s into two categories those that boot and those that are or appear dead. The “Dead” Pi’s will be revisited at a later date but lets take a look at how I’ve gone about testing the ones that boot up. </p><p>Using a cheap 3.5″ TFT Pi display and a hacky bash script I have created a diagnostic tool that will test the following: </p></div>



<ul><li>USB Ports</li><li>Ethernet</li><li>Display Output</li></ul>



<p>This also gives me an opportunity to test the GPIO to an extent as the display uses the I2C, VCC and GND pins and also gives me a chance to assess the physical condition of the device. </p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="3573" data-permalink="https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/63309619129__9379d143-f95e-4cd3-9144-77a3d23c7f59/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/63309619129__9379d143-f95e-4cd3-9144-77a3d23c7f59-scaled.jpg?fit=1920%2C2560&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1920,2560" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone 8 Plus&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1611403391&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;3.99&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;100&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.066666666666667&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="63309619129__9379d143-f95e-4cd3-9144-77a3d23c7f59" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/63309619129__9379d143-f95e-4cd3-9144-77a3d23c7f59-scaled.jpg?fit=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/63309619129__9379d143-f95e-4cd3-9144-77a3d23c7f59-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="1920" height="2560" src="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/63309619129__9379d143-f95e-4cd3-9144-77a3d23c7f59-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" data-src="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/63309619129__9379d143-f95e-4cd3-9144-77a3d23c7f59-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-srcset="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/63309619129__9379d143-f95e-4cd3-9144-77a3d23c7f59-scaled.jpg?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/63309619129__9379d143-f95e-4cd3-9144-77a3d23c7f59-scaled.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/63309619129__9379d143-f95e-4cd3-9144-77a3d23c7f59-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/63309619129__9379d143-f95e-4cd3-9144-77a3d23c7f59-scaled.jpg?resize=1600%2C2133&amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/63309619129__9379d143-f95e-4cd3-9144-77a3d23c7f59-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-old-src="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/63309619129__9379d143-f95e-4cd3-9144-77a3d23c7f59-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/63309619129__9379d143-f95e-4cd3-9144-77a3d23c7f59-scaled.jpg?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/63309619129__9379d143-f95e-4cd3-9144-77a3d23c7f59-scaled.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/63309619129__9379d143-f95e-4cd3-9144-77a3d23c7f59-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/63309619129__9379d143-f95e-4cd3-9144-77a3d23c7f59-scaled.jpg?resize=1600%2C2133&amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/63309619129__9379d143-f95e-4cd3-9144-77a3d23c7f59-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-lazy-src="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/63309619129__9379d143-f95e-4cd3-9144-77a3d23c7f59-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure>



<p>So far I am around half way through the diagnostics and 59 of the Pi’s boot and work with minor damage such as snapped SD card slots or physically damaged USB ports.</p>



<p>10 of the Pi’s are fully working although their is no Ethernet – These will not be fixed as such although the Ethernet chip and port will be removed transforming the device into a Model A. </p>



<div><p>A further 4 devices are fully working although the HDMI port doesn’t work, all 4 of these look to have damaged traces on the PCB around the HDMI circuitry – I will not be fixing these although I can make them safe to run headless. </p><p>A further 40 Pi’s are dead although some of them are likely just broken power delivery circuits which should be easy fixes – I will revisit these in the near future. </p><p>Here are the remaining devices that need to be diagnosed: </p></div>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="3575" data-permalink="https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/img_1456/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1456-scaled.jpg?fit=1920%2C2560&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1920,2560" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone 8 Plus&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1611407783&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;3.99&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;100&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.11111111111111&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="img_1456" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1456-scaled.jpg?fit=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1456-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="1920" height="2560" src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1456-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" data-src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1456-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-srcset="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1456-scaled.jpg?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1456-scaled.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1456-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1456-scaled.jpg?resize=1600%2C2133&amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1456-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-old-src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1456-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1456-scaled.jpg?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1456-scaled.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1456-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1456-scaled.jpg?resize=1600%2C2133&amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1456-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-lazy-src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1456-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure>



<div><p>Over the next few days I will diagnose the remaining devices and add a follow up post that will have a total count of Pi’s in the box and a count of the ones that I believe are repairable. </p></div>



<h2>Repairing the Pi’s</h2>



<p>Although I haven’t finished diagnosing the Pi’s I couldn’t help but repair a few of the easier fixes, lets look at a few repairs I carried out this morning.</p>



<h3>Bent GPIO pins</h3>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="3577" data-permalink="https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/img_1432/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1432-scaled.jpg?fit=1920%2C2560&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1920,2560" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone 8 Plus&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1611314976&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;3.99&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;64&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.066666666666667&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="img_1432" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1432-scaled.jpg?fit=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1432-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="1920" height="2560" src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1432-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" data-src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1432-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-srcset="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1432-scaled.jpg?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1432-scaled.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1432-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1432-scaled.jpg?resize=1600%2C2133&amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1432-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-old-src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1432-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1432-scaled.jpg?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1432-scaled.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1432-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1432-scaled.jpg?resize=1600%2C2133&amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1432-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-lazy-src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1432-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><figcaption>Bent GPIO Pins on one of the damaged Pi’s’</figcaption></figure>



<p>How the hell does this happen?! one of the Pi’s had the GPIO pins swashed flat. I could have replaced the header but as no pins were snapped I carefully straightened them a metal ruler. <br></p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="3578" data-permalink="https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/img_1434/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1434-scaled.jpg?fit=1920%2C2560&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1920,2560" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone 8 Plus&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1611315440&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;3.99&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;64&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.066666666666667&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="img_1434" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1434-scaled.jpg?fit=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1434-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="1920" height="2560" src="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1434-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" data-src="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1434-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-srcset="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1434-scaled.jpg?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1434-scaled.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1434-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1434-scaled.jpg?resize=1600%2C2133&amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1434-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-old-src="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1434-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1434-scaled.jpg?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1434-scaled.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1434-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1434-scaled.jpg?resize=1600%2C2133&amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1434-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-lazy-src="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1434-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure>



<p>Whilst they didn’t come out perfect it is once again a fully working device.</p>



<h3>Broken USB Ports</h3>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="3582" data-permalink="https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/img_1438/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1438-scaled.jpg?fit=1920%2C2560&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1920,2560" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone 8 Plus&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1611331791&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;3.99&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;100&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.25&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="img_1438" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1438-scaled.jpg?fit=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1438-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="1920" height="2560" src="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1438-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" data-src="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1438-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-srcset="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1438-scaled.jpg?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1438-scaled.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1438-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1438-scaled.jpg?resize=1600%2C2133&amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1438-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-old-src="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1438-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1438-scaled.jpg?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1438-scaled.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1438-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1438-scaled.jpg?resize=1600%2C2133&amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1438-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-lazy-src="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1438-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure>



<p>Ok broken is an understatement! This poor Pi has had the ports ripped right off it, fortunately there is plenty dead Pi’s that will not be fixable so rather than buying parts I salvaged the USB ports from a dead Pi. </p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="3568" data-permalink="https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/img_1441/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1441-scaled.jpg?fit=1920%2C2560&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1920,2560" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone 8 Plus&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1611333172&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;3.99&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;100&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.2&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="img_1441" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1441-scaled.jpg?fit=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1441-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="1920" height="2560" src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1441-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" data-src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1441-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-srcset="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1441-scaled.jpg?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1441-scaled.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1441-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1441-scaled.jpg?resize=1600%2C2133&amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1441-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-old-src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1441-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1441-scaled.jpg?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1441-scaled.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1441-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1441-scaled.jpg?resize=1600%2C2133&amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1441-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-lazy-src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1441-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure>



<p>I then carefully unsoldered the remains of the broken port:</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="3579" data-permalink="https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/img_1440-2/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1440-1-scaled.jpg?fit=1920%2C2560&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1920,2560" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone 8 Plus&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1611332424&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;3.99&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;100&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.066666666666667&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="img_1440" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1440-1-scaled.jpg?fit=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1440-1-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="1920" height="2560" src="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1440-1-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" data-src="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1440-1-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-srcset="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1440-1-scaled.jpg?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1440-1-scaled.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1440-1-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1440-1-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-old-src="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1440-1-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1440-1-scaled.jpg?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1440-1-scaled.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1440-1-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1440-1-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-lazy-src="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1440-1-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure>



<p>Added the salvaged port along with plenty of no-clean flux and soldered it on:</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="3581" data-permalink="https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/img_1444/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1444-scaled.jpg?fit=1920%2C2560&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1920,2560" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone 8 Plus&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1611333515&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;3.99&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;200&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.25&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="img_1444" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1444-scaled.jpg?fit=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1444-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="1920" height="2560" src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1444-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" data-src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1444-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-srcset="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1444-scaled.jpg?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1444-scaled.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1444-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1444-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-old-src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1444-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1444-scaled.jpg?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1444-scaled.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1444-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1444-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-lazy-src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1444-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure>



<p>There we have it, another Pi saved from the scrap pile! </p>



<p>I know people are excited to see the board level repairs but I can assure that they are coming, there are just a lot of devices to go through and I want to get the easy fixes out of the way first. <br></p>



<div><p>I fixed several with broken USB ports and added them to the box of working Pi’s. I will be covering SD card slot repairs when my AliExpress parts arrive but for now this is all on the repairs. </p><p>Here is a final photo showing the so-far working devices: </p></div>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="3576" data-permalink="https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/img_1455/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1455-scaled.jpg?fit=1920%2C2560&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1920,2560" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone 8 Plus&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1611407779&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;3.99&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;100&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.090909090909091&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="img_1455" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1455-scaled.jpg?fit=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1455-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="1920" height="2560" src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1455-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" data-src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1455-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-srcset="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1455-scaled.jpg?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1455-scaled.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1455-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1455-scaled.jpg?resize=1600%2C2133&amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1455-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-old-src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1455-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1455-scaled.jpg?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1455-scaled.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1455-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1455-scaled.jpg?resize=1600%2C2133&amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1455-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-lazy-src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1455-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure>



<h2>What am I going to do with 200 Raspberry Pi’s?!</h2>



<p>I’m sorry to disappoint but I won’t be building a cluster or decorating my walls with them! In fact I don’t have a project planned for these instead they will be sold on starting at £4 for a “Model A” and up to £9 for a fully boxed un-repaired Model B. I’m not doing this to make a quick buck I’m doing it for the blog content and the experience and to hopefully provide you guys with some very cheap Raspberry Pi’s for your projects!</p>



<p>I had a lot of suggestions to send the Pi’s to a developing Country for students to learn IT on and whilst I really like that idea the logistics of it and finding someone trustworthy enough to hand them out aren’t straight forward. Then there is the issue or 200 Pi’s requiring SD cards, Keyboards, Mice and Displays A board alone just isn’t enough here and its just not simple or easy for me to do. Instead I will be donating the proceeds of the sales to the Raspberry Pi Foundation and they can decide what to do with the Money! </p>



<p>I will post an update tomorrow with the results of the diagnostics and a link where you can purchase the repaired devices – UK only though I’m afraid unless you are willing to cover the shipping. </p>



<p>Let me know what you think of this mammoth task in a comment below and please consider following this blog for updates. </p>



<p>Edit: 24/01/21<br>Part 2 is now out <a href="https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/i-bought-200-raspberry-pi-model-bs-and-im-going-to-fix-them-part-2/">here</a>.</p>



<p>Part 3 is now out <a href="https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/i-bought-200-raspberry-pi-model-bs-and-im-going-to-fix-them-part-3/">here</a></p>

	</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->

				
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/i-bought-200-raspberry-pi-model-bs-and-im-going-to-fix-them-part-1/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25885348</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 19:36:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why am I wasting time on EndBASIC?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 57 | Comments 42 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25884859">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://jmmv.dev/2021/01/why-endbasic.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jmmv.dev/2021/01/why-endbasic.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <div>
              
              <article><p>If you have been following this blog or my social profiles for the last year, you are probably aware that <a href="https://jmmv.dev/tags/endbasic">I have been working on something called EndBASIC</a>. You also probably know that this is a retro-looking BASIC interpreter written in Rust that <a href="https://endbasic.jmmv.dev/">happens to run on the web</a>. And if you know those two things, you are probably wondering, like some of my friends do: why am I <em>wasting</em> time developing such a useless project? <strong>Because.</strong></p>
<p>No, seriously, because. It is obvious that the EndBASIC language and environment will not gain massive traction, and I do not have any interest in inventing a perfect new language (because, let’s face it, we already have one and it’s called Rust 😉).</p>
<p>So, then, why do I spend any of my scarce free time on this project? If you must know:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>It’s a fun thing to do.</strong> Just like some people enjoy watching TV shows, playing video games, or crafting wood, I enjoy programming. It feels like a game. And EndBASIC <em>itself</em> could be seen as a game at this point.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>It’s a form of art.</strong> Developing a personal project is a different experience than developing a work project. I can spend all the time in the world polishing the same turd over and over again, playing with different ideas until things look best.</p>
<p>If you have ever considered that programming may be art, then this kind of side project is where you crank your craft up a notch. As just one example, working on EndBASIC’s tests made me come up with the idea of <a href="https://jmmv.dev/2020/12/builder-pattern-for-tests.html">using the builder pattern for tests</a> and it seemed to have been well-received.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>It’s a learning experience.</strong> In writing EndBASIC, I’m playing with Rust. I strongly believe that Rust is one of the languages of the future and it’s the language that makes me say “aha, I agree” at every corner I turn. Yet, I haven’t mastered it. Working on Rust projects lets me learn a bunch of stuff about the language that will be helpful in future endeavors. And it’s not only about Rust per se: <a href="https://jmmv.dev/2020/04/rust-into-trait.html">learning the idioms</a> used in this language can <a href="https://jmmv.dev/2018/06/rust-review-protect-the-data.html">help write better code</a> in any other.</p>
<p>Another example is that I also got to learn about WASM, targeting the browser from a “native” app and making it work on various different devices. This led me down the path of async programming and how to interact with Javascript in that context—which was <a href="https://jmmv.dev/2020/05/bridging-the-web-gap-endbasic.html">a painful but eventually-gratifying obstacle</a> to overcome.</p>
<p>And yet another example is that I also got to set up continuous <em>deployment</em>, first via Travis CI and then via the new GitHub Actions coolness. This, in turn, gave me ammo to write up more <a href="https://jmmv.dev/2021/01/github-actions-code-health.html">interesting</a> <a href="https://jmmv.dev/2021/01/do-not-submit.html">stuff</a> in this blog.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Copying an “old technology” is irrelevant.</strong> Yes, BASIC is not the language of the future (although… VB.NET users may disagree with you because it supports, I don’t know, thousands of businesses?). But that doesn’t matter. Only 5,000 lines of the codebase (about 30% of the total) are devoted to parsing the language, and most of those lines are unit tests anyway. If I wanted to change the language per se to offer a more “modern” experience with things like first-order functions, objects, etc. it’d be <em>trivial</em> to do so.</p>
<p>To be clear, I have no interest in building my own language as mentioned in the opening, but having worked on the <em>building blocks</em> of a real language is enlightening, and having those building blocks around will surely come in handy in the future.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>So what happened to the <a href="https://jmmv.dev/2020/04/hello-endbasic.html">original goal</a> of teaching programming to my kids via this project? Well… uhh… let’s say I’ve gotten distracted having fun by myself rather than actually getting them in front of this. I should get back to that goal after all the recent improvements to make the environment more usable and seeing if they care at all.</p>
<p>But yes. For the most part, EndBASIC is a crazy/useless language. Although… ~50 other people currently disagree with the thought of this being useless if <a href="https://github.com/jmmv/endbasic/">GitHub stars</a> mean anything at all 😉 If you are one of those ~50, thank you! And if you are not, join me in the craze?</p>
<p><strong>Edit (Jan 24th): If you are here from the recent bump in Hacker News, hello! I have <a href="https://jmmv.dev/2021/01/endbasic-0.5.html">just published the 0.5.0 release</a> which might answer some of the questions you have.</strong></p>
</article>
            </div>
          </div><div>
            <div>
              <p><b>Want more posts like this one? Take a moment to subscribe!</b></p>
            </div>
            <div>
              
              <p>
                  <a href="https://twitter.com/intent/follow?original_referer=https%3A%2F%2Fjmmv.dev%2F&amp;screen_name=jmmv">
                    <img src="https://jmmv.dev/images/badges/Twitter_logo_blue_32.png" alt="Follow @jmmv on Twitter">
                  </a>
                </p>
              <p><a href="https://jmmv.dev/feed.xml"><img src="https://jmmv.dev/images/badges/feed-icon-28x28.png" alt="RSS feed"></a></p>
            </div>
          </div><div>
            <div>
              <p><b>Enjoyed this article? Spread the word or join the ongoing discussion!</b></p>
            </div>
            
          </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jmmv.dev/2021/01/why-endbasic.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25884859</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 18:31:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Emails a browser extension developer gets from scammers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 194 | Comments 79 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25884338">thread link</a>) | @ajayyy
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://sponsor.ajay.app/emails/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://sponsor.ajay.app/emails/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p>I've been seeing a lot of stories about extensions getting taken over by unknown developers and becoming malware. Sadly, with how many permissions many  extensions have, it can do a lot of damage. I decided to compile a list of these sketchy emails I have received, to show the kinds of offers that exist.</p><p>To be clear I <strong>will never</strong> do anything of this sort, but make sure any extensions you install are from trusted developers and have as few permissions as possible. Most of these scams wouldn't even work with SponsorBlock due to lack of permissions (it only has access to youtube.com), but they spam email all developers anyway.</p><h2>From partners@infatica.io (A proxy service (botnet?)):</h2><p><a href="https://infatica.io/sdk-monetization/?utm_campaign=1+SDK+N+-+Accept+All">Their explanation page</a> <a href="https://archive.vn/Oax8a">(Archive)</a></p><p>Here's the <a href="https://pastebin.com/MXVMmwAx">code</a> for their sdk. In the email they told me it was "open", so that should mean it is meant to be public.</p><p><img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/12688112/105428261-04d7f180-5c1d-11eb-9d97-9f9be56eecef.png" alt="scam"><img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/12688112/105428173-d0643580-5c1c-11eb-8d41-a8214efa2725.png" alt="scam"><img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/12688112/105427987-68155400-5c1c-11eb-8837-cf6574dfea85.png" alt="scam"><img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/12688112/105427949-52079380-5c1c-11eb-956b-6e9a74d6567a.png" alt="scam"></p><h2>From extensionmetric.com</h2><p>The site disapeared exactly one month after their email, almost like they weren't planning on paying anything after all... Here's the <a href="https://pastebin.com/dUXNDfNs">code</a> for their sdk. This one is FAR worse than infatica. There are some calls to getAllResponseHeaders, which could mean stealing logged in accounts.</p><p><img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/12688112/105615170-8b670d00-5d9c-11eb-8f4d-9b9fe0c4a6e9.png" alt="scam"><img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/12688112/105615192-bb161500-5d9c-11eb-8185-2ff28ac67a1b.png" alt="scam"></p><h2>From datos.live:</h2><p><img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/12688112/105609313-6d86b180-5d76-11eb-8eb5-540e2ca76391.png" alt="scam"></p><h2>From admedia.com:</h2><p><img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/12688112/105428058-8d09c700-5c1c-11eb-861a-30af42eb7bfe.png" alt="scam"></p><h2>From invokevision.com/invoke.vision:</h2><p><img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/12688112/105428076-998e1f80-5c1c-11eb-8fce-d1f457bdd133.png" alt="scam"></p><h2>From admitad.com:</h2><p><img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/12688112/105428131-b62a5780-5c1c-11eb-9c7a-dde5c23b8bc1.png" alt="scam"></p><h2>From monetisationsolutions@gmail.com:</h2><p><img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/12688112/105428492-7dd74900-5c1d-11eb-842f-552131926ad5.png" alt="scam"></p><h2>From sponsoredsearchsolutions@gmail.com:</h2><p><img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/12688112/105428629-be36c700-5c1d-11eb-8408-88bce74574a8.png" alt="scam"></p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://sponsor.ajay.app/emails/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25884338</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 17:37:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[VisualAge for Java 1.0 – Let the Future Begin (1997)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 74 | Comments 43 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25884159">thread link</a>) | @rufus_foreman
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://www.tug.ca/articles/Volume13/V13N1/V13N1_Jenkins_VisualAge-for-Java.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.tug.ca/articles/Volume13/V13N1/V13N1_Jenkins_VisualAge-for-Java.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">

	<img src="https://www.tug.ca/articles/graphics/TUGLOGO_red.gif" alt=" Logo: TUG ">
	<span size="5" color="teal"><b>TORONTO USERS GROUP <i>for Midrange Systems</i></b></span><b><br>
	<span size="5" color="black">TUG </span></b>
	<span size="5" color="maroon"><b><i>e</i></b></span>
	<span size="5" color="black">-server magazine</span><h3>
September 1997: Volume 13, Number 1
	</h3><hr>



	<p>
<img src="https://www.tug.ca/articles/graphics/Verdana_I.gif">
n a recent interview, Bill Zeitler, IBM's General Manager for the AS/400 Division, was asked a very blunt question: What are you betting the AS/400 business on today?  His answer, in all of two words, was "Network Computing".  In the next breath, he explained that he wasn't just talking about connectivity, but about conducting business electronically, over the Internet, and largely by virtue of a superior Java environment.

</p><p>
It's remarkable to think that IBM is basing so much of its future on, of all things, a programming language, and on a programming language that not only didn't exist a few years ago, but also was developed by an IBM competitor, Sun Microsystems.  What on earth could a new programming language offer to merit such attention?  Some new killer op-code?  A revolutionary new way to program a do-loop?

<img src="https://www.tug.ca/articles/Volume13/V13N1/V13N1_Jenkins_Fig-1.jpg" alt="Figure 1. ">

</p><p>
The answer is that there is not much in the Java language itself to write home about - it is a slightly simplified and streamlined version of C++, with some features that make it suitable for running applications over a network - the Internet, for an obvious example.  However, Java does have the revolutionary attribute of being hardware platform and operating system independent: "Write Once, Run Anywhere" is the battle cry of the Java faithful, and when you think about it, it certainly would change the industry landscape if hardware platforms and their respective operating systems became the handmaidens of applications, not vice versa.  Put a Java applet on your Web page, and it can be used, unchanged, by a Windows user in Buenos Aires, a Mac bigot in Australia, a Unix nut in Sweden, and an OS/2 diehard in Singapore (and all this with no royalties accruing to Microsoft!)

</p><p>
Thus, Java has the potential, at least, to break the hold that the hardware and operating system monoliths have on the computer world, and could make hardware and software tycoons like Steve Jobs and Bill Gates as obsolete in the 21st century as railway barons have become in the 20th.  From IBM's point of view, if business application software were uncoupled from hardware platforms and operating systems, then computer systems could be sold on their own merits - robustness, security, manageability, etc. - and IBM no doubt feels that with the AS/400 they can compete quite well on that playing field.

</p><p>
Computer industry geopolitics aside, Java has become the Next Big Thing in the computer field - and if you're not constantly eager to get in on the Next Big Thing (even before you've fully mastered the Previous Three Big Things), then why the heck did you choose this industry to work in!

<img src="https://www.tug.ca/articles/Volume13/V13N1/V13N1_Jenkins_Fig-2.jpg" alt="Figure 2. ">

</p><p>
Since Java was introduced by Sun Microsystems, the Java Development Kit (JDK) has been available to be downloaded free over the Internet.  The JDK (now at version 1.1) includes a Java compiler, an applet viewer, and standard class libraries.  However, it is strictly command line based.  If you want to design the graphical interface of your application on-screen, as well as take advantage of the other benefits of graphical integrated development environments, you have to open your wallet a bit and look at something like Borland's JBuilder, Microsoft's Visual J++, or Symantec's Visual Café.  Or, as of July 25, IBM's Visual Age for Java.

</p><p>
The latest in IBM's Visual Age series of development environments had been available in a beta test version for several months, but recently Version 1.0 was officially released.  It's available in two flavours: the Professional Edition, and the pricier Enterprise Edition, which adds support for team development, as well as "Enterprise Access Builders" - tools for developing components to connect a Java client to various database platforms.  Within the Visual Age for Java environment you can create both applications and "applets" - Java programs that can be embedded in an HTML document and run by Web browsers which implement the JVM (Java Virtual Machine).  (Note that Visual Age for Java includes its own JVM as well as an applet viewer, so you can view and test your programs locally).  VA for Java also has a version control capability, and a debugger is included.

</p><p>
The Professional Edition is priced to compete with its counterparts mentioned above - that is, in the 100 - 200 dollar range per license.  However, if even that amount is a deterrent to you, the neophyte dabbler in Java, you may be interested to know that you can download a free copy of the Entry Edition - which contains all the functionality of the Professional Edition, minus only the documentation and online help, and limited to the creation of 100 classes.  In the remainder of this article, I'll show how you can download and install the Entry Edition of Visual Age for Java, and have a quick look at some of its features.

</p><p>
First, you'll have to consider the prerequisites, which are pretty significant, particularly for RAM.  You'll need Windows 95 or Windows NT 4.0 or OS/2 Warp V4, an SVGA display, and, IBM says, 32MB of RAM (with 48MB recommended), at least 45MB of free disk space for the software (with an additional 30MB free disk space for swapping), and lastly, an unzip program.

</p><p>
If you're still standing, here's where you can find the Entry Edition on the Internet: <a href="http://www.software.ibm.com/ad/vajava" target="_blank"> www.software.ibm.com/ad/vajava</a>.  (Before downloading it, you should uninstall any Beta versions of the product from your system).  The Windows version of the download file (wenty100.ZIP) is a single .ZIP file almost 22MB in size - so you'll finally be able to wallpaper that bathroom while it's downloading.  Download it into a temporary directory, then unzip it.  One of the unzipped files is a setup.exe file, which can be invoked to complete the installation.  There is also an install.txt file with further installation and troubleshooting information.
After a successful installation, you'll have an "IBM Visual Age for Java" icon on your desktop to invoke the program.  It will bring up the Workbench window seen in Figure 1.  It will also bring up the "Quick Start" window seen in Figure 2 (which also can be brought up at any time from the Window… Quick Start… menu option).  If you select to create a new applet, as shown, you will be taken to a Smart Guide window (comparable to a Windows 95 "wizard"), which prompts you for applet name, project, and package, and whether you want to design the applet visually, or write source code for it.  If you select the former, the Visual Composition Editor is invoked (Figure 3).

<img src="https://www.tug.ca/articles/Volume13/V13N1/V13N1_Jenkins_Fig-3.jpg" alt="Figure 3. ">

</p><p>
The Visual Composition Editor allows you to create a graphical interface, with all the usual components - buttons, lists, menus, entry fields, etc., which it calls (in yet another of those coffee metaphors which are already becoming tiresome) "beans".  These are selectable from the left hand side of the window.  Beyond just laying out an application window, basic application logic can be constructed by making connections between components in the window (marked out with the dashed line), or with non-visual components outside the window.  In the example shown, the Remove button has been connected to the list, to indicate that clicking Remove should delete the highlighted item from the list.  The source code for this event logic is then generated automatically.
With Version 1.0, "beans" for all the standard Java Class Libraries are available.  In future, more sophisticated - and AS/400-specific - components will accessible, allowing, for example, access to files and fields in DB2/400, analogous to using externally described files in RPG/400.

</p><p>
Regardless of how many pre-built components, or "beans", are available, there will always be a requirement for new classes in any custom application.  VA for Java of course enables the creation of such classes in the old fashioned way - typing source code - with Smart Guides that prompt you and provide some of the fundamental class definition code.  And even if you are programming the old fashioned way, the VA for Java environment makes life easier by making instantly accessible the definitions of all the classes on the system and their methods, organized by their respective packages, whether standard Java classes or your own previously created classes (see again Figure 1).  If, like me, you've tried to learn and program Java from one of the many books available today, you may have been frustrated by not having access to such comprehensive documentation of the numerous standard Java classes.

</p><div><p>
What I've given above is just a quick overview of IBM's Java development environment - and admittedly not much reference is made to where the AS/400 comes into all this.  The AS/400, as of V3R7, does not currently natively support Java applications - a coming release of OS/400 will rectify that.  And as of the time of writing this article, much of the AS/400-specific Java development capability is still under construction.  In future articles, I hope to explore more AS/400-related capabilities of Java as they become available.  In the meantime, the latest scoop from IBM is of course available on the Internet, at www.software.ibm.com/ad/vajava.   
 



	<span>T</span>
	<span>&lt;</span>
	<span>G</span></p></div><hr>

	</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.tug.ca/articles/Volume13/V13N1/V13N1_Jenkins_VisualAge-for-Java.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25884159</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 17:20:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[TRS-80: a TRS-80 running a custom Associated Press ROM]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 97 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25883853">thread link</a>) | @Aloha
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://wayne.lorentz.me/This_TRS-80/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://wayne.lorentz.me/This_TRS-80/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
		
		<section>
			<blockquote>
				<p>
					February 2019 â€” I created this document from a collection of memories of a particular time in my life.  It is accurate to the best of my memory, but that does not mean it is complete.  Still, I think itâ€™s worth making public because there is almost no similar information on the intarwebs.
				</p>
				<p>
					If youâ€™re here to read about the TRS-80 Model 100 computer, you will have to slog through a lot of background information and personal anecdotes.  I didnâ€™t write this for clicks, or popularity, or recognition.  I wrote it for my own edification.  And I wrote the text of it on a TRS-80 Model 100.
				</p>
			</blockquote>
		</section>
		<section>
			<h2>
				Introduction
			</h2>
			<p>
				There are many TRS-80â€™s in the world. But this one is mine.
			</p>
			<figure>
				<a href="https://wayne.lorentz.me/This_TRS-80/images/2000/TRS-80_Model_100-001.jpeg"><img src="https://wayne.lorentz.me/This_TRS-80/images/1000/TRS-80_Model_100-001.jpeg" alt="My TRS-80 Model 100 computer on a table at Starbucks, as I wrote this story."></a>
				<figcaption>My TRS-80 Model 100 computer on a table at Starbucks, as I wrote this story.</figcaption>
			</figure>
			<p>
				The TRS-80 Model 100 is claimed by some to be the worldâ€™s first portable computer.  Whether that is true or not is hard to say.  Ninety percent of online journalism these days is nothing more than wannabe reporters summarizing other peopleâ€™s assumptions from web sites that know how to game a search engine.  But looking at old magazines of its era, the Model 100 was at least the first portable computer that wasnâ€™t a glorified calculator, or a suitcase so hefty that you could chock a tire with it to keep a Greyhound bus from rolling away.
			</p>
			<p>
				This document exists to show that the urban legend about TRS-80's being the devices that ushered journalism into the modern age is true. The Model 100 was a workhorse for a number of journalists, including a cadre of  roving correspondents for the Associated Press.  And also for me: a cub reporter for a radio station in a medium-sized, unremarkable city.
			</p>
		</section>
		<section>
			<h2>
				Background
			</h2>
			<p>
				This was a city not unlike dozens of other river towns across the United States.  For me, it wasnâ€™t my first experience as a broadcast journalist, but it was my first full-time, all-on-my-own job hundreds of miles from home.  More importantly, it was my first job with a computer.
			</p>
			<p>
				The conventional wisdom is that the computer revolution came all at once, and from the top down; with big businesses investing in hardware and software to make their employees more productive.  But it was a two-pronged offense.
			</p>
			<p>
				While desktop computers were commonplace in large companies in large office towers in large cities, it took decades for computers to become everyday objects in 90% of America.
			</p>
			<p>
				The second prong came from that 90%.
			</p>
			<p>
				Across the country, computers were becoming regular fixtures in ordinary households.  Commodore 64â€™s, TI99/4Aâ€™s, Apple ][â€™s and the like opened up a new world of possibilities for Joe and Jane Lunchbucket, and their children.  Online services like CompuServe, QLink, The Source, and Delphi connected people to information and each other in ways that previous generations could only imagine.
			</p>
			<p>
				It was also unimaginable to many of the people running the companies for which these people worked.
			</p>
			<p>
				Even as late as the turn of the millennium, it was commonplace for someone to have a computer and online connection at home that was faster and better than what was available in their workplace.  Complaints about this upside-down situation put pressure on small and mid-sized companies to land computers on every desk.  Firms like Dell, Gateway 2000 and eMachines were happy to churn out millions of low-quality â€œbusiness" computers to fill this technology gap.
			</p>
			<p>
				This story starts during the early portion of that gap.
			</p>
		</section>
		<section>
			<h2>
				Work before computers
			</h2>
			<p>
				I had a computer at home.  It was home-built, which wasnâ€™t unusual for the time.  But at work, it was all typewriters and pencils.  So many pencils.  I often wondered if it would make sense for all the reporters to put their pencils in a big communal bucket and have the interns sharpen them at the beginning of each work day.
			</p>
			<p>
				In addition to pencils, the primary tools of the reporterâ€™s trade were reporter notepads.  These are special spiral-bound pads of lined paper that are unusually narrow and unusually long.  They are the perfect size for stuffing into the inside pocket of a suit jacket or the outside pocket of a trench coat.  Each big story got its own pad, and youâ€™d build up a library of pads as an archive you could reference.
			</p>
			<p>
				Reporter pads were more than utilitarian.  They helped define the local journalism hierarchy.  Interns and reporters for alternative rags carried steno pads.  Real journalists had real reporter notepads from real journalism supply companies.
			</p>
			<p>
				But there was another level in the notepad caste system.  If you were lucky enough to be in the presence of a network correspondent, or someone working for one of the broadsheet institutions, you might be lucky enough to catch a glimpse of their special reporter notepads.  These looked like the regular notepads that plebs like myself used.  But their companies were so professional, and so focused on making sure their people had everything they needed to do a good job that the notepads had the company logos stamped on the cover.  It was like bird watching for news nerds.  A big black CBS eye here. An academic maroon AP logo there.  A corporate blue UPI logo could be spied if you were very lucky.
			</p>
			<p>
				Just as important as paper were the pencils a reporter carried.  Pens were right out.  If a pen dries up, explodes in your pocket, or otherwise refuses to cooperate, youâ€™re screwed.  A pencilâ€™s point might break, but you could pop into any random office building and ask the first secretary you came across to use her sharpener.  Plus, you always carried a fistful of spares.  In the worst case scenario, you could use a random sharp implement to expose enough lead to scratch with.  We all envisioned a story that was so important weâ€™d have to gnaw the wood off the end of a pencil just to make sure we didnâ€™t miss that career-making quote.
			</p>
			<figure>
				<a href="https://wayne.lorentz.me/This_TRS-80/images/2000/TRS-80_Model_100-008.jpeg"><img src="https://wayne.lorentz.me/This_TRS-80/images/1000/TRS-80_Model_100-008.jpeg" alt="Teletype paper from 1983"></a>
				<figcaption>Teletype paper was never meant to last more than a few hours or days.  This is from 1983.</figcaption>
			</figure>
			<p>
				In the radio newsroom, an intermittent tide of information came in on an Associated Press teletype machine.  It was something that looked like it belonged on the deck of a battleship spewing hot lead at airborne foes.  Two or three times a day someone would search through the ribbon of paper it spit onto the floor, rip each story from the spool, and file the stories into wire baskets labeled â€œLocal,â€� â€œState,â€� and â€œNational.â€�  There was also a â€œSaveâ€� bin way off to the side where people could collect copies of important news alerts and bulletins for posterity or their own personal collections.  International news went into the trash bins.  Thatâ€™s what we had the national network for.
			</p>
			<p>
				Thatâ€™s not to say that we didnâ€™t know what was going on.  At that level, all reporters are experts on national issues and foreign affairs.  Just ask them.  It was a game of one-upmanship that we all played to feed the fantasy that we might get a call from the network to join the big leagues in New York or D.C.  Which almost never happened.  No matter how much you contributed, you were more likely to squeeze into one of the few desirable slots at Voice of America than to be remembered by the network editors at Black Rock for more than six seconds after your voice left their air.
			</p>
			<p>
				But while we had pencils and we had paper and we had teletype machines, what we didnâ€™t have were computers.
			</p>
			<p>
				In school the boys didnâ€™t learn how to type.  That was for girls.  But since I had a computer at home, I knew my way around a keyboard.  You couldnâ€™t get a journalism degree without being able to bang out 40 words per minute on an IBM Selectric.  My scores were consistently above 80.  My J-school professors thought I was cheating.
			</p>
			<p>
				When I started my career, my home base was an AM/FM combo in the center of a small market.  Since I wasnâ€™t a full-time employee, I was free to work elsewhere.  And I did.  I would do a day at this station to fill in for someone who was sick, or a week at that station so someone could go on vacation.  At the time, it was very unusual for a local radio station to not have news at least once an hour.  Automation existed, but the spinning wheels of carts stopped when it was time for news.
			</p>
			<p>
				Doing news after school and on weekends helped pay for college.  To make that happen I got myself on the fill-in sheets of half the radio stations within 200 miles of where I lived.  Doing so allowed me to list more than a dozen commercial stations on my resume at a point in my career when my peers were lucky to get a DJ shift at a carrier current college station.
			</p>
			<p>
				I was bouncing between so many stations that one day I did, regrettably, announce that â€œKOJ news time is 7:05â€� on a station that wasnâ€™t KOJ.  The good people at K-104 never asked me back, which was a shame.  It was the first place I ever considered working full-time.  The facilities at K-104 were terrible.  But that was because management invested money in the employees instead of the physical plant, and everyone was paid far above what the competition paid.  The result was that everyone worked hard, and we were all handsomely rewarded.  But after my on-air mistake, I decided it was time to find one job, and stick to it.
			</p>
			<p>
				When it came time for a career change, I did what all radio people did: I consulted the help wanted listings in a strange industry newsletter that came in every day by fax.  Some station managers would tear the want ads off the end of the transmissions.  It was a very effective way to keep people from jumping ship in an era when information was still easy to control.  But if you were on the morning shift, you came in six hours before sales and management. That gave you an …</p></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://wayne.lorentz.me/This_TRS-80/">https://wayne.lorentz.me/This_TRS-80/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://wayne.lorentz.me/This_TRS-80/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25883853</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 16:57:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Replicating GPT-2 at Home]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 250 | Comments 45 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25883791">thread link</a>) | @bkkaggle
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://bkkaggle.github.io/blog/algpt2/2020/07/17/ALGPT2-part-2.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bkkaggle.github.io/blog/algpt2/2020/07/17/ALGPT2-part-2.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <ul>
<li><a href="#tldr">TL;DR</a></li>
<li><a href="#the-idea">The Idea</a></li>
<li><a href="#background">Background</a></li>
<li><a href="#gpt-2-and-albert">GPT-2 and ALBERT</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#factorized-embedding">Factorized embedding</a></li>
<li><a href="#layer-wise-parameter-sharing">Layer-wise parameter sharing</a></li>
<li><a href="#sentence-order-prediction-auxillary-loss">Sentence-order-prediction auxillary loss</a></li>
<li><a href="#removing-dropout">Removing dropout</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#setup">Setup</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#openwebtext">OpenWebText</a></li>
<li><a href="#tokenization">Tokenization</a></li>
<li><a href="#tfrecords">TFRecords</a></li>
<li><a href="#coding-it-up">Coding it up</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#replicating-gpt-2">Replicating GPT-2</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#replicating-gpt-2-1">Replicating GPT-2</a></li>
<li><a href="#adamw-vs-adafactor">AdamW vs Adafactor</a></li>
<li><a href="#learning-rates">Learning rates</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#pretraining-algpt-2">Pretraining ALGPT-2</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#implementing-parameter-sharing">Implementing parameter sharing</a></li>
<li><a href="#implementing-a-factorized-embedding">Implementing a factorized embedding</a></li>
<li><a href="#effect-of-layer-wise-parameter-sharing">Effect of layer-wise parameter sharing</a></li>
<li><a href="#effect-of-removing-dropout">Effect of removing dropout</a></li>
<li><a href="#effect-of-factorized-embeddings">Effect of factorized embeddings</a></li>
<li><a href="#effect-of-model-size">Effect of model size</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#conclusion-and-next-steps">Conclusion and next steps</a></li>
</ul><hr>

<blockquote>
  <p><a href="https://bkkaggle.github.io/blog/algpt2/2020/06/22/ALGPT2-part-1">Part 1: Best Practices for Finetuning Large Transformer Language models</a></p>

  <p>Part 2: How I (almost) replicated OpenAI’s GPT-2 (124M version)</p>
</blockquote>

<hr>

<blockquote>
  <p>small update (01/25/21): I posted this to <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25883791">HN</a> and it ended up at the top of the front page for a couple of hours :O</p>
</blockquote>



<hr>

<p>A few months ago I started working on a research project trying to pretrain my own, more efficient language model from scratch. I got access to a 128-core TPUv3 pod from the Tensorflow Reseach Cloud and used it to pretrain a $124$M parameter GPT-2 model to a perplexity pretty close to OpenAI’s results (my pretrained model was trained for about $1/8$th of the number of iterations that OpenAI trained their model for and got $21$ ppl on OpenWebText compared to $17$ ppl for OpenAI’s model), and then pretrained an ALBERT-style GPT-2 (that I’m calling ALGPT2) language model with a factorized input embedding and layer-wise parameter sharing that would reduce the number of paramters in the model from $124$M to around $12$M.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, ALGPT-2 doesn’t perform as well as GPT-2 (ALGPT-2 gets $31$ ppl on OpenWebText compared to $21$ ppl for my pretrained GPT-2 model), but I’m writing this series of blog posts to go through everything I’ve learned over the last few months.</p>

<hr>



<hr>

<p>The main thing that I wanted to do from this sort-of “research project” that I was working on by myself this spring was to develop and train a more efficient version of the $124$M parameter version of <a href="https://openai.com/blog/better-language-models/">GPT-2</a>. I wanted to pretrain the $1.5$B parameter version of GPT-2 but since I only got access to the TPU pod for a week, I had to choose a model that would train in time. A $100$k iteration training run takes about $20$ hours to run which gave me plenty of time to run multiple experiments. In contrast, following OpenAI’s training procedure exactly and training for the full $800$k iterations would take up almost an entire week and use up most of my quota.</p>

<p>I was able to almost replicate the $124$M parameter version of GPT-2 by pretraining it to a perplexity pretty close to OpenAI’s results (my pretrained model used was trained for about $1/8$th of the number of iterations that OpenAI trained their model for and got $21$ perplexity (ppl) on the standard OpenWebText dataset compared to $17$ ppl for OpenAI’s model),</p>

<p>My idea of making a more efficient transformer didn’t really work out since my pretrained transformer ended up being about $20$ppl worse than an equivalent GPT-2 model, but I wanted to writeup what I learned over the two or three months that I was working on this anyway.</p>

<hr>



<hr>

<p>A little bit about myself: I’m an incoming software engineering student at the University of Waterloo and this post is supposed to be a writeup of a NLP research project that I was working on from around March to May of 2020 (right in the middle of the first Covid-19 lockdown of 2020, I’m currently writing this on July 15, 2020 while waiting for my Pix2PixHD model to train for a few hundred epochs on colab for a new project that I’m working on).</p>

<p>I was pretty lucky that I started learning NLP right before transformers exploded in popularity, I remember when <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1301.3781">word2vec</a> and LSTMs were SOTA on a lot of NLP tasks, and it has been really interesting to see how much the field of NLP has changed in just a few years, going from when LSTMs with only a a handful of layers and somewhere on the order of $512$ units were considered to be large networks and computationally expensive to train, to training LSTMs with <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1409.0473">attention</a> layers on top, to the original <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1706.03762">transformer encoder/decoder networks</a>, to <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1801.06146">ULMFIT</a> and <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1802.05365">ELMO</a>, then <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.04805">BERT</a>, <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1907.11692">RoBERTa</a>, <a href="https://openai.com/blog/better-language-models/">GPT-2</a>, and <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1910.10683">T5</a>, to just a few months ago with the explosion of new, more efficient replacements for self-attention like the <a href="https://openai.com/blog/sparse-transformer/">Sparse Transformer</a>, the <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2001.04451">Reformer</a>, and <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2005.00743">Synthesizers</a>, and now <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2005.14165">GPT-3</a>, which IMO has the potential to really change the whole field of NLP.</p>

<p>Just a few years ago we trained shallow recurrent networks on datasets, then pretrained large transformer language models on large datasets and finetuned on task-specific datasets. Now the whole idea of just training a gigantic language model on a huge dataset, then conditioning the model in a form of few-shot learning by prepending a few examples of a certain task to an input feels like it can really make NLP models a lot more accessible and easier to productionize as well as making human-chatbot interactions a lot more realistic than they are today.</p>

<p>I’ve rambled on for long enough, lets get to the main topic of this post.</p>

<hr>



<hr>

<p><a href="https://openai.com/blog/better-language-models/">GPT-2</a> is a transformer decoder.</p>

<p>The embedding layer at the root of the model maps a one-hot vector of a given token’s index (all the GPT-2 models use a vocabulary size of $50257$) to a $768$ dimensional vector (all GPT-2 numbers in this blog post will be for the $124$m parameter version of GPT-2).</p>

<p>The embedding matrix is followed by a stack of self-attention and feed-forward layers that each output a $768$ dimensional vector (keeping the number of outputs for each layer constant), which makes up the main part of the transformer.</p>

<p>The stack of self-attention layers is then followed by an output embedding (the weights of the input and output embeddings are tied to make training easier) that maps the $768$ dimensional vector that is the output of the last layer of the transformer to the same $50257$ dimensional vector that represents the probability of each token in the vocabulary being the next token in the sequence.</p>

<p>Take a look at <a href="http://jalammar.github.io/illustrated-gpt2/">The Illustrated GPT-2</a> for a more in-depth look into GPT-2.</p>

<p><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1909.11942">ALBERT</a> (A Lite BERT) is a paper that takes a look at <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.04805">BERT</a> and identifies some ways in which to make it more efficient and reduce the number of parameters in the model in four major ways: a factorized embedding, layer-wise parameter sharing, a sentence-order-prediction auxillary loss, and removing dropout.</p>

<hr>

<h3 id="factorized-embedding">
Factorized embedding</h3>

<hr>

<p>GPT-2’s embedding has a lot of parameters. It’s really just a matrix of dimensions $50257 \times 768$. That means that the input embedding alone uses up almost $50257 \times 768 = \space \sim 38,000,000$ parameters which is a pretty big chunk of the $128$M total parameters in the model.</p>

<p>The ALBERT authors propose a factorized embedding with an intermediate embedding size of $128$: one embedding of size $50257 \times 128$ and another embedding of size $128 \times 768$. By breaking up the large embedding matrix into two smaller matrices, the total number of parameters used in the embedding goes from about $38$M to about $6$M.</p>

<p>$50257 \times 128 = \sim 6,000,000$</p>

<p>$128 \times 768 = \sim 100,000$</p>

<p>The authors try different intermediate embedding sizes and settle on $128$ as a good tradeoff betweeen parameters and performance.</p>

<hr>

<h3 id="layer-wise-parameter-sharing">
Layer-wise parameter sharing</h3>

<hr>

<p>In a normal transformer model, the transformer layers are created something like this:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>class</span> <span>BERT</span><span>(</span><span>nn</span><span>.</span><span>Module</span><span>):</span>
    <span>def</span> <span>__init__</span><span>(</span><span>self</span><span>,</span> <span>n_layers</span><span>):</span>
        <span>super</span><span>().</span><span>__init__</span><span>()</span>
        <span>//</span> <span>...</span>
        <span>self</span><span>.</span><span>blocks</span> <span>=</span> <span>nn</span><span>.</span><span>ModuleList</span><span>([</span><span>Block</span><span>()</span> <span>for</span> <span>_</span> <span>in</span> <span>range</span><span>(</span><span>n_layers</span><span>)])</span>
        <span>//</span> <span>...</span>
    <span>def</span> <span>forward</span><span>(</span><span>self</span><span>,</span> <span>x</span><span>):</span>
        <span>//</span> <span>...</span>
        <span>for</span> <span>block</span> <span>in</span> <span>self</span><span>.</span><span>blocks</span><span>:</span>
            <span>x</span> <span>=</span> <span>block</span><span>(</span><span>x</span><span>)</span>
        <span>//</span> <span>...</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>ALBERT shares all parameters across the transformer layers something like this:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>class</span> <span>ALBERT</span><span>(</span><span>nn</span><span>.</span><span>Module</span><span>):</span>
    <span>def</span> <span>__init__</span><span>(</span><span>self</span><span>,</span> <span>n_layers</span><span>):</span>
        <span>super</span><span>().</span><span>__init__</span><span>()</span>
        <span>//</span> <span>...</span>

        <span>self</span><span>.</span><span>n_layers</span> <span>=</span> <span>n_layers</span>
        <span>self</span><span>.</span><span>block</span> <span>=</span> <span>Block</span><span>()</span>
        <span>//</span> <span>...</span>
    <span>def</span> <span>forward</span><span>(</span><span>self</span><span>,</span> <span>x</span><span>):</span>
        <span>//</span> <span>...</span>
        <span>for</span> <span>_</span> <span>in</span> <span>self</span><span>.</span><span>n_layers</span><span>:</span>
            <span>x</span> <span>=</span> <span>block</span><span>(</span><span>x</span><span>)</span>
        <span>//</span> <span>...</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>By only defining one transformer block and looping around it <code>n_layers</code> times, ALBERT saves the GPU memory that would be used to store the parameters for all the layers.</p>

<p>Since we normally use $32$ bit floats to store parameters on the GPU, storing the $1.5$B parameter GPT-2 on the GPU will use up about $6$GB of the GPU’s memory — that’s a pretty big chunk of the $16$GB of memory that’s on a normal V100 GPU already being used up before taking into account the memory needed to store the model’s activations as well as any momentum parameters needed by the optimizer. In contrast, if you share parameters across all transformer layers in the $1.5$B parameter GPT-2, the resulting model will only have about $37$M parameters, the parameter-sharing version would only use up around $148$MB of GPU memory.</p>

<p>The authors try applying parameter sharing to BERT and see that it reduces performance but makes it easier to train larger and larger models.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>In a machine learning framework like JAX, which by default unrolls and inlines loops when it’s compiling your code with XLA, the size of the unrolled and inlined loop would make the computation graph really large and take a long time to compile. This is why you’re recommended to use somehting like <a href="https://jax.readthedocs.io/en/latest/_autosummary/jax.lax.scan.html"><code>lax.scan()</code></a> in these situations.</p>
</blockquote>

<hr>

<h3 id="sentence-order-prediction-auxillary-loss">
Sentence-order-prediction auxillary loss</h3>

<p>The ALBERT authors add an auxillary loss to help training. Since language modelling is usually done autoregressively, I didn’t use this for my custom model.</p>

<hr>

<h3 id="removing-dropout">
Removing dropout</h3>

<p>The ALBERT authors remove all dropout from BERT and see that it significantly improves performance.</p>

<hr>

<p>That’s pretty much what my idea was: Take GPT-2, add a factorized embedding, share parameters across all transformer layers, remove dropout (I actually missed the part about ALBERT removing dropout until I was pretty far into my work, but I did run one or two runs without dropout to see how that works), and pretrain on a large dataset for a few hundred thousand iterations.</p>

<p>There’s no way …</p></div></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://bkkaggle.github.io/blog/algpt2/2020/07/17/ALGPT2-part-2.html">https://bkkaggle.github.io/blog/algpt2/2020/07/17/ALGPT2-part-2.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bkkaggle.github.io/blog/algpt2/2020/07/17/ALGPT2-part-2.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25883791</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 16:52:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Rollerball Pens of 2021]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 123 | Comments 125 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25882702">thread link</a>) | @thomas
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://unsharpen.com/best-rollerball-pen/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://unsharpen.com/best-rollerball-pen/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p><small>Unsharpen may earn a commission when you buy through links on our site.</small></p><div>

                                
                                <p>If you are in search of a great rollerball you have a lot of work ahead of you. There are many brands of rollerball pens and many styles of rollerball inks, as well as many sizes and colors.</p>
<p>We’ve done the testing and done the research to fine the best rollerball pens and rollerball refills available today.</p>

<h2><span id="What_Is_A_Rollerball_Pen">What Is A Rollerball Pen?</span></h2>
<p>As we noted in our <a href="https://unsharpen.com/ballpoint-vs-rollerball/">rollerball vs. ballpoint guide</a>, a rollerball is a pen that uses water-based ink where a ballpoint pen uses oil-based ink. Rollerballs use smaller writing tips — usually 0.5 mm or 0.7 mm — because their ink spreads out on the paper and forms lines that are wider than the tip of the pen. Most rollerballs use dye for color but some are pigments so they are water-resistant and semi-permanent.</p>
<p>Japanese pen maker Ohto is created with developing the first rollerball, then known as the “water-based ballpoint ink pen” in 1964.</p>
<figure id="attachment_7469" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7469"><a href="https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/Unsharpen-Rollerball-Scan-scaled.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/Unsharpen-Rollerball-Scan-450x303.jpg" alt="Unsharpen Rollerball Scan" width="450" height="303" srcset="https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/Unsharpen-Rollerball-Scan-450x303.jpg 450w, https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/Unsharpen-Rollerball-Scan-1024x690.jpg 1024w, https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/Unsharpen-Rollerball-Scan-768x517.jpg 768w, https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/Unsharpen-Rollerball-Scan-1536x1035.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7469">Unsharpen Rollerball Pen Testing Sample Scan</figcaption></figure><h2><span id="Testing_Rollerball_Pens">Testing Rollerball Pens</span></h2>
<p>In order to create this guide in a repeatable, methodical manner, we purchased a large number of rollerball pens and refills and use each across a number of different paper types. The favorite pens and refills were isolated and then used further, both for testing and real-world writing. The below rollerball pens — our top picks — are the ones we considered to be the finest rollerballs sold today.</p>
<p>Please note, that while the initial testing list included many rollerball pens, the list was not exhaustive and where are always pens and refills that will be missing in any test like this. Please contact us if you see anything notable missing.</p>
<p>Where possible all sizes of a rollerball were tested and both blue and black were testing. When options were limited the focus was on blue and 1.0 mm, which is where a rollerball can really differentiate itself from the competition.</p>
<p>Please note that gel pens were not part of this test. Gel pens have become their own category and will receive their own buying guide! <a href="https://unsharpen.com/rollerball-pen-fountain-pen-ink/">Refillable rollerball pens</a> are eligible for this list.</p>
<h2><span id="Best_Mainstream_Rollerball_Pens">Best Mainstream Rollerball Pens</span></h2>
<p>If you find yourself walking through the aisles of an office superstore and you want a great rollerball, what should you get? Or if you want a 12-pack of excellent, not-too-expensive rollerballs, what’s the best pick? These are the pens in this list.</p>
<h3><span id="Uni-ball_Vision_Elite">Uni-ball Vision Elite</span></h3>
<p>The <a href="https://unsharpen.com/pen/uni-ball-vision-elite/">Uni-ball Vision Elite</a>&nbsp;has lone been a top pick among choosy rollerball fans as well as dedicated fountain pen users who want something for day-to-day writing. This pen is smooth, a bit watery in its ink, and uses Uni-ball’s Super Ink, which is chemical-, water-, and fade-resistant, plus is acid-free and of archival quality.</p>
<p>This pen is affordable, easy to find, quite smooth, and is reliable. The downsides are that its design is somewhat dated at this point, and it’s not really refillable <a href="https://amzn.to/3hrqYhu" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">(the refills are almost full pens themselves</a>). This is the essence of a great everyday rollerball.</p>
<p><a href="https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/Uni-ball_Vision_Elite.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/Uni-ball_Vision_Elite-450x51.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="51" srcset="https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/Uni-ball_Vision_Elite-450x51.jpg 450w, https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/Uni-ball_Vision_Elite-1024x117.jpg 1024w, https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/Uni-ball_Vision_Elite-768x87.jpg 768w, https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/Uni-ball_Vision_Elite.jpg 1476w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px"></a></p>
<h3><span id="Uni-ball_Air">Uni-ball Air</span></h3>
<p>The <a href="https://unsharpen.com/pen/uni-ball-air/">Uni-ball Air</a>&nbsp;is a unique, high-tech take of the everyday rollerball. It also uses Uni-ball’s everything-resistant Super Ink and it’s similarly not refillable, but it has Uni’s “Cushion Tip” writing end which is smooth and forgiving, making the pen a great choice for almost all writing scenarios.</p>
<p>The pen isn’t refillable and has an entirely plastic body (including the clip), but it’s still a great everyday rollerball because it’s fun to use, easy to find, and a great writer overall.</p>
<h2><span id="Best_Rollerball_Pens">Best Rollerball Pens</span></h2>
<p>If you are in the market for a great rollerball pen and are willing to upgrade past a disposable pen, here are the top picks of 2021.</p>
<p><a href="https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/zoom_505-e1608993432315.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/zoom_505-e1608993432315-450x44.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="44" srcset="https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/zoom_505-e1608993432315-450x44.jpg 450w, https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/zoom_505-e1608993432315-768x75.jpg 768w, https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/zoom_505-e1608993432315.jpg 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px"></a></p>
<h3><span id="Tombow_Zoom_505">Tombow Zoom 505</span></h3>
<p>The Tombow Zoom 505 combines an affordable metal body with a pigmented refill that is permanent and surprisingly fun to use, even though Tombow is not typically known for their rollerballs. The build quality of this pen’s body is excellent for the price which is surprising right around $20.</p>
<p>The Tombow Zoom 505 also benefits from being sold as a set of instruments. So if you like the rollerball, you can also buy the 505 in a mechanical pencil and a fountain pen. The downsides of this rollerball are that it has a proprietary refill, the older models of which tend to leak, but it’s still a great writer.</p>
<h3><span id="Lamy_Vista">Lamy Vista</span></h3>
<p>The Lamy Vista (the clear version of the Lamy Safari) uses Lamy’s <a href="https://unsharpen.com/refill/lamy-m63/">M63 rollerball refill</a>. This means the pen is a combination of a good rollerball refill and a great pen body. The good news is that the refill is easy to swap out if you want to use a standard European rollerball refill, like a Waterman or even a Pilot G2 gel refill. This is just an all-round great pen that is ideal for everyday use and will last you for years of writing.l</p>
<p><a href="https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/Pilot-Rollerballs.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/Pilot-Rollerballs-450x226.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="226" srcset="https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/Pilot-Rollerballs-450x226.jpg 450w, https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/Pilot-Rollerballs-768x386.jpg 768w, https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/Pilot-Rollerballs-1024x515.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px"></a></p>
<h3><span id="Pilot_Hi-Tecpoint_V7">Pilot Hi-Tecpoint V7</span></h3>
<p>The <a href="https://unsharpen.com/pilot-precise-and-hi-tecpoint-pen-guide/">Hi-Tecpoint V7</a> is a refillable rollerball pen that uses fountain pen-like cartridges and a liquid rollerball ink. The pen is great looking, with a flat paint job, and handsome aesthetics. The pen is like a better version of the Pilot Precise V7 — which is much more common in the US — because the Hi-Tecpoint looks better and is refillable using a cartridge.</p>
<p>Then pen is also sold in a very wet 1.0 mm and a smooth but precise 0.5 mm version, called the <a href="https://unsharpen.com/pen/pilot-v10-grip-hi-tecpoint/">V10</a> and V5 respectively.</p>
<p><a href="https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/stabilo-bionic-worker.png"><img loading="lazy" src="https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/stabilo-bionic-worker-450x46.png" alt="" width="450" height="46" srcset="https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/stabilo-bionic-worker-450x46.png 450w, https://4bdggq3b9eos1q9hpx466wnu-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/stabilo-bionic-worker.png 680w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px"></a></p>
<h3><span id="Stabilo_Worker">Stabilo Worker+</span></h3>
<p>While it’s not as popular as the rest of the pens on this list, the Stabilo Worker+ is an excellent roller, as is its refillable counterpart, the <a href="https://unsharpen.com/pen/stabilo-bionic/">Bionic</a>. These pens have confusing conventions, where the 0.5 mm Medium version writes more like a 1.0 mm, but they are both exceptionally smooth and comfortable pens.</p>
<p>The Worker+ is known for its bold orange body and comfortable rubber coating, but then pen is also available in black, grey, and now other colors if you want something more muted.</p>
<p>This is super smooth rollerball that deserves more attention.</p>



                            </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://unsharpen.com/best-rollerball-pen/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25882702</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 15:04:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[FBI agents track cell phones that pinged near the Capitol]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 364 | Comments 483 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25882688">thread link</a>) | @danso
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://www.wusa9.com/article/features/producers-picks/fbi-tracks-cell-phones-that-were-near-capitol-insurrection-and-riot/65-ca268165-a5c5-46a4-8b88-943a8517343a | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.wusa9.com/article/features/producers-picks/fbi-tracks-cell-phones-that-were-near-capitol-insurrection-and-riot/65-ca268165-a5c5-46a4-8b88-943a8517343a">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>A DC woman said an FBI agent contacted her and said investigators were reaching out to the owner of every phone that touched a cell tower near the riot.</p><div>
                            <p>WASHINGTON — If you were anywhere near the Capitol on Jan. 6, you may be getting a knock on your door from the FBI.</p>
                    <p>A D.C. woman said an agent visited her neighbor and called her, telling them investigators were tracking people whose cell phones connected to wi-fi or pinged cell phone towers near the Capitol during the riots.</p>
                        
                    <p>"They don't call first, they just come to your house," Bree Stevens, a legal investigator who lives near Capitol Hill, said.&nbsp;</p>
                    <p>Stevens said an FBI agent told her they were reaching out to every single person whose cell phone put them near the Capitol during the riots.</p>
                    <p>She was out for a walk with a friend and his two young daughters on the afternoon of Jan. 6, but they were diverted by bomb scares until they ended up right next to the insurrection. Adults and kids were cordoned off and unable to get back to their apartments for four hours.</p>
                    <p>"You don't want to be anywhere where they're going to go!" she said on a video she shot while police officers in riot gear quick-stepped toward the Capitol.&nbsp;</p>
                                <div>
        <div data-module="video" data-stream="https://video.tegna-media.com/assets/WUSA/videos/187d0b2f-3e6e-4754-8f6a-fa7174d479fd/187d0b2f-3e6e-4754-8f6a-fa7174d479fd.m3u8" data-float="false" data-thumbnail="https://media.wusa9.com/assets/WUSA/images/05e27a77-8b56-418d-aede-fe82b97100b1/05e27a77-8b56-418d-aede-fe82b97100b1_1920x1080.jpg" data-title="More than 85 people charged in the US Capitol riots" data-description="Authorities say additional complaints have been submitted and investigations are ongoing." data-site="65" data-id="187d0b2f-3e6e-4754-8f6a-fa7174d479fd" data-dfpposition="" data-mute="false" data-autoplay="false" data-link="https://www.wusa9.com/video/news/more-than-85-people-charged-in-the-us-capitol-riots/65-187d0b2f-3e6e-4754-8f6a-fa7174d479fd" data-origin="clipping" data-section="news" data-subsection="" data-subcategory="" data-topic="" data-subtopic="" data-captions="" data-related-playlist-id="tSIkxFyA" data-related-media-id="9qoUuTLb" data-use-trending="true" data-is-watch-player="false" data-is-live-now="false" data-ugc-preroll-disabled="true" data-duration="129" data-disable-preroll-at-duration="0">
            <div>
                <div>
                    <div>
                        <div>
                            <p><img data-asset-fallback="default" src="https://media.wusa9.com/assets/WUSA/images/05e27a77-8b56-418d-aede-fe82b97100b1/05e27a77-8b56-418d-aede-fe82b97100b1_1920x1080.jpg"></p>
                            
                        </div>
                        
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
                            
        </div>
                                </div>
                    <p><br>Monday night, an investigator knocked on the door of her friend's apartment, who was "in house clothes" at the time.&nbsp;</p>
                    <p>"His little girl had just painted his toenails, that was a little bit embarrassing," Stevens said.&nbsp;</p>
                    <p>Stevens was out of town, so the agent called her on the phone number that the FBI had tracked.&nbsp;</p>
                    <p>"Extremely creepy, because he explained that they have everyone’s phone number from pinging off the cell phone towers, and they know basically exactly where you were, within the vicinity of the Capitol," Stevens said. "And they can actually pinpoint on Google Maps exactly where you were standing. Like, he knew where I was standing on the sidewalk, like specifically, based on my cell phone ping."&nbsp;</p>
                    <p>Stevens said the agent told her she wasn't a suspect, but said he wanted pictures of things she might have seen.</p>
                    <p>Some civil rights advocates are concerned about the FBI's surveillance power.</p>
                    <p>When contacted, the FBI declined to discuss its investigative methods.&nbsp;</p>
                                

                    
                    
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.wusa9.com/article/features/producers-picks/fbi-tracks-cell-phones-that-were-near-capitol-insurrection-and-riot/65-ca268165-a5c5-46a4-8b88-943a8517343a</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25882688</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 15:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Teleguard: Swiss Made Safe Messaging]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 54 | Comments 77 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25882319">thread link</a>) | @0x10c0fe11ce
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://teleguard.com/en/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://teleguard.com/en/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        


<section id="screenshots">
    <div>
        
        <h2>get in touch with the swiss feeling of modern messaging</h2>

        

        
    </div>
</section>

<section id="benefits">
    <p>
        
        <h2>Designed to be the most private messenger in the world</h2>
    </p>
    <div>
        <div>
            <div>
                <svg><use xlink:href="/images/icons.svg#teleguard-swiss-outline"></use></svg>
                <p>Practical, modern messenger with full functionality for iOS and Android</p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <svg><use xlink:href="/images/icons.svg#shield-account-outline"></use></svg>
                <p>Independent company under Swiss data protection law and GDPR-compliant</p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <svg><use xlink:href="/images/icons.svg#lock-check-outline"></use></svg>
                <p>Complex encryption system for all transmitted data</p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <svg><use xlink:href="/images/icons.svg#image-filter-hdr"></use></svg>
                <p>All servers are located in data centers in Switzerland</p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <svg><use xlink:href="/images/icons.svg#cube-outline"></use></svg>
                <p>No storage of user data on the servers</p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <svg><use xlink:href="/images/icons.svg#guy-fawkes-mask"></use></svg>
                <p>No connection to a telephone number and no collection of user identification data</p>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div>
        <p>
            download teleguard for free:            
        </p>
        <p><a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/teleguard/id1505636751" target="_blank">
                <img alt="ios app" src="https://teleguard.com/images/app-ios-en.png">
            </a>
            <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=ch.swisscows.messenger.teleguardapp" target="_blank">
                <img alt="android app" src="https://teleguard.com/images/app-android-en.png">
            </a>
        </p>
    </div>
</section>

<section id="faq">
    <div>
        
        <h2>get information from the very first hands</h2>
        <div><p><em>01.</em>What is TeleGuard?</p>


<p><em>02.</em>Why is TeleGuard better than other messengers?</p>


<p><em>03.</em>Must I do TeleGuard updates?</p>


<p><em>04.</em>What is a TeleGuard ID?</p>


<p><em>05.</em>How do I add friends?</p>


<p><em>06.</em>Will there be a web / desktop version?</p>



<p><em>07.</em>Which operating systems are supported?</p>


<p><em>08.</em>Will there be a TeleGuard business solution?</p>


<p><em>09.</em>How do I delete my account?</p>


<p><em>10.</em>How is my privacy secured?</p>


<p><em>11.</em>How do I login / logout?</p>


</div>
    </div>
</section>

<section id="contacts">
    <div>
        

<h2>Please share your thoughts and ideas with us</h2>

<p><b>Do you have a question, comment or suggestion?</b><br>
        For more information, please fill out the contact form. Please note that there are mandatory fields.</p>


    </div>
</section>



        
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://teleguard.com/en/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25882319</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 14:10:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Irma: Open-source, attribute based credentials]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 57 | Comments 17 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25881954">thread link</a>) | @jeroenhd
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://irma.app/docs/what-is-irma/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://irma.app/docs/what-is-irma/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><article><p><span><p>IRMA is a set of free and open source software projects implementing the Idemix attribute-based credential scheme, allowing users to safely and securely authenticate themselves as privacy-preserving as the situation permits. Users receive digitally signed attributes from trusted issuer, storing them in their IRMA app, after which the user can selectively disclose attributes to others. Schematically:</p>
<p><img src="https://irma.app/docs/assets/issuance.png" alt="issuance-flow">
  <img src="https://irma.app/docs/assets/disclosure.png" alt="disclosure-flow">
</p>
<p>Using the issuer's digital signature over the attributes the verifier can verify that the attributes were given to the user in the past, and that they have not been modified since.</p>
<h2>IRMA session flow</h2>
<p>A typical IRMA session is depicted schematically below.</p>
<p><img src="https://irma.app/docs/assets/irmaflow.png" alt="IRMA session flow"></p>
<p>Software components:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Requestor backend and frontend</em>: Generally the requestor runs a website with a (JavaScript) frontend in the user's browser, and a backend server. During an IRMA session the frontend displays the IRMA QR that the <a href="https://irma.app/docs/irma-app">IRMA app</a> scans. All frontend tasks depicted in the diagram are supported by <a href="https://irma.app/docs/irma-frontend"><code>irma-frontend</code></a>.</li>
<li><a href="#irma-servers"><em>IRMA server</em></a>: Handles IRMA protocol with the IRMA app for the requestor.</li>
<li><a href="https://irma.app/docs/irma-app"><em>IRMA mobile app</em></a>: <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.irmacard.cardemu">Android</a>, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/nl/app/irma-authentication/id1294092994">iOS</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>Explanation of the steps:</p>
<ol>
<li>Usually the session starts by the user performing some action on the website (e.g. clicking on "Log in with IRMA").</li>
<li>The requestor sends its <a href="https://irma.app/docs/session-requests">session request</a> (containing the attributes to be disclosed or issued, or message to be signed) to the <a href="#irma-servers">IRMA server</a>. Depending on its configuration, the IRMA server accepts the session request only if the session request is authentic (e.g. a validly signed <a href="https://irma.app/docs/session-requests#jwts-signed-session-requests">session request JWT</a>) from an authorized requestor.</li>
<li>The IRMA server accepts the request and assigns a session token (a random string) to it. It returns the contents of the QR code that the frontend must display: the URL to itself and the session token.</li>
<li>The frontend (<a href="https://irma.app/docs/irma-frontend"><code>irma-frontend</code></a>) receives and displays the QR code, which is scanned by the IRMA app.</li>
<li>The IRMA app requests the session request from step 1, receiving the attributes to be disclosed or issued, or message to be signed.</li>
<li>The IRMA server returns the session request.</li>
<li>The IRMA app displays the attributes to be disclosed or issued, or message to be signed, and asks the user if she wants to proceed.</li>
<li>The user accepts.</li>
<li>The IRMA server performs the IRMA protocol with the IRMA app, issuing new attributes to the user, or receiving and verifying attributes from the user's IRMA app, or receiving and verifying an attribute-based signature made by the user's app.</li>
<li>The session status (<code>DONE</code>, <code>CANCELLED</code>, <code>TIMEOUT</code>), along with disclosed and verified attributes or signature depending on the session type, are returned to the requestor.</li>
</ol>
<p>Additional notes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Which of these tasks are performed by the requestor's backend and which by its frontend differs case by case:
<ul>
<li>Often the session request is sent to the IRMA server by the requestor's backend, after which the IRMA server's reply in step 2 is forwarded to the frontend which renders it as a QR code. Step 1 can however also be done by <code>irma-frontend</code>, in which case <code>irma-frontend</code> automatically picks up the IRMA server's reply in step 2 and renders the QR code.</li>
<li>Similarly, <code>irma-frontend</code> can be instructed to fetch the session result in step 10, but this can also be done in the backend. In the latter, <code>irma-frontend</code> can fetch a custom result at your backend, if desired.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>The IRMA server could be deployed on the same machine as the requestor's backend, but it need not be; possibly it is not even controlled by the requestor. Generally, steps 2/3 and 10 are done with REST HTTP calls to the IRMA server, but in case the <a href="https://irma.app/docs/irma-server-lib"><code>irmaserver</code></a> library is used, these steps are function calls. Alternatively, you could use one of the packages in <a href="https://irma.app/docs/irma-backend"><code>irma-backend-packages</code></a> to do these steps with function calls in other programming languages.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Session types</h2>
<p>In an IRMA session, the <a href="https://irma.app/docs/irma-app">IRMA mobile app</a> performs one of the following three <em>session types</em> with an <a href="#irma-servers"><em>IRMA server</em></a>:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Disclosure sessions</em>: Upon receiving a list of requested attributes from the IRMA server, the app discloses the required attributes to the IRMA server if the app user agrees, after which they are verified by the IRMA server.</li>
<li><em>Attribute-based signature sessions</em>: Similar to disclosure sessions, but the attributes are attached to a message digitally signed into an <a href="https://irma.app/docs/overview#attribute-based-signatures"><em>attribute-based signature</em></a>. The attribute-based signature can be verified at any later time, ensuring that the signed message is intact, and that the IRMA attributes attached to it were valid at the time of creation of the attribute-based signature.</li>
<li><em>Issuance sessions</em>: the IRMA app receives a new set of IRMA attributes including valid issuer signatures from the IRMA server, to use in later disclosure or attribute-based signature sessions. (Possibly the user is asked to disclose some attributes as well, within the same IRMA session, before receiving the new attributes. This is called a <em>combined issuance-disclosure session</em>.)</li>
</ul>
<p>This process is depicted schematically and explained in more detail in the <a href="https://irma.app/docs/what-is-irma#irma-session-flow">IRMA session flow</a> chapter. For the user, after scanning the QR in his/her IRMA app a disclosure session generally looks like the following. (Attribute-based signature sessions and issuance sessions are identical in terms of their flow (scan qr, provide permission, success screen); only the graphical interface is different.)</p>
<p><img src="https://irma.app/docs/assets/disclose-permission.png" alt="disclose-permission">
  <img src="https://irma.app/docs/assets/disclose-done.png" alt="disclosure-done">
</p>
<h2>IRMA servers</h2>
<p>Various existing software components documented on this website can perform the role of the IRMA server.
Apart from exposing an API that is used by the <a href="https://irma.app/docs/irma-app">IRMA app</a> during IRMA sessions, each of these components also offer an API with which IRMA sessions can be started and monitored, for use by the <a href="https://irma.app/docs/overview#participants"><em>requestor</em></a>: the party wishing to issue attributes to or verify attributes from an IRMA app. The IRMA server handles the IRMA session with the IRMA app for the requestor.</p>
<p>Currently the following IRMA servers exist:</p>
<ul>
<li>The <code>irma server</code> command of the <a href="https://irma.app/docs/irma-cli"><code>irma</code></a> binary: a standalone daemon exposing its requestor API as HTTP endpoints. <a href="https://irma.app/docs/irma-server">Documentation</a>; <a href="https://irma.app/docs/api-irma-server">API reference</a>.</li>
<li>The <code>irmaserver</code> Go library, exposing a HTTP server that handles IRMA sessions with the IRMA app, and Go functions for starting and managing IRMA sessions. <a href="https://irma.app/docs/irma-server-library">Documentation</a>; <a href="https://godoc.org/github.com/privacybydesign/irmago/server/irmaserver">API reference</a>.</li>
<li>The now deprecated <a href="https://github.com/privacybydesign/irma_api_server"><code>irma_api_server</code></a>.</li>
</ul>
<h2>About this documentation</h2>
<p>IRMA uses JSON to pass messages within IRMA sessions. The majority of IRMA is <a href="https://github.com/privacybydesign/irmago">written in Go</a>, and the JSON messages generally correspond to specific Go structs. For example, the <a href="https://irma.app/docs/api-irma-server#get-session-token-result"><code>GET /session/{token}/result</code></a> endpoint of the <a href="https://irma.app/docs/irma-server"><code>irma server</code></a> outputs instances of the <a href="https://godoc.org/github.com/privacybydesign/irmago/server#SessionResult"><code>server.SessionResult</code></a>.  In such cases, a link to the corresponding Go struct will be included. This can tell you what fields you can use or expect. (Note that some structs have custom (un)marshalers. See also the <a href="https://blog.golang.org/json-and-go">Go documentation</a> on JSON and Go.)</p>
</span></p></article></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://irma.app/docs/what-is-irma/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25881954</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 13:13:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[But how, exactly, do databases use mmap?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 204 | Comments 113 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25881911">thread link</a>) | @brunoac
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://brunocalza.me/but-how-exactly-databases-use-mmap/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://brunocalza.me/but-how-exactly-databases-use-mmap/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">
    <div>

        <article>

            


            <section>
                <div>
                    <p>In a previous post <a href="https://brunocalza.me/discovering-and-exploring-mmap-using-go/">Discovering and exploring mmap using Go</a>, we talked about how databases have a major problem to solve, which is: <strong>how to deal with data stored in disk that is bigger than the available memory</strong>. We talked about how many databases solve this problem using <strong>memory-mapped files</strong> and explored <strong>mmap</strong> capabilities.</p><p>Knowing that databases use <strong>memory-mapped files </strong>to solve the problem was not enough for me. It solved part of the mystery but a question remained: <strong>how, exactly, databases use <em>mmap</em> to read and write data from disk?</strong></p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>I decided to dig through a database source code to answer that question. There are plenty of databases that use mmap. Some of them decided to not use anymore. Some examples: <a href="https://www.sqlite.org/index.html">SQLite</a> has an option of accessing disk content directly using memory-mapped I/O<sup>[1]</sup>, it seems <a href="https://github.com/google/leveldb">LevelDB</a> used to use but it changed it<sup>[2]</sup>, <a href="https://lucene.apache.org/">Lucene</a> has an option with <em>MMapDirectory</em><sup>[3]</sup>, <a href="https://lmdb.readthedocs.io/">LMDB</a> uses mmap<sup>[4]</sup>, a simple key/value in-memory database from Counchbase called <a href="https://github.com/couchbase/moss">moss</a> uses mmap for durability of in-memory data<sup>[5]</sup> and <a href="https://www.mongodb.com/">MongoDB</a> removed <strong>mmap</strong> storage engine for <em>WiredTiger</em><sup>[6]</sup>.</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>I chose <a href="https://github.com/boltdb/bolt">bolt</a>, a simple <strong>key/value store</strong> implemented in <strong>Go</strong> by <a href="https://twitter.com/benbjohnson">Ben Johnson</a> inspired by the <strong>LMDB</strong> project, for this endeavor. Mostly because of source code simplicity and my familiarity with Go language. I know a simple key/value store might not be the most complete source code for learning all the details of reading/writing data to disk, but as I have found out, it was more than enough to get a grasp of it. </p><p>The original bolt repository is no longer maintained. A fork of <strong>bolt</strong> called <strong>bbolt</strong> is maintained and used by <a href="https://github.com/etcd-io/bbolt">etcd</a>. If you are not familiar with <strong>bolt</strong>, I recommend the articles <a href="https://npf.io/2014/07/intro-to-boltdb-painless-performant-persistence/">Intro to BoltDB: Painless Performant Persistence</a> and <a href="https://www.progville.com/go/bolt-embedded-db-golang/">Bolt — an embedded key/value database for Go </a>.</p><h2 id="the-start">The start</h2><p>I download the code to my machine and opened it in my editor. I thought a good place to start digging was to find out where the database was initialized and look for any references of <strong>mmap</strong> there. Like most embedded databases, <strong>bolt </strong>has an <a href="https://github.com/boltdb/bolt/blob/fd01fc79c553a8e99d512a07e8e0c63d4a3ccfc5/db.go#L150">Open</a> method for opening the database or creating a new one if it does not exist. Inside it, I found a reference to a private <strong>mmap</strong> function. That's a good start. </p><pre><code>// Memory map the data file.
if err := db.mmap(options.InitialMmapSize); err != nil {
    _ = db.close()
    return nil, err
}</code></pre><h2 id="how-much-memory-should-i-allocate">How much memory should I allocate?</h2><p>The private <a href="https://brunocalza.me/p/b43be99e-c260-446b-a1b1-40261aaffcf3/func%20(db%20*DB)%20mmap(minsz%20int)%20error%20%7B">mmap</a> is responsible for opening the memory-mapped file. In order to do this, it needs to figure out how much memory it is going to allocate. This task is accomplished by another method called <a href="https://github.com/boltdb/bolt/blob/fd01fc79c553a8e99d512a07e8e0c63d4a3ccfc5/db.go#L308">mmapSize</a>. Given the size of the database, this method figures out how many bytes of memory should be allocated.</p><p>It starts by doubling the size from <strong>32KB</strong> to <strong>1GB</strong>. But if the database is larger than <strong>1GB</strong>, it grows <strong>1GB</strong> at a time.</p><pre><code>// Double the size from 32KB until 1GB.
for i := uint(15); i &lt;= 30; i++ {
	if size &lt;= 1&lt;&lt;i {
		return 1 &lt;&lt; i, nil
	}
}

...

// If larger than 1GB then grow by 1GB at a time.
sz := int64(size)
if remainder := sz % int64(maxMmapStep); remainder &gt; 0 {
	sz += int64(maxMmapStep) - remainder
}</code></pre><p>It is all fine by now. That's how <strong>bolt</strong> figured out how much to allocate. But there is a piece of the puzzle now that will be very important when we talk about database storage layout. After figuring out how much to allocate, it needs to ensure that the allocated size is a multiple of the <strong>page size</strong>. If you are not familiar with database storage and don't know what a <strong>page</strong> is, don't worry, we'll be back to this.</p><pre><code>// Ensure that the mmap size is a multiple of the page size.
// This should always be true since we're incrementing in MBs.
pageSize := int64(db.pageSize)
if (sz % pageSize) != 0 {
	sz = ((sz / pageSize) + 1) * pageSize
}</code></pre><p>Shouldn't it check if we are allocating more than we have available? That's the last piece of the <a href="https://github.com/boltdb/bolt/blob/fd01fc79c553a8e99d512a07e8e0c63d4a3ccfc5/db.go#L308">mmapSize</a> method.</p><pre><code>// If we've exceeded the max size then only grow up to the max size.
if sz &gt; maxMapSize {
	sz = maxMapSize
}</code></pre><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>The <a href="https://github.com/boltdb/bolt/blob/fd01fc79c553a8e99d512a07e8e0c63d4a3ccfc5/bolt_amd64.go#L4">maxMapSize</a> constant is set to <code>0xFFFFFFFFFFFF</code> on <strong>AMD64</strong> architectures.</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><blockquote>The <strong>AMD64</strong> architecture defines a 64-bit virtual address format, of which the low-order 48 bits are used in current implementations. This allows up to 256 TiB (2<sup>48</sup> bytes) of virtual address space. - <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/X86-64">x86-64 Wiki</a></blockquote><p>This is the limit of the <strong>bolt</strong> database file.</p><h2 id="calling-the-system-call">Calling the system call</h2><p>Now that <strong>bolt</strong> knows how much it should allocate, it calls the system call <a href="https://brunocalza.me/p/b43be99e-c260-446b-a1b1-40261aaffcf3/func%20mmap(db%20*DB,%20sz%20int)%20error%20%7B">mmap</a>. Here is the full code for <em>Unix</em>-like environments:</p><pre><code>// mmap memory maps a DB's data file.
func mmap(db *DB, sz int) error {
	// Map the data file to memory.
	b, err := syscall.Mmap(int(db.file.Fd()), 0, sz, syscall.PROT_READ, syscall.MAP_SHARED|db.MmapFlags)
	if err != nil {
		return err
	}

	// Advise the kernel that the mmap is accessed randomly.
	if err := madvise(b, syscall.MADV_RANDOM); err != nil {
		return fmt.Errorf("madvise: %s", err)
	}

	// Save the original byte slice and convert to a byte array pointer.
	db.dataref = b
	db.data = (*[maxMapSize]byte)(unsafe.Pointer(&amp;b[0]))
	db.datasz = sz
	return nil
}</code></pre><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>It is a pretty straightforward code. I have some observations to make about <code>syscall.PROT_READ</code>, but I'll leave for the next session. It is nice to see the call to madvise there, although I don't know its benefits. I would love to know the importance of that call, if it improves performance or if another flag could be set to get different behavior from OS for different use cases.</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>The mapped memory is set to the variables <code>db.dataref</code> and <code>db.data</code>.</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><pre><code>db.dataref = b
db.data = (*[maxMapSize]byte)(unsafe.Pointer(&amp;b[0]))
</code></pre><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>I would like to know about the importance of keeping track of both variables. I could not grasp what is going on in the conversion to <code>db.data</code>. But anyway, what we have to keep in mind is that is through these variables that <strong>bolt</strong> will read data from disk.</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><h2 id="what-about-writes">What about writes?</h2><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>While skimming through the source code, I looked for evidence of how <strong>mmap</strong> was used for both reads and writes. I dug both <a href="https://github.com/boltdb/bolt/blob/fd01fc79c553a8e99d512a07e8e0c63d4a3ccfc5/bucket.go#L266">Get</a> and <a href="https://github.com/boltdb/bolt/blob/fd01fc79c553a8e99d512a07e8e0c63d4a3ccfc5/bucket.go#L285">Put</a> method. I could not find any place where the references to <code>db.dataref</code> or <code>db.data</code> were being updated. I discovered that the writes to disk happen when <a href="https://github.com/boltdb/bolt/blob/fd01fc79c553a8e99d512a07e8e0c63d4a3ccfc5/tx.go#L144">Commit</a> is called to a transaction. But there I could only find calls to <a href="https://golang.org/pkg/os/#File.WriteAt">WriteAt</a>. So I gave up my search of trying to understand how <strong>mmap</strong> was used for writes.</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>Then, suddenly, while looking back to the call of <strong>mmap</strong>, I noticed the  <code>syscall.PROT_READ</code> flag that I have not noticed the first time I looked at the code. So <strong>mmap</strong>, is only used for reads in <strong>bolt</strong>. Another place that indicates this is in the definition of <a href="https://github.com/boltdb/bolt/blob/fd01fc79c553a8e99d512a07e8e0c63d4a3ccfc5/db.go#L100">DB struct</a>:</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><pre><code>dataref  []byte   // mmap'ed readonly, write throws SEGV
data     *[maxMapSize]byte</code></pre><p>That made perfect sense to me. Since flushes to disk are very hard to control when using <strong>mmap</strong>, it is probably the safest approach. How <strong>bolt</strong> does writing is a topic of another post. </p><h2 id="how-the-database-file-is-structured">How the database file is structured?</h2><p>We know how and when<strong> bolt </strong>allocates memory and that <strong>mmap</strong> is not used for writes. But how, exactly, <strong>bolt</strong> can find the value of a key? To understand that, we have to understand how typically databases structure their files. I am not going to do deep here. Mostly because I don't understand enough to go deep. Just going to try to give a glimpse of what is going on. </p><p>A file is just an array of bytes. We have to apply some reasoning to this array of bytes to work with it effectively. Databases structure their files in disk into blocks (chunks of bytes) called <strong>pages</strong>. <strong>bolt </strong>is no different. The database file can be seen as</p><figure><img src="https://brunocalza.me/content/images/2021/01/image--17-.png" alt=""></figure><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>Each page has a <strong>fixed length of bytes</strong>, typically the same size as the OS page (usually <code>4096 bytes</code>). Here is the <a href="https://github.com/boltdb/bolt/blob/fd01fc79c553a8e99d512a07e8e0c63d4a3ccfc5/db.go#L40">part</a> of <strong>bolt</strong> that sets the <code>pageSize</code>.</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><pre><code>// default page size for db is set to the OS page size.
var defaultPageSize = os.Getpagesize()
</code></pre><p>Every database has its own page layout. The page layout of <strong>bolt</strong> is defined at <a href="https://github.com/boltdb/bolt/blob/fd01fc79c553a8e99d512a07e8e0c63d4a3ccfc5/page.go#L28">page.go</a> as</p><pre><code>const (
	branchPageFlag   = 0x01
	leafPageFlag     = 0x02
	metaPageFlag     = 0x04
	freelistPageFlag = 0x10
)

const (
	bucketLeafFlag = 0x01
)

type pgid uint64

type page struct {
	id       pgid
	flags    uint16
	count    uint16
	overflow uint32
	ptr      uintptr
}
</code></pre><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><ul>
<li><code>id</code>: it is the page identifier used to index the page. Given a page id, I can locate it in the disk through <strong>mmap</strong>, since the disk file is just a list of continuous fixed length pages;</li>
<li><code>flags</code>: it tells the page type. There are four types of page: <code>meta</code>, <code>freeList</code>, <code>leaf</code> and <code>branch</code>;</li>
<li><code>count</code>: indicates the number of elements stored in the page;</li>
<li><code>overflow</code>: represents the number of subsequent pages;</li>
<li><code>ptr</code>: indicates the end of page header and start of page data. This is where the keys and values are going to be stored.</li>
</ul>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>A visual representation of a page:</p><figure><img src="https://brunocalza.me/content/images/2021/01/image--16-.png" alt=""><figcaption>Layout of a page</figcaption></figure><p>With this in mind, we can look at the code that retrieves a <a href="https://github.com/boltdb/bolt/blob/fd01fc79c553a8e99d512a07e8e0c63d4a3ccfc5/db.go#L792">page</a> given its id.</p><pre><code>// page retrieves a page reference from the mmap based on the current page size.
func (db *DB) page(id pgid) *page {
	pos := id * pgid(db.pageSize)
	return (*page)(unsafe.Pointer(&amp;db.data[pos]))
}</code></pre><h2 id="how-to-perform-an-efficient-search">How to perform an efficient search?</h2><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>We know how the database file is structured in disk and we know how to retrieve a page from disk. But how a <code>bucket.Get([]byte("key"))</code> search works? We are not going to go into too much detail here. I hope the abstraction I created will be enough to get a clue about what is going on.</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p><strong>What if the pages themselves, in the data part, contained references to other pages? And what if these references build up to form a B+Tree?</strong></p><p>That is exactly what <strong>bolt</strong> does. Thinking of the page as a node of a <strong>B+Tree</strong>. In a <strong>B+Tree</strong> we have internal nodes and leaves. That's the reason for the `flags` attribute, to indicate what kind of node that page is.</p><figure><img src="https://brunocalza.me/content/images/2021/01/image--18-.png" alt=""><figcaption>Abstract representation of a B+Tree in <strong>bolt</strong></figcaption></figure><p>So to perform the search of a key, you start at the root node a do a B+Tree traversal on mmapped disk pages. Therefore, <strong>bolt</strong> is a memory-mapped B+Tree file. The more memory you have, the more it will behave like a memory key/value store.</p><p>There are many more details about this process. Most of it I don't understand myself. So let's just keep it simple at this abstract level. </p><h2 id="resizing-mmap">Resizing mmap</h2><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>When I started looking …</p></div></section></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://brunocalza.me/but-how-exactly-databases-use-mmap/">https://brunocalza.me/but-how-exactly-databases-use-mmap/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://brunocalza.me/but-how-exactly-databases-use-mmap/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25881911</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 13:06:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Italy Blocks Users on TikTok After 10-Year-Old Girl Died in a Blackout Challenge]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 94 | Comments 74 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25881460">thread link</a>) | @sodrick
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://relayvibes.co/italy-blocks-users-on-tiktok-after-a-10-year-old-girl-died-in-a-blackout-challenge/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://relayvibes.co/italy-blocks-users-on-tiktok-after-a-10-year-old-girl-died-in-a-blackout-challenge/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-1450">
	
		<div>
<figure>
<img src="https://relayvibes.co/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/tiktok-678x381.jpg" alt="Italy Blocks Users On Tiktok" title="tiktok">
</figure>

<div><p><a href="https://relayvibes.co/tag/Italianauthority">Italian authority</a> has blocked certain users from accessing TikTok. Users, who can’t definitely verify their age after the tragic death of a young girl who is taking part in a “blackout challenge”, from accessing Tiktok.</p>
<p>This girl’s death was firstly reported by ANSA on Thursday when it happened.</p>
<p>From the report:</p>
<p>A Italian girl,10, was pronounced brain dead by a Palermo hospital on Thursday after she took the Blackout Challenge on TikTok.</p>
<p>Her parents have accepted to donate the organs of the girl, who tied a belt round her neck to self-asphyxiate in the challenge on Tiktok.</p>
<p>Read also: <strong><a href="https://relayvibes.co/tiktok-star-tony-lopez-sued-for-sexual-battery/">TikTok Star, Tony Lopez Sued For Sexual Battery</a></strong></p>
<p>According to <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jan/23/italy-blocks-tiktok-for-certain-users-after-death-of-girl-allegedly-playing-choking-game#:~:text=Italian%20prosecutors%20have%20opened%20an,could%20not%20be%20proved%20definitively." target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Guardian</a>, an investigation has been opened by Italian prosecutors , and Italy has temporarily blocked users from gaining access to the popular social platform “whose age couldn’t be verified.”</p>
<p>TikTok had reported that it has not discovered any content on its site that may have persuaded the girl to participate in the challenge, but was assisting the authorities in probing the incident.</p>
<p>A Tiktok spokesperson said: “The safety of the TikTok community is our absolute priority, for this reason we do not allow any content which encourages, promotes or glorifies behavior that could be dangerous”</p>
<p>The report shows that the Italian Data Protection Authority had blocked TikTok till February 15th immediately till regulator’s demands are met. This challenge being referred to was also reportedly called “scarfing” or “the choking game”, involving participants blocking oxygen to their brain in order to get high. The girl’s parents told La Repubblica that they are not aware of the game and only aware of their daughter going on TikTok for dances, and to watch videos.</p>

</div>

	</div><div id="text-13">			<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://relayvibes.co/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/ad-300x250-mh-magazine-3.png" alt="" width="300" height="250"></p>
		</div></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://relayvibes.co/italy-blocks-users-on-tiktok-after-a-10-year-old-girl-died-in-a-blackout-challenge/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25881460</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 11:15:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Raspberry Pi as x2go “thin” client]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 108 | Comments 58 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25881126">thread link</a>) | @indigodaddy
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | http://www.multi-seat.com/x2go/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.multi-seat.com/x2go/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<div id="content">

<div>
	<div id="primary">
		<main id="main" role="main">

			
<article id="post-45" class="page">
	<!-- .entry-header -->
	<div>
		
<p><a href="https://wiki.x2go.org/doku.php/download:start">https://wiki.x2go.org/doku.php/download:start</a></p>



<p>X2GO is one of the easiest open source remote access applications to  install on Linux, including on the Raspberry Pi 3B/4B. If the host is  LinuxMint and the client is a Raspberry PI, you can have both the  LinuxMint panel on the bottom of the client screen as well as the  Rasbian panel on the top of the screen – that way you can run both  local and remote apps at the same time in a split screen,  or even full screen  on separate client  monitors, or x2go client window spanning both monitors.</p>



<p>The x2goserver can handle multiple  simultaneous client computers with distinct usernames and their home  directories – rather like thin clients without PXE booting. X2GO is not   integrated into the loginctl multi-seat system but functions beside  that capability. Thus the multi-seat behavior of the client is handled by the x2goserver but initiated by the x2go client,&nbsp; not the&nbsp; host side that loginctl controls. The Raspberry Pi 4B is fast enough to be used as a full desktop and supports two HDMI monitors. It only needs to become an x2go client of an x2go server when it needs more computing power or to save files. Its window on the server can span both monitors, or stay on one of the monitors so that the user can run apps both locally and remotely on the server at the same time, moving the mouse to control which desktop the keyboard is connected to.</p>



<p>While there is a x2goclient for Windows computers, there is no  x2goserver for Windows computers.  Supporting multiple independent client sessions would violate a  Windows single workstation license. The Windows malware problem can be  solved by running Windows as a guest OS under VirtualBox on a Linux  host server. Then there is no need for the Windows OS to be connected to the  internet because you can use the browser on the Raspbian local client desktop  when needed.</p>



<p>If multiple  network cards on the x2goserver, the default is to  listen on all for clients. With lots of simultaneous clients, you might want to configure the server to separate server internet traffic from  client traffic.</p>



<p><strong>Installation of server on Linux Mint 19:</strong></p>



<pre>asm32@M5A88-M:~$ sudo apt-get install x2goserver x2goserver-xsession
[sudo] password for (username):

... skipping output during installation process ...
 
asm32@M5A88-M:~$</pre>



<pre>asm32@M5A88-M:~$ sudo service x2goserver start
[sudo] password for (username): 
asm32@M5A88-M:~$
</pre>



<p>or, alternatively,</p>



<pre>asm32@M5A88-M:~$
asm32@M5A88-M:~$sudo systemctl start x2goserver
asm32@M5A88-M:~$</pre>



<p>To make it start automatically on boot:</p>



<pre>asm32@M5A88-M:~$ sudo update-rc.d x2goserver defaults
[sudo] password for asm32: 
asm32@M5A88-M:~$</pre>



<p><strong>Installation of client on Raspberry Pi3 B+&nbsp; running <strong>Raspberry Pi OS</strong></strong> <strong>with Desktop:</strong></p>



<p>x2goclient is already in the Raspberry Pi Raspberry Pi OS&nbsp; repository, so all that is needed is</p>



<pre>pi@raspberrypi:~ $ sudo apt-get install x2goclient</pre>



<p>Once installed, there will be a new menu item under Internet category.</p>



<p>When configuring x2goclient sessions, you can use server hostnames instead of IP addresses. There can be more than one server on a LAN but hostnames must be unique.</p>



<p><strong>X2goclient as Raspberry Pi software zeroclient!</strong></p>



<div><p>A new raspberry pi is approximately 1/3 the cost of a new network attached zero client. Raspberry Pi could be configured to initiate an x2goclient session immediately, much like a hardware zero client, with the difference  that the x2go client provides the login screen instead of the server. </p><p>You will want to install the perl script, wakeonlan, so that you can wake up the desktop server from any of the Pi zero clients. I have edited my version so that the desired server MAC address is in the script instead of needed on the command line or in a separate file.</p></div>



<p>While x2goclient is trivial to install on a Raspberry Pi with a desktop environment, for a single purpose network attached zero client, it is not required to have a windows manager and desktop environment so you could use the <strong>Raspberry Pi OS (32-bit) Lite</strong> image at 432 MB (compared to the desktop version at 1128 MB).</p>



<p>Download here: <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/downloads/raspberry-pi-os/"><strong>https://www.raspberrypi.org/downloads/raspberry-pi-os/</strong></a></p>



<p>Once you have downloaded and flashed a MicroSD card with this and done the initial configuration at first boot on the Raspberry Pi, add the following:</p>



<pre><code>sudo apt-get install --no-install-recommends xserver-xorg</code></pre>



<pre><code>sudo apt-get install --no-install-recommends xinit</code></pre>



<div><p>To start up the xserver automatically, edit the file .bashrc to append the line “/usr/bin/startx” without the quotes.</p><p>Next edit the file .xinitrc to delete or make a comment the line “. /etc/X11/Xsession” and append a new line ” /usr/bin/x2goclient –thinclient –session=session-name” without the quotes. The second option launches a named session that you have setup already. Leave this option off if you have more than one server and the user needs to choose a session. If you have more than one user, you should not fill in the user name for the session. If you have only one server and one user (you are using this to remotely administer the server, perhaps) then you can set up automatic login so that the Raspberry Pi boots directly to a desktop of the remote server computer.</p></div>



<p><strong>Auto login with ssh rsa</strong></p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="570" src="http://www.multi-seat.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/x2go-autologin-1024x570.jpg" alt="" srcset="http://www.multi-seat.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/x2go-autologin-1024x570.jpg 1024w, http://www.multi-seat.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/x2go-autologin-300x167.jpg 300w, http://www.multi-seat.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/x2go-autologin-768x427.jpg 768w, http://www.multi-seat.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/x2go-autologin-1536x854.jpg 1536w, http://www.multi-seat.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/x2go-autologin.jpg 1812w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px"></figure>



<div><p>Assuming you already have a x2go session working with login, several things in the x2go session are needed for auto login to work. You most have a username (server end) or it will not know where to look for the authorized public key on the server end. It is preferable to check the box for “Try auto login” and leave the path entry  just above empty so that it will use the default location.  There can be multiple authorized public keys on the server – it will look for the one matching the client private key. There can also be multiple client sessions, each with a different private key. It is the client end (at possibly multiple separate workstations) that initiates the conversation with the server.</p><p><strong>Setting up private and public keys</strong></p></div>



<pre>pi@raspberrypi:~ $ ssh-keygen
Generating public/private rsa key pair.
Enter file in which to save the key (/home/pi/.ssh/id_rsa):
Enter passphrase (empty for no passphrase):
Enter same passphrase again:
Your identification has been saved in /home/pi/.ssh/id_rsa.
Your public key has been saved in /home/pi/.ssh/id_rsa.pub.
The key fingerprint is:
[edited out for my privacy]
The key's randomart image is:
+---[RSA 2048]----+
[edited out for my privacy]
+----[SHA256]-----+
pi@raspberrypi:~ $

pi@raspberrypi:~ $ ls .ssh/ -l
total 8
-rw------- 1 pi pi 1823 Jul 12 17:49 id_rsa
-rw-r--r-- 1 pi pi 396 Jul 12 17:49 id_rsa.pub
pi@raspberrypi:~ $</pre>



<p>Having generated these keys at the client end, they need to be installed at both ends. In my case asm32@asus-centos7 is my username on my server hostname.</p>



<pre>pi@raspberrypi:~ $ ssh-copy-id asm32@asus-centos7
/usr/bin/ssh-copy-id: INFO: Source of key(s) to be installed: "/home/pi/.ssh/id_rsa.pub"
The authenticity of host 'asus-centos7 (192.168.10.105)' can't be established.
ECDSA key fingerprint is SHA256: [edited out for my privacy]
Are you sure you want to continue connecting (yes/no)? yes
/usr/bin/ssh-copy-id: INFO: attempting to log in with the new key(s), to filter out any that are already installed
/usr/bin/ssh-copy-id: INFO: 1 key(s) remain to be installed -- if you are prompted now it is to install the new keys
asm32@asus-centos7's password:
Number of key(s) added: 1
Now try logging into the machine, with: "ssh 'asm32@asus-centos7'"
and check to make sure that only the key(s) you wanted were added.
pi@raspberrypi:~ $ ssh 'asm32@asus-centos7'
Last login: Sun Jul 12 17:52:03 2020
[asm32@asus-centos7 ~]$ ls -l .ssh/
total 4
-rw-------. 1 asm32 asm32 396 Jul 12 17:56 authorized_keys
[asm32@asus-centos7 ~]$
[asm32@asus-centos7 ~]$ exit
logout
Connection to asus-centos7 closed.
pi@raspberrypi:~ $ ls -l .ssh/
total 12
-rw------- 1 pi pi 1823 Jul 12 17:49 id_rsa
-rw-r--r-- 1 pi pi 396 Jul 12 17:49 id_rsa.pub
-rw-r--r-- 1 pi pi 444 Jul 12 17:55 known_hosts
pi@raspberrypi:~ $</pre>



<p>Note that after the client end command,  ssh-copy-id,  the public key has been added to the server end .ssh/authorized_keys and the client end now has a .ssh/known_hosts.</p>



<p>The right panel of x2goclient has all the sessions you have configured. When you select one of these, it will move to the blue left panel. With auto login, it will immediately start to connect to the server.  If you leave it in the left panel when you exit the session, then the next invocation of x2goclient will immediately attempt to connect to the server. In the case of a <strong>Raspberry Pi OS (32-bit) Lite</strong> installation as described above, the Pi will boot directly into connecting to its configured session on the server – similar to the Phistek ZE7000 network attached zero client at less than 1/3 the hardware cost.</p>



<p>The Phistek ZE7000 has superior video performance. Its silicon USB over IP chip is transmitting compressed USB over IP protocol, whereas the x2go method is transmitting compressed X protocol graphic primitives which is more efficient for non video applications.</p>




	</div><!-- .entry-content -->
</article><!-- #post-45 -->

		</main><!-- #main -->
	</div><!-- #primary -->
</div><!-- .wrap -->


		</div><!-- #content -->

		<!-- #colophon -->
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.multi-seat.com/x2go/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25881126</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 10:03:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Facebook Disabled My Account After I Criticized Them]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 355 | Comments 229 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25881112">thread link</a>) | @thereare5lights
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://lincoln.metacannon.net/2021/01/facebook-disabled-my-account-after-i-criticized-them.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://lincoln.metacannon.net/2021/01/facebook-disabled-my-account-after-i-criticized-them.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="Audio"><i></i> Checking for recording ...</p><div id="Content"><p><img src="https://lincoln.metacannon.net/images/posts/censored-by-facebook.jpg" alt="Facebook Disabled My Account After I Criticized Them" title="Facebook Disabled My Account After I Criticized Them"></p> <p>Facebook unfriended me. Why? So far as I can tell, it’s because I’ve been using Facebook to advocate for decentralization of social media. And apparently the algorithm didn’t like that.</p> <p>This morning, sometime between 8:54am and 9:06am Mountain, Facebook disabled my account. Just after 8:54am, I copy-pasted the content of my latest Twitter post into a new post on Facebook. At 9:06am, a friend received a Facebook notification indicating that he needed to update his trusted contacts because I was no longer available. Here’s the exact text and link that I posted to both Twitter and Facebook:</p> <blockquote> <p>“Now is the time to build, promote, and adopt decentralized social networks. The future of humanity depends on it. Ben Goertzel gets it right. Read his explanation. <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/decentralized-social-networks-next-big-blockchain-opportunity">https://www.coindesk.com/decentralized-social-networks-next-big-blockchain-opportunity</a>” (<a href="https://twitter.com/LincolnCannon/status/1352645833569669121">22 January 2021</a>)</p> </blockquote> <blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Now is the time to build, promote, and adopt decentralized social networks. The future of humanity depends on it. Ben Goertzel gets it right. Read his explanation. <a href="https://t.co/3DMsYiQdLa">https://t.co/3DMsYiQdLa</a></p>— Lincoln Cannon (@LincolnCannon) <a href="https://twitter.com/LincolnCannon/status/1352645833569669121?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 22, 2021</a></blockquote>  <p>When my friend’s notification came to my attention, I attempted to access Facebook. I was able to login. But I wasn’t able to see anything except the following message:</p> <blockquote> <p>“Your Account Has Been Disabled. For more information please visit the Help Center. Your account was disabled on Jan 22, 2021. If you think your account was disabled by mistake you can submit more information via the Help Center for up to 30 days after your account was disabled. After that, your account will be permanently disabled and you will no longer be able to request a review.”</p> </blockquote> <figure><span><img src="https://lincoln.metacannon.net/images/posts/facebook-screen-shot-2021-01-22-at-11.04.16-am.jpg" alt="Facebook Screen Shot on 22 January 2021 at 11:04am Mountain"></span><figcaption>Facebook Screen Shot on 22 January 2021 at 11:04am Mountain</figcaption></figure> <p>I clicked on a link at the end of the message. It took me to the Help Center. There I found a link to request a review. Clicking on that link took me to a form which requested my full name and photo ID.</p> <p>I filled out the form, providing my name and a JPG of my government issued ID. Then I submitted the form. In response, I received the following message:</p> <blockquote> <p>“We Cannot Review the Decision to Disable Your Account. Your Facebook account was disabled because it did not follow our Community Standards. This decision can’t be reversed.”</p> </blockquote> <figure><span><img src="https://lincoln.metacannon.net/images/posts/facebook-screen-shot-2021-01-22-at-9.26.23-am.jpg" alt="Facebook Screen Shot on 22 January 2021 at 9:26am Mountain"></span><figcaption>Facebook Screen Shot on 22 January 2021 at 9:26am Mountain</figcaption></figure> <h2 id="why-facebook-disabled-my-account">Why Facebook Disabled My Account</h2> <p>I don’t know for sure why Facebook disabled my account. I didn’t receive an explanation. There was no reference to particular Facebook Community Standards that I might have broken. There was no indication of how I might have been violating Facebook’s terms of service.</p> <p>Moreover, I have never received a warning from Facebook. And I didn’t receive a warning today. They provided no information beyond what I’ve quoted above.</p> <p>I’ve never used Facebook or any other social media to advocate violence, political or otherwise. And I’m a political centrist. In fact, during the political controversies of 2020, I repeatedly insisted on civility to such an extent that it frustrated some of my more partisan friends. So we can’t plausibly look for an explanation there.</p> <p>We could imagine a conspiracy among people who dislike my religious views. There’s plenty of <a href="https://lincoln.metacannon.net/2018/09/this-post-is-brought-to-you-by.html">strong anti-Mormon and anti-Transhumanist sentiment</a> out there. Perhaps, banding together, a group of people reported or otherwise flagged my content on Facebook as inappropriate. But this seems a bit paranoid to me.</p> <p>I don’t think the cause was the link that I shared, in itself. Quite a few other people have shared that link on Facebook. In fact, at this moment, their API indicates that <a href="https://developers.facebook.com/tools/debug/?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.coindesk.com%2Fdecentralized-social-networks-next-big-blockchain-opportunity">the link has received at least 88 likes, shares, and comments across Facebook</a>. And that number has been increasing throughout the day without Facebook banning others for it, to the best of my knowledge.</p> <p>So I think the cause must have been the comment itself. Or, more generally, it may have been an emerging pattern in the comments of my posts. For a long time, I have advocated replacing Facebook with <a href="https://lincoln.metacannon.net/2015/05/the-reputation-web.html">decentralized social networks</a>. And current events have motivated me to increase the frequency of that advocacy.</p> <p>Several times over the last week or two, I have promoted decentralization in posts to both Facebook and Twitter. The content and links of the original posts were identical on the two platforms. So you can see them on my Twitter account. For easy reference, here are copies of my most recent cross-posts in reverse chronological order (as ordered on Twitter and previously on Facebook):</p> <ul> <li> <p>“Congratulations to President Biden and Vice-President Harris. May your term in office be peaceful and prosperous, for the United States of America and for our world.” (<a href="https://twitter.com/LincolnCannon/status/1351953891655520258">20 January 2021</a>)</p> </li> <li> <p>“The debate between capitalism and socialism is often framed as a choice between large corporations and large government. This framing is cultivated by political and economic elites. The truth is that there’s an alternative to both. Limit both. Decentralize ALL power.” (<a href="https://twitter.com/LincolnCannon/status/1351914808753307649">20 January 2021</a>)</p> </li> <li> <p>“In a recent discussion with the Christian Transhumanist Association, I presented and answered questions about the New God Argument. Here’s a recording. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kCUrUnZavGk&amp;list=PL9Yc4oMKukRkMnBAkXNv9JWApl9D4Qe8j">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kCUrUnZavGk&amp;list=PL9Yc4oMKukRkMnBAkXNv9JWApl9D4Qe8j</a>” (<a href="https://twitter.com/LincolnCannon/status/1351384453231230976">18 January 2021</a>)</p> </li> <li> <p>“Decentralization is a practical necessity. For Christians, it’s also a theological mandate. Essential to the Gospel is a transformative discipleship, wherein we each participate in the role of Christ and become joint heirs in the glory of God. Divine creation IS decentralization.” (<a href="https://twitter.com/LincolnCannon/status/1350943723908198406">17 January 2021</a>)</p> </li> <li> <p>“If God ensures the right spirit is associated with the right body during human-mediated procreation, why wouldn’t God ensure the same for human-mediated resurrection? If you build it, they will come. If they don’t come, you didn’t build it right. Seems straightforward to me.” (<a href="https://twitter.com/LincolnCannon/status/1350259207107317760">15 January 2021</a>)</p> </li> <li> <p>“‘The long view is a thriving decentralized marketplace, fueled by personal empowerment and collaboration.’ <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/10/technology/tim-berners-lee-privacy-internet.html">https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/10/technology/tim-berners-lee-privacy-internet.html</a>” (<a href="https://twitter.com/LincolnCannon/status/1348662980175564802">11 January 2021</a>)</p> </li> <li> <p>“Let’s say you have enough spare cash to buy a gun, donate to a charity, or invest in some Bitcoin. What do you do and why? What does your choice say about your vision of the future? How does your choice impinge on the creation of that future?” (<a href="https://twitter.com/LincolnCannon/status/1348082874239524865">9 January 2021</a>)</p> </li> <li> <p>“Trump was banned from Facebook and Twitter. That may or may not be comparatively fair. But if it constitutes an infringement on freedom of speech then we’ve given far too much power to Facebook and Twitter. Centrally controlled freedom of speech should terrify us.” (<a href="https://twitter.com/LincolnCannon/status/1347931805370863617">9 January 2021</a>)</p> </li> </ul> <p>In addition, on 13 January 2021, I shared to Facebook some thoughts in support of a tweet from Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey. I can no longer quote the text from my Facebook post because it wasn’t a cross-post like the others. But it essentially affirmed Jack Dorsey’s interest in supporting decentralized social media, as he expressed in a recent tweet:</p> <blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">We are trying to do our part by funding an initiative around an open decentralized standard for social media. Our goal is to be a client of that standard for the public conversation layer of the internet. We call it <a href="https://twitter.com/bluesky?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@bluesky</a>: <a href="https://t.co/51or6OuNNv">https://t.co/51or6OuNNv</a></p>— jack (@jack) <a href="https://twitter.com/jack/status/1349510780043988992?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 14, 2021</a></blockquote> <p>As you can see, almost all of my recent social media posts have been related to decentralization. Even the ones that aren’t obviously related to decentralization are still implicitly or indirectly related to decentralization. For example, decentralization is an important aspect of the <a href="https://new-god-argument.com/compassion-argument.html">Compassion Argument of the New God Argument</a>. And a theology that would include <a href="https://lincoln.metacannon.net/2019/04/how-to-raise-dead.html">human action toward resurrection</a> as an expression of God’s work is a decentralized theology.</p> <p>A machine learning algorithm would be capable of identifying accounts that publish posts with a pattern of negative sentiment toward centralized social media. The algorithm could also assign a score to the degree of negative sentiment. And Facebook could use that score to trigger automatic deactivation of accounts that surpass a relatively high score. None of this would require direct human intervention.</p> <p>Again, I don’t know for sure why Facebook deactivated my account. But based on what I know, I think the best explanation is that Facebook now implicitly hates decentralization. I suspect that one of its algorithms is checking for accounts that encourage use of alternative social networks. And it caught my account in its automated net.</p> <p>As an aside, perhaps some Facebook managers and engineers originally intended the algorithm to catch accounts that encourage use of social networks that focus on controversial politics. That seems possible. I’ve neither advocated for nor participated in those social networks. But I can see how my posts might have some syntactical commonalities with posts that advocate for those social networks.</p> <h2 id="why-facebook-doesnt-ban-everyone">Why Facebook Doesn’t Ban Everyone</h2> <p>Aren’t other people advocating for decentralized social networks without being banned? Maybe so. But the algorithm may have identified my account as a particularly useful target. Here’s why.</p> <p>Social network theory categorizes people according to how they function in networks. Some people are influencers within groups of similar persons. Some people are followers within groups. And some people are connectors between groups.</p> <p>Connectors facilitate transmission of ideas between dissimilar groups. Transmission of ideas can be good, promoting adaptability over time and creation of new value. But transmission of ideas can also be bad insofar as they undermine the coherence and survival of the group or system. All groups and systems, even the most creative, require a balance.</p> <p>As it turns out, my social connections are unusually diverse. For example, I have many politically progressive and many politically conservative connections. I have many religious, secular, and atheist connections. And these connections include many influencers in a wide variety of geographies around the world.</p> <p>I’m a connector. I …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://lincoln.metacannon.net/2021/01/facebook-disabled-my-account-after-i-criticized-them.html">https://lincoln.metacannon.net/2021/01/facebook-disabled-my-account-after-i-criticized-them.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://lincoln.metacannon.net/2021/01/facebook-disabled-my-account-after-i-criticized-them.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25881112</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 10:00:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Bitcoin Core Lead Maintainer Steps Back, Encourages Decentralization]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 106 | Comments 206 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25880727">thread link</a>) | @runeks
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://laanwj.github.io/2021/01/21/decentralize.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://laanwj.github.io/2021/01/21/decentralize.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p>Recent events have made me reflect on a few things in my life I was already thinking about for a while. Also, responses on social media have made me realize that people have <em>strange</em> expectations from me, and what my role in the Bitcoin Core project is.</p>

<h2 id="growth">growth</h2>

<p>Bitcoin has grown a lot since I started contributing to it in 2011. Some arrangements that were acceptable for a small scale FOSS project are no longer so for one runing a 600 billion dollar system. Market cap is famously deceptive, but my point is not about specific numbers here.</p>

<p>One thing is clear: this is a serious project now, and we need to start taking decentralization seriously.</p>

<h2 id="moving-on">moving on</h2>

<p>I realize I am myself somewhat of a centralized bottleneck. And although I find Bitcoin an extremely interesting project and believe it’s one of the most important things happening at the moment, I also have many other interests. It’s also particularly stressful and I don’t want it, nor the bizarre spats in the social media around it, to start defining me as a person.</p>

<h2 id="spreading-out">spreading out</h2>

<p>I will start by delegating my own tasks, and decreasing my involvement. I do not intend to stop contributing to Bitcoin, or even to the Bitcoin Core project, but I would like to remove myself from the critical path and take (even more) of a background role.</p>

<p>Note that we had a nice growth in development activity, and that maintenance of the code itself has already been spread over multiple people for a while. I’m not the most active maintainer. Looking at the number of git merges</p>

<div><div><pre><code>bitcoin<span>$ </span>git log <span>--pretty</span><span>=</span><span>"format:%cn"</span> <span>--merges</span> <span>--since</span><span>=</span>2020-01-01 | <span>sort</span>| <span>uniq</span> <span>-c</span>
    313 fanquake
     51 Jonas Schnelli
    727 MarcoFalke
      7 Pieter Wuille
     65 Samuel Dobson
    363 Wladimir J. van der Laan
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Only about 24% of the merges were done by me, last year.</p>

<h2 id="plans">plans</h2>

<p>But there’s plenty of things left to figure out, from the top of my head:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Decentralize distribution.</p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>In the short run, transfer bitcoincore.org to an organization instead of private ownership. Reduce the “bus factor”.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>I think it would be good if some other organizations set up mirrors, so there is less incentive to try to take bitcoincore.org down.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>In the long run, move away from a website for code distribution completely. No matter who owns it, a website on the clearnet can be shut down with the press of a button, and it seems that the global internet is gearing up to make censorship increasingly easy. We need a decentralized web. For us, one option would be IPFS, which is starting to catch on. For the binaries themselves there’s already the option of downloading through torrents.</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Decentralize the release process, and release signing.</p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>Delegate more parts of the release process. Other maintainers should be able to do a release without my involvement.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Rename the GPG key used to sign <code>SHA256SUMS.asc</code> to “Bitcoin Core release signing key”, instead of having it in my personal title. Make some construct so that N of M (minimally) trusted gitian signers doing a succesful build automatically results in a signed distribution.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Same for the native code signing for Windows and MacOS.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Even better in the long run would be to split up the keys, e.g. though RSA threshold signing, so that the whole process is geographically distributed.</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Decentralize the development hub.</p>

    <ul>
      <li>It’s not clear whether github can be trusted to act in our interest in the long run. Although issues and PRs are backed up through the API, having to move somewhere else could give significant interruption in development. And hopping from provider to provider would be awful—ideally the whole thing would not rely on a central server <em>at all</em>. For this I’ve been watching the <a href="https://radicle.xyz/">radicle</a> project, a P2P distributed code collaboration platform. It’s not quite there yet, but seems promising.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Bitcoin is quite different in some of the requirements here from other FOSS projects, so we’ll have to develop some tools as we go. We could also, definitely, use some help here.</p>

<p>Some smaller things to consider:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Find someone else who wants to do the IRC meeting chair instead of me. Or maybe rotate it between multiple people.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Release (and release candidate) mails to the <code>bitcoin-dev</code> and <code>bitcoin-core-dev</code> lists will no longer be necessarily signed and sent by me.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>There’s some development specific tooling hosted by me (e.g. the PR notification bots on IRC and mastodon). As they are non-critical and only little time goes into maintaining them, I’m fine with this for now.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>As for decentralizing Bitcoin’s node software itself:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Carl Dong’s <code>libbitcoin_kernel</code> work. Bitcoin Core is a large monolithic project which includes the consensus code, which is much more critical than the other parts. The kernel would be an isolated part with well-defined interface, and at some point, its own review flow for changes. The difference with previous <code>libbitcoin_consensus</code> plans is that the kernel is stateful: it includes UTXO management and validation. It however does not include P2P, mempool policy, wallet, GUI, and RPC code. It could be re-used in different clients, to have more diversity in clients, but without the risks of a deviating consensus implementation.</li>
</ul>

<p>Over the course of 2021 this will be my focus with regard to Bitcoin Core.</p>

  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://laanwj.github.io/2021/01/21/decentralize.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25880727</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 08:45:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Rysolv – Fix open source issues, get paid]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 247 | Comments 101 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25879238">thread link</a>) | @themanmaran
<br/>
January 22, 2021 | https://rysolv.com/issues | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rysolv.com/issues">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rysolv.com/issues</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25879238</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 03:14:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
