<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 5]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 5. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 08:20:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-5.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 08:20:27 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Bootstrap finance and the cost of other people's money [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 13 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24090104">thread link</a>) | @sturza
<br/>
August 8, 2020 | http://library.cust.edu.pk/teacher_resources/Cases&Articles/Entrepreneurship/BootstrapFinance-TheArtofStart-Ups.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://library.cust.edu.pk/teacher_resources/Cases&Articles/Entrepreneurship/BootstrapFinance-TheArtofStart-Ups.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://library.cust.edu.pk/teacher_resources/Cases&amp;Articles/Entrepreneurship/BootstrapFinance-TheArtofStart-Ups.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24090104</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 08:43:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Intel, ARM, IBM, AMD Processors Vulnerable to New Side-Channel Attacks]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 117 | Comments 22 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24089281">thread link</a>) | @beefhash
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://modernnetsec.io/intel-arm-ibm-amd-processors-vulnerable-to-new-side-channel-attacks/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://modernnetsec.io/intel-arm-ibm-amd-processors-vulnerable-to-new-side-channel-attacks/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<div><a href="https://modernnetsec.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/intel-arm-ibm-amd-processors-vulnerable-to-new-side-channel-attacks-1.jpg"><amp-img alt="Side-Channel Attacks" data-original-height="380" data-original-width="728" src="https://modernnetsec.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/intel-arm-ibm-amd-processors-vulnerable-to-new-side-channel-attacks-1.jpg" title="Side-Channel Attacks" width="728" height="380" layout="intrinsic" i-amphtml-layout="intrinsic"><img alt="Side-Channel Attacks" src="https://modernnetsec.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/intel-arm-ibm-amd-processors-vulnerable-to-new-side-channel-attacks-1.jpg" title="Side-Channel Attacks" width="728" height="380" data-old-src="data:image/svg+xml;base64,PHN2ZyBoZWlnaHQ9JzM4MCcgd2lkdGg9JzcyOCcgeG1sbnM9J2h0dHA6Ly93d3cudzMub3JnLzIwMDAvc3ZnJyB2ZXJzaW9uPScxLjEnLz4="></amp-img></a></div>
<p>It turns out that the root cause behind several previously disclosed speculative execution attacks against modern processors, such as <a href="https://thehackernews.com/2018/01/meltdown-spectre-vulnerability.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Meltdown</a> and <a href="https://thehackernews.com/2018/08/foreshadow-intel-processor-vulnerability.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Foreshadow</a>, was misattributed to ‘prefetching effect,’ resulting in hardware vendors releasing incomplete mitigations and countermeasures.</p>
<p>Sharing its findings with The Hacker News, a group of academics from the Graz University of Technology and CISPA Helmholtz Center for Information Security finally revealed the exact reason behind why the kernel addresses are cached in the first place, as well as presented several new attacks that exploit the previously unidentified underlying issue, allowing attackers to sniff out sensitive data.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2008.02307.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">new research explains</a> microarchitectural attacks were actually caused by speculative dereferencing of user-space registers in the kernel, which not just impacts the most recent Intel CPUs with the latest hardware mitigations, but also several modern processors from ARM, IBM, and AMD — previously believed to be unaffected.</p>
<div>
<a href="https://go.thn.li/contrast" rel="nofollow noopener sponsored noreferrer" target="_blank" title="cybersecurity"><amp-img alt="cybersecurity" src="https://modernnetsec.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/intel-arm-ibm-amd-processors-vulnerable-to-new-side-channel-attacks-2.jpg" width="728" height="90" layout="intrinsic" i-amphtml-layout="intrinsic"><img alt="cybersecurity" src="https://modernnetsec.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/intel-arm-ibm-amd-processors-vulnerable-to-new-side-channel-attacks-2.jpg" width="728" height="90" data-old-src="data:image/svg+xml;base64,PHN2ZyBoZWlnaHQ9JzkwJyB3aWR0aD0nNzI4JyB4bWxucz0naHR0cDovL3d3dy53My5vcmcvMjAwMC9zdmcnIHZlcnNpb249JzEuMScvPg=="></amp-img></a>
</div>
<p>“We discovered that effects reported in several academic papers over the past 4 years were not correctly understood, leading to incorrect assumptions on countermeasures,” the researchers told The Hacker News.</p>
<p>“This <a href="https://gruss.cc/files/prefetch.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">prefetching effect</a> is actually unrelated to software prefetch instructions or hardware prefetching effects due to memory accesses and instead is caused by speculative dereferencing of user-space registers in the kernel.”</p>
<p>Besides analyzing the actual root cause of the prefetching effect, some other key findings from the research are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Discovery of several new attacks exploiting the underlying root cause, including an address-translation attack in more restricted contexts, direct leakage of register values in specific scenarios, and an end-to-end Foreshadow exploit targeting non-L1 data.</li>
<li>A novel cross-core covert channel attack that, in some instances, could let attackers observe caching of the address (or value) stored in a register without relying on shared memory.</li>
<li>Spectre ‘prefetch’ gadgets can directly leak actual data, which not only makes <a href="https://thehackernews.com/2019/11/zombieload-cpu-vulnerability.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ZombieLoad attack</a> efficient on Intel CPUs to leak sensitive data from internal buffers or memory but also impact non-Intel CPUs.</li>
<li>The speculative dereferencing issue — in certain attacks like <a href="https://thehackernews.com/2020/03/rowhammer-vulnerability-ddr4-dram.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rowhammer</a>, cache attacks, and DRAMA — could let attackers recover the physical addresses of JavaScript variables and exfiltrate information via <a href="https://gruss.cc/files/rowhammerjs.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">transient execution</a> remotely via a web browser.</li>
</ul>
<p>Additionally, researchers also demonstrated that the Foreshadow vulnerability on Intel CPUs could be exploited even when the recommended mitigations are enabled. This is made possible due to the fact the attack can be mounted on data not residing in L1 cache on kernel versions containing ‘prefetch’ gadgets.</p>
<h2>From Address Translation Attack to Foreshadow</h2>
<p>The idea behind this is straight-forward. System software relies on the CPU’s address translation mechanism to implement isolation among different processes. Each process has its own virtual memory space and cannot access arbitrary physical memory addresses outside of it.</p>
<p>[embedded content]</p>
<p>Address translation, thus, acts as an intermediate layer that maps the virtual address space, which is used by a program, to the physical address to a physical address.</p>
<p>The virtual address space also includes a kernel address space to house Linux kernel threads, thus making it easy for the underlying hardware to handle privileged instructions from user threads in kernel mode.</p>
<p>While operating system kernels can be secured against prefetch side-channel attacks via a technique called kernel page-table isolation (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kernel_page-table_isolation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">KPTI</a> or <a href="https://gruss.cc/files/kaiser.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">KAISER</a>) — which enforces a strict kernel and userspace isolation such that the hardware does not hold any information about kernel addresses while running in user mode — the researchers found that it does not guarantee full protection from address-translation attacks, where an attacker tries to check if two different virtual addresses map to the same physical address.</p>
<p>Put differently, the “address-translation attack allows unprivileged applications to fetch arbitrary kernel addresses into the cache and thus resolve virtual to physical addresses on 64-bit Linux systems.”</p>
<p>While the original line of thought was that such attacks were related to prefetch instructions, the new finding proves otherwise, thereby validating that KAISER isn’t an adequate countermeasure against microarchitectural side-channel attacks on kernel isolation.</p>
<p>Instead, it exploits a Spectre-BTB-SA-IP (Branch Target Buffer, same address, in-place) gadget to cause information leakage, causing speculative execution, and further carry out Meltdown and Foreshadow (L1 Terminal Fault) attacks by bypassing current L1TF mitigations.</p>
<p><a href="https://thehackernews.com/2018/11/meltdown-spectre-vulnerabilities.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Spectre-BTB-SA-IP</a> is a variant of <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1811.05441.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Spectre vulnerability</a> that exploits the Branch Target Buffer — a cache-like component in CPUs that’s used for branch prediction — to perform attacks within the same address space and the same branch location.</p>
<p>“The same prefetching effect can be used to perform Foreshadow,” the researchers said. “If a secret is present in the L3 cache and the direct-physical map address is derefenced in the hypervisor kernel, data can be fetched into the L1. This reenables Foreshadow even with Foreshadow mitigations enabled if the unrelated Spectre-BTB mitigations are disabled.”</p>
<p>“The consequence is that we are able to mount a Foreshadow attack on older kernels patched against Foreshadow with all mitigations enabled and on a fully patched kernel if only Spectre-v2 mitigations are disabled.”</p>
<h2>Enable Spectre-BTB mitigations such as Retpoline</h2>
<p>To highlight the impact of the side-channel attacks, the researchers established a cache-based covert channel that exfiltrated data from a process running on an Intel Core i7-6500U CPU to another stealthy process, achieving a transmission rate of 10 bit/s to relay a total of 128 bytes from the sender to the receiver process.<br>Furthermore, the researchers disclosed that it’s possible to leak register contents from an SGX enclave of Intel CPUs using a register that’s speculatively dereferenced (called “Dereference Trap”), using it to recover a 32-bit value stored in a 64-bit register within 15 minutes.</p>
<p>Lastly, ‘certain attacks’ can now be mounted remotely using JavaScript in a web browser, and “fill 64-bit registers with an attacker-controlled value in JavaScript by using WebAssembly.”</p>
<p>To mitigate these attacks, it’s recommended that current CPUs enable Spectre-BTB mitigations, including <a href="https://support.google.com/faqs/answer/7625886" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">retpoline</a> (short for “return trampoline”), which aims to <a href="https://software.intel.com/security-software-guidance/insights/deep-dive-retpoline-branch-target-injection-mitigation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">prevent branch-target-injection</a> by isolating <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Branch_predictor#Indirect_branch_predictor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">indirect branches</a> from speculative execution.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://modernnetsec.io/intel-arm-ibm-amd-processors-vulnerable-to-new-side-channel-attacks/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24089281</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 05:24:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Alcohol as a social technology to check the trustworthiness of others (2014)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 248 | Comments 255 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24088202">thread link</a>) | @searchableguy
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://hndex.org/7798063 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://hndex.org/7798063">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
<header>

<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=7798063" target="_blank">comments</a> <a href="https://plus.google.com/+KajSotala/posts/hofuxyXz78j" target="_blank">original article</a></header>
<p>Ohhh, never thought of this hypothesis: that the act of getting
drunk together might be a social technology that helps us verify
the trustworthiness of others by inhibiting their higher cognitive
functions and thus making it harder to consciously fake things.
That would make sense.</p>
<p>&gt; To enhance our natural thin-slicing abilities, humans have
therefore also developed various cultural practices that make these
instant assessments more reliable. These techniques take advantage
of the fact that deception is fundamentally a cold-cognition act
and relies on cognitive control centers. This means that if we can
impair the cognitive control abilities of people we're trying to
judge, we’ll do a better job of sussing them out: they will
be less able to confuse our cheater-detection systems.</p>
<p>&gt; In one study that has proven enormously useful to law
enforcement agencies, researchers found that police officers could
significantly improve their ability to detect false statements if
suspects were asked to give their alibis in reverse order, starting
with the most recent event and working their way back. This is not
the way we normally tell stories, so being forced to do it
increases cognitive load. Dishonest suspects, it turns out, are
less effective liars if you handicap their conscious minds in this
way.</p>
<p>&gt; This reverse-order alibi technique is a great tool for law
enforcement but not terribly practical when evaluating a potential
business partner or deciding if the people you’re about to
make a peace treaty with are being sincere. There are other ways to
achieve the same effect, though. The police study aimed to reduce
subjects’ cognitive control ability by increasing the
load-adding more weight, as it were. Alternately, you can keep the
load constant but decrease cognitive control ability-weaken the
mental muscles-by suppressing cognitive control centers. One way to
do this is transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS), which involves
applying a powerful magnetic force to the appropriate region of the
skull. TMS, however, is a very recent technology and not exactly
widely available. Also, in most cultures it’s considered bad
form to shock the heads of new acquaintances with huge magnets.</p>
<p>&gt; A much more low-tech and socially acceptable way to produce
the same effect is to get someone completely wasted. As we
discussed in chapter 6, one of the primary effects of alcohol and
other intoxicants is to "downregulate," or temporarily paralyze,
areas of the prefrontal cortex associated with cognitive control. A
couple shots of tequila is the liquid equivalent of a nice jolt of
TMS. It’s therefore no accident that intoxicants of various
sorts are frequently employed by human beings as social lubricants.
Alcohol, kava, cannabis, magic mushrooms, you name it: any
intoxicant that people can get their hands on quickly comes to play
a central role in social occasions, both formal and informal. In
ancient China, no major treaty was signed without first bringing
everyone together in an extended, alcohol-soaked banquet. In fact,
this is one feature of Chinese culture that has not changed a bit
in over four thousand years. Any modern businessperson hoping to
ink a deal with Chinese partners had better get his or her liver in
shape first.</p>
<p>&gt; On a less formal level, this is no doubt why intoxicants
are a universal feature of all sorts of human social gatherings,
from casual cocktail parties to fraternity mixers. Not only is
getting drunk pleasant, it also typically causes people to get
along more freely and easily (at least to a certain point, after
which the drunken fights break out). Intoxication enhances
cooperation in at least two ways. First of all, it reduces social
faking by inhibiting cognitive control centers. Second, if we all
get drunk together, we create a situation of mutual vulnerability
that makes trust easier to establish. Getting drunk is essentially
an act of mental disarmament. In the same way that shaking right
hands with someone assures them that you’re not holding a
weapon, downing a few tequila shots is like checking your
prefrontal cortex at the door. See? No cognitive control. You can
trust me.</p>
<p>Excerpt From: Slingerland, Edward. "Trying Not to Try." Crown
Publishing Group, 2014-03-04. ﻿</p>
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://hndex.org/7798063</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24088202</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 01:32:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Migrating a Server to AWS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 18 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24087614">thread link</a>) | @pcast
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://www.iobasis.com/How-Migrate-a-server-to-AWS/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.iobasis.com/How-Migrate-a-server-to-AWS/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Migrating a server to the cloud</em> always sounds great. But we know it’s a hassle. Especially for servers in production. We want a new server, but keeping current data. And we need to migrate it fast with minimum service disruption.</p>
<p>It takes some time to understand how to do it. Therefore I wrote a <strong>step-by-step guide</strong> to make migration simple and repeatable. Here is how I did it.</p>
<p>
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="Intro" title="" src="https://www.iobasis.com/static/8d61fb2550e39d4d1476d5512d9afb97/4b190/How-to-migrate-a-server-to-AWS.jpg" srcset="https://www.iobasis.com/static/8d61fb2550e39d4d1476d5512d9afb97/e07e9/How-to-migrate-a-server-to-AWS.jpg 200w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/8d61fb2550e39d4d1476d5512d9afb97/066f9/How-to-migrate-a-server-to-AWS.jpg 400w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/8d61fb2550e39d4d1476d5512d9afb97/4b190/How-to-migrate-a-server-to-AWS.jpg 800w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/8d61fb2550e39d4d1476d5512d9afb97/e5166/How-to-migrate-a-server-to-AWS.jpg 1200w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/8d61fb2550e39d4d1476d5512d9afb97/b17f8/How-to-migrate-a-server-to-AWS.jpg 1600w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/8d61fb2550e39d4d1476d5512d9afb97/0f98f/How-to-migrate-a-server-to-AWS.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px">
    </span>
  </span>
  </p>
<h2>1. Creating a CloudEndure Account</h2>
<p>The tool I used is CloudEndure. This is a free tool that orchestrates migration tasks. To get started, I created a <a href="https://console.cloudendure.com/#/register/register">CloudEndure account</a>. I received a confirmation email. And afterward, I was able to log in to CloudEndure console.</p>
<h2>2. Granting Access to AWS Account</h2>
<p>The first step in the console was creating a new project.</p>
<p>
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="Adding access key ID and secret access key" title="" src="https://www.iobasis.com/static/e62f6c9eac1269c4728b5f760976cd0a/5a190/CloudEndure01.png" srcset="https://www.iobasis.com/static/e62f6c9eac1269c4728b5f760976cd0a/772e8/CloudEndure01.png 200w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/e62f6c9eac1269c4728b5f760976cd0a/e17e5/CloudEndure01.png 400w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/e62f6c9eac1269c4728b5f760976cd0a/5a190/CloudEndure01.png 800w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/e62f6c9eac1269c4728b5f760976cd0a/7e4a6/CloudEndure01.png 952w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px">
    </span>
  </span>
  </p>
<p>Note that the CloudEndure account is different from the AWS account. So I needed to create a user that gives CloudEndure access to my AWS account. I followed the steps described in <a href="https://docs.cloudendure.com/#Generating_and_Using_Your_Credentials/Working_with_AWS_Credentials/Generating_the_Required_AWS_Credentials/Generating_the_Required_AWS_Credentials.htm">Generating the Required AWS Credentials</a>. The result was an access key ID and a secret access key.</p>
<p>Then I added these credentials in CloudEndure console and click Save. This verified that CloudEndure got access to my AWS account. And the project changed from <em>“Project not setup”</em> to <em>“Project not fully setup”</em> status.</p>
<p>
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="Setting Replication Settings" title="" src="https://www.iobasis.com/static/b63c54ee57aade1dc4ce326fa92dcbd3/5a190/CloudEndure02.png" srcset="https://www.iobasis.com/static/b63c54ee57aade1dc4ce326fa92dcbd3/772e8/CloudEndure02.png 200w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/b63c54ee57aade1dc4ce326fa92dcbd3/e17e5/CloudEndure02.png 400w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/b63c54ee57aade1dc4ce326fa92dcbd3/5a190/CloudEndure02.png 800w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/b63c54ee57aade1dc4ce326fa92dcbd3/97bfd/CloudEndure02.png 1078w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px">
    </span>
  </span>
  </p>
<h2>3. Defining Replication Settings</h2>
<p>Once communication with AWS is enabled, the next step was configuring the migration project details. I set the migration source to <em>“Other Infrastructure”</em> (because the server to migrate was located on-premises). And I set the target to <em>“AWS US East (Northern Virginia)”</em>. That was the region chosen to migrate the server.</p>
<p>That project tab also had these settings:</p>
<ul>
<li>Replication instance type</li>
<li>Converter instance type</li>
<li>Disks types (SSD or standard)</li>
<li>Subnet (where Replication Servers will be launched)</li>
<li>Security Groups (for Replication servers)</li>
<li>Network Bandwith Throttling</li>
</ul>
<p>Note that the <strong>replication instances</strong> are used to continuously sync your source disks to the cloud. CloudEndure completely manages them.</p>
<p>Apart from these, CloudEndure uses temporary <strong>converter instances</strong>. They adapt the source disks just before launching the target machine, so they can boot and run in the cloud. This might include changing the bootloader and adding drivers for the new HW.</p>
<p>In my case, I just used default settings, and click <em>“Save replication Settings”</em>. And I got a <em>“Project setup complete”</em> message.</p>
<p>
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="CloudEndure project setup complete" title="" src="https://www.iobasis.com/static/5c4d3d5e1f6676482cb11fc622f6a34e/a6d36/CloudEndure03.png" srcset="https://www.iobasis.com/static/5c4d3d5e1f6676482cb11fc622f6a34e/772e8/CloudEndure03.png 200w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/5c4d3d5e1f6676482cb11fc622f6a34e/e17e5/CloudEndure03.png 400w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/5c4d3d5e1f6676482cb11fc622f6a34e/a6d36/CloudEndure03.png 650w" sizes="(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px">
    </span>
  </span>
  </p>
<h2>4. Verifying Agent Requirements</h2>
<p>The <em>“Cloudendure agent”</em> is a small program to install on the source machine. It connects to CloudEndure and sends the disks data to <em>“replication servers”</em> on the AWS account. The replication is continuous. So any change in the source is automatically sent to the cloud.</p>
<p>First I checked CloudEndure <a href="https://docs.cloudendure.com/Content/Getting_Started_with_CloudEndure/Supported_Operating_Systems/Supported_Operating_Systems.htm">supported operating systems</a>. Ubuntu is supported from version 12.04. So my OS was supported.</p>
<p>I also checked the other agent <a href="https://docs.cloudendure.com/Content/Installing_the_CloudEndure_Agents/Agent_Installation_Requirements/Agent_Installation_Requirements.htm">installation prerequisites</a>. All these verifications makes sure that the agent works correctly in the source machine.</p>
<h2>5. Installing the Agent</h2>
<p>Then I installed the CloudEndure agent on the source server. The <em>“Machine”</em> window on CloudEndure console showed how to install the agent.</p>
<p>
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="CloudEndure agent installation instructions" title="" src="https://www.iobasis.com/static/e6fccda739f4a9d99b3816d12447d156/5a190/CloudEndure04.png" srcset="https://www.iobasis.com/static/e6fccda739f4a9d99b3816d12447d156/772e8/CloudEndure04.png 200w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/e6fccda739f4a9d99b3816d12447d156/e17e5/CloudEndure04.png 400w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/e6fccda739f4a9d99b3816d12447d156/5a190/CloudEndure04.png 800w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/e6fccda739f4a9d99b3816d12447d156/0f67e/CloudEndure04.png 921w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px">
    </span>
  </span>
  </p>
<p>For Linux source machines, there are 2 commands. The first one downloads the agent. And the second one installs it. This command also has a code (the <em>“Agent Installation Code”</em>) that links the agent to a particular CloudEndure account.</p>
<p>The installation wasn’t as simple as it appeared. I had to use <code>python3</code> command (instead of <code>python</code>). The first installation also failed. The agent didn’t detect the root disk correctly. But I removed the <code>--no-prompt</code> argument from the second installation command. That allowed me to specify the correct device <code>/dev/sda</code> during the installation process.</p>
<p>The second installation had issues also. CloudEndure agent couldn’t establish a connection to the console. In order to solve this, I installed some packages (<code>make</code>, <code>openssl</code>, <code>wget</code>, <code>curl</code>, <code>gcc</code>, and <code>build-essential</code>). This solved the problem and the agent was finally installed. Both product documentation and <code>~/cloudendure.log</code> were useful for troubleshooting.</p>
<p>
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="CloudEndure agent installed" title="" src="https://www.iobasis.com/static/6cce179e8a0a83e3acead559400a4259/76cea/CloudEndure05.png" srcset="https://www.iobasis.com/static/6cce179e8a0a83e3acead559400a4259/772e8/CloudEndure05.png 200w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/6cce179e8a0a83e3acead559400a4259/e17e5/CloudEndure05.png 400w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/6cce179e8a0a83e3acead559400a4259/76cea/CloudEndure05.png 799w" sizes="(max-width: 799px) 100vw, 799px">
    </span>
  </span>
  </p>
<h2>6. Replicating Disk</h2>
<p>After installing the agent, a row appeared in the <em>“Machines”</em> tab of CloudEndure console, and it showed the source server’s name (<em>“ubuntu”</em>).</p>
<p>
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="CloudEndure new source machine" title="" src="https://www.iobasis.com/static/6cbea1d7ca1d3b0b154b537e2a1d6be2/5a190/CloudEndure06.png" srcset="https://www.iobasis.com/static/6cbea1d7ca1d3b0b154b537e2a1d6be2/772e8/CloudEndure06.png 200w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/6cbea1d7ca1d3b0b154b537e2a1d6be2/e17e5/CloudEndure06.png 400w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/6cbea1d7ca1d3b0b154b537e2a1d6be2/5a190/CloudEndure06.png 800w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/6cbea1d7ca1d3b0b154b537e2a1d6be2/3dde1/CloudEndure06.png 1018w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px">
    </span>
  </span>
  </p>
<p>That row also showed the status of the replication. For example, at the moment of the screenshot, replication was 3.78% complete. And the ETA to get full replication was <em>“An hour”</em>. This indicator is very useful when you need to sync lots of data (or your upload bandwidth is limited).</p>
<p>I also noticed that CloudEndure launched a <strong>t3.small</strong> machine on the target region.</p>
<p>
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="CloudEndure replication server" title="" src="https://www.iobasis.com/static/843277e88d0bc650ef2fc1b7981ec69e/5a190/CloudEndure07.png" srcset="https://www.iobasis.com/static/843277e88d0bc650ef2fc1b7981ec69e/772e8/CloudEndure07.png 200w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/843277e88d0bc650ef2fc1b7981ec69e/e17e5/CloudEndure07.png 400w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/843277e88d0bc650ef2fc1b7981ec69e/5a190/CloudEndure07.png 800w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/843277e88d0bc650ef2fc1b7981ec69e/4ff83/CloudEndure07.png 843w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px">
    </span>
  </span>
  </p>
<p>That instance was used as the <strong>Replication instance</strong>. It runs when there is any replication in progress. And it replicates up to 15 source volumes simultaneously.</p>
<p>I also noticed that CloudEndure created 2 EBS volumes:</p>
<p>
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="CloudEndure EBS Volumes" title="" src="https://www.iobasis.com/static/7dcd217a12ee248e880a4175081dcf8a/227ba/CloudEndure08.png" srcset="https://www.iobasis.com/static/7dcd217a12ee248e880a4175081dcf8a/772e8/CloudEndure08.png 200w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/7dcd217a12ee248e880a4175081dcf8a/e17e5/CloudEndure08.png 400w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/7dcd217a12ee248e880a4175081dcf8a/227ba/CloudEndure08.png 769w" sizes="(max-width: 769px) 100vw, 769px">
    </span>
  </span>
  </p>
<p>Both volumes were attached to the replication server. The first one was intended to store the replicated data. And the volume size was the same as the source disk (in this case 8 GiB). And the second volume was for the <strong>replication server</strong> software.</p>
<p>I also found that CloudEndure created snapshots of these volumes. I found multiple snapshots of my disc, as shown below.</p>
<p>
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="CloudEndure EBS Snapshots" title="" src="https://www.iobasis.com/static/f035b9fe3ffeaa9115782c893733a0f8/5a190/CloudEndure09.png" srcset="https://www.iobasis.com/static/f035b9fe3ffeaa9115782c893733a0f8/772e8/CloudEndure09.png 200w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/f035b9fe3ffeaa9115782c893733a0f8/e17e5/CloudEndure09.png 400w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/f035b9fe3ffeaa9115782c893733a0f8/5a190/CloudEndure09.png 800w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/f035b9fe3ffeaa9115782c893733a0f8/6c745/CloudEndure09.png 893w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px">
    </span>
  </span>
  </p>
<h2>7. Completing Replication</h2>
<p>After some time, the sync finished. It took me around 2 hours to sync an 8 Gb disk. Here is a screenshot of the console at that moment:</p>
<p>
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="CloudEndure Sync finished" title="" src="https://www.iobasis.com/static/4d22c1882462ebd90bfcd6252636399c/5a190/CloudEndure10.png" srcset="https://www.iobasis.com/static/4d22c1882462ebd90bfcd6252636399c/772e8/CloudEndure10.png 200w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/4d22c1882462ebd90bfcd6252636399c/e17e5/CloudEndure10.png 400w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/4d22c1882462ebd90bfcd6252636399c/5a190/CloudEndure10.png 800w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/4d22c1882462ebd90bfcd6252636399c/e24fe/CloudEndure10.png 1073w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px">
    </span>
  </span>
  </p>
<p>Note that the Data Replication Progress changed to <em>“Continuous Data Replication”</em>. That means there was an EBS volume with a complete replica of my source volume. And that any changes were replicated instantly to AWS.</p>
<p>By clicking in the target machine row, I was able to see the details of the machine in CloudEndure. And the main characteristics of the source server were also described there (e.g. CPUs, Memory, OS, Disks, and installed packages).</p>
<p>
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="CloudEndure Machine Details" title="" src="https://www.iobasis.com/static/631057def589e8d5c0da54ab2a4adfa0/4597d/CloudEndure11.png" srcset="https://www.iobasis.com/static/631057def589e8d5c0da54ab2a4adfa0/772e8/CloudEndure11.png 200w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/631057def589e8d5c0da54ab2a4adfa0/e17e5/CloudEndure11.png 400w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/631057def589e8d5c0da54ab2a4adfa0/4597d/CloudEndure11.png 631w" sizes="(max-width: 631px) 100vw, 631px">
    </span>
  </span>
  </p>
<p>The Blueprint tab described the Target configuration. These are the settings of the target server to launch in AWS.</p>
<p>
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="CloudEndure Machine BluePrint" title="" src="https://www.iobasis.com/static/211938a6c9fd54555cdc886eab1c9403/4597d/CloudEndure12.png" srcset="https://www.iobasis.com/static/211938a6c9fd54555cdc886eab1c9403/772e8/CloudEndure12.png 200w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/211938a6c9fd54555cdc886eab1c9403/e17e5/CloudEndure12.png 400w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/211938a6c9fd54555cdc886eab1c9403/4597d/CloudEndure12.png 631w" sizes="(max-width: 631px) 100vw, 631px">
    </span>
  </span>
  </p>
<p>CloudEndure automatically defines the settings of the target machine (for example machine type, subnets, IP, Security Group, and Disk Type). These settings are very important because they define the new EC2 instance characteristics. It’s important to review these settings and adjust default values if necessary.</p>
<p>In my case, I just adjusted a few parameters. First, I changed the machine type to t3.medium. I also set the <em>“Private IP”</em> to <em>“Create new”</em>. This assigns the target machine an IP in the target subnet. And also changed the disk type to SDD. That was all I needed to fine-tune my new server.</p>
<h2>8. Testing the Launch</h2>
<p>The next step was making sure that the server migration would be successful. So I made a test launch before final migration. This is started with the <em>“Launch Target Machines”</em> button.</p>
<p>
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="CloudEndure Test Launch" title="" src="https://www.iobasis.com/static/6e9b2130ecb217a1a1f27f8bbd014b1e/8b153/CloudEndure13.png" srcset="https://www.iobasis.com/static/6e9b2130ecb217a1a1f27f8bbd014b1e/772e8/CloudEndure13.png 200w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/6e9b2130ecb217a1a1f27f8bbd014b1e/8b153/CloudEndure13.png 366w" sizes="(max-width: 366px) 100vw, 366px">
    </span>
  </span>
  </p>
<p>This process creates the new EC2 instance with the migrated volume. That was completed in 7 minutes. And I found the new EC2 instance in the AWS Console. That was very fast.</p>
<p>
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="CloudEndure Instances created on Test Launch" title="" src="https://www.iobasis.com/static/d6a32080e7205bc329dc32e11b089d45/5a190/CloudEndure14.png" srcset="https://www.iobasis.com/static/d6a32080e7205bc329dc32e11b089d45/772e8/CloudEndure14.png 200w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/d6a32080e7205bc329dc32e11b089d45/e17e5/CloudEndure14.png 400w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/d6a32080e7205bc329dc32e11b089d45/5a190/CloudEndure14.png 800w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/d6a32080e7205bc329dc32e11b089d45/a1dd2/CloudEndure14.png 838w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px">
    </span>
  </span>
  </p>
<p>I noticed that there was an instance in <em>“Terminated”</em> state. That’s normal. That’s the temporary converter instance. The conversion time was below 2 minutes. And that conversion instance was terminated afterward.</p>
<p>I wrote down the public IP address of the new instance just launched in the Virginia region. And I was able to login to the instance without any issue. That means that the migration test was successful.</p>
<p>
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="CloudEndure Successful Launch Test" title="" src="https://www.iobasis.com/static/444bd785438bc571a15028a3812bfbac/a0209/CloudEndure15.png" srcset="https://www.iobasis.com/static/444bd785438bc571a15028a3812bfbac/772e8/CloudEndure15.png 200w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/444bd785438bc571a15028a3812bfbac/e17e5/CloudEndure15.png 400w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/444bd785438bc571a15028a3812bfbac/a0209/CloudEndure15.png 725w" sizes="(max-width: 725px) 100vw, 725px">
    </span>
  </span>
  </p>
<h2>9. Removing Unused Test Resources</h2>
<p>After all tests on the instance were completed, I still had the target instance running on AWS. And it wasn’t useful anymore. So I decided to remove its resources from AWS. This was done by selecting the instance in CloudEndure console and choosing <em>“Delete Target Machine”</em>.</p>
<p>
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="CloudEndure Delete Target Machine" title="" src="https://www.iobasis.com/static/ebff82e8acaa67b072fc56c3a3eb7bd8/07484/CloudEndure16.png" srcset="https://www.iobasis.com/static/ebff82e8acaa67b072fc56c3a3eb7bd8/772e8/CloudEndure16.png 200w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/ebff82e8acaa67b072fc56c3a3eb7bd8/e17e5/CloudEndure16.png 400w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/ebff82e8acaa67b072fc56c3a3eb7bd8/07484/CloudEndure16.png 540w" sizes="(max-width: 540px) 100vw, 540px">
    </span>
  </span>
  </p>
<p>Then, the target instance was terminated in AWS as expected.</p>
<p>Note that the replication instance was still active. It was still used to sync the source machine.</p>
<p>
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="CloudEndure Delete Target Machine results" title="" src="https://www.iobasis.com/static/0388c95175ff7ecd2de6dc50baed27a7/5a190/CloudEndure17.png" srcset="https://www.iobasis.com/static/0388c95175ff7ecd2de6dc50baed27a7/772e8/CloudEndure17.png 200w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/0388c95175ff7ecd2de6dc50baed27a7/e17e5/CloudEndure17.png 400w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/0388c95175ff7ecd2de6dc50baed27a7/5a190/CloudEndure17.png 800w,
https://www.iobasis.com/static/0388c95175ff7ecd2de6dc50baed27a7/ddc81/CloudEndure17.png 837w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px">
    </span>
  </span>
  </p>
<p>But I noticed that the Volume previously used by the Target instance wasn’t removed from AWS. So deleted it on my own.</p>
<h2>10. Cutover</h2>
<p>Then the last step was the final migration. I launched a new machine. But this time I used <em>“Cutover Mode”</em> instead of <em>“Test Mode”</em>.</p>
<p>The process was the same as in the <em>“Test Mode”</em>. A new machine was launched in 7 minutes. And I was able to log into the migrated server successfully. So the migration completed successfully again.</p>
<h2>11. Cleaning up</h2>
<p>I still had lots of unused resources on my AWS account. These are the steps I took to clean everything up:</p>
<ul>
<li>I completed a <em>“Remove Machine from this console”</em> on CloudEndure Console. This removes the agent from the source server and stops replication. Note that the target machine isn’t modified. We don’t want the migrated server to be terminated.</li>
<li>I terminated the <em>“Replication Server”</em> instance in AWS (because I had no other replication in progress). This has to be done manually because it isn’t done by CloudEndure.</li>
<li>I removed the EBS volumes previously used by <em>“Replication Server”</em>.</li>
<li>I also removed all unused snapshots.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>This process allowed me to <strong>lift-and-shift</strong> the server. Lift-and-shift is always the first step in the cloud journey. And this tool allowed to complete it efficiently.</p>
<p>I want to mention that the process had many advantages. For example, I used the same tool for uploading the data to the cloud and orchestrate the migration. I was also able to test the process before the cutover. That’s very important because it eliminates possible migration mistakes. The unavailability period was very short. Additionally, I didn’t have to adapt the disk to boot in the cloud, because that was managed by the tool. And this process allows me to automate the migration of …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.iobasis.com/How-Migrate-a-server-to-AWS/">https://www.iobasis.com/How-Migrate-a-server-to-AWS/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.iobasis.com/How-Migrate-a-server-to-AWS/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24087614</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 23:44:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[When science hits a limit, learn to ask different questions]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 7 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24087589">thread link</a>) | @sinapticasblog
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://sinapticas.com/2020/08/07/when-science-hits-a-limit-learn-to-ask-different-questions/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://sinapticas.com/2020/08/07/when-science-hits-a-limit-learn-to-ask-different-questions/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<blockquote><p><em>The fish will be the last to discover water.</em><br>Modern proverb</p></blockquote>



<p>Talk to high-school students preparing for their science exams, and you’ll probably hear two things: that they’re scared of physics, and relatively comfortable with biology. Strangely, this is contrary to the view of most researchers. The scientific zeitgeist is that physics is easy. Its simplicity comes from an ability to create crystalline theories that are powerfully predictive, for everything from the existence of subatomic particles to how light bends around stars. Biology, on the other hand, is much harder to distil into elegant theorems and mathematical equations. For this reason, some eminent thinkers have <a href="https://aeon.co/ideas/black-holes-are-simpler-than-forests-and-science-has-its-limits">argued</a> that cells and forests are harder to understand than distant and difficult-to-observe black holes.</p>



<p>But perhaps there is no such thing as an easy or hard discipline. Maybe there are only easy and hard questions. Biology only <em>seems</em> so hard because it has been defined by a set of very hard questions. Physics only <em>seems</em> easy because centuries of effort by deeply insightful thinkers have produced a set of answerable questions.</p>



<p>What makes biology so challenging, ironically, is our closeness to it. Ask yourself: who is ‘easier’ to understand – a romantic crush or a work colleague? Our intimacy with biology – as well as to psychology and social science – has led us to interrogate these phenomena with profound knowledge already in hand. We ask very detailed questions, and then we’re surprised by the seemingly mysterious or contradictory answers.</p>



<p>On a walk through the forest, we might observe the unusual shapes of the foliage on a maple tree. That might lead us to wonder why the leaves have lobes, why they turn red in autumn, what insects live in the leaf litter, and how they decompose and feed the soil. These questions are deceptively complex, despite the naturalness with which we ask them. By contrast, the cold vast vacuum of space and the unseeable smallness of quarks are so foreign to us that we are proud – at least initially – to say the simplest things about these entities, even just to show that they exist.</p>



<p>Intimacy has sometimes slowed our understanding in physics, too. The question of how the planets move is one of humanity’s oldest obsessions, and runs through many different mythologies. Yet thanks to our species’ self-absorption, the longstanding theory of epicycles wrongly placed the Earth at the centre of the Universe – a mistake that persisted for around 2,000 years. When the question was abstracted to matters of force, mass and gravity in Newtonian physics, planetary motion became much easier to predict and understand.</p>



<p>There are still plenty of hard questions for physicists to puzzle over. If physics pinned its reputation on predicting the next solar flare that could interfere with telecommunications on Earth, it would be viewed as a much more complicated and difficult discipline. Why? Because modelling the many mechanisms that produce the dynamics of the Sun’s surface – all of the gravitational, electromagnetic, thermal and nuclear processes involved – is fiendishly tricky. As for planetary motion, we can get a good-enough picture of a planet’s trajectory by recognising that the massiveness of our Sun allows us to ignore the influence of other heavenly bodies. But if we really wanted to attend to these details, we’d soon find that we can’t precisely predict the motion of three bodies of equal mass. Similarly, with chaos theory, we learned that we can make only rough guesses about the specific position of two pendulums whose motion is coupled together. We cannot, however, say with certainty where either pendulum will ever be.</p>



<p>Perhaps the questions that we have demanded of biology are just too hard. How do we save an individual human life? Why is this bluejay slightly darker than the other? But just because we demand more from biology doesn’t mean we can’t pose slightly easier questions. In fact, drawing on ‘easy’ physics can help us figure out how to <em>find</em> those questions. Physicists are particularly good at looking for pervasive, large-scale phenomena that apply across multiple systems and that are likely the result of simple, shared mechanisms.</p>



<p>Take the idea of <em>biological scaling</em>. This concept stems from early observations that a mammal’s metabolic rate depends predictably and nonlinearly on body size via a <em>power law</em>. A power law is a mathematical relationship that tells us how much a feature changes as the size of the system increases by orders of magnitude (that is, by multiples of a certain number, usually 10). So when a creature’s body mass increases by 1,000-fold, the principles of biological scaling accurately predict that its metabolic rate will increase 100-fold.</p>



<p>But how can the same mathematics apply to something as simple as the gravitational pull between two objects and the messy process of speciation across diverse habitats? In physics, power laws point to shared mechanisms and symmetries that operate across all scales. In biology, our own <a href="https://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/article?id=10.1371/journal.pcbi.1000171">research</a> – as well as <a href="http://science.sciencemag.org/content/276/5309/122.long">that</a> of Geoffrey B West, James H Brown, and Brian J Enquist – shows that the fundamental mechanism at work is the structure and flow of vascular networks. It turns out that blood vessels tend to efficiently span the body and deliver resources to all of a creature’s cells while reducing the strain on the heart. This simple insight has given birth to a growing batch of successful theories that use the idea of an optimised biological structure to predict phenomena such as the distribution of <a href="http://www.pnas.org/content/106/17/7040">trees in a forest</a>, how long we need to <a href="http://www.pnas.org/content/104/3/1051">sleep</a>, the rate of growth of a <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0022973">tumour</a>, the largest and smallest <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5281582/">sizes of bacteria</a>, and <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0020551">the tallest possible tree</a> in any environment.</p>



<p>However, biology can also give rise to its own unique questions. For example, as our colleagues <a href="http://rsta.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/375/2109/20160338">Jessica Flack</a> and <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0959438816000246?via%3Dihub">David Krakauer</a> at the Santa Fe Institute have shown, the information-processing and decision-making capabilities of agents (such as primates, neurons and slime moulds) lead to unique types of feedback, adaptability and causation that differ from purely physical systems. It remains to be seen if the additional complexities of biological systems can be explained by expanding on physics-inspired perspectives such as information theory. It might be that the study of biology and complex systems in general will progress one day to insurmountably hard questions – or that a brilliant recasting of the questions will lead to the elimination of current challenges. This might show a path to easier answers, as Charles Darwin did by reformulating questions about the origins and diversity of life in terms of natural selection and variation.</p>



<figure><img src="https://d2e1bqvws99ptg.cloudfront.net/user_image_upload/729/Aeon-Essay-Hardness-Figure-02.001.jpg" alt="" title=""><figcaption>The complexity of systems measured along two axes: 1) the detail and precision required of the scientific description; 2) the number of mechanisms being combined in a particular phenomenon. The hardest sciences ask detailed questions about systems that are composed of many mechanisms.</figcaption></figure>



<p>In his <a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/1734697?seq=1#page_scan_tab_contents">article</a> ‘More Is Different’ (1972), the physicist Philip Anderson highlighted the dangers of attempting to reduce everything to the most microscopic level. He focused instead on jumps in complexity that occur at various scales of natural phenomena – such as moving from quantum mechanics to chemistry. However, readers often overlook his argument that effective theories should rest on building blocks that explain the underlying mechanisms of a system – even if those building blocks are relatively large or medium-sized entities.</p>



<p>Building on this latter perspective, our argument is that we <em>don’t know</em> if black holes are simpler than forests. We <em>can’t</em> know, until we have a general effective theory that explains the existence of forests or until we can observe the most detailed dynamics of black-hole collapse and evaporation. A statement of relative complexity cannot be made without thoroughly defining the type of questions we are asking for each system. There are probably certain types of enquiries where our knowledge will hit a hard edge, but more often that’s about questions we’re posing than about the systems themselves.</p>



<p>So physics <em>can</em> be hard, and biology <em>can</em> be easy. The degree of difficulty depends more on what questions are being asked than on the field. Within complex-systems science, great advances are often made at the interface between these two perspectives. One path forward is to solve the easy questions first, and then use our answers to try to find principles that are helpful when it comes to more detailed questions and theories. It’s possible that by starting with the easy questions, we can slowly ‘build up’ to the hard ones. Or, in the opposite direction, observing the strange similarity of phenomena across disciplines might incline us to search for brand new mechanisms and principles. This will sometimes demand a less detailed, more abstract perspective – what our colleague John Miller, quoting the Nobel prizewinning physicist Murray Gell-Mann, discusses in his book <em>A Crude Look at the Whole</em> (2016). These crude looks – forced by the remoteness of physics, and obscured by the intimacy of biology – should yield many more deep insights and simplifications in science in the years to come.</p>



<p><em>Published in association with the Santa Fe Institute, an Aeon Strategic Partner.</em></p>



<p>Chris Kempes &amp; Van Savage</p>



<p>This article was originally published at <a href="https://aeon.co/?utm_campaign=republished-article" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Aeon</a> and has been republished under Creative Commons.</p>
			</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://sinapticas.com/2020/08/07/when-science-hits-a-limit-learn-to-ask-different-questions/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24087589</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 23:41:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Swedish doctor's perspective on Covid]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 126 | Comments 244 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24087287">thread link</a>) | @gofiggy
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://sebastianrushworth.com/2020/08/04/how-bad-is-covid-really-a-swedish-doctors-perspective/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://sebastianrushworth.com/2020/08/04/how-bad-is-covid-really-a-swedish-doctors-perspective/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Ok, I want to preface this article by stating that it is entirely anecdotal and based on my experience working as a doctor in the emergency room of one of the big hospitals in Stockholm, Sweden, and of living as a citizen in Sweden. As many people know, Sweden is perhaps the country that has taken the most relaxed attitude of any towards the covid pandemic. Unlike other countries, Sweden never went in to complete lockdown. Non-essential businesses have remained open, people have continued to go to cafés and restaurants, children have remained in school, and very few people have bothered with face masks in public.</p>



<p>Covid hit Stockholm like a storm in mid-March. One day I was seeing people with appendicitis and kidney stones, the usual things you see in the emergency room. The next day all those patients were gone and the only thing coming in to the hospital was covid. Practically everyone who was tested had covid, regardless of what the presenting symtom was. People came in with a nose bleed and they had covid. They came in with stomach pain and they had covid.</p>



<p>Then, after a few months, all the covid patients disappeared. It is now four months since the start of the pandemic, and I haven’t seen a single covid patient in over a month. When I do test someone because they have a cough or a fever, the test invariably comes back negative. At the peak three months back, a hundred people were dying a day of covid in Sweden, a country with a population of ten million. We are now down to around five people dying per day in the whole country, and that number continues to drop. Since people generally die around three weeks after infection, that means virtually no-one is getting infected any more. If we assume around 0.5 percent of those infected die (which I think is very generous, more on that later), then that means that three weeks back 1,000 people were getting infected per day in the whole country, which works out to a daily risk per person of getting infected of 1 in 10,000, which is miniscule. And remember, the risk of dying is at the very most 1 in 200 if you actually do get infected. And that was three weeks ago. Basically, covid is in all practical senses over and done with in Sweden. After four months.</p>



<p>In total covid has killed under 6,000 people in a country of ten million. A country with an annual death rate of around 100,000 people. Considering that 70% of those who have died of covid are over 80 years old, quite a few of those 6,000 would have died this year anyway. That makes covid a mere blip in terms of its effect on mortality.</p>



<p>That is why it is nonsensical to compare covid to other major pandemics, like the 1918 pandemic that killed tens of millions of people. Covid will never even come close to those numbers. And yet many countries have shut down their entire economies, stopped children going to school, and made large portions of their population unemployed in order to deal with this disease.</p>



<p>The media have been proclaiming that only a small percentage of the population have antibodies, and therefore it is impossible that herd immunity has developed. Well, if herd immunity hasn’t developed, where are all the sick people? Why has the rate of infection dropped so precipitously? Considering that most people in Sweden are leading their lives normally now, not socially distancing, not wearing masks, there should still be high rates of infection.</p>



<p>The reason we test for antibodies is because it is easy and cheap. Antibodies are in fact not the body’s main defence against virus infections. T-cells are. But T-cells are harder to measure than antibodies, so we don’t really do it clinically. It is quite possible to have T-cells that are specific for covid and thereby make you immune to the disease, without having any antibodies. Personally, I think this is what has happened. Everybody who works in the emergency room where I work has had the antibody test. Very few actually have antibodies. This is in spite of being exposed to huge numbers of infected people, including at the beginning of the pandemic, before we realized how widespread covid was, when no-one was wearing protective equipment.</p>



<p>I am not denying that covid is awful for the people who do get really sick or for the families of the people who die, just as it is awful for the families of people who die of cancer, or influenza, or an opioid overdose. But the size of the response in most of the world (not including Sweden) has been totally disproportionate to the size of the threat.</p>



<p>Sweden ripped the metaphorical band-aid off quickly and got the epidemic over and done with in a short amount of time, while the rest of the world has chosen to try to peel the band-aid off slowly. At present that means Sweden has one of the highest total death rates in the world. But covid is over in Sweden. People have gone back to their normal lives and barely anyone is getting infected any more. I am willing to bet that the countries that have shut down completely will see rates spike when they open up. If that is the case, then there won’t have been any point in shutting down in the first place, because all those countries are going to end up with the same number of dead at the end of the day anyway. Shutting down completely in order to decrease the total number of deaths only makes sense if you are willing to stay shut down until a vaccine is available. That could take years. No country is willing to wait that long.</p>



<p>Covid has at present killed less than 6000 in Sweden. It is very unlikely that the number of dead will go above 7,000. An average influenza year in Sweden, 700 people die of influenza. Does that mean covid is ten times worse than influenza? No, because influenza has been around for centuries while covid is completely new. In an average influenza year most people already have some level of immunity because they’ve been infected with a similar strain previously, or because they’re vaccinated. So it is quite possible, in fact likely, that the case fatality rate for covid is the same as for influenza, or only slightly higher, and the entire difference we have seen is due to the complete lack of any immunity in the population at the start of this pandemic. </p>



<p>This conclusion makes sense of the Swedish fatality numbers – if we’ve reached a point where there is hardly any active infection going on any more in Sweden in spite of the fact that there is barely any social distancing happening then that means at least 50% of the population has been infected already and have developed immunity, which is five million people. This number is perfectly reasonable if we assume a reproductive number for the virus of two: If each person infects two new, with a five day period between being infected and infecting others, and you start out with just one infected person in the country, then you will reach a point where several million are infected in just four months. If only 6000 are dead out of five million infected, that works out to a case fatality rate of 0.12 percent, roughly the same as regular old influenza, which no-one is the least bit frightened of, and which we don’t shut down our societies for.</p>



<p>If you thought this article was interesting, then you might be interested in my follow-up article, about <a href="https://sebastianrushworth.com/2020/08/08/what-is-the-best-way-to-measure-rates-of-covid-immunity/">the best way to measure rates of covid infection in a population</a></p>



<p>Additionally, If you liked this article, then please click the link at the bottom of this page to subscribe and receive future articles straight to your inbox.</p>

<div>
	<p><img alt="" src="https://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f80948fe1de6fa8784ebcbce1a6c153c?s=42&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" height="42" width="42">	</p><!-- .author-avatar -->

	<div>
		

		<p>
			I am a practicing physician in Stockholm, Sweden. Every day I get asked questions by my patients about health, diet, exercise, supplements, and medications. There is a lot of misinformation on the internet and it is easy to get the wrong advice, and hard to tell what is right and what is wrong if you don’t have advanced scientific training. The purpose of this blog is to share what the science actually says.			<a href="https://sebastianrushworth.com/author/doctorsebastian/" rel="author">
				View all posts by Sebastian Rushworth, M.D.			</a>
		</p><!-- .author-bio -->
	</div><!-- .author-description -->
</div><!-- .author-info -->
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://sebastianrushworth.com/2020/08/04/how-bad-is-covid-really-a-swedish-doctors-perspective/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24087287</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 23:00:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Terran: A Human Perception Library]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 23 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24084632">thread link</a>) | @nagitsu
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://pento.ai/blog/introducing-terran | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://pento.ai/blog/introducing-terran">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div><main><article><main><a href="https://pento.ai/blog/introducing-terran"><p>Introducing Terran: A human perception library</p></a></main><p>Computer vision has seen tremendous change in the last decade. Along this journey, the nature of the techniques used has shifted from fixed-pipeline algorithms based mostly in heuristics and little data to resource-intensive general-purpose models that require both heavy computing power and a lot of data. This shift, while unlocking new capabilities, presents some drawbacks.</p><p>Most of the work done at the research level is fragmented because researchers, by the very nature of good research, need to focus on one aspect at a time when planning their experiments. And while there are papers on unifying techniques, the difficulty to evaluate, and the requirements on what a novel contribution is being so stringent, these are few and apart. Most of these works come from non-academic initiatives such as <a href="http://fast.ai/">fast.ai</a>.</p><p>The objective of research is to present and validate a novel approach to a problem. Being that their end goal, the focus is on results and the published paper, not on the code used to run those experiments. Even when code is made publicly available, more often than not, it tends to be hard to extend, optimize, or integrate with other pieces of code.</p><p>Commercially available APIs may solve this issue since they are usually easy to use and integrate. However, they come with another set of problems.</p><p>First and foremost, code is not auditable. Since they are commercial solutions, code is not open source, so you cannot be certain what the code is doing. You may trust the company you are working with, but that may not be enough for other stakeholders. Plus, it is always nice to be able to check what is being done. Also, since they are usually cloud solutions, you have to share your data with them. This is a no-go for some companies, since the data may be somewhat sensitive.</p><p>There are some great services by some big-name companies, which may work fine for some set of problems. Nevertheless, their "best" models remain behind closed door. In addition to this, the technique that it is used may be unknown. While you can easily use Amazon Rekognition or Google Vision AI, you can't know what's under the hood. This may be fine for some scenarios, but for other cases you may need to have a sense of in which cases the solution fails, or which biases it has.</p><p>We believe that there's a place for an open-source initiative focusing on addressing the above
points.</p><p>That's where <a href="https://terran-project.com/">Terran</a> comes in.</p><p><img src="https://pento.ai/images/blog/terran-faces.png" alt="Terran Face Detection"></p><p>An example of Face Detection made with Terran</p><p>An open-source human perception library. We focus on providing open, auditable, and performant alternatives to closed approaches. Solutions that can run on your computer or device and that will adapt to the environment that it's in. But most importantly, code that you can test (without piling-up costs), understand and modify to your needs.</p><p>We strive for code that is easy to integrate and understand. While it is open-source, it is not specifically targeted for researchers. We want to make computer vision accessible to anyone who can code, and enable them to create innovative applications. To achieve this, Terran was built with these guiding principles in mind:</p><ul><li>A self-explanatory API that tells you what you are doing.</li><li>No intricate configuration files.</li><li>Simplest I/O operations for any kind of videos and images.</li></ul><p>The focus is on being a production-grade library, not a toy project. Only models whose performance can be assessed and with reasonable (and knowable) computational and memory requirements will be included.</p><p><img src="https://pento.ai/images/blog/terran-poses.png" alt="Terran Pose Estimation"></p><p>An example of Pose Estimation using Terran</p><p>Let's see a small example of what we can build with it.</p><p>We could do our own image album creator grouping photos of the same people. That's a use case that all cloud providers (such as Google Photos and Apple Photos) do. For the sake of keeping it simple and focusing on Terran, lets do the core of this problem: finding on which photos someone is present.</p><p>We will start with some imports:</p><pre><pre><code>import click

from pathlib import Path
from scipy.spatial.distance import cosine

from terran.face import extract_features, face_detection
from terran.io import open_image, resolve_images
from terran.vis import display_image, vis_faces
</code></pre></pre><p>We will use <code>click</code> to create a small CLI tool (we love click — highly recommended). We will use <code>pathlib</code> to handle paths and a measure of distance from <code>scipy</code>. Finally, we import some functions from Terran's modules: from face, core functions to detect faces and extract features; from io, utility functions to resolve paths and open images; from vis, some visualization functions (extremely important and useful when working with images!).</p><ol><li>from <code>terran.face</code>, we import core functions to detect and extract features from faces</li><li>from <code>terran.io</code>, utility functions to resolve paths and open images</li><li>and finally, from <code>terran.vis</code>, we import some visualization functions that are extremely important and useful when working with images!</li></ol><p>Now we will create a function that deals with the problem of finding the photos where a person is present. You'll see how easy it is with Terran!</p><pre><pre><code>@click.command(name='match-dir')
@click.argument('reference')
@click.argument('image-dir')
@click.option('--batch-size', type=int, default=1)
@click.option('--threshold', type=float, default=0.5)
@click.option('--display', is_flag=True, default=False)
def match_directory(reference, image_dir, batch_size, threshold, display):

    reference = open_image(reference)
    faces_in_reference = face_detection(reference)

    if len(faces_in_reference) != 1:
        click.echo('Reference image must have exactly one face.')
        return

    ref_feature = extract_features(reference, faces_in_reference[0])
</code></pre></pre><p>Our function takes in two arguments: a reference image and a directory where we should scan the photos. Then, our first step is to get a set of features out of our reference image that represents the person we are looking for.</p><p>Then, we get the paths to all of the images that we will be scanning:</p><pre><pre><code>    paths = resolve_images(
        Path(image_dir).expanduser(),
        batch_size=batch_size
    )
</code></pre></pre><p>This Terran function gives paths in batches, so you can process them in parallel (if needed).</p><p>So the only thing remaining to do is, for each image, open it, detect the faces, get the features, and compare it with our reference image. Easy enough with Terran!</p><pre><pre><code>    for batch_paths in paths:
        # Open them
        batch_images = list(map(open_image, batch_paths))

        # Detect the faces
        faces_per_image = face_detection(batch_images)

        # Get the features
        features_per_image = extract_features(batch_images, faces_per_image)

        for path, image, faces, features in zip(
            batch_paths, batch_images, faces_per_image, features_per_image
        ):
            for face, feature in zip(faces, features):
                # Compare each feature with our reference feature
                confidence = cosine(ref_feature, feature)

                # If it is a match print it / display it!
                if confidence &lt; threshold:
                    click.echo(f'{path}, confidence = {confidence:.2f}')
                    if display:
                        display_image(vis_faces(image, face))
</code></pre></pre><p>All the code together:</p><pre><pre><code>import click

from pathlib import Path
from scipy.spatial.distance import cosine

from terran.face import extract_features, face_detection
from terran.io import open_image, resolve_images
from terran.vis import display_image, vis_faces

@click.command(name='match-dir')
@click.argument('reference')
@click.argument('image-dir')
@click.option('--batch-size', type=int, default=1)
@click.option('--threshold', type=float, default=0.5)
@click.option('--display', is_flag=True, default=False)
def match_directory(reference, image_dir, batch_size, threshold, display):
    reference = open_image(reference)
    faces_in_reference = face_detection(reference)
    if len(faces_in_reference) != 1:
        click.echo('Reference image must have exactly one face.')
        return
    ref_feature = extract_features(reference, faces_in_reference[0])

    paths = resolve_images(
        Path(image_dir).expanduser(),
        batch_size=batch_size
    )
    for batch_paths in paths:
        batch_images = list(map(open_image, batch_paths))
        faces_per_image = face_detection(batch_images)
        features_per_image = extract_features(batch_images, faces_per_image)

        for path, image, faces, features in zip(
            batch_paths, batch_images, faces_per_image, features_per_image
        ):
            for face, feature in zip(faces, features):
                confidence = cosine(ref_feature, feature)
                if confidence &lt; threshold:
                    click.echo(f'{path}, confidence = {confidence:.2f}')
                    if display:
                        display_image(vis_faces(image, face))

if __name__ == '__main__':
    match_directory()
</code></pre></pre><p>With just a few lines of code, you can easily check in which images you are present! From your computer, not needing to upload them anywhere, and tweaking the parameters to fit your case (take a look at threshold). You can also take a look at this example in our <a href="https://github.com/pento-group/terran/blob/master/examples/match.py">Github</a>, and to the rest of Terran and see how it works.</p><p>Right now, Terran has models for Face Detection, Face Recognition, and Pose Estimation. We think that several applications can be created using these features, like controlling your computer with body gestures or changing what gets displayed depending on the presence of a face or not. You can use Terran as an interface to interact to your computer with your body, among several other ideas that one could think of.</p><p>In the future, we plan to:</p><ul><li>Add more models for these same problems, but that are more lightweight, in case you need it to run on a small device.</li><li>Add other models to tackle other problems, e.g. segmentation.</li><li>Add the functionality to train or fine-tune the existing models.</li></ul><p>While this is our current roadmap, feel free to create an issue on github to tell us if you'd like us to work on …</p></article></main></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://pento.ai/blog/introducing-terran">https://pento.ai/blog/introducing-terran</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://pento.ai/blog/introducing-terran</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24084632</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 17:49:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Psychedelic Inspiration for Hypercard (2018)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 50 | Comments 10 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24083738">thread link</a>) | @bobbiechen
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://www.mondo2000.com/2018/06/18/the-inspiration-for-hypercard/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.mondo2000.com/2018/06/18/the-inspiration-for-hypercard/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-2917">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>
		
		<p><img data-attachment-id="2921" data-permalink="https://www.mondo2000.com/2018/06/18/the-inspiration-for-hypercard/images-20/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/images-1.jpeg?fit=511%2C286&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="511,286" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="images" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/images-1.jpeg?fit=300%2C168&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/images-1.jpeg?fit=511%2C286&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/images-1.jpeg?resize=511%2C286" alt="" width="511" height="286" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/images-1.jpeg?w=511&amp;ssl=1 511w, https://i2.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/images-1.jpeg?resize=300%2C168&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/images-1.jpeg?resize=210%2C118&amp;ssl=1 210w" sizes="(max-width: 511px) 100vw, 511px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p>by Bill Atkinson, as told to Leo Laporte</p>
<p>In 1985 I swallowed a tiny fleck of gelatin containing a medium dose of LSD, and I spent most of the night sitting on a concrete park bench outside my home in Los Gatos, California.</p>

<p>I gazed up at a hundred billion galaxies each with a hundred billion stars, and each star a giant thermonuclear fusion reaction as powerful as our Sun. And for the first time in my life I knew deep down inside that we are not alone.&nbsp;</p>

<p>I knew that life on planet Earth is not the only pocket of consciousness in the universe, and likely not the most advanced. But we still have a role to play in the unfolding drama of creation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It seemed to me the universe is in a process of coming alive. Consciousness is blossoming and propagating to colonize the universe, and life on Earth is one of many bright spots in the cosmic birth of consciousness.</p>

<p>But the stars are separated by enormous distances of darkness and vacuum, which may hinder communication between them. I lowered my gaze and saw the street lamps below glowing brightly, each casting a pool of light but surrounded by darkness before the next lamp. As above, so below.</p>


<p><img data-attachment-id="2928" data-permalink="https://www.mondo2000.com/2018/06/18/the-inspiration-for-hypercard/nightsk/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/NightSK.jpeg?fit=446%2C297&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="446,297" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="NightSK" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/NightSK.jpeg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/NightSK.jpeg?fit=446%2C297&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/NightSK.jpeg?resize=777%2C517" alt="" width="777" height="517" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/NightSK.jpeg?w=446&amp;ssl=1 446w, https://i0.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/NightSK.jpeg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/NightSK.jpeg?resize=210%2C140&amp;ssl=1 210w" sizes="(max-width: 777px) 100vw, 777px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>

<p>The street lamps reminded me of bodies of knowledge, gems of discovery and understanding, but separated from each other by distance and different languages. Poets, artists, musicians, physicists, chemists, biologists, mathmeticians, and economists all have separate pools of knowledge, but are hindered from sharing and finding the deeper connections.</p>

<p>My vision distorted by thick eyeglasses, I witnessed the curvature of the Earth’s horizon, and I felt the pull of gravity toward its center, such that every one of us is standing at the very apex. Each of us stands at the top of planet Earth, and each of us is a leader or captain of the “Blue Marble” team.</p>

<p>How could I help? By focusing on the weak link. If I were captain of a soccer team, I would look for the weak link and work on it. If the goalie was letting too many through, I would spend extra practice time with him, and the whole team would prosper.</p>

<p>It occurred to me the weak link for the Blue Marble team is wisdom. Humanity has achieved sufficient technological power to change the course of life and the entire global ecosystem, but we seem to lack the perspective to choose wisely between alternative futures. But I was young, without much life experience or wisdom myself.</p>

<p>Knowledge, it seemed to me, consists of the “How” connections between pieces of information, the cause and effect relationships. How does this action bring about that result. Science is a systematic attempt to discover the “How” connections.&nbsp;</p>

<p><img data-attachment-id="2923" data-permalink="https://www.mondo2000.com/2018/06/18/the-inspiration-for-hypercard/images-2-11/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/images-2.jpeg?fit=454%2C340&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="454,340" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="images-2" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/images-2.jpeg?fit=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/images-2.jpeg?fit=454%2C340&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/images-2.jpeg?resize=454%2C340" alt="" width="454" height="340" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/images-2.jpeg?w=454&amp;ssl=1 454w, https://i0.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/images-2.jpeg?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/images-2.jpeg?resize=210%2C157&amp;ssl=1 210w" sizes="(max-width: 454px) 100vw, 454px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>

<p>Wisdom, it seemed to me, was a step further removed, the bigger perspective of the “Why” connections between pieces of knowledge. Why, for reasons ethical and aesthetic, should we choose one future over another?</p>

<p>I thought if we could encourage sharing of ideas between different areas of knowledge, perhaps more of the bigger picture would emerge, and eventually more wisdom might develop. Sort of a trickle-up theory of information leading to knowledge leading to wisdom.</p>

<p>This was the underlying inspiration for HyperCard, a multimedia authoring environment that empowered non-programmers to share ideas using new interactive media called HyperCard stacks.&nbsp;</p>

<p><img data-attachment-id="2922" data-permalink="https://www.mondo2000.com/2018/06/18/the-inspiration-for-hypercard/mtiymzi2odgxmjywntyznzm3/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/MTIyMzI2ODgxMjYwNTYzNzM3.jpg?fit=600%2C424&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="600,424" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="MTIyMzI2ODgxMjYwNTYzNzM3" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/MTIyMzI2ODgxMjYwNTYzNzM3.jpg?fit=300%2C212&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/MTIyMzI2ODgxMjYwNTYzNzM3.jpg?fit=600%2C424&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/MTIyMzI2ODgxMjYwNTYzNzM3.jpg?resize=600%2C424" alt="" width="600" height="424" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/MTIyMzI2ODgxMjYwNTYzNzM3.jpg?w=600&amp;ssl=1 600w, https://i1.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/MTIyMzI2ODgxMjYwNTYzNzM3.jpg?resize=300%2C212&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/www.mondo2000.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/MTIyMzI2ODgxMjYwNTYzNzM3.jpg?resize=210%2C148&amp;ssl=1 210w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>

<p>Each card in a HyperCard stack included graphics, text, interactive buttons, and links that took you to another card or stack. Built-in painting tools, drag-and-drop authoring with a library of pre-fab buttons and fields, and simple event based scripting made HyperCard flexible and easy to use.</p>

<p>It took a lot of hard work and a dedicated team to complete this mission. Apple shipped HyperCard in August 1987, and included it free with every Mac so any user could create and share HyperCard stacks. Many creative people expressed their ideas and passions, and several million interactive HyperCard stacks were created.&nbsp;</p>

<p>HyperCard was a precurser to the first web browser, except chained to a hard drive before the worldwide web. Six years later Mosaic was introduced, influenced by some of the ideas in HyperCard, and indirectly by an inspiring LSD experience.</p>

<p><em>Leo Laporte did a great interview with me in April 2016. You can <a href="https://twit.tv/shows/triangulation/episodes/247?autostart=false">watch it here</a>&nbsp;—&nbsp; with the part about hypercard inspiration starting at 22:43&nbsp;</em></p>




<p><span></span>
				<span>Post Views: </span>
				<span>7,716</span>
			</p>			</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.mondo2000.com/2018/06/18/the-inspiration-for-hypercard/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24083738</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 16:30:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Microsoft Fast Design]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 552 | Comments 181 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24083260">thread link</a>) | @no_wizard
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://www.fast.design/docs/introduction | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.fast.design/docs/introduction">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Welcome to the FAST documentation! We're glad you're here. We can't wait to show you around.</p><h2>What is FAST?</h2><p>FAST is a collection of JavaScript packages centered around web standards, designed to help you efficiently tackle some of the most common challenges in website and application design and development.</p><p>Have you ever needed a reusable set of UI components that you could drop into your app and have an amazing experience? <em><strong>That's FAST.</strong></em></p><p>Have you ever needed to create your own components, and share them across your company, including across groups that use different, incompatible front-end frameworks? <em><strong>That's FAST.</strong></em></p><p>Have you ever needed to implement a branded experience or a design language like Microsoft's Fluent UI or Google's Material Design? <em><strong>That's FAST.</strong></em></p><p>Have you ever wanted to improve your app's startup time, render speed, or memory consumption? <em><strong>That's FAST.</strong></em></p><p>Have you ever wanted to adopt more web standards and build your site or app on a native web foundation that's immune to the shifting sands of the modern JavaScript front-end landscape? <em><strong>That's FAST.</strong></em></p><p>Let's take a look at what each of FAST's core packages gives us today.</p><h3>fast-element</h3><p><a href="https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://img.shields.io/badge/License-MIT-yellow.svg" alt="License: MIT"></a>
<a href="https://badge.fury.io/js/%40microsoft%2Ffast-element" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://badge.fury.io/js/%40microsoft%2Ffast-element.svg" alt="npm version"></a></p><p>The <code>fast-element</code> library is a lightweight means to easily building performant, memory-efficient, standards-compliant Web Components. FAST Elements work in every major browser and can be used in combination with any front-end framework or even without a framework. To get up and running with <code>fast-element</code> see <a href="https://www.fast.design/docs/fast-element/getting-started">the Getting Started guide</a>.</p><h3>fast-foundation</h3><p><a href="https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://img.shields.io/badge/License-MIT-yellow.svg" alt="License: MIT"></a>
<a href="https://badge.fury.io/js/%40microsoft%2Ffast-foundation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://badge.fury.io/js/%40microsoft%2Ffast-foundation.svg" alt="npm version"></a></p><p>The <code>fast-foundation</code> package is a library of Web Component classes, templates, and other utilities intended to be composed into registered Web Components by design systems (e.g. Fluent Design, Material Design, etc.). The exports of this package can generally be thought of as un-styled base components that implement semantic and accessible markup and behavior.</p><p>This package does not export Web Components registered as <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Web_Components/Using_custom_elements" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">custom elements</a> - it exports parts and pieces intended to be <em>composed</em> into Web Components, allowing you to implement your own design language by simply applying CSS styles and behaviors without having to write all the JavaScript that's involved in building production-quality component implementations.</p><h3>fast-components</h3><p><a href="https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://img.shields.io/badge/License-MIT-yellow.svg" alt="License: MIT"></a>
<a href="https://badge.fury.io/js/%40microsoft%2Ffast-components" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://badge.fury.io/js/%40microsoft%2Ffast-components.svg" alt="npm version"></a></p><p><code>fast-components</code> is a library of Web Components that <em>composes</em> the exports of <code>fast-foundation</code> with stylesheets aligning to the FAST design language. This composition step registers a custom element. See the <a href="https://www.fast.design/docs/components/getting-started">quick start</a> to get started using the components.</p><h3>fast-components-msft</h3><p><a href="https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://img.shields.io/badge/License-MIT-yellow.svg" alt="License: MIT"></a>
<a href="https://badge.fury.io/js/%40microsoft%2Ffast-components-msft" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://badge.fury.io/js/%40microsoft%2Ffast-components-msft.svg" alt="npm version"></a></p><p><code>fast-components-msft</code> is a library of Web Components that <em>composes</em> <code>fast-foundation</code>. <code>fast-components-msft</code> uses the same custom element names as <code>fast-components</code>, but makes use of different stylesheets that support Microsoft's Fluent design language.</p><h3>Component Explorer</h3><p>Launch our <a href="https://explore.fast.design/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Component Explorer</a> to experience our <a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/@microsoft/fast-components" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">FAST Components</a> and development tools.</p><h2>Getting started</h2><p>If you're looking to get started using our components right away, take a look at <a href="https://www.fast.design/docs/components/getting-started">the components quick start</a>. You'll also want to check out <a href="https://www.fast.design/docs/integrations/introduction">our integrations</a> if you're looking to add the components into a Webpack build or incorporate them with another front-end framework. For those interested in implementing their own design system or customizing the styles of the components, after you <a href="https://www.fast.design/docs/components/getting-started">have a look at the components</a>, you'll want to read through <a href="https://www.fast.design/docs/design/introduction">our styling docs</a>. Finally, if your goal is to build your own components or apps with <code>fast-element</code>, you can learn all about that in our <a href="https://www.fast.design/docs/fast-element/getting-started">guide to building web components with FASTElement</a>.</p><h2>Joining the community</h2><p>Looking to get answers to questions or engage with us in realtime? Our community is most active <a href="https://discord.gg/FcSNfg4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">on Discord</a>. Submit requests and issues on <a href="https://github.com/Microsoft/fast/issues/new/choose" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub</a>, or join us by contributing on <a href="https://github.com/Microsoft/fast/labels/community:good-first-issue" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">some good first issues via GitHub</a>.</p><p>We look forward to building an amazing open source community with you!</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.fast.design/docs/introduction</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24083260</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 15:55:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Cancel Culture Checklist]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 9 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24083055">thread link</a>) | @jeremylevy
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://www.persuasion.community/p/the-cancel-culture-checklist | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.persuasion.community/p/the-cancel-culture-checklist">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a target="_blank" href="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F7de7e5e6-310f-4028-acf3-05d3975fe601_5134x3050.jpeg"><img src="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F7de7e5e6-310f-4028-acf3-05d3975fe601_5134x3050.jpeg" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/7de7e5e6-310f-4028-acf3-05d3975fe601_5134x3050.jpeg&quot;,&quot;height&quot;:865,&quot;width&quot;:1456,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:null,&quot;bytes&quot;:4757250,&quot;alt&quot;:null,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;image/jpeg&quot;,&quot;href&quot;:null}" alt=""></a></p><p>Cancel culture now poses a real threat to intellectual freedom in the United States. According to <a href="https://www.cato.org/publications/survey-reports/poll-62-americans-say-they-have-political-views-theyre-afraid-share">a recent poll by the Cato Institute</a>, a third of Americans say that they are personally worried about losing their jobs or missing out on career opportunities if they express their real political opinions. Americans in all walks of life have been publicly shamed, pressured into ritualistic apologies or summarily fired.</p><p>But critics of the critics of cancel culture make a powerful retort. Accusing others of canceling can, they claim, be a way to stigmatize legitimate criticism. As Hannah Giorgis <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2020/07/harpers-letter-free-speech/614080/">writes in the </a><em><a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2020/07/harpers-letter-free-speech/614080/">Atlantic</a></em>, “critical tweets are not censorship.”</p><p>So what, exactly, does a cancellation consist of? And how does it differ from the exercise of free speech and robust critical debate? </p><p>At a conceptual level, the difference is clear. Criticism marshals evidence and arguments in a rational effort to persuade. Canceling, by contrast, seeks to organize and manipulate the social or media environment in order to isolate, deplatform or intimidate ideological opponents. It is about shaping the information battlefield, not seeking truth; and its intent—or at least its predictable outcome—is to coerce conformity and reduce the scope for forms of criticism that are not sanctioned by the prevailing consensus of some local majority.</p><p>In practice, however, telling canceling apart from criticism can be difficult because both take the <em>form</em> of criticizing others. That is why it is probably impossible to devise a simple bright-line test of what should count as a harmful instance of cancelation.</p><p>A better approach might therefore be diagnostic. Like the symptoms of cancer, the hallmarks of a cancellation are many. Though not all instances involve every single characteristic, they all involve <em>some </em>of its key attributes. Rather than issuing a single litmus test, the diagnostic approach allows us to draw up a checklist of warning signs. The more signs you see, the more certain you can be that you are looking at a cancel campaign.</p><p>Six warning signs make up my personal checklist for cancel culture. </p><p><strong>Punitiveness</strong></p><p><em>Are people denouncing you to your employer, your professional groups or your social connections? Are you being blacklisted from jobs and social opportunities? Does what is being said to or about you have the goal—or foreseeable effect—of jeopardizing your livelihood or isolating you socially?</em></p><p>A critical culture seeks to correct rather than punish. In science, the penalty for being wrong is not that you lose your job or your friends. Normally, the only penalty is that you lose the argument. Even the phenomenon of retracting papers is new and deservedly controversial, because the usual—and very effective—method has been for science to simply discard mistakes and move on. Wrong answers and bad science die on the vine and disappear. Incentives are mostly positive, not punitive: for being right, you win citations, promotions, fame and fancy prizes. Taking a punitive attitude toward mistakes undermines the scientific process because knowledge advances by trial and error.</p><p>Canceling, by contrast, seeks to punish rather than correct—and often for a single misstep rather than a long track record of failure. A professor <a href="https://spectator.us/academics-get-paper-retracted-some-havent-read-nathan-cofnas/">swears</a> to “ruin [a graduate student’s] reputation permanently and deservedly.” Campaigners against an art curator <a href="https://news.artnet.com/art-world/gary-garrels-departure-sfmoma-1893964">declare</a> he “must be removed from his job, effective immediately.”</p><p>The point is to make the errant suffer. </p><p><strong>Deplatforming</strong></p><p><em>Are campaigners attempting to prevent you from publishing your work, giving speeches or attending meetings? Are they claiming that allowing you to be heard is violence against them or makes them unsafe?</em></p><p>A critical culture tolerates dissent rather than silencing it. It understands that dissent can seem obnoxious, harmful, hateful and, yes, <em>unsafe</em>. To minimize unnecessary damage, it goes to great lengths to encourage people to express themselves in a civil manner. But it also understands that, every so often, an obnoxious dissenter is right—and so it opposes silencing and deplatforming.</p><p>Canceling, by contrast, seeks to shut up and shout down its targets. Cancelers often define the mere act of disagreeing with them as a threat to their safety or even an act of violence. Staffers at the <em>New York Times </em><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/07/business/media/new-york-times-washington-post-protests.html">claimed</a> that the mere act of publishing a controversial op-ed piece endangered them. Staffers at the <em>New Yorker</em> demanded that Steve Bannon be <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/04/opinion/bannon-new-yorker-festival-remnick.html">deplatformed</a>. Shout-downs, <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;ved=2ahUKEwjYkNS36ILrAhVUYDUKHWcADuIQFjAAegQIARAC&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.thefire.org%2Fresearch%2Fdisinvitation-database%2F&amp;usg=AOvVaw2ONE1G9KXx27R20K-ezA56">disinvitations</a> and demands for retractions and withdrawals are cancelers’ stock in trade.</p><p><strong>Organization</strong></p><p><em>Does criticism appear to be organized and targeted? Are the organizers recruiting others to pile on? Are you being swarmed and brigaded? Are people hunting through your work and scouring social media to find ammunition to use against you?</em></p><p>Critical culture relies on persuasion. The way to win an argument is to convince others that you are right. Often, of course, schools of thought form, and arguments between them can grow heated; but organizing pressure campaigns against political or ideological targets is usually considered out of bounds.</p><p>By contrast, it’s common to see cancelers organize hundreds of petition-signers or thousands of social media users to dig up and prosecute an indictment. Recently, for example, campaigners picked through the social media posts of the psychologist (and member of <em>Persuasion</em>’s Board of Advisers) Steven Pinker in the hope of digging up some kind of case against him. Though they only came up with <a href="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/2020/07/05/the-purity-posse-pursues-pinker/">trivial charges</a>, such as that he had twice used the terms “urban crime” and “urban violence,” they got hundreds of signatories to join a group denunciation.</p><p><strong>Secondary Boycotts</strong></p><p><em>Is there an explicit or implicit threat that people who support you will get the same punitive treatment that you are receiving? Are people putting pressure on employers and professional colleagues to fire you or stop associating with you? Do people who defend you, or criticize the campaign against you, have to fear adverse consequences?</em></p><p>With its commitments to exploring a wide range of ideas and correcting rather than coercing the errant, a critical culture sees no value in instilling a climate of fear. But instilling fear is what canceling is all about. By choosing targets unpredictably (almost anything can trigger a campaign), providing no safe harbors (even conformists can get hit), and implicitly threatening anyone who sides with those who are targeted, canceling sends the message: “you could be next.”</p><p>Thus, a canceled journalist was quickly dropped by his employer, his professional association and his publisher, becoming “<a href="https://reason.com/2019/08/23/im-radioactive/">radioactive</a>,” as he put it. (At last check, he was applying to law schools.) In the resulting climate, people will often join public denunciations or <a href="https://www.persuasion.community/p/stand-up-for-the-wrongly-accused-341">refrain from defending targets they believe to be innocent</a>, to avoid becoming controversial themselves.</p><p><strong>Moral Grandstanding</strong></p><p><em>Is the tone of the discourse ad hominem, repetitive, ritualistic, posturing, accusatory, outraged? Are people flattening distinctions, demonizing you, slinging inflammatory labels and engaging in moral one-upmanship? Are people ignoring what you actually say—talking about but not to you? </em></p><p>Precisely because speech can be hurtful, critical culture discourages extreme rhetoric. It encourages people to listen to each other, to use evidence and argumentation, to behave reasonably and to avoid personal attacks.</p><p>Cancel culture is much more invested in what philosophers Justin Tosi and Brandon Warmke call “<a href="https://global.oup.com/academic/product/grandstanding-9780190900151?cc=us&amp;lang=en&amp;">moral grandstanding</a>”: the display of moral outrage to impress one’s peer group, dominate others, or both. Grandstanders who condemn someone are not interested in persuading or correcting her; in fact, they are not really talking <em>to</em> her at all. Rather, they are using her as a convenient object in a campaign to elevate their own status. Pile-ons, personal attacks and bidding wars to show the most outrage are all ways of engaging in moral grandstanding.</p><p><strong>Truthiness</strong></p><p><em>Are the things being said about you inaccurate? Do the people saying them not even seem to care about their veracity? Do they feel at liberty to distort your words, ignore corrections and make false accusations?</em></p><p>Concern for accuracy is the north star of a critical culture. Not everyone gets every fact right, nor do people always agree on what is true; and yet people in a critical culture try to present their own and others’ viewpoints honestly and accurately. Though I may fail to live up to this standard in some cases, I recognize that I should address what you actually said, not an inflammatory caricature or some out-of-context quotation.</p><p>One of many reasons Donald Trump is a menace to democracy is that he views truth instrumentally, as something to use, abuse or ignore depending on the needs of the moment. He repeats discredited assertions <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2018/12/10/meet-bottomless-pinocchio-new-rating-false-claim-repeated-over-over-again/">again and again</a>—or shifts ground <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/trump-says-it-doesnt-really-matter-if-iranian-general-posed-an-imminent-threat/2020/01/13/c9f7ea1c-362e-11ea-9541-9107303481a4_story.html">to another</a> when one assertion is definitively debunked. Cancelers often play the same kind of <a href="https://www.persuasion.community/p/rhetorical-calvinball">rhetorical Calvinball</a>.</p><p>Cancelers’ characterizations of a paper by the philosopher Rebecca Tuvel, for example, were <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2017/05/transracialism-article-controversy.html">demonstrably incorrect</a>. The person who initiated the campaign even admitted to <a href="http://www.butterfliesandwheels.org/2017/can-we-get-this-person-fired/">not having read</a> the supposedly objectionable paper. “So little of what has been said … is based upon people actually reading what I wrote,” Tuvel <a href="http://dailynous.com/2017/05/01/philosophers-article-transracialism-sparks-controversy/">lamented</a> in a public statement. </p><p>But that did not stop anybody. For canceling is not about seeking truth or persuading others; it is a form of information warfare, in which <a href="http://www.cc.com/video-clips/63ite2/the-colbert-report-the-word---truthiness">truthiness</a> suffices if it serves the cause.</p><p>Those are my six warning signs. If you spot one or two, you should fear that a canceling may be happening; if you see five or six, you can be sure.</p><p>Obviously, mine is not the only approach. Other people, such as <a href="https://www.persuasion.community/p/a-taxonomy-of-fear">Emily Yoffe</a> and <a href="https://reason.com/2020/08/04/whats-the-best-way-to-protect-free-speech-ken-white-and-greg-lukianoff-debate-cancel-culture/">Greg Lukianoff</a>, have made their own attempts at characterizing the current climate of fear or defining cancel culture. Hopefully, many more suggestions and refinements will follow. </p><p>As with most other concepts, we might never come to a complete consensus about its best definition. Still, I predict …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.persuasion.community/p/the-cancel-culture-checklist">https://www.persuasion.community/p/the-cancel-culture-checklist</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.persuasion.community/p/the-cancel-culture-checklist</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24083055</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 15:40:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[UI/UX Best Practices for IdP and SP-Initiated Single Sign-On (SSO)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24083027">thread link</a>) | @grinich
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://workos.com/blog/ui-ux-best-practices-for-idp-and-sp-initiated-sso | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://workos.com/blog/ui-ux-best-practices-for-idp-and-sp-initiated-sso">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div><div><p>If you’ve used a web app in the last decade, you’ve probably signed in using <a href="https://workos.com/blog/the-developers-guide-to-sso">Single Sign-On (SSO)</a>. Clicked “Sign in with Twitter” or built an integration to allow users to sign in with Google? That’s SSO. SSO is a popular authentication mechanism that’s enabled application developers to register and sign in users easily, while allowing users to use a single service for their identity. Implementing SSO enables users to sign in using their Google credentials rather than remembering passwords for another service. </p><p>While SSO authentication lowers the barrier to entry to your product, it also presents new user experiences as you start to consider the actual mechanics of signing into your application. The SSO handshake involves validation between two parties - the Identity Provider (e.g. Okta) and the service provider (e.g. your app). Enterprise users now have two unique flows to sign into your application - via an Identity Provider (IdP) initiated flow or via a Service Provider (SP) initiated flow. &nbsp;</p></div><h2>IdP-initiated SSO</h2><div><p>SSO Identity Providers typically offer an application marketplace / dashboard that shows an enterprise user all of the applications they have access to. For example, Okta offers a browser extension that provides a quick way to see and sign in to the applications you have access to. IdP-initiated sign on is when an enterprise user clicks on your application from one of these places. The sign-on is initiated by the IdP provider, hence it’s called “IdP-initiated SSO.”</p></div><figure id="w-node-72914696f046-e13c3243"><p><img src="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5f03ef1d331a69193fae6dcd/5f2c523fead65f22b3c3b05a_SSO_Hero_Image-Desktop_Mobile.png" alt=""></p><figcaption>Your Okta application dashboard might look like this (<a href="https://www.okta.com/products/single-sign-on/">Source</a>)</figcaption></figure><p>A Service Provider cannot solely rely on IdP-initiated sign on for users to access their application. Some Identity Providers don’t support IdP-initiated sign on and some app developers don’t build in the ability to use IdP-initiated sign on. On the other hand, consider the user experience of enterprise users who come directly to your website wanting to use your application. Only allowing IdP-initiated SSO requires users to always go through their Identity Provider dashboard, something users may forget. <br></p><h2>SP-initiated SSO</h2><p>Service Provider initiated sign on is when an enterprise user signs in by visiting an application’s website directly. If you decide to allow your enterprise users to sign in to your application from your own website, you have a few UX options, but one aspect is absolutely crucial no matter what you chose to do: <em>you must obtain an enterprise user’s domain</em>. The domain is used to map the user to the enterprise - without it, how will you know which user belongs to which enterprise? There's a few different approaches to Service Provider initiated sign on that we commonly see utilized by applications:<br></p><ul role="list"><li>Subdomaining tenants</li><li>Signing in with SSO</li><li>Separating the email and password fields</li><li>Dynamic password fields <br></li></ul><h3>Subdomain your tenants</h3><p>One approach you can take would be to serve your application at a subdomain per tenant / enterprise. Slack is one web application that does this. When you visit <a href="https://slack.com/">slack.com</a> and click on the Sign In button, you’re taken to this page:<br></p><figure><p><img src="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5f03ef1d331a69193fae6dcd/5f2c5283468662a73c040719_image%20(7).png" alt=""></p></figure><p>If we consider WorkOS here, a WorkOS employee would enter <strong><em>workos</em></strong> into the input, Slack looks up what sign in options are allowed for <strong><em>workos</em></strong>, and on the next page offers the user the various methods their organization may use for signing in.<br></p><figure><p><img src="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5f03ef1d331a69193fae6dcd/5f2c52a7ead65f409ac413a7_Screen%20Shot%202020-08-04%20at%201.09.57%20PM.png" alt=""></p></figure><h3>Sign in with SSO</h3><p>A second approach would be to put a link or button on your login page for <strong><em>Sign in with SSO</em></strong>. One thing to remember is the <a href="https://indieweb.org/NASCAR_problem">NASCAR Problem</a> - where a cluster of 3rd party branded buttons creates both visual noise and confusion on behalf of the user.<br></p><figure id="w-node-3086f52aa857-e13c3243"><p><img src="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5f03ef1d331a69193fae6dcd/5f2c52c519f125323b9f5a1a_0_4fYlCDFKodWOMQlX.png" alt=""></p><figcaption>That’s a lot of login buttons! (<a href="https://medium.com/code-oil/oauth-introduction-for-busy-managers-engineers-d9d792504888">Source</a>) </figcaption></figure><p>Cypress takes this approach, but is careful to only offer a couple of sign in options that are relevant to their user base:<br></p><figure id="w-node-df6971397a76-e13c3243"><p><img src="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5f03ef1d331a69193fae6dcd/5f2c710a9c652c0f3c9af534_image%20(8).png" alt=""></p></figure><p>Clicking the Single Sign-On link takes you here:<br></p><figure id="w-node-9d11dcad3940-e13c3243"><p><img src="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5f03ef1d331a69193fae6dcd/5f2c71b0260f332d32d30720_image%20(9).png" alt=""></p></figure><h3>Separate email / password fields</h3><p>Take a look at the initial login screens of two of the world’s largest tech companies. Notice anything missing?<br></p><figure id="w-node-d7f7ce9329f4-e13c3243"><p><img src="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5f03ef1d331a69193fae6dcd/5f2c72843b75e571dba65898_image%20(10).png" alt=""></p><figcaption>Where is the password field?</figcaption></figure><p>They separate the login process into multiple steps or pages. When signing into Apple’s developer portal, it first asks only for your email then your password, because between the steps, Apple is doing a lookup to see if your domain is SSO-enabled. If it is SSO-enabled, instead of showing your password, it will take you though the SSO flow instead. Here at WorkOS, we even use it for our login page.<br></p><figure id="w-node-ecfa60f44263-e13c3243"><p><img src="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5f03ef1d331a69193fae6dcd/5f2c72a49fd1df81c7694b71_Screen%20Shot%202020-08-03%20at%2012.56.18%20PM.png" alt=""></p></figure><h3>Dynamically hide the password field<br></h3><p>An extension to the previous approach is dynamically hiding the password field - but only for domains which have SSO enabled. This is a bit more complicated to implement, but it provides a nicer and more “unified” user experience. An example of this style is implemented on the Dropbox login form. <br></p><figure><p><img src="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5f03ef1d331a69193fae6dcd/5f2c72b88e63c617c8e4154e_ezgif.com-gif-maker.gif" alt=""></p><figcaption>Disclaimer: Please, don’t try to hack into Marc’s Dropbox account because you see this gif. </figcaption></figure><div><p>Dropbox has implemented SSO, but that’s not immediately apparent from their login screen. As a user, for example <strong><em><a href="https://workos.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection" data-cfemail="5d303c2f3e1d2e3c31382e3b322f3e38733e3230">[email&nbsp;protected]</a></em></strong>, types their email into the respective field,&nbsp;a search is being executed on the backend on every keypress to check if a matching SSO-enabled domain exists. Once a match is found, the password experience is replaced with the <strong><em>Single sign-on enabled</em></strong> flow. Now, the user just clicks <strong><em>Continue</em></strong> to sign in.</p><p>In our opinion, this is the smoothest SSO UI/UX, but again, we understand it’s more work to implement and test.</p></div><h2>The SSO journey doesn’t end here</h2><div><p>Adding SSO doesn’t mean you can get rid of usernames and passwords altogether. Users without SSO-based login still need some way to access your product. Even with SSO-enabled accounts, admin users need to be able to <a href="https://developer.okta.com/docs/concepts/saml/#implementing-a-backdoor">login using username / password</a> so they can configure SSO for all users or get into the system in the event SSO isn’t working. </p><p>Your login page is the gate to your application, and it’s important to make it a polished experienced. A third-party service like <a href="https://workos.com/features/sso">WorkOS</a> can help you build it faster so you can focus on the details.</p></div></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://workos.com/blog/ui-ux-best-practices-for-idp-and-sp-initiated-sso</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24083027</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 15:37:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A T Cell Army against SARS-CoV-2]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 68 | Comments 28 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24082327">thread link</a>) | @karmel
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://www.hellovirology.com/2020/08/a-t-cell-army-against-sars-cov-2.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.hellovirology.com/2020/08/a-t-cell-army-against-sars-cov-2.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<div id="post-body-3178459137750369132">



<p>
We have talked a fair <a href="https://www.hellovirology.com/2020/07/what-is-mrna-vaccine.html">amount</a> <a href="https://www.hellovirology.com/2020/07/antibody-hope-in-sars-cov-2.html">about</a> antibodies, and much of the SARS-CoV-2 discussion is focused on antibodies as indicators, treatments, or vaccines. However, antibodies produced by B-cells are only one part of the larger immune picture, albeit one of the most accessible parts. To develop a comprehensive treatment strategy for SARS-CoV-2, we will likely need to understand how the broader network of immune cells responds to the virus. Today, we’ll take a closer look at the T cell response to SARS-CoV-2 infection, and what it says about long-term immunity.
</p>
<h3>A robust T cell response</h3>


<p>
A brief refresher: T cells, <a href="https://www.hellovirology.com/2020/06/adaptive-immune-cells.html">you may remember</a>, are adaptive immune cells. Each T cell has a unique T cell receptor that recognizes a different set of foreign peptides, and if a T cell’s receptor is activated, that T cell clones itself and produces an army of similar T cells capable of fighting off the invader that was recognized. T cells come in several varieties, the two most prominent of which are CD4+ T cells and CD8+ T cells. CD4+ T cells are responsible for surveying peptides (that is, short protein fragments) presented by antigen-presenting cells like B cells and macrophages and starting a signaling cascade that activates the rest of the immune system, and are thus referred to as “helper” T cells. CD8+ T cells survey peptides presented by normal tissue cells throughout the body, and, if they recognize one of the presented peptides as foreign, they kill the cell under the assumption that it has been infected. CD8+ T cells are thus called “killer” T cells.</p><p><img height="441" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/VHihcE0ie5EooWOw2mc8MzfuYgaOlru5R7lLNl22U_DTENRS9eBrKdPNZd1a0q609Hhyl7WZLuQpw8lVU3fO2ZsWAYwdT_anu_JpkUAMOyP1IkBQ_TGsvrYS4geTdOtRC1TVjQLU=w499-h441" width="499"></p><p>Given these critical roles in immune system activation, scientists are studying the extent to which CD4+ and CD8+ T cells recognize peptides from SARS-CoV-2. In <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-020-2550-z">one recent paper</a>, Grifoni et al. created pools of peptides that tile the entire set of proteins that make up SARS-CoV-2. In one pool, they created a peptide for every set of 15 amino acids from the Spike protein, tiled such that each length-15 chain overlapped by ten amino acids with the next peptide in the pool. In another pool, they computationally predicted which peptides would be efficiently held by antigen presenting cells like macrophages, and made peptides that covered the rest of the SARS-CoV-2 proteins. A similar pool was made for the peptides predicted to be efficiently held in the MHC class I molecules that CD8+ T cells recognize.</p> <p><img height="250" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/zUoM8PrduU9w1Tw6QW9QYVvR_PE7ctTnUvJyqoBkLcEO6jqFuuZwkc97g5hStxr7hNOl4ceN3bcB4PBHx0GrHLioF1cOAWLW9-eK3K7Xk6U_rw-ZTmx9oj5FiyisoABi1VRZ7fYv" width="241"></p><p>
Scientists regularly create overlapping peptides that tile proteins of interest when studying which pieces of a protein immune cells recognize. This is a generic example showing overlap strategies from Mimotopes.com, a company that creates and sells custom peptides.
</p>
<p>
To test out the effects of these peptide pools, the researchers collected blood from patients who tested positive for COVID-19 but were not hospitalized, 20 - 35 days after symptom onset. The researchers extracted the Peripheral Mononuclear Blood Cells (PBMCs) from the blood, as these include circulating T cells and other immune cells, and then ran a series of experiments to see how the T cells responded to the peptide pools. The number of patients was small (20 patients exposed to SARS-CoV-2, and 20 unexposed controls), but even so, the results were consistent: all recovered COVID-19 patients showed evidence of a robust T cell response to SARS-CoV-2 peptides. 100% of patients had CD4+ T cells that recognized and became activated in response to peptides from the Spike pool as well as peptides from the non-Spike peptide pool. These activated cells were able to produce inflammatory cytokines (immune signaling molecules) and to quickly clone themselves. The response of the patients’ CD8+ T cells was less universal, but still robust: 70% of patients had CD8+ T cells that were activated in response to the SARS-CoV-2 peptide pools. 
</p>
<h3>Memories of infections past</h3>


<p>
What does this T cell response mean? For starters, it indicates that recovered COVID-19 patients have a stronghold of “memory” T cells— T cells that have seen SARS-CoV-2 and learned its patterns so that they are ready to respond more quickly in the future. It’s unclear whether these T cells are able to confer long-term immunity for the patients, but there is some evidence that they might: another paper published by <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-020-2550-z">Le Bert et al.</a> ran a similar set of peptide/T cell experiments, but they were able to include a set of long-recovered SARS-CoV-1 patients. They found that even after 17 years, these patients had T cells that were able to quickly respond to both SARS-CoV-1 and SARS-CoV-2 peptides, which gives us hope that T cell memory of SARS-CoV-2 will be similarly long-lived.
</p>
<p>
These cross-reactive T cells were not limited to SARS-CoV-1 patients, either. Both Grifoni et al. and Le Bert et al. used PBMCs drawn from donors without any exposure to COVID as controls, but these unexposed controls proved more interesting than the “zero baseline” we might have expected, as up to 50% of the unexposed controls showed some degree of reactivity to peptides from SARS-CoV-2, though these reactions were skewed toward the non-spike peptide pools. The researchers reason this is likely due to previous exposure to coronaviruses that cause common colds, and indeed, all unexposed controls had antibodies for two common coronaviruses, HCoV-OC43 and HCoV-NL63. If true, this cross-reactivity between common cold coronaviruses and SARS-CoV-2 could explain some of the variability in severity of COVID-19 across different people; some immune systems may already be primed to react to SARS-CoV-2 by prior infections. Further, given that the cross-reactive responses were more pronounced for non-spike proteins, this finding lends support to the idea that we should have a multi-target approach to vaccination and treatment, rather than a Spike-only approach.
</p>
<p>
(We should pause for a moment here to address a nagging question: wait, if even the unexposed controls showed responses to SARS-CoV-2 peptides, how do we know any of these responses are real? Isn’t the whole idea of a control to give a baseline to compare to? There are several reasons to believe these results are legitimate: peptide assays are fairly robust in immunological studies; the amplitude and targets of the control response are distinct from the COVID-19-exposed response; and multiple studies from multiple labs found the same results with the same peculiarities. That said, the sample size is very small, and the lack of a non-reactive control should always be concerning, so more studies in this area should be conducted before we draw any strong conclusions here.)
</p>

<p>
COVID-19-exposed cells (top row) showed a robust response to a number of SARS-CoV-2 targets, but the unexposed controls also showed some responsiveness, especially among lesser-known viral peptides.
</p>
<h3>Reading the T leaves</h3>


<p>
Taken all together, these T cell experiments demonstrate that, well, T cells matter, too. A robust immune response requires many cells, and the evidence of consistent T cell activation in recovered patients indicates that T cells play an important role in the natural clearance of the virus. It stands to reason, then, that an effective vaccination strategy will likely have to consider how and when to activate T cells. These studies identify a number of distinct peptides that activate T cells across patients, and could therefore be used along with antibodies as part of a vaccination strategy.
</p>
<h3 id="sources">Sources</h3>


<ul>

<li>Image 1: <a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Figure_42_02_04.png">https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Figure_42_02_04.png</a>

</li><li>Image 2: Product image from <a href="http://www.mimotopes.com/peptideLibraryScreening.asp?id=90">http://www.mimotopes.com/peptideLibraryScreening.asp?id=90</a> , which sells peptide services

</li><li>Image 3: Figure 6B and 6C from Grifoni et al.

</li><li><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7289747/">Vaccination strategies to combat novel corona virus SARS-CoV-2</a>

</li><li>Grifoni et al: <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0092867420306103">Targets of T Cell Responses to SARS-CoV-2 Coronavirus in Humans with COVID-19 Disease and Unexposed Individuals</a> 

</li><li>Le Bert et al: <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-020-2550-z">SARS-CoV-2-specific T cell immunity in cases of COVID-19 and SARS, and uninfected controls</a> </li></ul>
</div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.hellovirology.com/2020/08/a-t-cell-army-against-sars-cov-2.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24082327</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 14:38:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[JuliaCon2020: Julia Is Production Ready]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 185 | Comments 97 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24082281">thread link</a>) | @ViralBShah
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://bkamins.github.io/julialang/2020/08/07/production-ready.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bkamins.github.io/julialang/2020/08/07/production-ready.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    

<p>Last time I have <a href="https://bkamins.github.io/julialang/2020/08/02/post_juliacon_1.html">posted</a> about the take-aways for DataFrames.jl from
<a href="https://juliacon.org/2020/">JuliaCon 2020</a>. This time I wanted to share my general conclusions
from attending different talks at this extremely successful event.</p>

<p>I have spent 20 years now deploying data science related projects in corporate
environments (back then it was not called data science, but we were already
training neural networks to make predictions) and have many colleagues who are
deeply into enterprise software development. Quoting a discussion with
Tomasz Olczak I had some time ago, who is a genuine one-man army in
delivering complex enterprise projects:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Julia is fast, and has a very nice syntax, but its ecosystem is not mature
enough for use in serious production projects.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>For many years I would agree with it, but after <a href="https://juliacon.org/2020/">JuliaCon 2020</a>
I believe we can confidently announce that</p>

<p>
  <b><i>Julia is production ready!</i></b>
</p>

<p>Let me now give a list of key (in my opinion) presentations given during
<a href="https://juliacon.org/2020/">JuliaCon 2020</a> that make me draw this conclusion.</p>

<p>I will not comment here on functionalities related to number crunching, as it
is clear that Julia shines here, but rather I want to focus on the things that
make Julia a great tool for deployment in production (still I skip many
interesting talks in this area — check out the detailed <a href="https://live.juliacon.org/agenda/">agenda</a> to
learn more).</p>



<p>In <a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/Y3H7FG">this talk</a> <a href="https://github.com/quinnj">Jacob Quinn</a> gives an end to end tutorial how
to build and deploy in an enterprise setting a microservice using Julia.
He gives ready recipes how to solve typical tasks that need to be handled in
such contexts: logging, context management, middleware setup, authentication,
caching, connection pooling, dockerization, and many other, that
are bread and butter of enterprise projects.</p>

<p>As an addition be sure to check out:</p>

<ul>
  <li>the <a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/Z8TE39">shippable apps</a> talk, where <a href="https://github.com/KristofferC">Kristoffer Carlsson</a> guides you
through creating executables which can be run on machines that do not have Julia
installed.</li>
  <li>the <a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/N39HSX">Julia for scripting</a> presentation, during which
<a href="https://github.com/fredrikekre">Fredrik Ekre</a> discusses the best practices for using Julia in contexts
where you need to execute short code snippets many times.</li>
  <li>the <a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/DTLBM9">Genie.jl</a> talk, in which <a href="https://github.com/essenciary">Adrian Salceanu</a> shows that it is currently
a mature, stable, performant, and feature-rich Julia web development framework.</li>
</ul>



<p>The two talks <a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/PLFURQ">Pkg.update()</a> and <a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/RXAN8F">What’s new in Pkg</a> show that
currently Julia has best in class functionalities for enterprise grade dependency
management for your projects. The list of provided functionalities is so long
that it is hard to list them all here.</p>

<p>Let me just mention one particular tool in this ecosystem, that is presented in
<a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/9WMAVU">BinaryBuilder.jl</a> talk that explains how to take software written in compiled
languages such as C, C++, Fortran, Go or Rust, and build precompiled artifacts
that can be used from Julia packages with ease (which means that no compilation
has to take place on client side when you install packages having such dependencies).</p>



<p>A natural topic related to dependency management is how to integrate Julia with
external tools. This area of functionality is really mature. Here is a list of
talks that cover this topic:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/7MALUA">Make your Julia code faster and compatible with non-Julia code</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/NNVQQF">Wrapping a C++ library using CxxWrap.jl</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/XGHSWW">Julia and C++: a technical overview of CxxWrap.jl</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/Y7ERM9">Introducing the @ccall macro</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/PHGCKB">Integrating Julia in R with the JuliaConnectoR</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/Q88P8U">Integrate Julia and Javascript using Node.js extensions</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Here it is worth to add Julia has had a great integration with Python for many
years now, see <a href="https://github.com/JuliaPy">JuliaPy</a>.</p>

<p>A good end to end example of doing some real work in Julia that requires integration
is <a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/KK9S9V">Creating a multichannel wireless speaker setup with Julia</a>
talk that show how to easily stitch things together (and in particular featuring
ZMQ.jl, Opus.jl, PortAudio.jl, and DSP.jl).</p>

<p>Another interesting talk showcasing integration capabilities is
<a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/GFE3DB">JSServe: Websites &amp; Dashboards in Julia</a>
that shows a high performance framework to easily combine interactive plots,
markdown, widgets and plain HTML/Javascript in Jupyter / Atom / Nextjournal and
on websites.</p>



<p>The two great talks <a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/DWCJUK">Juno 1.0</a> and <a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/HBTFT7">Using VS Code</a> that current IDE
support for Julia in VS Code is first class. You have all tools that normally you
would expect to get: code analysis (static and dynamic), debugger, workspaces,
integration with Jupyter Notebooks, and remote capabilities.</p>



<p>I do not want to cover many different ML algorithms that are available in Julia
natively, as there are just too many of them (and if something is missing you
can easily integrate it — see the integration capabilities section above).</p>

<p>However, on top of particular models you need frameworks that let you manage
ML workflows. In this area there are two interesting talks, one about
<a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/DMHZCC">MLJ: a machine learning toolbox for Julia</a> and the other showing
<a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/AD7TQW">AutoMLPipeline: A ToolBox for Building ML Pipelines</a>. From my experience
such tools are crucial when you want to move with your ML models from data scientist’s
sandbox to a real production usage.</p>



<p>Obviously, I have omitted many interesting things that were shown during
<a href="https://juliacon.org/2020/">JuliaCon 2020</a>. However, I hope that the aspects I have covered here,
that is:</p>

<ul>
  <li>enterprise grade patterns to create microservices and applications in Julia,</li>
  <li>robust dependency management tools,</li>
  <li>very flexible and powerful capabilities to integrate Julia with existing code
bases that were not written in Julia,</li>
  <li>excellent developer tooling in VSCode,</li>
  <li>mature packages that help you to create production-grade code for ML solutions
deployment,</li>
</ul>

<p>show that already now Julia can (and should) be considered as a serious option
for your next project in enterprise environment.</p>

<p>What I believe is crucially important is that not only we have required tools
ready but also we have great practical showcases how they can be used to build
robust production code with.</p>


  </div>
</article>

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bkamins.github.io/julialang/2020/08/07/production-ready.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24082281</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 14:32:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Self-Contained Development Environments (2018) [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 63 | Comments 24 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24082194">thread link</a>) | @tosh
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://charig.github.io/assets/papers/SCDE-DLS.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://charig.github.io/assets/papers/SCDE-DLS.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://charig.github.io/assets/papers/SCDE-DLS.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24082194</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 14:25:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Secure Coding Done Right]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24081878">thread link</a>) | @plastic_teeth
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://www.securecoding.com/secure-coding-done-right/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.securecoding.com/secure-coding-done-right/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section id="b-text-1">
	<div>
		<div>
		<p><span>Security is one of the most important aspects of software development. Gone are the days when companies focused on the amount of code developers produce. Nowadays, they care about the quality and security of your code.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></p>

<p><span>The increasing number of</span><a href="https://selfkey.org/data-breaches-in-2019/"> <span>security breaches over the past years</span></a><span> is alarming. Too often, we hear scary stories about how millions of people’s personal information and financial records were exposed following a data breach. With this trend, every developer should focus on building more secure systems.</span></p>

<p><span>In this article, I will put together a list of practices that, in my view, offer a solid foundation for building more secure applications. Having worked with hundreds of developers in multiple companies for the past few decades, I’ve had the privilege to interact and learn a great deal from various development professionals.</span></p>

<p><span>So, here are my ground rules for writing more secure code.&nbsp;</span></p>

<h2><b>Secure By Design</b></h2>

<p><span>Writing</span><a href="http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.228.5794&amp;rep=rep1&amp;type=pdf#page=70"> <span>clean and secure code</span></a><span> begins long before creating the first class or forming the first loop. When designing systems, I see some architects focusing more on the functional requirements but sidelining the security side of things. They tend to assume that access controls and other security measures will be implemented later in the development stage.</span></p>

<p><span>This is wrong. Instead, development teams should embrace the</span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_by_design"> <span>secure by design</span></a><span> concept during application development.</span></p>

<p><span>During the design stage, prepare a list of technical and regulatory security requirements for your project. Think of every component that will be used in application development, from the class-level language to API endpoint authorization.</span></p>

<p><span>Having security in mind right from project inception is the best way to eliminate weaknesses inherent in the architecture of a product. Furthermore, it becomes harder to implement security controls or address vulnerabilities as the system develops.&nbsp;</span></p>

<p><span>The most effective approach is enforcing security controls right from the design stage.</span></p>

<h2><b>Model Threats to Your Code</b></h2>

<p><span>Threat modeling is a cost-effective approach to implementing security in the application design phase. It involves identifying potential threats to software, analyzing their risks, and developing mitigations strategies to be implemented in the design, coding, and testing stages.</span></p>

<p><span>By modeling threats to your code, you can anticipate the kind of threats that may affect your application way before coding begins. For instance, if you deal with credit card numbers, personally identifiable information, or intellectual property, it will be easier to identify possible security risks and devise ways of protecting your application.</span></p>

<p><span>If you can imagine an attack on your code, you can keep the threat in mind when designing and implementing the system.</span></p>

<h2><b>Don’t Trust User Data</b></h2>

<p><span>If you look at the vast majority of software vulnerabilities, you will realize they share a common trait in that they stem from</span><a href="https://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/20.html"> <span>improper input validation</span></a><span>. Think of SQL injections, cross-site scripting, LDAP injections, xPath injections, buffer overflow, uncontrolled string format, and other common security gaps.</span></p>
<p><span>So, I’ll insist on this – always treat all input as untrusted until proven otherwise. Sometimes being skeptical pays. As long as the data is coming from an external source, there’s every reason to verify it.&nbsp; This should be done regardless of whether the input comes from environment variables, network interfaces, command line arguments, or user controlled files.</span></p>

<p><span>When developing a PHP application, for instance, you need to validate several elements. Here is an example class you can call to validate user input from your forms.</span></p>



	</div>
	</div>
</section><section id="b-text-2">
	<div>
		<div>
		<h2><span>the</span><span> Principle </span><span>o</span><span>f Least Privilege</span></h2>
<div>
<p><span>Some developers give users access to all features and permissions they might need to avoid restructuring their code in the future. This leaves a pathway that attackers can abuse upon getting their hands on your system.</span></p>

<p><span>A good practice is to limit privileges by giving each account the appropriate</span> <span>(least)</span><span> amount of privilege. Access within applications should be designed in a way that attackers are denied most functionalities.&nbsp;</span></p>

<p><span>Ideally, base your access controls on permission as opposed to exclusion. In doing this, access is denied by default so that the protection scheme will determine the conditions under which access is granted.</span></p>


<h2><span>Sanitize Data Sent </span><span>to</span><span> Other Systems</span></h2>
</div>
<p>Data passed to an output subsystem may contain malicious content, especially if it originates from an untrusted source. If not escaped or sanitized properly, this data can be used to facilitate injection attacks. For this reason, output sanitization as vital as proper input validation to prevent attacks.</p>
<div>

<p><span>To prevent attackers from taking advantage of unused functionality in output data, always sanitize the data before invoking another system component. &nbsp;</span></p>

<p><span>The only code that can identify malicious characters is the code responsible for output in a given context. This is where you should add a contextual escaping functionality before displaying data to the user.</span></p>

<p><span>For instance, when building SQL, you can use parameterized query features to ensure proper escaping:</span></p>

</div>




<p><span>Below is a simple non-compliant code that uses the </span><span><a href="https://www.javatpoint.com/spring-mvc-tutorial" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener" data-target-href="https://www.javatpoint.com/spring-mvc-tutorial">Java MVC concept</a></span><span> to display data to users without escaping or encoding it. The code below sends data to a web browser, which means it is subject to XSS and HTML injection attacks.</span></p>




	</div>
	</div>
</section><section id="b-text-3">
	<div>
		<div>
		<p><span>To fix this, I can create a ValidateOutput class that will normalize the output and sanitize it using a whitelist. Note that you can use a different whitelisting pattern depending on your output fields.</span></p>



<h2><b>Adopt Secure Coding Standards</b></h2>

<p><span>Every developer has been in at least one lecture about</span><a href="https://owasp.org/www-community/How_to_write_insecure_code"> <span>secure coding practices</span></a><span>. It might get boring, but it’s important to safeguard your code.&nbsp;</span></p>

<p><span>Some secure coding standards you should follow at every stage of the application development process include:</span></p>

<ul>
<li><span>Avoid using language functions and other components with known security vulnerabilities.</span></li>
<li><span>Use proper encyprion techniques to protect user data.</span></li>
<li><span>Avoid revealing internal implementation through error messages.</span></li>
<li><span>Do not implement your own authentication and authorization system. Instead, consider adding an extra security layer through 2-factor authentication.</span></li>
<li><span>Effective monitoring and logging of user activity.</span></li>
<li><span>Scan and analyze your codebase for dependency vulnerabilities.</span></li>
<li><span>Stay on top of security releases.</span></li>
<li><span>Perform quality assurance checks through rigorous testing and source code audits.</span></li>
<li><span>Integrate the right security tools in your IDE, source repository, bug tracking systems, and other environments used during development.</span></li>
<li><span>Make necessary security documentation.</span></li>
</ul>

<h2><b>Wrap Up</b></h2>

<p><span>Code security is the ultimate measure of code quality, and it’s not hard to achieve. I’ve seen most of my colleagues complicate stuff by overthinking secure designs. At the end, they have a strangely complex system that’s even harder to secure.</span></p>

<p><span>The best approach is keeping your designs as simple as you possible. This way, you can understand and prove the security of your system.</span></p>

<p><span>Embrace the above practices as you write your code. It’s a sure way of contributing to a safer world today.</span></p>


	</div>
	</div>
</section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.securecoding.com/secure-coding-done-right/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24081878</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 14:00:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[On the Performance of User-Mode Threads and Coroutines]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 142 | Comments 52 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24081713">thread link</a>) | @carimura
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://inside.java/2020/08/07/loomperformance/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://inside.java/2020/08/07/loomperformance/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://inside.java/2020/08/07/loomperformance/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24081713</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 13:46:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Surprising Economics of Load-Balanced Systems]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 49 | Comments 6 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24081681">thread link</a>) | @MindGods
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | http://brooker.co.za/blog/2020/08/06/erlang.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://brooker.co.za/blog/2020/08/06/erlang.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="post">


<p>The M/M/c model may not behave like you expect.</p>


<p>I have a system with <code>c</code> servers, each of which can only handle a single concurrent request, and has no internal queuing. The servers sit behind a load balancer, which contains an infinite queue. An unlimited number of clients offer <code>c * 0.8</code> requests per second to the load balancer on average. In other words, we increase the offered load linearly with <code>c</code> to keep the per-server load constant. Once a request arrives at a server, it takes one second to process, on average. How does the client-observed mean request time vary with <code>c</code>?</p>

<p><img src="https://mbrooker-blog-images.s3.amazonaws.com/erlang_c_plot.png" alt=""></p>

<p>Option A is that the mean latency decreases quickly, asymptotically approaching one second as <code>c</code> increases (in other words, the time spent in queue approaches zero). Option B is constant. Option C is a linear improvement, and D is a linear degradation in latency. Which curve do you, intuitively, think that the latency will follow?</p>

<p>I asked my Twitter followers the same question, and got an interestingly mixed result:
<img src="https://mbrooker-blog-images.s3.amazonaws.com/erlang_twitter_poll.png" alt=""></p>

<p>Breaking down the problem a bit will help figure out which is the right answer. First, names. In the terminology of queue theory, this is an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/M/M/c_queue">M/M/c</a> queuing system: Poisson arrival process, exponentially distributed client service time, and <code>c</code> backend servers. In teletraffic engineering, it's <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Agner_Krarup_Erlang">Erlang's</a> delay system (or, because terminology is fun, M/M/n). We can use a classic result of queuing theory to analyze this system: Erlang's C formula <em>E<sub>2,n</sub>(A)</em>, which calculates the probability that an incoming customer request is enqueued (rather than handled immediately), based on the number of servers (<code>n</code> aka <code>c</code>), and the offered traffic <code>A</code>. For the details, see page 194 of the <a href="https://www.itu.int/dms_pub/itu-d/opb/stg/D-STG-SG02.16.1-2001-PDF-E.pdf">Teletraffic Engineering Handbook</a>. Here's the basic shape of the curve (using our same parameters):</p>

<p><img src="https://mbrooker-blog-images.s3.amazonaws.com/erlang_c_result.png" alt=""></p>

<p>Follow the blue line up to half the saturation point, at 2.5 rps offered load, and see how the probability is around 13%. Now look at the purple line at half its saturation point, at 5 rps. Just 3.6%. So at half load the 5-server system is handling 87% of traffic without queuing, with double the load and double the servers, we handle 96.4% without queuing. Which means only 3.6% see any additional latency.</p>

<p>It turns out this improvement is, indeed, asymptotically approaching 1. The right answer to the Twitter poll is A.</p>

<p>Using the mean to measure latency is controversial (although <a href="http://brooker.co.za/blog/2017/12/28/mean.html">perhaps it shouldn't be</a>). To avoid that controversy, we need to know whether the percentiles get better at the same rate. Doing that in closed form is somewhat complicated, but this system is super simple, so we can plot them out using a Monte-Carlo simulation. The results look like this:</p>

<p><img src="https://mbrooker-blog-images.s3.amazonaws.com/sim_result.png" alt=""></p>

<p>That's entirely good news. The median (p50) follows the mean line nicely, and the high percentiles (99<sup>th</sup> and 99.9<sup>th</sup>) have a similar shape. No hidden problems.</p>

<p>It's also good news for cloud and service economics. With larger <code>c</code> we get better latency at the same utilization, or better utilization for the same latency, all at the same per-server throughput. That's not good news only for giant services, because most of this goodness happens at relatively modest <code>c</code>. There are few problems related to scale and distributed systems that get easier as <code>c</code> increases. This is one of them.</p>

<p>There are some reasonable follow-up questions. Are the results robust to our arbitrary choice of 0.8? Yes, they are<sup><a href="#foot1">1</a></sup>. Are the M/M/c assumptions of Poisson arrivals and exponential service time reasonable for typical services? I'd say they are reasonable, albeit wrong. Exponential service time is especially wrong: realistic services tend to be something more like log-normal. It may not matter. More on that another time.</p>

<p><em>Update:</em> Dan Ports responded to my thread with a fascinating <a href="https://twitter.com/danrkports/status/1291517540280070144">Twitter thread</a> pointing to <a href="https://drkp.net/papers/latency-socc14.pdf">Tales of the Tail: Hardware, OS, and Application-level Sources of Tail Latency</a> from SoCC'14 which looks at this effect in the wild.</p>

<p><strong>Footnotes</strong></p>

<ol>
<li><a name="foot1"></a> Up to a point. As soon as the mean arrival rate exceeds the system's ability to complete requests, the queue grows without bound and latency goes to infinity. In our case, that happens when the request load exceeds <code>c</code>. More generally, for this system to be stable <code>λ/cμ</code> must be less than 1, where <code>λ</code> is the mean arrival rate, and <code>μ</code> is the mean time taken for a server to process a request.</li>
</ol>


</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://brooker.co.za/blog/2020/08/06/erlang.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24081681</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 13:43:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Devsheets – Quickly find the cheatsheets for everything tech]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24081374">thread link</a>) | @mkfeuhrer
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://mohitkhare.me/devsheets/#/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://mohitkhare.me/devsheets/#/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://mohitkhare.me/devsheets/#/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24081374</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 13:09:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Docker install and upgrade guide – CentOS and Ubuntu]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 15 | Comments 6 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24081171">thread link</a>) | @lukasbar
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://knowledgepill.it/posts/docker-install-upgrade/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://knowledgepill.it/posts/docker-install-upgrade/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p>Install and upgrade of Docker Engine is simple and straightforward process.</p>
<p>In this post I will cover all important information in one place.</p>
<h2 id="docker-install-requirements">Docker install requirements</h2>
<p>Minimum requirements</p>
<ul>
<li>8GB RAM per manager node</li>
<li>4GB RAM per worker node</li>
<li>3GB of free disk space</li>
</ul>
<p>Recommended production requirements</p>
<ul>
<li>16GB RAM per manager node</li>
<li>4 vCPUs per manager node</li>
<li>25-100GB of free disk space on each node</li>
</ul>
<p>Also you must have one of the following OS:</p>
<ul>
<li>CentOS 7.1+ 64 bit version</li>
<li>Ubuntu 16.04/18.04/19.10 64 bit versions</li>
</ul>
<p>Preferable storage driver on newer OS is <code>overlay2</code>.<br>
Docker engine will set it by default.</p>
<p>If you want to get to know what is storage driver, what storage drivers are advised on certain OS and how to change it or looking for detailed info about setup of devicemapper, look at:</p>
<p><a href="https://knowledgepill.it/posts/docker_storage_drivers/">Docker storage driver - guide </a><br>
<a href="https://knowledgepill.it/posts/docker_configure_devicemapper/">Docker devicemapper - setup</a></p>
<hr>
<h4 id="important">Important</h4>
<p>If you plan to use Docker Enterprise with multiple nodes or Swarm - remember to set up time synchro between nodes - use NTP for that.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="docker-install-centos">Docker install CentOS</h2>
<ul>
<li>Ensure that <code>centos-extras</code> repo is enabled</li>
<li>Install <code>yum-utils</code>:</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Add repo</li>
</ul>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">yum-config-manager <span>\
</span><span></span>  --add-repo <span>\
</span><span></span>  https://download.docker.com/linux/centos/docker-ce.repo
</code></pre></div><ul>
<li>Install docker engine(Valid GPG Key: <code>060A 61C5 1B55 8A7F 742B 77AA C52F EB6B 621E 9F35</code>)</li>
</ul>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">yum install docker-ce docker-ce-cli containerd.io
</code></pre></div><p>CentOS 8 at day of writing this post has problem with dependiences for containerd.io - you can solve this by installing manually correct version of containerd.io before running <code>docker-ce</code> instalation command. Example</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">yum install https://download.docker.com/linux/centos/7/x86_64/stable/Packages/containerd.io-1.2.6-3.3.el7.x86_64.rpm
</code></pre></div><ul>
<li>Start and enable autostart of daemon:</li>
</ul>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">systemctl start docker
systemctl enable docker
</code></pre></div><p>Optionally you can list available versions of docker and install preferable one:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">yum list docker-ce --showduplicates | sort -r
</code></pre></div><div><pre><code data-lang="bash"> yum install docker-ce-&lt;VERSION_STRING&gt; docker-ce-cli-&lt;VERSION_STRING&gt; containerd.io
</code></pre></div><hr>
<p>For installing Docker Enterprise Edition you have to set up repo on your OS after getting from <a href="https://hub.docker.com/my-content">Docker Hub Account</a> Docker EE Repo Adress.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="docker-install-ubuntu">Docker install Ubuntu</h2>
<ul>
<li>Update system and install important packages</li>
</ul>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">apt-get update

apt-get install <span>\
</span><span></span>   apt-transport-https <span>\
</span><span></span>   ca-certificates <span>\
</span><span></span>   curl <span>\
</span><span></span>   gnupg-agent <span>\
</span><span></span>   software-properties-common
</code></pre></div><ul>
<li>Add GPG Key(fingerprint: <code>9DC8 5822 9FC7 DD38 854A  E2D8 8D81 803C 0EBF CD88</code>)</li>
</ul>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">curl -fsSL https://download.docker.com/linux/ubuntu/gpg | sudo apt-key add -
</code></pre></div><ul>
<li>Add repo</li>
</ul>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">add-apt-repository <span>\
</span><span></span>   <span>"</span><span>deb [arch=amd64] https://download.docker.com/linux/ubuntu \
</span><span>   </span><span>$(</span>lsb_release -cs<span>)</span><span> \
</span><span>   stable</span><span>"</span>
</code></pre></div><ul>
<li>Install docker engine</li>
</ul>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">apt-get update

apt-get install docker-ce docker-ce-cli containerd.io
</code></pre></div><p>Optionally check available versions:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">apt-cache madison docker-ce
</code></pre></div><p>And install specific one:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">apt-get install docker-ce<span>=</span>&lt;VERSION_STRING&gt; docker-ce-cli<span>=</span>&lt;VERSION_STRING&gt; containerd.io
</code></pre></div><h2 id="docker-upgrade">Docker upgrade</h2>
<h3 id="live-restore">Live restore</h3>
<p>If you want that running containers won’t stop with docker daemon you can enable live restore feature. After enabling it you can perform upgrade of docker engine without stopping running containers.</p>
<p>In <code>/etc/docker/daemon.json</code> set:</p>
<p>Upgrade on CentOS or Ubuntu - if we install docker engine from repo - can be performed with simple <code>yum upgrade</code> or <code>apt-get upgrade</code> commands.</p>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://knowledgepill.it/posts/docker-install-upgrade/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24081171</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 12:37:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[TikTok’s potential $588 per user valuation in Microsoft deal]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 33 | Comments 46 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24081067">thread link</a>) | @dig6x
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://4thquadrant.io/snippets/business-model2/snippet-tiktoks-potential-588-per-user-valuation/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://4thquadrant.io/snippets/business-model2/snippet-tiktoks-potential-588-per-user-valuation/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-td-block-uid="tdi_27_d73">

<div>
<p><em>“At a market cap of $755 billion (at point of writing) Facebook’s per user value is around $288. If Facebook is some leading indicator for the pinnacle of per user value for social media, then at $50 billion for the roughly 85 million American users, TikTok’s per user value would be $588.”</em></p>



<p>As talks of TikTok’s ban or potential acquisition picks up steam, Microsoft is navigating rocky waters in an attempt to extrude some kind of deal amid the crossfire between Beijing and Washington – not to mention the multitude of big tech forces shaping the narrative. Whether the deal takes place, for what price and for how much of TikTok’s operations will have a resounding impact on the competition between Instagram, Facebook, Microsoft and even Amazon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let’s break down speculation around the deal first:</p>



<p><strong>Price:</strong> The estimated value of the US arm is currently ranging between $20-50 billion. The exact amount depends on a plethora of factors and several discordant stakeholders coming to consensus. The best speculative guess we can make has to be grounded in as much context as possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Bytedance valuation:</strong> Bytedance, TikTok’s parent company has a private-market valuation of more than <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-05-20/tiktok-owner-s-value-surpasses-100-billion-in-private-markets" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">$100 billion</a>, reaching up to $140 billion based on a small private sale made by early stakeholder Cheetah Mobile. Some analysts have predicted that Bytedance could IPO at a valuation north of this, going up as far as $180 billion.</p>



<p><strong>TikTok share of Bytedance:</strong> Bytedance revenue in 2019 was estimated to be around $17 billion, of this TikTok (including DouYin) revenue made up about $179.6 million.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>TikTok projected revenue 2020:</strong> $1 billion, 315 million downloads globally in Q1 (TikTok and DouYin)</p>



<p><strong>Tiktok projected revenue 2021</strong>: TikTok expects to bring in $6 billion in revenue in 2021 according to TikTok management but outsiders have expressed that this is an aggressive estimate, putting a more reasonable range at around $4 billion.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>American Share of TikTok: </strong>Of the 2019 revenue China’s DouYin arm accounted for $122.9 million (69%) while the American market accounted for about $36 million (20%). In April of 2020 in-app purchases on the app increased ten-fold to $78 million where the Chinese market accounted for 86.6% followed by an 8.2% contribution from the American market. At the moment it is predicted that there are about 85 million monthly active TikTok users in the U.S.</p>



<p>There have been reports of investors valuing TikTok around $50 billion in the takeover bid, this is approximately 50 times its projected revenue for 2020. Many publications have compared this to SnapChat’s market capitalization which sits around $33 billion at the moment (15 times its 2020 projected revenue). While Snapchat exists within the same social media ecosystem the comparison has to account for two factors.&nbsp;</p>



<ol><li>TikTok vs Snapchat’s position in the growth cycle</li><li>TikTok vs Snapchat’s core proposition&nbsp;</li></ol>



<p>Snapchat is vastly different on both fronts. For this reason, it’s difficult to gauge whether the current 50x pricing model is absurd or not in relative terms. A reference point, despite being more distant, that I find more revealing is the 2012 Facebook acquisition of Instagram for $1 billion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the time Instagram represented an up and coming giant in the social media landscape (which in and of itself was quite new) and was doing for photo sharing what TikTok has been doing for short video content (at least, doing more effectively than any of its predecessors). Facebook acquired Instagram at an average price of about $30 per user, when its own platform was valued at about $100 per user. Given that social media in 2012 represented a far less developed market and the almost ten year lead time, it’s difficult to directly compare Instagram to TikTok. Today Instagram is valued at over $100 billion and has over 1 billion users, placing its per user rate at $100. At a market cap of $755 billion (at point of writing) Facebook’s per user value is around $290. If Facebook is some leading indicator for the pinnacle of per user value for social media, then at $50 billion for the roughly 85 million American users, TikTok’s per user value would be $588 (this doesn’t change significantly when accounting for the Australian/Canadia/NZ markets given low penetration).&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><br>Where Instagram made up less than a third of Facebooks per user value at the point of acquisition, TikTok is hovering around double or more and more than 5x Instagrams current per user value. Of course, Instagram had no revenue generation and far few users (33 million) in 2012 while TikTok’s rapid growth has made it a giant in its own right. What we’re then looking at, assuming a $50 billion valuation is a complete market disruptor. Even at a $30 billion takeover bid, Microsoft would be paying $352 per user. </p>



<p>Microsoft isn’t negotiating a price range between $20-50 billion based on revenue projections of which a majority are derivative of the Chinese Douyin market, they are at the table on the basis of becoming potentially larger than the largest social media platform in the world. Rather than how this valuation pans out for investors, the longer-lasting and more pertinent question is how does this change the entire social media landscape and Microsoft’s role in the next decade. With such weighty questions up in the air, a 50x pricing model of revenue projection doesn’t seem so absurd – rather a significant turning point in the decade’s narrative around big tech.</p>



<div id="slimcalltoaction"><p>This is box title</p><p>If you enjoyed this article, take advantage of our 14 days free trial to explore our exclusive content. Or sign-up for our free weekly newsletters. View our subscription options <a href="https://4thquadrant.io/subscribe">here.</a></p></div>
</div></div><div data-td-block-uid="tdi_28_0bf">

<div><h3><span>CONTACT THE EDITOR</span></h3>
<p>We welcome thoughtful discourse on all our content. If you would like to further explore or discuss any of the ideas covered in this article please contact our editors directly.<br><span>Contact Details</span></p>
</div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://4thquadrant.io/snippets/business-model2/snippet-tiktoks-potential-588-per-user-valuation/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24081067</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 12:20:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I made a mechanical keyboard with 3D-printed switches]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 177 | Comments 30 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24081046">thread link</a>) | @jstanley
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/stories/jesboard.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/stories/jesboard.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

<h3>I made a mechanical keyboard with 3d-printed switches</h3>
<p><i>Fri  7 August 2020</i></p>
<p><i>Tagged: <a href="https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/tags/3dprinting.html">3dprinting</a>, <a href="https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/tags/keyboard.html">keyboard</a></i></p>
<p>The keyboard is done! This is basically the result of what I've been working on for the past 2 months, which has
involved 3 iterations of testing machines, over 100 printed switches, and now finally a keyboard that I can type on.
Unfortunately it is not a very good keyboard, but you can't win them all.</p>
<p>Here's some pictures of the keyboard:</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2843"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2843"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2844"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2844"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2845"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2845"></a></p>
<p>And here's a video of me typing on it:</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/iEBbCk1WJUk" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>(In the video it is a bit wobbly because the back is propped up to take the pressure off the exposed wiring. I have subsequently printed a couple of small legs to raise up
the back of the keyboard and now it is a lot <i>less</i> wobbly, but it could still do with some soft feet).</p>
<p>I am very happy with how the keyboard looks, and also happy that I have managed to produce a working keyboard using 3d-printed switches in the first place. I believe
this may be a world first.</p>
<p>That said, I started using the jesboard to write this blog post, and it was too annoying to type on so I went back to the Filco. Spending some time typing
on my homemade switches has given me a newfound appreciation for just how good Cherry MX switches are. I'm not sure what it is that makes the
jesboard so unpleasant to type on, there's just a general vagueness to it that makes typing frustrating. Pressing a single key up and down feels basically fine, which is why I hadn't
noticed this problem while developing the switches. But trying to use it as an actual keyboard, and type at a sensible speed, just feels <i>really</i> bad. It
is genuinely the worst keyboard I have ever used. So that's disappointing.</p>
<p>I think to improve upon this you'd probably want to reduce the activation force (that's easy, just make the spring thinner) and add some tactile feedback so it is easier to tell
when the switch has actually been pressed. Beyond that, I'm not sure.</p>
<h2>Switches</h2>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2841"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2841"></a></p>
<p>If you want to learn more about the switches, I would recommend looking at some of my other <a href="https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/tags/keyboard.html">posts tagged "keyboard"</a>, but in short:
pressing on the stem at the top compresses the spiral spring (I copied the spring design from <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCSsm4h2ccJMdR6bsAFyIu6A">Riskable 3D Printing</a>, he
is also developing 3d-printable keyboard switches, but using magnet sensors instead of making mechanical switches himself). Once
the stem is pressed down far enough, a contact wire bridges the 2 contacts at the bottom, activating the switch. As the switch is pressed further, the leaf spring compresses, allowing
the stem to move further down while allowing the contact wire to remain in place. Eventually the spiral spring bottoms out against its casing and then stem movement stops. When the key is released,
the spiral spring pushes everything back up to the top.</p>
<p>The leaf spring has a section in its bend that is narrow in the "other" axis, to allow it easily tilt side-to-side to ensure good contact with both of the contact wires.</p>
<p>I don't have a good photo of the latest switch design, but I have this of an earlier version:</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2757"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2757"></a></p>
<p>The working principle is the same but the new version is a bit shorter.</p>
<p>The switches are printed in PETG. If you want to see them in action, you might enjoy my <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hRBQBf6jzFM">video of operating the switch tester</a>.
The final incarnation of the switch design lasted over 350k presses in all cases, and some instances still hadn't failed at 500k presses. This is a lot lower than the "tens of millions" that might be
expected of a commercial switch, but it's a big improvement over <a href="https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/stories/keyswitch-failure.html">13907</a> which is where the first iteration failed, and that was on an extremely
gentle machine.</p>
<p>I said I was going to experiment with moving the activation point down to 75% of the plunger travel so as to reduce the strain on
the leaf spring. I did test this on the <a href="https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/stories/another-new-tester.html">new machine</a>, with 5 of the old design and 5 of the new design side-by-side, and the new design lasted almost
twice as long, so that was a good improvement.</p>
<p>The gold-plated "jewellery wire" that I bought off eBay ended up working well and soldering well (so I conclude it was not varnished),
and 4 metres (costing £4) was <i>just</i> enough to do the entire keyboard.</p>
<p>If you want, you can <a href="https://incoherency.co.uk/interest/3dpswitch.tar.gz">download the switch CAD</a>, including STL and FreeCAD files.</p>
<h2>Case</h2>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2805"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2805"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2804"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2804"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2832"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2832"></a></p>
<p>The case is split into 2 halves that are then glued together, so that it fits on the bed of the 3D printer. There is a large rectangular hole at the top and bottom in each half, and a long bit of plastic
inside joining them, to add a bit more strength to the joint. There's not a lot to the case design really, it is just a shape to fit the switches into,
with a bulge at the top to house the microcontroller, an exit hole for the cable, stabiliser mounts, and a cool-looking logo. I made the general shape of the case halves in FreeCAD, and then imported the resulting STL
into OpenSCAD to cut out the holes for the switches, because I found it easier to get the layout correct with code.</p>
<p>I printed the logo in a different colour by having the printer stop and wait for me to change the filament at the layer height where the colour changes, using the
<a href="https://marlinfw.org/docs/gcode/M600.html">M600</a> G-code command. PrusaSlicer has a nice GUI for setting this up, so I didn't even need to manually edit the G-code.</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2846"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2846"></a></p>
<p>If I were to make another keyboard, I would give myself more space to work with underneath by reducing the thickness of the "solid" middle part that the switches are mounted in.
I found that there was not really enough room to run the diodes and wires. I would also add provision for a few screws to attach a bottom cover to protect the wiring inside.</p>
<p>The case and keycaps are printed in Prusament Galaxy Black PLA, which I think gives a really nice finish.</p>
<h2>Keycaps</h2>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2848"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2848"></a></p>
<p>The keycaps were designed using <a href="https://github.com/rsheldiii/KeyV2">KeyV2</a>, a free parametric keycap library for OpenSCAD. If you want to design
some keycaps, you should check out KeyV2. Its creator, <a href="https://github.com/rsheldiii">Bob</a>, is friendly and gave me helpful advice and assistance.</p>
<p>There are several different ways to make an ISO (UK-style) enter key in KeyV2, but I couldn't find any combination of settings that would let me have rounded corners, sloping top,
and dished top, so I ended up making the enter key by hand in FreeCAD.</p>
<p>I was originally going to use "outset" legends on the keycaps, like I used on the <a href="https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/stories/3pct-keyboard.html">macro keypad</a>. But I read this comment in the KeyV2 source
which changed my mind, so I used inset legends instead:</p>
<pre><code>// make legends outset instead of inset.
// broken off from artisan support since who wants outset legends?
$outset_legends = false;</code></pre>
<p>But having printed all the keycaps, I'm not sure whether I think inset legends actually <i>are</i> better. They range from "perfectly fine" to "almost invisible" depending on the lighting. I'd
say the outset legends were easier to read.</p>
<h2>Wiring</h2>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2836"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2836"></a></p>
<p>The switches are hand-wired in a 15x5 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keyboard_matrix_circuit">keyboard matrix</a>, with diodes allowing current to pass only in one direction. 14x5 would be enough
if you thought about it a bit more than I did, but 15x5 is fine.</p>
<p>Originally I was planning to use an Arduino for the microcontroller, which has only 16 IO pins. This would allow for an 8x8 matrix, but when I went to layout the wiring, I came up with this, where
red is columns and green is rows:</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2824"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2824"></a></p>
<p>Obviously this is too complicated to wire up in real life, particularly in the small amount of space provided in the bottom of my case. You may also notice it was too complicated for me to
lay out in GIMP, as I have failed to connect the full-stop and apostophe keys to any row. For these reasons I decided to use a <a href="https://www.pjrc.com/teensy/">Teensy</a> 2.0 instead, which allowed me to use a more sensible matrix layout:</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2835"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2835"></a></p>
<p>(I laid this out on <a href="https://kbfirmware.com/">kbfirmware.com</a>).</p>
<p>The other part of the wiring is that the USB cable has to reach the microcontroller. I left a 4mm hole in the side of the case for the cable to run through, but this is too small for the connector
on the end. I was originally planning to cut the connector off and solder the wires directly to the USB pads on the micocontroller board, but they were too small and annoying to access, so instead
I just soldered the MiniUSB end back on and plugged it in. It's a tight fit but it does the job.</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2847"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2847"></a></p>
<p>In hindsight, I am not sure whether I regret hand-wiring the keyboard. I toyed with the idea of getting a PCB made up that I could directly solder my switches to. It would certainly have
made it easier to put the keyboard together, but I thought outsourcing the manufacturing of a PCB kind of takes the edge off making your own switches...</p>
<h2>Stabilisers</h2>
<p>Here's a clip showing how the stabilisers work:</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ZTvDP3Qutwk" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The idea is that when you press down on one side you cause the bar to rotate, which then pulls down on the other side of the switch, forcing the key to move down parallel (instead of rocking)
and activate the switch properly. The bar is made of 1.75mm stainless steel wire bent into a suitable shape. Thick stainless wire is quite hard to cut, but doable with a big-ish pair of nippers.</p>
<p>While trying to fit the stabilisers for the spacebar, I managed to break off the mounts attached to the case. This is bad news because the case halves are about a 10-hour print each, and aside from
that I had already soldered up all of the switches. To reprint the case halves would involve undoing all of my soldering work, and then 20 hours of printing, and then redoing all of the soldering.</p>
<p>I wasn't interested in redoing all of that work, so as a last resort I drilled a hole into the case in the position of each stabiliser mount, and printed 2 new stabiliser mounts, long enough to fit
in the holes. I printed the mounts in PETG so that they'd be less likely to break.</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2842"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2842"></a></p>
<p>This worked really well, disaster averted! The mounts were a tight fit in the drilled holes so I didn't even need to use any glue.</p>
<h2>QMK</h2>
<p>I used <a href="https://qmk.fm/">QMK</a> for the keyboard firmware, running on a Teensy 2.0. I found it quite hard to get started with my custom keyboard, because almost all of the documentation
is geared towards the case where you are using an off-the-shelf keyboard which is already defined in QMK. The key point I needed to know was that you can use the script "<tt>./util/new_keyboard.s…</tt></p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/stories/jesboard.html">https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/stories/jesboard.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/stories/jesboard.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24081046</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 12:17:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Define a CI/CD pipeline in few steps]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 9 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24080948">thread link</a>) | @markothedev
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://microtica.com/how-to-create-simple-ci-cd-pipeline/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://microtica.com/how-to-create-simple-ci-cd-pipeline/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article><div>
<p>Cloud-native applications are on the rise thanks to the scalability and flexibility they provide. However, this type of architecture has its own challenges. Implementing a CI/CD pipeline will solve most of them, like <strong>defining delivery procedures, <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://microtica.com/cracking-the-continuous-deployment-code/" target="_blank">delivering applications independently</a>, and gaining observability of the numerous building blocks in a system</strong> are some of them.</p>



<p>A CI/CD pipeline is the key to <strong>automating the steps of the software delivery process</strong>. This includes initiating code builds, running automated tests, and deploying to a testing or production environment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One CI/CD <strong>pipeline</strong> consists of multiple steps executed one after another or in parallel. There are two known pipeline syntaxes — <strong>Scripted </strong>and <strong>Declarative</strong>. The key difference between them is their flexibility. </p>



<p>Although both syntaxes are based on Groovy DSL, the <strong>Scripted Pipeline Syntax</strong> is less restrictive. It also allows almost anything that can be done in Groovy. This means that the script can easily become hard to read and write.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the other hand, the <strong>Declarative syntax </strong>is more restrictive and provides a well-defined structure, which is ideal for simpler CI/CD pipelines. This syntax supports the “pipeline as code” concept. Therefore, you can write in a file that can be checked into a source control management system like Git. </p>



<p>In order to make it more convenient for developers to set up a CI/CD pipeline, <strong><a href="https://www.microtica.com/">Microtica</a> supports the Declarative syntax to define build procedures along with the source code</strong>.&nbsp;</p>



<h2><strong>Declarative CI/CD pipelines</strong></h2>



<p>For the pipeline process to work, each component/microservice should have a file named <strong><em>microtica.yaml </em></strong>on the root level in its source code. This file contains the specification of the build process. </p>



<p>During the build process, Microtica extracts the specification from the code. Then, it creates a state machine to drive the defined process.</p>



<blockquote><p>In order to ensure a single source of truth for pipeline specification, Microtica does NOT allow changes in the Build pipelines from the UI. Changes will only take effect from the YAML file provided in each source code repository. We find this very helpful in avoiding possible confusion of definition, maintenance, and, most importantly, debugging problems in the process.&nbsp;</p></blockquote>



<h2><strong>Define a CI/CD pipeline</strong></h2>



<p>There are no limitations to the steps of the build pipeline that you can define. Here is one example of a <strong><em>microtica.yaml </em></strong>file that defines a <strong>build pipeline for NodeJS application</strong>. This pipeline executes three particular commands defined in the <em>commands </em>section.</p>



<pre><code>Pipeline:
 StartAt: Build
 States:
   Build:
     Type: Task
     Resource: microtica.actions.cmd
     Parameters:
       commands:
       - npm install
       - npm test
       - npm prune --production
       sourceLocation: "$.trigger.source.location"
       artifacts: true
     End: true</code></pre>



<ul><li><strong><em>Pipeline</em></strong><em> — </em>is the root key which defines the start of the pipeline section</li><li><strong><em>StartAt</em></strong><em> — </em>defines the first action of the pipeline</li><li><strong><em>States</em></strong><em> — </em>defines a list of states for the particular pipeline</li><li><strong><em>Type</em></strong><em> — a </em>type of pipeline action. Always set it to <em>Task</em>.</li><li>Resource — an action that the engine will use. Currently, we support <em>microtica.actions.cmd</em>, an action that executes bash scripting.</li><li>Parameters — a set of parameters that are given to the action<ul><li><strong><em>commands</em></strong><em> — </em>a list of bash commands. Here, you define your custom scripts for build, test, code quality checks, etc.</li><li><strong><em>sourceLocation</em></strong> — the location where the action can find the source code. You should NOT change this. Once pulled from the Git repository, Microtica stores the artifacts on a location specified by the user for the particular component/microservice. <em>$.trigger.source.location</em> defines that location.</li><li><strong><em>artifacts</em></strong> — a value that defines that this build will produce artifacts which will be stored in S3 and used during deployment. Set this value should to <em>false</em> in case the artifact of the build is Docker image</li></ul></li><li><strong><em>End</em></strong><em> — </em>defines that this is the last action in the pipeline.</li></ul>



<p><a href="https://www.microtica.com/">Microtica</a> supports bash commands for the execution action. In the future, we are planning to allow developers to define their own custom actions.</p>



<h2>Getting a Docker image ready for deployment</h2>



<p>Let’s create an extended pipeline from the example above, adding an additional step to prepare a Docker image for deployment:</p>



<pre><code>Pipeline:
  StartAt: Build
  States:
    Build:
      Type: Task
      Resource: microtica.actions.cmd
      Parameters:
        environmentVariables:
          pipelineId: "$.pipeline.id"
          version: "$.commit.version"
        commands:
        - echo Starting build procedure...
        - npm install
        - npm test

        - echo Logging in to Amazon ECR...
        - $(aws ecr get-login --region $AWS_REGION --no-include-email)

        - echo Checking if repository exists in ECR. If not, create one
        - repoExists=`aws ecr describe-repositories --query "repositories[?repositoryName=='$pipelineId']" --output text`
        - if [ -z "$repoExists" ]; then aws ecr create-repository --repository-name $pipelineId; fi

        - awsAccountId=$(echo $CODEBUILD_BUILD_ARN | cut -d':' -f 5)
        - artifactLocation=$awsAccountId.dkr.ecr.$AWS_REGION.amazonaws.com/$pipelineId

        - echo Build Docker image...
        - docker build -t $pipelineId .
        - docker tag $pipelineId $artifactLocation:$version
        - docker tag $pipelineId $artifactLocation:latest

        - echo Push Docker image
        - docker push $artifactLocation
        sourceLocation: "$.source.location"
        artifacts: false
      End: true</code></pre>



<p>In this example, we first inject environment variables in the step runtime with <em>environmentVariables</em> parameter (<em>$.pipeline.id</em> and <em>$.commit.version</em> are both provided by Microtica).</p>



<p>The CI/CD pipeline in the latest example starts by executing necessary instructions to build and test the code. Once this is done, Microtica creates an ECR repository if it doesn’t already exist.</p>



<p>Once we have the ECR repository in place, the last step is to build a new Docker image and then push it in the repository.</p>



<figure><img src="https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-27-at-12.51.06-PM-1024x690.png" alt="automate-build-trigger-ci/cd-pipeline" srcset="https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-27-at-12.51.06-PM-1024x690.png 1024w, https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-27-at-12.51.06-PM-300x202.png 300w, https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-27-at-12.51.06-PM-768x518.png 768w, https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-27-at-12.51.06-PM-1536x1035.png 1536w, https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-27-at-12.51.06-PM-2048x1380.png 2048w, https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-27-at-12.51.06-PM-593x400.png 593w" sizes="100vw"><figcaption>Automate build trigger</figcaption></figure>



<p>After you define the <strong><em>microtica.yaml </em></strong>file with the build pipeline, you can <strong>automate</strong> your build process in Microtica when you create the component or microservice with the wizard in the portal. This option will add a webhook to your repository. </p>



<p>A webhook is a listener that triggers a build process whenever you <strong>push new code to your repository branch</strong>. This way, you can be sure that you’re always working with the newest changes.</p>



<p>Building the docker image gave us an artifact so we can deploy it in a Kubernetes cluster.&nbsp;<strong>You can do this from&nbsp;<em>Microservice details — Add to Cluster</em>, or in the<em>&nbsp;Kubernetes Dashboard — Microservices — Deploy.</em></strong></p>



<div><figure><img src="https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/deploy-ms-cd-1024x882.png" alt="" width="521" height="448" srcset="https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/deploy-ms-cd-1024x882.png 1024w, https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/deploy-ms-cd-300x258.png 300w, https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/deploy-ms-cd-768x661.png 768w, https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/deploy-ms-cd-464x400.png 464w, https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/deploy-ms-cd.png 1470w" sizes="100vw"><figcaption><em>Deploy microservice configuration</em></figcaption></figure></div>



<p>When you deploy your microservice in a Kubernetes Cluster&nbsp;you can select the scaling options. Moreover, you can also set up <strong>continuous delivery</strong> for your microservice.</p>



<h2><strong>Pipelines overview</strong></h2>



<figure><img src="https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-27-at-12.53.34-PM-1024x632.png" alt="details-logs-cicd-pipeline" srcset="https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-27-at-12.53.34-PM-1024x632.png 1024w, https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-27-at-12.53.34-PM-300x185.png 300w, https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-27-at-12.53.34-PM-768x474.png 768w, https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-27-at-12.53.34-PM-1536x948.png 1536w, https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-27-at-12.53.34-PM-2048x1264.png 2048w, https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-27-at-12.53.34-PM-648x400.png 648w" sizes="100vw"><figcaption>Build details and logs</figcaption></figure>



<p>Once you trigger a build manually or automatically, follow the build process in the portal and see the events in real-time. If the build fails, it will mark it with red on the screen and it will show the error in the logs.</p>



<p>Follow all the pipelines for your components and microservices in the <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://portal.microtica.com/pipelines" target="_blank">Pipelines overview page</a> and track their status. Microtica will mark a pipeline as not healthy if there are several failed builds detected. </p>



<p>From this page, you can access any build in the history of your project. More importantly, you can also and inspect the logs to find the problems.</p>



<figure><img src="https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-27-at-12.57.06-PM-1024x610.png" alt="cicd-pipeline-overview" srcset="https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-27-at-12.57.06-PM-1024x610.png 1024w, https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-27-at-12.57.06-PM-300x179.png 300w, https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-27-at-12.57.06-PM-768x457.png 768w, https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-27-at-12.57.06-PM-1536x915.png 1536w, https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-27-at-12.57.06-PM-2048x1220.png 2048w, https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2020-04-27-at-12.57.06-PM-672x400.png 672w" sizes="100vw"><figcaption>Pipelines overview</figcaption></figure>



<p>We are strong advocates for automated pipelines as they <strong>remove manual errors.</strong> Moreover, they are crucial for reliable and sustainable software delivery. </p>



<p>They make software developers <strong>more productive,</strong> releasing them from the need to perform pipeline steps manually. Most importantly, they reduce the stress around new product releases.</p>



<figure><img src="https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/1HMw9Wu19NIalIZ3WRGzvrw-1024x512.png" alt="" srcset="https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/1HMw9Wu19NIalIZ3WRGzvrw-1024x512.png 1024w, https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/1HMw9Wu19NIalIZ3WRGzvrw-300x150.png 300w, https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/1HMw9Wu19NIalIZ3WRGzvrw-768x384.png 768w, https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/1HMw9Wu19NIalIZ3WRGzvrw-740x370.png 740w, https://mk0microtica2di3k2co.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/1HMw9Wu19NIalIZ3WRGzvrw.png 1200w" sizes="100vw"></figure>
<!--<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
			xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
			xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/">
		<rdf:Description rdf:about="https://microtica.com/how-to-create-simple-ci-cd-pipeline/"
    dc:identifier="https://microtica.com/how-to-create-simple-ci-cd-pipeline/"
    dc:title="How to Create a Simple CI/CD Pipeline"
    trackback:ping="https://microtica.com/how-to-create-simple-ci-cd-pipeline/trackback/" />
</rdf:RDF>-->
</div></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://microtica.com/how-to-create-simple-ci-cd-pipeline/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24080948</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 11:59:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pocket P.C. Open Sourced]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 81 | Comments 33 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24078853">thread link</a>) | @nullagent
<br/>
August 6, 2020 | https://blog.popcorncomputer.com/2020/08/05/pocket-p-c-open-sourced/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.popcorncomputer.com/2020/08/05/pocket-p-c-open-sourced/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-content" role="main">

	
<article id="post-194">

	
<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>

		<div>

			
<div><figure><img src="https://opensource.popcorncomputer.com/community/bottom-2lyr-pcb-twitter-resolution-scaled.jpg" alt=""></figure></div>



<p>If you would like to follow along with the latest design or would like to dive deep into the internals of <a href="https://pocket.popcorncomputer.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pocket P.C.</a> we have created a repository on <a href="https://github.com/PopcornComputer/PocketPC-Hardware" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GitHub</a> for the latest hardware files. The work is licensed under a <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/us/">Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 United States License</a>.</p>



<p>&nbsp; Click the GitHub image below to check out the latest files.</p>



<figure><a href="https://github.com/PopcornComputer/PocketPC-Hardware" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://opensource.popcorncomputer.com/blog/GitHub_PocketPC.png" alt="GitHub Repository Badge"></a></figure>



<h3><strong>We are one step closer to shipping Pocket P.C. with the latest developments.</strong></h3>



<p>The latest D.V.T PCB design is out for production. We expect the PCBs to arrive within 10-12 days.&nbsp; After that, we will be assembling 25 units.</p>



<p>The D.V.T. design brings with it a newly added SPI Flash which will allow <a href="https://pocket.popcorncomputer.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pocket P.C. </a>to more easily boot multiple operating systems on the same <a href="https://pocket.popcorncomputer.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pocket P.C.</a> We also changed the design to a 10-layer PCB stackup vs. 8-layers which will ensure better signal integrity for high-speed signals.</p>



<p>The keyboard layout has been tweaked incorporating feedback from community suggestions and from hands-on the 3D printed prototypes. Thank you to everyone who submitted feedback about our initial layout. The space bar has been extended to allow for it to be pressed from a comfortable hand position and a few other minor changes. You can view the latest layout in our community keyboard thread here: <a href="https://community.popcorncomputer.com/t/pocket-p-c-keyboard-layout-part-2/541" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pocket P.C. Keyboard Layout (Part 2)</a></p>



<p>We learned a lot from the last production run of Original Popcorn. We did not receive the level of support that we were promised from the USB-C IC manufacturer that we chose to handle the USB Power Delivery system. As such, we changed the <a href="https://pocket.popcorncomputer.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pocket P.C.</a> design to incorporate a robust Texas Instruments single-chip solution. With this new solution, we added to the design dedicated port protector ICs with ESD protection and surge protection ICs also from Texas Instruments on every ports. This will make the design more robust to faulty power conditions.</p>



<p>Finally, to ensure that <a href="https://pocket.popcorncomputer.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pocket P.C. </a>has great software support out of the box, we have requested embedded development help from the community. Our goal is to ensure that we get all aspects of our products mainlined so that custom kernels will not be required. In order to accomplish this, a community effort is required to review and test new solutions before submitting them to the Linux Kernel mailing list. If you are interested in following with our development efforts you can join the discussion here: <a href="https://community.popcorncomputer.com/t/embedded-linux-development-help-requested/559/15" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Embedded Linux Development Help Requested</a></p>



<figure><img src="https://opensource.popcorncomputer.com/community/top-2lyr-pcb-twitter-resolution-scaled.jpg" alt=""></figure>



<h3>Visit the shop to pre-order your Pocket P.C. today!</h3>



<h4><a href="https://shop.popcorncomputer.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Pre-order Now</strong></a></h4>



<h3>Keep up to date on the latest developments in our community.</h3>



<p>In an effort to be more transparent with the latest on-goings with development and production, we have created a community thread where we will post updates as they happen.</p>



<h4><a href="https://community.popcorncomputer.com/t/pocket-p-c-development-updates/552" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Community Website</strong></a></h4>





		</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	</div><!-- .post-inner -->

	<!-- .section-inner -->

	
	<!-- .pagination-single -->

	
		<!-- .comments-wrapper -->

		
</article><!-- .post -->

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.popcorncomputer.com/2020/08/05/pocket-p-c-open-sourced/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24078853</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 06:04:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
