<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 08:18:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 08:18:01 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What is GPT-3? written in layman's terms]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 151 | Comments 54 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23923799">thread link</a>) | @skylarker
<br/>
July 22, 2020 | https://tinkeredthinking.com/index.php?id=841 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://tinkeredthinking.com/index.php?id=841">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2><a href="https://tinkeredthinking.com/index.php?id=841">WHAT IS GPT-3?</a></h2><h5>July 21st, 2020<sup></sup></h5>
<p>After playing around with the new tool from OpenAI, named GPT-3, it’s clear that we’ve probably reached an inflection point in the progress of artificial intelligence.&nbsp; To think of it in more commonplace terms, parents will often have the interesting experience of watching their children suddenly gain competency in a skill, seemingly overnight.&nbsp; There will be lots of struggle and failed starts and then as if all in one moment, boom, suddenly the kid can do something new.&nbsp; GPT-3 hails a moment when machine learning got turned on and suddenly it could do an amazing new trick, and it does this new trick with astonishing coherence and ability.&nbsp; The hope of this episode is to present a description of what GPT-3 is in layman’s terms and then explore some possible ways that this could be used, and how it might impact society.</p>


<p>But first, what is GPT?&nbsp; The acronym stands for Generative Pretrained Transformer.&nbsp; Ok sure, but what exactly is it?&nbsp; How do we interact with it?&nbsp; In simple terms <em>it’s a program that accepts some text and then generates a continuation of this text.</em>&nbsp; What exactly does this look like?&nbsp; For those with access to the GPT-3 playground through OpenAI, it just looks like an empty textbox with a submit button.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Now enters a principle that has emerged during the last week as developers have played around with it:</p>

<p><em>Garbage in, Garbage out.</em></p>

<p>GPT-3 mimics the style, tone and character of whatever text you feed it.&nbsp; (For those curious, you can hit the submit button with an empty textbox and GPT-3 will generate something.&nbsp; The first time I did this it started talking in French about libraries.&nbsp; The second time it started talking about heatwaves being in the headlines.)&nbsp; There is a bit of an art to the prompt you give GPT-3.&nbsp; Again, garbage in, garbage out.</p>


<p>Here are two examples:</p>


<p>Input: What’s up?</p>

<p>GPT-3 continuation: <em>A confused voice came from inside. When I opened the door, the person that looked back at me was Hayama Hayato. Why was Hayama, who I only shared memories of me playing soccer with, in my room at this hour of the night? That question immediately flew out from my mouth.</em></p>


<p>Second example, same exact input:</p>

<p>Input: What’s up?</p>

<p>GPT-3 continuation:&nbsp; <em>they respond 'Super' – at least they were back in the days of Fox Mulder and Dana Scully. I love the little sixties touches too, the poodle skirts, the VWs, the hippydom.</em><strong><em>&nbsp;</em></strong></p>

<p>The input of “what’s up?” doesn’t provide any context, so GPT-3 generates text in a random direction each time. But notice how coherent it was…</p>

<p>But if you provide GPT-3 with context, say, the first couple paragraphs of an episode from Tinkered Thinking and it will generate a continuation of that episode which is shockingly on point and very believable.&nbsp; Episode <a target="_blank" href="https://tinkeredthinking.com/index.php?id=836">823</a> and <a target="_blank" href="https://tinkeredthinking.com/index.php?id=837">824</a> are non-fiction episodes that explore just this idea.&nbsp; About half of each episode was <em>generated</em> by GPT-3.&nbsp; This collaboration was also done for <a target="_blank" href="https://tinkeredthinking.com/index.php?id=837">Episode 826</a> which is a fictional short story.&nbsp; GPT-3’s contribution to that episode is not explicitly indicated but there too it wrote approximately half of the text, and that episode in particular demonstrates an aspect of context in relationship to GPT-3.&nbsp; The program’s initial contributions to the fictional short story are a bit clunky.&nbsp; But as the story goes on, GPT-3’s contributions get <em>better and better </em>as the entire context of the story grows. &nbsp;</p>

<p>It should be obvious at this point that if you were to do something nefarious like input some dangerous ideas into GPT-3, then it would continue in the same vein.&nbsp; This is an important point that lends to obvious criticism and it’s a topic of which OpenAI is extremely conscious.&nbsp; The use of GPT-3 in the wild requires a security application among other safeguards to limit GPT-3’s use in obviously negative ways.&nbsp; Again, the principle holds: <em>garbage in, garbage out.&nbsp; </em>That holds not just for level of composition but of course, also subject matter.</p>

<p>Now how exactly does this magic work?&nbsp; To answer this, it’s necessary to wrap one’s mind around machine learning.&nbsp; How exactly does a machine learn?&nbsp; To be honest, nobody really knows.&nbsp; In a way, we’ve created a black box that can learn to figure things out.&nbsp; To really answer the question: how exactly does a machine learn is similar to asking: how does a person arise from all the chatter between neurons in a person’s brain?&nbsp; No one can answer that question.&nbsp; And likewise, no one can really answer the question about what’s really going on when a neural net is being trained in a machine learning context.&nbsp; That being said, we can describe some aspects of the process that help us grasp a sense of what’s going on.</p>

<p>Turns out, Machine Learning doesn’t seem too much different than human learning, though the differences are enormous and enormously important.&nbsp; Our brains are vast networks of neurons and they all talk to each other and somehow from all that chatter, we as individuals, emerge.&nbsp; To be sure, our understanding of the brain is still rudimentary, but it’s clear that neurons ‘listen’ to the chatter around them via a web of arms or dendrites that reach out to other neurons, and based on the signals they hear, they fire their own signal to be heard by another neuron or set of neurons.&nbsp; Multiply that process roughly 86 billion times, give it the right shape, and some configuration and boom, you have a human brain that will try to figure things out.&nbsp; (To dive a little deeper it’s useful to know that an infant actually has around 100 billion neurons, and as we learn how to exist in the world, we pare down this number significantly.)</p>

<p>GPT-3 was trained to generate text using a computational model that bares a lot of similarity to our jumble of neurons we call a brain.&nbsp; The analogy is so close in fact that this computational model is referred to as a ‘neural net’.&nbsp; Now here’s an interesting fact about GPT-3:&nbsp; the neural net upon which it was trained contains 175 billion parameters, or what you might think of as neurons.&nbsp; But there’s a distinction here we need to be very careful about.&nbsp; The node, or neuron, or what’s often referred to as a ‘parameter’ within this neural net is not a neuron in the same way that our neurons are.&nbsp; There is a similarity, but our neurons are vastly more complex than the nodes that exist within a neural net.&nbsp; Within the context of machine learning, a neuron is a fairly simple weighted value.&nbsp; These values dictate how one node talks to another.&nbsp; An actual human neuron is far more complex regarding how it listens and signals it’s neighbors.&nbsp; We must also take into account that there are many different types of neurons in the human brain specializing in different ways with different functions.&nbsp; Human neurons also have varying numbers of dendrites which are used to listen to other neurons.&nbsp; A single neuron can have over 100 dendrites and each dendrite has characteristics that determine how and what the core neuron hears and ultimately what sort of signal it sends.&nbsp; This presents a level of complexity that far exceeds what is going on with the nodes or neurons in a machine learning context.&nbsp; And this difference in complexity should make it intuitive why GPT-3 was trained using so many ‘neurons’.&nbsp; It’s construction and organization of these ‘neurons’ is far simpler and more straightforward than what we have going on between our ears, so where the neural net lacks in terms of shape and initial configuration, it attempts to make up for in size and the brute force achieved by speed and computational iteration.</p>

<p>So how does a neural net learn in order for something like GPT-3 to work?&nbsp; First you need a gargantuan amount of data.&nbsp; GPT-3 was trained using text from the internet - an amount of text that is just inconceivable for a single human being to think about reading.&nbsp; Think of every comment, every post, every description, every pdf book freely available, all the tweets and blogs, manuals, dissertations, threads, rantings - all of it.&nbsp; That was the block of text that was given to the neural net for it’s training. &nbsp;</p>

<p>So how does that training work?&nbsp; Imagine I gave you a paragraph to read, but I left off the last word, and asked you to guess what that word is.&nbsp; As a human, you’d probably do really well at this.&nbsp; You’d certainly do a perfect job guessing a <em>sensible</em> word that fits the context and which works, regardless of whether you guess the actual word. Here’s a tiny example:&nbsp; Please provide the last word that should be added to the end of this ___________ . &nbsp;</p>

<p>The above example is easy.&nbsp; The word is ‘sentence’.&nbsp; But.&nbsp; Since I’ve started a new paragraph, you could also plop the word ‘paragraph’ into the slot and it still works.&nbsp; This is the task that GPT-3 has become remarkably good at:&nbsp; <em>what word would make sense to come next?&nbsp; </em>The training of the neural net essentially asked this question of itself over and over.&nbsp; We can imagine the neural net reading 99 words and guessing what the 100th word would be.&nbsp; It would then check the answer and see how far ‘off’ the answer was, and based on the difference it would backtrack through the neural net to find all of the nodes that were most responsible for the choice of the wrong word, and then it would adjust the weights of those nodes, which in turn effects how those nodes will talk to one another in the next round.&nbsp; Run this game an astronomical number of times with an inconceivably large amount of text and after a while the neural net gets pretty good at the game it’s playing. &nbsp;</p>

<p>What’s important to note is that the computer is not actually ‘reading’ the text that’s given to it.&nbsp; The computer first creates embeddings for this block of text.&nbsp; What is an embedding?&nbsp; It’s arbitrary, but it’s a form that the computer can actually work with.&nbsp; Computers function using binary code.&nbsp; Each letter that you read on a website is actually derived from a binary code.&nbsp; So embeddings are bits of binary code that are associated with the words and word-snippets that the computer ‘reads’.&nbsp; These embeddings …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://tinkeredthinking.com/index.php?id=841">https://tinkeredthinking.com/index.php?id=841</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://tinkeredthinking.com/index.php?id=841</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23923799</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 03:06:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Verified seL4 on secure RISC-V processors]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 128 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23923090">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
July 22, 2020 | https://ts.data61.csiro.au/publications/csiroabstracts/Heiser_20.abstract.pml | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ts.data61.csiro.au/publications/csiroabstracts/Heiser_20.abstract.pml">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>


    <main id="main-content">         
        <div>
                


<h2>Authors</h2>




<h2>Abstract</h2><p>RISC-V has many attractions, ranging from the openness of the architecture, its clean-slate design based on simplicity and scalability, as well as the RISC-V Foundation's strong commitment to security from the ground up.

As such, RISC-V is an extremely attractive platform for the open-source seL4 microkernel with its unrivalled verification and security story. This has led industry players, especially Germany-based HENSOLDT Cyber, making a major bet on the combination of RISC-V and seL4, resulting in them funding the formal verification (implementation correctness proof) of seL4 on RISC-V.

I will discuss our experience with implementing and verifying seL4 on the RISC-V architecture, and related open-source technologies we are employing to allow us to build secure systems. This includes the CAmkES component framework that supports a security-by-architecture approach, and the Cogent systems language that is designed to reduce the cost of verified system components such as file systems and device drivers. 

One interesting aspect are timing channels. We have been working for a number of years on *time protection*, the temporal equivalent of memory protection, as a systematic timing-channel prevention. Our experience on x86 and ARM processors is that they lack the mechanisms to do this completely. RISC-V presents an opportunity to get this right, and I will report on my experience working with the RISC-V Foundation's Security Standing Committee to get the required mechanisms into the processor specification.
 </p>
 <h2>BibTeX Entry</h2><pre>  @misc{Heiser_20,
    author           = {Heiser, Gernot},
    month            = jan,
    date             = {2020-1-17},
    year             = {2020},
    keywords         = {operating systems; verification; cyber security; safety-critical systems; {RISC}-{V}},
    title            = {Verified {seL4} on secure {RISC}-{V} processors},
    address          = {Gold Coast},
    numpages         = {online},
    video            = {https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wJ96s3pNtI0&amp;feature=youtu.be},
    note             = { at linux.conf.au},
    booktitle        = {Linux.conf.au},
    publisher        = {Online},
    slides           = {https://ts.data61.csiro.au/publications/papers/Heiser_20.slides.pdf}
  }</pre>
<h2>Download</h2>



        </div>
    </main>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ts.data61.csiro.au/publications/csiroabstracts/Heiser_20.abstract.pml</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23923090</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:46:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Amazon Ion]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 290 | Comments 96 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23921610">thread link</a>) | @BerislavLopac
<br/>
July 22, 2020 | https://amzn.github.io/ion-docs/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://amzn.github.io/ion-docs/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <div>
        

<p><strong><span size="+1">Amazon Ion</span></strong> is a <a href="https://amzn.github.io/ion-docs/guides/why.html#rich-type-system">richly-typed</a>, <a href="https://amzn.github.io/ion-docs/guides/why.html#self-describing">self-describing</a>, hierarchical data serialization
format offering <a href="https://amzn.github.io/ion-docs/guides/why.html#dual-format-interoperability">interchangeable binary and text</a> representations. The <a href="https://amzn.github.io/ion-docs/docs/spec.html">text format</a>
(a superset of <a href="http://json.org/">JSON</a>) is easy to read and author, supporting rapid
prototyping. The <a href="https://amzn.github.io/ion-docs/docs/binary.html">binary representation</a> is <a href="https://amzn.github.io/ion-docs/guides/why.html#read-optimized-binary-format">efficient to store, transmit, and
skip-scan parse</a>.  The rich type system provides unambiguous semantics for
long-term preservation of data which can survive multiple generations
of software evolution.</p>

<p>Ion was built to address rapid development, decoupling, and efficiency
challenges faced every day while engineering large-scale, service-oriented
architectures. It has been addressing these challenges within Amazon for nearly
a decade, and we believe others will benefit as well.</p>

<p><strong>Available Languages:</strong> <a href="https://github.com/amzn/ion-c">C</a> – <a href="https://github.com/amzn/ion-dotnet">C#</a> – <a href="https://github.com/amzn/ion-java">Java</a> – <a href="https://github.com/amzn/ion-js">JavaScript</a> – <a href="https://github.com/amzn/ion-python">Python</a> <br>
<strong>Related Projects:</strong> <a href="https://amzn.github.io/ion-hash">Ion Hash</a> – <a href="https://amzn.github.io/ion-schema">Ion Schema</a><br>
<strong>Tools:</strong> <a href="https://github.com/amzn/ion-hive-serde">Hive SerDe</a><br></p>



<h3 id="gettingstarted">Getting Started</h3>

<p>All JSON values are valid Ion values, and while any value can be encoded in JSON (e.g., a timestamp value can be converted to a string), such approaches require extra effort, obscure the actual type of the data, and tend to be error-prone.</p>

<p>In contrast, Ion’s rich type system enables unambiguous semantics for data (e.g., a timestamp value can be encoded using the timestamp type).  The following illustrates some of the features of the Ion type system:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>timestamp:</strong>  arbitrary precision date / timestamps
    <div><div><pre><code>2003-12-01T
2010-03-22T18:00:00Z
2019-05-01T18:12:53.472-0800
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li><strong>int:</strong>  arbitrary size integers
    <div><div><pre><code>0
-1
12345678901234567890...
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li><strong>decimal:</strong>  arbitrary precision, base-10 encoded real numbers
    <div><div><pre><code>0.
-1.2
3.141592653589793238...
6.62607015d-34
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li><strong>float:</strong>  32-/64-bit IEEE-754 floating-point values
    
  </li>
  <li><strong>symbol:</strong>  provides efficient encoding for frequently occurring strings
    <div><div><pre><code>inches
dollars
'high-priority'    // symbols with special characters ('-' in this example)
                   // are enclosed in single-quotes
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li><strong>blob:</strong>  binary data
    
  </li>
  <li><strong>annotation:</strong>  metadata associated with a value
    <div><div><pre><code>dollars::100.0
height::inches::72
lotto_numbers::[7, 9, 19, 40, 42, 44]
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>The <a href="https://amzn.github.io/ion-docs/docs/spec.html">Specification</a> provides an overview of the full set of Ion types.</p>

<h3 id="binary-encoding">Binary Encoding</h3>

<p>Ion provides two encodings:  human-readable text (as shown above), and a space- and read-efficient binary encoding.  When binary-encoded, every Ion value is prefixed with the value’s type and length.  The following illustrates a few of the efficiences provided by Ion’s binary encoding:</p>

<ul>
  <li>The following timestamp encoded as a JSON string requires 26 bytes:  “2017-07-26T16:30:04.076Z”.  This timestamp requires just 11 bytes when encoded in Ion binary:
    <div><div><pre><code>6a 80 0f e1 87 9a 90 9e 84 c3 4c
</code></pre></div>    </div>
    <p>That first byte <code>6a</code> indicates the value is a timestamp (type <code>6</code>) represented by the subsequent 10 bytes (that’s what the <code>a</code> represents).  If this particular timestamp value is not of interest, a reader can jump over the value by skipping 10 bytes.  This ability to skip over a value enables faster navigation over Ion data.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Binary encoding of a symbol replaces the text of a symbol with an integer that can be resolved to the original text via a symbol table.  This can result in substantial space savings for symbols that occur frequently!</p>
  </li>
  <li>While blob data is base-64 encoded in text (which produces 4 bytes for every 3 bytes of the original data), a blob encoded as Ion binary is simply encoded as is—no base-64 expansion required!</li>
</ul>

<p>Similar space efficiencies are found in other aspects of Ion’s binary encoding.</p>

<h3 id="give-ion-a-try">Give Ion a Try!</h3>

<p>
/* Ion supports comments. */
// Here is a struct, which is similar to a JSON object
{
  // Field names don't always have to be quoted
  name: "Fido",

  // This is an integer with a 'years' annotation
  age: years::4,

  // This is a timestamp with day precision
  birthday: 2012-03-01T,

  // Here is a list, which is like a JSON array
  toys: [
    // These are symbol values, which are like strings,
    // but get encoded as integers in binary
    ball,
    rope,
  ],

  // This is a decimal -- a base-10 floating point value
  weight: pounds::41.2,

  // Here is a blob -- binary data, which is
  // base64-encoded in Ion text encoding
  buzz: {{VG8gaW5maW5pdHkuLi4gYW5kIGJleW9uZCE=}},
}
</p>


<h3 id="more-information">More Information</h3>

<p>To learn more, check out the <a href="https://amzn.github.io/ion-docs/docs.html">Docs</a> page, or see <a href="https://amzn.github.io/ion-docs/libs.html">Libs</a> for the officially supported libraries as well as community supported tools.  For information on how to contribute, how to contact the Ion Team, and answers to the frequently asked questions, see <a href="https://amzn.github.io/ion-docs/help.html">Help</a>.</p>

<!-- References -->

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://amzn.github.io/ion-docs/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23921610</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 21:09:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Biff – Self-hosted Firebase alternative for Clojure]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 96 | Comments 19 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23921220">thread link</a>) | @jacobobryant
<br/>
July 22, 2020 | https://findka.com/biff/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://findka.com/biff/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <div>
          <p>Biff</p>
          <p>A web framework + self-hosted deployment solution for Clojure</p>
        </div>
        
<p>Biff is designed to make web development with Clojure fast and easy, especially
for early stage startups and hobby projects. Over time I'd like to make it
suitable for apps that need scale as well.
I use it in production for <a href="https://findka.com/" target="_blank">Findka</a>, my startup. I started writing Biff after 18 months
of experimenting with various web technologies like Firebase, Datomic and
several Clojure web frameworks/libraries. It includes:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Installation and deployment</strong> on DigitalOcean (or other VPS).</li>
<li><strong>Crux</strong> (an immutable document database with Datalog queries).</li>
<li><strong>Subscriptions</strong>. Specify what data the frontend needs declaratively, and
Biff will keep it up-to-date.</li>
<li><strong>Read/write authorization rules</strong>. No need to set up a bunch of endpoints
for CRUD operations. Queries and transactions can be submitted from the
frontend as long as they pass the rules you define.</li>
<li><strong>Database triggers</strong>. Run code when documents of certain types are created,
updated or deleted.</li>
<li><strong>Authentication</strong>. Email link for now; password and SSO coming later.</li>
<li><strong>Websocket communication</strong>.</li>
<li>Serving <strong>static resources</strong>.</li>
<li><strong>Multitenancy</strong>. Run multiple apps from the same process.</li>
<li>Less than <strong>2K lines of code</strong>.</li>
</ul>

<p>Also: instead of trying to do everything for everyone, Biff is designed to be
easy to take apart (without forking). This should help mitigate the main
drawback of frameworks, which is that it's often less work in the long run to
just stitch the libraries together yourself.</p>

<p>Biff is currently alpha quality. Join <code>#biff</code> on <a href="http://clojurians.net/" target="_blank">Clojurians Slack</a> for
discussion. Feel free to reach out for help, bug reports or anything else. Also
see the issues and source on the <a href="https://github.com/jacobobryant/biff" target="_blank">Github
repo</a>.</p>
<h2 id="comparison-to-firebase">Comparison to Firebase</h2>
<p>Basically, if you like Firebase and you like Clojure backend dev, you might
enjoy using Biff for your next side project. Same if you like the idea of
Firebase but in practice you have issues with it. If you want something mature
or you like having a Node/ClojureScript backend, Firebase is a great choice. <a href="https://github.com/jacobobryant/mystery-cows" target="_blank">Here's a non-trivial
example</a> of using Firebase with ClojureScript.</p>

<p>Some shared features:</p>

<ul>
<li>Natural modeling of graph data</li>
<li>Basic query subscriptions (no joins)</li>
<li>Client-side transactions</li>
<li>Authorization rules</li>
<li>Triggers</li>
<li>Authentication built-in</li>
</ul>

<p>Some differences:</p>

<ul>
<li>Biff has a long-running JVM/Clojure backend instead of an ephemeral
Node/ClojureScript backend =&gt; better library ecosystem IMO and lower response
times/no cold start.</li>
<li>Firebase has way more features and is vastly more mature.</li>
<li>Biff is open-source + self-hosted =&gt; you have total control. If there's anything you don't like, you can fix it.</li>
<li><a href="https://opencrux.com/" target="_blank">Crux</a> (the database Biff uses) is immutable and has Datalog queries.</li>
<li>Authorization rules in Firebase are IMO error-prone and hard to debug.</li>
<li>Firebase supports password and SSO authentication.</li>
</ul>

<p>The fastest way to get started with Biff is by cloning the Github repo and running the
official example project (an implementation of Tic Tac Toe):</p>

<ol>
<li>Install dependencies: <a href="https://clojure.org/guides/getting_started" target="_blank">Clojure</a>,
<a href="https://www.npmjs.com/get-npm" target="_blank">NPM</a> and
(optionally) <a href="https://github.com/DarthSim/overmind#installation" target="_blank">Overmind</a>.</li>
<li><code>git clone https://github.com/jacobobryant/biff</code></li>
<li><code>cd biff/example</code></li>
<li><code>./task setup</code></li>
<li><code>./task dev</code></li>
<li>Go to <code>localhost:9630</code> and start the <code>app</code> build.</li>
<li>Go to <code>localhost:8080</code></li>
</ol>

<p><strong>Note:</strong> if you're on Windows/don't have Bash, you'll need to run the
commands inside <code>task</code> individually (translated to whatever shell you're
using). Also, you may need to install
<a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=48145" target="_blank">this package</a>
(see <a href="https://github.com/facebook/rocksdb/issues/2531" target="_blank">facebook/rocksdb#2531</a>).</p>

<p>You can tinker with this app and use it as a template for your own projects. See
<a href="#production">Production</a> when you want to deploy.</p>

<p>The example project uses tools.deps, Shadow CLJS, and Overmind.
<code>task</code> is the main entrypoint:</p>


<div><pre><code><span>#!/bin/bash</span>
<span>set</span> <span>-e</span>

setup <span>()</span> <span>{</span>
  which clj npm <span>&gt;</span> /dev/null <span># Assert dependencies</span>
  npm <span>install</span> <span># Or `npm init; npm install --save-dev shadow-cljs; npm install --save react react-dom`</span>
  clj <span>-Sresolve-tags</span>
<span>}</span>

repl <span>()</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>BIFF_ENV</span><span>=</span>dev clj <span>-m</span> biff.core
<span>}</span>

cljs <span>()</span> <span>{</span>
  npx shadow-cljs server
<span>}</span>

dev <span>()</span> <span>{</span>
  <span># Download dependencies first. This prevents clj and shadow-cljs from trying</span>
  <span># to clone new git dependencies at the same time which causes an error.</span>
  clojure <span>-Spath</span> <span>&gt;</span> /dev/null
  <span>if </span>which overmind <span>&gt;</span> /dev/null 2&gt;&amp;1 <span>;</span> <span>then
    </span>overmind start
  <span>else
    </span>cljs &amp;
    repl
  <span>fi</span>
<span>}</span>

...

<span>"</span><span>$@</span><span>"</span>
</code></pre></div>

<div><pre><code>repl: ./task repl
cljs: ./task cljs
</code></pre></div>
<p>So <code>./task dev</code> will run <code>./task repl</code> and <code>./task cljs</code> in the same terminal
window. Hit <code>ctrl-c</code> to exit. If you'd like to restart just one process and you
have Overmind installed, run e.g. <code>overmind restart repl</code> in another window.
You can easily add new build tasks by creating new functions in <code>task</code>. Also, I
recommend putting <code>alias t='./task'</code> in your <code>.bashrc</code>.</p>

<p>To fetch the latest Biff version, start out with only <code>:git/url</code> and <code>:tag</code> in the dependency:</p>


<div><pre><code><span>{</span><span>...</span><span>
 </span><span>:deps</span><span>
 </span><span>{</span><span>github-jacobobryant/biff</span><span>
  </span><span>{</span><span>:git/url</span><span> </span><span>"https://github.com/jacobobryant/biff"</span><span>
   </span><span>:tag</span><span> </span><span>"HEAD"</span><span>}}}</span><span>
</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Then run <code>clj -Sresolve-tags</code>. The latest commit hash will be added to <code>deps.edn</code>.</p>

<p>When you run <code>clj -m biff.core</code>, Biff searches the classpath for plugins and then starts
them in a certain order. To define a plugin, you must set <code>^:biff</code> metadata on a namespace
and then set a <code>components</code> var to a list of plugin objects in that namespace:</p>


<div><pre><code><span>(</span><span>ns</span><span> </span><span>^</span><span>:biff</span><span> </span><span>example.core</span><span>
  </span><span>(</span><span>:require</span><span>
    </span><span>[</span><span>biff.system</span><span>]</span><span>
    </span><span>[</span><span>clojure.pprint</span><span> </span><span>:refer</span><span> </span><span>[</span><span>pprint</span><span>]]</span><span>
    </span><span>[</span><span>example.handlers</span><span>]</span><span>
    </span><span>[</span><span>example.routes</span><span>]</span><span>
    </span><span>[</span><span>example.rules</span><span>]</span><span>
    </span><span>[</span><span>example.static</span><span>]</span><span>
    </span><span>[</span><span>example.triggers</span><span>]))</span><span>

</span><span>(</span><span>defn</span><span> </span><span>send-email</span><span> </span><span>[</span><span>opts</span><span>]</span><span>
  </span><span>(</span><span>pprint</span><span> </span><span>[</span><span>:send-email</span><span> </span><span>opts</span><span>]))</span><span>

</span><span>(</span><span>defn</span><span> </span><span>start-example</span><span> </span><span>[</span><span>sys</span><span>]</span><span>
  </span><span>(</span><span>-&gt;</span><span> </span><span>sys</span><span>
    </span><span>(</span><span>merge</span><span> </span><span>#</span><span>:example.biff.auth</span><span>{</span><span>:send-email</span><span> </span><span>send-email</span><span>
                               </span><span>:on-signup</span><span> </span><span>"/signin/sent/"</span><span>
                               </span><span>:on-signin-request</span><span> </span><span>"/signin/sent/"</span><span>
                               </span><span>:on-signin-fail</span><span> </span><span>"/signin/fail/"</span><span>
                               </span><span>:on-signin</span><span> </span><span>"/app/"</span><span>
                               </span><span>:on-signout</span><span> </span><span>"/"</span><span>})</span><span>
    </span><span>(</span><span>merge</span><span> </span><span>#</span><span>:example.biff</span><span>{</span><span>:routes</span><span> </span><span>example.routes/routes</span><span>
                          </span><span>:static-pages</span><span> </span><span>example.static/pages</span><span>
                          </span><span>:event-handler</span><span> </span><span>#</span><span>(</span><span>example.handlers/api</span><span> </span><span>%</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>:?data</span><span> </span><span>%</span><span>))</span><span>
                          </span><span>:rules</span><span> </span><span>example.rules/rules</span><span>
                          </span><span>:triggers</span><span> </span><span>example.triggers/triggers</span><span>})</span><span>
    </span><span>(</span><span>biff.system/start-biff</span><span> </span><span>'example</span><span>)))</span><span>

</span><span>(</span><span>def</span><span> </span><span>components</span><span>
  </span><span>[{</span><span>:name</span><span> </span><span>:example/core</span><span>
    </span><span>:requires</span><span> </span><span>[</span><span>:biff/init</span><span>]</span><span>
    </span><span>:required-by</span><span> </span><span>[</span><span>:biff/web-server</span><span>]</span><span>
    </span><span>:start</span><span> </span><span>start-example</span><span>}])</span><span>
</span></code></pre></div>
<p><code>:biff/init</code> and <code>:biff/web-server</code> are plugins defined in the <code>biff.core</code>
namespace. The <code>:requires</code> and <code>:required-by</code> values are used to start plugins
in the right order. You can think of plugins kind of like Ring middleware. They
receive a system map and pass along a modified version of it.</p>

<p><code>biff.system/start-biff</code> starts a Biff app. That includes initializing:</p>

<ul>
<li>a Crux node</li>
<li>a Sente websocket listener and event router</li>
<li>some default event handlers that handle queries, transactions and subscriptions from the frontend</li>
<li>a Crux transaction listener, so clients can be notified of subscription updates</li>
<li>some Reitit HTTP routes for authentication</li>
<li>any static resources you've included with your app</li>
</ul>

<p>If you connect to nrepl port 7888, you can access the system with
<code>@biff.core/system</code>. Biff provides some helper functions for repl-driven
development:</p>
<div><pre><code><span>(</span><span>biff.core/stop</span><span>)</span><span>
</span><span>(</span><span>biff.core/start</span><span>)</span><span>
</span><span>(</span><span>biff.core/refresh</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>; stops, reloads namespaces from filesystem, starts.</span><span>
</span></code></pre></div>
<p>App-specific configuration can go in your plugin, as shown above. For example, we set
<code>:example.biff.auth/on-signin</code> so that clients will be redirected to <code>/app/</code> after they
sign in successfully.</p>

<p>Environment-specific configuration and secrets can go in <code>config.edn</code>. They will be read in
by the <code>:biff/init</code> plugin.</p>


<div><pre><code><span>{</span><span>:prod</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span>; If you set jdbc credentials, remove this file from source control!</span><span>
        </span><span>:biff.crux.jdbc/dbname</span><span> </span><span>"..."</span><span>
        </span><span>:biff.crux.jdbc/user</span><span> </span><span>"..."</span><span>
        </span><span>:biff.crux.jdbc/password</span><span> </span><span>"..."</span><span>
        </span><span>:biff.crux.jdbc/host</span><span> </span><span>"..."</span><span>
        </span><span>:biff.crux.jdbc/port</span><span> </span><span>...</span><span>
        </span><span>:example.biff/host</span><span> </span><span>"example.com"</span><span>
        </span><span>:example.mailgun/api-key</span><span> </span><span>"..."</span><span>}</span><span>
 </span><span>:dev</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span>:inherit</span><span> </span><span>[</span><span>:prod</span><span>]</span><span>
       </span><span>:biff/dev</span><span> </span><span>true</span><span>
       </span><span>:example.biff/host</span><span> </span><span>"localhost"</span><span>}}</span><span>
</span></code></pre></div>


<p>The system map is mostly flat, with namespaced keys. For example, Biff
configuration for the example app is stored under the <code>:example.biff</code> namespace.
You could run multiple Biff apps in the same process by using a different
namespace, e.g. <code>(biff.system/start-biff sys 'another-app)</code>. Keys under
the <code>:biff</code> namespace (e.g. <code>:biff/dev</code> from <code>config.edn</code> above) will become
defaults for all Biff apps.</p>

<p>Similarly, the return values from <code>biff.system/start-biff</code> will be namespaced. For example,
you can get the Crux node in our example app with <code>(:example.biff/node @biff.core/system)</code>.</p>

<p>When the <code>:biff/init</code> plugin reads in your <code>config.edn</code> file, it will merge the
nested maps according to the current environment and the value of <code>:inherit</code>.
The default environment is <code>:prod</code>. This can be overridden by setting the
<code>BIFF_ENV</code> environment variable:</p>
<div><pre><code><span>BIFF_ENV</span><span>=</span>dev clj <span>-m</span> biff.core
</code></pre></div>
<p>Here is a complete list of configuration options and their default values. See the following sections
for a deeper explanation.</p>

<p>Note: <code>:foo/*</code> is used to denote all keywords prefixed by <code>:foo/</code> or <code>:foo.</code>.</p>
<div><pre><code><span>; === Config for the :biff/init plugin ===</span><span>

</span><span>:biff.init/start-nrepl</span><span> </span><span>true</span><span>
</span><span>:biff.init/nrepl-port</span><span> </span><span>7888</span><span>
</span><span>:biff.init/instrument</span><span> </span><span>false</span><span> </span><span>; Calls orchestra.spec.test/instrument if true.</span><span>
</span><span>:biff.init/timbre</span><span> </span><span>true</span><span>
</span><span>:timbre/*</span><span> </span><span>...</span><span>               </span><span>; If :biff.init/timbre is true, these keys are passed to</span><span>
                            </span><span>; taoensso.timbre/merge-config! (without the timbre prefix).</span><span>


</span><span>; === Config for biff.system/start-biff ===</span><span>
</span><span>; Note: app-ns is the second parameter in biff.system/start-biff</span><span>

</span><span>; REQUIRED</span><span>
</span><span>:biff/host</span><span> </span><span>nil</span><span>          </span><span>; The hostname this app will be served on, e.g. "example.com" for prod</span><span>
                        </span><span>; or "localhost" for dev.</span><span>

</span><span>; RECOMMENDED</span><span>
</span><span>:biff/static-pages</span><span> </span><span>nil</span><span>  </span><span>; A map from paths to Rum data structures, e.g.</span><span>
                        </span><span>; {"/hello/" [:html [:body [:p {:style {:color "red"}} "hello"]]]}</span><span>
</span><span>:biff/rules</span><span> </span><span>nil</span><span>         </span><span>; An authorization rules data structure.</span><span>
</span><span>:biff/fn-whitelist</span><span> </span><span>nil</span><span>  </span><span>; Collection of fully-qualified function symbols to allow in</span><span>
                        </span><span>; Crux queries sent from the …</span></code></pre></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://findka.com/biff/">https://findka.com/biff/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://findka.com/biff/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23921220</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 20:28:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Consider getting a “DIY” degree online instead of a traditional CS major]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 103 | Comments 160 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23919579">thread link</a>) | @pashabitz
<br/>
July 22, 2020 | https://www.pashabitz.com/posts/undergrad-altenative/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.pashabitz.com/posts/undergrad-altenative/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
			<p>As universities are switching to <a href="https://www.marketwatch.com/story/as-pandemic-rages-prominent-colleges-announce-online-semesters-11594130062">100% remote teaching in the coming semester</a>, many undergraduate students should strongly consider getting a “DIY” CS degree: take the same courses you would at your own school, but on any one of the online Massive Open Online Course (MOOC) platforms, like <a href="https://coursera.org/">Coursera</a> or <a href="https://edx.org/">edX</a>.</p>
<h2 id="advantages">Advantages</h2>
<p><strong>Cost</strong>: this one is a no-brainer. According to <a href="https://www.usnews.com/education/best-colleges/paying-for-college/articles/paying-for-college-infographic">US News</a> one year of college tuition costs $10,116 on average for in-state students at a public school, and $36,801 on average at private schools.</p>
<p>Compare this with just a few hundred dollars for taking the equivalent MOOCs.</p>
<p>If you don’t have the money - you just saved yourself a decade of paying off student debt. If you do have the money - congrats! Put it in an investment account and use it as seed money for your first startup company!</p>
<p><strong>Better teaching</strong>: MOOCs are now freely available from the very best schools and world class professors, even if you didn’t get into Stanford or Harvard.</p>
<h2 id="disadvantages">Disadvantages</h2>
<p><strong>No face time</strong>: you will be getting little to no live, personal time with the professors and TAs. This is somewhat mitigated by the TAs actively participating in the online forums the most MOOC platforms have, but still - not the same.</p>
<p><strong>No community</strong>: this one is the biggest one IMO. You don’t have the experience of learning together with your peers. MOOC platforms do have forums and group projects and it’s likely those features will continue to evolve and improve.</p>
<p><strong>No college life</strong>: you will be missing on the college experience. This one is a big one. However, with the current uncertainty around COVID19 - there’s no telling how many semesters you’ll be missing out on <em>anyway</em>, so you might end up not missing as much.</p>
<p><strong>No structure</strong>: you will have to be very disciplined. There will be no structure of “being at school”. You’ll need to get your butt out of bed and do the work, by yourself, at home.</p>
<p><strong>Existing investment</strong>: if you’re a junior or senior, you’ve already invested time, effort and money into your degree. Switching to self-directed online learning will nullify that.</p>
<p><strong>No degree</strong>: at the end of it all you’re not getting a degree. Those still matter to many but I believe it matters less over time. If you invest effort into creating a viable curriculum, doing all the work and getting the certificates, and documenting everything - you’ll end up with a very impressive “DIY degree”.</p>
<p>As a hiring manager, if I saw this on a resume (I haven’t yet) - I would be very impressed.</p>
<h2 id="future">Future</h2>
<p>There is lots of room and value in creating an online learning “community” where students will be able to engage with peers and teachers in a live, face-to-face manner. This functionality will continue to improve on the existing MOOC platforms, but can also exist as a third party product.</p>
<p>Another missing feature that should exist is pre-built degree curriculums for different majors, linking out to all the available (and recommended or “best”) MOOCs for each subject.</p>

		</section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.pashabitz.com/posts/undergrad-altenative/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23919579</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 17:44:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The trauma of Facebook’s content moderators]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 213 | Comments 238 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23918763">thread link</a>) | @donohoe
<br/>
July 22, 2020 | https://restofworld.org/2020/facebook-international-content-moderators/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://restofworld.org/2020/facebook-international-content-moderators/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			
<p><span>E</span>arlier this year, when Facebook reached a $52 million settlement with lawyers representing more than 10,000 former and current content moderators in four U.S. states, their colleagues in India and the Philippines were entirely left out.</p>



<p>In their case against Facebook, workers in the United States had claimed that examining content on the social media giant’s platform, which can include screening for everything from child pornography to videos of terrorist decapitations, had led to severe psychological <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/25/18229714/cognizant-facebook-content-moderator-interviews-trauma-working-conditions-arizona">consequences</a>. And like their American colleagues, Asian workers, thousands of whom are employed as content moderators by outsourcing firms like Genpact and Cognizant, have been reporting<a href="https://www.newyorker.com/tech/annals-of-technology/the-human-toll-of-protecting-the-internet-from-the-worst-of-humanity" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> grueling working conditions</a> that<a href="https://www.livemint.com/news/india/inside-the-world-of-india-s-content-mods-11584543074609.html"> expose them to a stream</a> of violent, graphic content, leaving some of them with lasting mental scars.</p>



<p>Facebook <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2020/06/08/1002894/facebook-needs-30000-of-its-own-content-moderators-says-a-new-report/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">employs more than 15,000</a> content moderators globally. While the lawsuit provided relief for some moderators in the U.S., it did not address the plight of those who worked for the company abroad.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“In the U.S., people can speak up for their rights,” one former content moderator, a 25-year-old man in India who requested anonymity, told <em>Rest of World</em>. “But it’s not the same here.”</p>



<p><strong>Read: <a href="https://restofworld.org/2020/facebook-myanmar-scale/">The trouble with scale: why not all growth is good</a></strong></p>



<p>The outsourcing boom began in India and the Philippines in the late 1980s and 1990s, when Western technology companies began offloading back-office functions like customer service or IT to countries with well-educated but considerably cheaper workforces. Today, business process outsourcing (BPO) companies employ more than 1.2 million people in the Philippines and more than <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/business/the-transformation-of-indias-bpo-industry-1776399" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">1.1 million</a> in India. When Facebook began outsourcing its moderation efforts in the late aughts, the two countries <a href="https://www.latimes.com/business/la-fi-philippines-economy-20150202-story.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">established themselves</a> as hubs for BPO, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2012/03/29/world/asia/29iht-letter29.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">most notably</a> call center work.</p>



<p>Unlike U.S.-based moderators, for whom the job is often temporary, many Indian and Filipino moderators consider BPO work a career path unto itself. These jobs, often performed by workers who are educated and English proficient but not particularly well-off, can function as a springboard to the middle class. Without these foreign workers, Facebook would be inundated with the type of violent content that would eventually drive users and advertisers away.</p>



<p>“Given the centrality of content moderation, it’s not natural to outsource it,” says Paul Barrett, deputy director of the Center for Business and Human Rights at New York University. “It makes it somewhat problematic right from the start because the function is that important.”</p>



<p>Rahul, a 30-year-old man in Hyderabad, India, who asked to use a pseudonym to protect his identity,&nbsp;joined Genpact after working in customer services at a bank for several years. The starting salary was good, close to $500 a month (now it’s closer to $200), and he found the opportunity to work on-site at Facebook alluring.</p>



<p>When Rahul arrived at the company’s Hyderabad office, he marveled at its plush couches, Ping-Pong tables, and meals catered by the best restaurants in the city. Rahul hadn’t seen anything like it before. The chance to tell his friends that he worked in Hitech City, a campus for some of the most notable international tech companies, seemed too good to pass up. “It was 60% of why I took the job,” he said.&nbsp;</p>


		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/GettyImages-1142321813-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/GettyImages-1142321813-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/GettyImages-1142321813-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/GettyImages-1142321813-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/GettyImages-1142321813-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/GettyImages-1142321813-2800x1866.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 600px(max-width: 992px) calc(100vw - 40px), (max-width: 1140px) calc(100vw - 290px), calc(100vw - ((100vw - 640px)/2))" alt="AUSTIN, TX - MARCH 5: Content moderators work at a Facebook office in Austin, Texas. (Photo by Ilana Panich-Linsman for The Washington Post via Getty Images)">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				<span itemprop="copyrightHolder">Ilana Panich-Linsman for The Washington Post via Getty Images</span>
			</figcaption>
		</figure>


<p>Rafael, a Filipino man who spoke to <em>Rest of World </em>on the condition that he be identified by a pseudonym to protect his identity, said that he took on content moderation work to advance his career. A former journalism student who enjoyed writing, he was happy to exercise his creativity by writing blog posts for some of his firm’s other clients, in addition to his moderation work.</p>



<p>Even when the work proved trying, he focused on the potential for professional growth. “To enrich my portfolio, I stuck with it for some time,” Rafael said. He also noted that as soon as he saw an opportunity to leave content moderation and take a new job, two years into the position, he “jumped on it.”</p>



<p>Daniel Charest, a Dallas-based attorney, represented some of the moderators in the U.S. suit. His success, he said, stemmed largely from the ability to discuss the psychological harm done by the work to his clients, who were diagnosed with PTSD, depression, and anxiety by psychological professionals, in court. But in countries like India and the Philippines, social stigmas and a lack of mental health access often stand in the way of speaking openly about psychological issues, not to mention getting diagnoses in the first place.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Rafael felt comfortable and even confident moderating everything from hate speech to pornography. But it was a graphic video of a child being abused that stuck with him. After seeing the video, he began to notice a change in his own behavior that worried him. “I am not a bad person,” he told <em>Rest of World. </em>“But I’d find myself doing little diabolical things, saying things I would regret. Thinking things I didn’t want to.”</p>



<p>At the time, the company he worked for did not offer its moderators any sort of in-house counseling. So he paid for therapy, using his own money. When asked if he believed companies like Facebook should be responsible for bearing these types of costs on behalf of moderators, Rafael said he had signed a nondisclosure agreement with his current company, preventing him from answering such a question.</p>



<p>“Sometimes the despair and darkness of people will get to you, even if you say, ‘Oh, I’m a professional, I can handle that,’” he said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In his first few weeks on the job, Rahul felt shocked by the graphic videos he encountered of car crashes and child abuse. Eventually, he grew desensitized.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“It gets to a point where you can eat your lunch while watching a video of someone dying. … But at the end of the day, you still have to be human.” Rahul said he didn’t see a therapist — it wouldn’t have been useful to him, he said.</p>



<p>Rahul’s experience of desensitization mirrors that of other moderators, one former counselor who worked with Genpact and requested anonymity, told <em>Rest of World</em>. When moderators finally did seek treatment — often when content would remind them of events in their personal lives — they were surprised to be affected. According to the former counselor, “They’d say, ‘I’ve been doing this for so long. Why am I feeling this now?’”</p>



<p>According to Dr. K. Jyothirmayi, a Hyderabad-based psychiatrist, stigmas, such as the perceived impact of a mental health diagnosis on one’s marital prospects, often prevent young Indians from seeking treatment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Philippines has comparatively <a href="https://www.rappler.com/nation/205425-duterte-signs-mental-health-law-services-philippines" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">progressive mental health legislation</a>, but barriers and stigmas persist.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Issues ranging from Manila’s notorious traffic to the prohibitive costs of mental health care, may make treatment unattainable to the average Filipino BPO worker, according to Lawrence Wang, founder of MyGolana, Inc., a U.S.-based online counseling startup that works in the Philippines.</p>



<p>While Rafael had to seek private counseling, some BPO firms do offer this service in-house in the Philippines, though even that can be outsourced.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mariel, who also asked that she be identified by a pseudonym because she is bound by a nondisclosure agreement, worked as a hotline counselor at a BPO company. Her clients were employees at other BPO companies, including content moderators for Facebook. Because the sessions took place over the phone, Mariel was not able to offer psychological diagnoses.</p>



<p>Over the course of her two years with the company, Mariel had several clients who began to contemplate suicide after moderating suicide-related content. Callers who expressed suicidal thoughts or tendencies were flagged to the firm handling content moderation and referred to an in-person counselor. But, she said, there were no such protocols for moderators experiencing other issues, such as anxiety, depression, or sleep deprivation, that might alert the company to brewing mental health crises.</p>


		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/GettyImages-968999822-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/GettyImages-968999822-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/GettyImages-968999822-400x266.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/GettyImages-968999822-600x399.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/GettyImages-968999822-1600x1065.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/GettyImages-968999822-2800x1864.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 600px(max-width: 992px) calc(100vw - 40px), (max-width: 1140px) calc(100vw - 290px), calc(100vw - ((100vw - 640px)/2))" alt="A man uses Facebook on a mobile phone in Yangon on June 7, 2018. - Facebook has blacklisted a group of Myanmar Buddhist hardliners including monks notorious for bilious hate speech against Rohingya Muslims, the company said June 7, as it scrambles to show it is tackling inflammatory content. (Photo by Ye Aung THU / AFP)        (Photo credit should read YE AUNG THU/AFP via Getty Images)">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				<span itemprop="copyrightHolder">YE AUNG THU/AFP via Getty Images</span>
			</figcaption>
		</figure>


<p>“The deep seething thought will haunt you; it will creep you out,” Rafael said. “It’s impossible that it wouldn’t, because I saw it; it’s already recorded in my mind.” Rafael attributes his ability to recover from seeing the video to therapy.</p>



<p>“I feel like, if I had not consulted a specialist back then, it [the feeling of being haunted by the video] would have manifested in some form that I would have regretted later on.”</p>



<p>Even if moderators did receive in-person counseling, they would run into inhospitable legal climates.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In India, workers’ compensation lawsuits are adjudicated through various&nbsp;laws, but the country’s legal framework does not consider mental health an occupational hazard. “Indian labor law frameworks were designed with factories in mind,” Ayush Rathi, a researcher with India’s Centre for Internet &amp; Society, told <em>Rest of World</em>.</p>



<p>Geetha Devarajan, a labor lawyer and consultant to the Forum for IT Employees, a trade union for IT and BPO workers, said Indian content moderators might file a lawsuit under the country’s Industrial Disputes Act of 1947. But before filing a lawsuit under the act, moderators would have to be unionized and enter arbitration with their employers in order to try to reach an acceptable compromise.</p>



<p>Though labor laws in the Philippines generally state that third-party companies share responsibility for employees working for a contracting firm, <a href="https://iclg.com/practice-areas/outsourcing-laws-and-regulations/philippines">those regulations do not apply to the BPO industry</a> — which allows third-party companies that outsource work to BPO firms to avoid responsibility for the employees who do that work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The entire legal system in the Philippines is designed to attract foreign investment into industries like business process outsourcing,” said Alden Sajor Marte-Wood, an assistant professor at …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://restofworld.org/2020/facebook-international-content-moderators/">https://restofworld.org/2020/facebook-international-content-moderators/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://restofworld.org/2020/facebook-international-content-moderators/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23918763</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 16:33:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Terminal Server on a Budget]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 68 | Comments 31 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23915777">thread link</a>) | @Jaruzel
<br/>
July 22, 2020 | https://blog.lasseter.org/posts/2020/07/terminal-server-on-a-budget/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.lasseter.org/posts/2020/07/terminal-server-on-a-budget/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <p>The following is the result of my junkyard-wars attempt to throw together a terminal server solution in the continued pursuit of zero-touch provisioning and administration of my home linux systems.</p>
<h2 id="why-i-wanted-remote-console-access">Why I wanted remote console access</h2>
<p>I run a number of services in my home covering all the essentials such as media serving, DNS, local cloud, PBX, Minecraft containers, etc.  This started out years ago from a single Mac Mini, but has grown over time to consist of two redundant headless PCs.  Having two systems rather than one has been critical for uptime as my family has become more dependent on these services.  Embracing IaC (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Infrastructure_as_code">Infrastructure as Code</a>) through tools like Ansible has helped tremendously;  particularly with the reality of a home network where I can’t just drop other responsibilities to put on my sysadmin dad cap (or <a href="https://getfedora.org/">fedora</a> in my case).</p>
<p>Having this redundancy has helped, but more than a few times I have gotten into a situation where I have attempted to preform a system update on one of the pair remotely from cafe or sofa and the PC failed to come back up after a reboot.  Often this was due to DKMS mods that didn’t work on a new kernel version or things of that nature.  I would have to either give up on it until I had time to get physical access (get off the sofa) or beg one of my kids to act as remote hands.  These are PCs and they don’t have any iLO, LOM, or DRAC built in.  I could not justify the cost of upgrading to server-grade motherboards.  I needed something that would give me remote console access to these systems on the cheap.  I spotted a Raspberry Pi collecting dust in the corner of my office and started to have some ideas.</p>

    <p><img src="https://blog.lasseter.org/img/grub_screen.png" alt="retro term grub screen"></p><h2 id="serial-hardware">Serial hardware</h2>
<p>It has been a while, but I have great memories of pinning out custom serial cables.  Spending hours in the blissful white-noise hum of the data center with my trusty RS-232 breakout box (das blinkenlights), occasionally an oscilloscope if things got really desperate, and a huge box of almost every conceivable serial adaptor and null modem, but almost never the one you need.  I even impressed my wife (gf at that time) back then by turning a box of spare shiny silver RJ45-DB9 adaptors into ornaments for our first Christmas tree.  At least, I think she was impressed.  Yes, of course she was impressed.  That was the coolest tree in all of New York that year.  The way the lights reflected off the silver Sun Microsystems logos really captured the holiday spirit.  But I digress.  I no longer have that box of serial adaptors and my wife somehow can’t remember where it went since we got maried.  So, off to Amazon I went.</p>
<p>My PCs didn’t have serial ports on the back, though a quick look under the hood showed that both had COM1 headers.  I just needed to get backplates for access.  But, these these are pretty cheap: <a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/gp/product/B001Y1F0HW">https://www.amazon.co.jp/gp/product/B001Y1F0HW</a></p>

    <p><img src="https://blog.lasseter.org/img/serial_orders.png" alt="adaptor and backplate"></p><h2 id="cable-runs">Cable runs</h2>
<p>Now that my PCs had serial ports, I needed to decide how to connect to them.  My idea was to use a Raspberry Pi as a terminal server and connect to the two serial ports of the PCs using USB-DB9 RS-232 adaptors,  But, before getting the RaPi involved I would just connect the servers to each other in the same fashion. I wanted to have some flexibility with what cables I used in case I changed how far apart the PCs sat, so I opted for a cableless adaptor that I could plug a USB cable extender into of whatever length I needed.  I already had spare extenders, so this worked out great.  I found these adaptors came in two varieties: PL2303 and FTDI.  I checked reviews long enough to find evidence of Linux users using the FTDI kind with success and went with that one.  <a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/gp/product/B0769G9HK4">https://www.amazon.co.jp/gp/product/B0769G9HK4</a></p>
<h2 id="bios-changes">BIOS changes</h2>
<p>On each PC, I booted into BIOS and confirmed COM1 was enabled.  Both had the ability to turn it off, but they were both on by default, so no change needed.  While I was in there I also looked for the BIOS settings to auto-power-on after power-loss and set those so that I would not have to press a button to start them up when power returned.  Now with both systems running again and each connected to the other via USB to serial, I was done with the hardware side of the project (aside from the RaPi addition to come).</p>
<h2 id="configuring-io">Configuring IO</h2>
<p>I run CentOS on my servers.  If you use this post as a guide, do keep that in mind.  The following software configuration is likely to be different outside of the RHEL/CentOS/Fedora family.</p>
<h3 id="giving-the-serial-port-access-to-login">Giving the serial port access to login</h3>
<p>getty is the program that listens for terminal connections and provides login access to a given terminal.  Here I enabled and started the service for COM1 (ttyS0).  Without this, the remote serial user would never be prompted to log in.</p>
<p><code>$ sudo systemctl enable --now serial-getty@ttyS0.service</code></p>
<h3 id="grub-setup">Grub setup</h3>
<p>I needed to configure grub2 to use the serial port for input and output, otherwise I would not be able to interact with grub on a reboot.  An example is escaping the boot process at the grub menu in order to boot into recovery mode or to simply boot from the last known working kernel.  To achieve this, I made these changes to /etc/default/grub:</p>
<ul>
<li>Set GRUB_TERMINAL_OUTPUT and GRUB_TERMINAL_INPUT to <code>serial</code>.</li>
<li>Set GRUB_SERIAL_COMMAND with the appropriate speed of 115200.</li>
<li>Added <code>console=ttyS0,115200n8 serial</code> to the end of GRUB_CMDLINE_LINUX so the kernel would also use the serial port.</li>
<li>Removed both <code>rhgb</code> and <code>quiet</code> from GRUB_CMDLINE_LINUX in order to have verbose output of the boot status.</li>
</ul>
<p>Here is my grub config:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="ini"><span># /etc/default/grub</span>
<span>GRUB_TIMEOUT</span><span>=</span><span>5</span>
<span>GRUB_DISTRIBUTOR</span><span>=</span><span>"$(sed 's, release .*$,,g' /etc/system-release)"</span>
<span>GRUB_DEFAULT</span><span>=</span><span>saved</span>
<span>GRUB_DISABLE_SUBMENU</span><span>=</span><span>true</span>
<span>GRUB_TERMINAL_OUTPUT</span><span>=</span><span>"serial"</span>
<span>GRUB_TERMINAL_INPUT</span><span>=</span><span>"serial"</span>
<span>GRUB_SERIAL_COMMAND</span><span>=</span><span>"serial --speed=115200"</span>
<span>GRUB_CMDLINE_LINUX</span><span>=</span><span>"crashkernel=auto resume=/dev/mapper/cl-swap rd.lvm.lv=cl/root rd.lvm.lv=cl/swap console=ttyS0,115200n8 serial"</span>
<span>GRUB_DISABLE_RECOVERY</span><span>=</span><span>"true"</span>
<span>GRUB_ENABLE_BLSCFG</span><span>=</span><span>true</span>
</code></pre></div><p>To activate this new configuration, I used <code>grub2-mkconfig -o &lt;output file&gt;</code>.  You would need to check on your setup, but for recent RHEL/CentOS/Fedora systems, that would be <code>/boot/grub2/grub.cfg</code> for MBR or <code>/boot/efi/EFI/&lt;distro&gt;/grub.cfg</code> for EFI.</p>
<h2 id="console-session-management">Console session management</h2>
<p>There are a number of different tools you could use to access the terminal, such as <code>screen</code>, <code>minicom</code>, or <code>tip</code>, but I want something that will manage the connection fully as a daemon and keep logs of the output for my review.  That is important because sometimes when a system runs into trouble, it may be able to log clues to the console even when permanent storage is not available at that moment.  There is a fantastic program called <code>conserver</code> that does all that and more.  You can define connections, whether they be local or over ssh.  It can facilitate user management with access rules and even concurrent connections to the same terminal session with the admins taking turns having write access.  In the world of serial consoles, this is all very exciting.  Well, I think it is exciting, anyway.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.conserver.com/">https://www.conserver.com/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/bstansell/conserver">https://github.com/bstansell/conserver</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="setting-up-conserver">Setting up conserver</h3>
<p>For this specific setup, I’ve installed and configured conserver in a very limited way.  Both servers run the conserver service independently rather than having it centralized.  I configure <code>console</code> in <code>/etc/hosts</code> to point to localhost on both systems.  This is needed because conserver’s client program, <code>console</code> looks to connect to the host named <code>console</code> by default.  And finally, the <code>/etc/conserver.cf</code> configuration is minimal and defines just enough to instruct it to manage the tty of our connected USB serial adaptor (<code>/dev/ttyUSB0</code> in my case for both systems).</p>
<p>On each server I install the following two packages which are availible in the <code>EPEL</code> repo for REHL/CentOS and the base <code>fedora</code> repo for Fedora:</p>
<ul>
<li>conserver</li>
<li>conserver-client</li>
</ul>
<p><code>$ sudo dnf install -y conserver conserver-client</code></p>
<p>I’ve found that this package doesn’t create the default log directory, so I need to do that ahead of time:</p>
<p><code>$ sudo mkdir -p /var/consoles</code></p>
<p>This minimal configuration will set up a managed session named <code>peer</code> for device <code>/dev/ttyUSB0</code>.  If you would rather use the hostname of the remote system, then change that.  And of course, adjust the tty name if it doesn’t match what is correct for your environment.</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="tcl"><span># /etc/conserver.cf
</span><span>
</span><span></span>default <span>*</span> <span>{</span>
        logfile <span>/</span>var<span>/</span>consoles<span>/&amp;</span><span>;</span>        <span># '&amp;' is replaced with console name
</span><span></span>        timestamp <span>1</span>hab<span>;</span>                 <span># write timestamps
</span><span></span>        rw <span>*</span><span>;</span>                           <span># allow all users
</span><span></span>        master localhost<span>;</span>
<span>}</span>

console peer <span>{</span>
        type device<span>;</span>
        device <span>/</span>dev<span>/</span>ttyUSB0<span>;</span> parity none<span>;</span> baud <span>115200</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>

access <span>*</span> <span>{</span>
        trusted <span>127.0</span>.0.1<span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div><p>Lastly, I enable and start the conserver daemon:</p>
<p><code>$ sudo systemctl enable --now conserver</code></p>
<h3 id="using-conserver">Using conserver</h3>
<p>Now that I have installed and configured all of the hardware and software and have the two servers each connected to each other’s serial ports, I’m ready to connect with conserver’s <code>console</code> command.  In the example configuration above, I named the conserver session <code>peer</code>, and thus I connect by issuing the following:</p>
<p><code>$ console peer</code></p>
<p>If everything is working I should get a login prompt from the peer server when I hit enter after launching console.  The default escape sequence while within console is <code>ctrl</code>-<code>e</code> <code>c</code> (ctrl and the e key, let go, then press c).  To disconnect from the console, enter the escape sequence, followed by a period (<code>ctrl</code>-<code>e</code> <code>c</code> <code>.</code>).  To see all of the control codes, type the escape sequence, followed by a question mark (<code>ctrl</code>-<code>e</code> <code>c</code> <code>?</code>).  The man page on <code>console</code> explains the rest, however that covers the basics to connect and disconnect from the running console session.  You can review log history from within the same interface, but I usually find it easier to open the generated log file in <code>/var/console</code> with my favorite pager.</p>
<h2 id="results">Results</h2>
<p>So far this setup has served me well and I have already needed to use remote console access a few times while doing installs and network interface reconfigurations without …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.lasseter.org/posts/2020/07/terminal-server-on-a-budget/">https://blog.lasseter.org/posts/2020/07/terminal-server-on-a-budget/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.lasseter.org/posts/2020/07/terminal-server-on-a-budget/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23915777</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 11:09:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Design Docs at Google]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 423 | Comments 171 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23915521">thread link</a>) | @thesephist
<br/>
July 22, 2020 | https://www.industrialempathy.com/posts/design-docs-at-google/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.industrialempathy.com/posts/design-docs-at-google/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><article><p>One of the key elements of Google's software engineering culture is the use of defining software designs through design docs. These are relatively informal documents that the primary author or authors of a software system or application create before they embark on the coding project. The design doc documents the high level implementation strategy and key design decisions with emphasis on the trade-offs that were considered during those decisions.</p><p>As software engineers our job is not to produce code per se, but rather to solve problems. Unstructured text, like in the form of a design doc, may be the better tool for solving problems early in a project lifecycle, as it may be more concise and easier to comprehend, and communicates the problems and solutions at a higher level than code.</p><p>Besides the original documentation of a software design, design docs fulfill the following functions in the software development lifecycle:</p><ul><li><p>Early identification of design issues when making changes is still cheap.</p></li><li><p>Achieving consensus around a design in the organization.</p></li><li><p>Ensuring consideration of cross-cutting concerns.</p></li><li><p>Scaling knowledge of senior engineers into the organization.</p></li><li><p>Form the basis of an organizational memory around design decisions.</p></li><li><p>Acts as a summary artifact in the technical portfolio of the software designer(s).</p></li></ul><h2 id="anatomy-of-a-design-doc">Anatomy of a design doc <a href="#anatomy-of-a-design-doc">#</a></h2><p>Design docs are informal documents and thus don’t follow a strict guideline for their content. Rule #1 is: Write them in whatever form makes the most sense for the particular project.</p><p>Having said that, a certain structure has established itself as really useful.</p><h3 id="context-and-scope">Context and scope <a href="#context-and-scope">#</a></h3><p>This section gives the reader a very rough overview of the landscape in which the new system is being built and what is actually being built. This isn’t a requirements doc. Keep it succinct! The goal is that readers are brought up to speed but some previous knowledge can be assumed and detailed info can be linked to. This section should be entirely focused on objective background facts.</p><h3 id="goals-and-non-goals">Goals and non-goals <a href="#goals-and-non-goals">#</a></h3><p>A short list of bullet points of what the goals of the system are, and, sometimes more importantly, what non-goals are. Note, that non-goals aren’t negated goals like “The system shouldn’t crash”, but rather things that could reasonably be goals, but are explicitly chosen not to be goals. A good example would be “ACID compliance”; when designing a database, you’d certainly want to know whether that is a goal or non-goal. And if it is a non-goal you might still select a solution that provides it, if it doesn’t introduce trade-offs that prevent achieving the goals.</p><h3 id="the-actual-design">The actual design <a href="#the-actual-design">#</a></h3><p>This section should start with an overview and then go into details.</p><p><img alt="Visualization of how to draw an owl. First picture: two circles labeled &quot;1. Draw some circles&quot;. Second picture: Picture of an own labeled &quot;2. Draw the rest of the fucking owl&quot;" height="488" src="https://www.industrialempathy.com/img/remote/ZCBwPv.jpg" width="600" decoding="async" loading="lazy" sizes="(max-width: 608px) 100vw, 608px" srcset="https://www.industrialempathy.com/img/remote/ZCBwPv-1920w.jpg 1920w, https://www.industrialempathy.com/img/remote/ZCBwPv-1280w.jpg 1280w, https://www.industrialempathy.com/img/remote/ZCBwPv-640w.jpg 640w, https://www.industrialempathy.com/img/remote/ZCBwPv-320w.jpg 320w"></p><p>The design doc is <em>the place to write down the trade-offs</em> you made in designing your software. Focus on those trade-offs to produce a useful document with long-term value. That is, given the context (facts), goals and non-goals (requirements), the design doc is the place to suggest solutions and show why a particular solution best satisfies those goals.</p><p>The point of writing a document over a more formal medium is to provide the flexibility to express the problem set at hand in an appropriate manner. Because of this, there is no explicit guidance for how to actually describe the design.</p><p>Having said that, a few best practices and repeating topics have emerged that make sense for a large percentage of design docs:</p><h4 id="system-context-diagram"><strong>System-context-diagram</strong> <a href="#system-context-diagram">#</a></h4><p>In many docs a <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System_context_diagram">system-context-diagram</a></em> can be very useful. Such a diagram shows the system as part of the larger technical landscape and allows readers to contextualize the new design given its environment that they are already familiar with.</p><p><img alt="Block diagram showing how various systems are related to each other. The actual text is just examples and not needed to be seen to understand the example." height="333" src="https://www.industrialempathy.com/img/remote/2mPr0N.png" width="655" decoding="async" loading="lazy" sizes="(max-width: 608px) 100vw, 608px" srcset="https://www.industrialempathy.com/img/remote/2mPr0N-1920w.jpg 1920w, https://www.industrialempathy.com/img/remote/2mPr0N-1280w.jpg 1280w, https://www.industrialempathy.com/img/remote/2mPr0N-640w.jpg 640w, https://www.industrialempathy.com/img/remote/2mPr0N-320w.jpg 320w"><br><em>Example of a system-context-diagram.</em></p><h4 id="apis">APIs <a href="#apis">#</a></h4><p>If the system under design exposes an API, then sketching out that API is usually a good idea. In most cases, however, one should withstand the temptation to copy-paste formal interface or data definitions into the doc as these are often verbose, contain unnecessary detail and quickly get out of date. Instead focus on the parts that are relevant to the design and its trade-offs.</p><h4 id="data-storage">Data storage <a href="#data-storage">#</a></h4><p>Systems that store data should likely discuss how and in what rough form this happens. Similar to the advice on APIs, and for the same reasons, copy-pasting complete schema definitions should be avoided. Instead focus on the parts that are relevant to the design and its trade-offs.</p><h4 id="code-and-pseudo-code">Code and pseudo-code <a href="#code-and-pseudo-code">#</a></h4><p>Design docs should rarely contain code, or pseudo-code except in situations where novel algorithms are described. As appropriate, link to prototypes that show the implementability of the design.</p><h4 id="degree-of-constraint">Degree of constraint <a href="#degree-of-constraint">#</a></h4><p>One of the primary factors that would influence the shape of a software design and hence the design doc, is the degree of constraint of the solution space.</p><p>On one end of the extreme is the “greenfield software project”, where all we know are the goals, and the solution can be whatever makes the most sense. Such a document may be wide-ranging, but it also needs to quickly define a set of rules that allow zooming in on a manageable set of solutions.</p><p>On the other end are systems where the possible solutions are very well defined, but it isn’t at all obvious how they could even be combined to achieve the goals. This may be a legacy system that is difficult to change and wasn’t designed to do what you want it to do or a library design that needs to operate within the constraints of the host programming language.</p><p>In this situation you may be able to enumerate all the things you can do relatively easily, but you need to creatively put those things together to achieve the goals. There may be multiple solutions, and none of them are really great, and hence such a document should focus on selecting the best way given all identified trade-offs.</p><h3 id="alternatives-considered">Alternatives considered <a href="#alternatives-considered">#</a></h3><p>This section lists alternative designs that would have reasonably achieved similar outcomes. The focus should be on the trade-offs that each respective design makes and how those trade-offs led to the decision to select the design that is the primary topic of the document.</p><p>While it is fine to be succinct about solution that ended up not being selected, this section is one of the most important ones as it shows very explicitly why the selected solution is the best given the project goals and how other solutions, that the reader may be wondering about, introduce trade-offs that are less desirable given the goals.</p><h3 id="cross-cutting-concerns">Cross-cutting concerns <a href="#cross-cutting-concerns">#</a></h3><p>This is where your organization can ensure that certain cross-cutting concerns such as security, privacy, and observability are always taken into consideration. These are often relatively short sections that explain how the design impacts the concern and how the concern is addressed. Teams should standardize what these concerns are in their case.</p><p>Due to their importance, Google projects are required to have a dedicated privacy design doc, and there are dedicated reviews for privacy and security. While the reviews are only required to be completed by the time a project launches, it is best practice to engage with privacy and security teams as early as possible to ensure that designs take them into account from the ground up. In case of dedicated docs for these topics, the central design doc can, of course, reference them instead of going into detail.</p><h3 id="the-length-of-a-design-doc">The length of a design doc <a href="#the-length-of-a-design-doc">#</a></h3><p>Design docs should be sufficiently detailed but short enough to actually be read by busy people. The sweet spot for a larger project seems to be around 10-20ish pages. If you get way beyond that, it might make sense to split up the problem into more manageable sub problems. It should also be noted that it is absolutely possible to write a 1-3 page “mini design doc”. This is especially helpful for incremental improvements or sub tasks in an agile project–you still do all the same steps as for a longer doc, just keep things more terse and focused on a limited problem set.</p><h2 id="when-not-to-write-a-design-doc.">When <em>not</em> to write a design doc. <a href="#when-not-to-write-a-design-doc.">#</a></h2><p>Writing design docs is overhead. The decision whether to write a design doc comes down to the core trade-off of deciding whether the benefits in organizational consensus around design, documentation, senior review, etc. outweigh the extra work of creating the doc. At the center of that decision lies whether the solution to the design problem is ambiguous–because of problem complexity or solution complexity, or both. If it is not, then there is little value in going through the process of writing a doc.</p><p>A clear indicator that a doc might not be necessary are design docs that are really <em>implementation manuals</em>. If a doc basically says “This is how we are going to implement it” without going into trade-offs, alternatives, and explaining decision making (or if the solution is so obvious as to mean there were no trade-offs), then it would probably have been a better idea to write the actual program right away.</p><p>Finally, the overhead of creating and reviewing a design doc may not be compatible with prototyping and rapid iteration. However, most software projects do have a set of <em>actually known problems</em>. Subscribing to agile methodologies is not an excuse for not taking the time to get solutions to actually known problems right. Additionally, prototyping itself may be part of the design doc creation. “I tried it out and it works” is one of the best arguments for choosing a design.</p><h2 id="the-design-doc-lifecycle">The design doc lifecycle <a href="#the-design-doc-lifecycle">#</a></h2><p>The steps in the lifecycle of a design document are:</p><ol><li>Creation and rapid iteration</li><li>Review (may be in multiple rounds)</li><li>Implementation and iteration</li><li>Maintenance and learning</li></ol><h3 id="creation-and-rapid-iteration">Creation and rapid iteration <a href="#creation-and-rapid-iteration">#</a></h3><p>You write the doc. Sometimes together with a set of co-authors.</p><p>This phase quickly evolves into a time of rapid iteration where the doc is shared with colleagues who have the most knowledge about the problem space (often belonging to the same team) and through their clarifying questions and suggestions drive the doc to a first relatively stable version.</p><p>While you certainly find engineers and even teams who prefer version control and code …</p></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.industrialempathy.com/posts/design-docs-at-google/">https://www.industrialempathy.com/posts/design-docs-at-google/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.industrialempathy.com/posts/design-docs-at-google/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23915521</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 10:12:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ListenBrainz moves to TimescaleDB]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 149 | Comments 88 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23915509">thread link</a>) | @kingkool68
<br/>
July 22, 2020 | https://blog.metabrainz.org/2020/07/22/listenbrainz-moves-to-timescaledb/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.metabrainz.org/2020/07/22/listenbrainz-moves-to-timescaledb/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-8142">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	
	
	<div>
		
<p>The <a href="https://listenbrainz.org/">ListenBrainz</a> team has been working hard on moving our primary listen store from <a href="https://www.influxdata.com/">InfluxDB</a> to <a href="https://www.timescale.com/">TimescaleDB</a>, and today at UTC 16:00 we’re going to make the switch.</p>



<p>We were asked on Twitter as to why we’re making the switch — and in the interest of giving a real world use case for switching, I’m writing this post. The reasons are numerous:</p>



<p><strong>Openness</strong>: InfluxDB seems on a path that will make it less open over time. TimescaleDB and its dependence on Postgres makes us feel much safer in this regard.</p>



<p><strong>Existing use</strong>: We’ve been using Postgres for about 18 years now and it has been a reliable workhorse for us. Our team thinks in terms of Postgres and InfluxDB  always felt like a round peg in a square hole for us.</p>



<p><strong>Data structure</strong>: InfluxDB was clearly designed to store server event info. We’re storing listen information, which has a slightly different usage pattern, but this slight difference is enough for us to hit a brick wall with far fewer users in our DB than we ever anticipated. InfluxDB is simply not flexible enough for our needs.</p>



<p><strong>Query syntax and measurement names</strong>: The syntax to query InfluxDB is weird and obfuscated. We made the mistake of trying to have a measurement map to a user, but <a href="https://github.com/metabrainz/listenbrainz-server/blob/b0846d2a/listenbrainz/utils.py#L42">escaping measurement names correctly</a> nearly drove one of our team members to the loonie bin. </p>



<p><strong>Existing data</strong>: If you ever write bad data to a measurement in InfluxDB, there is no way to change it. I realize that this is a common Big Data usage pattern, but for us it represented significant challenges and serious restrictions to put simple features for our users into place. With TimescaleDB we can make the very occasional UPDATE or DELETE and move on.</p>



<p><strong>Scalability</strong>: Even though we attempted to read as much as possible in order to design a scalable schema, we still failed and got it wrong. (I don’t even think that the docs to calculate scalability even existed when we first started using InfluxDB.) Unless you are using InfluxDB in exactly the way it was meant to be used, there are chances you’ll hit this problem as well. For us, one day insert speed dropped to a ridiculously low number per second, backing up our systems. Digging into the problem we realized that our schema design had a fatal flaw and that we would have drastically change the schema to something even less intuitive in order to fix it.  This was the event that broke the camel’s back and I started searching for alternatives. </p>



<p>In moving to TimescaleDB we were able to delete a ton of complicated code and embrace a DB that we know and love. We know how Postgres scales, we know how to put it into production and we know its caveats. TimescaleDB allows us to be flexible with the data and the amazing queries that can be performed on the data is pure Postgres love. TimescaleDB still requires some careful thinking over using Postgres, it is far less than what is required when using InfluxDB. TimescaleDB also gives us a clear scaling path forward, even when TimescaleDB is still working on their own scaling roadmap. If TimescaleDB evolves anything like Postgres has, I can’t wait to see this evolution.</p>



<p>Big big thanks to the Postgres and TimescaleDB teams! </p>
	</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.metabrainz.org/2020/07/22/listenbrainz-moves-to-timescaledb/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23915509</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 10:10:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[GraphQL Query Generator]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 74 | Comments 44 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23915395">thread link</a>) | @oczek
<br/>
July 22, 2020 | https://blog.graphqleditor.com/graphql-query-generator/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.graphqleditor.com/graphql-query-generator/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>GraphQL Query Generator is an interesting library brought to you by the IBM team, which’s the main idea is to allow users to <strong>generate randomized GraphQL queries</strong> from any given GraphQL schema.</p>
<p>The first thought that comes to your mind might be:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>“Why I may ever want a bunch of randomized queries?”</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>but giving it a second thought it might be quite useful. The team behind the GraphQL Query Generator suggested <strong>two basic use-cases</strong> for their library:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Engineering</strong> - when operating a GraphQL service you might find this library useful for:</p>
<ul>
<li>developing a collection of test modules of GraphQL queries,</li>
<li>developing a test group of queries to check the effect of performance improvements,</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Scientific</strong> - to learn about the characteristics of various GraphQL services.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Queries generation</h2>
<p>The library provides two functions for generating random GraphQL queries, both expecting a GraphQL schema, as well as specific  instructions provided in configuration object as an input:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>getRandomQuery(schema: GraphQLSchema, config: Configuration)</code> - this function produces a random query from the given schema, considering configuration passed as an input,</li>
<li><code>getRandomMutation(schema: GraphQLSchema, config: Configuration)</code> -  that produces a random mutation from the given schema, considering passed configuration.</li>
</ul>
<p><span>
      <a href="https://blog.graphqleditor.com/static/3a19065691d09d87bb2b280d1da3ca32/52fbd/graphql_query_generator_diagram.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="Diagram representing how GraphQL Query Generator works" title="Diagram representing how GraphQL Query Generator works" src="https://blog.graphqleditor.com/static/3a19065691d09d87bb2b280d1da3ca32/fcda8/graphql_query_generator_diagram.png" srcset="https://blog.graphqleditor.com/static/3a19065691d09d87bb2b280d1da3ca32/12f09/graphql_query_generator_diagram.png 148w,
https://blog.graphqleditor.com/static/3a19065691d09d87bb2b280d1da3ca32/e4a3f/graphql_query_generator_diagram.png 295w,
https://blog.graphqleditor.com/static/3a19065691d09d87bb2b280d1da3ca32/fcda8/graphql_query_generator_diagram.png 590w,
https://blog.graphqleditor.com/static/3a19065691d09d87bb2b280d1da3ca32/efc66/graphql_query_generator_diagram.png 885w,
https://blog.graphqleditor.com/static/3a19065691d09d87bb2b280d1da3ca32/c83ae/graphql_query_generator_diagram.png 1180w,
https://blog.graphqleditor.com/static/3a19065691d09d87bb2b280d1da3ca32/52fbd/graphql_query_generator_diagram.png 3124w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></p>
<h5>Source: <a href="https://github.com/IBM/graphql-query-generator">github.com/IBM</a></h5>
<p>The configuration object accepts a set of predefined properties i.e.:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>maxDepth</code> - that defines the maximum depths of the query/mutation to generate,</li>
<li><code>argumentsToIgnore</code> - in which you can  list arguments names that should be ignored,</li>
<li><code>considerInterfaces</code>- which a signal for the generator that it should create queries containing interfaces,</li>
<li><code>considerUnions</code> - that creates queries that contain unions etc.</li>
</ul>
<p>The full list of available properties is available in the <a href="https://github.com/IBM/graphql-query-generator">GraphQL Query Generator docs</a>.</p>
<h3>Sample GraphQL Query Generator configuration object</h3>
<p><span>
      <a href="https://blog.graphqleditor.com/static/d771602f03451efe49368226d09bd62f/569c6/sample_configuration.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="Sample configuration object" title="Sample configuration object" src="https://blog.graphqleditor.com/static/d771602f03451efe49368226d09bd62f/fcda8/sample_configuration.png" srcset="https://blog.graphqleditor.com/static/d771602f03451efe49368226d09bd62f/12f09/sample_configuration.png 148w,
https://blog.graphqleditor.com/static/d771602f03451efe49368226d09bd62f/e4a3f/sample_configuration.png 295w,
https://blog.graphqleditor.com/static/d771602f03451efe49368226d09bd62f/fcda8/sample_configuration.png 590w,
https://blog.graphqleditor.com/static/d771602f03451efe49368226d09bd62f/efc66/sample_configuration.png 885w,
https://blog.graphqleditor.com/static/d771602f03451efe49368226d09bd62f/c83ae/sample_configuration.png 1180w,
https://blog.graphqleditor.com/static/d771602f03451efe49368226d09bd62f/569c6/sample_configuration.png 1674w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></p>
<h5>Source: <a href="https://github.com/IBM/graphql-query-generator">github.com/IBM/graphql-query-generator</a></h5>
<h2>Great addition</h2>
<p>GraphQL Query Generator is a great addition to the already broad spectrum of GraphQL tools. Its a relatively new library that is worth experimenting with as maybe you could find some other innovative ways it could be used by the GraphQL community.</p></div><p>The GraphQL Editor is a supportive tool for both advanced GraphQL users as well as those taking their first steps with GraphQL APIs. Our all-in-one development environment for GraphQL will help you build, manage &amp; deploy your GraphQL API much faster thanks to dozens of built-in micro features. Its graphical interface will also fix communication within your product team. Visualization is the key!</p></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.graphqleditor.com/graphql-query-generator/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23915395</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 09:44:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[In Bangladesh, the majority of e-commerce now happens on Facebook]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 143 | Comments 42 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23914982">thread link</a>) | @gyre007
<br/>
July 22, 2020 | https://restofworld.org/2020/bangladesh-economy-runs-on-facebook/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://restofworld.org/2020/bangladesh-economy-runs-on-facebook/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			
<p><span>I</span>n April 2020, in the midst of an ongoing national lockdown, Ahmed Imran Kabir decided to buy a parrot.&nbsp;</p>



<p>After most of the management classes Kabir taught at a university in Dhaka were canceled or moved online, he suddenly had plenty of time to focus on his passion project: becoming a part-time bird breeder. Sitting in his three-bedroom apartment one day, Kabir keyed in the phrase “Buy-sell birds Dhaka” on Facebook and joined about half a dozen groups dedicated to avian retail.</p>



<p>“Breeding pair. Age: 20 days. Contact by phone or inbox” read one post, alongside images of a pair of grayish-brown cockatiels. Another seller, located in the Kallyanpur neighborhood in Dhaka, posted pictures of yellow-feathered lutino cockatiels, with the Bengali phrase <em>hat bodol hobe — </em>which loosely translates as “to change hands.” The wording was intended to circumvent a Facebook algorithm that, to prevent wildlife trafficking, automatically takes down posts with “buy” or “sell” in the description. If an interested buyer did contact an owner, the next step was to haggle over the price of the bird on Facebook Messenger.</p>



<p>Kabir bought his first pair of birds from the 3,000-person Facebook group <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/485404175472217/">A.S.ককাটেল পাখি হাত বদল</a> — “A.S. Cockatiel changes hands.” For that purchase, the seller delivered the birds in person to collect them, and Kabir paid in cash. He was so pleased with his decision that he bought 24 more pairs over the next two weeks, including breeds such as Gouldian finches, Bengalese finches, and crested Bengalese finches. Each pair cost anywhere between $15 and $60, depending upon the breed and its age. “At one point, I started running out of space to accommodate all the birds, and sent about half a dozen Bengalese finches, along with some Gouldians, to my fiancee’s place,” he recalled. Finally, he gave in and bought a large birdcage.</p>



<p>From discovery to delivery, this whole process happened on Facebook.</p>



<p>Kabir’s story is reflective of how the majority of e-commerce now happens in Bangladesh. In the absence of giant online marketplaces like Amazon, thousands of bespoke Facebook pages and groups have been created to meet customer demand for ornaments, apparel, cosmetics, mobile accessories, and, of course, birds.</p>



<p><strong>Read: <a href="https://restofworld.org/2020/randi-rahbar-shopyobrand-iraq/"><em>“What do I do with a credit card in a country like Iraq?”</em></a></strong></p>



<p>The phenomenon has grown so much over the years that the number of stores on Facebook now eclipse the number of sellers on local e-commerce websites like Evaly, Ajkerdeal, or the Alibaba-acquired <a href="https://www.daraz.com.bd/">Daraz</a>. No one knows exactly how many of these businesses exist, but the most recent estimates suggest that Bangladesh <a href="https://idlc.com/mbr/article.php?id=192">has over 300,000</a>. The low barriers to entry —&nbsp;all an aspiring entrepreneur needs is an internet connection and around $350<strong> </strong>to cover startup costs —&nbsp;present a tremendous opportunity for a generation of young Bangladeshis reeling from mass layoffs and fear of <a href="https://www.dhakatribune.com/opinion/op-ed/2019/06/28/rise-of-the-educated-unemployed">rising unemployment</a> rates, which are projected to impact at least 15% of the working population. It also has opened other doors: in a country where just over 15 percent of women have mobile internet access, <a href="https://idlc.com/mbr/article.php?id=192">half</a> of Facebook sellers are female.</p>



<p>By and large, these Facebook stores are usually window fronts for click-and-order shopping. Unlike in formal marketplaces, most sellers are not licensed, store their inventory at home, and partner with third-party logistics companies for last-mile delivery. It’s all very simple: after a buyer makes a selection, payments are arranged via off- or online methods, and items are delivered by mail. No equivalent exists in the West, where Facebook’s forays into commerce have been met with a muted response. For a 162-million-strong country struggling with poverty and limited job growth, this new model of business is illustrative of the South Asian concept of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jugaad"><em>jugaad</em></a> — making do with what’s available. And it already has a name: F-commerce.&nbsp;</p>


		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-16-at-11.41.06-AM-e1594928419404-40x23.png" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-16-at-11.41.06-AM-e1594928419404-768x432.png" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-16-at-11.41.06-AM-e1594928419404-400x230.png 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-16-at-11.41.06-AM-e1594928419404-600x345.png 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-16-at-11.41.06-AM-e1594928419404-1600x919.png 1600w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, (max-width: 992px) calc(100vw - 40px), (max-width: 1140px) calc(100vw - 290px), calc(100vw - ((100vw - 640px)/2))" alt="https://www.facebook.com/groups/485404175472217/">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				<span itemprop="copyrightHolder"><a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/485404175472217/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">facebook.com</a></span>
			</figcaption>
		</figure>


<hr>



<p><strong>Nuzhat Akhter has</strong> been selling on Facebook for only six years, but she’s already considered a veteran in the F-commerce sphere. Her site, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/277430245935147/"><em>Posh World</em></a>, has over 8,000 followers on Facebook, thanks to her carefully cultivated selection of consumer<strong> </strong>goods. From her home in Bangladesh, Akhter sources all kinds of products — helmets, handbags, Ralph Lauren shirts, even branded car parts — and accepts preorders daily. If an item isn’t featured on her site, customers can send links or screenshots of things they want from any co.uk website. Customer service is handled via Messenger and her Facebook page, and Akhter guarantees delivery within two weeks.</p>



<p>The 34-year-old mother set up her Facebook store three months after the birth of her son in 2014 and has built a loyal following over the years. Akhter spends her mornings scouring the<em> </em>British websites of popular brands like The Body Shop, Superdrug, Clarks, and so on, hunting for flash sales or discounts. Once she finds a good deal, she shares the link on her Facebook group with screenshots: “3 hr left flash sale bodyshop 50%.” In June, orders totaled over $800. Akhter’s success is especially notable, as it’s uncommon to see a Bangladeshi woman running her own business. In many traditional South Asian households, women are discouraged from working after marriage.</p>



<p>The reason thousands of Bangladeshis depend on Akhter to do their shopping is that she has access to something very few of them do: a credit card, and an international one at that. “It’s my secret weapon,” Akhter said. To prevent money laundering, Bangladesh has issued roughly <a href="https://www.thedailystar.net/business/banking/credit-card-market-still-untapped-1452808">1.5 million</a> credit cards, and even those cards have a $300 transaction limit for international online purchases. This has created a boom in cross-border F-commerce and turned retail arbitrage into a thriving sector.</p>



<p>The rise of F-commerce has also inadvertently ushered in more-direct models of customer engagement, moving away from impersonal help pages and suggestion boxes.<strong> </strong>Qazi<strong> </strong>Fahimda Hasan, the 26-year-old founder of an F-commerce business that focuses on beauty and lifestyle products, has made this part of her brand’s identity. Through Facebook Messenger, she shares tips for identifying counterfeit products, such as checking for irregularities in packaging, spotting spelling errors, verifying barcodes, and so on. She also invested in a mini-photography studio to take professional photos and videos of her inventory. The pictures on her Facebook wall act as a real-time bulletin board for her click-and-order store. &nbsp;</p>


    <figure>
      <div>
				<ul>
					<li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Zia_Row2020-07-14-at-10.29.45-PM-5-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Zia_Row2020-07-14-at-10.29.45-PM-5-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Zia_Row2020-07-14-at-10.29.45-PM-5-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Zia_Row2020-07-14-at-10.29.45-PM-5-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Zia_Row2020-07-14-at-10.29.45-PM-5-1600x1068.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Zia_Row2020-07-14-at-10.29.45-PM-5-2800x1869.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li><li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Zia_Row2020-07-14-at-10.29.45-PM-10-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Zia_Row2020-07-14-at-10.29.45-PM-10-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Zia_Row2020-07-14-at-10.29.45-PM-10-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Zia_Row2020-07-14-at-10.29.45-PM-10-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Zia_Row2020-07-14-at-10.29.45-PM-10-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Zia_Row2020-07-14-at-10.29.45-PM-10-2800x1867.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li>
				</ul>
			</div>
      <figcaption>Akhter’s site, Posh World, has over 8,000 followers on Facebook.</figcaption>
    </figure>


<p>Globally, the hottest new trend for online sellers is livestreaming. In China, consumers on Pinduoduo are using it to break into the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/e-commerce/article/3022929/chinas-social-e-commerce-sector-more-double-us185-billion-sales">$200 billion</a> market for impulse and everyday purchases. In the United States, Amazon has been experimenting with <a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/amazon-live-launches-with-live-streamed-shopping-videos/">Amazon Live</a> Creator, which lets merchants set up streams to showcase their products. (So far, it seems to have had little success.) In Bangladesh, sellers go on Facebook Live to promote items, respond to questions, and take instant orders. Some products attract larger crowds than others. </p>



<p>“People simply go crazy for whitening creams,” said Akhter. “I mean, you could have 1,000 or 2,000 people watching a live demo on Facebook.” With little formal regulation, this is all based on trust. Many sellers aren’t concerned with looking glamorous or dressing up for the camera, and at first glance, their streams often come across as an ersatz version of the Home Shopping Network in the U.S.</p>


		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screenshot_20200719-054733-40x87.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screenshot_20200719-054733-600x1066.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screenshot_20200719-054733-400x867.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screenshot_20200719-054733-600x1300.jpg 600w, " sizes="300px" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure>


<p>Before the pandemic, a seller who goes by only Sulaiman would spend his evenings holding Facebook livestreams in front of multicolor <em>sarees</em> in his clothing shop, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/symbolfashionhouse/videos/2684482508481909/">Symbol Fashion House</a>, in Dhaka. Then, he was forced to change venues. In a twenty-minute stream from his living room, Sulaiman <a href="https://www.facebook.com/symbolfashionhouse/videos/">shows</a> off a variety of clothes on offer, explaining the decorative stones on a <em>salwar </em>and the embroidery on a fabric. “Each of our <em>chunni</em> prints cost 550 taka [6$]. Take a screenshot and inbox the picture if interested,” Sulaiman exhorts viewers. Throughout the livestream, buyers flood the chat, asking to see more colors and sizes. “We started doing Facebook Live only about six months ago,” Sulaiman told <em>Rest of World. </em>Since then, he has averaged about $4,500 a month in online orders.</p>



<p>F-commerce emerged in Bangladesh largely because there was no major e-commerce platform to absorb all the business. But although it’s biggest there, this form of selling isn’t exclusive to the country, or even the region: globally, 160 million small stores operate on Facebook, and in countries like Thailand, almost <a href="https://asia.nikkei.com/Economy/Thais-embrace-shopping-via-social-media">half of all online sales</a> happen through social media. Recently, platforms have started to accommodate them. Earlier this year, Facebook introduced <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2020/05/introducing-facebook-shops/">features</a> allowing sellers to customize their online shops and made it easier for them to catalogue their goods and process payments.</p>



<p>The rise of F-commerce is, of course, inextricable from Facebook. As whole sections of Bangladeshi society get online for the first time, many consider “being on the internet” as simply having registered on Facebook. According to one estimate, the social media giant had nearly <a href="https://napoleoncat.com/stats/facebook-users-in-bangladesh/2020/05">39 million</a> active users in Bangladesh in May<sub> </sub>—&nbsp;23.8% of the population. This widespread use has meant that F-commerce has expanded beyond cities like Dhaka, Chittagong, and Sylhet and pulled new kinds of consumers into online shopping.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><blockquote><p>“If Amazon were to enter, they could wipe out the market.”</p></blockquote></figure>



<p>It’s also changed other dynamics. While Bangladeshi F-commerce shops relied on snail mail until just a few years ago, many sellers have hired logistics firms to carry out their quality checks, packaging, and delivery services, as they’ve expanded their businesses. Apart from transporting goods, logistics firms such as <a href="http://ecourierz.com/">eCourierz</a>, <a href="http://shopup.com.bd/">ShopUp</a>, …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://restofworld.org/2020/bangladesh-economy-runs-on-facebook/">https://restofworld.org/2020/bangladesh-economy-runs-on-facebook/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://restofworld.org/2020/bangladesh-economy-runs-on-facebook/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23914982</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 08:20:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Medium is not the home for your ideas]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 550 | Comments 336 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23914052">thread link</a>) | @rahulchowdhury
<br/>
July 21, 2020 | https://hulry.com/medium-vs-own-blog/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://hulry.com/medium-vs-own-blog/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-content" role="main">

	
<article id="post-334">

	
<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>

		<div>

			
<p>Medium’s most significant selling points are how easy it is to publish your thoughts and the social aspect of the platform.</p>



<p>However, with ease, comes restrictions.</p>



<p>In this post, I’ll discuss how Medium has burned me in the past and why I don’t think it’s the right place for your stories on the web.</p>



<p>Let’s start with:</p>



<h2>My experience with Medium</h2>



<p>When Medium was new, I jumped into the bandwagon, and called it the home for my blog posts for quite some time.</p>



<p>I was happy with the experience. The editor was beautiful, and the presence of community made the platform a suitable place to publish my thoughts, and reach people quickly.</p>



<p>After writing solo for some time, I got accepted to write for a couple of Medium publications like <a aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)" href="https://medium.com/swlh" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">The Startup</a>, freeCodeCamp, <a href="https://hackernoon.com/" target="_blank" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Hacker Noon</a>, and <a aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)" href="https://byrslf.co/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Be Yourself</a>.</p>



<p>I thought my blog hosting days were behind me. Medium was going to be my one-stop blogging destination.</p>



<p>But then, came the hammer:</p>



<p>Medium’s content moderation algorithm blocked my profile by mistake without a notice.</p>



<p>I didn’t even realise that my Medium profile wasn’t visible to anyone but me. I assumed since I haven’t written for some time, my views started dropping naturally.</p>



<p>It was until I tried sharing my profile link with a friend did I notice that my profile page returned a 404 error like this:</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="340" data-permalink="https://hulry.com/medium-vs-own-blog/medium-404-page/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-404-page.png?fit=1710%2C946&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1710,946" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="medium-404-page" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-404-page.png?fit=300%2C166&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-404-page.png?fit=580%2C321&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-404-page.png?resize=580%2C321&amp;ssl=1" alt="Medium's 404 error page." srcset="https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-404-page.png?resize=1024%2C566&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-404-page.png?resize=300%2C166&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-404-page.png?resize=768%2C425&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-404-page.png?resize=1536%2C850&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-404-page.png?resize=1200%2C664&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-404-page.png?w=1710&amp;ssl=1 1710w" sizes="(max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-404-page.png?resize=1024%2C566&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-404-page.png?resize=300%2C166&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-404-page.png?resize=768%2C425&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-404-page.png?resize=1536%2C850&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-404-page.png?resize=1200%2C664&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-404-page.png?w=1710&amp;ssl=1 1710w" data-lazy-src="https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-404-page.png?resize=580%2C321&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><figcaption>I was getting Medium’s 404 page while trying to open my profile page.</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>After contacting Medium Support on Twitter, they unblocked my profile with a reply that my account was flagged mistakenly.</p>



<p>Check this reply from Medium Support:</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Hey Rahul! One of your posts was mistakenly flagged by our automatic spam filter. Our sincerest apologies! We've unsuspended your account immediately, and we'll make improvements to the filter to avoid such false alarms in the future.</p>— Medium Support (@MediumSupport) <a href="https://twitter.com/MediumSupport/status/1019889238991671296?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2018</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>What’s crazy?</p>



<p>Neither you nor I can stop this from happening again because Medium is a rented land for us.</p>



<p>On the web:</p>



<h2>It’s always better to own your platform</h2>



<p>This advice is accurate for any form of content, be it blog posts or a video.</p>



<p>Until you host your content on your platform, they will always live at the mercy of the company hosting the platform.</p>



<p>I was not the only case where Medium’s algorithm went haywire; it happened with other people as well:</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">This is called shadowbanning. It's extremely unethical and, sadly, <a href="https://twitter.com/MediumSupport?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MediumSupport</a> is known to do this to many of their contributors. It would be wise for you to stop using <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Medium?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Medium</a> – you're lucky they even responded to you this time. More info here:<a href="https://t.co/Carp3Tr9AR">https://t.co/Carp3Tr9AR</a></p>— Malcolm Rose 🥶 (@MalcolmRoseGM) <a href="https://twitter.com/MalcolmRoseGM/status/1020117535839215617?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 20, 2018</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>And this is true for other content platforms like YouTube. There had been cases where YouTube videos with tons of views disappeared overnight.</p>



<blockquote><p><strong>The web is meant for free speech. Your content shouldn’t be jailed for being controversial.</strong></p><a href="http://twitter.com/share?&amp;text=%3Cstrong%3EThe%20web%20is%20meant%20for%20free%20speech.%20Your%20content%20shouldn%27t%20be%20jailed%20for%20being%20controversial.%3C%2Fstrong%3E&amp;url=https://hulry.com/medium-vs-own-blog/&amp;via=thehulry" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tweet</a></blockquote>



<p>Even though Medium reinstated my profile, I stopped publishing on the platform and moved to my blog again.</p>



<p>You might be thinking:</p>



<h2>What about the virality that comes from Medium’s community?</h2>



<p>It’s true. Medium has a good community. And, if your content catches fire, it will be viral.</p>



<p>However, that’s not always the case. I have had very few organic traffic from Medium.</p>



<p>Most of my articles had traffic from external sources. Here are some stats for you:</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="350" data-permalink="https://hulry.com/medium-vs-own-blog/medium-story-stats-1/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-story-stats-1.png?fit=1440%2C812&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1440,812" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="medium-story-stats-1" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-story-stats-1.png?fit=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-story-stats-1.png?fit=580%2C327&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-story-stats-1.png?resize=580%2C327&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-story-stats-1.png?resize=1024%2C577&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-story-stats-1.png?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-story-stats-1.png?resize=768%2C433&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-story-stats-1.png?resize=1200%2C677&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-story-stats-1.png?w=1440&amp;ssl=1 1440w" sizes="(max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-story-stats-1.png?resize=1024%2C577&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-story-stats-1.png?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-story-stats-1.png?resize=768%2C433&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-story-stats-1.png?resize=1200%2C677&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-story-stats-1.png?w=1440&amp;ssl=1 1440w" data-lazy-src="https://i2.wp.com/hulry.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/medium-story-stats-1.png?resize=580%2C327&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><figcaption>Stats from one of my articles on Medium.</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Even if you manage to score a good amount of traffic on your content on Medium, it’s wise to use this opportunity to build an initial traction for your blog.</p>



<p>A lot of companies like <a aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)" href="https://m.signalvnoise.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Basecamp</a> and <a aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)" href="https://engineering.atspotify.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Spotify</a> executed this idea with their company blogs.</p>



<p>They started with a Medium publication, and when they gained traction on their content, they moved to their own hosted blogs.</p>



<p>Coincidentally:</p>



<p>I was listening to&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/1370USFCRZJnv2BXc631pq" rel="noreferrer noopener">a podcast episode</a>&nbsp;a few days back where a YouTuber said that he is building his platform to prevent his content from being taken down by YouTube.</p>



<p>That said:</p>



<h2>Medium is still suitable for some cases</h2>



<p>There are situations when Medium is the best choice for writers. Some of them are:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Blogging casually. </strong>When you’re just jotting your thoughts down and don’t care about your brand, Medium can be a right fit for those occasional brain dumps.</li><li><strong>Not being able to afford hosting fees.</strong> Hosting your blog costs money, whereas Medium is free.</li><li><strong>Quick money.</strong> Earning money from your blog takes time. On Medium, however, you can put your story behind a paywall and make money from <a aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)" href="https://help.medium.com/hc/en-us/articles/115011694187-Join-the-Partner-Program" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Medium’s Partner Program</a>.</li></ul>



<p>However, if you’re serious about blogging, you should always focus on your own blog.</p>



<p>Apart from the freedom to publish anything you want, you’ll also get unlimited branding and customisation options on your blog.</p>



<p>Medium allows only a handful of customisations for publications and little to nothing for the article content.</p>



<p>Even the everyday use cases like syntax highlighting requires jumping through multiple hoops to make it possible.</p>



<p>Also, Medium <a aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)" href="https://help.medium.com/hc/en-us/articles/115003053487-Custom-Domains-service-deprecation" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">stopped allowing custom domains</a> for publications starting <strong>November, 2017</strong>. That means, your publication will have an URL structure like this:</p>



<p><mark>medium.com/yourpublication</mark></p>



<p>There’s, however, one approach where you can make Medium work for you with acceptable side-effects.</p>



<p>How?</p>



<h2>Mirror your blog on Medium</h2>



<p>This technique isn’t something I invented. I have seen a lot of established authors like <a aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)" href="https://dariusforoux.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Darius Foroux</a> do this regularly and I tried it on my own as well.</p>



<p>The concept is to publish first on your own blog and then later republish the same content on Medium.</p>



<p>You can either create a publication on Medium for reposting or publish under your profile.</p>



<p>And at the end of each article, add a byline which links to the original article on your site.</p>



<p>The benefit of this approach is that while your content is safely resting on your blog, you can leverage Medium and get more eyeballs for your writing.</p>



<p>However, there’s a catch, SEO-wise.</p>



<p>Since Medium has a high domain authority on Google Search, your articles on Medium might outrank the same articles published on your blog.</p>



<p>Also, Google might add negative signals for your website, thinking that you copy-pasted an article from Medium on your blog.</p>



<p>Tread carefully.</p>



<p><strong>Update:</strong> As pointed out in the comments section, Medium has an&nbsp;<a aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)" target="_blank" href="https://help.medium.com/hc/en-us/articles/214550207-Import-a-post" rel="noreferrer noopener">import tool</a>&nbsp;which allows you to add a canonical link from your Medium post to your original blog post. </p>



<p>This process ensures that Google does not think of your blog post as a duplicate. Thanks to Nicolas and Matthias for this correction.&nbsp;🥂</p>



<h2>Tell me about your strategy</h2>



<p>Now that you know the disadvantages of blogging on Medium, what do you think?</p>



<p>Will you be <a href="https://hulry.com/back-to-wordpress/">moving your blog</a> from Medium? Or vice-versa?</p>



<p>Have you already moved from Medium? Love to hear that story too.</p>



<p><em>Let me know by leaving a comment below.</em></p>



<div><div>
<hr>



<h2>Subscribe to my newsletter</h2>



<p>By subscribing, you’ll get:</p>



<p>🎉 Notified of new articles<br>👍 Curated article recommendations from around the web<br>🎟 Subscribers-only tips and tricks for apps<br>🙅‍♂️ No spam<br>📅 Maximum one email per week</p>



	<div data-blog-id="179209184">
		<div>
			
			
				<p>
					Processing…				</p>
				<p>
					Success! You're on the list.				</p>
				<p>
					Whoops! There was an error and we couldn't process your subscription. Please reload the page and try again.				</p>

					</div>
	</div>
	</div></div>

		</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	</div><!-- .post-inner -->

	<!-- .section-inner -->

	
	<!-- .pagination-single -->

	
		<!-- .comments-wrapper -->

		
</article><!-- .post -->

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://hulry.com/medium-vs-own-blog/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23914052</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 04:56:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Aristotle's Lost Book on Magic (2018)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 83 | Comments 22 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23913571">thread link</a>) | @benbreen
<br/>
July 21, 2020 | https://www.ancientmedicine.org/home/2018/3/11/aristotles-lost-book-on-magic | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.ancientmedicine.org/home/2018/3/11/aristotles-lost-book-on-magic">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-block-type="2" id="block-94edc3520e97f986fec9"><div><p>Here are all of V. Rose's <em>testimonia</em>&nbsp;of a work attributed to Aristotle called <em>Magic (</em>ὁ Μαγικός λόγος, or τὸ μαγικόν?). The title either refers to the art practised by the Magi (the Zoroastrian priests from Persia), or it refers to the fact that the discussion is a discussion about the Magi. The latter seems more likely, even though the first passage, from Diogenes Laertius, suggests the discussion mentioned all sorts of wisdom cults.</p><p>The attribution is disputed. Diogenes Laertius says it is by Aristotle, but doesn't put it in his list of Aristotle's works (it doesn't show up in any other list I've looked at in either Greek or Arabic). The Suda says it is by Antisthenes, and that some people attributed it to Aristotle or someone named Rhodon. It's not clear where the Suda is getting this from.</p><p>While we don't know who wrote it, its contents are hinted at by the testimonies gathered in Rose (+ a few others I've put together). Diogenes reports that Aristotle thought magic wasn't sorcery, but philosophy or wisdom. This is confirmed by the Suda. It has something to do with prognostication. Eudoxus, according to Pliny,&nbsp;believed it was useful and very valuable, and so it was not only practical but connected to more valuable objects of study, probably the heavenly bodies. This is especially supported by the etymology of Zoroaster ('star-diviner') reported by Diogenes,&nbsp;and Porphyry's etymology of 'magus' as 'wise in divine matters'. Philo specifies that it was a kind of 'optics'&nbsp;and a very precise branch of natural science. Finally, Philo, Porphyry and the Suda associate it with both wisdom <em>and </em>with kingship. Philo says not only private citizens practice magic, but that Persian kings themselves had to be educated as Magi to become king.</p><p>It seems to me as if all these testimonies could be referring to a discussion of wise philosopher kings who are able to predict the future through their understanding of the heavens and the science of nature.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1520798591087_18030"><div><p>"Some say the work of philosophy originated with the barbarians. For among the Persians are the Magi, among the Babylonians and Assyrians the Chaldeans, among the Indians the Gymnosophists (lit. naked philosophers), and among the Celts and Gauls, those called 'Druids' and holy people, according to what Aristotle says in the book on <em>Magic </em>and Sotion in the twenty-third book of the <em>Succession of Philosophers</em>."</p><p>Τὸ τῆς φιλοσοφίας ἔργον ἔνιοί φασιν ἀπὸ βαρβάρων ἄρξαι. γεγενῆσθαι γὰρ παρὰ μὲν Πέρσαις μάγους, παρὰ δὲ Βαβυλωνίοις ἢ Ἀσσυρίοις Χαλδαίους, καὶ γυμνοσοφιστὰς παρ' Ἰνδοῖς, παρά τε Κελτοῖς καὶ Γαλάταις τοὺς καλουμένους δρυίδας καὶ σεμνοθέους, καθά φησιν Ἀριστοτέλης ἐν τῷ μαγικῷ καὶ Σωτίων ἐν εἰκοστῷ τρίτῳ τῆς διαδοχῆς.</p><p><strong>Diogenes Laertius, <em>Lives of the Eminent Philosophers</em>, 1.1</strong></p><p>"The Magi were ignorant of sorcerers' magic, says Aristotle in the book on <em>Magic </em>and Dinon in the fifth book of his <em>Histories</em>. He also says 'Zoroaster' when translated literally means 'star-diviner'; Hermodorus says this as well. In the first book of <em>On Philosophy</em>, Aristotle says they (the Magi) are actually older than the Egyptians. And according to them there are two principles, a good daimon and a bad daimon: to the former, the name is Zeus and 'Oromasdes' [i.e., Ahura Mazda], to the other Hades and 'Arimanius' [i.e., Ahriman]. Hermippus says this too in the first book <em>On Magi</em>, so does Eudoxus in the <em>Survey</em>, and Theopompus in the eighth book of the <em>Philippics</em>."</p><p>Τὴν δὲ γοητικὴν μαγείαν [sc. οἱ Μάγοι] οὐδ' ἔγνωσαν, φησὶν Ἀριστοτέλης ἐν τῷ Μαγικῷ καὶ Δείνων ἐν τῇ πέμπτῃ τῶν Ἱστοριῶν· ὃς καὶ μεθερμηνευόμενόν φησι τὸν Ζωροάστρην ἀστροθύτην εἶναι· φησὶ δὲ τοῦτο καὶ ὁ Ἑρμόδωρος. Ἀριστοτέλης δ' ἐν πρώτῳ Περὶ φιλοσοφίας καὶ πρεσβυτέρους εἶναι τῶν Αἰγυπτίων· καὶ δύο κατ' αὐτοὺς εἶναι ἀρχάς, ἀγαθὸν δαίμονα καὶ κακὸν δαίμονα· καὶ τῷ μὲν ὄνομα εἶναι Ζεὺς καὶ Ὠρομάσδης, τῷ δὲ Ἅιδης καὶ Ἀρειμάνιος. φησὶ δὲ τοῦτο καὶ Ἕρμιππος ἐν τῷ πρώτῳ Περὶ μάγων καὶ Εὔδοξος ἐν τῇ Περιόδῳ καὶ Θεόπομπος ἐν τῇ ὀγδόῃ τῶν Φιλιππικῶν.</p><p><strong>Diogenes Laertius, <em>Lives of the Eminent Philosophers</em>, 1.7-8</strong></p><p>"Aristotle says that a certain <em>magus</em> [magician or priest from Persia] came from Syria to Athens and among the other things he predicted about Socrates, was that he will have a violent end."</p><p>φησὶ δ' Ἀριστοτέλης μάγον τινὰ ἐλθόντα ἐκ Συρίας εἰς Ἀθήνας τά τε ἄλλα καταγνῶναι τοῦ Σωκράτους καὶ δὴ καὶ βίαιον ἔσεσθαι τὴν τελευτὴν αὐτῷ.</p><p><strong>Diogenes Laertius, <em>Lives of the Eminent Philosophers</em>, 2.45</strong></p><p>"Eudoxus, who wanted it to be known that among the schools of philosophy, magic is the most illustrious and most useful,&nbsp;relates that this 'Zoroaster' lived six thousand years before Plato's death. Aristotle says this too."</p><p>Eudoxus qui inter sapientiae sectas clarissimam utilissimamque eam (magicam) intellegi voluit, Zoroastren hunc sex milibus annorum ante Platonis mortem fuisse prodidit. sic et Aristoteles.</p><p><strong>Pliny, <em>Natural History</em>, 30.3</strong></p><p>"Antisthenes, an Athenian, Socratic philosopher from among the orators, who first was called a Peripatetic, then 'played the dog' (i.e., acted like someone from what would later be called the 'Cynic' school). He was the son of a father with the same name, and his mother came from the people of Thrace. He wrote these ten volumes: first, <em>Magic</em>: it tells about a certain <em>magus</em>, Zoroaster, who discovered wisdom. Some people attribute this to Aristotle, others to Rhodon."</p><p>Ἀντισθένης, Ἀθηναῖος, ἀπὸ ῥητόρων φιλόσοφος Σωκρατικός, ὅστις Περιπατητικὸς ἐκλήθη πρῶτον, εἶτα ἐκύνισεν: υἱὸς δὲ ὢν ὁμωνύμου πατρὸς, μητρὸς δὲ τὸ γένος Θρᾴσσης. οὗτος συνέγραψε τόμους δέκα: πρῶτον μαγικόν: ἀφηγεῖται δὲ περὶ Ζωροάστρου τινὸς μάγου, εὑρόντος τὴν σοφίαν: τοῦτο δέ τινες Ἀριστοτέλει, οἱ δὲ Ῥόδωνι ἀνατιθέασιν.</p><p><strong>Suda, s.v. Ἀντισθένης</strong></p><p>"Execestus, the Phocian tyrant, used to wear two enchanted rings, and he used to determine the appropriate time to act by the sound they made against one another. But, he still died, murdered by treachery despite being warned by the sound, as Aristotle says in the <em>Phocian Constitution</em>."</p><p>Ἐξήκεστός τε ὁ Φωκαιέων τύραννος δύο δακτυλίους φορῶν γεγοητευμένους τῷ ψόφῳ τῷ πρὸς ἀλλήλους διῃσθάνετο τοὺς καιροὺς τῶν πράξεων, ἀπέθανεν δὲ ὅμως δολοφονηθεὶς καίτοι προσημήναντος τοῦ ψόφου, ὥς φησιν Ἀριστοτέλης ἐν τῇ Φωκαιέων πολιτείᾳ.</p><p><strong>Clement of Alexandria, <em>Stromateus </em>I, chapter 21</strong></p><p>"The true art of magic, which is a science of optics by which the works of nature are illuminated with a brighter appearance and is thought to be holy and highly prized, is not only practiced by private citizens, but also by kings and of kings the greatest, and most of all the Persian kings, to the extent that they say no one among them is able to be a successor to the kingship if he does not happen to share in the house of the Magi."</p><p>τὴν μὲν οὖν ἀληθῆ μαγικήν, ὀπτικὴν ἐπιστήμην οὖσαν, ᾗ τὰ τῆς φύσεως ἔργα τρανοτέραις φαντασίαις αὐγάζεται, σεμνὴν καὶ περιμάχητον δοκοῦσαν εἶναι, οὐκ ἰδιῶται μόνον ἀλλὰ καὶ βασιλεῖς καὶ βασιλέων οἱ μέγιστοι καὶ μάλιστα οἱ Περσῶν διαπονοῦσιν οὕτως, ὥστ' οὐδένα φασὶν ἐπὶ βασιλείαν δύνασθαι παραπεμφθῆναι παρ' αὐτοῖς, εἰ μὴ πρότερον τοῦ μάγων γένους κεκοινωνηκὼς τυγχάνοι.</p><p><strong>Philo of Judaea, <em>On Special Laws</em>, 3.100</strong></p><p>"Among the Persians, those who are wise in divine matters and worship it are called 'Magi'. This is just what 'Magus' means in the regional language. This house is considered to be so great and so holy by the Persians, that even Darius, son of Hystaspes, had engraved on his tombstone (among other things) that he was a teacher of magic arts."</p><p>παρά γε μὴν τοῖς Πέρσαις οἱ περὶ τὸ θεῖον σοφοὶ καὶ τούτου θεράποντες μάγοι μὲν προσαγορεύονται· τοῦτο γὰρ δηλοῖ κατὰ τὴν ἐπιχώριον διάλεκτον ὁ μάγος· οὕτω δὲ μέγα καὶ σεβάσμιον γένος τοῦτο παρὰ Πέρσαις νενόμισται, ὥστε καὶ Δαρεῖον τὸν Ὑστάσπου ἐπιγράψαι τῷ μνήματι πρὸς τοῖς ἄλλοις ὅτι καὶ μαγικῶν γένοιτο διδάσκαλος.</p><p><strong>Porphyry, <em>On Abstinence from Animal Food</em>, 4.16</strong></p><p>"Don't make drugs. Stay away from magic books."</p><p>Φάρμακα μὴ τεύχειν, μαγικῶν βίβλων ἀπέχεσθαι.</p><p><strong>Pseudo-Phocylides, <em>Sententiae</em>, l.149</strong></p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.ancientmedicine.org/home/2018/3/11/aristotles-lost-book-on-magic</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23913571</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 03:16:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Very Basic Intro to Elliptic Curve Cryptography]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 87 | Comments 18 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23913341">thread link</a>) | @igoose1
<br/>
July 21, 2020 | https://qvault.io/2020/07/21/very-basic-intro-to-elliptic-curve-cryptography/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://qvault.io/2020/07/21/very-basic-intro-to-elliptic-curve-cryptography/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			




<hr>
<p>Elliptic curve cryptography is an efficient modern approach to public-key cryptosystems. In this introduction, our goal will be to focus on the high-level principles of what makes ECC work. We will omit implementation details and mathematical proofs, we can save those for another article.</p>



<h2><span id="What_Its_For">What It’s&nbsp;For?</span>
</h2>



<p>A common use of ECC is to encrypt data so that only authorized parties can decrypt it. This has several obvious use cases but is most often used to encrypt internet traffic. For example, we can use ECC to ensure that when we send an email, no one but the recipient can read the message.</p>



<hr>
<h2><span id="ECC_is_public_key_cryptography">ECC is public key cryptography</span>
</h2>



<p>There are many types of public-key cryptography, and Elliptic Curve Cryptography is just one flavor. Other algorithms include RSA, Diffie-Helman, etc. I’m going to give a very simple background of public-key cryptography as a jumping-off point so that we can discuss ECC and build on top of these ideas. By all means, study more in-depth on public-key cryptography when you have the time.</p>



<p>Public-key cryptography allows the following to happen:</p>







<p>We create two keys, a public key, and a private key. The public key is given freely, and any party can encrypt data by using it. However, the private key is kept secret and only those who hold it will have the ability to decrypt data.</p>



<h2><span id="An_Example_of_Public-Key-Cryptography">An Example of Public-Key-Cryptography</span>
</h2>



<p>Let’s pretend that Facebook is going to receive a private post from Donald Trump. Facebook needs to be able to ensure that when the President sends his post over the internet, no one in the middle (Like the NSA, or internet service provider) can read the message. The entire exchange using Public Key Cryptography would go like this:</p>



<ul>
<li>Donald Trump Notifies Facebook that he wants to send them a private post</li>
<li>Facebook sends Donald Trump their public key</li>
<li>Donald Trump uses the public key to encrypt his post:</li>
</ul>
<p><em>“I love Fox and Friends” + Public Key = “s80s1s9sadjds9s”</em></p>



<ul>
<li>Donald Trump sends only the encrypted message to Facebook</li>
<li>Facebook uses its private key to decrypt the message:</li>
</ul>
<p><em>“s80s1s9sadjds9s” + Private Key= “I love Fox and Friends”</em></p>



<p>As you can see this is a very useful concept. Here are some key points:</p>



<ul>
<li>The public key can be sent to anyone. It is public.</li>
<li>The private key must be kept safe because if someone in the middle were to get the private key, they could decrypt messages.</li>
<li>Computers can very quickly use the public key to encrypt a message, and the private key to decrypt a message.</li>
<li>Computers require a very long time (millions of years) to derive the original data from the encrypted message if they don’t have the private key.</li>
</ul>
<h2><span id="How_it_Works_The_Trapdoor_Function">How it Works: The Trapdoor&nbsp;Function</span>
</h2>



<p>The crux of all public-key cryptographic algorithms is that they each have their own unique trapdoor function<strong>. </strong>A trapdoor function is a function that can only be computed one way, or at least can only be computed one way <em>easily</em> (in less than millions of years using modern computers).</p>



<p>Not a trapdoor function: <em>A + B = C</em></p>



<p>If I’m given A and B I can compute C. The problem is that if I’m given B and C I can also compute A. This is not a trapdoor function.</p>



<p>Trapdoor function:</p>



<p><em>“I love Fox and Friends” + Public Key –&gt; “s80s1s9sadjds9s”</em></p>



<p>If given <em>“I love Fox and Friends”</em> and the public key, I can produce <em>“s80s1s9sadjds9s”</em>, but if given <em>“s80s1s9sadjds9s”</em> and the Public Key I can’t produce <em>“I love Fox and Friends”</em></p>



<p>In RSA (Probably the most popular public-key system) the trapdoor function relies on how hard it is to factor large numbers into their prime factors.</p>



<p>Public Key:<em> 944,871,836,856,449,473</em></p>



<p>Private Key: <em>961,748,941</em> and <em>982,451,653</em></p>



<p>In the example above the public key is a very large number, and the private key is the two prime factors of the public key. This is a good example of a Trapdoor Function because it is very easy to multiply the numbers in the private key together to get the public key, but if all you have is the public key it will take a very long time using a computer to re-create the private key.</p>



<p><em>Note: In real cryptography, the private key would need to be 200+ digits long to be considered secure.</em></p>



<h2><span id="What_Makes_Elliptic_Curve_Cryptography_Different">What Makes Elliptic Curve Cryptography Different?</span>
</h2>



<p>You would use ECC for the same reasons as RSA. ECC and RSA both generate a public and private key and allows two parties to communicate securely.</p>


<p><span><span><a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwp.me%2Fpb7Qei-9x&amp;text=There%20is%20one%20major%20advantage%20however%20that%20ECC%20offers%20over%20RSA.%20A%20256%20bit%20key%20in%20ECC%20offers%20about%20the%20same%20security%20as%20a%203072-bit%20key%20using%20RSA.%20This%20benefits%20systems%20with%20limited%20resources.%20&amp;via=wagslane&amp;related=wagslane" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">There is one major advantage however that ECC offers over RSA. A 256 bit key in ECC offers about the same security as a 3072-bit key using RSA. This benefits systems with limited resources.  </a></span><a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwp.me%2Fpb7Qei-9x&amp;text=There%20is%20one%20major%20advantage%20however%20that%20ECC%20offers%20over%20RSA.%20A%20256%20bit%20key%20in%20ECC%20offers%20about%20the%20same%20security%20as%20a%203072-bit%20key%20using%20RSA.%20This%20benefits%20systems%20with%20limited%20resources.%20&amp;via=wagslane&amp;related=wagslane" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Click To Tweet</a></span></p><p>ECC allows resource-constrained systems like smartphones, embedded computers, and cryptocurrency networks to use 10% of the storage space and bandwidth required by RSA.</p>



<h2><span id="ECCs_Trapdoor_Function">ECC’s Trapdoor&nbsp;Function</span>
</h2>



<p>This is probably why most of you are here. The trapdoor function is what makes ECC special and different than RSA. The trapdoor function is similar to a mathematical game of pool. First, we start with a certain point on the curve. Next, we use a function (called the dot function) to find a new point. Finally, we keep repeating the dot function to hop around the curve until we finally end up at our last point. Lets walk through the algorithm.</p>







<ul>
<li>Starting at A:</li>
<li>A dot B = -C (Draw a line from A to B and it intersects at -C)</li>
<li>Reflect across the X axis from -C to C</li>
<li>A dot C = -D (Draw a line from A to C and it intersects -D)</li>
<li>Reflect across the X axis from -D to D</li>
<li>A dot D = -E (Draw a line from A to D and it intersects -E)</li>
<li>Reflect across the X axis from -E to E</li>
</ul>
<p>This is a great trapdoor function because if you know where the starting point (A) is and how many hops are required to get to the ending point (E), it is very easy to find the ending point. On the other hand, if all you know is where the starting point and ending point are, it is nearly impossible to find how many hops it took to get there.</p>



<p>Public Key: Starting Point A, Ending Point E</p>



<p>Private Key: Number of hops from A to E</p>



<h2><span id="Questions">Questions?</span>
</h2>



<p>Here are just a couple of questions I had when I first learned about ECC. Hopefully, I can address them properly.</p>



<h3><span id="How_is_the_second_point_found_If_the_dot_function_is_basically_drawing_a_line_between_two_points_dont_you_need_a_second_point_to_start_with">How is the second point found? If the dot function is basically drawing a line between two points, don’t you need a second point to start&nbsp;with?</span>
</h3>



<p>Answer: No. The second point (we will call it -R below) is actually the result of P dot P (let’s assume the first point is called P)</p>



<p>P dot P= -R</p>



<p>So what is P dot P? It is actually just the tangent line of P. See the graphic below:</p>







<h3><span id="What_happens_if_the_dot_function_produces_a_line_that_will_go_way_off_out_to_some_extreme">What happens if the dot function produces a line that will go way off out to some&nbsp;extreme?</span>
</h3>



<p>If the line doesn’t hit the curve close to the origin, we can actually define a maximum X value where the line will wrap back around and start from the beginning again. See the graphic below for an example.</p>







<h3><span id="I_get_the_trapdoor_function_but_how_are_public_and_private_keys_created_in_practice_How_are_they_used_in_conjunction_with_data_to_be_encrypted">I get the trapdoor function, but how are public and private keys created in practice? How are they used in conjunction with data to be encrypted?</span>
</h3>



<p>This is a great question, but it requires a much more in-depth answer. I gave very hand-wavy explanations of both RSA and ECC in this article. However, there are plenty of more technical resources out there and I encourage you to look into them.</p>



<hr>
<h2><span id="Who_Cares">Who Cares?</span>
</h2>



<p>ECC is used as the cryptographic key algorithm in Bitcoin because it potentially can save 90% of the resources used by a similar RSA system. It seems that each year we see more systems moving from a bloaty RSA system to a more modern elliptic curve approach. Hopefully, we’ve helped you gain a high-level understanding ECC and public-key cryptography.</p>



<div><div>
<h2><span id="Thanks_For_Reading">Thanks For Reading!</span>
</h2>



<p>Follow us on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/q_vault">@q_vault</a> if you have any questions or comments</p>



<p>Take game-like coding courses on <a href="https://classroom.qvault.io/#/">Qvault Classroom</a></p>



<p><a href="https://mailchi.mp/5c7f5c281bbe/qvault-newsletter-subscribe">Subscribe</a> to our Newsletter for more educational articles</p>
</div></div>



<h2><span id="Related_Articles">Related Articles</span>
</h2>



<p><br>– <a href="https://qvault.io/2020/01/29/hashing-passwords-python-cryptography-examples/">Hashing Passwords – Python Cryptography Examples</a><br>– <a href="https://qvault.io/2020/07/08/how-sha-2-works-step-by-step-sha-256/">How SHA-2 Works Step-By-Step (SHA-256)</a><br>– <a href="https://qvault.io/2019/07/09/is-aes-256-quantum-resistant/">Is AES-256 Quantum Resistant?</a></p>


		</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://qvault.io/2020/07/21/very-basic-intro-to-elliptic-curve-cryptography/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23913341</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 02:28:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Build a toy quantum computer at home]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 238 | Comments 39 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23912490">thread link</a>) | @dhruvp
<br/>
July 21, 2020 | https://www.dhruvonmath.com/2020/07/19/quantum-computers/# | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.dhruvonmath.com/2020/07/19/quantum-computers/#">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
  
  <time datetime="2020-07-19T00:00:00+00:00">19 Jul 2020</time>
  <h2 id="outline">Outline</h2>

<p>In the past few posts we’ve gone over how to interpret matrices, basis vectors, and eigenvectors. Today, we’ll put all that together towards a really fun goal - building a toy quantum computer at home!  We’ll even solve a real problem on this “computer” that we couldn’t solve as efficiently on a standard computer.</p>

<p>All this will continue our understanding of the diverse and exciting applications of Linear Algebra.</p>

<h3 id="project-overview">Project Overview</h3>

<p>We are going to build a toy “quantum computer” just using a display, and a few polarizing filters.</p>

<p><strong>Cost:</strong> $20</p>

<p><strong>Materials</strong></p>

<p>
    <img src="https://www.dhruvonmath.com/public/images/quantum_computer/materials.jpg">
These are all the materials we will use. A cell phone, and a linear polarizer filter sheet.
</p>

<ol>
  <li>Your cell phone (or any display/light).</li>
  <li>
    <p>A polarization sheet such as the one in the link below.</p>

    <p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Polarization-Polarizer-Educational-Physics-Polarized/dp/B06XWXRB75">Linear Polarization A4 Sheet Polarizer Educational Physics Polarized Filter Optical</a></p>
  </li>
  <li>Cut the polarizer sheet into squares. Apply a yellow post it flag so we can track the orientation of the square.</li>
</ol>

<p>
    <img src="https://www.dhruvonmath.com/public/images/quantum_computer/sticky_note.png">
    A small post it note lets us track the orientation of this square.
</p>

<hr>

<h2 id="some-background-knowledge">Some Background Knowledge</h2>

<h3 id="using-light-to-harness-quantum-properties">Using Light to Harness Quantum Properties</h3>

<p>To begin our process of building a computer we need to understand one of the foundational concepts in physics - light! Physicists in the 20th century developed quantum mechanics by studying some of the incredible properties of light. A few of these examples are shown below:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Photoelectric_effect">Photoelectric Effect (the discovery that Einstein won his Nobel Prize for)</a>.
    <ul>
      <li>Showed light is composed of discrete units called photons.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Iuv6hY6zsd0">Double-Slit Experiment</a>
    <ul>
      <li>One of the seminal experiments in proving light can behave as both a wave and a particle.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>The <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FXfrncRey-4">Black Body Radiation problem</a>
    <ul>
      <li>Studied by Max Planck and led to the discovery of Planck’s constant - a fundamental number in Quantum Mechanics.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>In this project, we will use the quantum properties of light to create something like a computer. Specifically, we will use a property of light known as polarization to carry out computations in our computer.</p>

<p>Let’s now dive into what exactly light polarization is and how we can leverage it.</p>

<hr>

<h2 id="polarization-overview">Polarization Overview</h2>

<p>In the 1800s, Maxwell <a href="https://www.space.com/speed-of-light-properties-explained.html">famously discovered</a> that light is a direct consequence of electricity and magnetism (in fact, the movement of electrons in space generates light!). He found that light is an <strong>electromagnetic</strong> wave (an electric and magnetic field that travels through space).</p>

<p>In this electromagnetic wave, there are two parts: the electric field wave and the magnetic field wave. We call direction of orientation of the electric field the <strong>polarization</strong> of light.</p>

<p>
    <img src="https://www.dhruvonmath.com/public/images/quantum_computer/em_wave.png">
    Image source: https://socratic.org/questions/58f0fd7e7c0149308e221579
</p>

<hr>

<p>You may be surprised at just how often we use polarization everyday. For instance, any time you put on a pair of polarized sunglasses on a sunny day, you are harnessing light polarization! The black lenses on polarized sunglasses block certain types of light to reduce the glare that we see. The lenses do so by only letting in light of a certain polarization angle and blocking all other light.</p>

<p>
    <img src="https://www.dhruvonmath.com/public/images/quantum_computer/sunglasses.png">
    The lenses on polarized sunglasses are polarization filters that only allow light of a specific polarization through. Image Source (https://vision-works.co.za/polarized-lenses-explained/)

    A sunglass lens is a specific example of a polarization filter - a barrier that only lets in light of a specific polarization angle.
</p>
<p>This may seem fairly straight forward but as we study polarization more, we notice some really counterintuitive properties that are in fact deeply rooted in quantum mechanics. Namely, light can seemingly be polarized in multiple states at once!</p>

<h2 id="photons-can-be-polarized-in-multiple-directions-at-once">Photons Can Be Polarized in Multiple Directions at Once</h2>

<p>Let us now dig into what makes light polarization so useful in building a quantum computer.</p>

<p>Through experiments, we  will see that a single photon of light can be polarized <strong>in multiple directions at once</strong>. This is an idea rooted in quantum physics known as <strong>superposition.</strong>.</p>

<p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UjaAxUO6-Uw" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
    <br>
    In the thought experiment, Schrodinger's Cat is somehow both **dead and alive** at the same time. In the same way, a photon of light can be polarized **in multiple directions** at the same time.
</p>

<p>You may have seen superposition in the famous Schrodinger’s Cat paradox where the cat is somehow both   “dead” and “alive” at the same time. This is exactly what we’ll see is going on with the state of a photon’s polarization!</p>

<h3 id="experiments">Experiments</h3>

<p>Let us now see this ourselves! We will run a set of experiments to in fact ourselves verify that <strong>light can be polarized in multiple angles at once.</strong>. Note with a large set of photons we can explain these effects using classical physics but when we get down to single photons, we need to use the quantum interpretation we will soon discuss.</p>

<p>Here are the experiments we will run:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Experiment 1 -</strong> Shows how polarizers work to help us develop an intuition.</li>
  <li><strong>Experiment 2 -</strong> Shows that if light is vertically polarized it cannot be horizontally polarized.</li>
  <li><strong>Experiment 3 -</strong> Shows that introducing a 45º&nbsp;polarizer allows light to be superposed in multiple polarizations at once.</li>
</ul>

<p>These experiments are heavily based on the following video from Minute Physics and 3Blue1Brown.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zcqZHYo7ONs" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<hr>

<h3 id="experiment-1---effect-of-vertical-polarizer">Experiment 1 - Effect of Vertical polarizer</h3>

<p><strong>Description</strong></p>

<p>Our first experiment is going to simply show what a vertical polarizer does. We’ll be able to see that it blocks out some amount of light and only lets vertically polarized light through.</p>

<p><strong>Instructions</strong></p>

<ol>
  <li>Take your cell phone. Turn the display on.</li>
  <li>Place a vertical filter on a section of the phone.</li>
  <li>Only vertically polarized light comes out of that section.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>Seeing it in Action</strong></p>

<p>Below is my phone with a small vertical polarizer on the top left corner.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.dhruvonmath.com/public/images/quantum_computer/phone_vertical.jpg">
    A vertical polarizer is present on the top-left corner of the screen.
</p>

<hr>

<p>Conceptually, the polarizer in the top-left corner is blocking everything but vertically polarized light as shown below.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.dhruvonmath.com/public/images/quantum_computer/exp_1.png" alt="Phone Blocked"></p>

<p><strong>Conclusions</strong></p>

<p>A vertically polarized filter only lets vertically polarized light out.</p>

<hr>

<h3 id="experiment-2---effect-of-vertical--horizontal-polarizer">Experiment 2 - Effect of Vertical + Horizontal Polarizer</h3>

<p><strong>Description</strong></p>

<p>Our next experiment will show that vertically polarized light is entirely blocked by a horizontal polarizer. We will place a horizontal polarizer on top of a vertical polarizer and see that little to no light comes through.</p>

<p><strong>Instructions</strong></p>

<ol>
  <li>Take your cell phone. Turn the display on.</li>
  <li>Place a vertical filter on a section of the phone.</li>
  <li>Place a horizontal filter on the same section of the phone.</li>
  <li>Notice how little to no light now appears.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>Seeing it In Action</strong></p>

<p>Below is my phone with a both a vertical and horizontal polarizer in sequence (the yellow tab shows the orientation of the polarizer). Notice how we can no longer read the screen.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.dhruvonmath.com/public/images/quantum_computer/phone_blocked.png" alt="Phone Blocked"></p>

<hr>

<p>With the addition of the horizontal polarizer, all light is effectively blocked in the top-left corner of the screen as seen below:</p>

<p>
    <img src="https://www.dhruvonmath.com/public/images/quantum_computer/exp_2.png">
    A vertical polarizer followed by a horizontal polarizer will block all light.
</p>

<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>

<p>Vertically polarized light cannot go through a horizontal filter.</p>

<hr>

<h3 id="experiment-3---effect-of-vertical--45º--horizontal-polarizer">Experiment 3 - Effect of Vertical + 45º + Horizontal polarizer</h3>

<p><strong>Description</strong></p>

<p>This is the fun part! We now get to see what happens when you place a 45º&nbsp;filter in between a vertical and horizontal polarizing filter. What we’d expect is the same as in experiment 2 - no light gets through. If polarizers just block light, surely adding a third polarizer will only block more light.</p>

<p>However,  what we end up seeing is quite unexpected!</p>

<p><strong>Instructions</strong></p>

<ol>
  <li>Take your cell phone. Turn the display on.</li>
  <li>Place a vertical filter on a section of the phone.</li>
  <li>Place a horizontal filter on top of it.</li>
  <li>Place a 45º&nbsp;filter in between the vertical and horizontal filter.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>Seeing it in Action</strong></p>

<p>Adding the diagonal polarizer really does let some light through (about 50% of it)! You can see this below as I move a diagonally oriented polarizer between the vertical and horizontal polarizer.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.dhruvonmath.com/public/images/quantum_computer/diagonal_polarizer.gif" alt="Diagonal Polarizer"></p>

<hr>

<p>Adding the diagonal polarizer somehow leads to <strong>more light</strong> against all expectations! We can see what’s happening in the diagram below. We will explain this more in the following section so don’t worry too much if you don’t understand it.</p>

<p>
    <img src="https://www.dhruvonmath.com/public/images/quantum_computer/exp_3.png">
    A vertical filter followed by a 45º filter and then a horizontal filter will let some light through.
</p>

<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Light that is seemingly vertically polarized can somehow become horizontally polarized.</li>
  <li>The 45º filter is needed for this change to happen. Without it we see no light can come out.
    <ul>
      <li>Without 45º filter</li>
    </ul>

    <p><img src="https://www.dhruvonmath.com/public/images/quantum_computer/exp_2.png" alt="Experiment 2"></p>

    <ul>
      <li>With 45º&nbsp;filter</li>
    </ul>

    <p><img src="https://www.dhruvonmath.com/public/images/quantum_computer/exp_3.png" alt="Experimenet 3"></p>
  </li>
</ul>

<hr>

<h2 id="understanding-experiment-3">Understanding Experiment 3</h2>

<p>So what is going on in Experiment 3? How does vertically polarized light go through the 45º&nbsp;filter?</p>

<h3 id="thinking-of-photons-as-combinations">Thinking of Photons as Combinations</h3>

<p>We can think of a vertical line/vector (black) as the sum of a 135º (blue) vector&nbsp;and 45º (purple) vector. This is shown below:</p>

<div>
    <p>
        <img src="https://www.dhruvonmath.com/public/images/quantum_computer/vectors.png">
        A vertical line can be seen as a sum of diagonal line 1 and diagonal line 2.
    </p>
    <p>
        <img src="https://www.dhruvonmath.com/public/images/quantum_computer/vectors_expanded.png">
            The horizontal components of 1 and 2 cancel out when added, leading to a vertical line.
    </p>        
</div>

<p>So in that sense, we can think of a vertically filtered photon as the <strong>combination</strong> of a 135º filtered photon and a 45º filtered photon. Or in other words, the vertically filtered photon can be seen as filtered in <strong>both these angles at once</strong> (Note that it’s a very <strong>specific amount</strong> (<span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mfrac><mrow><msqrt><mrow><mn>2</mn></mrow></msqrt></mrow><mrow><mn>2</mn></mrow></mfrac></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">  \frac{\sqrt{2}}{2} </annotation></semantics></math></span></span>) of each of these options. But we are going to postpone that discussion for now).</p>

<p>
    <img src="https://www.dhruvonmath.com/public/images/quantum_computer/photon_sum.png">
    A vertically filtered photon can be seen as a combination of a 45º polarized photon and a 135º polarized photon.
</p>

<p>Equipped with this idea, let’s now revisit experiment 4’s setup. We are going to break it up into <strong>Step 1, Step 2, and Step 3.</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://www.dhruvonmath.com/public/images/quantum_computer/exp_3_broken_up.png" alt="Experiment 3 Broken Up"></p>

<p>We will break up Experiment 3 into three steps.</p>

<h3 id="step-1---vertical-filter">Step 1 - Vertical Filter</h3>

<p>
    <img src="https://www.dhruvonmath.com/public/images/quantum_computer/exp_3_step_1.png">
</p>

<p>Step 1 is fairly straightforward - The vertical polarizer only lets vertically polarized  photons through. The horizontally polarized photons get blocked.</p>

<h3 id="step-2---45ºfilter">Step 2 - 45º&nbsp;Filter</h3>

<p>
    <img src="https://www.dhruvonmath.com/public/images/quantum_computer/exp_3_step_2.png">
</p>

<p>In Step 2, vertically …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.dhruvonmath.com/2020/07/19/quantum-computers/#">https://www.dhruvonmath.com/2020/07/19/quantum-computers/#</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.dhruvonmath.com/2020/07/19/quantum-computers/#</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23912490</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:21:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
