<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 17:09:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 17:09:06 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[TabFS: Mount your Browser Tabs as a Filesystem]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 524 | Comments 68 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25600338">thread link</a>) | @thesephist
<br/>
December 31, 2020 | https://omar.website/tabfs/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://omar.website/tabfs/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      

<!-- I'm setting this page in Verdana-on-gray so I feel more comfortable -->

<!-- jotting random notes and stuff down. -->



<p><a href="https://github.com/osnr/TabFS">TabFS</a> is a browser extension that
mounts your browser tabs as a filesystem on your computer.</p>

<p>Out of the box, it supports Chrome and (to a lesser extent<sup id="fnref:firefox"><a rel="footnote" href="#fn:firefox">1</a></sup>)
Firefox, on macOS and Linux.<sup id="fnref:otherbrowsers"><a rel="footnote" href="#fn:otherbrowsers">2</a></sup></p>

<p>Each of your open tabs is mapped to a folder.</p>

<div>
<p><img src="https://omar.website/tabfs/doc/00-browser.png">
<img src="https://omar.website/tabfs/doc/00-finder.png"></p><p>I have 3 tabs open, and
they map to 3 folders in TabFS</p>
</div>

<p>The files inside a tab's folder directly reflect (and can control) the
state of that tab in your browser. (TODO: update as I add more)</p>

<div>
<video autoplay="" loop="" muted="">
  <source src="https://omar.website/tabfs/doc/finder-contents.mp4" type="video/mp4">
</video>
<p>Example: the url.txt, text.txt, and title.txt
files inside a tab's folder, which tell me those live properties
for that tab</p>
</div>

<p>This gives you a <em>ton</em> of power, because now you can apply <a href="https://twitter.com/rsnous/status/1018570020324962305">all the
existing tools</a>
on your computer that already know how to deal with files -- terminal
commands, scripting languages, etc -- and use them to control and
communicate with your browser.</p>

<p>Now you don't need to <a href="https://twitter.com/rsnous/status/1261392522485526528">code up a browser extension from
scratch</a> every
time you want to do anything. You can write a script that talks to
your browser in, like, a melange of Python and bash, and you can save
it as <a href="https://twitter.com/rsnous/status/1308588645872435202">a single ordinary
file</a> that you
can run whenever, and it's no different from scripting any other part
of your computer.</p>

<h3 id="table-of-contents">table of contents</h3>




<h2 id="examples-of-stuff-you-can-do-examples">Examples of stuff you can do!<sup id="fnref:examples"><a rel="footnote" href="#fn:examples">3</a></sup></h2>

<p>(assuming your current directory is the <code>fs</code> subdirectory of the git
repo and you have the extension running)</p>

<h3 id="list-the-titles-of-all-the-tabs-you-have-open">List the titles of all the tabs you have open</h3>

<pre><code>$ cat mnt/tabs/by-id/*/title.txt
GitHub
Extensions
TabFS/install.sh at master · osnr/TabFS
Alternative Extension Distribution Options - Google Chrome
Web Store Hosting and Updating - Google Chrome
Home / Twitter
...
</code></pre>

<h3 id="cull-tabs-like-any-other-files">Cull tabs like any other files</h3>

<div>
<video autoplay="" loop="" muted="">
  <source src="https://omar.website/tabfs/doc/delete.mp4" type="video/mp4">
</video>
<p>Selecting and deleting a bunch of tabs in my file manager</p>
</div>

<p>I'm using Dired in Emacs here, but you could use whatever tools you
already feel comfortable managing your files with.</p>

<h3 id="close-all-stack-overflow-tabs">Close all Stack Overflow tabs</h3>

<pre><code>$ rm mnt/tabs/by-title/*Stack_Overflow*
</code></pre>

<p>or (older / more explicit)</p>

<pre><code>$ echo remove | tee -a mnt/tabs/by-title/*Stack_Overflow*/control
</code></pre>

<h4 id="btw">btw</h4>

<p>(this task, removing all tabs whose titles contain some string, is a
little contrived, but it's not that unrealistic, right?)</p>

<p>(now... how would you do this <em>without</em> TabFS?  I honestly have no
idea, off the top of my head. like, how do you even get the titles of
tabs? how do you tell the browser to close them?)</p>

<p>(I looked up the APIs, and, OK, if you're already in a browser
extension, in a 'background script' inside the extension, <em>and</em> your
extension has the <code>tabs</code> permission -- this already requires you to
make 2 separate files and hop between your browser and your text
editor to set it all up! -- you can do
<a href="https://developer.chrome.com/docs/extensions/reference/tabs/#method-query">this</a>:
<code>chrome.tabs.query({}, tabs =&gt; chrome.tabs.remove(tabs.filter(tab =&gt;
tab.title.includes('Stack Overflow')).map(tab =&gt; tab.id)))</code>)</p>

<p>(not <em>terrible</em>, but look at all that upfront overhead to get it set
up. and it's not all that discoverable. and what if you want to reuse
this later, or plug it into some larger pipeline of tools on your
computer, or give it a visual interface? the jump in complexity once
you need to communicate with anything -- possibly setting up a
WebSocket, setting up handlers and a state machine -- is pretty
horrifying)</p>

<p>(but to be honest, I wouldn't even have conceived of this as a thing I
could do in the first place)</p>

<h3 id="save-text-of-all-tabs-to-a-file">Save text of all tabs to a file</h3>

<pre><code>$ cat mnt/tabs/by-id/*/text.txt &gt; text-of-all-tabs.txt
</code></pre>

<h3 id="run-script">Run script</h3>

<pre><code>$ echo 'document.body.style.background = "green"' &gt; mnt/tabs/last-focused/execute-script
$ echo 'alert("hi!")' &gt; mnt/tabs/last-focused/execute-script
</code></pre>

<h3 id="reload-an-extension-when-you-edit-its-source-code">Reload an extension when you edit its source code</h3>

<p>Suppose you're working on a Chrome extension (apart from this
one). It's a pain to reload the extension (and possibly affected Web
pages) every time you change its code. There's a <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/2963260/how-do-i-auto-reload-a-chrome-extension-im-developing">Stack Overflow
post</a>
with ways to automate this, but they're all sort of hacky. You need
yet another extension, or you need to tack weird permissions onto your
work-in-progress extension, and you don't just get a command you can
trigger from your editor or shell to refresh the extension.</p>

<p>TabFS lets you do all this in <a href="https://github.com/osnr/playgroundize-devtools-protocol/blob/main/go.sh">an ordinary shell
script</a>.
You don't have to write any browser-side code at all.</p>

<p>This script turns an extension (this one's title is "Playgroundize
DevTools Protocol") off, then turns it back on, then reloads any tabs
that have the relevant pages open (in this case, I decided it's tabs
whose titles start with "Chrome Dev"):</p>

<pre><code>#!/bin/bash -eux
echo false &gt; mnt/extensions/Playg*/enabled
echo true &gt; mnt/extensions/Playg*/enabled
echo reload | tee mnt/tabs/by-title/Chrome_Dev*/control
</code></pre>

<p>I mapped this script to Ctrl-. in my text editor, and now I just hit
that every time I want to reload my extension code.</p>

<h3 id="todo-live-edit-a-running-web-page">TODO: Live edit a running Web page</h3>

<p>edit <code>page.html</code> in the tab folder. I guess it could just stomp
outerHTML at first, eventually could do something more sophisticated</p>

<p>(it would be cool to have a persistent storage story here
also. I like the idea of being able to put arbitrary files anywhere in
the subtree, actually, because then you could use git and emacs
autosave and stuff for free... hmm)</p>

<h3 id="todo-watch-expressions">TODO: Watch expressions</h3>

<pre><code>$ touch mnt/tabs/last-focused/watches/window.scrollY
</code></pre>

<p>Now you can <code>cat window.scrollY</code> and see where you are scrolled on the
page at any time.</p>

<p>Could make an <a href="https://twitter.com/rsnous/status/1080878682275803137">ad-hoc
dashboard</a>
around a Web page: a bunch of terminal windows floating around your
screen, each sitting in a loop and using <code>cat</code> to monitor a different
variable.</p>

<h3 id="todo-import-data-json-xls-js">TODO: Import data (JSON? XLS? JS?)</h3>

<p>drag a JSON file <code>foo.json</code> into the <code>imports</code> subfolder of the tab
and it shows up as the object <code>imports.foo</code> in JS. (modify
<code>imports.foo</code> in JS and then read <code>imports/foo.json</code> and you read the
changes back?)</p>

<p>import a plotting library or whatever the same way? dragging
<code>plotlib.js</code> into <code>imports/plotlib.js</code> and then calling
<code>imports.plotlib()</code> to invoke that JS file</p>

<p>the browser has a lot of potential power as an interactive programming
environment, one where graphics come <a href="https://twitter.com/rsnous/status/1295828978477932544">as
naturally</a> as
console I/O do in most programming languages. i think something that
holds it back that is underexplored is lack of ability to just... drag
files in and manage them with decent tools. many Web-based 'IDEs' have
to reinvent file management, etc from scratch, and it's like a
separate universe from the rest of your computer, and migrating
between one and the other is a real pain (if you want to use some
Python library to munge some data and then have a Web-based
visualization of it, for instance, or if you want to version files
inside it, or make snapshots so you <a href="https://twitter.com/rsnous/status/1288725175895068673">feel
comfortable</a>
trying stuff, etc).</p>

<p>(what would the persistent storage story here be? localStorage? it's
interesting because I almost want each tab to be <a href="https://twitter.com/rsnous/status/1344753559007420416">less of a
commodity</a>,
less
<a href="https://twitter.com/rsnous/status/1270192308772691968">disposable</a>,
since now it's the site I'm dragging stuff to and it might have some
persistent state attached. like, if I'm programming and editing stuff
and saving inside a tab's folder, that tab suddenly really
<a href="https://twitter.com/rsnous/status/1251863115022491653">matters</a>; I
want it to survive as long as a normal file would, unlike most browser
tabs today)</p>

<h2 id="setup">Setup</h2>

<p><strong>disclaimer</strong>: this extension is an experiment. I think it's cool and
useful and provocative, and I usually leave it on, but I make no
promises about functionality or, especially, security. applications
may freeze, your browser may freeze, there may be ways for Web pages
to use the extension to escape and hurt your computer ... In some
sense, the <a href="https://twitter.com/rsnous/status/1338932056743546880">whole
point</a> of this
extension is to create a gigantic new surface area of communication
between stuff inside your browser and software on the rest of your
computer.</p>

<p>Before doing anything, clone <a href="https://github.com/osnr/TabFS">this repository</a>:</p>

<pre><code>$ git clone https://github.com/osnr/TabFS.git
</code></pre>

<p>First, install the browser extension.</p>

<p>Then, install the C filesystem.</p>

<h3 id="1-install-the-browser-extension">1. Install the browser extension</h3>

<p>(I think for Opera or whatever other Chromium-based browser, you could
get it to work, but you'd need to change the native messaging path in
install.sh. Not sure about Safari. maybe Edge too? if you also got
everything to compile for Windows)</p>

<h4 id="in-chrome">in Chrome</h4>

<p>Go to the <a href="chrome://extensions">Chrome extensions page</a>. Enable
Developer mode (top-right corner).</p>

<p>Load-unpacked the <code>extension/</code> folder in this repo.</p>

<p><strong>Make a note of the extension ID Chrome assigns.</strong> Mine is
<code>jimpolemfaeckpjijgapgkmolankohgj</code>. We'll use this later.</p>

<h4 id="in-firefox">in Firefox</h4>

<p>You'll need to install as a "temporary extension", so it'll only last
in your current FF session. (TODO: is this fixable? signature stuff?)</p>

<p>Go to <a href="about:debugging#/runtime/this-firefox">about:debugging#/runtime/this-firefox</a>.</p>

<p>Load Temporary Add-on...</p>

<p>Choose manifest.json in the extension subfolder of this repo.</p>

<h3 id="2-install-the-c-filesystem">2. Install the C filesystem</h3>

<p>First, make sure you have FUSE and FUSE headers. On Linux, for example,
<code>sudo apt install libfuse-dev</code> or equivalent. On macOS, get <a href="https://osxfuse.github.io/">FUSE for
macOS</a>.</p>

<p>Then compile the C filesystem:</p>

<pre><code>$ cd fs
$ mkdir mnt
$ make
</code></pre>

<p>Now install the native messaging host into your browser, so the
extension can launch and talk to the filesystem:</p>

<h4 id="chrome-and-chromium">Chrome and Chromium</h4>

<p>Substitute the extension ID you copied earlier for
<code>jimpolemfaeckpjijgapgkmolankohgj</code> in the command below.</p>

<pre><code>$ ./install.sh chrome jimpolemfaeckpjijgapgkmolankohgj
</code></pre>

<p>or</p>

<pre><code>$ ./install.sh chromium jimpolemfaeckpjijgapgkmolankohgj
</code></pre>

<h4 id="firefox">Firefox</h4>

<pre><code>$ ./install.sh firefox
</code></pre>

<h3 id="3-ready">3. Ready!</h3>

<p>Go back to <code>chrome://extensions</code> or
<code>about:debugging#/runtime/this-firefox</code> and reload the extension.</p>

<p>Now your browser tabs should be mounted in <code>fs/mnt</code>!</p>

<p>Open the background page inspector to see the filesystem operations
stream in. (in Chrome, click "background page" next to "Inspect views"
in the extension's entry in the Chrome extensions page; in Firefox,
click "Inspect")</p>

<p><img src="https://omar.website/tabfs/doc/inspector.png">
</p>

<p>This console is also incredibly helpful for debugging anything that
goes wrong, which probably will happen. (If you get a generic I/O
error at the shell when running a command on TabFS, that probably
means that an exception happened which you can check here.)</p>

<p>(My OS and applications are pretty chatty. They do a lot of
operations, even when I don't feel like I'm actually doing
anything. My sense is that macOS is generally chattier than Linux.)</p>

<h2 id="design">Design</h2>

<ul>
<li><code>fs/</code>: Native FUSE filesystem, written in C
</li></ul></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://omar.website/tabfs/">https://omar.website/tabfs/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://omar.website/tabfs/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25600338</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 02:48:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Design of the Roland Juno Syntheziser's Oscillators]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 163 | Comments 55 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25598656">thread link</a>) | @cushychicken
<br/>
December 31, 2020 | https://blog.thea.codes/the-design-of-the-juno-dco/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.thea.codes/the-design-of-the-juno-dco/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p>This article is a comprehensive guide to the <a href="http://www.vintagesynth.com/roland/juno106.php">Roland Juno</a>'s <strong>digitally-controlled analog oscillators</strong> (<em>DCOs</em>). I fell in love with the Juno early in my synthesizer journey and I've spent the last year or so doing research on its design so that I could create my own Juno-inspired DCO, <a href="https://winterbloom.com/store/winterbloom-castor-and-pollux">Winterbloom's <em>Castor &amp; Pollux</em></a>.</p>
<p><img alt="Juno logo" src="https://blog.thea.codes/static/juno/juno-logo.png"></p>
<p>This article will cover a little history of the Juno, discuss the theory of operation behind digital-controlled oscillators, analyze the circuit designs for the Juno 6/60 &amp; the Juno 106, and discuss practical aspects of using DCOs. This article is somewhat lengthy and there is a <em>lot</em> of information here. I've tried my best to make this approachable for anyone with <a href="https://www.sparkfun.com/engineering_essentials">basic electronics knowledge</a>, so if you feel confused or overwhelmed please <a href="mailto:me@thea.codes">reach out</a> and I'll be more than happy to include more details or change something so that it's easier to understand.</p>
<h2 id="a-little-history">A little history</h2>
<p>Roland introduced the incredible <a href="http://www.vintagesynth.com/roland/juno6.php">Juno-6</a> and nearly identical <a href="http://www.vintagesynth.com/roland/juno60.php">Juno-60</a> in 1982. The Juno was a 6-voice polyphonic synthesizer that was an incredible value considering its array of features.</p>
<p><img alt="A photo of the Juno-60" src="https://blog.thea.codes/static/juno/juno-60.jpg"></p>
<p>The Juno notably featured <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digitally_controlled_oscillator"><em>digitally-controlled analog oscillators</em></a>. The DCO was designed to overcome the tuning instability of the usual <strong>voltage-controlled oscillators</strong> (<em>VCOs</em>) in contemporary polyphonic synthesizers. The DCOs operate with the same fundamental analog circuitry but differ in that they are controlled by a microcontroller. This imparted a unique sound to the Juno series and one that's become a favorite of many musicians.</p>
<p><img alt="A photo of the Juno 106" src="https://blog.thea.codes/static/juno/juno-106.jpg"></p>
<p>Roland followed with the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roland_Juno-106">Juno-106</a> in 1984. It offered some feature upgrades over its predecessor such as pitch bend, modulation, and support for a new thing called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MIDI">MIDI</a>. It still used the same digitally-controlled oscillator concept from the 6 &amp; 60, but its implementation is a little bit different.</p>
<p>This article will discuss and analyze both designs, but before getting into the nitty-gritty details let's take a look at the overall sound generation design of the Juno. Also, this article will refer to these three synthesizers - the 6, 60, and 106 - as <strong>the Juno</strong>, but note that this isn't necessarily applicable to later models.</p>
<h2 id="an-overview-of-the-junos-sound-generation">An overview of the Juno's sound generation</h2>
<p>The Juno has six voices. Each voice has a single oscillator that can generate three different <em>waveforms</em>. These oscillators are controlled by the microcontroller. Here's a block diagram that should help visualize the different parts at play:</p>
<p><img alt="A block diagram of a DCO-based synth" src="https://blog.thea.codes/static/juno/dco-block.png"></p>
<p>Sound generation starts with a <em>square</em> wave controlled by the microntroller and then goes through a series of <em>waveshapers</em> which generates a <em>ramp/sawtooth</em> waveform, a <em>sub</em> waveform (which is a square wave at half the frequency), and a <em>pulse</em> waveform. The frequency of the clock determines the frequency/note that the oscillator plays.</p>
<p>This is in contrast to a common design for a voltage-controlled oscillator (<em>VCO</em>) where a CPU isn't required. Instead, it uses analog circuitry to create a <em>control voltage</em> which determines the oscillator's frequency:</p>
<p><img alt="A block diagram of a VCO-based synth" src="https://blog.thea.codes/static/juno/vco-block.png"></p>
<p>Now that you've got a high-level overview of the sound generation inside of these synthesizers, let's take a deeper look at the components involved in sound generation.</p>
<h2 id="the-ramp-generator">The ramp generator</h2>
<p>Before jumping into the difference between DCOs and VCOs it's useful to discuss the similarities. As shown in the block diagrams above several designs for VCOs <strong>and</strong> the Juno DCOs are designed around a <strong>ramp generator</strong> (sometimes referred to as a <em>ramp core</em>) which creates a <em>sawtooth</em> (ramp) waveform:</p>
<p><img alt="A sawtooth waveform" src="https://blog.thea.codes/static/juno/ramp.png"></p>
<p>The ramp generator is the beginning of how an oscillator turns a <em>frequency input signal</em> into the various useful waveforms that are used to make musical sounds. For a VCO, the frequency input signal is a <strong>control voltage</strong>, hence "voltage-controlled". For a DCO, the frequency input signal is a <strong>digital clock</strong>, hence "digitally-controlled".</p>
<p>The difference in the type of input signal has a significant impact on the circuit design. Before getting into those differences, let's look at the heart of the ramp generator that's shared between both designs: the <strong>integrator</strong>.</p>
<h2 id="the-integrator">The integrator</h2>
<p>An integrator is a electronic circuit that performs the mathematical operation of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Integral"><em>Integration</em></a>. This is a fancy word from calculus but don't be afraid- it's actually pretty straightforward in practice.</p>
<p>The purpose of an integrator is to produce an output signal that changes (increase or decreases) at a rate that corresponds to the magnitude and duration of the input signal. In this case the input and output signals are both voltage. If you apply a <strong>constant</strong> voltage to an integrator, it will create a consistent increase or decrease in the output voltage over time (a <em>ramp</em>):</p>
<p><img alt="An ideal integrator" src="https://blog.thea.codes/static/juno/integrator-ramp.png"></p>
<p>More voltage means that the ramp will have a steeper slope. This is going to be helpful in generating a sawtooth waveform- the integrator ramp produces exactly one cycle of a sawtooth waveform. The trick is getting it to restart so that it creates a repeating (or <em>periodic</em>) sawtooth waveform.</p>
<p>You can create an integrator using an <a href="https://www.electronics-tutorials.ws/opamp/opamp_6.html">op-amp integrator circuit</a>:</p>
<p><img alt="A basic op-amp integrator circuit" src="https://blog.thea.codes/static/juno/op-amp-integrator.png"></p>
<p>The op-amp integrator is based on the idea that if you apply a voltage to a capacitor it <a href="http://hyperphysics.phy-astr.gsu.edu/hbase/electric/capchg.html">takes some time to charge</a>, in fact, it will charge at a rate that is proportional to the input voltage which sounds a <em>lot</em> like integration! Without going into too much op-amp theory, you can just assume that the integrator circuit will produce a voltage that increases or decreases at a rate determined by the input voltage and the values of <code>R</code> and <code>C</code>. The values of <code>R</code> and <code>C</code> determine the <a href="https://www.electronics-tutorials.ws/rc/rc_1.html"><strong>RC constant</strong></a> of the integrator - or put more simply, <em>how long it takes the circuit to charge up</em>. Remember this concept because it comes into play a <em>lot</em> in this article.</p>
<p>You can play around this with interactive illustration to see how changing the voltage, resistance, or capacitance changes the output of the integrator:</p>
<canvas id="integrator" width="1000" height="600"></canvas>


<p>The formula used to determine the output voltage of an integrator with a constant input voltage at a given time is:</p>
<pre><span>Vout</span> <span>=</span> <span>-</span><span>(</span><span>Vin</span> <span>/</span> <span>(</span><span>R</span> <span>*</span> <span>C</span><span>))</span> <span>*</span> <span>time</span>
</pre>
<p>Before going further, there are some interesting and noteworthy properties of the integrator's behavior to be aware of:</p>
<ul>
<li>First, notice that there are three ways of changing the steepness of the output's slope: changing the capacitance, changing the resistance, or changing the voltage. Making the voltage higher will charge the capacitor more quickly and increase the steepness of the slope. Making the resistance or capacitance lower will also cause the capacitor to charge more quickly and will increase the steepness of the slope.</li>
<li>Second, the output is <strong>inverted</strong> - a positive input voltage creates a downward slope and a negative input voltage creates an upward slope. This will come into play when we look at the difference between the Juno-6/60 design and the Juno-106 design.</li>
<li>Third, notice that with steeper slopes the output will <em>saturate</em> (stop increasing or decreasing). This is because a real op amp doesn't have an infinite amount of voltage to output and the capacitor can't hold an infinite amount of charge, so when either the output voltage is beyond the op amp's power supply or the capacitor can't hold any more charge the output voltage will saturate.</li>
</ul>
<p>At this point you should hopefully have a good grasp on how an op-amp integrator forms a ramp from a constant input voltage. So now we'll see how to change the circuit so that instead of a single slope it generates a repeating (periodic) sawtooth waveform.</p>
<p>A straightforward solution is to just start the circuit over - <strong>reset</strong> it. That'll start the ramp back at zero and let it start rising (or falling) again. If you keep resetting at regular intervals the circuit will keep generating ramps and which form cycles of the sawtooth waveform.</p>
<p>But what does it mean to reset a circuit? Well, it means to put it back into its initial state. Think about what <em>changes</em> in the integrator circuit over time: the <strong>charge</strong> of the capacitor. When the circuit first starts the capacitor has no charge and the output voltage is zero, but, as time goes on the capacitor charges more and more. So resetting the circuit means <em>discharging</em> the capacitor.</p>
<p>The easiest way to discharge a capacitor is to <em>short</em> it: connect its two leads together so there's nothing blocking it from discharging. You can do that by putting a little switch in the circuit:</p>
<p><img alt="An op-amp integrator with a switch to discharge the capacitor" src="https://blog.thea.codes/static/juno/integrator-with-switch.png"></p>
<p>When the switch is open the integrator behaves the same as before - its output goes up or down depending on the input voltage. When the switch is closed, it creates a circuit that connects the capacitor's leads and allows it to discharge:</p>
<p><img alt="An op-amp integrator with a switch to discharge the capacitor" src="https://blog.thea.codes/static/juno/integrator-with-switch-closed.png"></p>
<p>Once the switch is opened again the integrator starts over and begins ramping its output again.</p>
<p>Try out the little simulation below - press <code>start</code> to let the capacitor charge for a little bit and then press <code>close switch</code> to reset it:</p>
<canvas id="discharge" width="1000" height="600"></canvas>


<p>Take notice that when you press the button at consistent intervals the output is a sawtooth waveform and its frequency is determined by how often you press the button and reset the capacitor.</p>
<p>Obviously there aren't any synthesizers out there that require you to manually tap a switch at the desired note's frequency!<sup id="fnref:fast"><a href="#fn:fast">1</a></sup> So instead of requiring a person to press a switch this circuit should take some form of <strong>frequency input signal</strong> and use it to electronically close the switch.</p>
<p>The switch is the easy part - there's a well-known component that can act as an <em>electronically-controlled switch</em>: the <a href="https://learn.sparkfun.com/tutorials/transistors/all">transistor</a>. So, the ramp generator will use a transistor in place of the switch:</p>
<p><img alt="An op-amp integrator with a transistor to discharge the capacitor" src="https://blog.thea.codes/static/juno/integrator-with-transistor.png"></p>
<p>Note that I am explicitly not specifying which kind of transistor (PNP, NPN etc)- which one you choose depends on a few other factors so for now I'll keep it abstract. Notice that there's also a new resistor there between the capacitor and the transistor. This is generally a low-value resistor and it's just there to limit the current that goes through the transistor when the capacitor discharges as too much current could damage the transistor.</p>
<p>So now the circuit has a means of electronically resetting the capacitor. The next step is to create a circuit that takes a frequency input signal …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.thea.codes/the-design-of-the-juno-dco/">https://blog.thea.codes/the-design-of-the-juno-dco/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.thea.codes/the-design-of-the-juno-dco/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25598656</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 23:42:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[UK formally leaves European Union after 48 years]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 100 | Comments 209 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25598606">thread link</a>) | @mhh__
<br/>
December 31, 2020 | https://www.rte.ie/news/brexit/2020/1231/1187075-brexit-transition-end/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.rte.ie/news/brexit/2020/1231/1187075-brexit-transition-end/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section itemprop="articleBody" data-epic-field="content">
<p>The United Kingdom's Brexit transition period expired at 11pm last night, ending a 48-year history with the European project.</p>
<p>New <a href="https://www.rte.ie/news/2020/1228/1186705-brexit-eu/" target="_blank">trading rules now apply</a> between Britain and the EU.</p>
<p>Speaking on Wednesday, British Prime Minister Boris Johnson said the destiny of the UK now lies firmly in its people's hands.</p>
<p>He said his government would take on the duty "with a sense of purpose and with the interests of the British public at the heart of everything" it&nbsp;does.</p>
<p>Mr Johnson spoke of wanting a new relationship with the EU as its biggest ally, after <a href="https://www.rte.ie/news/2020/1230/1186933-brexit/" target="_blank">MPs approved the Brexit Withdrawal Agreement yesterday with an overwhelming majority in a House of Commons vote</a>.</p>
<p>17.4 million voters, or 52%&nbsp;opted to leave the EU in a referendum on 23 June 2016.&nbsp;16.1 million, or 48%, voted to remain.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The result of that referendum has dominated British politics ever since and seen the departure of two Prime Ministers,&nbsp;David Cameron and Theresa May,&nbsp;as debate raged about whether another referendum should be called, and how the result of the 2016 vote should be implemented.</p>
<p>The referendum showed a United Kingdom divided about much more than the European Union, and has fuelled soul-searching about everything from secession and immigration to capitalism, empire and modern Britishness.</p>
<p>After the United Kingdom leaves the Single Market and&nbsp;the Customs Union tonight, there is almost certain to be some disruption at borders. More red tape means more cost for those importing and exporting goods across the EU-UK border.</p>
<p>The English Port of Dover expects volumes to drop off in early January. The most worrisome period, it says, will be in mid&nbsp;to late January when volumes pick up again.</p>
<p>Walking away from almost half a century of membership means change to everything from pet passports and driving licence rules for the British in Europe to data rules.</p><hr>
<p><b><a href="https://www.rte.ie/news/brexit/" target="_blank">Latest Brexit stories</a></b></p>
<hr>
<p>After clinching a Christmas Eve trade deal intended to smooth out the worst disruption, European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen quoted both William Shakespeare and TS&nbsp;Eliot.</p>
<p>"Parting is such sweet sorrow," she said. "What we call the beginning is often the end. And to make an end is to make a beginning."</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://img.rasset.ie/00110cec-614.jpg?ratio=1.78"></p>
<p><b>Deal reached to keep Gibraltar border open</b></p>
<p>Gibraltar's border with Spain will remain open following the end of the Brexit transition period,&nbsp;after the UK and European Union agreed a draft deal.</p>
<p>The Rock's status was not covered in the trade agreement reached by Boris Johnson on Christmas Eve, prompting concerns about what would happen when the transition period ends at 11pm tonight.</p>
<p>Gibraltar, whose sovereignty is disputed by Spain and Britain, will remain subject to the rule of the free-travel Schengen area, Spain's foreign minister said.</p>
<p>Arancha Gonzalez Laya announced that the "agreement in principle" means people in Gibraltar "can breathe a sigh of relief".</p>
<p>She said that further details on the agreement would be published in the New Year.</p>
<p>Foreign Secretary Dominic Raab said: "Today, working side by side with the chief minister of Gibraltar, and following intensive discussions with the Spanish government, we reached agreement on a political framework to form the basis of a separate treaty between the UK and the EU regarding Gibraltar.</p>
<p>"We will now send this to the European Commission, in order to initiate negotiations on the formal treaty.</p>
<p>"In the meantime, all sides are committed to mitigating the effects of the end of the transition period on Gibraltar, and in particular ensure border fluidity, which is clearly in the best interests of the people living on both sides.</p>
<p>"We remain steadfast in our support for Gibraltar and its sovereignty. I am grateful to foreign minister Laya and her team for their positive and constructive approach.</p>
<p>"We have a warm and strong relationship with Spain, and we look forward to building on it in 2021."&nbsp;</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://img.rasset.ie/0015eea2-614.jpg?ratio=1.78"></p>
<p><b>Minister updates Cabinet of impact on fishing</b></p>
<p>The Minister for Agriculture has&nbsp;said that&nbsp;while trade can continue tariff-free, he updated the cabinet on the potential impacts on the agri-food and fishing sectors earlier this week.&nbsp;</p>
<p>"The main impacts in relation to administrative costs in doing trade with Britain and also health certification and SPS checks which agri-food products have to undergo," Charlie McConalogue said.</p>
<p>"There is differing assessments in what that might mean," he added.</p>
<p>Speaking on RTÉ's Today with Philip Boucher Hayes, he said there has been significant support assured already in advance of Brexit for the agri-food sector in terms of grant aid and financial support.</p>
<p>He also said post-Brexit he will be going to Brussels to fight the Irish case as strongly as possible for the fisheries sector.</p>
<p>"The Brexit adjustment reserve, we will be looking for our significant share of that in terms of the compensation.</p>
<p>"Also, in terms of working with my European colleagues to ensure we have a strong allocation of quota as we possibly can."&nbsp;</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Revenue has confirmed that its specialised Customs Service is already operating in advance of the Brexit transition period ending tonight</p>
<p>From 11pm a valid Pre-Boarding Notification (PBN) is required for all goods carried by commercial vehicles to and from Britain by ferry.</p>
<p>Revenue says its Customs Roll on-Roll off (RoRo) Service is up and running and a transport company, haulier, importer, exporter or customs agent can create a PBN for any ferry due to sail after 11pm.</p>
<p>The Customs RoRo Service was designed to help efficiently move goods and vehicles between Ireland and Great Britain.</p>
<p>The service also allows truck drivers to check, prior to disembarking a ferry in Ireland, if a vehicle can exit the port or if it is required to call to Customs.</p>
<p><i><b>Additional reporting Mícheál Lehane&nbsp;&nbsp;</b></i></p>
</section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.rte.ie/news/brexit/2020/1231/1187075-brexit-transition-end/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25598606</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 23:38:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[When Nintendo fought a device that gave Mario 'new superpowers']]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 88 | Comments 47 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25596587">thread link</a>) | @avery42
<br/>
December 31, 2020 | https://www.cbc.ca/archives/super-mario-enhancer-1990-1.5799393 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/archives/super-mario-enhancer-1990-1.5799393">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>The Game Genie could make Super Mario jump higher. But Nintendo didn't want him to, and in 1990 the game maker sued a Canadian company over the product.</p><div><p><span><span><div><div title="Game Genie's battle with Nintendo" role="button" tabindex="0"><div><div aria-labelledby="1817989699690-metadata-" title="Game Genie's battle with Nintendo"><div><p><img src="https://thumbnails.cbc.ca/maven_legacy/thumbnails/139/87/game_genie_1391x691.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p></div></div></div></div></div><span>The Game Genie was supposed to make Super Mario jump higher. But in 1990 Nintendo said the console add-on amounted to copyright infringement.<!-- --> <!-- -->2:30</span></span></span></p><p><span><p>The Game Genie could make Super Mario jump higher. But Nintendo wanted to keep him just the way he was.</p>  <p>On Nov. 18, 1990, the CBC business program <em>Venture </em>took viewers inside Nintendo's U.S. headquarters, where frustrated gamers could call for support when playing the video game <em>Super Mario Brothers</em>&nbsp;and others.</p>  <p>"<em>Crystalis</em>," said a caller on the phone with a customer service representative, with an inquiry about the role-playing game of the same name. "I can't defeat the general."</p>  <p>But, as correspondent Nora Pratt explained, the "army of kids" working Nintendo's hotline might not have to field calls about such games for much longer.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>  <h2>'New superpowers'</h2>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799671.1605209899!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/nintendo-help-line.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799671.1605209899!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/nintendo-help-line.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799671.1605209899!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/nintendo-help-line.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799671.1605209899!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/nintendo-help-line.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799671.1605209899!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/nintendo-help-line.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799671.1605209899!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/nintendo-help-line.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>"Did you use the sword of thunder?" asked a troubleshooting customer service representative at Nintendo's American headquarters.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Venture/CBC Archives)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>The reason was a product called the Game Genie, which was distributed in Canada by a company called Camerica.</p>  <p>"Game Genie is an electronic device that lets you give new superpowers to the battling heroes of Nintendo's games," explained Pratt.</p>  <p>According to the Globe and Mail, it was&nbsp;a cartridge that could be attached to a Nintendo game cartridge before being inserted into the game console.&nbsp;</p>  <p>But Nintendo —&nbsp;a Japanese company that had sold $4 billion in games that year —&nbsp;said the Game Genie was "riding on our coattails."&nbsp;</p>  <p>"They are taking our copyrighted work and changing it," said Howard Lincoln, a vice president at Nintendo. "There's no difference between what's happening here and if I were to write <em>Gone With the Wind</em> and change the characters, change the story, change the ending."</p>  <h2>'Mutilating' Mario</h2>  <p><span><span><div><div title="Trouble for the Game Genie" role="button" tabindex="0"><div><div aria-labelledby="1820732483767-metadata-" title="Trouble for the Game Genie"><div><p><img src="https://thumbnails.cbc.ca/maven_legacy/thumbnails/706/827/jump_higher_1383x788.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p></div></div></div></div></div><span>A Canadian company marketing a device to enhance Nintendo game play gets legal pushback from the video game giant.<!-- --> <!-- -->5:05</span></span></span></p>  <p>Pratt said Camerica's David Harding viewed it differently, comparing&nbsp;the device he sold for $50 wholesale to retailers to&nbsp;"any other software add-on."</p>  <p>His company&nbsp;had purchased the "world distribution rights" from Game Genie's&nbsp;British inventors 18 months earlier, and was expecting the Game Genie to generate up to 30 per cent of Camerica's revenues.</p>  <p>"Half a million plus," he said. "That's how many I plan on selling."</p>  <p>An excerpt from a TV commercial for the Game Genie "enhancer" touted its powers to make&nbsp;gamers&nbsp;"run faster" and "jump higher" with a list of retailers already selling it, including Toys R Us, <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/archives/the-240m-deal-that-meant-a-fast-farewell-for-kmart-in-canada-1.5443333">Kmart</a>, Woolco and <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/archives/the-days-when-tough-times-provided-good-times-for-zellers-1.5417584">Zellers</a>.</p>  <p>In August 1990, explained Pratt, Nintendo had filed a lawsuit charging Camerica&nbsp;with "violating their copyright, mutilating an artistic work ... and just plain stealing the fun out of their game."&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>  <p>"It makes our game boring," said Lincoln.</p>  <h2>Legal head-to-head</h2>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799765.1605626142!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/warehouse-boxes.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799765.1605626142!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/warehouse-boxes.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799765.1605626142!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/warehouse-boxes.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799765.1605626142!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/warehouse-boxes.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799765.1605626142!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/warehouse-boxes.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799765.1605626142!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/warehouse-boxes.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Without a victory in court, Camerica faced being stuck with a warehouse full of Game Genies it couldn't sell.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Venture/CBC Archives)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>"Their opinion is, it's harmful to the industry," Harding was seen telling his team after Nintendo filed a second lawsuit.</p>  <p>Both companies had hired PR firms and many lawyers in their fight to control the powers of, "the man in the red hat," as Pratt called Mario.</p>  <p>"That hat's worth billions in sales," said the reporter.</p>  <p>In February&nbsp;1991, according to the Associated Press, Nintendo lost its bid to halt sales of the Game Genie.</p>  <p>"Nintendo, the judge said, had produced 'not&nbsp;one scintilla of proof' that it had&nbsp;suffered&nbsp;irreparable harm from the sale of Camerica's device,"&nbsp;said an AP report in the Globe and Mail.&nbsp;</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799928.1605216746!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/duck-hunt.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799928.1605216746!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/duck-hunt.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799928.1605216746!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/duck-hunt.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799928.1605216746!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/duck-hunt.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799928.1605216746!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/duck-hunt.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5799928.1605216746!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/duck-hunt.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>"In this business, there's no buzzword more deadly than boring," said reporter Nora Pratt as a girl was seen playing Nintendo's Duck Hunt. <!-- --> <!-- -->(Venture/CBC Archives)</figcaption></figure></span></p></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/archives/super-mario-enhancer-1990-1.5799393</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25596587</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 20:08:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pure Digital CSS, Swiss Made, Clock – No JavaScript, almost no HTML]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 133 | Comments 81 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25595439">thread link</a>) | @IceWreck
<br/>
December 31, 2020 | https://www.quaxio.com/pure_css_digital_clock.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.quaxio.com/pure_css_digital_clock.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.quaxio.com/pure_css_digital_clock.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25595439</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 18:26:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Autofocus for the 16mm Telephoto Lens Mounted on the Raspberry Pi HQ Camera]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 90 | Comments 42 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25594894">thread link</a>) | @lemariva
<br/>
December 31, 2020 | https://lemariva.com/blog/2020/12/raspberry-pi-hq-camera-autofocus-telephoto-lens | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://lemariva.com/blog/2020/12/raspberry-pi-hq-camera-autofocus-telephoto-lens">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

<p>This tutorial opens the series of articles about "Project JiJi" and describes how to add autofocus to the 16 mm Telephoto Lens mounted on the Raspberry Pi HQ Camera. In the past months, I've been working on a project to add autofocus to the lens and this is the result:</p><div><p><iframe width="100%" height="315" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PrbyPmq_Z7Q" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div><p>Adding some background to this: The Raspberry Pi Foundation offers different Raspberry Pi Camera modules since 2013. The first module (5-megapixel) was produced in 2013, and an 8-megapixel module upgrade (v2) was released in 2016. Both models have visible light and infrared versions. This year (2020), the Foundation launched the HQ Camera. This is a 12-megapixel High Quality (thus HQ) camera (Sony IMX477), which adds the possibility to use a lens with CS-mount. It is a great upgrade, but the lens and the camera lack autofocus up to now.</p><p>If you are impatient, you can find the hardware design, firmware and software on the <a href="https://github.com/lemariva/rPIFocus">lemariva/rPIFocus</a> and <a href="https://github.com/lemariva/uPyFocus">lemariva/uPyFocus</a> repositories. But, you should come back and read the tutorial until the end, so that you can understand how it works, and if you want to, you can also cooperate on this project!</p><h2><span id="software-and-hardware-590389">Software and Hardware</span></h2><p>This section includes the software and hardware needed for this tutorial.</p><h2><span id="diy-project-jiji-590389">DIY: Project JiJi</span></h2><p>In this article, I will explain how to build the project yourself. I won't go deeper in detail. These will be covered in future articles.</p><h2><span id="hardware-pcb-ordering-soldering-and-mounting-590389">Hardware: PCB ordering, soldering, and mounting</span></h2><p>As you may have already noticed, to add autofocus to the camera, you will need to order a PCB and solder and mount some parts. In the Github repository, under the folder <a href="https://github.com/lemariva/rPIFocus/tree/main/pcb">`pcb</a>`, you'll find the schematic as well as the board files for the PCB. To open those files, you'll need <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.autodesk.de/products/eagle/overview">Eagle</a>. Eagle is still free for hobbyists, thus, download and install it to open the files. You can export Gerber files using <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://support.jlcpcb.com/article/137-how-to-generate-gerber-and-drill-files-in-autodesk-eagle">this export-to-gerber tutorial</a>.</p><p>To simplify the process for you, I also added the Gerber files that you can directly send to your PCB provider. I use and recommend <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://jlcpcb.com/">jlcpcb</a>. They are fast, cheap, reliable and the quality of the boards is pretty good. Check out the setting and costs for this project in Fig. 1. Don't forget to select the LeadFree HASL-RoHS surface finish!</p><div uk-grid=""><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/70d/d54/c63/5fe8fb550b22d311339148__1285.jpg" alt="jlcpcb settings" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/70d/d54/c63/5fe8fb550b22d311339148__1285.jpg 1285w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/70d/d54/c63/5fe8fb550b22d311339148__400.jpg 400w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/70d/d54/c63/5fe8fb550b22d311339148__768.jpg 768w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/70d/d54/c63/5fe8fb550b22d311339148__1024.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1285px) 100vw, 1285px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/70d/d54/c63/5fe8fb550b22d311339148__1285.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/70d/d54/c63/5fe8fb550b22d311339148__1285.jpg 1285w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/70d/d54/c63/5fe8fb550b22d311339148__400.jpg 400w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/70d/d54/c63/5fe8fb550b22d311339148__768.jpg 768w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/70d/d54/c63/5fe8fb550b22d311339148__1024.jpg 1024w"><br><span>Fig. 1: jlcpcb settings for this project.</span></p></div><p>I designed the PCB for people with two types of skills: advanced and basic. So, if you're a pro, grab your solder and solder every element (ICs) for yourself, or, if your skills are basic, don't worry, grab your solder and solder the small hobbies boards that you can buy from the selection above. Two steppers rotate the focus and aperture rings. They are controlled by the M5Stack ATOM, which also measures the steppers' currents and offers an RestAPI to send the commands (see Fig. 2 for an basic PCB schematic).</p><div uk-grid=""><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/625/29e/b52/5feca3f70da50778861950__899.jpg" alt="Simple PCB schematic" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/625/29e/b52/5feca3f70da50778861950__899.jpg 899w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/625/29e/b52/5feca3f70da50778861950__400.jpg 400w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/625/29e/b52/5feca3f70da50778861950__768.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 899px) 100vw, 899px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/625/29e/b52/5feca3f70da50778861950__899.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/625/29e/b52/5feca3f70da50778861950__899.jpg 899w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/625/29e/b52/5feca3f70da50778861950__400.jpg 400w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/625/29e/b52/5feca3f70da50778861950__768.jpg 768w"><br><span>Fig. 2: Simple PCB schematic.</span></p></div><p>Fig. 3 to Fig. 8 show you some close photos of the design to help you to mount the elements. Fig. 3 shows you how to mount the aperture and focus belt rings. They usually have a standard of 0.8 mm pitch. So the motor pinions should be compatible with that. Fig. 4 shows the mounted motor. Check the cable color - or the order! They are connected to the A4988 drivers (Fig. 5) and that's the right connection. Otherwise, the driver won't be able to switch the electromagnets in the right sequence and the motor won't rotate. I planned a cut on the PCB so that the pinion distance to the belt ring can be modified and the motor can be fixed as shown in Fig. 6 (using a 2.5 mm screw) - not the best way, but it works ;). To fix the camera to the board, I used a 3/8 inch screw and an adapter to mount that to a tripod (see Fig. 7). The screw fixes the camera to the board. The camera tends to rotate, and it releases the screw. If that's the case, you can fix it using the two 3mm holes on the left of the camera base (see Fig. 8) with an e.g. rectangular piece of wood over the board. Finally, you need to mount the INA219 and two pinheads for the M5Stack ATOM Matrix. The INA219 measures the current of the steppers, which are used to identify the rotational limits of the focus and aperture rings. Therefore, after booting, the system calibrates itself and it doesn't require encoders to measure the steppers positions.</p><div uk-grid=""><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/028/bde/13d/5fe90f321ecc9579624920__300.jpg" alt="Focus and aperture ring belts" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/028/bde/13d/5fe90f321ecc9579624920__300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/028/bde/13d/5fe90f321ecc9579624920__300.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/028/bde/13d/5fe90f321ecc9579624920__300.jpg 300w"><br><span>Fig. 3: Focus and aperture ring belts.</span></p><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/df5/25f/3b1/5fe90f2482bd7006993442__300.jpg" alt="Motor connection and gear mouting" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/df5/25f/3b1/5fe90f2482bd7006993442__300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/df5/25f/3b1/5fe90f2482bd7006993442__300.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/df5/25f/3b1/5fe90f2482bd7006993442__300.jpg 300w"><br><span>Fig. 4: Motor connection and gear mouting.</span></p><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/4bc/2a4/32c/5fe910d944bfb013963036__300.jpg" alt="A4988 Motor stepper driver" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/4bc/2a4/32c/5fe910d944bfb013963036__300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/4bc/2a4/32c/5fe910d944bfb013963036__300.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/4bc/2a4/32c/5fe910d944bfb013963036__300.jpg 300w"><br><span>Fig. 5: A4988 Motor stepper driver.</span></p><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/b09/476/b07/5fe90f2b34a72694523645__300.jpg" alt="Motor fixing" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/b09/476/b07/5fe90f2b34a72694523645__300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/b09/476/b07/5fe90f2b34a72694523645__300.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/b09/476/b07/5fe90f2b34a72694523645__300.jpg 300w"><br><span>Fig. 6: Motor fixing.</span></p><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/b6f/13c/272/5fe90f3b8a223189023619__300.jpg" alt="Camera fixing / tripod adapter" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/b6f/13c/272/5fe90f3b8a223189023619__300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/b6f/13c/272/5fe90f3b8a223189023619__300.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/b6f/13c/272/5fe90f3b8a223189023619__300.jpg 300w"><br><span>Fig. 7: Camera fixing / tripod adapter.</span></p><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/0cd/6a5/977/5feb9cc4b3ea3328038215__300.jpg" alt="INA219 and M5Stack ATOM matrix" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/0cd/6a5/977/5feb9cc4b3ea3328038215__300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/0cd/6a5/977/5feb9cc4b3ea3328038215__300.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/0cd/6a5/977/5feb9cc4b3ea3328038215__300.jpg 300w"><br><span>Fig. 8: Camera rotate fix option.</span></p><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/2f2/8ca/74e/5fe90f2f2e446168683514__300.jpg" alt="INA219 and M5Stack ATOM matrix" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/2f2/8ca/74e/5fe90f2f2e446168683514__300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/2f2/8ca/74e/5fe90f2f2e446168683514__300.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/2f2/8ca/74e/5fe90f2f2e446168683514__300.jpg 300w"><br><span>Fig. 9: INA219 and M5Stack ATOM matrix.</span></p></div><p>As you can see in Fig. 9, there are some ICs, capacitors, and resistors that aren't assembled and also two cables (red and black). The cables supply 7.5V for the motors. The ICs, capacitors, and resistors are planned to provide 5V and 3.3V to the M5Stack, A4988 drivers, and the INA219. Currently (in that Fig. 9), they are supplied via the USB cable connected, on one end, to the M5Stack, on the other, to the Raspberry Pi. So, you have two ways to supply the system :). But, yes, you need two power suppliers: one for the steppers (7.5V) and one for the Raspberry Pi (5V). The 5V on the board (via ICs) won't be able to supply the Raspberry Pi. Sorry, but I didn't want to use bigger ICs for that.</p><h2><span id="m5stack-application-590389">M5Stack Application</span></h2><p>As I described before, the M5Stack ATOM Matrix controls the motors and offers a RestAPI to receive the commands. The M5Stack application is programmed in MicroPython. If you haven't heard about MicroPython, you can check this tutorial: <a href="https://lemariva.com/blog/2020/03/tutorial-getting-started-micropython-v20">Getting Started with MicroPython on ESP32, M5Stack, and ESP8266</a>. MicroPython is a lean and efficient implementation of the Python 3 programming language that includes a small subset of the Python standard library and is optimized to run on microcontrollers and in "constrained environments".
The application is located <a href="https://github.com/lemariva/uPyFocus">lemariva/uPyFocus</a>.</p><p>So, follow these steps to upload the application to the M5Stack:</p><ol><li>Flash MicroPython to the M5Stack as described in <a href="https://lemariva.com/blog/2020/03/tutorial-getting-started-micropython-v20">this tutorial</a>.</li><li>Clone the <a href="https://github.com/lemariva/uPyFocus">lemariva/uPyFocus</a> repository:
<pre><code>git clone https://github.com/lemariva/uPyFocus.git</code></pre></li><li>Open the folder <code>uPyFocus</code> with <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://code.visualstudio.com/">VSCode</a> and rename the <code>config.py.sample</code> to <code>config.py</code>.</li><li>Open the file and add your Wi-Fi credentials in this section:
<pre><code>wifi = {
    'ssid':'',
    'password':''
}</code></pre>
<p>The M5Stack needs to connect to your Wi-Fi so that the Raspberry Pi (also connected to your Wi-Fi/LAN) can find it and sends the commands to control the steppers.</p></li><li>Upload the application to the M5Stack.</li></ol><p>After uploading the code, the M5Stack resets and starts with the calibration routine (check video section: nnn). Take note of the IP that the M5Stack reports while connecting to your Wi-Fi. You'll need that to configure the Microservices Application.</p><h2><span id="docker-and-docker-compose-on-raspberry-pi-590389">Docker and docker-compose on Raspberry Pi</span></h2><p>The application that runs on the Raspberry Pi is a microservices application. That means different services are orchestrated to offer an application. The orchestration is performed by docker-compose and the services are containerized using Docker.</p><p>To install Docker on the Raspberry Pi, just type the following on a Terminal:</p>
<pre><code>curl -sSL https://get.docker.com | sh
sudo usermod -aG docker pi</code></pre>
<p>If you want to learn more about Docker on Embedded System, just read this tutorial: <a href="https://lemariva.com/blog/2018/05/tutorial-docker-on-embedded-systems-raspberry-pi-beagleboard">Tutorial: Docker on Embedded Systems (Raspberry Pi &amp; Beagleboard)</a></p><p>To orchestrate the services, you need to install <code>docker-compose</code>. This can be done by typing:</p>
<pre><code>sudo pip3 -v install docker-compose</code></pre>
<p>Usually, you need to install these dependencies:</p>
<pre><code>sudo apt-get install -y libffi-dev libssl-dev
sudo apt-get install -y python3 python3-pip
sudo apt-get remove python-configparser</code></pre>
<h2><span id="memory-disk-optional-590389">Memory Disk (optional)</span></h2><p>To take photos faster, you can create a disk on RAM. A RAM disk offers faster access to the data compared to an SD card or a connected USB disk. Thus, this allows the application to reduce the time between photos. To do that, you need to create a folder by typing on a Terminal:</p>
<pre><code>sudo mkdir /mnt/ramdisk</code></pre>
<p>Then, you need to modify the <code>/etc/fstab</code> file and add a line at the end of the file:</p>
<pre><code>sudo nano /etc/fstab
### add the following line at the file's end:
tmpfs /mnt/ramdisk tmpfs nodev,nosuid,size=50M 0 0</code></pre>
<p>Then, you can mount it using:</p>
<pre><code>sudo mount -a</code></pre>
<p>To ensure that everything is working, just reboot your Raspberry Pi using:</p>
<pre><code>sudo reboot</code></pre>
<p>To display the newly created drive and check it use the following command.</p>
<pre><code>df -h</code></pre>
<h2><span id="microservices-application-590389">Microservices Application</span></h2><p>The services of the microservices application are the following:</p><ul><li><strong>webapp</strong>: it provides the frontend application (webserver). It is programmed in Angular.</li><li><strong>backend</strong>: it communicates with the frontend via a RestAPI (Flask server), controls the camera, sends the signals to the M5Stack to control the motors, sends the signals and data to the other services to identify objects and take photos. Basically, it is the core service. It is programmed in Python.</li><li><strong>obj-detector</strong>: it receives an image over UDP and identifies the object on it and returns a JSON message. It is programmed in Python. It uses TensorFlow and connects to the Coral USB Accelerator to process the data in real-time.</li><li><strong>photo-service</strong>: it receives a signal via RestAPI (Flask server) to take photos and it processes them to create HDR photos. It is programmed in Python and it uses Celery for multitasking/non-blocking response to the RestAPI.</li><li><strong>redis</strong>: Celery uses this service to schedule the tasks.</li></ul><div uk-grid=""><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/828/27f/a52/5fec60ad052fc228241834__800.jpg" alt="Webservice Microservices Application" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/828/27f/a52/5fec60ad052fc228241834__800.jpg 800w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/828/27f/a52/5fec60ad052fc228241834__400.jpg 400w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/828/27f/a52/5fec60ad052fc228241834__768.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/828/27f/a52/5fec60ad052fc228241834__800.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/828/27f/a52/5fec60ad052fc228241834__800.jpg 800w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/828/27f/a52/5fec60ad052fc228241834__400.jpg 400w, https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/828/27f/a52/5fec60ad052fc228241834__768.jpg 768w"><br><span>Fig. 10: Webservice Microservices Application.</span></p></div><p>To start the Microservices application, follow these steps:</p><ol><li>Download the <code>docker-compose.yml</code> file or just clone the complete <a href="https://github.com/lemariva/rPIFocus">lemariva/rPIFocus</a> repository:
<pre><code>git clone https://github.com/lemariva/rPIFocus.git</code></pre></li><li>Open the <code>docker-compose.yml</code> file and change the <code>HOST_M5STACK=&lt;ip-address&gt;</code> with the IP of your M5Stack.</li><li>Start the application by typing inside the <code>rPiFocus</code> folder:
<pre><code>docker-compose up -d</code></pre></li><li>Open a browser and visit the URL address: <code>http://&lt;ip-raspberrypi&gt;:4200</code>, you'll see an interface like in Fig. 9. (shhhh... I've just noticed that I wrote Raspberry HD camera and not HQ camera... :()</li><li>To stop the application, type:
<pre><code>docker-compose down</code></pre></li></ol><div uk-grid=""><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/f5a/b64/244/5fec63443a76c981023585__300.jpg" alt="Focus Type: Box - Background focused" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/f5a/b64/244/5fec63443a76c981023585__300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/f5a/b64/244/5fec63443a76c981023585__300.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/f5a/b64/244/5fec63443a76c981023585__300.jpg 300w"><br><span>Fig. 11: Focus Type: Box - Background focused (<a href="https://lemariva.com/storage/app/media/blog_imgs/hqcamera/hq_camera_background_focused.jpg">download</a>).</span></p><p><img data-src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/24c/bc0/434/5fec6339224b0320000410__300.jpg" alt="Focus Type: Box - Nanoblock bird focused" data-srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/24c/bc0/434/5fec6339224b0320000410__300.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" src="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/24c/bc0/434/5fec6339224b0320000410__300.jpg" srcset="https://lemariva.com/storage/temp/public/24c/bc0/434/5fec6339224b0320000410__300.jpg 300w"><br><span>Fig. 12: Focus Type: Box - Nanoblock bird focused (<a href="https://lemariva.com/storage/app/media/blog_imgs/hqcamera/hq_camera_nanoblock_bird_focused.jpg">download</a>).</span></p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://lemariva.com/blog/2020/12/raspberry-pi-hq-camera-autofocus-telephoto-lens">https://lemariva.com/blog/2020/12/raspberry-pi-hq-camera-autofocus-telephoto-lens</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://lemariva.com/blog/2020/12/raspberry-pi-hq-camera-autofocus-telephoto-lens</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25594894</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 17:41:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Probabilistic Machine Learning: An Introduction]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 263 | Comments 37 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25593262">thread link</a>) | @joaorico
<br/>
December 31, 2020 | https://probml.github.io/pml-book/book1.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://probml.github.io/pml-book/book1.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
by Kevin Patrick Murphy.
<br>
MIT Press, 2021.


<h2>Key links</h2>

<ul>

  <li> <a href="https://probml.github.io/pml-book/pml1/pml1-toc-short-2020-12-26.pdf">Short table of
      contents</a>

  </li><li> <a href="https://probml.github.io/pml-book/pml1/pml1-toc-long-2020-12-26.pdf">Long table of
      contents</a>

  </li><li> <a href="https://probml.github.io/pml-book/pml1/pml1-preface-2020-12-26.pdf">Preface</a>

  </li><li> <a href="https://github.com/probml/pml-book/releases/latest/download/pml1.pdf">Draft pdf file</a>,  CC-BY-NC-ND license. (Please cite the official reference below.)

    </li><li> <a href="https://somsubhra.com/github-release-stats/?username=probml&amp;repository=pml-book&amp;page=1&amp;per_page=5">Book download statistics</a>
    
    </li><li> <a href="https://github.com/probml/pyprobml">Python code</a>
      
  </li><li> <a href="https://github.com/probml/pml-book/issues">Issue tracker</a>. Use this to report problems with the book and/or code. Be sure to specify which 
    release (date stamp) of the book you are using. Please specify pdf and print page number (which sometimes differ). For reporting small typos, please collect
    a batch of errors into a doc, and create a single issue.
      
</li></ul>

If you use this book, please be sure to cite
<pre><code>
 @book{pml1Book,
 author = "Kevin P. Murphy",
 title = "Probabilistic Machine Learning: An introduction",
 publisher = "MIT Press",
 year = 2021,
 url = "http://mlbayes.ai"
}
</code></pre>

<h2> Endorsements</h2>

<ul>

  <li> "My favorite machine learning book just received a face-lift!
    'Probabilistic Machine Learning: An Introduction' is the most
    comprehensive and accessible book on modern machine learning by a
    large margin.  
    It now also covers the latest developments in deep learning and
    causal discovery. With this upgrade it will remain the reference
    book for our field that every respected researcher needs to have
    on their desk."  -- <a href="https://staff.fnwi.uva.nl/m.welling/">Max Welling</a>,
    U. Amsterdam 

    </li><li> "There are many books on machine learning out there, but none gives
    such a well-rounded, up-to-date, and comprehensive view of the
    field as this one. We use this book as reference reading for our
    students taking the advanced machine learning course at Oxford to
    introduce them to fundamental as well as current topics in the
    field. I'm amazed at the amount of work that went into this
    book---which will surely be used by many to train the next
      generation of machine learning experts."
      -- <a href="http://www.cs.ox.ac.uk/people/yarin.gal/website/">Yarin    Gal</a>, U. Oxford
    

    </li></ul>

<h2>Table of contents</h2>

<br>
    <img src="https://probml.github.io/pml-book/pml1/pml1-toc-short-2col-2020-12-27.png" alt="TOC 2020-12-26">
</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://probml.github.io/pml-book/book1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25593262</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 15:03:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Spirulina Algae Photobioreactor (2017)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 59 | Comments 16 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25593247">thread link</a>) | @seesawtron
<br/>
December 31, 2020 | https://www.mikechatzidakis.com/home/2017/7/29/spirulina-algae-photobioreactor | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.mikechatzidakis.com/home/2017/7/29/spirulina-algae-photobioreactor">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <article id="article-597d365603596eab18a33f7f">
      
      <div>
        <p><time datetime="2016-07-28" pubdate="">
          <p><span>Jul </span><span>28</span>
          </p>
        </time></p><h2 itemprop="headline" data-content-field="title"><time itemprop="datePublished" datetime="2016-07-28" pubdate="">Jul 28 </time>Spirulina Algae Photobioreactor</h2>

        
      </div>
      
      <div data-controller="BlogProgressBar">
        
        
        <div><div data-layout-label="Post Body" data-type="item" data-updated-on="1501378473772" id="item-597d365603596eab18a33f7f"><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-5b388869c77c096f4e8c"><div><p>I first heard about <em>Arthospira platensis</em> (Spirulina) when I saw a NASA mission featuring the growth of these microbes onboard the ISS. Why grow a cyanobacteria in space you might say? Well what these little guys can do is convert carbon dioxide into oxygen gas for one, and secondly they can also be ingested as a protein substitute. It contains<a target="_blank" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spirulina_(dietary_supplement)#Food_and_nutrition"> 50-70% protein </a>by dry weight for starters, high in iron, and is nearly 300 cals / 100 g to boot. So in terms of a great symbiotic friend for a closed biome (i.e. a sealed steel ball in orbit), Spirulina is a pretty darn perfect room mate.</p><p>Okay I was hooked after a few videos from Youtube and Reddit. How do I get a sample of this West African extremophile? Turns out Amazon, among a myraid of products, also carries this...</p><p>So I ordered this from <a target="_blank" href="http://www.algaelab.org/">AlgaeLab</a> back when they had a Amazon store, it appears they don't have it anymore (July 2017). But they still do ship from their website. So take this in, I purchased a biological sample, shipping from California to Toronto, and it arrived in a little over a week with a bunch of Alkali salts without any major delay at customs. Are you kidding me? A biological sample and miscellaneous white powder can pass through the borders that easy, but I have had books delayed?!</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1501375207629_153452"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501381077828-VKSVEYADYJIT9Y4URHOU/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kA9MJP8G-Te-KF6G_txWkV1Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWEtT5uBSRWt4vQZAgTJucoTqqXjS3CfNDSuuf31e0tVHz1OCtlxDsjXY12tun39jAhdGVKUGCmpVBBjfR2L-Oc8E8-vZB1rw5b7FMBZGIOl4/image-asset.jpeg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501381077828-VKSVEYADYJIT9Y4URHOU/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kA9MJP8G-Te-KF6G_txWkV1Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWEtT5uBSRWt4vQZAgTJucoTqqXjS3CfNDSuuf31e0tVHz1OCtlxDsjXY12tun39jAhdGVKUGCmpVBBjfR2L-Oc8E8-vZB1rw5b7FMBZGIOl4/image-asset.jpeg" data-image-dimensions="400x711" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Spirulina sample sent from AlgaeLab" data-load="false" data-image-id="597d379d3e00bed8e5d33b4d" data-type="image" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501381077828-VKSVEYADYJIT9Y4URHOU/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kA9MJP8G-Te-KF6G_txWkV1Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWEtT5uBSRWt4vQZAgTJucoTqqXjS3CfNDSuuf31e0tVHz1OCtlxDsjXY12tun39jAhdGVKUGCmpVBBjfR2L-Oc8E8-vZB1rw5b7FMBZGIOl4/image-asset.jpeg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
          
          <figcaption>
            <p>Spirulina sample sent from AlgaeLab</p>
          </figcaption>
        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1501381010248_13798"><p>I was so fascinated when I got the sample. It could photosynthesize before your eyes! I recorded a timelapse to see it in direct sunlight. Pretty dope right. The timelapse was over half an hour and condensed into about 5 seconds.</p></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1501381010248_22505"><div><p>The kit from AlgaeLab came with alkali salts and nutrients with directions and ratios for dilution to the volume of water. I took the starter vial and added it into a large Voss glass water bottle.</p><p>Using aquarium air pumps, air was piped through plastic tubing. First into a water percolator to catch dust, then into the glass bottles. One tube was connected to an airstone which creates small air bubbles which will allow greater oxygen dissolution into the medium, and the second tube causes stirring from the bottom to the top of the water column by means of entraining liquid in a bubble tea straw similar to an <a target="_blank" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Airlift_pump">airlift pump</a> or geyser pump. The effect of the air pump is then two fold, greater carbon dioxide diffusion and stirring of the algae.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1501381010248_27504"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501382433389-XTE9RHMTZODM1Z7DY6EQ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPTrHXgsMrSIMwe6YW3w1AZ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fKTrY37saURwPBw8fO2esROAxn-RKSrlQamlL27g22X2A/image-asset.jpeg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501382433389-XTE9RHMTZODM1Z7DY6EQ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPTrHXgsMrSIMwe6YW3w1AZ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fKTrY37saURwPBw8fO2esROAxn-RKSrlQamlL27g22X2A/image-asset.jpeg" data-image-dimensions="2500x1406" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Spirulina reactor underneath the window with a DIY hydroponic garden above it." data-load="false" data-image-id="597d470a4402438918214587" data-type="image" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501382433389-XTE9RHMTZODM1Z7DY6EQ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPTrHXgsMrSIMwe6YW3w1AZ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fKTrY37saURwPBw8fO2esROAxn-RKSrlQamlL27g22X2A/image-asset.jpeg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
          
          <figcaption>
            <p>Spirulina reactor underneath the window with a DIY hydroponic garden above it.</p>
          </figcaption>
        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1501381010248_30812"><p>Below is a short video of the pump system in action. The third tube at the top of the reactors is just for air outflow to avoid pressure building. It would frequently sputter out water and salt everywhere. I will touch on the hydroponic garden in a later blog post.</p></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1501381010248_32831"><div><p>Around one week later we have hit the first exponential bloom phase! Here is another great thing about autotropic microbes, they are so freaking efficient. No photons wasted! Well, I guess thats not entirely true, many photons wasted, but they make trees look like slackers.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1501381010248_34530"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501382904391-J9202TDVO03SJCCBJ9LZ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPTrHXgsMrSIMwe6YW3w1AZ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fKTrY37saURwPBw8fO2esROAxn-RKSrlQamlL27g22X2A/image-asset.jpeg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501382904391-J9202TDVO03SJCCBJ9LZ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPTrHXgsMrSIMwe6YW3w1AZ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fKTrY37saURwPBw8fO2esROAxn-RKSrlQamlL27g22X2A/image-asset.jpeg" data-image-dimensions="2500x1406" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="" data-load="false" data-image-id="597d48f6d2b8570b18c96491" data-type="image" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501382904391-J9202TDVO03SJCCBJ9LZ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPTrHXgsMrSIMwe6YW3w1AZ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fKTrY37saURwPBw8fO2esROAxn-RKSrlQamlL27g22X2A/image-asset.jpeg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1501381010248_35744"><div><p>I think however my favourite thing about Spirulina is their defense mechanism towards getting too much light. Ever wonder why its called Spirlina? The cyanobacteria form a spiral-like shape when they get too much sunlight. Since sunlight is always going to come from one direction at a time (applied to one face), by rearranging into a spiral, only a fraction of total surface area is exposed. And what if the amount of light is too low and not ideal? They straighten out into a line to increase available surface area! How neat is that?</p><p>I bought a cheap $60 chinese microscope on Amazon (most of my projects start at amazon tbh) capable of 800x magnification and I took a cell phone picture through the cheap crappy plastic lenses. As you can see, spirals! Look at that!</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1501381010248_38600"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501383118830-BZR0QQY1JFXL7T3BGT0I/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPTrHXgsMrSIMwe6YW3w1AZ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fKTrY37saURwPBw8fO2esROAxn-RKSrlQamlL27g22X2A/image-asset.jpeg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501383118830-BZR0QQY1JFXL7T3BGT0I/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPTrHXgsMrSIMwe6YW3w1AZ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fKTrY37saURwPBw8fO2esROAxn-RKSrlQamlL27g22X2A/image-asset.jpeg" data-image-dimensions="2500x1406" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="" data-load="false" data-image-id="597d49cd197aea062b6f648b" data-type="image" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501383118830-BZR0QQY1JFXL7T3BGT0I/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPTrHXgsMrSIMwe6YW3w1AZ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fKTrY37saURwPBw8fO2esROAxn-RKSrlQamlL27g22X2A/image-asset.jpeg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1501381010248_61733"><div><p>It was at this point in the project where I realized I should never step foot in a casino. I had a nice batch of algae, now should I do double or nothing? Because of this whole exponential growth business, if my principal amount of algae is higher than before, I should get a ton more algae if I throw in a new batch of nutrients. Or maybe I should harvest these in a 5 micron cloth for consumption and grow a fraction of them again?</p><p>I decided to scale up the operation, and I was at this (below) amount of algae after another 10 days. I put an aquarium heater in the large sack of algae to maintain its temperature at ~32 C.</p><p>I also made this sack of plastic by buying a roll of vacuum pack freezer bag. Typically the vacuum pack machines use this uncut freezer bag material and they singe it closed to the correct size using a heated metal wire. I reproduced this and sealed the bags using a soldering iron. I should note all of these vials are hanging precariously above where I sleep... I sure have a lot of faith in a DIY sealed plastic bag eh??</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1501381010248_63989"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501383866718-SN6I2ATQOEWRB21P8HKO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPTrHXgsMrSIMwe6YW3w1AZ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fKTrY37saURwPBw8fO2esROAxn-RKSrlQamlL27g22X2A/image-5883.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/597d2753be6594cef6a34840/1501383866718-SN6I2ATQOEWRB21P8HKO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPTrHXgsMrSIMwe6YW3w1AZ7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0k5fwC0WRNFJBIXiBeNI5fKTrY37saURwPBw8fO2esROAxn-RKSrlQamlL27g22X2A/image-5883.jpg" data-image-dimensions="2500x1406" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="image-5883.jpg" data-load="false" data-image-id="597d4cb8d482e9f4cc74af7a" data-type="image" src="https://www.mikechatzidakis.com/home/2017/7/29/image-5883.jpg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_2_1501381010248_66437"><div><p>I'm sure you are wondering, "But Mike, you said you shouldn't gamble at a casino, wasn't this a good gamble? Thats a great yield in the picture above?!" Well, you are indeed correct, its a great yield, but what happened next was quite traumatic for me (no the sack did not fall on my head while I slept). I left for a long weekend, and over that weekend we had one of the hottest heat waves in a while. Between the aquarium heater, tne additional heat and photon flux, the algae overheated and turned yellow. I tried to shade them and I took out the heater but they died.</p><p>I know, there is no happy ending, I'm sorry if you got emotionally invested through this journey. Yes they died, they are very fickle and although they are extremophiles that live in Eastern African salt lakes, they are not invincible.</p><p>I will add more to this blog post as I get along, a few other topics I want to hit (because i researched them during construction) are the following:</p><p>&nbsp;- Fresh vs dried spirulina</p></div></div></div></div></div></div>

        

        

        
      </div>
      

    </article>
  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.mikechatzidakis.com/home/2017/7/29/spirulina-algae-photobioreactor</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25593247</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 15:01:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Big Little Guide to Message Queues]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 266 | Comments 107 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25591492">thread link</a>) | @sudhirj
<br/>
December 31, 2020 | https://sudhir.io/the-big-little-guide-to-message-queues/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://sudhir.io/the-big-little-guide-to-message-queues/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            
<div>
    <main>
            <article>
    
    <div>
                <p>Message Queues are now fairly prevalent—there are so many of them showing up so fast you'd think they were <a href="https://www.rabbitmq.com/">rabbits</a> with an unlimited supply of <a href="https://docs.celeryproject.org/en/stable/">celery</a>, resulting in an <a href="https://kafka.apache.org/">kafkaesque</a> situation where making a decision is like trying to catch a <a href="https://redis.io/topics/streams-intro">stream</a> in your hands. If only there were fewer <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/sns">simple</a> <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/sqs/">services</a> that could help with <a href="https://cloud.google.com/pubsub">publishing and subscribing</a>, it would be so much easier to make a <a href="https://zeromq.org/">zero-effort</a> choice 😕</p><p>Whether we use them by themselves as-is to move data between parts of our application, or as an integral part of the architecture (like event driven systems), message queues are here to stay. In a way, they've been here all along—just without as many names. But what are they? Why are they useful? And how do we use them effectively? Which implementation do we pick? Does it even matter which one we use? And do we need to learn each of them individually, or are there more general concepts that apply to all message queues?</p><p>In this guide, we'll talk about:</p><ul><li>What message queues are and their history.</li><li>Why they're useful and what mental models to use when reasoning about them.</li><li>Delivery guarantees that the queuing systems make (at-least-once, at-most-once, and exactly-once semantics).</li><li>Ordering and FIFO guarantees and how they effect sequencing, parallelism and performance.</li><li>Patterns for fan-out and fan-in: delivering one message to many systems or messages from many systems into one.</li><li>Notes on the pros and cons of many popular systems available today.</li></ul><h2 id="what-are-message-queues">What are message queues?</h2><p>Message Queues are a way to transfer information between two systems. This information—a message—can be data, metadata, signals, or a combination of all three. The systems that are sending and receiving messages could be processes on the same computer, modules of the same application, services that might but running on different computers or technology stacks, or entirely different kinds of systems altogether—like transferring information from your software into an email or an SMS on the cellphone network.</p><p>The idea of a messaging system has been around a very long time, from the message boxes used for moving information between people or office departments (literally where the words <em>inbox </em>and <em>outbox</em> come from), to telegrams, to your local postal or courier service. The messaging systems in the physical world that come closest to what we have in computing are probably the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pneumatic_tube">pnuematic</a> <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=pneumatic+tubes&amp;source=lnms&amp;tbm=isch&amp;sa=X&amp;biw=2560&amp;bih=1366">tubes</a> that moved messages through buildings and cities using compressed air until a few decades ago (and are still used in some places today).</p><p>The kinds of messages we transfer today might be a note that something technical happened, like CPU usage exceeding a limit; or a business event of interest, like a customer placing an order; or a signal, like a command that tells another service to do something. The contents of each message will be driven entirely by the architecture of your application and its purposes—so for the rest of this guide, we don't need to be concerned about what's inside a message—we're more concerned with how the message gets from the system where it originates (the <em>producer</em>, <em>source, publisher</em> or <em>sender</em>) to the system where's it's supposed to go (the <em>consumer</em>, <em>subscriber</em>, <em>destination</em> or <em>receiver</em>).</p><h2 id="and-why-do-we-need-them">And Why Do We Need Them?</h2><p>We need message queues because no system exists or works in isolation—all systems need to communicate with other systems in structured ways that they both can understand, and at a controlled speed that they both can handle. Any non-trivial process needs a way to move information between each stage of the process; any workflow needs a way to move the intermediate product between the stages of that workflow. Message queues are a great way to handle this movement. There are plenty of ways of getting these messages around using API calls, file systems, or many other abuses of the natural order of things; but all of these are ad-hoc implementations of the message queue that we sometimes refuse to acknowledge we need.</p><p>The simplest mental model for a message queue is a very long tube that you can roll a ball into. You write your message on a ball, roll it into the tube, and someone or something else receives it at the other end. There are a lot of interesting benefits with this model, some of which are:</p><ul><li>We don't need to worry about <em>who or what</em> is going to receive the message – that's one less responsibility for the sender to be concerned about.</li><li>We don't need to worry about <em>when</em> the receiver is going to pick up the message.</li><li>We can put <em>as many</em> messages as we want into the tube (let's assume we have a infinitely long tube) at whatever <em>speed</em> is comfortable to us.</li><li>The receiver will <em>never be impacted</em> by our actions—they will pull out as many messages as they want at whatever rate is comfortable to them.</li><li>Neither the sender nor the receiver are concerned with <em>how</em> the other works.</li><li>Neither the sender nor the receiver are concerned with the <em>capacity or load</em> of the other.</li><li>Neither system is concerned with <em>where</em> the other one is – they may or many not reside on the same computer, network, continent or even the same planet.</li></ul><p>Each of these advantages (and this isn't even an exhaustive list) has very important benefits in software development—what they all have in common is <em>decoupling</em>. One system is decoupled from the other in terms of responsibility, time, bandwidth, internal workings, load and geography. And decoupling is a very desirable part of any distributed or complex system—the more decoupled the parts of the system are, the easier it is to independently build, test, run, maintain and scale them.</p><p>Most systems interact with other outside or third-party systems as well—if we build a shopping site we might interact with a payment processor, and let’s say we attempt to directly communicate with the payment processor on each user click. If our system is under heavy load, we're also subjecting the other system to the same load. And vice versa—if our payment provider needs to send us millions of pieces of information about our past payment statues, our system better be ready. The two systems are now <em>coupled</em>. The decisions and actions made by one system have a significant impact on the other, so the needs of both need to be taken into account while making every decision. Add enough other systems into the mix, like logistics or delivery systems, and we quickly have a paralysing mess that makes it difficult to decide anything at all. If one system goes down, the other systems have effectively gone down as well, for no fault of their own.</p><p>We’re also in trouble if we want to switch out any one of these systems for another one, like a new payment processor or delivery system. We’d have to make deep changes in multiple places in our application, and it’s even more difficult to build code to split our messages between multiple providers—we may want to use a ratio to load balance them or split them by geography; or dynamically switch between them based on each provider’s availability or cost.</p><p>Message queues offer the decoupling that solves a lot of these problems. If we set up a queue between two systems that need to communicate with each other, they can now go about their work without having to worry about each other at all—we put our messages aimed at any system into a queue, and we expect information from the other system to come to us through another queue as well. We now have clear points at which we can add rules or make the changes we require, without either system knowing or caring about what's different.</p><h3 id="so-what-s-the-catch">So what's the catch?</h3><p>Are message queues the holy grail of computing, though? Do they solve all the world's problems? No, of course not. There are plenty of situations where we might not want to use them. And we certainly don't want to use a queue just because we have one easily available and think it might be fun. There are some systems that are really simple that just don't require it—a message queue is a way to reduce to complexity of communicating systems, but two communicating systems will always be more complex than one system that doesn't have to communicate. If you have a system that’s simple enough to not require communication with any others, there simply isn't any reason to reach for a queue.</p><p>There are also systems that communicate with each other, but where the complexity added by that communication added is insignificant and not worth worrying about. Or more often the systems are already coupled, in the sense that they all need to work together to function. A really common example is an application server and a data service (in an <em>OLTP</em> system). There's not much point in decoupling them with a queue, because neither can do anything useful without the direct involvement of the other.</p><p>Then there's performance to consider as well—the whole point of decoupling two systems with regards to time and load is so that they can each process information at their own pace—but we certainly would <em>not</em> want this to happen in performance sensitive applications or real-time systems. A queue might help us process more work at the same time (the receiver might have many processes working in parallel on the messages you send) but will remove any guarantees we need about the exact time taken for each piece of work. If predictability is more important than throughput, we're better off without a queue.</p><p>Using a queue might increase the time taken to process each <em>individual</em> message, but will allow you process many more messages at the same time across different computers—so your total number of messages processed per minute or hour, or <em>throughput</em>, will increase.</p><p>If we do have multiple systems that need to communicate, and that communication needs to be <em>durable </em>(if we’ve put a message into a queue, we want to be sure that the messaging system isn’t going to ‘forget’ about it) and decoupled, a message queue is indispensable.</p><h2 id="arguing-semantics">Arguing Semantics</h2><p>There's simply no way to learn about message queues without reading and/or arguing about delivery guarantees …</p></div></article></main></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://sudhir.io/the-big-little-guide-to-message-queues/">https://sudhir.io/the-big-little-guide-to-message-queues/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://sudhir.io/the-big-little-guide-to-message-queues/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25591492</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 10:38:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Shamelessness as a Strategy (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 186 | Comments 202 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25591066">thread link</a>) | @etherio
<br/>
December 31, 2020 | https://nadiaeghbal.com/shameless | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nadiaeghbal.com/shameless">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div ?="">
        <p>I’ve enjoyed playing a game called Avalon recently. I won’t go too far into the rules, but it’s a <a href="https://www.bestplay.co/ultimate-guide-hidden-role-board-games/">hidden role game</a> in the vein of Secret Hitler or Werewolf, where one team is “good”, trying to uncover who among them is “evil”, before the evil team wins.</p>

<p>One of the characters you can play is Merlin. Merlin knows who the evil players are, but can’t reveal what he knows, because the evil team can kill Merlin and win the game. So Merlin relies on another character, Percival, to be his decoy.</p>

<p>Percival’s only power is that he knows who Merlin is. So he secretly watches Merlin’s actions throughout the game and amplifies those signals to the rest of the group. The typical strategy is for Percival to attract attention away from Merlin and towards himself.</p>

<p>But another, riskier strategy is for <em>Merlin</em> to play as though <em>he</em> is Percival. In this case, Merlin displays what he knows so shamelessly that he throws everyone off. The evil team, believing that no Merlin would be stupid enough to put himself out there like that, figures he must be Percival, and writes him off.</p>

<p>The Merlin-as-Percival strategy is bold, because it blatantly defies our expectations about how the game is won. To pull it off, Merlin must create confusion around his actions. He needs the other players to feel unsure about whether he’s being incredibly stupid or incredibly smart.</p>

<p>Increasingly, I think the “shameless” approach is becoming a dominant strategy today. It was first popularized in modern canon by Paris Hilton, who played the “dumb blonde heiress” stereotype so smoothly that everyone assumed she really was as stupid as she seemed.</p>

<p>Paris didn’t play by the “obvious” rules for famous people. She was widely derided by both media and her peers as at best, a train wreck, and at worst, a self-serving aggrandizer. And yet, people couldn’t stop talking about her. A decade later, Paris is now remembered as the mastermind behind the playbook that’s made the Kardashians, Jenners, and other celebrity socialites so successful.</p>

<p>It’s important to note that people were dismissive of Paris because validating her playbook would mean admitting that <em>they</em> were playing an inferior game. Everyone else had invested years into optimizing for the most legible version of the rules. They’d look silly if they were to admit she had found a better way of doing things.</p>

<p>Without getting into tiresome politics, the “shameless” strategy also defined the 2016 U.S. presidential elections. It was shouted down by people in both established political parties, because they were used to playing by the “obvious” rules, but I suspect that in a decade’s time, we’ll look back on that election and realize that it marked the beginning of an entirely new style of politics.</p>

<p>Ditto to, perhaps, the leadership styles of Mark Zuckerberg, who’s followed the “obvious” playbook for years, versus Jack Dorsey, who employs tactics that seem so obviously stupid (tweeting about fasting and meditation!) that we’re quick to write them off. And yet, I’d guess that Zuckerberg’s strategy makes him increasingly unlikeable and untrustworthy, in the same way that any major politician sticking to a pre-2016 playbook today is almost certainly not going to win.</p>

<p>The shameless strategy feels counterintuitive, because our first instinct is to want to punish that sort of behavior. And historically, those sanctions have been effective. Punishing outlandish behavior is an important aspect of cooperative governance: it preserves social order by ensuring that we all play by the same rules.</p>

<p>Today, it seems like punishing shamelessness only <em>increases</em> social rewards to the transgressor. What’s changed?</p>

<p>One explanation might be that it’s an expected effect of the blurring of social boundaries today. In the past, if the size of your community was finitely bounded (like a village, or an aristocratic social class), people didn’t enter or exit these communities as frequently. Under these conditions, sanctions are probably still effective, because members of the community want to be liked and accepted.</p>

<p>But the borders to online communities are much more fluid - perhaps even nonexistent. Under open borders, sanctions will backfire, because they just serve as a signaling boost for the transgressor, attracting outsiders who resonate with that person’s message. What’s meant to be punishment instead becomes a flare shot straight into the night sky.</p>

<p>The “establishment” mistakenly assumes that a shameless person wants the approval of their community, when it turns out that, much like any cult or counterculture, that person’s goal was to attract a following, regardless of who the members are. The disgust of one’s peers doesn’t matter anymore, because that disgust forms the basis for an entirely new community.</p>

<p>A common critique of shameless people is questioning their intelligence. But one of the most bizarre aspects here is it doesn’t actually matter how aware that person is of what they’re doing. The concept of a “genius mastermind” is itself outdated, because it assumes that someone needs to be in control. The shameless person is simply a host for a set of ideas, which, like any virus, will continue to propagate as long as there are willing hosts to receive it.</p>

<p>I’m not really sure what the long-term implications of shamelessness will be. I also don’t think that everybody has to employ this strategy to win (at least, I hope not!). But what I do know is when I see my peers rolling their eyes at someone or deriding them for being “shameless”, there’s a good chance that, instead of writing them off, we should examine their actions a bit more closely.</p>

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nadiaeghbal.com/shameless</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25591066</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 09:26:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[RC3 talk: How to survive in spacecraft [video]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 77 | Comments 13 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25590724">thread link</a>) | @hurlga
<br/>
December 31, 2020 | https://media.ccc.de/v/rc3-158638-how_to_survive_in_spacecraft | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://media.ccc.de/v/rc3-158638-how_to_survive_in_spacecraft">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">



<div>

<p>
<span></span>
<a href="https://media.ccc.de/search?p=urs">urs</a>

</p>

<p><a href="https://media.ccc.de/c/rc3/Chaos-West" rel="tag">Chaos-West</a>
<a href="https://media.ccc.de/c/rc3/CWTV" rel="tag">CWTV</a>
Playlists:
<a href="https://media.ccc.de/v/rc3-158638-how_to_survive_in_spacecraft/playlist">'rc3' videos starting here</a>
/
<a data-method="get" href="https://media.ccc.de/v/rc3-158638-how_to_survive_in_spacecraft/audio">audio</a></p>
<!-- %h3 About -->
<p>If you pop out into space, you die. No oxygen to breathe, no ambient pressure makes your bodily fluids boil, UV radiation burns your skin to a crisp. It's not a good place to be for humans. So in order to survive, you need to bring a number of things along, commonly called the "life support system". This talk explains how this works!</p>

<p>How do oxygen generators and CO_2 scrubbers work? Do you need to heat or cool your craft? If you eat beans and fart a lot, do you ever get rid of the smell? Can you just fill your spacecraft with plants and live off them? <br> This talk goes through historic, present and future ways that life support is managed in spacecraft, spacesuits and future planetary outposts. It also explains why you have to breathe your own pee on the International Space Station. <br> (This is the logical followup to the two previous, german talks about how to fly spaceships and how to build them, from the GulaschProgrammierNacht 13 and 16)</p>

<p>Slides: http://urs.nerd2nerd.org/rC3-talk.svg</p>

<h3>Download</h3>

<!-- %h3 Embed/Share -->

<h3>Tags</h3>

</div>





</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://media.ccc.de/v/rc3-158638-how_to_survive_in_spacecraft</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25590724</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 08:26:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Linux Hardening Guide]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 441 | Comments 272 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25590079">thread link</a>) | @FlyMoreRockets
<br/>
December 30, 2020 | https://madaidans-insecurities.github.io/guides/linux-hardening.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://madaidans-insecurities.github.io/guides/linux-hardening.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
    

    <p><i><time datetime="2020-12-25">Last edited: December 25, 2020</time></i></p>

    <div>
      <p><a href="https://madaidans-insecurities.github.io/linux.html">Linux is not a secure operating system</a>. However, there are steps you can take to improve it. This guide aims to explain
      how to harden Linux as much as possible for security and privacy. This guide attempts to be distribution-agnostic and is not tied to any specific one. </p><p>
      
      DISCLAIMER: Do not attempt to apply anything in this article if you do not know exactly what you are doing. This guide is focused purely on security and privacy,
      not performance, usability, or anything else. </p><p>
      
      All commands listed in this guide will require root privileges. Words beginning with "$" sign indicate a variable that may differ between users as to suit their
      setup.
    </p></div>

    <h2>Contents</h2>

    

    <h2 id="choosing-the-right-distro"><a href="#choosing-the-right-distro">1. Choosing the right Linux distribution</a></h2>

    <p>
      There are many factors that go into choosing a good Linux distribution.
    </p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        Avoid distributions that freeze packages as <a href="https://madaidans-insecurities.github.io/linux.html#debian">they are often quite behind on security updates</a>.
      </li>

      <li>
        Use a distribution with an init system other than <a href="https://systemd.io/">systemd</a>. systemd contains a lot of unnecessary
        attack surface; <a href="https://ewontfix.com/14/">it attempts to do far more things than necessary</a> and goes beyond what an
        init system should do. An init system should not need many lines of code to function properly.
      </li>

      <li>
        Use <a href="https://musl.libc.org/">musl</a> as the default C library. musl is heavily focused on minimality which <a href="https://github.com/NixOS/nixpkgs/issues/90147#issuecomment-643473182">results in very small attack surface</a> whereas other C libraries
        such as glibc are overly complex and prone to vulnerabilities. For example, <a href="https://www.cvedetails.com/vulnerability-list/vendor_id-72/product_id-767/GNU-Glibc.html">
        over a hundred vulnerabilities in glibc have been publicly disclosed</a> compared to the <a href="https://www.cvedetails.com/vulnerability-list/vendor_id-16859/product_id-39652/Musl-libc-Musl.html">
        very few in musl</a>. While counting CVEs by itself is often an inaccurate statistic, it can sometimes be used to represent an overaching issue such as
        in this case. musl also has <a href="https://www.dustri.org/b/security-features-of-musl.html"> decent exploit mitigations</a>, particularly its
        <a href="https://www.openwall.com/lists/musl/2020/05/13/1">new hardened memory allocator</a>.
      </li>

      <li>
        Preferably use a distribution that utilizes <a href="https://www.libressl.org/">LibreSSL</a> by default rather than <a href="https://www.openssl.org/">
        OpenSSL</a>. <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2014/04/openssl-code-beyond-repair-claims-creator-of-libressl-fork/">OpenSSL contains
        tremendous amounts of totally unnecessary attack surface and follows poor security practices</a>. For example, it still maintains OS/2 and VMS support —
        ancient operating systems that are multiple decades old. These abhorrent security practices are what led to the dreaded <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heartbleed">Heartbleed vulnerability</a>. LibreSSL is a fork of OpenSSL by the OpenBSD team that applies
        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LibreSSL#Changes">superior programming practices</a> and <a href="https://opensslrampage.org/">eradicates
        a lot of attack surface</a>. Within LibreSSL's first year, <a href="https://www.openbsd.org/papers/libtls-fsec-2015/mgp00005.html">it mitigated a
        large number of vulnerabilities, including a few high severity ones</a>.
      </li>
    </ul>

    <div><p>
      The best distribution to use as a base for your hardened operating system would be <a href="https://www.gentoo.org/">Gentoo Linux</a> as it allows you to configure
      your system exactly how you want it to be which will be extremely useful, especially when we come to <a href="#hardened-compilation-flags">more secure compilation
      flags</a> later in the guide. </p><p>
      
      However, Gentoo may not be feasible for many people due to its significant usability pitfalls. In this case, <a href="https://voidlinux.org/">Void Linux</a>'s musl
      build is a good compromise.
    </p></div>

    <h2 id="kernel"><a href="#kernel">2. Kernels</a></h2>

    <p>
      The kernel is the core of the operating system and is unfortunately very prone to attacks. As Brad Spengler has once said, <a href="https://grsecurity.net/huawei_hksp_introduces_trivially_exploitable_vulnerability">it can be thought of as the largest,
      most vulnerable setuid root binary on the system</a>. Thus, it is very important for the kernel to be hardened as much as possible.
    </p>

    <h3 id="stable-vs-lts"><a href="#stable-vs-lts">2.1 Stable vs. LTS kernels</a></h3>

    <div><p>
      The Linux kernel is released under two main forms: stable and long-term support (LTS). Stable releases are more recent whereas LTS
      releases are an older stable release that is being supported for a long time. <a href="https://www.grsecurity.net/the_truth_about_linux_4_6">
      There are many consequences to choosing either of the aforementioned releases</a>. </p><p>
      
      The Linux kernel <a href="https://grsecurity.net/reports_of_cves_death_greatly_exaggerated">does not use CVEs to identify security
      vulnerabilities properly</a>. This means that fixes for most security vulnerabilities are not able to be backported to LTS kernels;
      but stable releases contain all security fixes made so far. </p><p>
      
      With those fixes however, a stable kernel includes a lot more new features, therefore vastly increasing the attack surface of the
      kernel and introducing a large amount of new bugs. On the contrary, LTS kernels have less attack surface because these features are
      not being constantly added. </p><p>
      
      Additionally, stable kernels include newer hardening features to mitigate certain exploits which LTS kernels do not. A few examples
      of such features are the <a href="https://mjg59.dreamwidth.org/55105.html">Lockdown LSM</a> and <a href="https://a13xp0p0v.github.io/2018/11/04/stackleak.html">STACKLEAK GCC plugin</a>. </p><p>
      
      To conclude, there is a trade-off when choosing a stable or LTS kernel. LTS kernels have less hardening features and not all public bug fixes
      at that point have been backported, but it generally has less attack surface and potentially a smaller chance of introducing unknown bugs.
      Stable kernels have more hardening features and all known bug fixes are included but it also has more attack surface and greater chances of
      introducing more unknown bugs. In the end though, a more recent LTS branch such as the 4.19 kernel would be preferred due to the much smaller
      attack surface.
    </p></div>

    <h3 id="sysctl"><a href="#sysctl">2.2 Sysctl</a></h3>

    <p>
      Sysctl is a tool that allows the user to configure certain kernel settings and enable various security features or disable dangerous
      features to reduce attack surface. To change settings temporarily you can execute:
    </p>

    <pre><code>sysctl -w $tunable = $value</code></pre>

    <div><p>
      To change sysctls permanently you can add the one you want to change to <code>/etc/sysctl.conf</code> or the corresponding files within
      <code>/etc/sysctl.d</code>, depending on your Linux distribution. </p><p>
      
      The following are the recommended sysctl settings that you should change.
    </p></div>

    <h4 id="sysctl-kernel"><a href="#sysctl-kernel">2.2.1 Kernel self-protection</a></h4>

    <pre><code>kernel.kptr_restrict=2</code></pre>

    <p>
      A kernel pointer points to a specific location in kernel memory. <a href="https://kernsec.org/wiki/index.php/Bug_Classes/Kernel_pointer_leak">
      These can be very useful in exploiting the kernel</a> but kernel pointers are not hidden by default — it is easy to uncover them by, for example,
      reading the contents of <code>/proc/kallsyms</code>. This setting aims to mitigate kernel pointer leaks. Alternatively, you can set
      <code>kernel.kptr_restrict=1</code> to only hide kernel pointers from processes without the <code>CAP_SYSLOG</code> <a href="#capabilities">capability</a>.
    </p>

    <pre><code>kernel.dmesg_restrict=1</code></pre>

    <p>
      <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dmesg">dmesg</a> is the kernel log. It exposes a large amount of useful kernel debugging information but this
      can often leak sensitive information such as kernel pointers. Changing the above sysctl restricts the kernel log to the <code>CAP_SYSLOG</code>
      <a href="#capabilities">capability</a>.
    </p>

    <pre><code>kernel.printk=3 3 3 3</code></pre>

    <p>
      Despite the value of <code>dmesg_restrict</code>, the kernel log will still be displayed in the console during boot. Malware that is
      able to record the screen during boot may be able to abuse this to gain higher privileges. This option prevents those information
      leaks. This must be used in combination with certain boot parameters <a href="#boot-kernel">described below</a> to be fully effective.
    </p>

    <pre><code>kernel.unprivileged_bpf_disabled=1
net.core.bpf_jit_harden=2</code></pre>

    <p>
      <a href="https://madaidans-insecurities.github.io/linux.html#kernel">eBPF exposes quite large attack surface</a>. As such, it must be restricted. These sysctls restrict eBPF
      to the <code>CAP_BPF</code> <a href="#capabilities">capability</a> (<code>CAP_SYS_ADMIN</code> on kernel versions prior to 5.8) and enable
      JIT hardening techniques such as <a href="https://github.com/torvalds/linux/blob/9e4b0d55d84a66dbfede56890501dc96e696059c/include/linux/filter.h#L1039-L1070">constant blinding</a>.
    </p>

    <pre><code>dev.tty.ldisc_autoload=0</code></pre>

    <p>
      This <a href="https://lkml.org/lkml/2019/4/15/890">restricts loading TTY line disciplines</a> to the <code>CAP_SYS_MODULE</code>
      <a href="#capabilities">capability</a> to prevent unprivileged attackers from loading vulnerable line disciplines with the <code>TIOCSETD</code>
      ioctl which <a href="https://a13xp0p0v.github.io/2017/03/24/CVE-2017-2636.html">has been abused in a number of exploits before</a>.
    </p>

    <pre><code>vm.unprivileged_userfaultfd=0</code></pre>

    <p>
      The <code><a href="https://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man2/userfaultfd.2.html">userfaultfd()</a></code> syscall is <a href="https://git.kernel.org/pub/scm/linux/kernel/git/torvalds/linux.git/commit/?id=cefdca0a86be517bc390fc4541e3674b8e7803b0">often</a> <a href="https://duasynt.com/blog/linux-kernel-heap-spray">abused</a> to exploit use-after-free flaws. Due to this, this sysctl is used to restrict
      this syscall to the <code>CAP_SYS_PTRACE</code> <a href="#capabilities">capability</a>.
    </p>

    <pre><code>kernel.kexec_load_disabled=1</code></pre>

    <p>
      <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kexec">kexec is a system call that is used to boot another kernel during runtime</a>. This functionality can
      be abused to load a malicious kernel and gain arbitrary code execution in kernel mode so this sysctl disables it.
    </p>

    <pre><code>kernel.sysrq=4</code></pre>

    <p>
      The <a href="https://www.kernel.org/doc/html/latest/admin-guide/sysrq.html">SysRq key</a> exposes a lot of potentially dangerous debugging functionality
      to unprivileged users. Contrary to common assumptions, SysRq is not only an issue for physical attacks as <a href="https://github.com/xairy/unlockdown">
      it can also be triggered remotely</a>. The value of this sysctl makes it so that a user can only use the <a href="https://www.kernel.org/doc/Documentation/SAK.txt">
      secure attention key</a> which will be necessary for <a href="#accessing-root-securely">accessing root securely</a>. Alternatively, you can simply set the
      value to <code>0</code> to disable SysRq completely.
    </p>

    <pre><code>kernel.unprivileged_userns_clone=0</code></pre>

    <div><p>
      User namespaces are a feature in the kernel which aim to improve sandboxing and make it easily accessible for unprivileged users however, <a href="https://madaidans-insecurities.github.io/linux.html#kernel">this feature exposes significant kernel attack surface for privilege escalation</a> so this sysctl restricts the
      usage of user namespaces to the <code>CAP_SYS_ADMIN</code> <a href="#capabilities">capability</a>. For unprivileged sandboxing,
      it is instead recommended to use a setuid binary with little attack surface to minimize the potential for privilege escalation. This topic is
      covered further in the <a href="#application-sandboxing">sandboxing section</a>. </p><p>
      
      Be aware though that this sysctl only exists on certain Linux distributions as it requires a kernel patch. If your kernel does not include
      this patch, you can alternatively disable user namespaces completely (including for root) by setting <code>user.max_user_namespaces=0</code>.
    </p></div>

    <pre><code>kernel.perf_event_paranoid=3</code></pre>

    

    <h4 id="sysctl-network"><a href="#sysctl-network">2.2.2 Network</a></h4>

    <pre><code>net.ipv4.tcp_syncookies=1</code></pre>

    <p>
      This helps protect against <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SYN_flood">SYN flood attacks</a> which are a form of denial of service attack
      in which an attacker sends a large amount of bogus SYN requests in an attempt to consume enough resources to make the system unresponsive to
      legitimate traffic.
    </p>

    <pre><code>net.ipv4.tcp_rfc1337=1</code></pre>

    <p>
      This protects against <a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc1337">time-wait assassination</a>…</p></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://madaidans-insecurities.github.io/guides/linux-hardening.html">https://madaidans-insecurities.github.io/guides/linux-hardening.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://madaidans-insecurities.github.io/guides/linux-hardening.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25590079</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 06:14:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Interview Transcript – Donald Knuth [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 162 | Comments 36 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25589619">thread link</a>) | @asicsp
<br/>
December 30, 2020 | https://philipkiely.com/assets/files/WfSD_Bonus_Interview_-_Donald_Knuth.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://philipkiely.com/assets/files/WfSD_Bonus_Interview_-_Donald_Knuth.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://philipkiely.com/assets/files/WfSD_Bonus_Interview_-_Donald_Knuth.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25589619</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 04:30:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Shortformer: Better Language Modeling using Shorter Inputs [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 63 | Comments 6 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25588675">thread link</a>) | @blast
<br/>
December 30, 2020 | https://ofir.io/shortformer.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ofir.io/shortformer.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ofir.io/shortformer.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25588675</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 01:51:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Leading someone with more years of experience than my age]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 97 | Comments 95 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25586883">thread link</a>) | @drojasug
<br/>
December 30, 2020 | https://danielrrojas.com/2020/12/27/leading-someone-with-more-years-of-experience-than-my-age/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://danielrrojas.com/2020/12/27/leading-someone-with-more-years-of-experience-than-my-age/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			
<p>It all started at my first job. I’ve been around 6 months in the company and was happy getting used to the ropes of my current job. In those 6 months, I quickly pushed to prod (without even knowing it) and was learning very fast. I still remember when my boss called me to his office: We are going to do some changes and you’ll lead this new 3 person team. I thought to myself: Cool, I’ve learned some books about leadership, this could be fun.</p>



<p>The tricky part was the members of the team. They were a couple of technicians who had more than ten years on the job and more than twenty years in the company ( I was twenty years old). One of them was even a team lead recently. I did not understand the mechanics of that re-org at the time and still don’t have all the information about what was happening. I wish I had some cool story about why I was chosen to lead the team, really don’t know.</p>



<p>It was not a walk in the park, things started to get ugly before they could get better. As expected they pushed back a lot, they did not like the change, me, or anything that was happening. It’s funny, looking back I think my ego should have been hurt based on all the times they tried to avoid working with me and change things. I guess I was so confused with everything that I had no time for that.</p>



<p>When we started to work together, one thing was clear: they were not in the mood to take orders from a kid. I was not in the mood to give orders to them. This particular situation helped me a lot and shaped the way I work ten years later.</p>



<p>Given that it was almost impossible to give orders and avoid starting a world war. I started listening, that’s what I did the most in the first weeks. I listened and asked questions. Not like interrogations, more like curious questions. I think the key to the questions what that I wanted to learn from them. I was not a trick, I was very interested in what they were doing.</p>



<p>I still remember some kind of pranks they pulled on me. They would tell me they had run out of a particular material they needed. I had made a lot of calls and research to try to find it for them, then they magically found some in the warehouse or the car they used. I did not know these were pranks, I learned later when they had another team lead (I laughed that time).</p>



<p>With some retrospective, I think these pranks were not just to pick on the new guy. I think they were testing me. They wanted to see what I did, would I forget about the problem, slack off, blame it on them, or take ownership and be part of the team. Most of the time I came with solutions and discussed alternatives with the team. Some weeks later I think they started to trust me.</p>



<p>There was a point where I started to notice that I could help with some things. Not so much in executing, but there were some things they needed help with. Mostly operational excellence. They were relieved to have someone handle that. Every week we were becoming a better team.</p>



<p>Patience was a foundation for this team. At least from my side. I did not rush things out (I was not even sure how to do that) and never try to impose my ideas or way of working. I trusted a lot the team and things started to look better.</p>



<p>Not everything was perfect. We had disagreements and sometimes we preferred different approaches. This is normal in all teams, the good part is that we started to have a process. We had a daily meeting, talked about what we needed to do that day and we talked briefly at the end of the day. Every side learned to cede sometimes and when months have passed we were playing by ear.</p>



<p>Even though we were a productive team and technically very respected, what I always treasure from these experiences is human relationships. I still have a great time whenever I talk to these two people and we have a blast remembering the good old days. Based on what they say, they learn a thing or two from me, but I learned a ton from them and that experience.</p>
					</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://danielrrojas.com/2020/12/27/leading-someone-with-more-years-of-experience-than-my-age/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25586883</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 22:20:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Clams filter the water and check whether the water is polluted or clean]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 311 | Comments 71 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25586861">thread link</a>) | @ta988
<br/>
December 30, 2020 | https://www.polishnews.co.uk/poznan-the-clams-filter-the-water-they-check-whether-the-water-is-polluted-or-clean/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.polishnews.co.uk/poznan-the-clams-filter-the-water-they-check-whether-the-water-is-polluted-or-clean/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>They are more accurate than complicated devices in the laboratory, they know “something is wrong” faster and cannot be fooled.  In Poznań, mussels have been keeping water purity for 26 years.  The TVN24 reporter checked what exactly their “work” is all about and whether the inconspicuous barks have raised the alarm. </p>
<p><span>In Poznań, 26 years ago, mussels were “employed” to check the safety of water, and more specifically large ones.  The capital of Greater Poland was the first Polish city to decide on such a solution. </span></p>
<p><span>– Working as a microbiologist, I always thought to introduce a system that would work independently and would be based on living organisms.  The idea was for such a system to give us information about the quality of the water.  When looking at chemical tests, you can check a lot of things, but for each type of test you need a separate device – says Grzegorz Podolski, senior technologist for water quality at Aquanet. </span></p>
<div>
<figure>

<p><span>Mussels have been “evaluating” the condition of water for 26 years</span><span>TVN24</span></p>
</figure>
</div>
<div>
<p><span>- Advertisement -</span>
<ins data-ad-layout="in-article" data-ad-format="fluid" data-ad-client="ca-pub-9526668220208198" data-ad-slot="5339701839"></ins>
</p><p><span>It is different with biomonitoring.  – Here one organism, in this case a clam, checks many parameters and if there is any chemical contamination, it lets you know.  And that’s enough to take a sample, take it to the laboratory and see what it is about: confirm or deny that something is happening to the water.  It is a system that ensures safety against pollution and even terrorist activities.  The work of the mussels is closely related to what the laboratory does, adds Podolski. </span></p>
</div>
<h2>Work for two months </h2>

<p><span>Clams nourish themselves by filtering the water.  They are extremely sensitive to all kinds of pollution and much more than humans.  That is why they belong to the indicators, i.e. species of plants and animals that have a low degree of tolerance to changes in conditions in the environment in which they live. </span></p>
<p><span>How many mussels were given a “job” and how long they can work was checked and described in the instruction by scientists from the Adam Mickiewicz University in Poznań.  – We have three measuring devices in the company and eight clams in each.  In total, we “employ” 200 individuals during the year – says Podolski. </span></p>
<p><span>Within an hour, one individual can filter 1.5 liters of water.  – It is a good cooperation.  We have full democracy and gender equality here, because we have both male and female individuals – says Dorota Wiśniewska, spokesman for Aquanet SA in Poznań. </span></p>
<p><span>Each clam is first prepared and fed.  Then it goes to a special flow-through aquarium.  And there, for two months, they are on “duty”.  – This is the time when he can work and live safely.  Then the “workers” return to their natural environment, that is, to water reservoirs – explains Wiśniewska. </span></p>

<h2>They filter and alarm </h2>

<p><span>Biomonitoring based on mussels consists in constant, round-the-clock observation and registration of their shell movements.  How it’s working? </span></p>
<p><span>– Mussels open the shells and every now and then take in a small amount of water, filtering out everything that is suitable for eating.  When the water is polluted, they do their best to separate from it, and everyone’s shells just close at the same time.  This happens within two minutes.  If two or three clams close, it doesn’t have to mean anything, but if there are eight, it’s an alarm.  Then our role is to find out what has upset them so much and find out if it is a real or a false alarm – says Podolski. </span></p>
<div>
<figure>
<p><span>How wide do the shells of clams open?</span><span>Paula Przetakowska / TVN24</span></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p><span>– Have they all shut down?  – the TVN24 reporter asks. </span></p>
<p><span>– There has not been such a situation for these 26 years.  The water that goes to the mussels is of very good quality – adds Podolski. </span></p>
<p><span>Scientists have translated these clam responses into ‘computer language’.  – The mussels are glued to the plastic pedestal.  In addition, a magnet disc is glued to the shell, and a probe is mounted nearby that detects changes in the magnetic field.  When the clam closes or opens, it touches the probe with this magnet.  And we translate it into an image of the degree of opening and closing – explains the Aquanet employee.  </span></p>
<div>
<figure>

<p><span>Mussels have been “keeping” the purity of water since 1994 </span><span>TVN24</span></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p><span>– During these 26 years, when we talk about the work of mussels during “open doors” or educational lessons, they always arouse positive emotions and great interest.  Visitors are always surprised that such small creatures play such an important role – adds Wiśniewska. </span></p>
<p><span>Water biomonitoring in Poland is carried out in several water supply companies, including in Łódź, Warsaw and Silesia. </span></p>
<p><span>Main photo source: </span>TVN24</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.polishnews.co.uk/poznan-the-clams-filter-the-water-they-check-whether-the-water-is-polluted-or-clean/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25586861</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 22:18:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Developer progression as a function of navigating complexity]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 53 | Comments 37 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25586471">thread link</a>) | @sid6376
<br/>
December 30, 2020 | https://www.siddharthsarda.com/p/developer-progression-as-a-function | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.siddharthsarda.com/p/developer-progression-as-a-function">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I came across this <a href="https://files.eric.ed.gov/fulltext/EJ1204031.pdf">paper</a> which looks at ways to teach students complex systems courtesy of Jessica Kerr’s <a href="https://jessitron.com/2020/10/11/clockwork-to-complexity-scale-in-time-and-software/">blog</a>.</p><p>Based on how students reason about complex systems, they were placed in 4 categories in order of increasing sophistication: <strong>Completely Clockwork</strong><em>, </em><strong>Somewhat Clockwork, Somewhat Complex and Completely Complex.</strong></p><blockquote><p><em>“Clockwork responses are those that show deterministic, linear, single-cause, non-networked, centralized, or static system interactions or states, whereas complex responses are those that demonstrate nondeterministic, nonlinear, multiple causes, networked, decentralized, or dynamic system interactions or states”.</em></p></blockquote><div><figure><a target="_blank" href="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F325111ba-e7ab-4fb2-8bb1-743e63fe634d_1600x632.png"><img src="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F325111ba-e7ab-4fb2-8bb1-743e63fe634d_1600x632.png" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/325111ba-e7ab-4fb2-8bb1-743e63fe634d_1600x632.png&quot;,&quot;height&quot;:575,&quot;width&quot;:1456,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:null,&quot;bytes&quot;:null,&quot;alt&quot;:null,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:null,&quot;href&quot;:null}" alt=""></a></figure></div><p>In my experience this translates extremely well to the progression of a developer and their understanding of the complexity of the ecosystem they operate in. So, I wanted to attempt to derive a learning progression for developers.</p><p>At each level of development, I recommend a few books. Each book hopefully is a thread you can pull on, if you want to go deeper into a particular topic.The book recommendations are subjective, but I believe that one can chart their own curriculum following the basic model. The recommendations that I make are just based on my own experience and aim to serve merely as guidance.</p><p>When it comes to progression to the next level, my general advice would be to master the level you are operating on and then aim to understand whats needed to operate at the next level.</p><p><strong>Completely Clockwork</strong></p><p>At this level most of the work is involved in making changes in a single service or component. This is where most of the <em>‘coding’</em> happens. The amount of time that will be spent reading your code will be multiples of the amount you would take to write it. You will work more with existing code rather than writing new code. A corollary of this fact is that you need to know how to make your code easy to change.So your focus should be on writing readable code and making it easy to change. </p><p>Your scope of work will probably within your team and its very likely that your circle of influence, impact and visibility would mostly be your team as well. The abstraction at which you operate in is your team. </p><p>The advice I would give at this level is to optimise for seeing problems solved through different <a href="https://charity.wtf/2020/11/01/questionable-advice-the-trap-of-the-premature-senior/">reference points</a>. </p><p>My recommendations for this level would be:</p><ul><li><p><a href="https://amzn.to/3rDymed">Refactoring</a></p></li><li><p><a href="https://amzn.to/2L4q3HJ">Clean Architecture</a></p></li></ul><p><strong>Somewhat Clockwork</strong></p><p>As you begin to build familiarity and also gain experience, you might see that increasingly you begin to look outward from the immediate scope of your team. You begin to try to understand how the surroundings affect the goals of your teams.  You start going on <a href="https://noidea.dog/blog/surviving-the-organisational-side-quest">organisational side quests</a> to achieve your team’s goals. The abstraction at which you operate is still typically your team but the way you look at things becomes more outward looking.</p><p>In modern software development, distributed systems are ubiquitous. Even when you are making a change to a single service, that service most likely lives in an ecosystem of other services and a plethora of other distributed tools. As you grow in seniority you need to understand how best to interact with other services  and also the tradeoffs involved with each tool.&nbsp;</p><p>Books for this level</p><ul><li><p><a href="https://amzn.to/3rFMkfH">Designing Data Intensive Applications&nbsp;</a></p></li><li><p><a href="https://amzn.to/3o1QDjf">Building Microservices</a></p></li></ul><p><strong>Somewhat Complex</strong></p><p>As you gain more experience, you would have ideally developed some <a href="https://blog.koehntopp.info/2020/08/31/on-touching-candles.html">calluses</a>, had a ring side view of  some <a href="https://twitter.com/StanTwinB/status/1336890442768547845">heart stopping close shaves</a>. This will prepare you to operate at next abstraction: teams of teams.  You would be advising on how to organise software and teams best to make teams successful in aggregate. You could be either leading <a href="https://lethain.com/migrations/">migrations to address technical debt</a> or <a href="https://lethain.com/reclaim-unreasonable-software/">reclaiming unreasonable software</a>. It will also probably be your call as to when to do what.</p><p>A practitioner operating mostly at this level needs to be able to use models to explain the  overall system or domain they are operating in and its interactions with its neighbouring domains. These models are not just to explain the software system but also the teams that surround that software. You need to understand the best models for organising teams to drive maximum impact. Additionally, as the operator of <a href="https://how.complexsystems.fail/">complex systems</a> they wear two hats : that of the producer and that of the protector against failure. The practitioner needs to be able to handle this duality well.&nbsp;</p><p>Books for this level</p><ul><li><p><a href="https://amzn.to/381eAl7">Domain Driven Design</a></p></li><li><p><a href="https://amzn.to/3o2KenM">Team Topologies</a></p></li><li><p><a href="https://amzn.to/3mYTWpZ">SRE Book&nbsp;</a></p></li><li><p><a href="https://amzn.to/381eWrX">Accelerate&nbsp;</a></p></li></ul><p><strong>Completely Complex</strong></p><p>The abstraction that you operate in now is the entire organisation or in bigger companies, an entire division or department. Your focus is primarily on what to build rather than the how.  You will be doing a lot of writing, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:6530173230102122496/">since you need to communicate at scale</a>.</p><p>According to the paper, a completely complex system is a dynamic process, which is constantly in a state of flux. Any patterns here are emergent. Changes have both short term and long term repercussions. You also realise that the system is self organised for the most part. This sounds a lot like the modern organisation. At this scope you are typically operating as the technical leadership. You need to be able to form technical strategies grounded in the needs of the business.&nbsp;</p><p>Books for this level</p><ul><li><p><a href="https://medium.com/wardleymaps/on-being-lost-2ef5f05eb1ec">Wardley Maps</a></p></li><li><p><a href="https://amzn.to/38Msirg">Enterprise Architecture as Strategy</a></p></li></ul><p>So to summarise, this is what we end up with as a progression plan for developers over varying degrees of complexity.&nbsp;</p><div><figure><a target="_blank" href="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F3051da8e-aaca-477b-93d1-96e243d91b22_3846x1168.png"><img src="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F3051da8e-aaca-477b-93d1-96e243d91b22_3846x1168.png" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/3051da8e-aaca-477b-93d1-96e243d91b22_3846x1168.png&quot;,&quot;height&quot;:442,&quot;width&quot;:1456,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:null,&quot;bytes&quot;:172810,&quot;alt&quot;:null,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;image/png&quot;,&quot;href&quot;:null}" alt=""></a></figure></div><p>There is a pithy saying - “<em><strong>All models are wrong, some are useful</strong></em>.” The model I have described here is not perfect. The skills and responsibilities needed at different levels are at a continuum, not discrete. I merely aim to expose you to the different abstractions that engineers operate in based on where they are in their career. I hope you found this useful.</p><p>If you are here, follow me on <a href="https://twitter.com/sidsarda">twitter</a>.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.siddharthsarda.com/p/developer-progression-as-a-function</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25586471</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 21:39:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Ditching Excel for Python in a legacy industry]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 297 | Comments 260 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25586063">thread link</a>) | @afkmango
<br/>
December 30, 2020 | https://amypeniston.com/ditching-excel-for-python/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://amypeniston.com/ditching-excel-for-python/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="wrapper">
  <div id="content">
    <div>
      

<p>I’ve been in a reflective mood lately, probably because it’s the end of a very eventful year. Change is all around us and technology is the enabler.</p>



<p>On that note, I’ve been thinking a lot about my own experiences with technology-driven change in the reinsurance industry, where I worked as an analyst from 2017 until recently.</p>



<p>During these three short years, I observed a radical shift in data analysis methodologies. Excel-based models, which had seemed top-of-the-line suddenly were too slow and too rigid; Integration with 3rd party data sources, which was once a luxury, became the norm; And analysts began to utilize scripts to accomplish many labor-intensive tasks typically performed by hand or in spreadsheets.</p>



<p>Enabling this change is a suite of accessible Python-powered tools. These technologies are rapidly displacing the old way of doing things, ushering in a new wave of reinsurance models and the talent needed to support them.</p>



<p>Admittedly, the following observations do come from a very niche industry. But I believe that the broader trends discussed here will also apply to other legacy companies and sectors.</p>



<p>In this post, I explore the following topics:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Section 1</strong> – An introduction to reinsurance</li><li><strong>Section 2 – </strong>The need for technological disruption in the reinsurance industry</li><li><strong>Sections 3 to 5</strong> – How Python is replacing Excel</li><li><strong>Section 6 </strong>– Arguments against adopting new technologies</li><li><strong>Section 7</strong> – The evolution of the reinsurance industry</li></ul>



<p>If you are curious about the transition from Excel to Python but aren’t interested in reinsurance, skip to section 3.</p>



<p>Without further ado, let’s get into it.</p>



<figure><img width="1024" height="406" src="https://amypeniston.com/downloads/ditching-excel-for-python-1024x406.jpg" data-src="https://amypeniston.com/downloads/ditching-excel-for-python-1024x406.jpg" alt="" data-srcset="https://amypeniston.com/downloads/ditching-excel-for-python-1024x406.jpg 1024w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/ditching-excel-for-python-300x119.jpg 300w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/ditching-excel-for-python-768x304.jpg 768w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/ditching-excel-for-python.jpg 1500w" data-sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://amypeniston.com/downloads/ditching-excel-for-python-1024x406.jpg 1024w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/ditching-excel-for-python-300x119.jpg 300w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/ditching-excel-for-python-768x304.jpg 768w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/ditching-excel-for-python.jpg 1500w"></figure>



<h2>1. Reinsurance, from an analyst’s perspective</h2>



<p>Most people understand insurance, but few have heard of its rather exotic sounding cousin: reinsurance. So, before I begin, here’s a quick intro:</p>



<p>Just as individuals transfer risk to insurers in exchange for a premium, insurers too must mitigate their risk by transferring some or all of their liabilities to one or more reinsurance companies. This enables insurers to protect themselves in the case of a large event, such as a hurricane, which affects many individual policyholders. Without reinsurers, insurance companies would not be able to survive catastrophes and would be much more risk averse, ultimately impacting the end consumer.</p>



<p>Reinsurance programs come in a variety of flavors to suit the need of the reinsured. I’ll spare you the details but suffice it to say that all potential reinsurance programs must first be analyzed. In industry speak, this is the process of “pricing a deal”.</p>



<p>For each deal, brokers gather relevant data from the insurance companies and send it to potential reinsurers as a “submission”. It is the underwriting analyst’s responsibility to parse this data, enter it into Excel-based models and produce a number.</p>



<p>This number, the loss ratio, represents the expected loss divided by the total premium and typically ranges between 10% to 150+%. LRs above 100% mean that the premium is not sufficient to cover the losses that we expect based on our model. In other words, we’d be writing the deal at a loss.</p>



<p>In reality, reinsurance companies have pricing hurdles well below 100% because they have other money outflows to account for such as brokerage (intermediary fees) and G&amp;A (general and administrative expenses).</p>



<p>The point is, Excel is the key piece of software that enables underwriting teams to assess new business. Throughout the company, different teams use different models, each with different processes and different pricing hurdles. But the one common theme is that all of the models are based on Excel spreadsheets. That’s just how the industry works. Everyone uses Excel for everything.</p>



<p>Well, until recently.</p>



<figure><img width="1024" height="190" src="https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-4-1024x190.jpg" data-src="https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-4-1024x190.jpg" alt="" data-srcset="https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-4-1024x190.jpg 1024w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-4-300x56.jpg 300w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-4-768x142.jpg 768w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-4.jpg 1500w" data-sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-4-1024x190.jpg 1024w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-4-300x56.jpg 300w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-4-768x142.jpg 768w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-4.jpg 1500w"></figure>



<h2>2. Change is coming</h2>



<p>In an industry that is notoriously behind the times, a fundamental change is underway. This change is in response to new business demands, including:</p>



<ol><li>The desire to price increasingly complex deals with increasingly large datasets</li><li>The desire to integrate with 3rd party data to augment pricing models</li><li>The desire for faster models and robust codebases that adhere to software development best practices</li></ol>



<p>Excel fails miserably at these tasks.</p>



<p>First, expressing complex reinsurance deals requires tabs and tabs of structural details, interlinking formulas and limiting assumptions. It’s a mess to build and a headache to understand. Have a lot of data? That’s more tabs and formulas to add to the model. Performance slows dramatically and minutes of your life are wasted waiting for bloated spreadsheets to finally open.</p>



<p>Second, you’re forced to use the VBA programming language if you want to query external data or implement user-defined functionality. According to one Stack Overflow survey, VBA ranked “most dreaded” of all the languages, which wholly sums up my feelings. The development environment is not user friendly, the syntax confusing, there’s no support for unit testing –&nbsp;I could go on.</p>



<p>Third, Excel is fragile. Views and logic are intermingled, making it very hard to troubleshoot errors. Also, models aren’t put into source control, so you can’t restore an old version. Massive spreadsheets with dozens of tabs frequently crash without warning, much to the dismay of underwriting analysts (like myself).</p>



<p>During my three years in reinsurance, I witnessed a dire need for new tooling. And, from what I observed, it is clear that this tooling will be powered by Python.</p>







<figure><img width="1024" height="190" src="https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-2-1024x190.jpg" data-src="https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-2-1024x190.jpg" alt="" data-srcset="https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-2-1024x190.jpg 1024w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-2-300x56.jpg 300w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-2-768x142.jpg 768w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-2.jpg 1500w" data-sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-2-1024x190.jpg 1024w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-2-300x56.jpg 300w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-2-768x142.jpg 768w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-2.jpg 1500w"></figure>



<h2>3. The future is Python</h2>



<p>As a technical underwriting analyst with programming skills, I was among the first to build and benefit from what I think are the next generation of pricing tools. These tools fall into two main categories:</p>



<ul><li>Excel models running Python code</li><li>Python notebooks in the browser</li></ul>



<p>Both options offer enhanced analysis capabilities while still catering to a non-technical or semi-technical end user.</p>



<p>Now, let’s explore each technology in more detail.</p>



<h2>4. Excel models running Python code</h2>



<p>The first category of new technology is based on augmentation. Rather than adding VBA code to your Excel spreadsheet, you can use Python instead. This is possible thanks to 3rd party Excel add-ins such <a href="https://www.pyxll.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PyXLL</a>, which brings the power of Python data analysis into the humble spreadsheet.</p>



<p>When you open Excel, the add-in makes your Python code accessible either as functions or as macros. This means that you can write Python code in the development environment of your choice, add unit tests, integrate with 3rd party libraries and push to source control.</p>



<p>PyXLL facilitated a step change in how we construct reinsurance models. Specifically, here’s how our setup looked before and after augmenting our model with Python:</p>



<figure><table><tbody><tr><td><strong>Before Python</strong></td><td><strong>After Python</strong></td></tr><tr><td>We used an Excel spreadsheet-based model with dozens of tabs containing complex formulas, endless pivot tables and unintelligible VBA code.</td><td>The tangled mess of VBA was re-written into independent Python modules, each of which performs a distinct function.</td></tr><tr><td>The spreadsheet took 30+ seconds to open.</td><td>The Excel spreadsheet is now just a view, so it is lightweight and quick to open.</td></tr><tr><td>There was no visibility into errors. “Debugging” meant manually breaking apart lengthy Excel formulas.</td><td>The new model logic is testable and can be upgraded independently.</td></tr><tr><td>We were limited by the assumptions made when the model was first created, with little ability to add new features.</td><td>The codebase lives in source control, enabling multiple collaborators to work in tandem.</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Developers can use their preferred development environment.</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>A robust peer review process helps to perpetuate high quality code.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>Using PyXLL, we built an underwriting pricing model powered entirely by Python code. We were able to express structural complexities of deals at a level never before achieved. And we were able to add simulation-based pricing techniques that simply cannot be done using spreadsheets alone.</p>



<p>The impact of PyXLL on how we build models and ultimately price business cannot be understated.</p>



<p>Which leads us to the second technology that is changing the way we perform underwriting data analysis…</p>



<figure><img width="1024" height="190" src="https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-3-1024x190.jpg" data-src="https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-3-1024x190.jpg" alt="" data-srcset="https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-3-1024x190.jpg 1024w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-3-300x56.jpg 300w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-3-768x142.jpg 768w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-3.jpg 1500w" data-sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-3-1024x190.jpg 1024w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-3-300x56.jpg 300w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-3-768x142.jpg 768w, https://amypeniston.com/downloads/Image-3.jpg 1500w"></figure>



<h2>5. Python notebooks in the browser</h2>



<p>The second novel approach to reinsurance risk assessment and pricing is enabled via Python notebooks. These are web-based documents that can contain narrative text, live code, charts and visuals, plus results from your data analysis. </p>



<p>Python notebooks are all about collaboration, visualization and rapid iteration. They are a way to execute code with minimal setup and overhead, making it easier for new programmers to explore data outside of Excel. One of my favorite parts of notebooks is how easy it is to access your data, whether that’s from a file, SQL databases or an external source.</p>



<p>Let’s look at what a data analysis project looked like for me with and without Python notebooks:</p>



<figure><table><tbody><tr><td><strong>Without Python Notebooks</strong></td><td><strong>With Python Notebooks</strong></td></tr><tr><td>Manually query SQL databases and copy data into Excel. Keep data fresh by re-querying SQL and copying in new data.</td><td>Drop in a csv file, connect directly to an internal SQL database or utilize a 3rd party API to retrieve external data.</td></tr><tr><td>Perform analysis using Excel functions, pivot tables and VBA code. Functions quickly became unwieldy and difficult to troubleshoot.</td><td>Manipulate data easily and rapidly using Python libraries like <a href="https://pandas.pydata.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pandas</a>.</td></tr><tr><td>Collaborate with a colleague by closing Excel and letting your colleague know that the spreadsheet is available for them to work on.</td><td>Collaborate with colleagues by sharing the notebook.</td></tr><tr><td>Copy tabular results and charts into Word or Powerpoint and add written narrative as necessary.</td><td>Export results to csv or generate professional-looking PDFs to give directly to key stakeholders.</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Add explanatory narrative directly to the document alongside related code blocks.</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Create interactive charts and static visuals using libraries like <a href="https://plotly.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Plotly</a>, <a href="https://seaborn.pydata.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">seaborn</a> or <a href="https://matplotlib.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">matplotlib</a>.</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Leverage existing libraries like <a href="https://www.scipy.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">SciPy</a> or <a href="https://scikit-learn.org/stable/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">scikit-learn</a> to …</td></tr></tbody></table></figure></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://amypeniston.com/ditching-excel-for-python/">https://amypeniston.com/ditching-excel-for-python/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://amypeniston.com/ditching-excel-for-python/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25586063</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 21:02:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Israeli startup claims Covid-19 likely originated in a lab, willing to bet on it]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 347 | Comments 347 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25585833">thread link</a>) | @delbarital
<br/>
December 30, 2020 | https://www.rootclaim.com/analysis/what-is-the-source-of-covid-19-sars-cov-2 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.rootclaim.com/analysis/what-is-the-source-of-covid-19-sars-cov-2">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.rootclaim.com/analysis/what-is-the-source-of-covid-19-sars-cov-2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25585833</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 20:41:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Writing my first Gameboy Emulator]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 55 | Comments 18 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25583964">thread link</a>) | @RupertWiser
<br/>
December 30, 2020 | http://benwiser.com/blog/Writing-my-first-Gameboy-Emulator.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://benwiser.com/blog/Writing-my-first-Gameboy-Emulator.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p id="h.f0zdx2p8r8sq"><span>Writing my first Gameboy Emulator</span></p><p><span>Okay so today’s post might be a bit of a cheat because I’m nowhere near complete on this project. But I’m really excited, because I just got the Tetris title screen working!</span></p><p><span><img alt="" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/O9JwbvM5phtNcpgBj_2Un5C3QWVLTn24SWN43trTYG7ryH4enLNU6vbMzqMYwridlrhT8HswNBQNVUk19vTe87fsSwvJf0W-IsUEx6j8u13I1zKrktnzabBUzOf3lZcNor0lvGxV" title=""></span></p><p><span>This is the first time I’ve worked on an emulator and </span><span>oh boy</span><span>&nbsp;do I regret taking this long to get around to it. This has been one of the most rewarding projects I’ve worked on. Not only do I feel like I’m truly gaining a more fundamental understanding of the internals of a machine (which is sort of the point), but it is SO exciting suddenly seeing someone else’s software pop up on the screen.</span></p><p><span>I’m still working on this journey myself but I thought I’d share what I’ve done so far to hopefully encourage others to give this a go.</span></p><p><span>It all started with the bootrom. The gameboy didn’t have an operating system. It simply had a simple bootrom that showed you that famous Nintendo logo (which is actually </span><span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I1cUIGHZLGA">a novel DRM scheme</a></span><span>). It’s a very simple program that you can read line by line making it pretty easy to work out where I was going wrong. I started by making a “</span><span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Central_processing_unit">CPU</a></span><span>” which was just a big ol switch statement going through </span><span><a href="https://meganesulli.com/generate-gb-opcodes/">each opcode</a></span><span>. This is definitely the most labour intensive part of the project. There are a lot of opcodes.</span></p><p><span>What you quickly discover while implementing opcodes is that the gameboy memory is basically just an array. So next I created registers and an “</span><span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Memory_management_unit">MMU</a></span><span>” (the gameboy didn’t really have an MMU but this made things easier to manage). After around four days, I had the Nintendo logo rendering!</span></p><p><span><img alt="" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/xRho4Dq1Fo1vUdM6BNTShSDwfBupG_CSlcrlkG2m9MhC_O75h1T1krLYA16RbOXUSH0BO-W_6u-2B6opnDkgzO3BYHmHJLxgrWbaPEJfbhumMPHAZp0acPT2iL_86tIv3zCLl6DB" title=""></span></p><p><span>Simple rendering is pretty straightforward. The Gameboy would write to a certain region of memory reserved for video so all you need to do is read from there to know what you should render. Once I got that far - I was completely hooked. My approach of just implementing more and more Gameboy hardware was working.</span></p><p><span>There are already a ton of resources that go into far more detail:</span></p><ul><li><span><a href="http://www.codeslinger.co.uk/pages/projects/gameboy.html">http://www.codeslinger.co.uk/pages/projects/gameboy.html</a></span></li><li><span><a href="http://imrannazar.com/GameBoy-Emulation-in-JavaScript:-The-CPU">http://imrannazar.com/GameBoy-Emulation-in-JavaScript:-The-CPU</a></span></li><li><span><a href="https://blog.ryanlevick.com/DMG-01/public/book/">https://blog.ryanlevick.com/DMG-01/public/book/</a></span></li></ul><p><span>If you have the time and you’re interested, I would strongly suggest you give this project a go. It is very fun. Happy coding!</span></p><p><span>You can find the code here:</span></p><p><span><a href="https://gitlab.com/BenWiser/gameboy-emulator">https://gitlab.com/BenWiser/gameboy-emulator</a></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://benwiser.com/blog/Writing-my-first-Gameboy-Emulator.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25583964</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 17:52:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Spirals, Snowflakes and Trees: Recursion in Pictures]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 105 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25583631">thread link</a>) | @nbaksalyar
<br/>
December 30, 2020 | http://learn.hfm.io/fractals.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://learn.hfm.io/fractals.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>©2019 Applicative, Utrecht, The Netherlands. All Rights Reserved.</p>
<p>Apple, the Apple logo, Mac and OS X are trademarks of Apple Inc., registered in the U.S. and other countries. App Store is a service mark of Apple Inc.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://learn.hfm.io/fractals.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25583631</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 17:27:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Vaccines Are the Safest Medical Procedure We Have. Make Your Wager Wisely]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 66 | Comments 144 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25583025">thread link</a>) | @CapitalistCartr
<br/>
December 30, 2020 | http://m.nautil.us/blog/vaccines-are-the-safest-medical-procedure-we-have-make-your-wager-wisely | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://m.nautil.us/blog/vaccines-are-the-safest-medical-procedure-we-have-make-your-wager-wisely">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			

			<figure data-alt=""><img src="http://static.nautil.us/18054_51331fcd89d45304a118755678da4a8b.jpg" width="733" alt=""><figcaption><span><i>All drugs and treatments have side effects, but vaccines in general have the fewest.</i></span><span>Illustration by eamesBot / Shutterstock</span></figcaption></figure><p><span>I</span>n the late 1650’s, the French polymath and renowned scientist Blaise Pascal, having undergone a religious experience that transformed him into something of a zealot, suggested the following logical strategy regarding belief in God: If there is a God, then believing in him will ensure you an eternity of bliss, while not believing in him could earn you an eternal sentence to misery.&nbsp;<br></p><p>On the other hand, if there is no God, believing in him anyway will cost you very little, and not believing in him will mean nothing in the non-existent after life. Therefore, the only sensible bet is to believe in God. This has come to be known as <a href="http://nautil.us/blog/why-pascals-wager-is-eminently-modern" target="_blank">Pascal’s wager</a>.</p><p>It has a surprising number of applications beyond concerns for a comfortable afterlife. There are many things for which the value of believing something or not can be seen as a cost-versus-likely-benefit wager,&nbsp;often without regard to the actual truth of the matter. Since science does not profess to have a final truth, and in many areas freely admits its incomplete knowledge, Pascal’s wager can provide a useful method of deciding between two alternatives.</p><blockquote><p>All drugs and treatments have side effects, but vaccines in general have the fewest.</p> </blockquote><p>For example, it seems that a significant percentage of the population is suspicious of science, or so we are told. We often hear that some large number, approaching or exceeding half of Americans, do not believe in evolution. This seems remarkable on the face of it because there is no viable scientific opposition to evolution and it is widely accepted by biologists and other life scientists as being fundamental to understanding biology—from genetics to medicine.<br></p><p>What we are not often told is that most of those who answer negatively about believing in evolution nonetheless understand evolution—or at least the basics of it. They are not stupid, ignorant, or uninformed. They have simply made a Pascalian wager. What benefit, we might ask, is derived from believing in evolution rather than a <a href="http://nautil.us/blog/how-to-weed-creationism-out-of-schools" target="_blank">divine creation</a>? Unless you are a professional biologist, it is hard to see how this would affect your everyday life. On the other hand, professing a belief in Darwinian evolution over the biblical narrative will likely ostracize you from family, friends, co-workers, your church community—in short most of your social infrastructure. Place your bets.</p><p>Can we apply any of this to decisions over the current controversy surrounding vaccination—and in particular the newly arrived COVID-19 vaccine?</p><p>There are certainly reasons to be concerned about being vaccinated, and it would be a gross over-simplification to consider anyone who expresses reticence about taking a vaccine, this new vaccine in particular, as being just plain dumb or scientifically illiterate or gullible. They need be none of these things and still may be suspicious of the vaccine.<br></p><p>One issue is safety. The vaccine, any vaccine, is designed to mobilize your immune system, essentially to fool it into believing that there is an invading virus present and to mount an immune response. That way it will be ready when the real invasion comes, if it comes. This seems pretty sensible and preferable to going to war with an opponent you know nothing about. But still, it is fooling around with Mother Nature and some people are uneasy about that. Although it must be pointed out that the virus is not at all shy about fooling around with your immune system and many other parts of you, so letting it have its way is not good policy, either.</p><p>What about a vaccine made of genes? This vaccine is being produced by what is being touted as a new method using RNA—genes. While it is true that for entirely economic reasons, this is the first vaccine to be produced in this way, the method is not really new and the science that makes it possible has been developing over the last 40 years. So it’s not so radical as the press makes it seem.&nbsp;</p><p>But it is true that this method uses RNA, genetic material, to make the vaccine. We hear a lot about gene modification and the potential dangers associated with it. Why then am I going to allow RNA, genes, to be injected into me? The first thing to realize is that this is exactly what the virus does—so whether you get a vaccine or an infection, you are getting genes injected into you. The virus RNA encodes around 12 functional genes (by comparison humans and other mammals have around 25,000 genes). The virus only contains the genes to make a new virus—it does not have any of the capabilities of a normal cell to actually turn those genes into the proteins that make up the complete virus. It hijacks your cells to do this—and that’s how it sickens you, by forcing your cells to make new viruses instead of what they should be doing.</p><blockquote><p>Vaccines have fewer side effects than virtually any other drug you wouldn’t even think twice about taking.</p> </blockquote><p>Now the new vaccines have taken just one of those genes—the one that directs the production of the now infamous spike protein that appears on the surface of a normal virus—and injects just that one gene into your muscle cells, which then make that one single protein. Your immune system comes along and sees that weird protein and makes antibodies to it. These same antibodies will now recognize the spike protein on the surface of any viral particles that invade your body. We have effectively turned the virus into its own enemy.</p><p>The viral RNA that you are getting will decompose over a few days because RNA is not a stable molecule (that, by the way, is why the vaccine needs to be kept frozen) and it will no longer exist in your body. It could only become a permanent part of your genome if it were a DNA molecule instead of an RNA molecule—and even the chances of that happening would be chemically remote. So regardless of how it sounds, this may actually be the safest sort of vaccine to use. In the future it is likely that all vaccines will be made this way.</p><p><span>T</span>hen, of course, there is the issue of who is running this whole vaccine program—the government and the pharmaceutical industry. These are the guys who brought you opioid addiction, death by Vioxx, soaring drug prices, the worst health-care system in the developed world, regulations where you don’t need them and none where you do—am I really going to trust this cast of so-called “inept villains,” as some believe, to dictate my personal health choices? Do we know for sure that the claims of efficacy are real or just made up to sell some worthless procedure? It would not be the first time. (I would not, on the other hand, worry about Bill Gates having a chip inserted into you along with the vaccine—if you use any social media, navigational tools, or purchase anything online, then Bill Gates already knows more about you than he will get from any injectable chip. So that train has left the station.)</p><p>All this and a few lesser issues are worth a pause, for sure. But we must also look on the positive side of the ledger. Why trust science? Modern medicine and the science behind it has eliminated or dramatically lessened such scourges as smallpox, polio, cholera, chicken pox, measles, rabies, and dozens of other killer pathogens that had previously wiped out enormous numbers of people, in some cases significant parts of entire generations. Don’t we depend on science for much of the comfort and safety of our everyday lives? Isn’t science the way we heat our homes, drive to work, fly around the world, have dependable food? Yes, there is the bomb—but there is also anesthesia.<br></p><div id="inpagesub">
	<p>Get the <span>Nautilus</span> newsletter</p>
<p>
	The newest and most popular articles delivered right to your inbox!
</p>
			<!-- Begin MailChimp Signup Form -->
			




</div><p>When it comes to viruses, the only tool we have to fight them is vaccination. The only tool. Antibiotics are for bacteria, a completely different sort of creature. Sanitation beyond personal hand-washing is ineffective. Vaccines trick the immune system into recognizing the virus earlier than it would otherwise and protect normal cells from invasion by the virus. Tricking the immune system is understandably problematic for people who believe that their body knows best if it’s just kept healthy. This virus, as we have seen from the array of infected people that includes apparently healthy folks, unfortunately does not subscribe to that belief.</p><p>By a similar sort of reasoning, some people make the plausible error of calculating that the vaccine is 95 percent effective but the survival rate is 99 percent, so why not just let my natural resistance take care of this? Indeed, that might not be unreasonable thinking if we were talking about the common cold, but this virus has shown itself to be a tricky character, and we are not yet able to predict who gets a serious case and who a mild one. With those sorts of stakes, you shouldn’t wager on either of those numbers because they have nothing to do with&nbsp;<i>you</i>&nbsp;as an individual. Like flipping a coin, there is only a 1 percent chance of it coming up heads 6 times in a row. But if it has come up heads 5 times in a row, the probability of it coming up heads on the next flip is…still 50/50.&nbsp;</p><p>An even larger unknown is whether there may be long-term effects associated with SARS-Cov-2, as is the case for many viruses. The 1918 influenza virus has been linked to a subsequent two-three fold increase in Parkinson’s disease by a mechanism we still don’t understand. The virus that gives children chicken pox will hide out in a person’s body for 40 years or more, and then emerge as a painful, sometimes debilitating, case of shingles. The 99 percent survivability rate of this virus is meaningless if, 20 years from now, it causes some devastating pulmonary or brain disease.</p><p>The main upside to vaccines is that because they use your already existing defense system, they are surprisingly safe. Safer than antibiotics, which have numerous side effects, because they are not part of our normal make up and are …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://m.nautil.us/blog/vaccines-are-the-safest-medical-procedure-we-have-make-your-wager-wisely">http://m.nautil.us/blog/vaccines-are-the-safest-medical-procedure-we-have-make-your-wager-wisely</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://m.nautil.us/blog/vaccines-are-the-safest-medical-procedure-we-have-make-your-wager-wisely</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25583025</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 16:28:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Don't Use Protobuf for Telemetry]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 222 | Comments 185 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25582962">thread link</a>) | @simonpure
<br/>
December 30, 2020 | https://richardstartin.github.io/posts/dont-use-protobuf-for-telemetry | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://richardstartin.github.io/posts/dont-use-protobuf-for-telemetry">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
    <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>Protobuf needs no introduction, but this post argues that you shouldn’t use it for telemetry.
The basic premise of this post is that a good telemetry library needs to be lightweight to avoid perturbing the application; inefficient diagnostic tools are self-defeating.
Unlike other formats, nested Protobuf messages cannot be written contiguously into a stream without significant buffering. 
The post doesn’t argue to never use Protobuf, but that the trade-off made by the <em>wire-format</em> itself, as opposed to any existing implementation, is unlikely to work for lightweight message senders.</p>

<h2 id="protobuf-java-is-a-little-heavy">Protobuf-java is a little heavy</h2>

<p>A few months ago I needed to become familiar with the Protobuf wire-format for a proof of concept.
The motivation for digging in to the wire-format, rather than just using <code>protobuf-java</code>, was the dimensions of the library, which I would need to bundle in an agent:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span><span>stat</span> <span>-c</span> %s protobuf-java-3.14.0.jar
1672950

<span>$ </span>jar <span>-tf</span> protobuf-java-3.14.0.jar | <span>grep</span> <span>'.class'</span> | <span>wc</span> <span>-l</span>
669
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Just depending on the library adds 1.6MB and nearly 700 classes before you even generate your own message classes.
Since the deployment in question was an agent which can’t assume the presence of <code>protobuf-java</code> at runtime, there is no way to avoid bundling the extra 1.6MB.
Since the aforementioned agent implements <code>ClassLoader</code> isolation to avoid interfering with application class loading, even if <code>protobuf-java</code> <em>is</em> present at runtime, the classes would need to be loaded again by an isolated <code>ClassLoader</code>.</p>

<p>A tracer only needs to <em>produce</em> messages, so not all of those 669 classes (which doesn’t include your own generated classes) will get loaded, but a lot of them do.
Having since implemented library-neutral Protobuf serialisation in Datadog’s <a href="https://github.com/DataDog/sketches-java">sketches-java</a>, I have a reasonable <a href="https://github.com/DataDog/sketches-java/blob/master/src/jmh/java/com/datadoghq/sketch/ddsketch/benchmarks/Serialize.java">point of comparison</a> to show how many classes get loaded in a write-only context:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>@OutputTimeUnit</span><span>(</span><span>TimeUnit</span><span>.</span><span>MICROSECONDS</span><span>)</span>
<span>@BenchmarkMode</span><span>(</span><span>Mode</span><span>.</span><span>AverageTime</span><span>)</span>
<span>public</span> <span>class</span> <span>Serialize</span> <span>extends</span> <span>BuiltSketchState</span> <span>{</span>

  <span>@Benchmark</span>
  <span>public</span> <span>byte</span><span>[]</span> <span>serialize</span><span>()</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>sketch</span><span>.</span><span>serialize</span><span>().</span><span>array</span><span>();</span>
  <span>}</span>

  <span>@Benchmark</span>
  <span>public</span> <span>byte</span><span>[]</span> <span>toProto</span><span>()</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>DDSketchProtoBinding</span><span>.</span><span>toProto</span><span>(</span><span>sketch</span><span>).</span><span>toByteArray</span><span>();</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<blockquote>
  <p>Since I mention a Datadog library and am a Datadog employee, I make clear that none of the opinions presented in this post or elsewhere on this blog represent those of my employer.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Each method produces identical bytes, and the purpose of the benchmark above is to compare speeds.
One of the methods relies on a single class consisting of fewer than 150 lines of code, including white-space, whereas the other depends on a large library.
For the record, the hand-written method <code>serialize</code> above is roughly 10x faster than using <code>protobuf-java</code>, but it’s not the point of this post. 
By running the benchmark for a single warmup iteration each, with the argument <code>-jvmArgsPrepend "-verbose:class"</code>, the classes which are loaded are logged, which I captured in separate files.
276 more classes are loaded when using <code>protobuf-java</code>:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span><span>wc</span> <span>-l</span> serialize.log 
1400 serialize.log
<span>$ </span><span>wc</span> <span>-l</span> to_proto.log 
1676 to_proto.log
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>If you work at a large organisation which has entirely embraced Protobuf, I would not suggest worrying about 1.6MB or a few hundred loaded classes; these costs quickly amortise as you use the library for more features.
However, your resource budget for a diagnostic agent which tells you what your application is doing and how it’s performing should be tiny, and I’m not sure <code>protobuf-java</code> can be made to fit in to it, given the isolation constraints for agents outlined above.</p>

<h2 id="length-delimiters-are-costly-to-produce">Length delimiters are costly to produce</h2>

<p>This meant that I needed to write my own (which is a lot easier than it sounds if you haven’t done this sort of thing before) so I had to read the only documentation there is on <a href="https://developers.google.com/protocol-buffers/docs/encoding">encoding</a>.
I couldn’t get the formatter I had written based on my first reading of this document to produce valid protobuf because I had skim-read the section on embedded messages, and because it includes a design decision that would never have occurred to me.
When I went back and read it again I was surprised to find that embedded messages are length-prefixed, but the length prefix is varint encoded, which means you don’t know how many bytes you need for the length until you’ve done the serialisation, and it’s recursive.</p>

<p>Length prefixes aren’t unusual in binary formats: BSON documents are prefixed by their sizes in bytes, meaning sub-documents need to be serialised recursively before their lengths can be written.
BSON makes this easy by not compressing the document length so you just leave 4 bytes for the length and come back and fill it in when popping document contexts (<a href="https://richardstartin.github.io/posts/shrinking-bson-documents">it can add up to a significant portion of your database though</a>).
Msgpack, for example, <em>does</em> apply prefix compression of embedded element lengths (e.g. maps and arrays) but the length is an element count, not a number of bytes, which makes streaming serialisation a lot easier to do.</p>

<p>Protobuf does both, and, consequently, there’s no way to produce nested Protobuf messages without doing something relatively expensive.
You must either maintain a stack and copy contents from frame to frame as they are popped, or pre-compute serialised lengths of nested elements recursively; it isn’t possible to simply write serialised output sequentially to a stream as it is with other formats. 
I abandoned the proof of concept when I found that a streaming zero-allocation msgpack codec I had written was around 6x faster than either <code>protobuf-java</code> or a handwritten Protobuf codec for messages with nesting.
Since I couldn’t remove the nesting in the messages I needed to produce, I blamed the wire-format and moved on.</p>

<p>People who actually know Protobuf already know this (it’s literally written in the encoding manual), and understand the benefits which arise from this cost elsewhere (e.g. implementing partial deserialisation is easy, easy to skip over sections of the message), but lots of people don’t seem to understand the cost model the wire-format imposes.
If they did, there would probably be a lot less nesting in Protobuf as used in the wild.</p>

<p>This more or less concludes my argument against using Protobuf for telemetry: if you find for yourself that producing Protobuf messages is costly, it’s not even a case of a third party library making the wrong trade-offs for your application; it’s the wire-format itself at fault.
If you want to ship telemetry data out of an application and aim to minimise the impact on the application, even if you implement your own zero-allocation, micro-optimised codec, you shouldn’t choose Protobuf.</p>

<p>This is a good opportunity to segue into describing the wire-format for Protobuf 3, filling in a couple of the gaps in <a href="https://developers.google.com/protocol-buffers/docs/encoding">Google’s encoding document</a>, but read the official document if you want to write your own.</p>

<h2 id="notes-on-the-wire-format">Notes on the wire format</h2>

<p>Protobuf’s wire format is really simple: it’s just a list of tagged key-value pairs. 
Since readers have a schema to refer to, ambiguity is permissible and advantageous.
The logical structure of a Protobuf message is as below, with each tag followed by some bytes associated with the tag.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>tag1:value1, tag3:value2, tag2:value3, ...
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Here is a pseudo-Backus-Naur form of the wire format.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>body 	         ::= 	tagged_value*
tagged_value     ::=    tag value
tag              ::=    varint((field_number &lt;&lt; 3) | wire_type)
wire_type        ::=    VARINT | FIXED_64 | LENGTH_DELIMITED | GROUP_BEGIN | GROUP_END | FIXED_32
VARINT           ::=    0
FIXED_64         ::=    1
LENGTH_DELIMITED ::=    2
GROUP_BEGIN      ::=    3 (deprecated)
GROUP_END        ::=    4 (deprecated)
FIXED_32         ::=    5
value            ::=    varint | fixed_64 | length_delimited | fixed_32
fixed_64         ::=    double | long
length_delimited ::=    varint(N) byte{N}
fixed_32         ::=    float | int
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Each data item has a tag, which contains the field number (as defined in the .proto file) and one of the four wire types still in use in Protobuf 3.
The tag is constructed by shifting the field number left by three bits and combining with the wire type, and then <em>varint-encoded</em> so it takes up less space.
Since there are only three bits for the wire type, there can only ever be eight wire types, and two have already been wasted on group begin and end markers (I don’t know the story behind these).
Given that <code>FIXED_32=5</code> with only two possible wire types left, I imagine that there were some tense meetings before deciding to add it.</p>

<p>The terminology above is my own, but notice that there are no terms like <code>repeated</code>, <code>oneof</code>, or <code>message</code>.
This is because they don’t exist at this level. 
<code>message</code> is just a length delimiter followed by some more protobuf, preceded by a <code>LENGTH_DELIMITED</code> tag; the schema has the necessary information to read the raw bytes.
<code>repeated</code> fields come in two kinds: packed and not packed. 
Packed <code>repeated</code> fields are indistinguishable from a <code>message</code> or a <code>string</code> on the wire.
<code>repeated</code> fields which aren’t packed are a list of tag-values with the same field number and the element type in each tag, and they don’t need to be contiguous within the message.
Incidentally, writers aren’t obliged not to repeat non-<code>repeated</code> fields, and as there is nothing to distinguish these fields over the wire, readers are obliged to take the <em>last value</em> for a non-<code>repeated</code> field (which makes some of the partial deserialisers I’ve seen illegal).</p>

<p><code>FIXED_32</code> corresponds to proto types <code>float</code>, <code>fixed32</code>, and <code>sfixed32</code>, whereas <code>FIXED_64</code> corresponds to <code>double</code>, <code>fixed64</code>, and <code>sfixed64</code>.
All other integers, which includes booleans, are <em>varint</em> encoded, which has the basic effect of removing leading zeros in order to save space.
Starting with the least significant bits, seven bits are taken at a time from the integer until no bits remain, and all but the last byte have their most significant bit set.
This allows the parser to detect the end of an integer by looking for a byte with the MSB unset. 
Whilst this saves space, it …</p></div></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://richardstartin.github.io/posts/dont-use-protobuf-for-telemetry">https://richardstartin.github.io/posts/dont-use-protobuf-for-telemetry</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://richardstartin.github.io/posts/dont-use-protobuf-for-telemetry</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25582962</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 16:20:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Interesting Research Programs from the 2010s]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 53 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25582656">thread link</a>) | @wannabebarista
<br/>
December 30, 2020 | https://bcmullins.github.io/interesting-research-2010s/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bcmullins.github.io/interesting-research-2010s/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p>The idea of this post is to introduce and discuss several interesting research programs from the past decade. A <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Research_program">research program</a> (or programme) refers to a common thread of research that shares similar assumptions, methodology, etc. The list below contains a variety of research programs: some on topics that have broad appeal e.g. <a href="#machine-learning-interpretability-and-explainability">explainable machine learning</a> and <a href="#the-disordered-mind-theory-of-mental-illness">mental disorder</a>; others moved the direction of entire industries e.g. advances in <a href="#image-recognition-and-object-detection">computer vision</a> and <a href="#blockchains-and-cryptocurrencies">cryptocurrencies</a>; and others still are more niche areas that I happen to be deeply interested in e.g. <a href="#topological-learning-theory">topological learning theory</a>, <a href="#privacy-attacks-on-machine-learning-models">privacy attacks on ML models</a>, and <a href="#the-graph-theoretic-approach-to-epistemic-justification">graph-theoretic approaches to epistemology</a>.</p>

<p>Obviously, a list of this variety can never be complete and is surely biased by what I happen to be reading. If I’ve missed something interesting that you enjoy, let me know at <a href="mailto:brettcmullins@gmail.com">brettcmullins@gmail.com</a>. Enjoy!</p>

<h2 id="image-recognition-and-object-detection">Image Recognition and Object Detection</h2>
<hr>

<p>It is difficult for me to begin this list without first talking about the area that most affected my professional career, led to (or at least accelerated) a boom in data science, and <a href="https://www.skynettoday.com/overviews/neural-net-history">potentially thawed an AI winter</a>. During the 2010s, <a href="https://bmk.sh/2019/12/31/The-Decade-of-Deep-Learning/">deep learning made enormous progress</a> in heuristics and applications. For <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_vision">computer vision</a> in particular, a good starting point is <a href="https://papers.nips.cc/paper/2012/file/c399862d3b9d6b76c8436e924a68c45b-Paper.pdf">AlexNet</a> in 2012 which used a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Convolutional_neural_network">convolutional neural network (CNN)</a> architecture to substantially surpass existing benchmarks for image recognition - the task of assigning a label such as <em>cat</em>, <em>dog</em>, or <em>tree</em> to an image - on the <a href="http://image-net.org/">ImageNet dataset</a>. Over the next few years, improvements would continue with architectures such as <a href="https://towardsdatascience.com/vgg-neural-networks-the-next-step-after-alexnet-3f91fa9ffe2c">VGG</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Residual_neural_network">ResNet</a>, and <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1409.4842.pdf">Inception</a>.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="https://miro.medium.com/max/500/1*r9ELExnk1B1zHnRReDW9Ow.png" width="300" height="250">
  <figcaption> Example output from R-CNN. Source: <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1311.2524">the R-CNN paper.</a></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>With progress being made with recognition, other tasks such as object detection - finding and labeling objects (sometimes multiple objects) within images - became more feasible. One approach to object detection introduced in 2013 <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1311.2524">Regional CNNs (or R-CNNs)</a> combined a model that first produced promising bounding boxes then utilized the newly developed recognition models (starting with AlexNet) to classify or label the regions in the bounding boxes. Over the next few years, progress in this direction was realized with <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1504.08083">Fast R-CNN</a> and <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1504.08083">Faster R-CNN</a>. These frameworks not only employed better recognition models and found better bounding boxes, but they integrated the model components together so that they could be more efficiently trained or tailored to one’s application. <a href="https://blog.athelas.com/a-brief-history-of-cnns-in-image-segmentation-from-r-cnn-to-mask-r-cnn-34ea83205de4">Here is an excellent overview</a> of these models with a bit more detail.</p>

<p>Accompanying these new techniques and improvements was a large amount of software - with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TensorFlow">TensorFlow</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caffe_(software)">Caffe</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Torch_(machine_learning)">Torch</a> at first then the more user friendly <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keras">Keras</a> - allowing anyone to implement these models for their use cases. It’s also worth mentioning the proliferation of online courses such as <a href="https://fast.ai/">fast.ai’s</a> <a href="https://course.fast.ai/">Practical Deep Learning for Coders</a> that facilitated getting potential users up to speed to test out and deploy these tools.</p>

<h2 id="topological-learning-theory">Topological Learning Theory</h2>
<hr>

<p>Topological Learning Theory is the mathematical study of the learnability/solvability of hypotheses/problems that is informed by the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computability_theory">theory of computation</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Descriptive_set_theory">descriptive set theory</a> rather than <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frequentist_inference">classical statistics</a> (with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistical_learning_theory">statistical learning theory</a>). The idea of learning theory is to analyze the learnability of hypotheses as one incrementally receives information about the true state of the world.</p>

<p><img src="https://images.pexels.com/photos/3858127/pexels-photo-3858127.jpeg?auto=compress&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;dpr=2&amp;h=750&amp;w=1260" width="200" height="350"></p>

<p>A <a href="https://plato.stanford.edu/entries/learning-formal/#1.1">classic example</a> is to consider an ornithologist observing the color of ravens as, say, black or not. With each raven observed, the ornithologist gains information which rules out some hypotheses but is consistent with others. By coding a black raven as 1 and other ravens as 0, we can mathematically represent possible observation histories as infinite sequences of 0s and 1s, i.e. points in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cantor_space">Cantor space</a>. The crux of this approach is that the <a href="http://www.personal.psu.edu/jsr25/Spring_11/Lecture_Notes/dst_lecture_notes_2011_lec_2.pdf">topology on the Cantor space and other such spaces</a> naturally <a href="http://www.andrew.cmu.edu/user/kk3n/kelly/learnreview.pdf">encodes the idea of information accumulation</a>. By considering the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Borel_hierarchy">descriptive complexity of hypotheses</a>, identifying a hypothesis with the set of sequences that make it true, we can say things about the learnability of the hypothesis. For instance, the hypothesis “all ravens are black” is the set containing the single sequence of all 1s. We say that this hypothesis is falsifiable since if there is a non-black raven our ornithologist will eventually observe it; however, it is verifiable not in finite time but in the limit since the hypothesis is never conclusively true after any finite number of observations. This corresponds to the topological notion of properly being an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/F%CF%83_set">$F_{\sigma}$ or $\Sigma^{0}_{2}$ set</a>.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.cmu.edu/dietrich/philosophy/people/faculty/kevin-kelly.html">Kevin Kelly’s</a> 1996 <a href="https://global.oup.com/academic/product/the-logic-of-reliable-inquiry-9780195091953?cc=us&amp;lang=en&amp;"><em>The Logic of Reliable Inquiry</em></a> has been an authoritative text on formal learning theory in the Cantor space and other <a href="https://ncatlab.org/nlab/show/Polish+space">Polish spaces</a>. Advances in <a href="https://ncatlab.org/nlab/show/computable+analysis">computable analysis</a> beginning in the early 2000s have enabled the extension of these classical formal learning theory results to a more general topological setting throughout the 2010s. The paper <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0890540109001631?via%3Dihub"><em>Topological Properties of Concept Spaces</em></a> from 2010 is the first to connect these computable analysis results to learning theory. By 2015, a pair of papers <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1606.07518"><em>On the Solvability of Inductive Problems</em></a> and <a href="https://www.imsc.res.in/tark/TARK2015-proceedings.pdf#page=119"><em>Theory Choice, Theory Change, and Inductive Truth-Conduciveness</em></a> - both presented at the <a href="https://www.imsc.res.in/tark/tark15.html">TARK 2015 conference</a> - provide complete topological characterizations of learnability/solvability in the limit as well as connections to <a href="https://plato.stanford.edu/entries/logic-belief-revision/">belief revision theory</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Occam%27s_razor">Ockham’s Razor</a> in this more general topological setting.</p>

<h2 id="the-disordered-mind-theory-of-mental-illness">The Disordered Mind Theory of Mental Illness</h2>
<hr>

<p>In a series of articles and books over the past decade, the philosopher <a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/contributors/george-graham">George Graham</a> develops a theory of mental disorder with the following qualities: 1. is non-reductionist with respect to the mind and the brain; 2. is informed by the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Philosophy_of_mind">philosophy of mind</a>; and 3. coheres with the experiences of patients and clinicians. Graham’s theory holds that mental illness is distinct from somatic/bodily illness though may co-occur or otherwise be bound up with so-called <a href="https://psycnet.apa.org/record/2008-07609-001">broken brains</a>. A helpful analogy for what is meant here by “the mental” or “the mind” is to view the brain as computer hardware, whereas the mind is software. On this picture, the mind and the brain are surely not independent; a hardware issue may impede the computation of some software. However, one may have bugs in one’s software - “gumming up the works” to use a common phrase of Graham - on perfectly functioning hardware.</p>

<p><img src="https://images.routledge.com/common/jackets/amazon/978036732/9780367322328.jpg" width="200" height="280"></p>

<p>This theory of mental disorder is developed in Graham’s text on mental illness in the context of the philosophy of mind: <a href="https://www.routledge.com/The-Disordered-Mind/Graham/p/book/9780367322328"><em>The Disordered Mind</em></a>. A follow-up book, <a href="https://global.oup.com/academic/product/the-abraham-dilemma-9780198728658?cc=us&amp;lang=en&amp;"><em>The Abraham Dilemma</em></a>, refines this theory for the case of delusion, religious delusion in particular (I discuss <em>The Abraham Dilemma</em> in greater detail in my <a href="https://bcmullins.github.io/top-books-2020/#the-abraham-dilemma-a-divine-delusion">Top Books in 2020</a>). Graham’s latest book <a href="https://global.oup.com/academic/product/hearing-voices-and-other-matters-of-the-mind-9780190091149?cc=us&amp;lang=en&amp;"><em>Hearing Voices and Other Matters of the Mind</em></a> explores the unique properties and challenges of mental disorders in the presence of religious content. The disordered mind theory <a href="https://ndpr.nd.edu/news/the-disordered-mind-an-introduction-to-philosophy-of-mind-and-mental-illness/">is not without its detractors</a> who hold that Graham goes too far in arguing that one need not situate and commit to positions in the philosophy of mind to reject the complete reduction of mental illness to neuroscience.</p>

<p>I took George Graham’s seminar on Philosophy and Mental Illness in 2014 at <a href="https://philosophy.gsu.edu/">Georgia State University</a> and had several interesting chats with him about the metaphysics and definability of mental disorders.</p>

<h2 id="machine-learning-interpretability-and-explainability">Machine Learning Interpretability and Explainability</h2>
<hr>

<p>The boom in data science and widespread use of machine learning models during the past decade was accelerated by innovations in model architectures as well as tools and software to train and deploy these models. In addition to the <a href="#image-recognition-and-object-detection">progress with neural networks and deep learning</a>, algorithms such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XGBoost">XGBoost</a> allowed users to achieve state-of-the-art classification and regression performance without much effort. XGBoost in particular became so prevalent in both industry and ML competitions - as had logistic regression and other GLMs in the past - that it was not unreasonable for some to wonder whether or not <a href="https://towardsdatascience.com/https-medium-com-vishalmorde-xgboost-algorithm-long-she-may-rein-edd9f99be63d">we should just use XGBoost all the time</a>.</p>

<p>For all that these models gained in performance, they lost ground in being able to provide answers to questions from stakeholders, developers, and so forth when things went wrong as to why a model’s prediction was so far off or why does the computer vision model <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1712.09665.pdf">think a banana is a toaster</a>. Two approaches were offered as a solution (three if you count “Who cares?! Let’s do nothing!”): interpretability and explanations. The former offers constraints on model building such as limiting the number of features used and restricting to linear models so that the model is sufficiently simple to allow the developer/user to reliably predict the model’s behavior with a reasonable amount of effort. The latter is a set of methods for generating reasons for a model’s behavior for arbitrarily complex models. <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1606.03490"><em>The Mythos of Model Interpretability</em></a> is an early effort to disentangle these terms and map the landscape for understanding models. Also see <a href="https://bcmullins.github.io/economic_methodology_interpretable_ml_blackboxes/">my attempt here</a> as well as Christoph Molnar’s ever-evolving text <a href="https://christophm.github.io/interpretable-ml-book/"><em>Interpretable Machine Learning</em></a>.</p>

<p><img width="40%" height="40%" src="https://bcmullins.github.io/images/blog/best_articles_2018/anchor.png"></p>

<p>The approach that I find the most compelling stems from the <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1602.04938">LIME paper</a>. LIME (or local interpretable model-agnostic explanations) is a method of generating an interpretable, i.e. linear, approximation of a model in the neighborhood of a given point in the feature space. This new model is then used to generate explanations by virtue of its interpretability. A second approach for classifiers called <a href="https://homes.cs.washington.edu/~marcotcr/aaai18.pdf">Anchors</a> - both are developed by the <a href="https://homes.cs.washington.edu/~guestrin/group.html">same research group at UW</a> that also developed XGBoost - produces a simple region of the feature space (a rectangle) where the model’s prediction holds with high probability for a given point. This region or anchor acts as a sort of sufficiency condition for classification. The image to the right illustrates these ideas with the dotted line being a local linear approximation and the …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://bcmullins.github.io/interesting-research-2010s/">https://bcmullins.github.io/interesting-research-2010s/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bcmullins.github.io/interesting-research-2010s/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25582656</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 15:49:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Things I Learnt in 2020]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 212 | Comments 63 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25582269">thread link</a>) | @valzevul
<br/>
December 30, 2020 | https://drobinin.com/posts/things-i-learnt-in-2020/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://drobinin.com/posts/things-i-learnt-in-2020/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I am pretty much a knowledge addict.</p>
<p>I use Twitter, RSS, and numerous other mediums of information — from Telegram channels to standalone blogs.</p>
<p>Out of a thousand articles a hundred gets skimmed through. A few dozens make it to my "Read Later" list, and only a fraction I find worthy of sharing.</p>
<p>These worthy ones end up in <a href="https://drobinin.com/newsletter/">my weekly newsletter, the Tuesday Triage</a>, where I comment on the most intriguing articles I've read and share facts I learnt over the week.</p>
<p>Some of those trivia are not trivial at all, so I decided to condense this <em>crème de la crème of the Internet</em> in a subjective list of the best ones in no particular order.</p>
<hr>
<h4 id="solresol"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Solresol">Solresol</a> <a href="#solresol">¶</a></h4>
<p>Most people know about the esperanto, an artificially created language. Way less people are aware of Solresol, another artificial language, built upon the musical grammar.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Is your health good? - Redofafa?</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Will you go to the countryside this year? - Fadoremi?</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Will you go to the theatre tonight? - Soldoremi?</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/5/56/Sol-resol.png" alt=""></p>
<hr>
<h4 id="logbook"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logbook">Logbook</a> <a href="#logbook">¶</a></h4>
<p>As developers we work with logs a lot. And the logs are stored in logbooks (or at least they were). What's the ethymology?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The term originally referred to a book for recording readings from the chip log that was used to estimate a ship's speed through the water.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So how come a chip log was used to estimate a ship's speed? In the absence of GPS and without any visible clues about the speed of a ship in the open water, sailors started to throw wooden pieces with a tied strope (hence the definition of knots as nautical miles per hour!) into water and then measure the relative speed against such logs, hence the name.</p>
<hr>
<h4 id="popcorn-in-the-1800s"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Popcorn#Consumption">Popcorn in the 1800s</a> <a href="#popcorn-in-the-1800s">¶</a></h4>
<blockquote>
<p>Popcorn as a breakfast cereal was consumed by Americans in the 1800s and generally consisted of popcorn with milk and a sweetener.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It doesn't surprise me when I think about this as a dish, and yet I'd probably never come up with that on my own.</p>
<hr>
<h4 id="danakil-depression"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Danakil_Depression">Danakil Depression</a> <a href="#danakil-depression">¶</a></h4>
<blockquote>
<p>The Danakil Depression is the northern part of the Afar Triangle or Afar Depression in Ethiopia, a geological depression that has resulted from the divergence of three tectonic plates in the Horn of Africa.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://live.staticflickr.com/3682/10387154385_32f2fdb136_b.jpg" alt=""></p>
<hr>
<h4 id="ansi-k-100.1-1974"><a href="https://groups.niso.org/apps/group_public/download.php/6140/K100.1-1974%20-%20American%20National%20Standard%20Safety%20Code%20%26%20Requirements%20for%20Dry%20Martinis%20.pdf">ANSI K 100.1-1974</a> <a href="#ansi-k-100.1-1974">¶</a></h4>
<p>The year is 1974. The American National Standards Institute introduces safety code and requirements for dry martinis, and boy-oh-boy are they good.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Definitions</p>
<p><em>Gibson.</em><br>
An unpardonable form of perversion. See onion soup.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>or</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Test Methods</p>
<p>[...] In testing, the taster shall watch for lightness of color, absence of sediment, a delicate aroma that effectively combines the scent of the juniper with the herbal infusion in the vermouth, a taste that is both sharp and clean with a faint body, and a light delicate aftertaste.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h4 id="by-the-bye"><a href="https://english.stackexchange.com/questions/57078/by-the-bye-etymology-and-usage">By the bye</a> <a href="#by-the-bye">¶</a></h4>
<p>This example left me, to put it succinctly, flabbergasted for a brief moment.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>by the by or by the bye : INCIDENTALLY [defined as "by way of interjection or digression : by the way"]</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I wonder if it will help me to up the game of interrupting folks in conversations.</p>
<hr>
<h4 id="pie-barm"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barm_cake">Pie Barm</a> <a href="#pie-barm">¶</a></h4>
<p>Watch after my hands:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>We ferment a liquid (beer, wine, or stock)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>We take the foam from the top of the liquid (this is called <strong>barm</strong>)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>We use this foam to leaven a bread roll, and then put something inside it (now this is called a <strong>barm cake</strong>)</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>And if we do all of that in Wigan, Greater Manchester, England, we most likely would put a pie as a filling (they also host the <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/av/uk-england-manchester-46620294/world-pie-eating-champion-crowned-in-wigan">World Pie Eating Championship</a>, so no surprise). And here it is, the pie barm:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In Wigan, a whole savoury pie is served in a barm cake, known locally as a "Wigan Kebab".</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://i2.wp.com/random-times.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/5813a857-4338-41ec-a2db-d751d986268c.jpeg?resize=878%2C659&amp;ssl=1" alt="The image by https://random-times.com/2020/04/24/pie-barm-an-unconventional-traditional-sandwich-from-wigan-england/"></p><hr>
<h4 id="two-spaces-after-period"><a href="https://www.cultofpedagogy.com/two-spaces-after-period/">Two spaces after period</a> <a href="#two-spaces-after-period">¶</a></h4>
<p>Back then people had to put two spaces after punctuation marks as typewriters had monospaced typesetting.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Here’s why: Back when we used typewriters, every character was given the exact same amount of space on the page. That meant the letter i was given the same amount of space as the letter m, even though it clearly didn’t need it. This is called monospaced typesetting and it’s, well, spacey. We needed that extra space between sentences to make it easier to see the beginning of new sentences.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>These days quite a few still do that; usually one can easily assume they've learnt to type not on a computer.</p>
<p>Rarely, one encounters someone like me, with a typewriter next to the keyboard, and just thinks I am stupid and don't know thine grammar.</p>
<hr>
<h4 id="erstwhile"><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/erstwhile">erstwhile</a> <a href="#erstwhile">¶</a></h4>
<p>Here is a beautiful word I unearthed recently:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The adverb erstwhile has been part of English since the 16th century, but it is formed from two words that are much older. It comes from the Old English words ær, meaning "early", and hwīl, which has much the same meaning as the modern word while. (The English word ere, meaning "before," is also descendant of ær.)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Used as a synonim to "former", e.g "erstwhile enemies".</p>
<hr>
<h4 id="children-used-to-be-sent-through-the-mail"><a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/brief-history-children-sent-through-mail-180959372/">Children used to be sent through the Mail</a> <a href="#children-used-to-be-sent-through-the-mail">¶</a></h4>
<p>I am just surprised that this practice was eventually banned.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Just a few weeks after Parcel Post began, an Ohio couple named Jesse and Mathilda Beagle “mailed” their 8-month-old son James to his grandmother, who lived just a few miles away in Batavia. According to Lynch, Baby James was just shy of the 11-pound weight limit for packages sent via Parcel Post, and his “delivery” cost his parents only 15 cents in postage (although they did insure him for $50).</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Postage was cheaper than train tickets back then (and still is, actually), so I can't really blame the parents.</p>
<hr>
<h4 id="ek-number"><a href="https://digg.com/2018/how-different-countries-laugh-online">ek number</a> <a href="#ek-number">¶</a></h4>
<p>Sometimes I realize that speaking in one (two, three, ...) languages means there are corners of the Internet and/or world you can't appreciate, in the first place because you can't understand them.</p>
<p>So while knowing both English and Russian is usually more than enough to find an answer to almost any question, I still miss the jewels like that:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"ek number," which loosely translates to "I rate this number one" — the "ek" itself means "one" in Hindi — is commonly used as an affirmative response to a joke. If you find something to be funny, you could always type "haha" or "hehe" in India, but you can also signal your enjoyment by responding "ek number."</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h4 id="remy-labesque-and-chocolate-chips"><a href="http://www.dandelionchocolate.com/2020/06/18/remy-chocolate-chip/">Remy Labesque and chocolate chips</a> <a href="#remy-labesque-and-chocolate-chips">¶</a></h4>
<p>Chocolate chips have a water drop's shape because it's easier to make that way. It's harder to use though.</p>
<p>Remy Labesque, one of Tesla's designers, helped Dandelion Chocolate to invent a machine to make ideal chocolate chips:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The shape of a typical store-bought chocolate chip is an arbitrary result of the industrial manufacturing process used to make it. As you might expect, a drop of molten chocolate is deposited onto a flat surface and left to cool. Chocolate chip taste varies widely by brand, but the shape of the chips does not.</p>
<p>The shape of our chip is faceted: The edges of a Dandelion Chocolate chip taper to thin-as-we could-make-’em without compromising structure. This is because the thermal mass of a thin piece of chocolate melts more quickly on the palate. So when you put a Dandelion chip on your tongue, the thin, chiseled edges warm-to-melt nearly instantly.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://i2.wp.com/www.dandelionchocolate.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Remy-3d-drawing.jpg?zoom=2&amp;resize=794%2C613&amp;ssl=1" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://i1.wp.com/www.dandelionchocolate.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/IMG_3609-1.jpg?zoom=2&amp;resize=516%2C511&amp;ssl=1" alt=""></p>
<p>1 lb of these chips costs 30$, not bad.</p>
<hr>
<h4 id="ogden's-basic-english"><a href="http://ogden.basic-english.org/">Ogden's Basic English</a> <a href="#ogden's-basic-english">¶</a></h4>
<p>Apparently removing all redundancies, synonims, etc from the English language leaves us only with 850 words or so:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We call this simplified language Basic English, the developer is Charles K. Ogden, and was released in 1930 with the book: Basic English: A General Introduction with Rules and Grammar. He founded the Orthological Institute to develop the tools for teaching Basic English. His most famous associate, I.A. Richards, led the effort in the Orient, which uses the techniques to this day.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The most interesting bit is, that change doesn't affect the grammar, so one could learn only 850 words and yet converse in English by using its grammar to its full extent.</p>
<hr>
<h4 id="brick-pencil"><a href="http://gordonbrander.com/pattern/brick-pencil/">Brick pencil</a> <a href="#brick-pencil">¶</a></h4>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Douglas_Engelbart">Doug Engelbart</a>, one of the people behind the creation of a computer mouse, and then graphical interfaces, argued about interfaces in his paper "Augmenting Human Intellect: a Conceptual Framework" in 1962 and to proof his point came up with a brick pencil:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Brains of power equal to ours could have evolved in an environment where the combination of artifact materials and muscle strengths were so scaled that the neatest scribing tool (equivalent to a pencil, possible had a shape and mass as manageable as a brick would be to us-assuming that our muscles were not specially conditioned to deal with it. We fastened a pencil to a brick and experimented. Figure 2 shows the results, compared with typewriting and ordinary pencil writing. With the brick pencil, we are slower and less precise. If we want to hurry the writing, we have to make it larger. Also, writing the passage twice with the brick-pencil tires the untrained hand and arm.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://dougengelbart.org/pubs/papers/images/augment-3906/fig2.gif" alt=""></p>
<p>(and now users complain that they have to click a button twice; such a shame)</p>
<hr>
<h4 id="cosmic-latte"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cosmic_latte">Cosmic Latte</a> <a href="#cosmic-latte">¶</a></h4>
<p>Wikipedia sums it up well:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Cosmic latte is the average colour of the universe, found by a team of astronomers from Johns Hopkins University.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>For those keen on putting this into their apps, here is the colour: #FFF8E7.</p>
<hr>
<h4 id="7-up's-history"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/7_Up#History">7-UP's history</a> <a href="#7-up's-history">¶</a></h4>
<p>In my childhood I used to love 7-UP a lot, mostly because it was nearly transparent hence felt less poisonous comparing to other sodas.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>It contained lithium citrate, a mood-stabilizing drug, until 1948</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Probably if I were to drink it until 1948 it'd be my favourite drink anyway, but not because of its (lack of) colour.</p>
<p>Also all myths about its name are hilarious.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A myth exists that the 7 Up name comes from the drink having a pH over 7. That would make it neutral or basic on the scale; however, this is not the case, as the 7 Up pH is close to 3.79, making it acidic on the pH scale and similar to other drinks of this type. [...]<br>
The real origin of the name is unclear, though Britvic claims that the name comes from the seven main ingredients in the drink, while others have claimed that the number was a coded reference to the lithium contained in the original recipe, which has an atomic mass around 7.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>However, this one makes the most sense to me:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Britvic also claims that the name is a result of the fact that 7 Up was bottled in 7-ounce bottles …</p></blockquote></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://drobinin.com/posts/things-i-learnt-in-2020/">https://drobinin.com/posts/things-i-learnt-in-2020/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://drobinin.com/posts/things-i-learnt-in-2020/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25582269</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 15:07:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How Python attributes work]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 102 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25581313">thread link</a>) | @r4victor
<br/>
December 30, 2020 | https://tenthousandmeters.com/blog/python-behind-the-scenes-7-how-python-attributes-work/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://tenthousandmeters.com/blog/python-behind-the-scenes-7-how-python-attributes-work/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://tenthousandmeters.com/blog/python-behind-the-scenes-7-how-python-attributes-work/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25581313</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 13:07:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Wasmino = WASM and Arduino – Running Arduino Code in Browser]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 74 | Comments 13 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25581081">thread link</a>) | @gyf304
<br/>
December 30, 2020 | https://blog.yifangu.com/2020/12/30/wasmino-wasm-arduino-running-arduino-code-in-browser/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.yifangu.com/2020/12/30/wasmino-wasm-arduino-running-arduino-code-in-browser/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">

	<section id="primary">
		<main id="main">

			
<article id="post-365">

	

	
	<div>
		
<figure><img data-attachment-id="394" data-permalink="https://blog.yifangu.com/wasmino/" data-orig-file="https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/wasmino.gif" data-orig-size="320,320" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="wasmino" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/wasmino.gif?w=300" data-large-file="https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/wasmino.gif?w=320" src="https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/wasmino.gif?w=320" alt=""><figcaption>Wasmino Running the “Fade” example</figcaption></figure>



<p>Wasmino is an Arduino core fully compatible with the Arduino IDE. It allows you to compile your Arduino sketch to WebAssembly and run it in a browser, all using the Arduino IDE.</p>



<h2>Showcase</h2>



<p>This is the off-the-shelf “Fade” example in the Arduino IDE.</p>


<pre title="">/*
  Fade

  This example shows how to fade an LED on pin 9 using the analogWrite()
  function.

  The analogWrite() function uses PWM, so if you want to change the pin you're
  using, be sure to use another PWM capable pin. On most Arduino, the PWM pins
  are identified with a "~" sign, like ~3, ~5, ~6, ~9, ~10 and ~11.

  This example code is in the public domain.

  http://www.arduino.cc/en/Tutorial/Fade
*/

int led = 9;           // the PWM pin the LED is attached to
int brightness = 0;    // how bright the LED is
int fadeAmount = 5;    // how many points to fade the LED by

// the setup routine runs once when you press reset:
void setup() {
  // declare pin 9 to be an output:
  pinMode(led, OUTPUT);
}

// the loop routine runs over and over again forever:
void loop() {
  // set the brightness of pin 9:
  analogWrite(led, brightness);

  // change the brightness for next time through the loop:
  brightness = brightness + fadeAmount;

  // reverse the direction of the fading at the ends of the fade:
  if (brightness &lt;= 0 || brightness &gt;= 255) {
    fadeAmount = -fadeAmount;
  }
  // wait for 30 milliseconds to see the dimming effect
  delay(30);
}
</pre>


<p>You can see it compiled to WASM and running here:</p>



<p>(<strong>Click the “Run” button</strong> and the LED should start to animate)</p>



<p><a href="https://demo.wasmino.org/#src=gist%3A%2F%2F01734051e7ab5b82173ea947b882ad80&amp;pins=%7B%229%22%3A%7B%22type%22%3A%22led%22%7D%7D">https://demo.wasmino.org/#src=gist%3A%2F%2F01734051e7ab5b82173ea947b882ad80&amp;pins=%7B%229%22%3A%7B%22type%22%3A%22led%22%7D%7D</a></p>



<h2>Setting it up</h2>



<p>Disclaimer: The toolchain is only tested on Windows (x86-64) and Linux (x86-64), and probably will work for MacOS. It 100% won’t work on 32bit systems since some dependencies (WASI and Binaryen) are 64bit only.</p>



<p>You’ll need your Arduino IDE installed first.</p>



<p>Go to File -&gt; Preferences, and add <a href="https://github.com/wasmino/wasmino-core/releases/download/v0.0.1/package_wasmino_index.json">https://github.com/wasmino/wasmino-core/releases/download/v0.0.1/package_wasmino_index.json</a> to “Additional Boards Manager URLs”.</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="368" data-permalink="https://blog.yifangu.com/image-8/" data-orig-file="https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/image.png" data-orig-size="969,725" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="image" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/image.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/image.png?w=750" src="https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/image.png?w=969" alt="" srcset="https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/image.png 969w, https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/image.png?w=150 150w, https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/image.png?w=300 300w, https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/image.png?w=768 768w" sizes="(max-width: 969px) 100vw, 969px"></figure>



<p>Install “Wasmino Virtual Boards” in Tools -&gt; Board -&gt; Board Manager. Select Wasmino as as target board.</p>



<p>Write some Arduino code, click upload, and an URL will be generated for you. (If you are uploading for the first time, it will ask you to login to your GitHub account. It uses GitHub Gist for saving the compiled WASM binary. The login times out in 60 seconds.)</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="402" data-permalink="https://blog.yifangu.com/image-1-4/" data-orig-file="https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/image-1.png" data-orig-size="969,725" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="image-1" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/image-1.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/image-1.png?w=750" src="https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/image-1.png?w=969" alt="" srcset="https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/image-1.png 969w, https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/image-1.png?w=150 150w, https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/image-1.png?w=300 300w, https://yifangucom.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/image-1.png?w=768 768w" sizes="(max-width: 969px) 100vw, 969px"></figure>



<p>Paste that URL into your browser and use the UI to add LEDs or toggle switches. The URL will automatically update as you make changes. You can then copy the resulting URL in the browser and share it with other people.</p>



<h2>Caveats</h2>



<p>The Wasmino should be viewed as having an infinitely fast CPU, and operations other than <code>delay</code> and <code>delayMicroseconds</code> do not take any CPU time. Calling time functions <code>micros</code> and <code>millis</code> should reflect this. IO can only happen during sleep, therefore you cannot do</p>


<pre title="">while (!digitalRead(2)) {} // this will hang the browser tab
</pre>


<p>and should do this instead</p>


<pre title="">while (!digitalRead(2)) {
    delay(50);
}
</pre>


<p>Having a infinitely fast CPU also means that interrupts will only happen during <code>delay</code> and <code>delayMicroseconds</code>. It is still good practice to use <code>noInterrupts</code> and <code>interrupts</code> to protect critical sections if you plan to use your code on real hardware.</p>



<p>Other caveats exist such as the lack of <code>BUILTIN_LED</code> macro since Wasmino, being virtual, doesn’t have a built-in LED.</p>



<h2>What works and what doesn’t work</h2>



<pre><code>From: https://www.arduino.cc/reference/en/

y: working
n: not working

Digital I/O
y   digitalRead()
y   digitalWrite()
y   pinMode()
Analog I/O
y*  analogRead()
n   analogReference()
y   analogWrite()
Zero, Due &amp; MKR Family
n   analogReadResolution()
n   analogWriteResolution()
Advanced I/O
n   noTone()
n   pulseIn()
n   pulseInLong()
n   shiftIn()
n   shiftOut()
n   tone()
Time
y   delay()
y   delayMicroseconds()
y   micros()
y   millis()
Math
y   abs()
y   constrain()
y   map()
y   max()
y   min()
y   pow()
y   sq()
y   sqrt()
Trigonometry
y   cos()
y   sin()
y   tan()
Characters
n   isAlpha()
n   isAlphaNumeric()
n   isAscii()
n   isControl()
n   isDigit()
n   isGraph()
n   isHexadecimalDigit()
n   isLowerCase()
n   isPrintable()
n   isPunct()
n   isSpace()
n   isUpperCase()
n   isWhitespace()
Random Numbers
n   random()
n   randomSeed()
Bits and Bytes
y   bit()
y   bitClear()
y   bitRead()
y   bitSet()
y   bitWrite()
y   highByte()
y   lowByte()
External Interrupts
y   attachInterrupt()
y   detachInterrupt()
Interrupts
y   interrupts()
y   noInterrupts()
Communication
y*  Serial
y   Stream
USB
n   Keyboard
n   Mouse

*   Not exposed in the demo web app.
*   Not exposed in the demo web app.</code></pre>



<p>The Wasmino Arduino core is available at <a href="https://github.com/wasmino/wasmino-core">https://github.com/wasmino/wasmino-core</a>.</p>



<p>The runtime is also available at <a href="https://github.com/wasmino/wasmino-runtime">https://github.com/wasmino/wasmino-runtime</a>.</p>




	</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->

				
</article><!-- #post-${ID} -->

	<nav role="navigation" aria-label="Posts">
		<h2>Post navigation</h2>
		
	</nav>
<!-- #comments -->

		</main><!-- #main -->
	</section><!-- #primary -->


	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.yifangu.com/2020/12/30/wasmino-wasm-arduino-running-arduino-code-in-browser/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25581081</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 12:26:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Emotional headlines have an impact regardless of the credibility of the source]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 231 | Comments 84 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25581064">thread link</a>) | @rustoo
<br/>
December 30, 2020 | https://www.hu-berlin.de/en/press-portal/nachrichten-en/december-2020/nr-201221 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.hu-berlin.de/en/press-portal/nachrichten-en/december-2020/nr-201221">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><span><span><span><span lang="EN-GB" xml:lang="EN-GB">Neurocognitive studies by researchers at the Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin (HU) show that headlines with emotional content influence our judgments about other people even when we consider the media source to be untrustworthy.</span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span lang="EN-GB" xml:lang="EN-GB">Rumours, half-truths and misinformation can be consumed and shared non-stop online and have an enormous reach. Although their truthfulness is questionable, they can have a significant impact on personal opinions and public discourse. Until now, however, little was known about the consequences of confrontation with such information on how it is processed in our brains and to what extent this neural process influences our judgments. New findings from neurocognitive psychology show that emotionally charged headlines exert a major influence on the way we process information and form judgments of others, even when we do not consider the news source credible.&nbsp; </span></span></span></span></p>

<h3><span><span><span>Exposure to headlines from trustworthy and untrustworthy sources</span></span></span></h3>

<p><span><span><span><span lang="EN-GB" xml:lang="EN-GB">The credibility we ascribe to news sources seems to be a simple cue for judging or classifying the truthfulness of information. But does such classification also protect us from the influence of emotional headlines? To investigate this, subjects in the study by the Berlin School of Mind and Brain and the HU’s Department of Psychology were confronted with fictitious headlines in the particular online layouts of well-known German media sources. There, they read headlines with social-emotional or comparatively neutral information about fictitious persons. For example, one person was reported to have embezzled tax revenues and another, to have shown outstanding civil courage. After a short break, the brain activity of the subjects was measured while they judged the persons presented on the basis of their faces. </span></span></span></span></p>

<h3><span><span><span>Emotions influence our judgments – the credibility of the media source has no effect</span></span></span></h3>

<p><span><span><span><span lang="EN-GB" xml:lang="EN-GB">Although the participants rated the media sources as having different levels of credibility, these ratings did not play a role in the formation of their opinions. The emotional content of the headlines, on the other hand, had a strong impact on their judgments: even when subjects did not trust a news source, they made extreme judgments about people whose negative or positive behaviour was reported in the headlines. Participants rated people whose behaviour was described as negative as unlikable and negative, while they rated people who made headlines due to good deeds as very likable and positive.&nbsp; </span></span></span></span></p>

<h3><span><span><span>Brain activity shows the impact of emotional headlines</span></span></span></h3>

<p><span><span><span><span lang="EN-GB" xml:lang="EN-GB">The subjects' brain activity was recorded using an electroencephalogram (EEG) while they made judgments about the individuals. Fast, involuntary brain responses can be distinguished here from slower, more controlled responses. The researchers had expected the latter to involve consideration of the source's credibility in addition to emotion, and thus that credibility might factor into people’s judgments, whereas emotion should dominate in early and more involuntary responses. However, both late and early brain responses showed dominant influences of headline emotionality independent of credibility. </span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span lang="EN-GB" xml:lang="EN-GB">These new findings show that news content that triggers emotions such as excitement or outrage does not simply bounce off us, even when the trustworthiness of the source is judged to be low. Rather, reservations about the reliability of a source have no effect when emotional content dominates our judgment. Recognising and further exploring these consequences of emotionally charged news is an essential first step in protecting against the potentially damaging ramifications of rumours, half-truths, and misinformation. </span></span></span></span></p>

<h3><span><span><span>Publication </span></span></span></h3>

<p><span><span><span><span>Baum, J. &amp; Abdel Rahman, R. (2020). </span><span lang="EN-GB" xml:lang="EN-GB">Emotional news affects social judgments independent of perceived media credibility. <i>Social Cognitive and Affective Neuroscience</i>. <a href="http://doi.org/10.1093/scan/nsaa164">http://doi.org/10.1093/scan/nsaa164</a> </span></span></span></span></p>

<h3><span><span><span>Contact </span></span></span></h3>

<p><span><span><span><span lang="EN-GB" xml:lang="EN-GB"><strong>Prof. Dr Rasha Abdel Rahman</strong><br>
Neurocognitive Psychology<br>
Department of Psychology<br>
<a href="mailto:rasha.abdel.rahman@hu-berlin.de">rasha.abdel.rahman@hu-berlin.de</a> &nbsp;<br>
Tel.: 030 2093-9413</span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><strong>Julia Baum</strong><br>
Neurocognitive Psychology<br>
Department of Psychology<br>
<a href="mailto:julia.baum@hu-berlin.de">julia.baum@hu-berlin.de</a></span></span></p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.hu-berlin.de/en/press-portal/nachrichten-en/december-2020/nr-201221</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25581064</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 12:23:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Virtualize Your Network on FreeBSD with VNET]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 85 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25580286">thread link</a>) | @vermaden
<br/>
December 30, 2020 | https://klarasystems.com/articles/virtualize-your-network-on-freebsd-with-vnet/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://klarasystems.com/articles/virtualize-your-network-on-freebsd-with-vnet/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>




<div>
<h2><strong>FreeBSD Jails are a well-known feature and have become core to many excellent tools on FreeBSD such as the Poudriere package builder. Jails offer process and file system isolation, but for a long time they did not offer very satisfying network isolation. VIMAGE provides isolation for networking through virtual network stacks or VNET.</strong></h2>



<p>VIMAGE was first presented in the Paper <a href="https://papers.freebsd.org/2003/zec-vimage/">“Implementing a Clonable Network Stack in the FreeBSD Kernel” by Macro Zec in 2003</a> and VIMAGE code appeared first in FreeBSD 8.0, however it wasn’t until FreeBSD 12.0 that VIMAGE was built into FreeBSD GENERIC kernels and it is a bit of an overlooked feature.</p>



<p>If you have used jails before you might wonder what more VNET jails offer or why you would want to migrate from using localhost-based networking. VNET jails give each jail its own isolated copy of the network stack. They get everything from the IP layer up, creating a network stack that is entirely its own, almost anything you could do with a distinct host you can do with a jail and VNET.</p>



<p>VNET network stacks can be given interfaces from the host and once an interface has been delegated into a VNET jail it disappears from the view of the host, becoming only visible in the jail. FreeBSD offers the epair interface that acts as a virtual Ethernet cable. Give one end of an epair to a VNET jail and keep the other end in the host and you have a way to network between the host and the jail or even between multiple jails. Unlike normal jail networking a VNET jail is able to fully use the interface and once given the correct permissions it can perform packet captures and traces as if it were a full host.</p>



<p>VNET allows jails to be closer to full virtual machines with much less overhead and they offer the ability to test networking in isolation with a very similar environment to the jail host.</p>



<h4><strong>Using VNET with a jail</strong></h4>



<p>The best way to experiment with VNET is to create some test jails and play with their networks. With VNET it is easy and cheap to create a new separate network that will not interfere with the hosts configuration.</p>



<p>First to demonstrate the power the VNET provides we will create a simple jail that only isolates networking from the host. If we run the following three commands on a FreeBSD system we can create a simple jail:</p>



<pre><code>    host # jail -c name=emptyjail persist vnet
    host # jexec emptyjail /bin/sh
    emptyjail # ifconfig
    lo0: flags=8008&lt;LOOPBACK,MULTICAST&gt; metric 0 mtu 16384
    options=680003&lt;RXCSUM,TXCSUM,LINKSTATE,RXCSUM_IPV6,TXCSUM_IPV6&gt;
    groups: lo
    nd6 options=21&lt;PERFORMNUD,AUTO_LINKLOCAL&gt;
</code></pre>



<p>The important flags to the jail command here are <em>persist</em> and <em>vnet</em>, <em>persist</em> keeps the jail around even though nothing is running inside of it, <em>vnet</em> creates the jail with its own VIMAGE network stack.</p>



<p>The jail we have created contains a loop back interface (lo0) but cannot see any of the interfaces from the host, it has been isolated at the network and process level. Because we do not specify a new root to use for the jails file system, it can see everything on the host file system as before, this can be really handy when you are developing and running tests that take advantage of VNET.</p>



<p>For our jail to be useful we need to be able to access network interfaces, VNET jails can be given any interface and once given to a jail they vanish from the view of the host network stack. When we want to network between the host and the jail we can use an epair(4) device. epair devices are a pair of Ethernet-like interfaces connected back to back, sort of like an emulated patch cable. Each side is denoted with a letter, they come as an ‘a’ and a ‘b’ part. If we create an epair and move one half into the jail, once it is configured we can communicate from the host to the jail.</p>



<pre><code>    host # ja    host # ifconfig epair create
    epair0a
    host # ifconfig
    lo0: flags=8049&lt;UP,LOOPBACK,RUNNING,MULTICAST&gt; metric 0 mtu 16384
            options=680003&lt;RXCSUM,TXCSUM,LINKSTATE,RXCSUM_IPV6,TXCSUM_IPV6&gt;
            inet6 ::1 prefixlen 128
            inet6 fe80::1%lo0 prefixlen 64 scopeid 0x2
            inet 127.0.0.1 netmask 0xff000000
            groups: lo
            nd6 options=21&lt;PERFORMNUD,AUTO_LINKLOCAL&gt;
    epair0a: flags=8842&lt;BROADCAST,RUNNING,SIMPLEX,MULTICAST&gt; metric 0 mtu 1500
            options=8&lt;VLAN_MTU&gt;
            ether 02:c5:7b:f8:1e:0a
            groups: epair
            media: Ethernet 10Gbase-T (10Gbase-T &lt;full-duplex&gt;)
            status: active
            nd6 options=29&lt;PERFORMNUD,IFDISABLED,AUTO_LINKLOCAL&gt;
    epair0b: flags=8842&lt;BROADCAST,RUNNING,SIMPLEX,MULTICAST&gt; metric 0 mtu 1500
            options=8&lt;VLAN_MTU&gt;
            ether 02:c5:7b:f8:1e:0b
            groups: epair
            media: Ethernet 10Gbase-T (10Gbase-T &lt;full-duplex&gt;)
            status: active
            nd6 options=29&lt;PERFORMNUD,IFDISABLED,AUTO_LINKLOCAL&gt;
</code></pre>



<p>This time when we create our jail we delegate one half of the epair to it. We need to configure the interface in the jail and on the host. Once we have the interfaces configured we can communicate between the host and jail (Note: when you delegate an interface to a jail all the configuration will be erased. You must configure the interface once it is inside the jail).</p>



<pre><code>    host # jail -c name=networkjail persist vnet vnet.interface=epair0b 
    host # jexec networkjail /bin/sh

    networkjail # ifconfig
    lo0: flags=8008&lt;LOOPBACK,MULTICAST&gt; metric 0 mtu 16384
            options=680003&lt;RXCSUM,TXCSUM,LINKSTATE,RXCSUM_IPV6,TXCSUM_IPV6&gt;
            groups: lo
            nd6 options=21&lt;PERFORMNUD,AUTO_LINKLOCAL&gt;
    epair0b: flags=8842&lt;BROADCAST,RUNNING,SIMPLEX,MULTICAST&gt; metric 0 mtu 1500
            options=8&lt;VLAN_MTU&gt;
            ether 02:c5:7b:f8:1e:0b
            groups: epair
            media: Ethernet 10Gbase-T (10Gbase-T &lt;full-duplex&gt;)
            status: active
            nd6 options=21&lt;PERFORMNUD,AUTO_LINKLOCAL&gt;
    networkjail # ifconfig epair0b inet 192.0.2.2/24 up     
    networkjail # exit

    host # ifconfig epair0a inet 192.0.2.1/24 up
    host # ping 192.0.2.2
    PING 192.0.2.2 (192.0.2.2): 56 data bytes
    64 bytes from 192.0.2.2: icmp_seq=0 ttl=64 time=0.143 ms
    64 bytes from 192.0.2.2: icmp_seq=1 ttl=64 time=0.069 ms
    ^C
    --- 192.0.2.2 ping statistics ---
    2 packets transmitted, 2 packets received, 0.0% packet loss
    round-trip min/avg/max/stddev = 0.069/0.106/0.143/0.037 ms
</code></pre>



<p>Python3 is installed on the host and as our jail doesn’t isolate the file system, all installed software is also available to the jail. We can use the http server built in to python3 to demonstrate a simple network service running inside the jail.</p>



<pre><code>    host # jexec networkjail sh -c "cd /usr/src; python3 -m http.server" 
    Serving HTTP on 0.0.0.0 port 8000 (http://0.0.0.0:8000/) ...
</code></pre>



<p>With this a web browser on the host machine can be pointed at 192.0.2.2:8000 and we can browse around the structure of the FreeBSD source tree that lives in /usr/src. We can run any service that will run on a FreeBSD host from within this VNET jail. The difference here between older jail networking is that we can do anything with the epair that we could do with a real network interface such as place add it to a bridge.</p>



<p>When we remove networkjail the half of the epair that was delegated is returned to the host:</p>



<pre><code>    host # ifconfig epair0b
    ifconfig: interface epair0b does not exist
    host # jls -v
       JID  Hostname                      Path
            Name                          State
            CPUSetID
            IP Address(es)
         1                                /
            networkjail                   ACTIVE
            3
    host # jail -r networkjail
    host # ifconfig epair0b
    epair0b: flags=8842&lt;BROADCAST,RUNNING,SIMPLEX,MULTICAST&gt; metric 0 mtu 1500
            options=8&lt;VLAN_MTU&gt;
            ether 02:c5:7b:f8:1e:0b
            groups: epair
            media: Ethernet 10Gbase-T (10Gbase-T &lt;full-duplex&gt;)
            status: active
            nd6 options=21&lt;PERFORMNUD,AUTO_LINKLOCAL&gt;
</code></pre>



<p>When we destroy either half of the epair both halves will be removed from the system, even if the side delegated to a jail.</p>



<p>VNET offers a facility for local testing with a network segment that is very similar to a real network. It is possible to perform any action from the host as you would on a non-virtual network interface such as adding it to a bridge or firewalling.</p>



<h4><strong>Using VNET to isolate networks</strong></h4>



<p>We are not limited to using virtual interfaces when using VNET, but are able to delegate any interface on the host into the VNET. VNET opens up the opportunity to isolate out chunks of networks allowing us to build complex topologies such as soft routers and firewalls.</p>



<p>We can also use the isolation offered by VNET to offer services from a host on a particular interface that might be undesirable or destructive or if the address space that a piece of equipment uses clashes with the network that the host is on.</p>



<p>On this development machine we have network interfaces on two different networks, one is in the development environment and the other lives in the sandbox testing environment. Never can packets go between the two. The sandbox testing network is where virtual machines live, normally these bhyve machines are configured with a tap interface and they join the network via a bridge interface on the host. VNET allows us to do the same thing, but with jails.</p>



<p>Before we start we need to load the kernel modules for epair and bridge on the host, they normally load automatically on the host when you try to use them, but the jail is unable to do this.</p>



<pre><code>    host # kldload if_epair if_bridge</code></pre>



<p>VNET also allows us to give a physical network interface on the development host to a jail and from that jail create further sub VNET jails that are isolated from the hosts network:</p>



<pre><code>    host # jail -c name=isojail persist vnet vnet.interface=em0 children.max=1</code></pre>



<p>This time we create …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://klarasystems.com/articles/virtualize-your-network-on-freebsd-with-vnet/">https://klarasystems.com/articles/virtualize-your-network-on-freebsd-with-vnet/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://klarasystems.com/articles/virtualize-your-network-on-freebsd-with-vnet/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25580286</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 10:00:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ACE: Apple Type-C Port Controller Secrets]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 274 | Comments 124 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25579286">thread link</a>) | @aunali1
<br/>
December 29, 2020 | https://blog.t8012.dev/ace-part-1/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.t8012.dev/ace-part-1/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">
<div>
<article>

<figure>
<img srcset="https://blog.t8012.dev/content/images/size/w300/2020/12/s-l400.jpg 300w,
                            https://blog.t8012.dev/content/images/size/w600/2020/12/s-l400.jpg 600w,
                            https://blog.t8012.dev/content/images/size/w1000/2020/12/s-l400.jpg 1000w,
                            https://blog.t8012.dev/content/images/size/w2000/2020/12/s-l400.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 400px,
                        (max-width: 1170px) 1170px,
                            2000px" src="https://blog.t8012.dev/content/images/size/w2000/2020/12/s-l400.jpg" alt="ACE: Apple Type-C Port Controller Secrets | Part 1">
</figure>
<section>
<div>
<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2><p>After our team successfully <a href="https://www.theiphonewiki.com/wiki/T8012#Bootrom_Exploits">ported</a> the <a href="https://www.theiphonewiki.com/wiki/Checkm8_Exploit">checkm8</a> exploit to the AppleSilicon T2 chip, we began exploring methods for closed-case hardware debugging, or CCD, as found on other iDevices. On such devices, the <a href="https://developer.arm.com/architectures/cpu-architecture/debug-visibility-and-trace/coresight-architecture/serial-wire-debug">Serial Wire Debug</a> protocol can be muxed out across the Lightning connector, which we presumed was replicable across the USB Type-C connector. With some assistance from easily obtainable schematics for our MacBook models, we have determined that muxing is handled by an Apple/TI co-designed <a href="https://www.usb.org/document-library/usb-type-cr-port-controller-interface-specification">USB Type-C Port Controller</a>, colloquially known as "ACE". The following details our findings and the vendor defined protocol, termed AppleVDM, Apple has implemented over the USB Power Delivery standard for muxing out various internal peripherals.</p><p>A member of our team, @h0m3us3r has dumped the ACE firmware by attaching a SWD probe onto exposed test points on the logic board of a MacBook Pro. Thanks to this we were able to obtain both the ROM and the firmware payload patch applied over it and discover that the ACE chip contains a <code><a href="https://developer.arm.com/ip-products/processors/cortex-m/cortex-m0">Cortex-M0 r0p1</a></code> ARM core. Most of the static analysis was later conducted by @mrarm.</p><pre><code>Connecting to target via SWD
Found SW-DP with ID 0x0BC11477
DPIDR: 0x0BC11477
Scanning AP map to find all available APs
AP[1]: Stopped AP scan as end of AP map has been reached
AP[0]: AHB-AP (IDR: 0x04770031)
Iterating through AP map to find AHB-AP to use
AP[0]: Core found
AP[0]: AHB-AP ROM base: 0xE00FF000
CPUID register: 0x410CC601. Implementer code: 0x41 (ARM)
Found Cortex-M0 r0p1, Little endian.
FPUnit: 4 code (BP) slots and 0 literal slots
CoreSight components:
ROMTbl[0] @ E00FF000
ROMTbl[0][0]: E000E000, CID: B105E00D, PID: 000BB008 SCS
ROMTbl[0][1]: E0001000, CID: B105E00D, PID: 000BB00A DWT
ROMTbl[0][2]: E0002000, CID: B105E00D, PID: 000BB00B FPB
Cortex-M0 identified.
</code></pre>
<center>Segger J-Link Probe output when attached to ACE2 (CD3217).</center><h2 id="ace-overview">ACE Overview</h2><p>To better understand the inner-workings of ACE, we began looking for identifying information within the dumped firmware. We found the string <code>CD3217 &nbsp; HW0022 FW002.032.00 ZACE2-J213</code> and upon searching <code>CD3217</code> online resulted in the similar <a href="https://www.ti.com/lit/ds/symlink/tps65986.pdf">TI TPS65986</a>. Based on how similar the functional description of the aforementioned TI USB Type-C Controller is to ACE, and considering that TI co-designed ACE with Apple, it was reasonable to assume most of the technical information applies to ACE.</p><p>TI's USB Type-C Controllers expose an I²C interface for host management, for which we found the excellent <a href="https://www.ti.com/lit/ug/slvuan1a/slvuan1a.pdf">Host Interface Technical Reference Manual</a>, documenting a multitude of public I²C registers and commands.</p><figure><img src="https://blog.t8012.dev/content/images/2020/12/image.png" alt="" srcset="https://blog.t8012.dev/content/images/size/w600/2020/12/image.png 600w, https://blog.t8012.dev/content/images/size/w1000/2020/12/image.png 1000w, https://blog.t8012.dev/content/images/2020/12/image.png 1330w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption>TPS65986 Functional Block Diagram</figcaption></figure><p>The primary component of focus based on the above block diagram is the digital core, which communicates directly with the host and runs the firmware we dumped previously. As mentioned, the core is based on a <code>Cortex-M0 r0p1</code>. Unfortunately, we were unable to create a complete memory map with peripherals as TI does not release public information on the core itself. Regardless, we have the basic memory layout as follows:</p><p>Since we weren't sure whether the code for muxing out things lives in the ACE or somewhere else (there are registers for receiving vendor messages and processing them on another chip), we also investigated the firmware of chips that can directly communicate with the ACE, the SMC, part of T2 SoC, and the Thunderbolt controller. While we obtained and analyzed the I2C usages in the SMC firmware and found no suspicious code whatsoever, we had issues with analyzing the Thunderbolt controller firmware and decided to only reverse engineer it as a last resort. We initially thought that the only way that we could talk with the ACE from Mac OS (Intel) was by modifying the SMC firmware to relay commands to the ACE. While we have successfully managed to edit the SMC firmware and talk with the ACE, it turned out that this effort wasn't needed. Later we stumbled upon the following project: <a href="https://github.com/osy/ThunderboltPatcher">https://github.com/osy/ThunderboltPatcher</a>, which uses the AppleHPM kext in order to communicate with the ACE.</p><p>The AppleHPM KEXT allows a user space program running as root to read and write ACE registers. It also has several interesting methods that seem to be intended for reading and writing registers on ACEs connected using a USB Type-C cable to the DUT. Unfortunately, while we tried invoking them, we didn't manage to get these methods working, suggesting that either they have been disabled on production hardware or need some more preparation work in order to work. We also discovered that there exists an EFI mode firmware updater for the ACE called <code>HPMUtil.efi</code>, which we also partially reverse engineered. There seems to be several methods of updating the ACEs depending on the hardware revision; the EFI program also seems to have an argument that makes it update externally connected ACEs, however at least for recent ACEs it seems to be broken; the only update route that would work on the firmware dump we obtained from our Mac (based on available commands) seems to be hardcoded in a few places to run commands on the local ACE.</p><p>There are at least 3 known revisions of the ACE chip. Based on hardware available to us, the first variant, ACE1, is known to be used in 2018 and older T2 models, the second, ACE2, in 2019 and newer T2 models, and the third in 2020 M1 enabled laptops. The software update method differs significantly between ACE1 and ACE2. At the time of writing the article, we have only successfully dumped a single ACE firmware (ACE2) and all the analysis here is based on that version.</p><h2 id="usb-pd">USB PD</h2><p>The logical channel for telling the Mac to mux out something other than USB from the chip would be USB PD, since ACE's main communication vector with external devices is USB PD and because controlling data lines using USB PD is a widespread practice (see: MIPI debug interface as well as this article on getting UART off an Samsung phone: <a href="https://ntnuopen.ntnu.no/ntnu-xmlui/bitstream/handle/11250/2632162/bookchapter.pdf">https://ntnuopen.ntnu.no/ntnu-xmlui/bitstream/handle/11250/2632162/bookchapter.pdf</a>). This TI-derived controller can be configured to support some variant of MIPI debug mode by default (and the MIPI debug ID is present in the Apple ACE firmware as well), however as we discovered later it is disabled in Apple's configuration and can not be used. As such, we decided to look for other Vendor Defined Messages that the ACE understands.</p><p>In the USB PD protocol, entering a vendor mode begins by sending a SVID (Standard ID or Vendor ID, usually the vendor's USB VID) and object position (think of it as a sub mode that the vendor can define). By analyzing the ACE firmware we found at least 3 possible object positions under the Apple SVID, however their availability is dynamic and by default only a single SVID and object position is available. This primary mode is, for example, used when the Apple's charger is connected. We are not sure when the other modes are activated and plan to do further work related to figuring out what the purpose of these other modes is.</p><p>Since it would be logical if there was a reply for the command for entering a mode and also because reverse engineering an embedded firmware with no context whatsoever is hard, we decided to look into the <code>VDMs</code> command, which can be used to send a VDM PD message. This allowed us to gather important information about the firmware's inner workings and also to find a few functions that sent a message with Apple's vendor ID. We investigated several of these, some of them were indeed related to the protocol used with the charger (which we aren't sure what the purpose of is; however from what it seems it can be only used to read some memory sections from the external device), but we also found another procedure that had three cases, two of which replied with 16-bit values (created from information from a particular memory area) in a similar way to the Discover SVIDs VDM, and one of them was complex and handled additional logic. We investigated it further and eventually managed to use it to mux things out of the controller.</p><p>Another possible use of the <code>VDMs</code> command can be found in the AppleHPM KEXT and the <code>HPLUtil.efi</code> program, which is reading registers from externally connected devices. Since we haven't given much attention to it as it was not our goal and our experiments were a failure, we are not going to describe it in this article.</p><p>Note that since SWD can also be muxed from the ACE, further reverse engineering ACE modes is not that interesting; you should be able to use the ACE's SWD to trigger any mux choice of your choosing and directly talk to all peripherals ACE has access to.</p><h2 id="dive-into-the-code">Dive into the code</h2><p>With @h0m3us3r's dump of ROM and RAM memory, we started by loading the ACE firmware in IDA. The reset handler address is present at <code>0x00000004</code> and can be used to get the address of the entrypoint.</p><p>The command table can be trivially found by looking for the 4 character codes. Register table requires a bit more effort but is also not hard to find (since there is a register that is a string, you can find what references it). In comparison to the public TI documentation, there are substantially more commands and registers available, some of which are Apple-specific additions. Since the firmware has barely any strings or debug information, the command list has been very helpful.</p><p>After initially exploring the firmware we quickly stumbled upon cursed looking trampolines such as the following:</p><pre><code>ROM:000266C2 _Command_HRST                           ; DATA XREF: ROM:commandsâ†“o
ROM:000266C2
ROM:000266C2
ROM:000266C2                 PUSH            {R4-R6,LR}
ROM:000266C4                 MOV             R4, R1
ROM:000266C6                 MOV             R5, R0
ROM:000266C8                 BL              sub_E4
ROM:000266CC                 LDR             R0, =dword_20041040
ROM:000266CE                 MOV             R1, R4
ROM:000266D0                 ADDS            R0, #0x40 ; '@'
ROM:000266D2                 LDR             R2, [R0]
ROM:000266D4                 MOV             R0, R5
ROM:000266D6                …</code></pre></div></section></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.t8012.dev/ace-part-1/">https://blog.t8012.dev/ace-part-1/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.t8012.dev/ace-part-1/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25579286</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 06:49:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Candymail – Email Automation for Node.js]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 85 | Comments 53 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25578834">thread link</a>) | @sssaini
<br/>
December 29, 2020 | https://saasbase.dev/candymail | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://saasbase.dev/candymail">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><article id="block-candymail"><p><span><span>CandyMail makes it easy to trigger and send multi-step email sequences in Node.js using a single JSON file. Built for bootstrappers, indie makers with special care.</span></span></p><div id="block-a7a22de82c9f4f61a9581a647e597231"><div><p><img alt="image" src="https://saasbase.dev/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.super.so%2Fasset%2Fsaasbase.dev%2F638675a6-a551-47cc-b24f-892b2cff969e.png&amp;w=1080&amp;q=100" srcset="https://saasbase.dev/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.super.so%2Fasset%2Fsaasbase.dev%2F638675a6-a551-47cc-b24f-892b2cff969e.png&amp;w=640&amp;q=100 1x, https://saasbase.dev/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.super.so%2Fasset%2Fsaasbase.dev%2F638675a6-a551-47cc-b24f-892b2cff969e.png&amp;w=1080&amp;q=100 2x" decoding="async"></p></div></div><h2 id="block-f23dcaeb10b744778d2080a9d073d409"><span id="f23dcaeb10b744778d2080a9d073d409"></span><span><span><strong>Features</strong></span></span></h2><ol><li id="block-45aa8049a4cf4dfa90441e2d4a931dc9"><span><span><strong>Portable</strong></span><span>: Create, share and reuse email marketing strategies between different products</span></span></li><li id="block-04009c38a7d743eb85e3206079018bf7"><span><span><strong>Simple to use</strong></span><span>: Time to send, subject, body of the emails can all be set up in a single JSON file</span></span></li><li id="block-a64766efe6574cc9b4c72db02135e034"><span><span><strong>Free</strong></span><span>: No need to pay for monthly Mailchimp etc. payments for email automation plans</span></span></li></ol><h2 id="block-5ab828b20084466c9a9655231ea704e7"><span id="5ab828b20084466c9a9655231ea704e7"></span><span><span><strong>Use Cases</strong></span></span></h2><ul><li id="block-c44e7c12446340988c153bfdfe2d4487"><span><span>Build better onboarding by guiding the user through the app with paced training emails</span></span></li><li id="block-04216dfc690441ccbc29f2c49eb56297"><span><span>Reduce churn by sending exciting community content every few days</span></span></li><li id="block-20f9940a1ef542958ad8c5faa7b5be4c"><span><span>Convert more customers to paid plans by offering discounts based on the user's usage activity</span></span></li></ul><h2 id="block-ebb2664d7aff451b83ee65168e44bbc8"><span id="ebb2664d7aff451b83ee65168e44bbc8"></span><span><span><strong>Installation</strong></span></span></h2><p><span><span>Install candymail using yarn:</span></span></p><p><span><span>Or npm:</span></span></p><div id="block-3b1e9c2a5b5442d99676426c2499d03f"><pre><code><span>npm install --save candymail</span></code></pre><figcaption><span></span></figcaption></div><h2 id="block-dafd20b6db8f4fa495bcc253547865b6"><span id="dafd20b6db8f4fa495bcc253547865b6"></span><span><span><strong>Getting Started</strong></span></span></h2><h3 id="block-427f998161b748f498f9b6cbc5ced03a"><span id="427f998161b748f498f9b6cbc5ced03a"></span><span><span><strong>Configuration</strong></span></span></h3><p><span><span>Create a&nbsp;</span><span><code>candymail.automation.json</code></span><span>&nbsp;file on the root level of your project.</span></span></p><p><span><span>Here's a sample:</span></span></p><div id="block-e0c98a5f7c5241d4bbe3eb12f1e5696c"><pre><code><span>{</span><span>
</span><span>  </span><span>"automations"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>[</span><span>
</span><span>    </span><span>{</span><span>
</span><span>      </span><span>"name"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"automation1"</span><span>,</span><span>
</span><span>      </span><span>"description"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"tell users about pro features"</span><span>,</span><span>
</span><span>      </span><span>"trigger_name"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"proplan"</span><span>,</span><span>
</span><span>      </span><span>"emails"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>[</span><span>
</span><span>        </span><span>{</span><span>
</span><span>          </span><span>"trigger"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"time"</span><span>,</span><span>
</span><span>          </span><span>"sendDelay"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>1</span><span>,</span><span>
</span><span>          </span><span>"subject"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"Have you tried Feature A?"</span><span>,</span><span>
</span><span>          </span><span>"body"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"Feature A will let you do ABC things. Check it out!"</span><span>,</span><span>
</span><span>          </span><span>"from"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"abc@gmail.com"</span><span>
</span><span>        </span><span>}</span><span>,</span><span>
</span><span>        </span><span>{</span><span>
</span><span>          </span><span>"trigger"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"time"</span><span>,</span><span>
</span><span>          </span><span>"sendDelay"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>3</span><span>,</span><span>
</span><span>          </span><span>"subject"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"Try our feature B!"</span><span>,</span><span>
</span><span>          </span><span>"body"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"We released feature B just last week and can't wait for you to try it out :)"</span><span>,</span><span>
</span><span>          </span><span>"from"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"abc@gmail.com"</span><span>
</span><span>        </span><span>}</span><span>
</span><span>      </span><span>]</span><span>
</span><span>    </span><span>}</span><span>
</span><span>  </span><span>]</span><span>
</span><span></span><span>}</span><span>
</span>
</code></pre><figcaption><span></span></figcaption></div><h3 id="block-4016925d0984430085d1ad2a72663cce"><span id="4016925d0984430085d1ad2a72663cce"></span><span><span><strong>Supported Email Providers</strong></span></span></h3><ul><li id="block-d88924222cb4409b9a8d37f5c3a28ed0"><span><span>Gmail</span></span></li><li id="block-1df81b4e29f54e25944ccc0e93ef641d"><span><span>Looking for more support? Send me a message.</span></span></li></ul><h3 id="block-82f3fafe4e084cb7af5c77bca9444d1d"><span id="82f3fafe4e084cb7af5c77bca9444d1d"></span><span><span><strong>Usage</strong></span></span></h3><div id="block-8d7360b2d2d045448baf1ed1063f3e13"><pre><code><span>const</span><span> path </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>require</span><span>(</span><span>'path'</span><span>)</span><span>
</span><span></span><span>const</span><span> candymail </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>require</span><span>(</span><span>'candymail'</span><span>)</span><span>
</span>
<span></span><span>const</span><span> automationPath </span><span>=</span><span> path</span><span>.</span><span>resolve</span><span>(</span><span>'candymail.automation.json'</span><span>)</span><span>
</span>
<span>candymail</span><span>.</span><span>init</span><span>(</span><span>automationPath</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span>
</span><span>  senderEmail</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>**</span><span>GMAILEMAIL</span><span>**</span><span>,</span><span>
</span><span>  senderPassword</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>**</span><span>GMAILPASSWORD</span><span>**</span><span>
</span><span></span><span>}</span><span>)</span><span>
</span>
<span>candymail</span><span>.</span><span>start</span><span>(</span><span>)</span><span>
</span>
<span></span><span>const</span><span> user </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>'howivey729@chatdays.com'</span><span>
</span><span>candymail</span><span>.</span><span>runAutomation</span><span>(</span><span>'automation1'</span><span>,</span><span> user</span><span>)</span><span>
</span>
<span></span><span>console</span><span>.</span><span>log</span><span>(</span><span>'Emails added to queue'</span><span>,</span><span> candymail</span><span>.</span><span>getAllScheduledMessages</span><span>(</span><span>)</span><span>)</span><span>
</span>
</code></pre><figcaption><span></span></figcaption></div><p><span><span>Note: Having problems with Gmail? Enable&nbsp;</span><span><code>Allow less secure apps</code></span><span>&nbsp;in Google Account settings&nbsp;</span><span><a href="https://myaccount.google.com/lesssecureapps" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a></span><span>.</span></span></p><h2 id="block-8905c8f6ec90428290f752898c389144"><span id="8905c8f6ec90428290f752898c389144"></span><span><span><strong>Automation File Options</strong></span></span></h2><div id="block-92d9833cf5bd44c895eee0027a1111fc"><div><table><thead><tr><th>Property</th><th>Required</th><th>Description</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p><span><span>trigger</span></span></p></td><td></td><td><p><span><span>Name of the trigger (Not usable)</span></span></p></td></tr><tr><td><p><span><span>sendDelay</span></span></p></td><td><div></div></td><td><p><span><span>Delay after which the email will be sent (in hours). From time 0, not from the last email</span></span></p></td></tr><tr><td><p><span><span>subject</span></span></p></td><td><div></div></td><td><p><span><span>Subject of the email</span></span></p></td></tr><tr><td><p><span><span>body</span></span></p></td><td><div></div></td><td><p><span><span>Body of the email</span></span></p></td></tr><tr><td><p><span><span>from</span></span></p></td><td><div></div></td><td><p><span><span>Sender's Email Address</span></span></p></td></tr></tbody></table></div></div><h2 id="block-9aac3da583924daf892d731f0ae707ed"><span id="9aac3da583924daf892d731f0ae707ed"></span><span><span><strong>Methods</strong></span></span></h2><h3 id="block-aa32ddc39a3949d99452397186c7f687"><span id="aa32ddc39a3949d99452397186c7f687"></span><span><span><strong>init (automationPath, config)</strong></span></span></h3><p><span><span>Initializes automations specified in the automation path and sets the configuration with sender's email and password.</span></span></p><ul><li id="block-1394bdb55dd148f9a9f5e08a65240a86"><span><span><strong>automationPath</strong></span><span>: Absolute path to the candymail.automation.json file. Example:&nbsp;</span><span><code>path.resolve('example', 'candymail.automation.json')</code></span><span>&nbsp;if the file is located at&nbsp;</span><span><code>ROOT*/example/candymail.automation.json</code></span><span>.</span></span></li><li id="block-35edceb8c19b427fa7f45d1de635de7a"><span><span><strong>config</strong></span><span>:&nbsp;</span><span><code>{ senderEmail -&gt; Gmail Address of the sender, senderPassword -&gt; Gmail Password of the sender }</code></span></span></li></ul><h3 id="block-86ce155fe82047cbaed3aab4820b7c4b"><span id="86ce155fe82047cbaed3aab4820b7c4b"></span><span><span><strong>start()</strong></span></span></h3><p><span><span>Starts the internal timer that will send emails at appropriate times.</span></span></p><h3 id="block-ca0e460e1f5a4dc28c00e2234cbcbfce"><span id="ca0e460e1f5a4dc28c00e2234cbcbfce"></span><span><span><strong>runAutomation(automationName)</strong></span></span></h3><p><span><span>Triggers an automation based on&nbsp;</span><span><code>name</code></span><span>&nbsp;specified in the&nbsp;</span><span><code>candymail.automation.json</code></span><span>&nbsp;file. Needs&nbsp;</span><span><code>candymail.start()</code></span><span>&nbsp;to have been called.</span></span></p><ul><li id="block-9d31ffa059614958b3e26dab0fa275ae"><span><span><strong>automationName</strong></span><span>: Name of&nbsp;</span><span><code>automation</code></span><span>&nbsp;in&nbsp;</span><span><code>candymail.automation.json</code></span><span>. Example: 'automation1'.</span></span></li></ul><h3 id="block-08de5de186f546e6b619a4028cd9b4d1"><span id="08de5de186f546e6b619a4028cd9b4d1"></span><span><span><strong>getAllScheduledMessages()</strong></span></span></h3><p><span><span>Get the list of all scheduled messages.</span></span></p><h3 id="block-7bfc9eff28bc4cbe8a2ae79733484e90"><span id="7bfc9eff28bc4cbe8a2ae79733484e90"></span><span><span><strong>getScheduledMessagesAtTime(time)</strong></span></span></h3><p><span><span>Get the list of scheduled messages for a particular&nbsp;</span><span><code>time</code></span><span>.</span></span></p><ul><li id="block-4544cfeaf80c42e491a6400962124475"><span><span><strong>time</strong></span><span>: Time should be specified in this format:&nbsp;</span><span><code>MM/DD/YYYY:HH</code></span><span>. For Example:&nbsp;</span><span><code>8/20/2020:2</code></span><span>.</span></span></li></ul><h3 id="block-a3786a62f496404c9660f76ba08033ed"><span id="a3786a62f496404c9660f76ba08033ed"></span><span><span><strong>clearAllScheduledMessages()</strong></span></span></h3><p><span><span>Clears all scheduled messages.</span></span></p><h3 id="block-7de077481f3147fea4dba9619476641f"><span id="7de077481f3147fea4dba9619476641f"></span><span><span><strong>stop()</strong></span></span></h3><p><span><span>Stops the internal timer. Can be restarted with&nbsp;</span><span><code>candymail.start()</code></span></span></p><h3 id="block-5d10311284a546dc80c3e57eb45c3392"><span id="5d10311284a546dc80c3e57eb45c3392"></span><span><span><strong>destroy()</strong></span></span></h3><p><span><span>Destroys the internal timer.</span></span></p><h2 id="block-1a98b5e65f4a41e28e4965b5d3d7de9b"><span id="1a98b5e65f4a41e28e4965b5d3d7de9b"></span><span><span><strong>Notes</strong></span></span></h2><ol><li id="block-6bdaea5d6e764e5da158efec480f2add"><span><span>Only the hour value will be used in the cron, minutes will be ignored. +1 hour at 11:58 is 12.</span></span></li><li id="block-d3354e8bdee045c69e7bb24dbd1bebec"><span><span>Object keys:&nbsp;</span><span><code>MM/DD/YYYY:HH</code></span><span>. Hours are specified in 24-hour format.</span></span></li><li id="block-ce94d7c86c894d17ab928f86fa776aef"><span><span>There is currently no&nbsp;</span><span><code>Unsubscribe</code></span><span>&nbsp;option in the emails. Being worked on right now.</span></span></li><li id="block-129c9e22b7c84f48bbcc4d3f284ea196"><span><span>Only supports GMail. More providers being added right now.</span></span></li></ol><div id="block-a05319bc3972418aa5f409ef65943cd3"><p><span><span>Got Feeback? Hit me up at&nbsp;</span><span><a href="mailto:sunnyashiin@gmail.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">sunnyashiin@gmail.com</a></span><span>&nbsp;Now available for freelance work.</span></span></p></div></article></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://saasbase.dev/candymail</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25578834</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 05:18:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
