<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 20]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 20. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 09:09:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-20.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 09:09:37 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[GPT-Neo recreating GPT-3 free open source]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 108 | Comments 47 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25819803">thread link</a>) | @sieste
<br/>
January 18, 2021 | https://www.eleuther.ai/gpt-neo | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.eleuther.ai/gpt-neo">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main" dir="ltr"><section id="h.9ed95fdf8c1e1d9_74"><div><div tabindex="-1"><div><div><div jscontroller="sGwD4d" jsaction="zXBUYb:zTPCnb;zQF9Uc:Qxe3nd;" jsname="F57UId"><div><div id="h.7261759c41748bba_16"><div><div><p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/H1AZ-PR0-JNbKwE_XoTHFBj-If_WUgfEeTtZidqWkwKVfySJQWu_TwcYNnrR_-NhY4hqDGPyGgHJIdF4GKMSvOxPXj71D6MgNhFZPGEqoOgaI_G0tts=w1280" role="img"></p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div><div><div><div jscontroller="sGwD4d" jsaction="zXBUYb:zTPCnb;zQF9Uc:Qxe3nd;" jsname="F57UId"><div><div id="h.9ed95fdf8c1e1d9_71"><div><div><p dir="ltr"><span>GPT-Neo is the code name for a series of transformer-based language models loosely styled around the GPT architecture that we plan to train and open source. Our primary goal is to replicate a GPT-3 sized model and open source it to the public, for free. </span></p><p dir="ltr"><span>Along the way we will be running experiments with </span><span><a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Farxiv.org%2Fabs%2F1701.06538&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHJmMleqfY7_hUomPrOnE0vc2d-VQ" target="_blank">alternative</a></span> <span><a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Farxiv.org%2Fabs%2F1911.03864&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFkViP0vtg72hlm50BfROBmFR67Ag" target="_blank">architectures</a></span><span> </span>and <span><a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Farxiv.org%2Fabs%2F2006.16236&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNECOymGhVzeI2sGyc6PufTta0RJlg" target="_blank">attention</a></span> <span><a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.aclweb.org%2Fanthology%2F2020.acl-main.672.pdf&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNE9TAomJh8x54cWNc_GMa-TnFV-Vg" target="_blank">types</a></span><span>, releasing any intermediate models, and writing up any findings on our blog. </span></p><p dir="ltr">We have a <span><a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2FEleutherAI%2Fgpt-neo%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFoMdHQMTwRf6mrVBBHu1ZYPeY_3A" target="_blank">codebase</a></span><span><a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2FEleutherAI%2Fgpt-neo%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFoMdHQMTwRf6mrVBBHu1ZYPeY_3A" target="_blank"> built in Tensorflow-mesh</a></span><span> (</span>for<span> training on TPU</span>s)<span>, and </span><span><a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2FEleutherai%2Fgpt-neox&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFerlkNsmlncTy6qDAuYM9WyhVTtQ" target="_blank">one built </a></span><span><a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2FEleutherai%2Fgpt-neox&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFerlkNsmlncTy6qDAuYM9WyhVTtQ" target="_blank">with Deepspeed</a></span> (for training on GPUs). Both can scale to GPT-3+ sizes, but we currently lack the TPUs to train a 175B model to completion. Thankfully, we don't lack GPUs.</p><p dir="ltr"><span><a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2FEleutherAI%2Fgpt-neo%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFoMdHQMTwRf6mrVBBHu1ZYPeY_3A" target="_blank">GPT-Neo</a></span> is now fairly stable, and we will be releasing smaller scale models shortly. <span><a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2FEleutherai%2Fgpt-neox&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFerlkNsmlncTy6qDAuYM9WyhVTtQ" target="_blank">GPT-Neox</a></span> is still a work in progress, and we will be releasing more updates as the project moves forward.</p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section><section id="h.9ed95fdf8c1e1d9_82"><div><div tabindex="-1"><div><div><div jscontroller="sGwD4d" jsaction="zXBUYb:zTPCnb;zQF9Uc:Qxe3nd;" jsname="F57UId"><div><div id="h.9ed95fdf8c1e1d9_79"><div><div><h3 id="h.i24o9xi2zff8" dir="ltr"><span><strong>Progress:</strong></span></h3><ul><li dir="ltr"><p dir="ltr">We<span> have the bulk of the model built, GPT-2 size models trained, and several experimental architectures implemented. </span></p></li><li dir="ltr"><p dir="ltr">Our current codebase should be able to scale up to GPT-3 sized models</p></li></ul></div></div></div></div></div></div></div><div><div><div jscontroller="sGwD4d" jsaction="zXBUYb:zTPCnb;zQF9Uc:Qxe3nd;" jsname="F57UId"><div><div id="h.9ed95fdf8c1e1d9_83"><div><div><h3 id="h.e8y7b91fgfoz" dir="ltr"><span><strong>Next Steps:</strong></span></h3><ul><li dir="ltr"><p dir="ltr">We are currently working on wrapping up GPT-2-sized model replication, looking mostly at evaluations there.</p></li><li dir="ltr"><p dir="ltr">The largest model we've gotten to train for a single step so far has been 200B parameters.</p></li></ul></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.eleuther.ai/gpt-neo</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25819803</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 09:13:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Amiga 1000 Parceiro]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 84 | Comments 6 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25818159">thread link</a>) | @jdkee
<br/>
January 17, 2021 | https://www.amigalove.com/viewtopic.php?t=1689 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.amigalove.com/viewtopic.php?t=1689">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/b0yBg6s99F0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>

<p><em>If you’d like to get an Amiga Parceiro for yourself, I explain how you can pre-order one at a heavily discounted rate at the end of the video and this article.</em></p><p>


A couple of years ago I made some videos where I showed my favorite Amiga 1000 setup at that time. It had two main hardware super powers that made it my daily driver. </p><p>

First, a fly-by of a glorious <a href="https://youtu.be/ZmW6LEwgruE">Rejuvenator board</a>, designed by the late Greg Tibbs out of Ohio (RIP Greg). A local good friend of mine here in Seattle named Christian Stich helped me upgrade that board to utilize a rare A3000 Agnus I found that can use 2MB of Chip RAM, which he custom built adapters for it to use. It also has a Kickstart 1.3 ROM chip to accelerate the boot up process and lose the typical Kickstart floppy. </p><div>

	
		
		

				<dl>
			<dt><img src="https://www.amigalove.com/download/file.php?id=6147&amp;sid=56223327f665c54364df1dd74cc11fa5" alt="IMG_7827.jpg" onclick="viewableArea(this);"></dt>
						<!-- <dd>IMG_7827.jpg (278.04 KiB) </dd>-->
		</dl>
		
		


		
		
	
</div>

<div>

	
		
		

				<dl>
			<dt><img src="https://www.amigalove.com/download/file.php?id=6148&amp;sid=56223327f665c54364df1dd74cc11fa5" alt="IMG_7842.jpg" onclick="viewableArea(this);"></dt>
						<!-- <dd>IMG_7842.jpg (275.15 KiB) </dd>-->
		</dl>
		
		


		
		
	
</div>

<p><em>Christian here is removing the old DRAMs, which were eight 256Kx4 in DIP format. He then installed four custom 1Mx4 in SOJ format  DRAMs with an adapter board that converts them to DIP format.</em></p><p>


The second thing was a hardware combo where I used a Microbotics Starboard expansion made back in 1987 that provided both extra fast RAM (in this case 1Mb), a real-time clock, and a SCSI module called the <a href="https://youtu.be/6BLXxY7FG5M">StarDrive which allowed me to use an Iomega SCSI Zip</a> as an external 100 MB hard drive. It used a custom Workbench boot disk that would pass control from the floppy over to the Zip drive and essentially turn the Zip into a semi-autobooting hard drive, which was a total game changer for that system. For all intents and purposes, that Amiga 1000 became one of my favorite, most treasured systems in my entire Amiga collection. </p><p>

<strong>A1000 equipped Starboard with SCSI Zip 100 as a hard drive </strong></p><p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6BLXxY7FG5M" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>

<p>
Fast-forward to today, as I made the difficult decision to <em>remove</em> the Starboard and Zip drive and replace it with a brand new device called the <strong>Amiga Parceiro</strong>. (Parceiro in Portuguese means “partner”.) So it’s the Friend Partner. <img src="https://www.amigalove.com/images/smilies/icon_e_wink.gif" width="15" height="17" alt=";)" title="Wink"></p><p>

The Amiga Parceiro was invented over the course of the past year by an Amiga hobbyist named David Dunklee who resides in a small town outside of Colorado Springs, CO. </p><p>

As Dunklee puts it:</p><div>

	
		
		

				<dl>
			<dt><img src="https://www.amigalove.com/download/file.php?id=6149&amp;sid=56223327f665c54364df1dd74cc11fa5" alt="DDunklee.png" onclick="viewableArea(this);"></dt>
						<!-- <dd>DDunklee.png (152.05 KiB) </dd>-->
		</dl>
		
		


		
		
	
</div>

<p>
Fun Trivia: Mr Dunklee, now retired, was the CIO of the <a href="https://www.spaceforce.mil/">United States Space Force</a>, as well as an Air Force base commander. You heard that right, Number One. </p><p>


So let’s take a look at Mr. Dunklee’s new device for the Amiga 1000 and see what it can do. </p><p>

At a high level, the Parceiro can do everything my Starboard &amp; Zip combo could do except in a very tidy, modern package. And it can do it all faster and better. </p><div>

	
		
		

				<dl>
			<dt><img src="https://www.amigalove.com/download/file.php?id=6150&amp;sid=56223327f665c54364df1dd74cc11fa5" alt="IMG_1027.JPG" onclick="viewableArea(this);"></dt>
						<!-- <dd>IMG_1027.JPG (356.15 KiB) </dd>-->
		</dl>
		
		


		
		
	
</div>

<p>
The Parceiro (sounds like par-say-ro) attaches to the side expansion port of the Amiga and is about the size of a harmonica that’s been run over by a steam roller as it’s only about 1/3 of an inch thick.</p><p>

It provides the following features: </p><ol><li> 8MB of Autoconfig Fast RAM. It is a single 8MB of SRAM versus DRAM, so it really and truly is indeed fast with zero wait states.</li> 
<li> Coin-cell battery backed Real Time Clock (RTC), which comes with its own clock software that gets put into your startup sequence.</li>
<li> SD Card Reader with 2GB MicroSD. It comes pre-formatted with the FAT32  file system and is readable on any PC as a result. This way you can quickly set up your new SD-based hard drive.</li></ol> <p>

It’s worth mentioning that this is running on period correct Amiga OS 1.3, too. </p><div>

	
		
		

				<dl>
			<dt><img src="https://www.amigalove.com/download/file.php?id=6151&amp;sid=56223327f665c54364df1dd74cc11fa5" alt="IMG_1080_b.jpg" onclick="viewableArea(this);"></dt>
			<dd><em>She is almost completely camouflaged into the Amiga battlestation at this point.</em></dd>			<!-- <dd>IMG_1080_b.jpg (259.01 KiB) </dd>-->
		</dl>
		
		


		
		
	
</div>

<p>
Possibly the best unseen feature is the silkscreen prints Dunklee put around the various chips and resistors on the board. It’s a complete sci-fi treasure trove of labelling, from Back to the Future to Battlestar Galactica. </p><div>

	
		
		

				<dl>
			<dt><img src="https://www.amigalove.com/download/file.php?id=6153&amp;sid=56223327f665c54364df1dd74cc11fa5" alt="IMG_1055_b.jpg" onclick="viewableArea(this);"></dt>
						<!-- <dd>IMG_1055_b.jpg (268.24 KiB) </dd>-->
		</dl>
		
		


		
		
	
</div>

<div>

	
		
		

				<dl>
			<dt><img src="https://www.amigalove.com/download/file.php?id=6152&amp;sid=56223327f665c54364df1dd74cc11fa5" alt="IMG_1054_b.jpg" onclick="viewableArea(this);"></dt>
						<!-- <dd>IMG_1054_b.jpg (380.51 KiB) </dd>-->
		</dl>
		
		


		
		
	
</div>

<div>

	
		
		

				<dl>
			<dt><img src="https://www.amigalove.com/download/file.php?id=6154&amp;sid=56223327f665c54364df1dd74cc11fa5" alt="IMG_1058_b.jpg" onclick="viewableArea(this);"></dt>
			<dd><em>This is where the brilliance really starts to shine.</em></dd>			<!-- <dd>IMG_1058_b.jpg (495.27 KiB) </dd>-->
		</dl>
		
		


		
		
	
</div>

<div>

	
		
		

				<dl>
			<dt><img src="https://www.amigalove.com/download/file.php?id=6155&amp;sid=56223327f665c54364df1dd74cc11fa5" alt="circuitboard-cu.jpg" onclick="viewableArea(this);"></dt>
			<dd><em>Yes, you've actually died and gone to heaven via worm hole.</em></dd>			<!-- <dd>circuitboard-cu.jpg (689.75 KiB) </dd>-->
		</dl>
		
		


		
		
	
</div>

<p>
For his fantastic creativity on the silkscreen, I half-jokingly suggested to Mr. Dunklee a future 3D printed case in clear acrylic so I could totally nerd out with his hilarious labels. And I think he might actually take me up on that idea some day! </p><div>

	
		
		

				<dl>
			<dt><img src="https://www.amigalove.com/download/file.php?id=6156&amp;sid=56223327f665c54364df1dd74cc11fa5" alt="clear-acryllic-case-parceiro.jpg" onclick="viewableArea(this);"></dt>
			<dd><em>UPDATE: He works really fast!</em></dd>			<!-- <dd>clear-acryllic-case-parceiro.jpg (248.37 KiB) </dd>-->
		</dl>
		
		


		
		
	
</div>

<p>
The Parceiro comes with instructions for creating your own KickWork disk to quickly boot up your machine and install all of the necessary software to run the device. This includes the necessary updates to your Mountlist, Startup-Sequence, adding fat95 drivers as well as the sd.device drivers. </p><p>

The <a href="https://amigalove.com/viewtopic.php?f=7&amp;t=312">KickWork disk idea</a> is based off a product developed in 1988 by Mr. Rudolph Loew (RIP). This is where a Kickstart disk is combined with a stripped down Workbench disk for faster machine boot ups off a single floppy rather than 2. </p><p>

With the Parceiro, Dunklee provides six pages of detailed instructions for getting you up and running in no time. The idea here is the modified KickWork (or Workbench) disk will begin the machine’s boot up process like normal then hand over total control to the SD card like a full-fledged autobooting hard drive. It’s not 100% autobooting, but it’s pretty danged close. And once the machine fully boots you just pop out the boot floppy disk and set it to the side. Mr Dunklee confided with me that in a distant hardware update he might take the next logical step and integrate an FPGA for a true autobooting experience. </p><p>

Since my machine is equipped with a Rejuvenator board, I didn’t need a KickWork disk. So I made a customized Workbench boot disk making the necessary adjustments following Mr Dunklee’s instructions for the RTC software, the SD card device driver and adding the FAT file system library. </p><p>

In the Amiga world, this is about as close to plug-and-play for a device with this many features that I’ve ever come across that doesn’t completely take over your machine and its identity like a Vampire, or some might argue even the ACA500+ (which basically uses the A1000's power to mostly take over). The Parceiro installation was absolutely seamless and I got it up and running without a hitch. </p><p>

Now some of you might be wondering how long it takes to boot this 2GB equipped Amiga. For example, on my Amiga 2000 I have a 40 MB mechanical boot drive, but I also have a SCSI2SD card with 2GB MicroSD for all of my software and data storage. When that machine boots it can sit on a gray screen for about 20 -25 seconds while the large drive is being validated. Once that process is done the A2K snaps to life and I’m on my way. </p><p>

With the Parceiro it’s a very different - and better - experience than I’m used to. The Parceiro still needs to validate the empty space on the drive, but instead it does it in the background. So the Amiga 1000 boots up without that normal long pause. While the background validation is going on, the volume is set to READ ONLY. I can still run programs but I simply can’t write to the drive while the validation is going on. To be honest I wouldn’t even know about this had it not been noted in the instructions, as I’m virtually never writing to the drive the moment I boot it up. And within a few seconds the little Cylon red LED light stops flickering and I know then it’s job is complete (which didn’t directly affect me anyway). </p><p>

Very, very cool! </p><p>

Now, this device is currently in extremely short supply. In fact, I happened to get S/N #1 and I know S/N #2 was sold a few hours after I got mine. At that stage the inventory was sold out. But several more will eventually get made over time so if you’re an Amiga 1000 fan that means you're patient by default. <img src="https://www.amigalove.com/images/smilies/icon_e_wink.gif" width="15" height="17" alt=";)" title="Wink"> I’d highly recommend you keep this on your radar and try to snag one of them for yourself. It’s simply bad ass and it didn’t require me to upgrade my OS beyond adding new drivers - or really change anything - like a lot of modern upgrades often do.  </p><p>

The Parceiro is a fantastic device, made in the USA, and is a very worthy successor to the Microbotics and Supra offerings from BITD. It is one of the few modern devices that is 100% designed for the Amiga 1000 for a change. And how cool and refreshing is that? </p><p>


<strong>Pre-Orders</strong></p><p>

If you’d like to pre-order one of these little technological marvels for yourself at a nearly <strong>20% discounted rate at $195</strong>, simply email <a href="https://www.amigalove.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#bafbd7d3dddb94eadbc8d9dfd3c8d5fad5cfced6d5d5d194d9d5d7"><span data-cfemail="185975717f793648796a7b7d716a7758776d6c74777773367b7775">[email&nbsp;protected]</span></a> to declare your interest <strong>and mention AmigaLove sent you</strong>. You will still need to cover expenses for shipping, of course, but you’ll get in line for your very own Parceiro. David Dunklee will manage the rest from there!</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.amigalove.com/viewtopic.php?t=1689</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25818159</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 04:28:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Tracking down a segfault that suddenly started happening]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 31 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25818126">thread link</a>) | @zdw
<br/>
January 17, 2021 | https://www.downtowndougbrown.com/2021/01/tracking-down-a-segfault-that-suddenly-started-happening/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.downtowndougbrown.com/2021/01/tracking-down-a-segfault-that-suddenly-started-happening/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
				
<p>I wanted to share a story of a segmentation fault I helped track down this weekend. I thought the final root cause of the segfault was interesting because of how unrelated it was to the code I was trying to debug.</p>



<p>I’ve been maintaining a <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://github.com/dougg3/obs-ios-camera-source" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/dougg3/obs-ios-camera-source" target="_blank">Linux fork</a> of <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://github.com/wtsnz/obs-ios-camera-source" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/wtsnz/obs-ios-camera-source">obs-ios-camera-source</a>, which is an <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://obsproject.com/" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://obsproject.com/">OBS</a> plugin that allows you to use an iPhone or iPad’s camera and microphone as a video and audio source in OBS. It works in conjunction with the “<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://obs.camera/" target="_blank">Camera for OBS Studio</a>” app in the App Store. This kind of thing is useful for online streamers who want to use their phone’s camera instead of buying a separate camera. For those of you who don’t know, OBS is short for Open Broadcaster Software. A lot of streamers use it to handle broadcasting their stream. It allows you to capture audio and video, mix it all together, do all kinds of cool things with it, and then record the final result and/or stream it to sites such as YouTube and Twitch.</p>



<p>Getting this plugin working on Linux wasn’t really complicated, because it was already well-written without much platform-specific code. After all, the existing codebase was already operational on both macOS and Windows. It mostly just required tweaking a few compile/link options to make the code run happily on Linux.</p>



<p>Anyway, I’m pretty sure a good number of people have been using my Linux port of this plugin without issues. I know it works fine for me when I test with it in Ubuntu 18.04 or 20.04. I’ve helped people on other distros get it working too. I don’t really do any streaming myself — maybe someday though!</p>



<p>On Friday, GitHub user rrondeau <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://github.com/dougg3/obs-ios-camera-source/issues/4" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/dougg3/obs-ios-camera-source/issues/4" target="_blank">reported an issue</a>: after a half a year of the obs-ios-camera-source plugin working without a problem, it suddenly started causing OBS to segfault on his computer (currently running Fedora 33). He provided a stack trace that showed that the segfault was happening because of something initiated by the plugin. Afterward, he used GDB to get a better stack trace that provided more info about the functions being called and the parameters being passed:</p>


<pre title="">#0  0x00007fffee7abc64 in socket_send () at /usr/lib64/samba/libsamba-sockets-samba4.so
#1  0x00007fff88b7813c in send_packet (sfd=50, message=8, tag=1, payload=0x1b22e60, payload_size=488) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-ios-camera-source/deps/libusbmuxd/src/libusbmuxd.c:400
#2  0x00007fff88b782a6 in send_plist_packet (sfd=50, tag=1, message=0x1ae53e0) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-ios-camera-source/deps/libusbmuxd/src/libusbmuxd.c:431
#3  0x00007fff88b7851b in send_list_devices_packet (sfd=50, tag=1) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-ios-camera-source/deps/libusbmuxd/src/libusbmuxd.c:499
#4  0x00007fff88b79367 in usbmuxd_get_device_list (device_list=0x7fffffffc740) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-ios-camera-source/deps/libusbmuxd/src/libusbmuxd.c:938
#5  0x00007fff88b725e1 in portal::Portal::addConnectedDevices() (this=0x1909378) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-ios-camera-source/deps/portal/src/Portal.cpp:109
#6  0x00007fff88b72684 in portal::Portal::reloadDeviceList() (this=0x1909378) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-ios-camera-source/deps/portal/src/Portal.cpp:126
#7  0x00007fff88b722db in portal::Portal::Portal(portal::PortalDelegate*) (this=0x1909378, delegate=0x1909240) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-ios-camera-source/deps/portal/src/Portal.cpp:57
#8  0x00007fff88b67053 in IOSCameraInput::IOSCameraInput(obs_source*, obs_data*) (this=0x1909240, source_=0x1aee000, settings=0x19210a0)
    at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-ios-camera-source/src/obs-ios-camera-source.cpp:74
#9  0x00007fff88b66358 in CreateIOSCameraInput(obs_data_t*, obs_source_t*) (settings=0x19210a0, source=0x1aee000) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-ios-camera-source/src/obs-ios-camera-source.cpp:371
#10 0x00007ffff6259c2a in obs_source_create_internal () at /lib64/libobs.so.0
#11 0x00007ffff626bb81 in obs_load_source_type () at /lib64/libobs.so.0
#12 0x00007ffff626e3c2 in obs_load_sources () at /lib64/libobs.so.0
#13 0x000000000049e750 in OBSBasic::Load(char const*) (this=0xa370b0, file=0x7fffffffd040 "/home/rrondeau/.config/obs-studio/basic/scenes/Untitled.json")
    at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-studio/UI/window-basic-main.cpp:973
#14 0x00000000004a2976 in OBSBasic::OBSInit() (this=0xa370b0) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-studio/UI/window-basic-main.cpp:1783
#15 0x000000000047feff in OBSApp::OBSInit() (this=0x7fffffffd690) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-studio/UI/obs-app.cpp:1415
#16 0x0000000000482503 in run_program(std::fstream&amp;amp;, int, char**) (logFile=..., argc=1, argv=0x7fffffffdd68) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-studio/UI/obs-app.cpp:2052
#17 0x0000000000484203 in main(int, char**) (argc=1, argv=0x7fffffffdd68) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-studio/UI/obs-app.cpp:2697
</pre>


<p>The actual segfault was happening inside of a function called “socket_send” in libsamba-sockets-samba4.so, which was being called by a function in libusbmuxd, which is bundled as part of the obs-ios-camera-source plugin source code and is used for communicating with iOS devices over USB. When I first saw this in the stack trace, my mind thought “Huh…that’s weird. Why does libusbmuxd use Samba’s library for its socket code instead of providing its own?” (<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.samba.org/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.samba.org/" target="_blank">Samba</a> is an implementation of the Windows file sharing protocol used by pretty much every Linux distribution)</p>



<p>I tested and couldn’t reproduce the issue in Ubuntu. I know basically nothing about Fedora, but I faked my way through grabbing a Fedora 33 virtual machine, installing OBS, and compiling the plugin. I ran into the exact same issue that he was seeing.</p>



<p>Before I had a chance to look deeper and understand what was going on, rrondeau beat me to the correct conclusion: code in Samba’s library was mistakenly being called. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://github.com/dougg3/obs-ios-camera-source/blob/8181922136e12ef618c8449f95a52e40d7104ded/deps/libusbmuxd/common/socket.h#L61" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/dougg3/obs-ios-camera-source/blob/8181922136e12ef618c8449f95a52e40d7104ded/deps/libusbmuxd/common/socket.h#L61" target="_blank">libusbmuxd has a function called socket_send</a>, but clearly <a href="https://github.com/samba-team/samba/blob/f52f531771d6a25b2e363384bf94a9fa14334e1b/source4/lib/socket/socket.h#L152" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/samba-team/samba/blob/f52f531771d6a25b2e363384bf94a9fa14334e1b/source4/lib/socket/socket.h#L152" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">libsamba-sockets-samba4’s function that is also named socket_send</a> was accidentally being called instead.</p>



<p>Honestly, that’s all we really needed to know. Renaming libusbmuxd’s socket_send function to something else, and updating all references to it to use the new name, fixed the issue. I still wanted to understand why this suddenly became an issue when it had been working fine prior to that. Why were we calling into Samba libraries? Why does an iOS USB multiplexing library even consider talking to a library associated with Windows file sharing?</p>



<p>Not knowing the answer to that question bothered me. I decided to dig deeper and understand exactly what was going on. I started by using <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ldd_(Unix)" data-type="URL" data-id="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ldd_(Unix)" target="_blank">ldd</a>, which lists all dynamic libraries used by a program or library:</p>


<pre title="">[fedora@fedora33 build]$ ldd obs-ios-camera-source.so 
	linux-vdso.so.1 (0x00007fffa599a000)
	libobs.so.0 =&gt; /lib64/libobs.so.0 (0x00007f0a3f688000)
	libavcodec.so.58 =&gt; /lib64/libavcodec.so.58 (0x00007f0a3e2db000)
	libavutil.so.56 =&gt; /lib64/libavutil.so.56 (0x00007f0a3e036000)
...
	libsamba-sockets-samba4.so =&gt; /usr/lib64/samba/libsamba-sockets-samba4.so (0x00007fd6af4b7000)
...
</pre>


<p>I truncated the output because it spit out a very long list of libraries. As we can see from ldd’s output, obs-ios-camera-source.so depends on libsamba-sockets-samba4.so. ldd lists all recursive dependencies as well, and I couldn’t find any references to “samba” in the plugin source code, so this was likely an indirect dependency instead. I confirmed this by using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Readelf" data-type="URL" data-id="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Readelf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">readelf</a> to show only the direct dependencies:</p>


<pre title="">[fedora@fedora33 build]$ readelf -d obs-ios-camera-source.so | grep NEEDED
 0x0000000000000001 (NEEDED)             Shared library: [libobs.so.0]
 0x0000000000000001 (NEEDED)             Shared library: [libavcodec.so.58]
 0x0000000000000001 (NEEDED)             Shared library: [libavutil.so.56]
 0x0000000000000001 (NEEDED)             Shared library: [libobs-frontend-api.so.0]
 0x0000000000000001 (NEEDED)             Shared library: [libstdc++.so.6]
 0x0000000000000001 (NEEDED)             Shared library: [libm.so.6]
 0x0000000000000001 (NEEDED)             Shared library: [libgcc_s.so.1]
 0x0000000000000001 (NEEDED)             Shared library: [libpthread.so.0]
 0x0000000000000001 (NEEDED)             Shared library: [libc.so.6]
</pre>


<p>At this point I used ldd and readelf to walk through the tree of dependencies and figure out what was actually linking against the Samba libraries. I later learned that I could have installed lddtree (part of the pax-utils package) to do this automatically. Either way, this led me to discover that the Samba libraries were being included through libsmbclient, which was a dependency of libavformat (part of FFmpeg). libavformat is a dependency of libobs.</p>



<p>Repeating this experiment on Ubuntu showed that libavformat on Ubuntu does not depend on libsmbclient. This explains why I couldn’t reproduce the issue on Ubuntu. So why does Fedora’s (well, <a href="https://rpmfusion.org/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://rpmfusion.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">RPM Fusion</a>‘s) version of libavformat depend on libsmbclient?</p>



<p>It turns out that it’s a compile-time option for FFmpeg. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://github.com/FFmpeg/FFmpeg/blob/master/libavformat/libsmbclient.c" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/FFmpeg/FFmpeg/blob/master/libavformat/libsmbclient.c" target="_blank">libavformat contains code for talking with Windows servers using libsmbclient</a>, but it’s an optional thing that you can choose to enable at compile time. Clearly Ubuntu chooses not to enable it, but RPM Fusion does. <a href="https://lists.rpmfusion.org/archives/list/rpmfusion-commits@lists.rpmfusion.org/thread/57UYP4VFY3VCJFU3DGPHLUE3JPYP73HJ/">Actually, I found the exact post on RPM Fusion’s commits mailing list</a> where the patch was added for enabling SMB support in FFmpeg. This patch is what led to the whole issue happening. If Ubuntu’s version of FFmpeg was being built with SMB support, we would have seen this a long time ago. This commit to RPM Fusion was made on December 31, 2020, which explains why rrondeau had only recently begun seeing the problem.</p>



<p>The root cause here is that the obs-ios-camera-source plugin was linking against two libraries that both provided a function named socket_send: libsamba-sockets-samba4 (indirectly through libobs) and libusbmuxd. libusbmuxd was being linked statically, but <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/62884945/shared-library-symbol-conflicts-and-static-linking-on-linux" data-type="URL" data-id="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/62884945/shared-library-symbol-conflicts-and-static-linking-on-linux" target="_blank">that doesn’t prevent functions in it from being resolved through dynamic linking rules anyway</a>. So even though libusbmuxd was a static library with its own internal implementation of socket_send, it was using …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.downtowndougbrown.com/2021/01/tracking-down-a-segfault-that-suddenly-started-happening/">https://www.downtowndougbrown.com/2021/01/tracking-down-a-segfault-that-suddenly-started-happening/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.downtowndougbrown.com/2021/01/tracking-down-a-segfault-that-suddenly-started-happening/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25818126</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 04:25:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Creating Comfy FreeBSD Jails Using Standard Tools]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 112 | Comments 22 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25813800">thread link</a>) | @kettunen
<br/>
January 17, 2021 | https://kettunen.io/post/standard-freebsd-jails/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://kettunen.io/post/standard-freebsd-jails/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
		<div>
			<div>
			
<main role="main">
	<article>
		<div>
			<p><a href="https://www.docker.com/">Docker</a> has stormed into software development in
recent years. While the concepts behind it are powerful and useful, similar
tools have been used in systems for decades. FreeBSD’s
<a href="https://www.freebsd.org/doc/handbook/jails.html">jails</a> in one of those tools
which build upon even older <code>chroot(2)</code> To put it shortly, with these tools, you
can make a safe environment separated from the rest of the system.</p>
<p>Jails in FreeBSD is by no means a new tool (introduced in 4.X), but for a reason
or another, I haven’t used them that often, which is a shame since they are so
powerful. So I wanted to explore this concept in a concise and summarized
manner.</p>
<h2 id="templates">Templates</h2>
<p>ZFS datasets are a great way of creating templates for jails since, after the
template creation, you can easily create new jails with <code>zfs clone</code> or <code>zfs send/receive</code>. Typically people tend to divide jails to complete and service
jails, where the former usually resembles a real FreeBSD system, and the latter
is often dedicated to applications/services. I’ll cover complete jails for now.</p>
<p>The creation of templates starts with creating a dataset for your jail and
template. Here I’ll make a new dataset for the base installation of FreeBSD
12.2.</p>
<pre><code>$ sudo zfs create -o mountpoint=/vm zroot/vm
$ sudo zfs create zroot/vm/tmpl
$ sudo zfs create zroot/vm/tmpl/12.2
</code></pre><p>After that, fetch the base installation itself:</p>
<pre><code>$ fetch ftp://ftp.freebsd.org/pub/FreeBSD/releases/amd64/12.2-RELEASE/base.txz
# Fetch all the necessary stuff for your template, e.g. lib32 if needed
$ sudo tar -xJvpf base.txz -C /vm/tmpl/12.2
</code></pre><p>After that you should write a minimum viable <code>/etc/rc.conf</code> for the template:</p>
<pre><code>$ sudo emacs /vm/tmpl/12.2/etc/rc.conf
</code></pre><blockquote>
<p><strong>Note</strong>: Refer to <code>rc.conf(5)</code>.</p>
</blockquote>
<pre><code># Start or stop services
sendmail_enable="NO"
sendmail_submit_enable="NO"
sendmail_outbound_enable="NO"
sendmail_msp_queue_enable="NO"
syslogd_flags="-ss"
cron_flags="-J 60"
</code></pre><p>You can also disable some unnecessary jobs for jails:</p>
<pre><code>$ sudo emacs /vm/tmpl/12.2/etc/periodic.conf
</code></pre><blockquote>
<p><strong>Note</strong>: Refer to <code>periodic.conf(5)</code>.</p>
</blockquote>
<pre><code># No output for successful script runs.
daily_show_success="NO"
weekly_show_success="NO"
monthly_show_success="NO"
security_show_success="NO"
   
# Output to log files which are rotated by default.
daily_output="/var/log/daily.log"
daily_status_security_output="/var/log/daily.log"
weekly_output="/var/log/weekly.log"
weekly_status_security_output="/var/log/weekly.log"
monthly_output="/var/log/monthly.log"
monthly_status_security_output="/var/log/monthly.log"
   
# No need for those without sendmail
daily_clean_hoststat_enable="NO"
daily_status_mail_rejects_enable="NO"
daily_status_mailq_enable="NO"
daily_queuerun_enable="NO"
   
# Host does those
daily_status_disks_enable="NO"
daily_status_zfs_zpool_list_enable="NO"
daily_status_network_enable="NO"
daily_status_uptime_enable="NO"
daily_ntpd_leapfile_enable="NO"
weekly_locate_enable="NO"
weekly_whatis_enable="NO"
security_status_chksetuid_enable="NO"
security_status_neggrpperm_enable="NO"
security_status_chkuid0_enable="NO"
security_status_ipfwdenied_enable="NO"
security_status_ipfdenied_enable="NO"
security_status_ipfwlimit_enable="NO"
security_status_ipf6denied_enable="NO"
security_status_tcpwrap_enable="NO"
</code></pre><p>You also might want to enable ports in your jail:</p>
<pre><code>$ sudo mkdir /vm/tmpl/12.2/usr/ports
$ sudo mkdir -p /vm/tmpl/12.2/var/ports/{distfiles,packages}
$ sudo emacs /vm/tmpl/12.2/etc/make.conf
</code></pre><pre><code>WRKDIRPREFIX = /var/ports
DISTDIR = /var/ports/distfiles
PACKAGES = /var/ports/packages
</code></pre><p>Apply system updates to the template:</p>
<pre><code>$ sudo freebsd-update -b /vm/tmpl/12.2 fetch install
</code></pre><p>Lastly, take a snapshot:</p>
<pre><code>$ sudo zfs snapshot zroot/vm/tmpl/12.2@complete
</code></pre><p>This creates a snapshot of <code>zroot/vm/tmpl/12.2</code> named <code>complete</code>. You can then check your current snapshots with:</p>
<pre><code>$ sudo zfs list -t snapshot
</code></pre><h2 id="creating-jails-from-the-template">Creating Jails from the Template</h2>
<p>Now you should be able to create a new jail based on that snapshot. You can do
it either with <code>zfs clone</code> or <code>zfs send/receive</code>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Difference Between the Two</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>“A clone is a writable volume or file system whose initial contents are the
same as the dataset from which it was created. As with snapshots, creating a
clone is nearly instantaneous and initially consumes no additional disk
space. In addition, you can snapshot a clone.” [1]</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>“The zfs send command creates a stream representation of a snapshot that is
written to standard output. By default, a full stream is generated. You can
redirect the output to a file or to a different system. The zfs receive
command creates a snapshot whose contents are specified in the stream that is
provided on standard input. If a full stream is received, a new file system is
created as well. You can send ZFS snapshot data and receive ZFS snapshot data
and file systems with these commands. See the examples in the next section.”
[2]</p>
</blockquote>
<pre><code>$ sudo zfs clone zroot/vm/tmpl/12.2@complete zroot/vm/jail1

# OR

$ sudo sh -c "zfs send zroot/vm/tmpl/12.2@complete | zfs receive zroot/vm/jail1"
</code></pre><h2 id="jail-configurations">Jail Configurations</h2>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Note</strong>: These configurations is for very bare-bones jail, e.g. without any
mounts or advanced networking. Further configurations are discussed in future posts.</p>
</blockquote>
<pre><code># /etc/rc.conf

cloned_interfaces="lo0"

# PF is used for NAT and port forwarding.
pf_enable="YES"
pflog_enable="YES"

jail_enable="YES"
jail_list="jail1"
</code></pre><blockquote>
<p><strong>Note</strong>: Refer to <code>jail.conf(5)</code>.</p>
</blockquote>
<pre><code># /etc/jail.conf

exec.start = "/bin/sh /etc/rc";
exec.stop = "/bin/sh /etc/rc.shutdown";
exec.clean;
mount.devfs;

host.hostname = $name;
path = "/vm/$name";
exec.consolelog = "/var/log/jail_${name}_console.log";
exec.prestart = "cp /etc/resolv.conf $path/etc";
exec.poststop = "rm $path/etc/resolv.conf";

jail1 {
        ip4.addr = "lo0|127.1.1.1/32";
        ip6.addr = "lo0|fd00:1:1:1::1/64";
        allow.chflags;
        allow.raw_sockets;
}
</code></pre><pre><code># /etc/hosts

...

127.1.1.1 jail1
fd00:1:1:1::1 jail1
</code></pre><h2 id="jail-management">Jail Management</h2>
<p>Start/stop all jails.</p>
<pre><code>$ sudo service jail start
</code></pre><p>Start/stop a specific jail(s).</p>
<pre><code>$ sudo service jail start jail1
</code></pre><p>Log in to jail.</p>
<pre><code>$ sudo jexec jail1
</code></pre><p>Exec a command on a jail.</p>
<pre><code>$ sudo jexec jail1 uname -a
FreeBSD jail1 12.2-RELEASE FreeBSD 12.2-RELEASE r366954 GENERIC  amd64
</code></pre><p>List running jails.</p>
<pre><code>$ jls
   JID  IP Address      Hostname                      Path
     3  127.1.1.1       jail1                         /vm/jail1
</code></pre><p>So that’s how you can spin up a simple restricted environment on your FreeBSD
system. There are still lots of things to cover in this topic, e.g., in-depth
networking and configurations. But I think those deserve their own posts. So see
you soon!</p>
<h2 id="notes">Notes</h2>
<p>[1] Overview of ZFS Clones: <a href="https://docs.oracle.com/cd/E19253-01/819-5461/gbcxz/index.html">https://docs.oracle.com/cd/E19253-01/819-5461/gbcxz/index.html</a></p>
<p>[2] Sending and Receiving ZFS Data: <a href="https://docs.oracle.com/cd/E18752_01/html/819-5461/gbchx.html">https://docs.oracle.com/cd/E18752_01/html/819-5461/gbchx.html</a></p>
<h2 id="references">References</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.freebsd.org/doc/handbook/jails.html">FreeBSD Jails</a></li>
</ul>

		</div>
		
	</article>
</main>







			</div>
			
		</div>
		

	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://kettunen.io/post/standard-freebsd-jails/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25813800</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 19:07:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News sentiment towards Big Tech companies]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 40 | Comments 28 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25812346">thread link</a>) | @greatwave1
<br/>
January 17, 2021 | https://www.quiverquant.com/sources/hackernews | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.quiverquant.com/sources/hackernews">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
					<p><a href="https://www.quiverquant.com/">
						<img src="https://www.quiverquant.com/static/img/logo.png" alt="">
					</a></p><p>Quiver scrapes alternative stock data from across the internet and aggregates it in a free, easy-to-use web dashboard.</p>
					<div>
						<p><span>Copyright © 2020 Quiver Quantitative, Inc. All rights reserved.</span></p><ul>
							<li><a href="https://www.quiverquant.com/privacypolicy">Privacy Policy</a></li>
							<li><a href="https://www.quiverquant.com/termsofservice">Terms of Service</a></li>
						</ul>
					</div>
				</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.quiverquant.com/sources/hackernews</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25812346</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 17:03:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Cyber Security; Beginner Roadmap]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 53 | Comments 50 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25812025">thread link</a>) | @ashimi
<br/>
January 17, 2021 | https://blog.ashimi.xyz/cyber-security-beginner-roadmap-ckk1cmmvb08jfqps1amjuh10o | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.ashimi.xyz/cyber-security-beginner-roadmap-ckk1cmmvb08jfqps1amjuh10o">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section itemprop="articleBody mainEntityOfPage"><div><div><div><div><p>Subscribe to <!-- -->my<!-- --> newsletter and never miss <!-- -->my<!-- --> upcoming articles</p></div></div></div><div itemprop="text"><p>I previously wrote an article on <a target="_blank" href="https://blog.ashimi.xyz/how-to-be-a-hacker-ckgsepg7y05i9z9s10bl92iy7">How to be a Hacker</a>, and I mentioned taking courses and practicing in Safe Environments. We will be taking a more precise look at that.</p>
<p>We will be exploring a Beginner to Expert Roadmap as designed by Tux in the infographic below
<img src="https://cdn.hashnode.com/res/hashnode/image/upload/v1610889439172/wAmw3SEGa.jpeg?auto=compress" alt="1603267450360.jpg"></p>
<h2 id="learning">Learning</h2>
<ul>
<li><p><a target="_blank" href="https://tryhackme.com/">tryhackme.com</a> provides a wide variety of security topics you can select from. These security topics give you access to different vulnerable machines and they are to be scanned and exploited with different tools for you to be able to complete the given tasks. Although there are certain aspects where you would require premium access, most of it is free. Every learning path comes with a different cybersecurity topic and they are very crucial to understand various concepts. TryHackMe Network can be connected to via OpenVPN in order to deploy machines / various Operating systems and carry out exploits.</p>
</li>
<li><p><a target="_blank" href="https://immersivelabs.online/">immersivelabs.online</a> is a gamified learning lab that is developed by experts as an emulation of world-class security threats. It allows you to visualize your capabilities as Hacker, practice with the latest discovered security threats, and earn points for completing labs.
It has over 600labs, and it's one of the coolest places to hon your skills</p>
</li>
<li><p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.hackthebox.eu/">hackthebox.eu</a> is very much hard than the previous two because you can't sign up directly, you have to hack your way into the platform. It is focused on practicing your skills and it comes with a Social Network feeling as you can connect with millions of hackers on the platform, share ideas, methodologies, and even compete for the Leaderboards. But It also has an Academy, if you need to review your knowledge or learn new concepts.</p>
</li>
<li><p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.vulnhub.com/">VulnHub.com</a> provides materials allowing anyone to gain practical hands-on experience with digital security, computer applications, and network administration tasks. VulnHub offers offline virtual machines, allowing users to practice without competing with other learners. There’s no need to worry about consistent internet access, high pings, or latency. Users can set up their own private labs to practice and learn new skills.</p>
</li>
<li><p><a target="_blank" href="https://academy.tcm-sec.com/p/practical-ethical-hacking-the-complete-course">PEH by tcm</a> is a 25 hours course by TCM Security, it is one of the best-paid courses you can ever get. It is recommended to have a hackthebox account before starting the course. They focus only on tools and topics that will make you successful as an ethical hacker, it is completely hands-on and covers all foundational topics.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="certification">Certification</h2>
<p>Once you have quite an experience in all of the above, you can decide to test your credibility and prepare for employment by getting the certifications, We will discuss below.</p>
<ul>
<li><p><a target="_blank" href="https://elearnsecurity.com/product/ejpt-certification/"> eLearnSecurity Junior Penetration
</a> is designed for students with no penetration testing experience, as shown in course content, the instructor’s mode of teaching, and the lab modules. The course teaches about practical skill-sets that are important to penetration testing such as networking knowledge, scripting/programming, vulnerability identification, etc. It has a fairly great structure and is delivered in the easiest way to understand. Although you can proceed to the certification without the course, it is still very recommended you take the course.</p>
</li>
<li><p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.offensive-security.com/pwk-oscp/OSCP/">Offensive Security Certified Professional</a>  is an ethical hacking certification offered by Offensive Security that teaches penetration testing methodologies and the use of the tools included with the Kali Linux distribution (successor of BackTrack). The OSCP is a hands-on penetration testing certification, requiring holders to successfully attack and penetrate various live machines in a safe lab environment.</p>
</li>
<li><p><a target="_blank" href="https://elearnsecurity.com/product/ecpptv2-certification/">eLearnSecurity’s Certified Professional Penetration Tester</a>  is a comprehensive, “black box” engagement against a given scope. You have seven days to complete the engagement, and another seven days to complete a professional penetration test report. </p>
</li>
<li><p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.offensive-security.com/courses-and-certifications/">Offensive Security Certified Expert</a>  is a 48-hour lab examination that will thoroughly test you on web exploitation, Windows exploit development, anti-virus evasion, x86 assembly, handcrafting shellcode, and more</p>
</li>
<li><p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.eccouncil.org/programs/certified-ethical-hacker-ceh/">Certified Ethical Hacker (CEH)</a>  is a qualification obtained by demonstrating knowledge of assessing the security of computer systems by looking for weaknesses and vulnerabilities in target systems, using the same knowledge and tools as a malicious hacker, but in a lawful and legitimate manner to assess the security posture of a target system.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Cyber Security is one of the most expensive fields, You are required to do a number of exams and certification. Unlike Software Development, These certifications are very crucial, They are more or less like a "Get out of jail free" Card.</p>
<p>Thanks for coming this far with me, I might be writing soon on preparatory exams for the above certifications</p>
<p>References:
<a href="https://medium.com/cybersecpadawan/ecppt-certified-a95fc842ca7b" target="_blank">medium.com/cybersecpadawan/ecppt-certified-..</a>
Wikipedia</p>
</div></div></section></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.ashimi.xyz/cyber-security-beginner-roadmap-ckk1cmmvb08jfqps1amjuh10o</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25812025</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 16:26:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Another scam paper published in a “scientific” journal]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 83 | Comments 45 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25811802">thread link</a>) | @DanielBMarkham
<br/>
January 17, 2021 | https://whyevolutionistrue.com/2021/01/15/another-scam-paper-published-in-a-scientific-journal/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://whyevolutionistrue.com/2021/01/15/another-scam-paper-published-in-a-scientific-journal/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-346301">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>
		<p>I’ve written before about predatory scientific journals: those fly-by-night venues that will publish nearly any submitted paper, however dreadful. Their motive is to get the thousands of dollars in “publication fees” that authors are forced to pay. In return, the authors get to cite their paper on their c.v.s, even though most papers in these journals are worthless. (Those who evaluate c.v.s, however, often don’t know which journals are bogus.)</p>
<p><a href="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/2020/04/16/hoax-a-crazy-hilarious-paper-in-a-predatory-journal/">In April of last year</a> I wrote about a hilarious and deliberately insane paper written by Daniel Baldassare, “What’s the deal with birds?”, published in the predatory <em>Scientific Journal of Research and Reviews</em> (it’s not there any longer).&nbsp; Its thesis, such as it was, was that birds tending to look like fish (i.e., penguins) occurred in areas most susceptible to climate change, while birds with weird beaks (i.e;, parrots), didn’t live in those areas. But it was a farrago of madness and humor, done on purpose to show that these journals will publish anything. Here are the “data” from Baldassare’s paper:</p>
<p><a href="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm.png"><img data-attachment-id="346443" data-permalink="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/2021/01/15/another-scam-paper-published-in-a-scientific-journal/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12-05-49-pm-2/" data-orig-file="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm.png" data-orig-size="2604,1432" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm-300x165.png" data-large-file="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm-500x275.png" loading="lazy" src="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm.png" alt="" width="739" height="407" srcset="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm.png 2604w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm-300x165.png 300w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm-500x275.png 500w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm-768x422.png 768w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm-1536x845.png 1536w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm-2048x1126.png 2048w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm-1200x660.png 1200w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm-863x475.png 863w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm-196x108.png 196w" sizes="(max-width: 739px) 100vw, 739px" data-lazy-srcset="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm.png 2604w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm-300x165.png 300w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm-500x275.png 500w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm-768x422.png 768w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm-1536x845.png 1536w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm-2048x1126.png 2048w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm-1200x660.png 1200w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm-863x475.png 863w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm-196x108.png 196w" data-lazy-src="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/screen-shot-2020-04-16-at-12.05.49-pm.png?is-pending-load=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></a></p>
<p>I guess after Baldassare exposed both the paper and the journal <a href="https://twitter.com/evornithology/status/1245817707024592898">in his Twitter thread</a>, they decided to remove the paper. Baldassare, by the way, managed to bargain the “author’s fee” down from $1700 to zero. <em><a href="https://www.audubon.org/news/whats-deal-birds-new-paper-ask">Audubon Magazine</a></em> even wrote a piece about the hoax.</p>
<p>Now we have another of these hoax papers, also dealing with “fishy” birds. <a href="https://juniperpublishers.com/ofoaj/">This one</a>, published by Martin Stervander and Danny Haelewaters, appears in&nbsp;in <em>Oceanography &amp; Fisheries. </em>It’s&nbsp;still up (click on the screenshot), but won’t be for long (I have a pdf for you if it’s taken down).</p>
<p><a href="https://juniperpublishers.com/ofoaj/OFOAJ.MS.ID.555850.php"><img data-attachment-id="346303" data-permalink="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/2021/01/15/another-scam-paper-published-in-a-scientific-journal/screen-shot-2021-01-14-at-9-36-37-am/" data-orig-file="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-14-at-9.36.37-AM.png" data-orig-size="1690,664" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Screen Shot 2021-01-14 at 9.36.37 AM" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-14-at-9.36.37-AM-300x118.png" data-large-file="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-14-at-9.36.37-AM-500x196.png" loading="lazy" src="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-14-at-9.36.37-AM.png" alt="" width="669" height="263" srcset="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-14-at-9.36.37-AM.png 1690w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-14-at-9.36.37-AM-300x118.png 300w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-14-at-9.36.37-AM-500x196.png 500w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-14-at-9.36.37-AM-768x302.png 768w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-14-at-9.36.37-AM-1536x603.png 1536w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-14-at-9.36.37-AM-1200x471.png 1200w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-14-at-9.36.37-AM-863x339.png 863w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-14-at-9.36.37-AM-275x108.png 275w" sizes="(max-width: 669px) 100vw, 669px" data-lazy-srcset="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-14-at-9.36.37-AM.png 1690w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-14-at-9.36.37-AM-300x118.png 300w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-14-at-9.36.37-AM-500x196.png 500w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-14-at-9.36.37-AM-768x302.png 768w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-14-at-9.36.37-AM-1536x603.png 1536w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-14-at-9.36.37-AM-1200x471.png 1200w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-14-at-9.36.37-AM-863x339.png 863w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-14-at-9.36.37-AM-275x108.png 275w" data-lazy-src="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-14-at-9.36.37-AM.png?is-pending-load=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></a></p>
<p>The premise and thesis is also bull-goose loony, again on purpose. This time their complex hypothesis took into account no fewer than four biological factors. Here’s how the authors describe the genesis of the hypothesis:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>At the time we developed the original idea about fishiness of birds potentially being correlated to absence of poisonous mushrooms, one of the authors (D.H.) was eating pizza with four cheeses, chicken, anchovies, and mushrooms. It was really a good one, and this prompted us to—just like the pizza—integrate all four parameters in this study: fishiness, birdiness, lack of fungal toxicity, and effects of prolonged heating. We note that integrative taxonomy approaches [8], and by extension approaches to integrate everything in research, are being increasingly employed, thus supporting the rationale for the work presented in this paper.</p>
<p>It is important to keep in mind that research has not always been this integrative, or cross-disciplinary. For example, Charles Darwin worked alone [9] and still published a relatively well-cited contribution to the field of theology and some other disciplines. We feel it is natural for humans to dangle up and down between extremes. This is true for scientists, just like it is for politicians (consider the formation of the European Union in the 1990s and early 2000s versus the current wish of some countries to leave again [10]).</p>
<p>All in all, in this study we present the results of our work with fishy birds (<i>fide Baldassarre</i>&nbsp;[1]). We hypothesize that, (1) despite climate change, it is still cold in Antarctica and thus the presumed lack of poisonous fungi leads to fishy-looking birds. Further, with a clear correlation of pizza and lower latitudes [11], we hypothesize that (2) birdy-looking birds (as well as fishy-looking fish) will be more prevalent than fishy-looking birds on pizzas.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Any good reviewer would have spotted this in an instant as a Poe, but of course these journals don’t care about quality, or even seriousness. I doubt the reviewers even read the papers.</p>
<p>Their results, like Baldassari’s are presented in a single bizarre figure, with lots of bogus statements in the text about statistical methods and significance. But what they conclude is that birds that look like fish (i.e., penguins) tend to occur in areas without poisonous fungi (Antarctica), while birds that don’t look like fish (chickens, swifts, etc; they also threw in a flying fish that looks like a swift, an anchovy, and a “Nemo fish”) live at lower latitudes where there’s an abundance of pizza. A remarkable vindication of their thesis! The results in graphic form:</p>
<p><a href="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM.png"><img data-attachment-id="346381" data-permalink="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/2021/01/15/another-scam-paper-published-in-a-scientific-journal/screen-shot-2021-01-15-at-5-39-26-am/" data-orig-file="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM.png" data-orig-size="2160,1296" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Screen Shot 2021-01-15 at 5.39.26 AM" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM-300x180.png" data-large-file="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM-500x300.png" loading="lazy" src="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM.png" alt="" width="899" height="539" srcset="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM.png 2160w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM-300x180.png 300w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM-500x300.png 500w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM-768x461.png 768w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM-1536x922.png 1536w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM-2048x1229.png 2048w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM-1200x720.png 1200w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM-863x518.png 863w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM-180x108.png 180w" sizes="(max-width: 899px) 100vw, 899px" data-lazy-srcset="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM.png 2160w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM-300x180.png 300w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM-500x300.png 500w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM-768x461.png 768w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM-1536x922.png 1536w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM-2048x1229.png 2048w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM-1200x720.png 1200w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM-863x518.png 863w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM-180x108.png 180w" data-lazy-src="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-5.39.26-AM.png?is-pending-load=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></a></p>
<p>. . .&nbsp; and in the text:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Our PCA revealed that most of the variation in the dataset was partitioned along the first (59.3%) and second (34.8%) principal components (PCs), with loadings corresponding to poisonous funginess and pizza toppingness, respectively (Table 1). There is a clear bimodality in both PC scores, distinguishing on the one hand penguins (PC1, low funginess) and on the other hand anchovy and chicken (PC2, high toppingness). Plotting the scores for all taxa, a quadratic model explains the two-dimensional distribution of avian species (p &lt;&lt;&lt; 0.05) with low residual variation except for the outlier&nbsp;<i>H. rustica</i>&nbsp;(Figure 1).</p>
</blockquote>
<p>They note that while fishy-looking birds occur in areas lacking poisonous fungi&nbsp;<em>and</em> pizza, that relationship doesn’t hold for birdy-looking fish (flying fish).&nbsp; They also note that the swallow is an outlier.</p>
<p>In the discussion they take up the parlous subject of climate change, and postulate that, with global warming, poisonous fungi may invade Antarctica and “may thus exert a strong selection pressure on penguins to evolve a less fishy morphology,” so that the evolved penguins may, with their new appearance, expand into “pizza topping habitats.”</p>
<p>There are two more immediate clues that this was a hoax: the acknowledgements (which damn predatory journals!) and the author contributions, which cite Darwin:</p>
<p><a href="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.05-AM.png"><img data-attachment-id="346450" data-permalink="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/2021/01/15/another-scam-paper-published-in-a-scientific-journal/screen-shot-2021-01-15-at-9-14-05-am/" data-orig-file="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.05-AM.png" data-orig-size="1104,808" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Screen Shot 2021-01-15 at 9.14.05 AM" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.05-AM-300x220.png" data-large-file="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.05-AM-500x366.png" loading="lazy" src="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.05-AM.png" alt="" width="450" height="330" srcset="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.05-AM.png 1104w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.05-AM-300x220.png 300w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.05-AM-500x366.png 500w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.05-AM-768x562.png 768w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.05-AM-863x632.png 863w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.05-AM-148x108.png 148w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" data-lazy-srcset="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.05-AM.png 1104w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.05-AM-300x220.png 300w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.05-AM-500x366.png 500w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.05-AM-768x562.png 768w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.05-AM-863x632.png 863w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.05-AM-148x108.png 148w" data-lazy-src="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.05-AM.png?is-pending-load=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.14-AM.png"><img data-attachment-id="346451" data-permalink="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/2021/01/15/another-scam-paper-published-in-a-scientific-journal/screen-shot-2021-01-15-at-9-14-14-am/" data-orig-file="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.14-AM.png" data-orig-size="1140,226" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Screen Shot 2021-01-15 at 9.14.14 AM" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.14-AM-300x59.png" data-large-file="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.14-AM-500x99.png" loading="lazy" src="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.14-AM.png" alt="" width="590" height="117" srcset="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.14-AM.png 1140w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.14-AM-300x59.png 300w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.14-AM-500x99.png 500w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.14-AM-768x152.png 768w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.14-AM-863x171.png 863w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.14-AM-480x95.png 480w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" data-lazy-srcset="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.14-AM.png 1140w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.14-AM-300x59.png 300w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.14-AM-500x99.png 500w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.14-AM-768x152.png 768w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.14-AM-863x171.png 863w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.14-AM-480x95.png 480w" data-lazy-src="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-15-at-9.14.14-AM.png?is-pending-load=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></a></p>
<p>First author Martin Stervander also wrote <a href="https://www.stervander.com/fishy-birds-birdy-fish-poisonous-fungi-and-pizza-our-scientific-breakthroughs-published-in-predatory-journal/">an exposé on his own website</a> about the paper, including a positive “review” of the paper for another journal where it was submitted, <em>Journal of Ecosystems and Ecography</em>, published by OMICS International. It’s clear that the reviewing process of all these journals is deficient—to say the least. But if it was rigorous, they’d have no way to make money!</p>
<p><a href="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PeerReviewComments-300x115-1.png"><img data-attachment-id="346462" data-permalink="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/2021/01/15/another-scam-paper-published-in-a-scientific-journal/peerreviewcomments-300x115/" data-orig-file="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PeerReviewComments-300x115-1.png" data-orig-size="300,115" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="PeerReviewComments-300×115" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PeerReviewComments-300x115-1.png" data-large-file="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PeerReviewComments-300x115-1.png" loading="lazy" src="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PeerReviewComments-300x115-1.png" alt="" width="412" height="158" srcset="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PeerReviewComments-300x115-1.png 300w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PeerReviewComments-300x115-1-282x108.png 282w" sizes="(max-width: 412px) 100vw, 412px" data-lazy-srcset="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PeerReviewComments-300x115-1.png 300w, https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PeerReviewComments-300x115-1-282x108.png 282w" data-lazy-src="https://whyevolutionistrue.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PeerReviewComments-300x115-1.png?is-pending-load=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></a></p>
<p>So we have another exposé of&nbsp; predatory journals, which we all know exist because every scientist gets daily requests for submissions to these journals, even when the journals aren’t remotely connected with the scientist’s research. (I’ve had pleas for my papers from journals in obstetrics and gynecology.) But there’s no better way to expose this nonsense than to publish a loony paper in it.&nbsp; Sadly, this doesn’t bring down the journals (they just remove the papers), and they continue to serve as citations for desperate scientists.</p>
<p>Is there anything unethical about these hoaxes? Hell, no: there’s no way anybody could be deceived by papers like these, and it’s the best way to show the journals up for what they are.</p>
<p>They also resemble the “hoax papers” sent by Boghossian, Pluckrose, and Lindsay to social-science journals in the famous “grievance studies affair” that now has<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grievance_studies_affair"> its own <em>Wikipedia</em> page</a>. As I wrote last April:</p>
<blockquote><p>One final remark. In the “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grievance_studies_affair">grievance studies affair</a>“, Helen Pluckrose, James Lindsay, and especially Peter Boghossian got into big trouble for “hoaxing” humanities journals with equally ludicrous papers.&nbsp; Baldassarre won’t get into trouble (and shouldn’t), for his paper is in a clearly predatory journal.&nbsp; But what’s the difference between a predatory scientific journal that will publish nonsense and humanities journals like&nbsp;<em>Fat Studies</em>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<em>Gender, Place &amp; Culture</em>&nbsp;that publish nonsense but also purport to be venues for serious research? In effect, they both do the same thing: help researchers fatten their c.v.s with worthless research. Why should Boghossian et al. be excoriated for exposing the same kind of crappy journal standards that Baldassarre did?</p>
<p><em>Anything</em>&nbsp;that exposes this kind of academic garbage, including clear hoax papers, is to be applauded, so long as the hoaxes are revealed (as they were with the Grievance Studies Trio) or are so palpably ridiculous (as with Baldassarre’s paper) that they couldn’t be anything&nbsp;<em>other</em>&nbsp;than a hoax.</p></blockquote>
<p>Amen.</p>
<p>h/t: Martim Melo</p>

			</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://whyevolutionistrue.com/2021/01/15/another-scam-paper-published-in-a-scientific-journal/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25811802</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 16:06:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[We can do better than Signal]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 168 | Comments 278 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25811696">thread link</a>) | @icy
<br/>
January 17, 2021 | https://icyphox.sh/blog/signal/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://icyphox.sh/blog/signal/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          <header>
            <section>
<a href="https://icyphox.sh/">
<img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/f294b31af19b6fafcede07b76eac214e9a381be7/5c724/static/white.svg" alt="icyphox's avatar">
</a>
</section>

          </header>
          <!--<section style="float: right">
            view in <a href="/txt/signal.txt">plain-text</a>
          </section>-->
          <section>
            17 January, 2021
          </section>
          <article>
            
            <h2>Centralized silos are never the solution</h2>
            <p>Signal is possibly the most recommended pro-privacy instant
communication app — one that was commonplace in the hacker community,
and has now gained a lot of mainstream traction, thanks to WhatsApp
deciding to screw its userbase over. It certainly presents a more
compelling alternative than others in the same space, like WhatsApp
itself, Telegram, etc. They engineered the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Signal_Protocol" rel="nofollow">Signal
Protocol</a>, which has
found its way into other messaging systems, and has been the base for
the likes of OMEMO and Matrix.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup> While I admire the tech behind
Signal, I still believe we can do better, and we ought to.</p>

<p>I have a few gripes with Signal — the biggest of them all is it’s
centralized, and in the US no less. This alone makes it not that
different from WhatsApp — we’re simply moving from one silo to another.
What’s to say that Signal will uphold its values, continue operating
<em>and</em> evade censorship and potential compromise? To top it off, they’re
becoming a fairly high value target off late. And if that isn’t
convincing enough, Signal’s massive outage lasting nearly a day<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2">2</a></sup>
should be enough evidence against centralization. Further, Signal is
known to use AWS<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3">3</a></sup> as their cloud provider — what if another
Parler<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4">4</a></sup> happens and the rug is pulled from under Signal’s feet?</p>

<p>A common defense in favor of Signal is, “But it’s all open source!”.
Sure is, but on what basis do I trust them? I don’t mean to sound
conspiratorial, but what’s to say that the server in production hasn’t
been backdoored? In fact, the <a href="https://github.com/signalapp/Signal-Server" rel="nofollow">Signal server
code</a> hasn’t even been
updated since April 2020. You’re telling me it’s undergone <em>no</em> changes?</p>

<p>Another response I usually see is “But Signal is all we have!”. While
that is somewhat true — at least by the metric of “secure messengers
your granny can use”, there are some promising alternatives who are
especially focused on decentralizing E2EE communications.</p>

<ol>
<li><a href="https://matrix.org/" rel="nofollow">Matrix</a>: Matrix has improved a whole lot, and I
like that they’re working to disprove that end-to-end encryption
cannot be decentralized<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5">5</a></sup>.</li>
<li><a href="https://getsession.org/" rel="nofollow">Session</a>: While it involves some cryptoshit,
and hasn’t been verified yet, it’s an interesting alternative to keep
an eye out for.</li>
</ol>

<p>All things said, Signal is the shiniest turd we have — it fits most
threat models, and does the job alright; I will continue to use it.
However, here’s something to think about: while privacy preserving tech
is commendable, does it have to come at the cost of user freedoms? Hint:
it doesn’t, and it shouldn’t.</p>


 
          </article>
          <p>Questions or comments? 
          Send an email to 
          <a href="mailto:~icyphox/x@lists.sr.ht?Subject=Re:%20We%20can%20do%20better%20than%20Signal">~icyphox/x@lists.sr.ht</a>—my <a href="https://lists.sr.ht/~icyphox/x">public inbox</a>.</p>
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://icyphox.sh/blog/signal/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25811696</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 15:55:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Software Distributions and Their Roles Today]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 30 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25811596">thread link</a>) | @nwotnagrom
<br/>
January 17, 2021 | https://venam.nixers.net/blog/unix/2020/03/29/distro-pkgs.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://venam.nixers.net/blog/unix/2020/03/29/distro-pkgs.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <article>
    <p><img src="https://venam.nixers.net/blog/assets/mailroom.jpg" alt="Mailroom" loading="lazy"></p>

<p><em>NB</em>: This is a repost on this blog of a post made on <a href="https://nixers.net/showthread.php?tid=2192">nixers.net</a></p>

<h2 id="what-is-a-distribution">What is a distribution</h2>

<p>What are software distributions? You may think you know everything there
is to know about the term software distribution, but take a moment to
think about it, take a step back and try to see the big picture.</p>

<p>We often have in mind the thousands of Linux distributions when we hear
it, however, this is far from limited to Linux, BSD, Berkeley Software
Distribution, has software distribution right in the name. Android,
and iOS are software distributions too.</p>

<p>Actually, it’s so prevalent, we may have stopped paying attention to
the concept. We find it hard to put a definition together.<br>
There’s definitely the part about distributing software in it. Software
that may be commercial or not, open source or not.<br>
To understand it better maybe investigating what problems software
distributions address would clear things up.</p>

<p>Let’s imagine a world before software distributions, does that world
exist? A world where software stays within boundaries, not shared with anyone
outside.<br>
Once we break these boundaries, and we want to share it, we’ll find that we
have to package all the software together meaningfully, configure
them so that they work well together, adding some glue in between when
necessary, find the appropriate medium to distribute the bundle, get
it all from one end to another safely, make sure it installs properly,
and follow up on it.</p>

<p>Thus, software distribution is about the mechanism and the community
that takes the burden and decisions to build an assemblage of coherent
software that can be shipped.</p>

<p>The operating system, or kernel if you like, could be, and is often,
part of the collage offered, a software just like others.</p>

<p>The people behind it are called distribution maintainers, or package
maintainers. Their role vary widely, they could write the software that
stores all the packages called the repository, maintain a package manager
with its format, maintain a full operating system installer, package and
upload software they built or that someone else built on a specific time
frame/life cycle, make sure there aren’t any malicious code uploaded on
the repository, follow up on the latest security issues and bug reports,
fix third party software to fit the distribution philosophical choices
and configurations, and most importantly test, plan, and make sure
everything holds up together.<br>
These maintainers are the source of trust of the distribution, they
take responsibility for it. In fact, I think it’s more accurate to call
them distributors.</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="#target-and-speciality">Target And Speciality</a></li>
  <li><a href="#the-layering">The Layering</a></li>
  <li><a href="#stable-releases-vs-rolling">Releases vs Rolling</a></li>
  <li><a href="#interdistribution-standard">Interdistribution Standard</a></li>
  <li><a href="#method-of-distribution">Medthod of Distribution</a></li>
  <li><a href="#format">Packages Format</a></li>
  <li><a href="#resolving-dependencies">Resolving Dependencies</a></li>
  <li><a href="#versioning">Versioning</a></li>
  <li><a href="#static-vs-dynamic-linking">Static vs Dynamic Linking</a></li>
  <li><a href="#reproducibility">Reproducibility</a></li>
  <li><a href="#stateless-and-verifiable-systems">Stateless and Verifiable Systems</a></li>
  <li><a href="#do-distros-matter-with-containers-virtualisation-and-specific-and-universal-package-managers">Do Distros Matter With Containers, Virtualisation, and Specific and Universal Package Managers</a></li>
  <li><a href="#if-packages-are-self-contained">If Packages Are Self-Contained</a></li>
  <li><a href="#programming-language-package-management-specific">Programming language package management specific</a></li>
  <li><a href="#going-distro-less">Going Distro-less</a></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="different-ways-to-approach-it">Different ways to approach it</h2>

<p>There’s so many distributions it can make your head spin. The software
world is booming, especially the open source one. For instance, we can
find bifurcations of distributions that get copied by new maintainers
and divert. This creates a tree like aspect, a genealogy of both common
ancestors and/or influences in technical and philosophical choices.<br>
Overall, we now have a vibrant ecosystem where a thing learned on a
branch can help a completely unrelated leaf on another tree. There’s
something for everyone.</p>

<h3 id="target-and-speciality">Target and speciality</h3>

<p>So what could be so different between all those software distributions,
why not have a single platform that everyone can build on.</p>

<p>One thing is specialization and differentiation. Each distro caters to
a different audience and is built by a community with its philosophy.</p>

<p>Let’s go over some of them:</p>

<ul>
  <li>A distribution can support specific sets and combinations of hardware:
from CPU ISA to peripherals drivers</li>
  <li>A distribution may be specifically optimized for a type of environment:
Be it desktop, portable mobile device, servers, warehouse size computers,
embedded devices, virtualised environment, etc.</li>
  <li>A distribution can be commercially backed or not</li>
  <li>A distribution can be designed for different levels of knowledge in a
domain, professional or not. For instance, security research, scientific
computing, music production, multimedia box, HUD in cars, mobile device
interface, etc.</li>
  <li>A distribution might have been certified to follow certain standards
that need to be adhered to in professional settings, for example security
standards and hardening</li>
  <li>A distribution may have a single purpose in a commodity machine,
specific machine functionalities such as firewall, a computer cluster,
a router, etc.</li>
</ul>

<p>That all comes to the raison d’être, the philosophy of the distribution,
it guides every decision the maintainers have to make. It guides how they
configure every software, how they think about security, portability,
comprehensiveness.</p>

<p>For example, if a distribution cares about free software, it’s going to
be strict about what software it includes and what licenses it allows
in its repository, having software to check the consistency of licenses
in the core.<br>
Another example is if their goal is to target a desktop audience then
internationalization, ease of use, user-friendliness, numerous
packages, is going to be prioritized. While, again, if the
target is a real time embedded device, the size of the kernel is going
to be small, configured and optimized for this purpose, and limiting and
choosing the appropriate packages that work in this environment. Or if
it’s targeted at advanced users that love having control of their machine,
the maintainers will choose to let the users make most of the decisions,
providing as many packages as possible with the latest version possible,
with a loose way to install the distribution, having a lot of libraries
and software development tools.</p>

<p>What this means is that a distribution does anything it can to provide
sane defaults that fit its mindset. It composes and configures a layer
of components, a stack of software.</p>

<h3 id="the-layering">The layering</h3>

<p>Distribution maintainers often have at their disposition different blocks
and the ability to choose them, stacking them to create a unit we call a
software distribution. There’s a range of approaches to this, they could
choose to have more, or less, included in what they consider the <em>core</em> of
the distribution and what is externally less important to it.<br>
Moreover, sometimes they might even leave the core very small and loose,
instead providing the glue software that makes it easy for the users
to choose and swap the blocks at specific stages in time: installation,
run time, maintenance mode, etc.</p>

<p>So what are those blocks of interdependent components.</p>

<p>The first part is the method of installation, this is what everything
hinges on, the starting point.</p>

<p>The second part is the kernel, the real core of all operating systems
today. But that doesn’t mean that the distribution has to enforce
it. Some distributions may go as far as to provide multiple kernels
specialised in different things or none at all.</p>

<p>The third part is the filesystem and file hierarchy, the component that
manages where and how files are spread out on the physical or virtual
hardware. This could be a mix and match where sections of the file system
tree are stored on separate filesystems.</p>

<p>The fourth part is the init system, PID 1. This choice has generated
a lot of contention these days. PID 1 being the mother process of all
other processes on the system. What role it has and what functionalities
it should include is a subject of debate.</p>

<p>The fifth part is composed of the shell utilities, what we sometimes
refer to as the userland or user space, as it’s the first layer the user
can directly interface with to have control of the operating system, the
place where processes run. The userland implementations on Unix-based
systems usually tries to follow the POSIX standard. There are many such
implementations, also subject of contention.</p>

<p>The sixth part is made up of services and their management. The daemons,
long-running processes that keep the system in order. Many argue if the
management functionality should be part of the init system or not.</p>

<p>The seventh part is documentation. Often it is forgotten but it is still
very important.</p>

<p>The last part is about everything else, all the user interfaces and
utilities a user can have and ways to manage them on the system.</p>

<h3 id="stable-releases-vs-rolling">Stable releases vs Rolling</h3>

<p>There exists a spectrum on which distributions place themselves when
it comes to keeping up to date with the versions of the software they
provide. This most often applies to external third party open source
software.<br>
The spectrum is the following: Do we allow the users to always have the
latest version of every software while running the risk of accidentally
breaking their system, what we call bleeding edge or rolling distro, or
do we take a more conservative approach and take the time to test every
software properly before allowing it in the repository, while not having
all the latest updates, features, and optimizations of the software,
what we call release based distro.</p>

<p><strong>NB</strong>: Keep in mind that this isn’t about the software version from the
developer’s perspective but the upstream/packaged software version from
the maintainers’ perspective. The distinction lies in the selection that
package maintainers make: will their upstream changes directly affect
all users and changes “roll” downstream, or are users able to select
between multiple upstreams sources/releases. We take the eyes of the
maintainers here.</p>

<p>The extreme of the first scenario would be to let users directly download
from the software vendor/creator source code repository, or the opposite,
let the software vendor/creator push directly to the distribution
repository. Which could easily break or conflict with the user’s system
or lead to security vulnerability. …</p></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://venam.nixers.net/blog/unix/2020/03/29/distro-pkgs.html">https://venam.nixers.net/blog/unix/2020/03/29/distro-pkgs.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://venam.nixers.net/blog/unix/2020/03/29/distro-pkgs.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25811596</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 15:45:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Apple II Basic Bot]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 48 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25811294">thread link</a>) | @elvis70
<br/>
January 17, 2021 | https://atari8bitbot.com/apple-ii-bot/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://atari8bitbot.com/apple-ii-bot/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-content" role="main">

	
<article class="page" id="post-82">

	
<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>

		<div>

			
<p>Send a tweet with a short BASIC program to <a href="https://twitter.com/AppleIIBot">@AppleIIBot</a> and your program will run on an emulated Apple II computer. The bot will tweet you back with a video your program’s output!</p>



<figure></figure>



<p id="block-6d1426fc-dbf0-4f3b-8e79-3976ce3135a7">The bot accepts programs in AppleSoft BASIC, the version of BASIC that was included with the Apple II computer. The first version of BASIC (Beginners’ All-purpose Symbolic Instruction Code) was released in 1964. AppleSoft BASIC, released in 1978, added commands for using the Apple II’s graphics capabilities and other features. </p>



<p>To send your program to the bot, just start your code after @AppleIIBot. Don’t forget to hit RETURN before each new line of code.</p>



<p>You need to use (at least one) line number. Immediate mode is not supported. Don’t add RUN to the end, the bot takes care of that.</p>



<p><strong>Caveats, Warnings, and Disclaimers</strong></p>



<ul><li>If the BASIC parser can’t understand something about your program (for instance, if you forget to include line numbers) it simply won’t respond. On a real Apple II, BASIC would tell you if something was amiss. On Twitter, it really isn’t feasible. So if you don’t get a reply within three or four minutes, check your code a try again. Or ask for help — it is Twitter, after all.</li><li>The bot doesn’t support sound yet.</li></ul>



<p>You can learn the fundamentals of AppleSoft BASIC with Apple’s book <a href="https://archive.org/details/ATouchOfApplesoftBASIC/">A Touch Of Applesoft BASIC</a>. More experienced programmers who need a refresher might want to reference the <a href="https://archive.org/details/Applesoft_BASIC_Programming_Reference_Manual_Apple_Computer">Applesoft BASIC Reference Manual</a>. </p>



<p><strong>Bracket Directives</strong></p>



<p>By default, the bot starts running your program, lets it run for 3 seconds before starting to record the video. It records the video for 30 seconds. If you don’t like this standard recording behavior — for instance, if your program takes a long time to draw a fractal — you can change it with a directive at the start of your tweet.</p>



<p>The B directive tells the bot how many seconds to wait before Beginning to record. {B20} will let your program run for 20 seconds before recording begins. {B0} will start recording immediately. The maximum wait is currently 99 seconds.</p>



<p>The S directive tells the bot how many Seconds to record your program running. {S2} will will record it running for just 2 seconds. {S99} will record it for the maximum 99 seconds. If you’re going to tie up the bot for that long, make it good. </p>



<p>The {G} directive gives you an authentic, old-school green screen. The {A} directive gives you an authentic, old-school amber screen. Who needs all those fancy colors?</p>



<p>You can combine directives in one set of brackets, like this: {B30S25} or {GS5B5}</p>



<p>Direct questions about the bot to&nbsp;<a href="https://twitter.com/kaysavetz">Kay Savetz</a>.</p>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>

		</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	</div><!-- .post-inner -->

	<!-- .section-inner -->

	
</article><!-- .post -->

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://atari8bitbot.com/apple-ii-bot/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25811294</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 15:14:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Review broken products instead of new ones]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 187 | Comments 90 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25810708">thread link</a>) | @hubraumhugo
<br/>
January 17, 2021 | https://www.buyforlife.com/blog/6CNqJGMKraaQhfivS0EH6L/why-we-should-review-broken-products-instead-of-new-ones | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.buyforlife.com/blog/6CNqJGMKraaQhfivS0EH6L/why-we-should-review-broken-products-instead-of-new-ones">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="app"><div data-v-1e6f7098=""><div data-v-1e6f7098=""><div data-v-1e6f7098=""><div data-v-1e6f7098=""><p data-v-1e6f7098=""><strong data-v-1e6f7098="">For most people, the majority of positive reviews are noise on any product and they evaluate them by reading negative reviews.</strong></p><p data-v-1e6f7098="">For once, let's turn it all upside down:</p><p data-v-1e6f7098="">We should build a collection about how things break - review broken and worn-out products to teach how to identify cheap products (where are the stress points, what manufacturing techniques exist to alleviate those). Then compare those with used products well past their warranty period that&nbsp;hasn't&nbsp;broken, and look at why they haven't.</p><p data-v-1e6f7098="">Repairability also comes to mind. Everything breaks eventually because we can't cheat entropy, but when it does, can you easily repair it?</p><p data-v-1e6f7098="">Use<a data-v-1e6f7098="" href="https://www.buyforlife.com/product-submission"> our submission form</a>&nbsp;for all your broken or thrown away products. If you select "Broken" as a condition, questions about the repairability and where the stress points were will show up.</p><p><img data-v-1e6f7098="" src="https://images.ctfassets.net/ma604jmaffkl/6mzc5DExU1fnSHCxxX40ln/0460f057d136bb07369b3c64f06887ae/broken-review.png"></p><p data-v-1e6f7098="">Even if things don’t break - waiting a minimum of 6+ months or 50—100 minimum uses really makes a review relevant. That's why I recently introduced&nbsp;<a data-v-1e6f7098="" href="https://www.buyforlife.com/blog/4kpaLtbnG6MkseMj44niVV/recurring-reviews-to-track-the-whole-lifecycle-of-a-product">recurring reviews</a>&nbsp;to track the whole lifecycle of a product. After every year, the reviewer will receive an automatic reminder to assess the condition of the product, and if the reviewer is still happy with it.
</p><p data-v-1e6f7098="">Let me know what you think! </p></div></div></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.buyforlife.com/blog/6CNqJGMKraaQhfivS0EH6L/why-we-should-review-broken-products-instead-of-new-ones</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25810708</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 14:04:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The values of Emacs, the Neovim revolution, and the VSCode gorilla]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 397 | Comments 319 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25810427">thread link</a>) | @mpereira
<br/>
January 17, 2021 | https://www.murilopereira.com/the-values-of-emacs-the-neovim-revolution-and-the-vscode-gorilla/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.murilopereira.com/the-values-of-emacs-the-neovim-revolution-and-the-vscode-gorilla/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>In 2018 Bryan Cantrill gave a brilliant talk where he shared his recent
experiences with the Rust programming language. More profoundly, he
explored a facet of software that is oftentimes overlooked: the <em>values</em> of
the software we use. To paraphrase him slightly:</p><blockquote><p><em>Values</em> are defined as <em>expressions of relative importance</em>. Two things that
we’re comparing could both be good attributes. The real question is, when
you have to make a choice between two of them, what do you choose? That
choice that you make, reflects your core values.</p></blockquote><p>He goes ahead to contrast the core values of some programming languages with
the core values we demand from systems software, like operating system
kernels, file systems, microprocessors, and so on. It is a really good talk
and you should <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2wZ1pCpJUIM">watch it</a>.</p><blockquote><p>It is important to think about values because they are <em>core to the
decisions that we make</em>.</p></blockquote><p>Unlike systems software, the values demanded from text editors or IDEs vary
greatly depending on who you ask. These are much more personal tools and
make room for a diverse set of desires.</p><p>The following listing enumerates values that could be attributed to
development tools.</p><table><thead><tr><th>Value</th><th>Commentary</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><strong>Approachability</strong></td><td>Ease of getting started with for typical tasks, and contribution friendliness</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Doing one thing well</strong></td><td>Unix philosophy, fitting into an ecosystem</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Editing efficiency</strong></td><td>Fewer interactions, mnemonics, composable keystrokes, etc.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Extensibility</strong></td><td>The degree to which behavior and appearance can be changed</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Freedom</strong></td><td>Embraces <a href="https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.en.html">free</a> software, rejects proprietary software</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Integration</strong></td><td>Cohesive core and concerted third-party functionality</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Introspectability</strong></td><td>Capable of being understood and inspected ad-hoc</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Keyboard centrism</strong></td><td>Focus on keyboard interactions</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Maintainability</strong></td><td>The degree to which it can be modified without introducing faults</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Progressiveness</strong></td><td>A measure of eagerness to make progress and leverage modern technology</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Stability</strong></td><td>Things that worked before continue to work the same way</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Text centrism</strong></td><td>Text as a universal interface</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Velocity</strong></td><td>Short and focused release cycles, aligned personpower, leveraging the community effectively</td></tr></tbody></table><div><p>Before we go any further, I'd like to point that out if you care about
any of the topics discussed ahead you will likely strongly disagree
with something or the other.</p><p>That's fine! We probably just have different values.</p></div><p>In my view, Emacs has the following core values:</p><p><strong>Emacs</strong></p><ul><li>Extensibility</li><li>Freedom</li><li>Introspectability</li><li>Keyboard centrism</li><li>Stability</li><li>Text centrism</li></ul><p>We can feel the clasp of <em>stability</em> in the following—rather
poetic—exchange in the Emacs development mailing list, which also provides
useful historical perspectives.</p><blockquote><p>Emacs is older than the operating systems people use today. (It is almost
as old as the first Unix, which barely resembled the Unix of later
decades.) It is much older than Linux, the kernel.</p><p>The oldest design elements were not designed for the uses we make of them
today. And since we wrote those, people have developed other areas of
software which don’t fit Emacs very well. So there are good reasons to
redesign some of them.</p><p>However, people actually use Emacs, so a greatly incompatible change in
Emacs is as unthinkable as a greatly incompatible change in the New York
City subway.</p><p>We have to build new lines through the maze of underground pipes and
cables.</p><p>— <a href="https://lists.gnu.org/archive/html/emacs-devel/2020-09/msg00607.html">Richard Stallman in “Re: Discoverability (was: Changes for 28)” (2020)</a></p></blockquote><p>The following exchange reifies <em>freedom</em> and <em>stability</em> while demonstrating a
disinclination to <em>progressiveness</em>. Which is neither good nor bad; it’s just
what it is.</p><blockquote><p>If Emacs was to become a “modern” app tomorrow, an editor extended in Lisp
still only has appeal for a minority of programmers, much like the Lisp
language itself. Most programmers looking for easy and modern experiences
will likely stick with Atom and Sublime.</p><p>Most of the push for a “modern look” comes from the desire for Emacs to
play more nicely with proprietary platforms. Rather, the goal of Emacs is
to support platforms like GNU/Linux. Platforms that respect your freedom,
and also do not push a corporate UI/UX vision of “modernity”.</p><p>(Perhaps if we do move forward with modernization, we should think of
modernization in the context of something like GNOME rather than MacOS or
Windows. Surely Emacs could be a better citizen of GNOME.)</p><p>Given that many of the people complaining about “how Emacs looks” are not
submitting patches to fix the problem themselves, resources would be
diverted from actual functionality to “modernity”.</p><p>By the time we do major code refactoring “modernizing” Emacs on the major
proprietary platforms, what is “modern” has now once again changed, and our
resources were put towards a project with a poor return on investment.</p><p>Basically, I don’t see a “modernizing” project playing out well. We will
spend extensive time and energy on a moving target, and even if we succeed,
our Lisp-based vision still has limited appeal. Additionally, I don’t think
“modernizing” Emacs advances the cause of free software, given that there
are other more popular casual libre tools for text editing that individuals
can use.</p><p>— <a href="https://lwn.net/ml/emacs-devel/863691n4xl.wl-me%40enzu.ru/">Ahmed Khanzada in “Re: Why is emacs so square?” (2020)</a></p></blockquote><p>Core values are self-reinforcing. They attract like-minded people, who
will then defend them.</p><p>I’m an Emacs user, and reading the Emacs mailing lists serves to remind me
that my values are very different from the values held by maintainers and
core contributors. I don’t value <em>freedom</em> or <em>stability</em> nearly as strongly
and have an inner affinity for <em>progressiveness</em> and <em>velocity</em>.</p><p>One part of valuing progressiveness is constantly re-evaluating: is our
current process or technology as good as it could be? What could be
improved? How do we measure improvement? How are others solving these
problems? Were there any advances in our area that we could leverage?</p><p>* * *</p><p>Now let’s talk about Vim. I see Vim as intersecting with a few of Emacs’
values, but ultimately diverging radically with its narrow focus on
providing really efficient editing capabilities.</p><p><strong>Vim</strong></p><ul><li>Doing one thing well</li><li>Editing efficiency</li><li>Keyboard centrism</li><li>Stability</li><li>Text centrism</li></ul><p>One might notice that <em>extensibility</em> is not in the list. That’s
intentional. Vim is certainly extensible to a degree, but it just does not
compare to Emacs. Vim <em>has</em> a “plugin system”, while Emacs <em>is</em> the system.
Your code becomes part of it the moment it’s evaluated. Since I’m sticking
to <em>yes/no</em> indicators for values I’m giving it a <em>no</em>.</p><p><em>Stability</em> emanates from communications with the primary maintainer.</p><blockquote><p>Vim development is slow, it’s quite stable and still there are plenty of
bugs to fix. Adding a new feature always means new bugs, thus hardly any
new features are going to be added now. I did add a few for Vim 7.3, and
that did introduce quite a few new problems. Even though several people
said the patch worked fine.</p><p>— <a href="http://vim.1045645.n5.nabble.com/Scrolling-screen-lines-I-knew-it-s-impossible-td3358342.html#a3359206">Bram Moolenar in “Re: Scrolling screen lines, I knew, it’s impossible.”
(2011)</a></p></blockquote><p>And of course in this famous exchange in a QA session.</p><blockquote><blockquote><p>How can the community ensure that the Vim project succeeds for the
foreseeable future?</p></blockquote><p>Keep me alive.</p><p>— <a href="https://www.binpress.com/vim-creator-bram-moolenaar-interview/">Bram Moolenaar in “10 Questions with Vim’s creator” (2014)</a></p></blockquote><p>At the end of 2013, a few folks were trying to get new concurrency
primitives merged into Vim. This would empower plugin authors to create
entirely new types of functionality and by extension, make Vim better.</p><p>This is what one of them had to say about the process:</p><blockquote><p>The author of Neovim (Thiago de Arruda) tried to add support for
multi-threaded plugins to Vim and has been stymied.</p><p>I’m not sure how to get a patch merged into Vim. Bram Moolenar is the only
person with commit access, and he’s not a fan of most changes beyond bug
fixes. My co-founder and I tried to add setTimeout &amp; setInterval to
vimscript. Even six weeks of full-time effort and bending over backwards
wasn’t enough. Eventually we were just ignored.</p><p>I’ve contributed to a lot of open source projects, and the Vim community
has been the most difficult to work with. I’ve been writing C for almost
two decades, and the Vim codebase is the worst C I’ve ever seen. The
project is definitely showing its age, and I’d love for something new to
replace it.</p><p>— <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=7279358">Geoff Greer in “Neovim (HN)” (2014)</a></p></blockquote><p>While they understood that some of their values were ultimately
incompatible with the values of the Vim maintainers—who prioritized
<em>stability</em>—they still tried to push for a change, because they treasured
the <em>idea of Vim</em>, embodied by some of its values.</p><p>It didn’t happen, so a Vim fork came to life: Neovim.</p><p>The vision was grand, and is summarized in a statement of its values:</p><blockquote><p>Neovim is a Vim-based text editor engineered for <em>extensibility</em> and
<em>usability</em>, to encourage new applications and contributions.</p><p><a href="https://neovim.io/charter/">neovim.io/charter</a></p></blockquote><p>Some of their concrete plans included</p><ul><li>improving testing, tooling, and CI to simplify maintenance, make
aggressive refactorings possible, and greatly reduce contributor friction</li><li>decoupling the core from the UI, making it possible to embed the Vim core
into browsers or IDEs (or any computer program really), also making way
for more powerful and diverse GUIs</li><li>embedding a Lua runtime and providing concurrency primitives to open the
doors for smoother, more efficient, and powerful plugins</li><li>extensive refactoring: bringing C code to modern standards (C99,
leveraging new compiler features), replacing platform-specific IO code
with libuv, removing support for legacy systems and compilers, including
automatic formatting, and fixing static analysis warnings and errors</li><li>creating a scriptable terminal emulator</li></ul><p>And they delivered it.</p><p>In a very short amount of time they were able to, and I don’t use this word
lightly, <em>revolutionize</em> Vim. The impact can be seen in Vim development,
which picked up considerably as Neovim gained ground, with features and
processes ending up being reimplemented in Vim.</p><div><p>And they aren't stopping there. Current plans include:</p><ul><li>translating all Vimscript to Lua under the hood, increasing execution
performance due to leveraging LuaJIT, a very, very fast runtime</li><li>shipping a built-in LSP client</li></ul></div><p>Neovim builds upon Vim, and the way I see it, holds the following core
values:</p><p><strong>Neovim</strong></p><ul><li>Approachability</li><li>Editing efficiency</li></ul></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.murilopereira.com/the-values-of-emacs-the-neovim-revolution-and-the-vscode-gorilla/">https://www.murilopereira.com/the-values-of-emacs-the-neovim-revolution-and-the-vscode-gorilla/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.murilopereira.com/the-values-of-emacs-the-neovim-revolution-and-the-vscode-gorilla/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25810427</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 13:18:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[BitLocker Lockscreen Bypass]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 522 | Comments 114 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25810250">thread link</a>) | @rdpintqogeogsaa
<br/>
January 17, 2021 | https://secret.club/2021/01/15/bitlocker-bypass.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://secret.club/2021/01/15/bitlocker-bypass.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>BitLocker is a modern data protection feature that is deeply integrated in the Windows kernel. It is used by many corporations as a means of protecting company secrets in case of theft. Microsoft recommends that you have a Trusted Platform Module which can do some of the heavy cryptographic lifting for you.</p><p>Given a Windows 10 system without known passwords and a BitLocker-protected hard drive, an administrator account could be adding by doing the following:</p><ul><li>At the sign-in screen, select “I have forgotten my password.”</li><li>Bypass the lock and enable autoplay of removable drives.</li><li>Insert a USB stick with my .exe and a junction folder.</li><li>Run executable.</li><li>Remove the thumb drive and put it back in again, go to the main screen.</li><li>From there launch narrator, that will execute a DLL payload planted earlier.</li></ul><p>Now a user account is added called hax with password “hax” with membership in Administrators. To update the list with accounts to log into, click <em>I forgot my password</em> and then return to the main screen.</p><h2 id="bypassing-the-lock-screen"> <a href="#bypassing-the-lock-screen">Bypassing the lock screen</a></h2><p>First, we select the “I have forgotten my password/PIN” option. This option launches an additional session, with an account that gets created/deleted as needed; the user profile service calls it a default-account. It will have the first available name of defaultuser1, defaultuser100000, defaultuser100001, etc.</p><p>To escape the lock, we have to use the Narrator because if we manage to launch something, we cannot see it, but using the Narrator, we will be able to navigate it. However, how do we launch something?</p><p><img src="https://secret.club/assets/bitlockerbypass/1.png" alt=""></p><p>If we smash shift 5 times in quick succession, a link to open the Settings app appears, and the link actually works. We cannot see the launched Settings app. Giving the launched app focus is slightly tricky; you have to click the link and then click a place where the launched app would be visible with the correct timing. The easiest way to learn to do it is, keep clicking the link roughly 2 times a second. The sticky keys windows will disappear. Keep clicking! You will now see a focus box is drawn in the middle of the screen. That was the Settings app, and you have to stop clicking when it gets focus.</p><p>Now we can navigate the Settings app using CapsLock + Left Arrow, press that until we reach Home. Now, when Home has focus, hold down Caps Lock and press Enter. Using CapsLock + Right Arrow navigate to Devices and CapsLock + Enter when it is in focus.</p><p><img src="https://secret.club/assets/bitlockerbypass/2.png" alt=""></p><p>Now navigate to AutoPlay, CapsLock + Enter and choose “Open Folder to view files (File Explorer).” Now insert the prepared USB drive, wait some seconds, the Narrator will announce the drive has been opened, and the window is focused. Now select the file <strong>Exploit.exe</strong> and execute it with CapsLock + Enter. That is arbitrary code execution, ladies and gentlemen, without using any passwords. However, we are limited by running as the default profile.</p><p>I have made a video with my phone, as I cannot take screenshots.</p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZdsSgklRoag" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe><h2 id="elevation-of-privilege"> <a href="#elevation-of-privilege">Elevation of privilege</a></h2><p>When a USB stick is mounted, BitLocker will create a directory named ClientRecoveryPasswordRotation in System Volume Information and set permissions to:</p><div><div><pre><code>NT AUTHORITY\Authenticated Users:(F)
NT AUTHORITY\SYSTEM:(I)(OI)(CI)(F)
</code></pre></div></div><p>To redirect the create operation, a symbolic link in the NT namespace is needed as that allows us to control the filename, and the existence of the link does not abort the operation as it is still creating the directory.</p><p>Therefore, take a USB drive and make <code>\System Volume Information</code> a mount point targeting <code>\RPC Control</code>. Then make a symbolic link in <code>\RPC Control\ClientRecoveryPasswordRotation</code> targetting <code>\??\C:\windows\system32\Narrator.exe.local</code>. If the USB stick is reinserted then the folder <code>C:\windows\system32\Narrator.exe.local</code> will be created with permissions that allows us to create a subdirectory:</p><div><div><pre><code>amd64_microsoft.windows.common-controls_6595b64144ccf1df_6.0.18362.657_none_e6c5b579130e3898
</code></pre></div></div><p>Inside this subdirectory, we drop a payload DLL named <em>comctl32.dll</em>. Next time the Narrator is triggered, it will load the DLL. By the way, I chose the Narrator as that is triggerable from the login screen as a system service and is not auto-loaded, so if anything goes wrong, we can still boot.</p><h2 id="combining-them"> <a href="#combining-them">Combining them</a></h2><p>The <code>ClientRecoveryPasswordRotation</code> exploit to work requires a symbolic link in <code>\RPC Control</code>. The executable on the USB drive creates the link using two calls to <code>DefineDosDevice</code>, making the link permanent so they can survive a logout/in if needed.</p><p>Then a loop is started in which the executable will:</p><ul><li>Try to create the subdirectory.</li><li>Plant the payload <code>comctl32.dll</code> inside it.</li></ul><p>It is easy to see when the loop is running because the Narrator will move its focus box and say “access denied” every second. We can now use the link created in <code>RPC Control</code>. Unplug the USB stick and reinsert it. The writeable directory will be created in <code>System32</code>; on the next loop iteration, the payload will get planted, and exploit.exe will exit. To test if the exploit has been successful, close the Narrator and try to start it again.</p><p>If the narrator does not work, it is because the DLL is planted, and Narrator executes it, but it fails to add an account because it is launched as <code>defaultuser1</code>. When the payload is planted, you will need to click back to the login screen and start Narrator; 3 beeps should play, and a message box saying the DLL has been loaded as <code>SYSTEM</code> should show. Great! The account has been created, but it is not in the list. Press “I forgot my password” and click back to update the list.</p><p>A new account named hax should appear, with password hax.</p><p>I used these steps to arm the USB device</p><div><div><pre><code>C:\Users\jonas&gt;format D: /fs:ntfs /q
Insert new disk for drive D:
Press ENTER when ready...
-----
File System: NTFS.
Quick Formatting 30.0 GB
Volume label (32 characters, ENTER for none)?
Creating file system structures.
Format complete.
30.0 GB total disk space.
30.0 GB are available.
</code></pre></div></div><p>Now, we need to elevate to admin to delete <code>System Volume Information</code>.</p><div><div><pre><code>C:\Users\jonas&gt;d:
D:\&gt;takeown /F "System Volume Information"
</code></pre></div></div><p>This results in</p><div><div><pre><code>SUCCESS: The file (or folder): "D:\System Volume Information" now owned by user "DESKTOP-LTJEFST\jonas".
</code></pre></div></div><p>We can then</p><div><div><pre><code>D:\&gt;icacls "System Volume Information" /grant Everyone:(F)
Processed file: System Volume Information
Successfully processed 1 files; Failed processing 0 files
D:\&gt;rmdir /s /q "System Volume Information"
</code></pre></div></div><p>We will use James Forshaw’s tool (attached) to create the mount point.</p><div><div><pre><code>D:\&gt;createmountpoint "System Volume Information" "\RPC Control"
</code></pre></div></div><p>Then copy the attached exploit.exe to it.</p><div><div><pre><code>D:\&gt;copy c:\Users\jonas\source\repos\exploitKit\x64\Release\exploit.exe .
1 file(s) copied.
</code></pre></div></div><p>I disclosed this vulnerability and it was assigned CVE-2020-1398. Its patch can be found <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-us/vulnerability/CVE-2020-1398">here</a></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://secret.club/2021/01/15/bitlocker-bypass.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25810250</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 12:46:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Lex Fridman AI Podcast Search]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 33 | Comments 51 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25810072">thread link</a>) | @rmeinl
<br/>
January 17, 2021 | https://share.streamlit.io/rmeinl/podcast_search/app.py | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://share.streamlit.io/rmeinl/podcast_search/app.py">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://share.streamlit.io/rmeinl/podcast_search/app.py</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25810072</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 12:07:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[People that think you’re an asshole]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 44 | Comments 54 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25809346">thread link</a>) | @LeonW
<br/>
January 17, 2021 | https://leowid.com/the-people-that-think-youre-an-asshole/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://leowid.com/the-people-that-think-youre-an-asshole/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <header>    
                
            </header>

            <section>
            <div>
                <div><p>“The people that think you’re an asshole, they already think that about you now, Leo! You might as well do what you want anyway.” This Is what my friend Ed told me when I shared with him my fears about telling some grueling stories in my upcoming book. And what people might think about me when they read it and what I’ve done so far in my life. Strangely that was a huge relief.</p>
<p>On the other hand, if they don’t think so negatively about me as I’d projected when they find out about another “outing”, it’ll probably bring us closer together. In a way, it’s a win-win.</p>
<p><a href="https://leowid.com/the-6-practices-that-influenced-my-life-the-most-over-the-past-5-years/">Radical honesty</a> is a bitch, I’m learning. It hurts so bad at times but also frees me so much.</p>
<p>I’ve since mentioned this phrase of his several times with friends and in coaching sessions in various ways: those people that you think don’t like you, they already don’t like you now. Whether you do the thing or not.</p>
<p>What this leads to is courage. Courage is the thing we find when we give up on needing to be liked. Even for a brief moment. Then we are free to do what we want to do because we want to do it. This is real freedom.</p>
<p>It’s crushing and disappointing that we can’t stay there in that state of freedom. That we retreat again after a while into the darkness and the need to be liked and wanted. That’s ok, that’s life. From there, we garner and ripen the courage yet again to go out there and not care for what others think of us.</p>
<p>Along the way, we might make some friends that encourage us in this process and that back and forth. But it’s really not necessary to be too harsh on ourselves when we realize none of these states are permanent.</p>
<p>“Cheer up! You can’t blame anyone else for the kind of world that you’re in. And if you know that “I”, in the sense of the person, the front, the ego, it really doesn’t exist. Then it won’t go to your head to badly if you wake up and discover that you’re god.” is what Alan watts said, which I feel belongs here.</p>
<p>So go out there. And don’t worry about the people you fear think of you as an asshole, they already do that now anyway. You might as well take my friend Ed’s advice and do your thing regardless. Good luck and I’m here if I can help.</p>
</div>
            </div>
        </section><section>
                <div>
                    <p><img data-src="https://leowid.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Leo-Profile.jpg" data-srcset="https://leowid.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Leo-Profile.jpg 400w, https://leowid.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Leo-Profile-300x300.jpg 300w, https://leowid.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Leo-Profile-150x150.jpg 150w, https://leowid.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Leo-Profile-180x180.jpg 180w" data-sizes="(max-width: 100px) 100vw, 100px" alt="" src="https://leowid.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Leo-Profile.jpg" srcset="https://leowid.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Leo-Profile.jpg 400w, https://leowid.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Leo-Profile-300x300.jpg 300w, https://leowid.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Leo-Profile-150x150.jpg 150w, https://leowid.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Leo-Profile-180x180.jpg 180w">
                        <span>Leo Widrich</span>
                        <span>Leo Widrich coaches extraordinary people. In his previous life, he co-founded Buffer, a $20m+ revenue software company. He also lived in Buddhist monasteries for close to two years, trained as a trauma therapist and now lives in Vienna near the forest. He tweets <a href="https://twitter.com/LeoWid">@leowid</a>. To learn about working with him, <a href="https://leowid.com/working-with-me/">go here</a>.</span>
                    </p>
                </div>
            </section><section>
        <div>
            <div><h3>Receive my most vulnerable and powerful lessons from meeting life.</h3><p>Add your details below for my weekly newsletter.</p></div>
        </div>
    </section>
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://leowid.com/the-people-that-think-youre-an-asshole/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25809346</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 09:13:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[When parties reverse their stance, supporters immediately switch their opinions]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 187 | Comments 195 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25807656">thread link</a>) | @nabla9
<br/>
January 16, 2021 | https://thespeakernewsjournal.com/science/when-political-parties-reverse-their-policy-stance-their-supporters-immediately-switch-their-opinions-too/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thespeakernewsjournal.com/science/when-political-parties-reverse-their-policy-stance-their-supporters-immediately-switch-their-opinions-too/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="page">
				<div id="content">
			
	<div id="primary">
		<main id="main">
			
<article id="post-15093" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork" itemscope="">
	<div>
				
					
			
		<div itemprop="text">
			<p>At least a significant portion of their supporters, according to U of Aarhus researchers.</p>
<p>When two competing political parties in Denmark reversed their policy stance on an issue — suddenly they both supported reducing unemployment benefits — their voters immediately moved their opinions by around 15% into line with their party.</p>
<p>The same thing happened when one of these parties shifted from opposing to supporting ending Denmark’s early retirement.</p>
<p>The researchers were studying how public opinion is formed. Their recent paper sheds light on how much influence political parties have over their supporters, according to the researchers, who surveyed their panel of subjects in five successive waves between 2010 and 2011. They studied the same group of party supporters before, during and after a policy reversal.</p>
<p>“We can see that [the] welfare programs were actually quite popular … and many of the voters of the center-right party were in favor of these welfare programs,” commented one of the researchers, Rune Slothuus. “Nevertheless, we can see that they reversed their opinion from supporting these welfare programs to opposing these welfare programs.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">“I was surprised to see the parties appeared this powerful in shaping opinions,” Slothuus said. “Our findings suggest that partisan leaders can indeed lead citizens’ opinions in the real world, even in situations where the stakes are real and the economic consequences tangible.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">The researchers pondered Western democracy in light of their findings: “If citizens just blindly follow their party without thinking much about it, that should lead to some concern about the mechanisms in our democracy. Because how can partisan elites represent citizens’ views if the views of citizens are shaped by the very same elites who are supposed to represent them?”</p>
<h6 dir="ltr">Source: How Political Parties Shape Public Opinion in the Real World.  and <a id="a2_Ctrl" role="button" href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/action/doSearch?ContribAuthorStored=Bisgaard%2C+Martin" data-id="a2" data-db-target-for="a2" aria-controls="a2" aria-haspopup="true">Martin Bisgaard. </a><span>First published: </span><span>04 November 2020</span> <a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/ajps.12550" aria-label="Digital Object Identifier">https://doi.org/10.1111/ajps.12550</a></h6>

						


<div>
    <h3>The brain listens for things it is trying to predict</h3>
    <div><p>The brain interprets sounds as they contrast with its expectations; it recognizes patterns of sounds faster when they’re in line with what it is predicting it will hear, but it only encodes sounds when they contrast with expectations, according to <span>Technische U researchers. </span></p>
<p>The researchers showed this by monitoring the two principal nuclei of the subcortical pathway responsible for auditory processing: the inferior colliculus and the medial geniculate body, as their subjects listened to patterns of sounds which the researches modified so that sometimes they would hear an expected sound pattern, and other times something unexpected.</p>
<h6>Source: Alejandro Tabas, Glad Mihai, Stefan Kiebel, Robert Trampel, Katharina von Kriegstein. <strong>Abstract rules drive adaptation in the subcortical sensory pathway</strong>. <em>eLife</em>, 2020; 9 DOI: <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.64501" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">10.7554/eLife.64501</a></h6>
</div>
</div>
						


<div>
    <h3>We have a particular way of understanding a room</h3>
    <div><p>When several research subjects were instructed to explore an empty room, and when they were instead seated in a chair and watched someone else explore the room, their brain waves followed a certain pattern, as recorded by a backpack hooked up to record their brain waves, eye movements, and paths. It didn’t matter if they were walking or watching someone else, according to UC researchers led by Dr Matthias Stangl.</p>
<p>The researchers also tested what happened when subjects searched for a hidden spot, or watched someone else do so, and found that brain waves flowed more strongly when they had a goal and hunted for something.</p>
<h6>Source: Matthias Stangl, Uros Topalovic, Cory S. Inman, Sonja Hiller, Diane Villaroman, Zahra M. Aghajan, Leonardo Christov-Moore, Nicholas R. Hasulak, Vikram R. Rao, Casey H. Halpern, Dawn Eliashiv, Itzhak Fried, Nanthia Suthana. <strong>Boundary-anchored neural mechanisms of location-encoding for self and others</strong>. <em>Nature</em>, 2020; DOI: <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41586-020-03073-y" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">10.1038/s41586-020-03073-y</a></h6>
</div>
</div>
						


<div>
    <h3>Extroverts and introverts use different vocabularies</h3>
    <div><p>Extroverts use ‘positive emotion’ and ‘social process’ words more often than introverts, according to new research conducted at <span>Nanyang Technological U</span>.</p>
<p>‘Love,’ ‘happy,’ and ‘blessed’ indicate pleasant emotions, and ‘beautiful’ and ‘nice’ indicate positivity or optimism, and are among the words found to be used more often by extroverts. So too are ‘meet,’ ‘share,’ and ‘talk,’ which are about socializing. Extroverts use personal pronouns — except ‘I’ — more too, another indication of sociability.</p>
<p>The correlation, however, was small, and the researchers think that stronger linguistic indicators need to be found to achieve their general goal, which is improving machine learning approaches to targeting consumer marketing.</p>
<h6>Source: Jiayu Chen, Lin Qiu, Moon-Ho Ringo Ho. <strong>A meta-analysis of linguistic markers of extraversion: Positive emotion and social process words</strong>. <em>Journal of Research in Personality</em>, 2020; 89: 104035 DOI: <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jrp.2020.104035" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">10.1016/j.jrp.2020.104035</a></h6>
</div>
</div>
						


<div>
    <h3>WhatsApp is changing today - Users must give the app permission to send their private data to Facebook or lose account</h3>
    <div><p>WhatsApp was bought by Facebook in 2014, but has thrived while promoting itself as a privacy-respecting messaging app that now has 1.5b monthly active users. This week, though, WhatApp sent out an update to users’ phones that they must ‘consent’ to a new policy or lose access.</p>
<p>Whatsapp will now share more of your data, including your IP address (your location) and phone number, your account registration information, your transaction data, and service-related data, interactions on WhatsApp, and other data collected based on your consent, with Facebook’s other companies. Facebook has been working towards more closely integrating Facebook, WhatsApp, Instagram and Messenger.</p>
<p>Users who do not agree to ‘consent’ to the new policy will see their WhatsApp account become inaccessible until they do ‘consent.’ These accounts will remain dormant for 120 days after which they will be ‘deleted.’</p>
<p>The biggest change to the user policy, which many people ignored and clicked ‘agree’ to, thinking it was just another unimportant app update message, now reads,</p>
<blockquote><p><em>‘We collect information about your activity on our Services, like service-related, diagnostic, and performance information. This includes information about your activity (including how you use our Services, your Services settings, how you interact with others using our Services (including when you interact with a business), and the time, frequency, and duration of your activities and interactions), log files, and diagnostic, crash, website, and performance logs and reports. This also includes information about when you registered to use our Services; the features you use like our messaging, calling, Status, groups (including group name, group picture, group description), payments or business features; profile photo, “about” information; whether you are online, when you last used our Services (your “last seen”); and when you last updated your “about” information.’</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Notably, Elon Musk tweeted on the news, saying that WhatsApp users should switch to Signal, one of several popular privacy-focused messaging apps similar to WhatsApp.</p>
<p>The data sharing policy change doesn’t affect people in Europe due to GDPR data protection regulations.</p>
</div>
</div>
						


<div>
    <h3>President Trump silenced on top social media platforms after mob storms Capitol</h3>
    <div><p>The US president was locked out from posting new messages on his Facebook and Twitter accounts after an unruly group of supporters assembled outside the capitol building where Biden’s election win was being confirmed.</p>
<p>The lockdown on Twitter lasted 12 hours until the president removed tweets Twitter said violated its ‘civic integrity policy,’ but Zuckerburg said that Trump would be silenced on Facebook and Instagram for at least two more weeks until his presidential term was over. Facebook and Twitter are two of the main ways the president communicates with citizens and the world.</p>
<p>It is the first time social media platforms have chosen to limit the free speech of such an important figure.</p>
<h6><em>Trump’s tweets from Jan 6, 2020, as recorded by thetrumparchive.com</em></h6>


<p>Many news organizations covered the story using language such as <a href="https://thespeakernewsjournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Trump-Incites-Rioters.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-slb-active="1" data-slb-asset="69001008" data-slb-internal="0" data-slb-group="15093_15041">‘Trump Incites Rioters.’</a></p>
<p>Following Trumps ‘ban,’ there was renewed talk about treating social media platforms, where people share informative content, as publishers themselves, in part because their algorithms amplify things shared when those things are engaging. There was also talk about how the social media platforms that censored the president’s content did so as a response to content or events but without first drawing their ‘red line’ and saying which content is and isn’t allowed on their platforms.</p>
<p>Some of Trump’s staff resigned following the incident at the Capitol building, and there were also a lot of questions why the national guard wasn’t capable of handling the incident properly.</p>
<p>UPDATE January 8: Twitter permanently banned Trump’s account. Google removed Parler, an app like Twitter used by Trump supporters, from the Android app store to make it harder for people to download it, saying Google requires social media apps to have content moderation policies to remove posts that incite violence.</p>
</div>
</div>		</div>

				
			</div>
</article>

			

					</main>
	</div>

	

	</div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thespeakernewsjournal.com/science/when-political-parties-reverse-their-policy-stance-their-supporters-immediately-switch-their-opinions-too/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25807656</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 02:56:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Tragedy of Gemini]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 60 | Comments 28 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25807633">thread link</a>) | @panic
<br/>
January 16, 2021 | https://maya.land/monologues/2021/01/11/the-tragedy-of-gemini.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://maya.land/monologues/2021/01/11/the-tragedy-of-gemini.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://maya.land/monologues/2021/01/11/the-tragedy-of-gemini.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25807633</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 02:52:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Fun with conversion-operator name lookup]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 38 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25806846">thread link</a>) | @mmastrac
<br/>
January 16, 2021 | https://quuxplusone.github.io/blog/2021/01/13/conversion-operator-lookup/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://quuxplusone.github.io/blog/2021/01/13/conversion-operator-lookup/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p>As of this writing (but perhaps not for very much longer!) the four mainstream compilers
on Godbolt Compiler Explorer give four different answers for
<a href="https://godbolt.org/z/jo3dc4">this simple C++ program</a>:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>struct A {
    using T = T1;
    using U = U1;
    operator U1 T1::*();
    operator U1 T2::*();
    operator U2 T1::*();
    operator U2 T2::*();
};

inline auto which(U1 T1::*) { return "gcc"; }
inline auto which(U1 T2::*) { return "icc"; }
inline auto which(U2 T1::*) { return "msvc"; }
inline auto which(U2 T2::*) { return "clang"; }

int main() {
    A a;
    using T = T2;
    using U = U2;
    puts(which(a.operator U T::*()));
}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The question is whether <code>U</code> should be looked up in the scope of <code>test</code> or in the scope of <code>A</code>;
and the same question for <code>T</code>.</p>

<p>According to the current draft standard, it sounds like the conforming answer is
“they should <em>both</em> be looked up in the scope of <code>A</code>”; i.e., GCC’s answer is correct
and the others are wrong in three different ways. <a href="http://eel.is/c++draft/basic.lookup.unqual#5">[basic.lookup.unqual]/5</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>An unqualified name that is a component name of a <em>type-specifier</em> or <em>ptr-operator</em>
of a <em>conversion-type-id</em> is looked up in the same fashion as the <em>conversion-function-id</em>
in which it appears. If that lookup finds nothing, it undergoes unqualified name lookup;
in each case, only names that denote types or templates whose specializations are types are considered.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I’m never a fan of lookups that don’t consider certain <em>kinds</em> of names; I’m sure there’s more divergence
to be discovered in this area. Anyway, in the type name <code>U T::*</code>, <code>U</code> is the <em>type-specifier</em>
and <code>T::*</code> is the <em>ptr-operator</em>, and the whole type is pronounced “pointer to a data member of <code>T</code>,
where that data member itself is of type <code>U</code>.”
(More concisely: “pointer to data member (of type <code>U</code>) of <code>T</code>,” or “pointer to a <code>U</code> member of <code>T</code>.”)</p>

<p>See also:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://quuxplusone.github.io/blog/2019/09/10/friend-access-inconsistencies/">“Implementation divergence with <code>friend</code>”</a> (2019-09-10)</li>
</ul>

  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://quuxplusone.github.io/blog/2021/01/13/conversion-operator-lookup/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25806846</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 00:21:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Google sends ‘24 hour warning’ to free-speech ‘anti-Facebook’ platform, Minds]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 37 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25806746">thread link</a>) | @drummer
<br/>
January 16, 2021 | https://speakingaboutnews.com/google-sends-24-hour-warning-to-free-speech-anti-facebook-platform-minds/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://speakingaboutnews.com/google-sends-24-hour-warning-to-free-speech-anti-facebook-platform-minds/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			<p><strong>The social media platform Minds had to remove ‘major functionality’ from its Android app after getting a chilling warning from Google. Its co-founder said plans for a censorship-resistant infrastructure are in the works.</strong></p>
<p>In a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.minds.com/newsfeed/1196949029506060288" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">post</a>&nbsp;on Friday evening, Bill Ottman said that Minds had received a&nbsp;<em>“24 hour warning”</em>&nbsp;from the Google Play store. This forced them to submit an updated version of the app, based on&nbsp;<em>“interim solution and ninja developers,”</em> which removed the search, discovery and comments functionality.</p>
<p><em>“I know. We aren’t happy and will be working towards something better,”</em>&nbsp;Ottman said.&nbsp;<em>“What is happening on the internet with major providers is fueling the cultural divide as much as anything,”</em>&nbsp;he added.</p>
<p>Operating since 2015, Minds was conceived as a blockchain-based community-owned social media platform that would not monetize user data but enable free speech instead.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.wired.com/story/minds-anti-facebook/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Wired</a>&nbsp;magazine once described it as the&nbsp;<em>“anti-Facebook.”</em></p>
<p><em>Owen is joined by James O’Keefe of Project Veritas, after the explosive video released of Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey who revealed his true intentions on social media.</em></p>
<p>Ottman advised users to download the app from Minds directly if possible.&nbsp;<em>“If you are on Apple, leave if you’re smart,”</em>&nbsp;he said.</p>


<p>As for going forward, he said a plan for&nbsp;<em>“fully censorship-resistant infrastructure”</em>&nbsp;is coming soon, and that Minds has&nbsp;<em>“multiple escape pods ready to go”</em>&nbsp;if Amazon moves against them.</p>
<p>Ottman’s comments were a clear reference to what happened to Parler. The free-speech social media platform attracted tens of thousands of users purged from Twitter in the wake of the January 6 unrest at the US Capitol – only to be banned from Google and Apple stores, and then taken down from the internet entirely after Amazon Web Services (AWS) denied them access to the cloud. Parler’s executives later revealed that other vendors rushed to jump ship as well, leaving them unable to operate entirely.</p>
<p>Those who complained about the rising tide of censorship have typically been told that the First Amendment to the US Constitution did not apply to private companies and that people should&nbsp;<em>“build their own”</em>&nbsp;platforms if they disagreed. Parler’s shutdown has shown that this is near-impossible when the major players control the internet infrastructure itself, however.</p>
<p>Mainstream media and tech platforms have gone after Parler, Gab, Minds, and Telegram for allegedly having&nbsp;<em>“far-right”</em>users and allowing&nbsp;<em>“hate speech”</em>&nbsp;as content. In Parler’s case, Amazon’s ultimatum demanded moderation policies they would approve of in order to avoid removal from AWS.</p>
<p>In a lawsuit accusing Amazon of breach of contract, antitrust violations and defamation, Parler argued that this was pretextual and revealed that Amazon staff sought to find out if US President Donald Trump – freshly banned from Twitter and locked out of Facebook – had set up an account on the platform.</p>
    
    		</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://speakingaboutnews.com/google-sends-24-hour-warning-to-free-speech-anti-facebook-platform-minds/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25806746</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 00:03:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
