<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 10]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 10. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 08:23:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-10.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 08:23:37 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Annoying website features I face as a blind person]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 220 | Comments 123 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24429012">thread link</a>) | @Garbage
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://bighack.org/5-most-annoying-website-features-i-face-as-a-blind-screen-reader-user-accessibility/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bighack.org/5-most-annoying-website-features-i-face-as-a-blind-screen-reader-user-accessibility/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p><span>These are the five most annoying inaccessible web elements I face as a blind screen reader user every day, and how to fix them.
</span>
					</p><div>
						<p><span>For blind and visually impaired people like me, accessibility is the difference between us being able to use a website and clicking off it.&nbsp;</span></p>
<h2>How screen readers work</h2>
<p><span>Screen readers allow blind and visually impaired people to use computers, phones and tablets independently. Most screen readers use software, and a Text To Speech (TTS) engine, which is what converts the text from the screen reader into speech. Screen readers convert the text displayed on screen into a format that blind users can process.</span></p>
<p><span>Screen readers read out loud everything that’s on the screen and allow people to navigate using touch gestures and shortcut keys. They also work with other output devices such as a braille display.</span></p>
<p><span>As a screen reader user, here are the most common issues I encounter on a daily basis.&nbsp;</span></p>
<h2>Unlabelled links and buttons</h2>
<p><span>Screen reader users rely on links and buttons to navigate around a website and to find the information we need. If links and buttons are not labelled correctly or if at all, then it makes it difficult for screen reader users to find the information they need. Ultimately, unlabelled links make it much harder to navigate the website easily, quickly and independently.</span></p>
<p><span>For example, when linking to an about page, ‘click here’ doesn’t give any clue as to where it leads to, but ‘find out more about who we are’ is clear.</span></p>
<p><span>If links and buttons are labelled correctly, screen readers can read the label out loud. It means that blind and visually impaired people don’t have to press the link or button without knowing where it will take them.</span></p>
<p><span>As well as unlabelled elements, links and buttons that do not have a clear description are also really frustrating. They must have a clear description of where they will lead to when pressed, rather than ‘click here’. Never make your users guess where a link will take them or force them into a trial-and-error situation. This makes for tedious user experience.</span></p>
<h2>No image descriptions</h2>
<p><span>This is probably the most common issue I encounter when browsing the web.&nbsp;</span><span>Using image descriptions is essential for accessibility. Image descriptions are also known as alt text (alternative text) which is a written description of an image.</span></p>
<p><span>Screen readers read image descriptions out loud. This means that blind and visually impaired people can understand the content of the image in an accessible way.&nbsp;</span><span>If images do not have alt text, then screen readers will simply say “image” or “graphic” which gives no context or meaning.</span></p>
<p><span>Images often convey valuable information. It’s therefore important that people with a visual impairment can access this information as well.&nbsp;</span><span>Alt text should be clearly written and give an accurate description of the image.</span></p>
<p><strong>Check out <a href="https://bighack.org/how-to-write-better-alt-text-descriptions-for-accessibility/">our tips for writing better alt text</a> to ensure your images are fully accessible.</strong></p>
<h2>Poor use of headings</h2>
<p><span>For quick and easy navigation, many screen reader users navigate using various elements on the page such as headings. They are a great way to find the information we need quickly and effectively. Especially when they follow a logical heading structure with H1s, H2s and H3s helping to prioritise the content.</span></p>
<p><img src="https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x.jpg" alt="Logical heading structure begins with Heading 1, with Heading 2 sitting beneath heading 1. Heading 3 sits within heading 2 and so on." width="1958" height="1236" srcset="https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x.jpg 1958w, https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x-300x189.jpg 300w, https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x-768x485.jpg 768w, https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x-1536x970.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1958px) 100vw, 1958px" data-srcset="https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x.jpg 1958w, https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x-300x189.jpg 300w, https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x-768x485.jpg 768w, https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x-1536x970.jpg 1536w" data-src="https://bighack.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Headings@2x.jpg" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></p>
<p><span>If websites don’t use headings, it means screen reader users are unable to use the keyboard shortcuts to navigate through the webpage this way. If that’s the case, we have to resort to tabbing or arrowing through a long web page to find the information we need.</span></p>
<p>Headings also help to break up the web content visually and improve readability. Other elements that screen reader users use to navigate webpages include links, lists or landmarks.</p>
<h2>Inaccessible web forms</h2>
<p><span>Most websites use forms in one way or another. Whether it’s to help you search for a product or to get in touch through a contact form. However, when these forms are not labelled, or not labelled correctly, it means we cannot use them.</span></p>
<p><span>For example, if a search box is not labelled, it means screen reader users have no idea of the purpose of that box. It means people who use screen readers cannot access the same functionality.</span></p>
<p><span>Contact forms are an effective way for customers to get in touch with your brand or business. And as a screen reader user, there’s nothing more frustrating than these forms being labelled incorrectly.</span></p>
<p><span>Especially CAPTCHA checkout requirements. Without an option to hear the audio, it’s not accessible. It means we are unable to fill in the form independently. I often have to enlist help from a sighted person, but this isn’t possible for everyone.</span><b>&nbsp;</b></p>
<h2>Auto-playing audio and video</h2>
<p><span>Most people will know how annoying it is to load a web page with noisy adverts that start playing suddenly. But for screen reader users, it can be even more alarming. When video or audio starts playing automatically, it can drown out the voice of the screen reader. This makes it harder to find the pause or stop buttons.</span></p>
<p><span>(And if these buttons are unlabelled, then it’s practically impossible for me to stop the video quickly which causes extra frustration.) If I’m unable to stop the sound or video, I normally click off.</span></p>
<p><span>The solution? Make sure there’s no auto-playing video or audio when your website loads. If you really want to use video, make sure the audio is muted and the user can pause, stop or hide the media player.</span></p>
<p><span>These issues may seem small to sighted users. But they’re the difference between me being able to use a website independently or not. And they make a huge difference when implemented correctly.</span></p>
					</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bighack.org/5-most-annoying-website-features-i-face-as-a-blind-screen-reader-user-accessibility/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24429012</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 04:55:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[On moving away from a six figure consultancy to becoming an indie hacker]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 14 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24428473">thread link</a>) | @jv22222
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://matteomosca.io/how-covid-and-a-kick-scooter-turned-me-into-an-indie-hacker | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://matteomosca.io/how-covid-and-a-kick-scooter-turned-me-into-an-indie-hacker">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://matteomosca.io/how-covid-and-a-kick-scooter-turned-me-into-an-indie-hacker</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24428473</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 02:52:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The amazing $1 microcontroller (2017)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 265 | Comments 123 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24426882">thread link</a>) | @appwiz
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://jaycarlson.net/microcontrollers/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jaycarlson.net/microcontrollers/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h4>Silcon Labs EFM8: Fantastic value and ease-of-use from the only 8-bit part with a totally-free cross-platform vendor ecosystem</h4><p>The <a href="https://jaycarlson.net/pf/silicon-labs-efm8/">EFM8</a> was the fastest 8-bit part in my round-up, and admittedly, my favorite 8-bit architecture to develop with overall. What these parts lack in brains they make up for in brawns — 14-bit ADCs, 12-bit DACs, lots of timers, and a 72 MHz core clock speed that gives you timing options not found in any other part in the round-up.</p><p>Plus, this is the only 8-bit part with a totally-free, cross-platform, vendor-provided ecosystem. Let that sink in.</p><p>Keil C51 is a silly compiler, but Silicon Labs does an excellent job hiding it under the hood — even when running its Eclipse-based Simplicity Studio on Linux or macOS.</p><p>Simplicity Configurator is the lightest-weight code generator in our round-up, using only 534 bytes of flash to house the entire DMX-512 receiver project. It was one of the easiest to use, and seemed to strike a good balance between abstraction, performance, and ease of use.</p><p>Debugging speeds are snappy with a J-Link debugger, but at $35, the official Silicon Labs USB Debug Adapter is one of the cheapest first-party debugger in the round-up, and clones of the hardware are even cheaper.</p><p>And call me old-fashioned, but I think the 8051 definitely has a place in 2017 — especially among hobbyists and students, where its bit-addressable memory, easy-to-use peripherals, and fuse-free configuration help get students comfortable with microcontrollers quickly.</p><h4>Microchip megaAVR &amp; tinyAVR 1-Series: Different strokes for different folks — still with the best 8-bit toolchain available</h4><p>The <a href="https://jaycarlson.net/pf/atmel-microchip-megaavr/">megaAVR</a> came in surprisingly flat for me: especially when compared with its lower-cost, new sibling, the <a href="https://jaycarlson.net/pf/atmel-microchip-tinyavr-1-series/">tinyAVR 1-Series</a>.</p><p>There’s no comparison when it comes to price: tinyAVR has incredible value — packing in a nice assortment of timers, analog peripherals (including a DAC), and a new 20 MHz internal oscillator — while costing 20-40% less than the megaAVR.</p><p>While the megaAVR has a perplexing debugging experience that requires two completely different interfaces and protocols to work with the part, the new one-wire UPDI interface the tinyAVR sports worked flawlessly in my testing.</p><p>But that’s the crux of the problem for the tinyAVR — by shedding many of its megaAVR roots, Microchip ended up with a wonderful microcontroller that will be challenging to use for a large base of Atmel fans: indie developers and hobbyists who use low-cost, open-source programmers (which don’t support the UPDI interface).</p><p>While the tinyAVR wasn’t the fastest part in the round-up (even among 8-bitters), it was the most efficient – both in terms of active-mode power and clock efficiency. Amazingly, the AVR only uses about twice as many instructions as 16- and 32-bit parts when performing 16-bit math.</p><p>Unfortunately, the AVR system as a whole is not without its issues. The Windows-only Atmel Studio is still buggy (especially with older megaAVR devices and AVR Dragon stuff in my tests), and there isn’t an under-$50 low-cost debugger available (other than hacking apart Xplained Mini dev boards).</p><p>In many ways, there seems to be a tacit demarcation Atmel creates between its hobbyist/indie developers, and the professional shops that use Atmel parts.</p><p>As a professional embedded developer, I most definitely have access to Windows computers, and I have no problem blowing a few billable hours’ worth of pay on a $140 debugger.</p><p>But even as popular as Atmel is among hobbyists, Atmel has largely stayed out of this space directly. Instead, they’ve secured small-volume AVR sales by relying on the open-source community to build their own tools for themselves: turning out a slew of hardware and software used to program the megaAVR devices.</p><p>While I applaud the efforts of these developers, these tools are inferior to Atmel’s. Their programming speeds are terrible, they don’t support the new tinyAVR 1-Series devices, and they have absolutely no debug capability.</p><p>Having said that, both the megaAVR and tinyAVR have the best toolchain available for 8-bit MCU development. The part supports a full, end-to-end Makefile-based GCC toolchain.</p><p>If you love printf() debugging, would never touch a proprietary toolchain, and hate IDEs, megaAVR and old tinyAVR parts are definitely for you. The older ones are still available in DIP packages, and as you probably know, there are a ton of low-cost programmers available across the world. The online community is massive, and as clunky as I find Atmel START to be, I have to applaud its support for Makefile-based project generation.</p><p>Consequently, the megaAVR remains the most open-source 8-bit microcontroller on the market — by a long shot.</p><p>But I’d really like to see Microchip provide a PicKit-priced debugger with UPDI support — and allow off-board debugging the way their PIC Curiosity Boards do.</p><p>I also hope these open-source projects can add UPDI support to their tools, so that hobbyists and indie developers can start integrating the tinyAVR into their projects — it’s a much better part, and if you’re an AVR user with access to Atmel Studio, you really ought to buy an Xplained Mini board and take it for a spin.</p><h4>STM32F0: A low-cost, no-nonsense part with arguably the best Arm development ecosystem tested</h4><p><a href="https://jaycarlson.net/pf/st-stm32f0/">The STM32F0</a> was the lowest-power Arm microcontroller in the round-up, and also one of the easiest to use. STM32CubeMX doesn’t generate the most compact code on Arm (that honor belongs to Cypress PSoC Creator and Infineon DAVE), but it has a snappy interface, and the generated code is easy enough to manipulate for your own goals.</p><p>I love the nearly-stock Eclipse-based environment that System Workbench for STM32 provides, and the ST-Link and excellent Discovery/Nucleo boards seals the deal for me.</p><p>Most pros have used ST parts in their work, but for all these reasons, any hobbyist looking at moving to Arm should probably pick up a dev board from this ecosystem, too. ST has a huge market footprint, so there’s tons of resources online — aimed at both hobbyists and professionals.</p><h4>SAM D10: Killer performance &amp; peripherals, but with runtime library hiccups</h4><p>The Microchip/Atmel <a href="https://jaycarlson.net/pf/atmel-microchip-sam-d10/">SAM D10</a> (and the broader D11/D20/D21 ecosystem) has good value (considering their analog portfolio includes a DAC, and they have good timing options), and the SAM D10 was the most efficient part tested when running at full speed.</p><p>Professionals will like the easy-to-use, well-documented header files, and hobbyists will appreciate the 1.27mm-pitch SOIC package options and GCC compilers that come with the Arm ecosystem. But before I grab this part for a project, Microchip really needs to fix the extremely slow, bloated peripheral library, and update their code-gen tool to do proper error-checking of clock and peripheral configurations.</p><p>As it is, whenever I use Atmel START on the D10, I want to STOP almost immediately. And there are no current, stand-alone peripheral drivers that Microchip has released for this part, so unless you want to do register programming from scratch, you’ll be relying on third-party, open-source projects — like Alex Taradov’s <a href="https://github.com/ataradov/mcu-starter-projects">code examples</a>.</p><h4>Infineon XMC1100: Interesting peripheral perks make this Cortex-M0 stand out</h4><p>The most interesting Arm chip was, without a doubt, the <a href="https://jaycarlson.net/pf/infineon-xmc1100/">Infineon XMC1100</a> — and I think professionals who may be wary of getting out of the ST/NXP/Atmel Arm ecosystem need to take a second look at these XMC1000 (and XMC4000) parts.</p><p>The timer options are amazingly flexible, and you can squeeze fantastic performance out of the USIC module.</p><p>I’m going to go out on a limb and recommend that serious hobbyists who are building motor / lighting control projects look into these parts, too. DAVE makes setting up these complex peripherals painless, and the 38-pin TSSOP chips will be substantially easier to solder than the 0.5mm QFNs and QFPs you usually end up with in these pin counts.</p><p>Like many of the parts reviewed here, the biggest problem for hobbyists and indie developers is the tiny online communities and lack of GitHub repos with open-source projects that use these chips. My advice — be bold, and post in the forums. Infineon employees monitor and usually respond within a day or so.</p><h4>PIC16: Tons of peripherals with a slower, power-efficient core</h4><p>When you compare the <a href="https://jaycarlson.net/pf/microchip-pic16-five-digit-enhanced/">PIC16</a> with other 8-bit parts out there, it’s obviously a part built for low-power applications, and not processing power. And while the development ecosystem is workable, there are other parts more friendlier pathways — especially for smaller shops, hobbyists, and students who need extremely low-cost tools (and free software).</p><p>To add fuel to the PIC-vs-AVR debate, my testing found that a 32 MHz PIC16 is roughly equivalent to an AVR part running at 1.4 MHz (in terms of math performance), and 9 MHz (in terms of bit-shuffling performance).</p><p>Having said that, the DMX-512 receiver seems a perfect match for the PIC16, and that’s where it looks best in my testing: the PIC16 was the lowest-power 8-bit part in my testing.</p><p>It’s also full of timers and digital logic-oriented peripherals that make it suitable for funky special-purpose projects that require some crafty use of configurable logic and and the numerically-controlled oscillator — these peripherals help offload the (relatively slow) CPU, at the expense of requiring more developer familiarity with the device and these peripherals.</p><p>The usual Microchip gotchas apply: clunky IDE, expensive compilers, and expensive debuggers.</p><p>The usual Microchip advantages apply: huge online community, seemingly infinite product lifetime guarantees, and DIP, SOIC, QFP, and QFN package availability.</p><h4>PIC24: An expensive MSP430 wannabe that doesn’t hit the mark</h4><p>The <a href="https://jaycarlson.net/pf/microchip-pic24/">PIC24</a> is nearly forgettable. In the biquad test, it’s marginally faster than the <a href="https://jaycarlson.net/pf/renesas-rl-78/">Renesas RL-78</a> but uses almost three times as much power. In the DMX-512 test, both the RL-78 and MSP430 beat it, too. It was also one of the least-endowed parts in the round-up (which really just means it’s expensive — higher-end PIC24 parts have no shortage …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://jaycarlson.net/microcontrollers/">https://jaycarlson.net/microcontrollers/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jaycarlson.net/microcontrollers/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24426882</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 22:56:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Zink (OpenGL on Vulkan) performance better than expected]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 161 | Comments 86 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24424462">thread link</a>) | @mfilion
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | http://www.supergoodcode.com/funday/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.supergoodcode.com/funday/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <h2 id="just-for-fun">Just For Fun</h2>

<p>I finally managed to get a complete piglit run over the weekend, and, for my own amusement, I decided to check the timediffs against a reference run from the IRIS driver. Given that the Intel drivers are of extremely high quality (and are direct interfaces to the underlying hardware that I happen to be using), I tend to use ANV and IRIS as my references whenever I’m trying to debug things.</p>

<p>Both runs used the same base checkout from mesa, so all the core/gallium/nir parts were identical.</p>

<p>The results weren’t what I expected.</p>

<p>My expectation when I clicked into the timediffs page was that zink would be massively slower in a huge number of tests, likely to a staggering degree in some cases.</p>

<p>We were, but then also on occasion we weren’t.</p>

<p>As a final disclaimer before I dive into this, I feel like given the current state of people potentially rushing to conclusions I need to say that <strong>I’m not claiming zink is faster than a native GL driver</strong>, only that <strong>for some cases, our performance is oddly better than I expected</strong>.</p>

<h2 id="the-good">The Good</h2>
<p><img src="https://zmike.github.io/assets/piglit-misc-bench.png" alt="piglit-misc-bench.png"></p>

<p>The first thing to take note of here is that IRIS is massively better than zink in successful test completion, with a near-perfect 99.4% pass rate compared to zink’s measly 91%, and that’s across 2500 more tests too. This is important also since timediff only compares between passing tests.</p>

<p>With that said, somehow zink’s codepath is significantly faster when it comes to dealing with high numbers of varying outputs, and also, weirdly, a bunch of <code>dmat4</code> tests, even though they’re both using the same softfp64 path since my icelake hardware doesn’t support native 64bit operations.</p>

<p>I was skeptical about some of the numbers here, particularly the <code>ext_transform_feedback</code> <code>max-varying-arrays-of-arrays</code> cases, but manual tests were even weirder:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>time MESA_GLSL_CACHE_DISABLE=true MESA_LOADER_DRIVER_OVERRIDE=zink bin/ext_transform_feedback-max-varyings -auto -fbo

MESA_GLSL_CACHE_DISABLE=true MESA_LOADER_DRIVER_OVERRIDE=zink  -auto -fbo  2.13s user 0.03s system 98% cpu 2.197 total
</code></pre></div></div>

<div><div><pre><code>time MESA_GLSL_CACHE_DISABLE=true MESA_LOADER_DRIVER_OVERRIDE=iris bin/ext_transform_feedback-max-varyings -auto -fbo

MESA_GLSL_CACHE_DISABLE=true MESA_LOADER_DRIVER_OVERRIDE=iris  -auto -fbo  301.64s user 0.52s system 99% cpu 5:02.45 total
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>wat.</p>

<p>I don’t have a good explanation for this since I haven’t dug into it other than to speculate that ANV is just massively better at handling large numbers of varying outputs.</p>

<h2 id="the-bad">The Bad</h2>

<p>By contrast, zink gets thrashed pretty decisively in <code>arb_map_buffer_alignment-map-invalidate-range</code>, and we’re about <strong>150x slower</strong>.</p>

<p>Yikes. Looks like that’s going to be a target for some work since potentially an application might hit that codepath.</p>

<h2 id="the-weird">The Weird</h2>
<p><img src="https://zmike.github.io/assets/piglit-fp64-bench.png" alt="piglit-fp64-bench.png"></p>

<p>Somehow, zink is noticeably slower in a bunch of other fp64 tests (and this isn’t the full list, only a little over half). It’s strange to me that zink can perform better in certain fp64 cases but then also worse in others, but I’m assuming this is just the result of different shader optimizations happening between the drivers, shifting them onto slightly less slow parts of the softfp64 codepath in certain cases.</p>

<p>Possibly something to look into.</p>

<p>Probably not in too much depth since softfp64 is some pretty crazy stuff.</p>

<h2 id="in-closing">In Closing</h2>
<p>Tests (and especially piglit ones) are not indicative of real world performance.</p>

  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.supergoodcode.com/funday/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24424462</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 18:56:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What are the legal issues around web scraping?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 32 | Comments 18 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24424277">thread link</a>) | @neoflexycurrent
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | http://evan.law/2020/09/09/what-are-the-legal-issues-around-web-scraping/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://evan.law/2020/09/09/what-are-the-legal-issues-around-web-scraping/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="page">
				<div id="content">
			
	<div id="primary">
		<main id="main">
			
<article id="post-5792" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork" itemscope="">
	<div>
		
		<!-- .entry-header -->

		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
<figure><p>
<iframe title="Web scraping - what are the legal issues? | Evan Brown" width="900" height="506" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YA4eDamJz24?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Web scraping is that activity where a party uses automated software to crawl the internet and copy data and other content, usually so that it can compile that together and make its own product offering.  This may be of concern to you because you are a company that does web scraping. Or you may be a web publisher and there are other parties that are scraping your content. Let’s examine some of the legal issues around web scraping.</p>



<h3>Breach of contract</h3>



<p>One of the questions that commonly arises around web scraping is whether the activity is a breach of contract. More specifically, the question is whether the use of automated software violates the terms of service of the website that is being scraped. You often see website terms of service prohibit the use of spider and other automated crawling software to access and use the site. Parties who own websites that are being scraped will often look to see whether the scraping of their site is a breach of contract. </p>



<h3>Copyright infringement</h3>



<p>Another common question arising when analyzing web scraping is lawful whether scraping constitutes copyright infringement. This is a difficult argument to make if all that is being scraped is data, because mere facts usually are not subject to copyright protection. But if there is other content being scraped, such as images or specific compilations of data, the question of copyright infringement becomes a bit easier to answer in that unauthorized copying is an likely an infringement.</p>



<h3>Computer Fraud and Abuse Act</h3>



<p>The <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/18/1030" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Computer Fraud and Abuse Act</a> is another topic that often comes up in discussions about web scraping. This is a federal law that makes it unlawful for a person to access a protected computer without authorization, or in excess of a specific authorization. So the question becomes whether that access by the automated web scraper violates the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act. There are some important things that have to be proven for a plaintiff to succeed under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act, and one of those is loss or damage that results from the unauthorized access. It is a very fact intensive inquiry that has to be made,  but the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act is one thing that parties should think about in the context of web scraping. </p>



<h3>Trade secrets</h3>



<p>The question of trade secrets is another good one to raise in the context of web scraping. A trade secret is any information that a company has that gives that company a commercial advantage in the marketplace because it is secret. The information also has to be the subject of protective efforts — the company has to try to keep the information secret. For example, if information on a website is put there in a way that is behind certain protective barrier,s and the party doing the scraping circumvents those barriers, it could be that there is a misappropriation of trade secrets, particularly if that information is used for some competitive purpose. </p>



<h3>Let’s talk</h3>



<p>Web scraping legal issues can be complex. Scraping presents certain legal risks to the ones doing it, and the law provides certain powerful remedies when web scraping runs afoul of the rules. If you have questions about web scraping, give me a call at (630) 362-7237, or send me an email at <a href="mailto:ebrown@internetcases.com" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ebrown@internetcases.com</a>. </p>



<h3>About the author</h3>



<p>Evan Brown is a technology and intellectual property attorney in Chicago. This content originally appeared on <a href="http://evan.law/">evan.law</a>. </p>



<h3>See also:</h3>



<ul><li><a href="http://evan.law/2018/11/19/web-scraping-case-fails-under-dastar/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Web scraping case fails under Dastar</a></li><li><a href="http://evan.law/2012/11/01/terms-of-service-data-scraping/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Online terms of service were not effective to prohibit data scraping</a></li><li><a href="http://evan.law/2005/04/06/forum-selection-clause-upheld-in-content-scraping-case/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Forum selection clause upheld in content scraping case</a></li></ul>
		</div><!-- .entry-content -->

					<!-- .entry-meta -->
			</div><!-- .inside-article -->
</article><!-- #post-## -->

					

							</main><!-- #main -->
	</div><!-- #primary -->

	<!-- #secondary -->

	</div><!-- #content -->
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://evan.law/2020/09/09/what-are-the-legal-issues-around-web-scraping/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24424277</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 18:43:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Hoarding critical knowledge is a way to stay employed]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 13 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24423857">thread link</a>) | @qrt
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://qatalog.com/blog/post/got-knowledge | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://qatalog.com/blog/post/got-knowledge">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://qatalog.com/blog/post/got-knowledge</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24423857</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 18:02:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Backup PostgreSQL to Cloud]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 17 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24423208">thread link</a>) | @Abishek_Muthian
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://abishekmuthian.com/backup-postgresql-to-cloud/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://abishekmuthian.com/backup-postgresql-to-cloud/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>This post will help you with easy, cost-effective and secure way to backup your PostgreSQL database to cloud.</p><h3 id="create-local-scheduled-backup-of-postgresql-database">Create local scheduled backup of PostgreSQL database</h3><ol><li><p>Login as <em>postgres</em> user on the console (<a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/671422/how-to-use-tmux-on-linux-and-why-its-better-than-screen/" target="_blank">tmux</a> is recommended).</p></li><li><p>Create .pgpass file to access database without entering credentials manually.</p><pre><code>$ nano .pgpass
</code></pre></li><li><p>Enter the credentials in the following format. Making changes according to the host if necessary.</p><pre><code>localhost:5432:dbname:dbusername:dbpassword
</code></pre></li><li><p>Set permissions to the file. login_username will be <em>postgres</em>, if you are logged in as that user.</p><pre><code>$ chmod 600 .pgpass
$ chown login_username:login_username .pgpass
</code></pre></li><li><p>Set the environment variable in the <em>.profile</em> file. Where /var/lib/pgsql is the home directory for the user <em>postgres</em> in my setup.</p><pre><code>$ nano .profile

export PGPASSFILE='/var/lib/pgsql/.pgpass'
</code></pre></li><li><p>Test the login. Making changes according to host if necessary.</p><pre><code>$ psql -h localhost -U dbusername dbname
</code></pre></li></ol><h3 id="setup-restic">Setup Restic</h3><p>Restic is a free open-source backup program available for multiple distributions. <a href="https://github.com/restic/restic/releases/" target="_blank">Download</a> the one appropriate to your operating system, extract it, move it to <em>/var/lib/pgsql/bin/</em> (home directory of user <em>postgres</em>) as <em>restic</em>, make it executable and set the PATH to that folder.</p><pre><code>$ bzip2 -d restic_*_linux_amd64.bz2
$ mv restic_*_linux_amd64 /usr/bin/restic
$ chmod u+x /var/lib/pgsql/bin/restic

$ nano .profile

export PATH=$PATH:/var/lib/pgsql/bin
</code></pre><p>Creat <em>restic-pw.txt</em> file with password for encrypting the Postgres database dump.</p><pre><code>$ nano restic-pw.txt
[Enter the password for encryption]

$ chmod 600 restic-pw.txt
$ chown postgres:postgres restic-pw.txt
</code></pre><h3 id="setup-backblaze">Setup Backblaze</h3><p>Backblaze is a cloud storage service, offering easy encrypted end-to-end cloud backup solutions for home and business users.</p><p>For backing up our PostgreSQL database to their cloud, we will use their <a href="https://www.backblaze.com/b2/sign-up.html?referrer=abishekmuthian" target="_blank">B2 service</a> for backing up our
data via their API. <strong>First 10GB of storage on B2 is free as of this writing</strong>, but charges may apply when we download those data and so read the pricing details carefully.</p><p>Create a B2 account to get the following credentials and export them in <em>.bashrc</em>.</p><pre><code>$ nano .bashrc

export B2_ACCOUNT_ID="XXXXX"
export B2_ACCOUNT_KEY="XXXXX"
export RESTIC_REPOSITORY="b2:bucket-name"
export RESTIC_PASSWORD_FILE="restic-pw.txt"
</code></pre><h3 id="setup-a-cron-job-to-schedule-the-backup-and-upload">Setup a cron job to schedule the backup and upload</h3><p>Setup a cronjob to create a PostgresSQL database dump using <em>pg_dump</em> tool, here it is done every day at 23:00 hours and is upload to B2 at 00:00 hours.</p><pre><code>$ crontab -e

0 23 * * * pg_dump -U dbusername -w -F t dbname &gt; /var/lib/pgsql/db.tar
0 0 * * * . /var/lib/pgsql/.bashrc; /usr/bin/restic backup -q /var/lib/pgsql/db.tar
</code></pre><p>Note: Depending upon the size of your database, how often it changes, you might need to change the schedule for the cron job accordingly.</p><h3 id="verify">Verify</h3><p>Check the Backblaze portal to verify that the snapshot was created in our b2 bucket.</p><h3 id="downloading-the-backup">Downloading the backup</h3><p>We can download the backup using restic again, when we need it.</p><p>Get the snapshot-ID.</p><pre><code>$ restic -r b2:bucket-name snapshots
</code></pre><p>Restore the snapshot to a folder using the snapshot_ID.</p><pre><code>$ restic -r b2:bucket-name restore snapshot_ID -t /tmp/restic-restore
</code></pre><p>Note: When downloading the snapshot in another machine, requisite credentials for restic and b2 should be provided as discussed earlier.</p><h3 id="retrieving-the-postgres-dump">Retrieving the Postgres dump</h3><p>Postgres dump would be available in the folder where the snapshot was restored.</p><pre><code>$ cd /tmp/restic-restore
</code></pre><h3 id="restoring-the-postgres-dump">Restoring the Postgres dump</h3><p>Create a database of the same name after logging in as the database user.</p><pre><code>$ CREATE DATABASE dbname;
</code></pre><p>Use the <em>pg_restore</em> tool to restore the database from the dump.</p><pre><code>$ pg_restore --dbname=dbname --verbose db.tar
</code></pre><p>That’s all, now we can have a safe and reliable backup postgres database in the cloud. You can <a href="https://twitter.com/heavyinfo" target="_blank">tweet</a> to me for queries and share this if you found it useful.</p><h3 id="backblaze-entire-storage-backup-solutions-for-home-and-business">Backblaze entire storage backup solutions for Home and Business</h3><p>If you would like unlimited automated backup your entire computer storage instead, then Backblaze has solutions for home and businesses users. Check them out using my affiliate links.</p><p><a href="https://www.backblaze.com/cloud-backup.html#af9vgw" target="_blank">Backblaze unlimited cloud backup for home users</a>.</p><p><a href="https://www.backblaze.com/business-backup.html#af9vgw" target="_blank">Backblaze business backup</a>.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://abishekmuthian.com/backup-postgresql-to-cloud/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24423208</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 17:12:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Classes are a way of writing higher order functions]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 114 | Comments 130 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24422547">thread link</a>) | @stopachka
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://stopa.io/post/250 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://stopa.io/post/250">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span><p>Joe and I recently <a href="https://twitter.com/stopachka/status/1295411936625074178" target="_blank">kicked off a re-read of SICP</a>. I can say that it is <em>the</em> most interesting textbook I have gone through. Imagine, you begin with just 4 or 5 constructs, and you end up building algebraic equation solvers, circuit simulators, and even logic programming languages. Because you start off with such few constructs, the added benefit is that you begin to see the fundamentally simple, shared essence in programming. </p><p>I wanted to give you one example that surprised me in the book. We tend to think that <strong>classes belong in a</strong> <strong>fundamentally different category</strong> <strong>from functions.</strong> </p><p>But are they so different? </p><p>For example, let’s say we have a class like this:</p><pre><code>class Person { 
  constructor(firstName, lastName) {
    this.fName = firstName; 
    this.lName = lastName;
  }
  getFullName() { 
    return this.fName + ' ' + this.lName;
  }
  setFirstName(firstName) {
    this.fName = firstName;
  }
}</code></pre><p>Well, if we think about it, this is really just a higher order function. a <code>Person</code> higher order function accepts arguments (constructor), and returns a list of functions that can manipulate those arguments (methods). We could write <code>Person</code> like this: </p><pre><code> function Person(firstName, lastName) {
  let fName = firstName; 
  let lName = lastName;

  function getFullName() { 
    return fName + ' ' + lName;
  }
  
  function setFirstName(firstName) { 
    fName = firstName
  }

  return function(method) { 
    switch (method) { 
      case 'getFullName': 
        return getFullName;
      case 'setFirstName': 
        return setFirstName;  
    }
  }
}</code></pre><p>Now, </p><pre><code>const person = new Person("Ben", "Bitdiddle")
person.getFullName()</code></pre><p>becomes</p><pre><code>const person = Person("Ben", "Bitdiddle")
person('getFullName')()</code></pre><p>Here, instead of invoking a method, we are “passing” a message. This is why by the way, many classic OO folks talk about object orientation really being about message passing.  </p><p>Yup, really. Classes are just higher order functions, which accept arguments (constructor) and return a list of functions that can manipulate those arguments (methods). </p><p>When you previously thought two concepts were different, but they turn out to be the same, you’re ripe to discover new ideas: you can find the deeper abstractions between them, apply ideas from across those seemingly different categories, and move between concepts more fluidly. So, not only are epiphanies like this fun, but they’re much more useful than you’d think. </p><p>If you liked this, there are a <em>ton</em> of similar epiphanies in the textbook. To experience it best, I suggest picking a partner and working through the book together.</p><p><em>Thanks to Daniel Woelfel, Alex Reichert, Jacky Wang for reviewing drafts of this essay</em></p></span></p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://stopa.io/post/250</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24422547</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 16:16:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[No-Code vs. Pro-Code: A New Hope]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 91 | Comments 18 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24421767">thread link</a>) | @ochiba
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://journeyapps.com/engineering-blog/no-code-vs-pro-code-a-new-hope/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://journeyapps.com/engineering-blog/no-code-vs-pro-code-a-new-hope/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              <p>When it comes to building apps, no-code is having its moment. Typeform is a shining example of how no-code is well suited for simple use cases, and here at JourneyApps we use it extensively. However, therein lies the problem: No-code’s sweet spot is simple use cases. This limitation of no-code tools has been well analyzed. [<a href="https://journeyapps.com/blog/low-code-road-to-software-enlightenment-part-1/">1</a>][<a href="https://www.alexhudson.com/2020/01/13/the-no-code-delusion/">2</a>]</p>

<p>If you want to build more sophisticated custom software, you essentially have two options:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Use a no-code/low-code tool and jump through nasty hoops to implement the sophisticated parts of your app — which most often means writing actual code that needs to conform to the constraints of the tool.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Use pro-code tools such as Swift/Objective-C, or frameworks like Xamarin/MAUI, etc.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p><img src="https://journeyapps.com/assets/images/blog/2020-09-08-no-code-vs-pro-code-a-new-hope/1.png" alt="image"></p>

<p><em>Image: building anything beyond basic logic with a visual programming language ends up looking like this</em></p>

<h3 id="a-big-problem-that-needs-solving">A Big Problem That Needs Solving</h3>

<p>Both of the above approaches (using pro-code, or using a low-code platform’s pro-code extensibility) are time-consuming, although for different reasons. Both also require senior developer talent, while senior developers are as scarce as hen’s teeth.</p>

<p>The result is that many companies are highly constrained while executing on ambitious software and digital initiatives.</p>

<p>These are the companies that we serve. Enterprise developers have been building custom apps using code on JourneyApps since 2009.</p>

<p>Towards the end of 2019 we wanted to up the ante. We wanted to offer a new app development paradigm for companies with a large app backlog, especially where a big chunk of that backlog consisted of ambitious B2E and B2B apps.</p>

<p>We set two high level goals for ourselves: help companies write great software much more productively (especially those whose core focus is not software), and let them do this using modern software technologies and best practices, without the typical barriers.</p>

<h3 id="key-tenets-of-what-we-set-out-to-build">Key Tenets of What We Set Out to Build</h3>

<p>We decided that the best thing we could do was to build a next-generation IDE (as a complement to our full-stack app platform) that has the <strong>power and flexibility of pro-code</strong> at its core, but also has the high <strong>development velocity and easy adoption of no-code/low-code platforms</strong>.</p>

<p>From the start, we decided that some things are non-negotiable:</p>

<h4 id="1-coding-should-be-easy">1. Coding should be easy</h4>

<ul>
  <li>Creating a new app shouldn’t require any configuration or setup.</li>
  <li>Developers should be able to start coding immediately.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="2-coding-should-have-a-fast-feedback-loop">2. Coding should have a fast feedback loop</h4>

<ul>
  <li>We will have a first-class IDE with real-time error checking, keyboard shortcuts, IntelliSense, etc.</li>
  <li>Developers should have access to a real debugger.</li>
  <li>We will have live, stateful hot reload on an actual device in development mode — not a time-consuming compile &amp; deploy process.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="3-coding-in-the-ide-should-be-fun-and-relevant">3. Coding in the IDE should be fun and relevant</h4>

<ul>
  <li>We will not use a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain-specific_language">DSL</a>: We will support open-source programming languages – preferably those with gradual typing.</li>
  <li>We will not use convoluted proprietary visual interfaces.</li>
  <li>We will not use a proprietary “app store”. Developers must be able to import open source packages.</li>
  <li>The IDE should be easily accessible to junior developers.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="4-coding-should-be-as-efficient-as-possible">4. Coding should be as efficient as possible</h4>

<ul>
  <li>We will provide developers with powerful functionality that can be used with minimal lines of code, and customized as required. This will include things like bi-directional relational offline data sync, dozens of UI components including Excel-like data grids, full audit trails, a cross-platform BLE engine, to name just a few.</li>
  <li>We will offer full git support with either hosted git, or external git providers (e.g. GitHub)</li>
  <li>We will support unit testing.</li>
  <li>We will support multiple environments, with easy portability of changes as new versions of software are moved from one environment to the next.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="5-there-should-always-be-an-escape-hatch">5. There should always be an escape hatch</h4>

<ul>
  <li>There will be APIs for everything.</li>
  <li>We will allow developers to easily mix in fully custom HTML in their UIs, and allow those custom HTML components to communicate bidirectionally with the rest of the frontend stack, when required.</li>
  <li>There will be a Node.js environment in our cloud backend where developers can build any custom backend functionality, without any configuration or setup.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="6-the-platform-should-be-secure-by-design">6. The platform should be secure by design</h4>

<h3 id="a-foundational-decision-building-a-web-ide">A Foundational Decision: Building a Web IDE</h3>

<p>We were taking the time to figure out a new approach to app development from first principles, so we had to make big design decisions with significant trade-offs. One major early decision was whether to build a web-based IDE or an installable desktop IDE.</p>

<p>The obvious question is: “Why an IDE on the web?”. We strongly believe that the recent developments across browser technology, transpiled languages and new approaches to software development (such as declarative UI) have made it possible to not only reach a desktop-grade level of quality in a web IDE, but also capitalize on the inherent benefits of the web paradigm.</p>

<p>Using this approach, we would have an IDE that is evergreen, cross-platform, cross-device, backed by modern UI and most importantly, ready for the future. Oh, and there would be nothing to install. Perhaps the biggest win, however, would be our ability to innovate quickly due to the open nature of web technologies and how quickly they evolve.</p>

<p>We’ll discuss other key design decisions in separate posts.</p>

<h3 id="unveiling-the-solution">Unveiling the Solution</h3>

<p>Today, we’re incredibly proud to announce <a href="https://journeyapps.com/platform/oxide/">OXIDE</a>. It’s the fruit of a lot of hard work by the JourneyApps team over the past year.</p>

<p>OXIDE helps both junior and senior developers build sophisticated cross-platform apps using JavaScript or TypeScript, complemented by visual tools. Apps can run natively on mobile and desktop operating systems, or in the browser as PWAs. Under the hood, OXIDE uses CRDTs [<a href="https://blog.kevinjahns.de/are-crdts-suitable-for-shared-editing/">3</a>] to enable live co-editing in teams, and it is deeply integrated with both GitHub and npm. In OXIDE, developers can switch between visual editing and coding for UI layout and schema design. Developers also have access to a first-class code debugging tool.</p>

<p>OXIDE is a fundamental pillar of the broader JourneyApps platform. Therefore, all apps inherit other flagship JourneyApps technologies out of the box — technologies that have seen around 10 years of R&amp;D and battle-hardening:</p>

<ul>
  <li>All apps ship with an enterprise-grade BaaS, and it’s easy to integrate with other data sources (in part because the platform is not based on a DSL).</li>
  <li>All apps are offline-first: Data is automatically synced to user devices, and loaded from the local database on each view. Querying data is fast. This avoids complicated state management and/or query cache systems. (What happens when data volumes scale? The platform provides highly configurable <a href="https://docs.journeyapps.com/reference/container/introduction-to-sync-rules">selective syncing.</a>)</li>
  <li>Each app is automatically provisioned with a Node.js serverless compute environment so that developers of all skill levels can add server-side logic and functionality.</li>
  <li>Developers have access to a rich built-in UI component set that is designed to work with data, with very little development overhead. No tweaking of styles or adding event listeners and state management to each component — this is handled for you.</li>
</ul>

<p>In general, JourneyApps takes the complexity out of the development cycle. We take care of the hard problems of enterprise software development (hosting, offline data sync, mobile app builds, backend APIs, deployment tooling, audit trails, and more) so that developers can focus on core app requirements and maximize the rate of innovation at their companies.</p>

<p>Working in OXIDE looks like this:</p>

<p><img src="https://journeyapps.com/assets/images/blog/2020-09-08-no-code-vs-pro-code-a-new-hope/2.png" alt="image"></p>

<p>And here’s a view of a debugging session. The app can be seen on the bottom right (running on macOS), the Chrome developer tools on the top right, and OXIDE on the left:</p>

<p><img src="https://journeyapps.com/assets/images/blog/2020-09-08-no-code-vs-pro-code-a-new-hope/3.png" alt="image"></p>

<p>Try it out and let us know what you think — <a href="https://accounts.journeyapps.com/portal/free-trial?utm_source=engineering-blog&amp;utm_medium=internal&amp;utm_campaign=engineering-blog">start building</a>.</p>


            </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://journeyapps.com/engineering-blog/no-code-vs-pro-code-a-new-hope/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24421767</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 15:01:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Designing New Cryptography for Non-Standard Threat Models]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 30 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24421073">thread link</a>) | @some_furry
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://soatok.blog/2020/09/09/designing-new-cryptography-for-non-standard-threat-models/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://soatok.blog/2020/09/09/designing-new-cryptography-for-non-standard-threat-models/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

		<div>

			
<p>Since the IETF’s CFRG decided to recommend OPAQUE as a next-generation <a href="https://soatok.blog/2020/04/21/authenticated-key-exchanges/">Password Authenticated Key Exchange</a>, there has been a lot of buzz in the cryptography community about committing authenticated encryption (known to the more academically inclined as Random Key Robustness), because OPAQUE requires <a href="https://mailarchive.ietf.org/arch/msg/cfrg/2W9LoeeiRzAiTWVnDsyxvjYPPmo/">an RKR-secure AE scheme</a>.</p>



<p>Random Key Robustness is a property that some symmetric encryption modes have, where it’s not feasible to decrypt a valid (ciphertext, tag) pair into two different plaintexts if both recipients are using different keys.</p>



<p>To illustrate this visually:</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="1348" data-permalink="https://soatok.blog/robustness/" data-orig-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/robustness.png" data-orig-size="750,550" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="robustness" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/robustness.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/robustness.png?w=580" src="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/robustness.png" alt="An example of random key robustness: encrypting two different images, with two different keys, can produce an identical stream of bits (ciphertext + tag)."><figcaption>RKR-secure ciphers don’t let people produce the same ciphertext+tag from two different plaintexts, with two different keys. You might be able to create an identical ciphertext, but the authentication tag will differ. (Art by <a href="https://twitter.com/SwizzlestixUK">Swizz</a>.)</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>In the wake of the CFRG discussion, it became immediately clear that <a href="https://soatok.blog/2020/05/13/why-aes-gcm-sucks/">AES-GCM doesn’t meet this requirement</a>.</p>



<p>What wasn’t immediately clear is <a href="https://keymaterial.net/2020/09/07/invisible-salamanders-in-aes-gcm-siv/">that AES-GCM-SIV also falls short</a>. But don’t take my word for it, Sophie Schmieg worked out the math in the linked post, which I highly recommend reading.</p>



<p>This isn’t to say that AES-GCM or AES-GCM-SIV are doomed, or should be deprecated. You probably don’t even care about Random Key Robustness in most of the places you’d use either algorithm! But if you are doing something where RKR actually matters, you probably care a lot. And it certainly violates the principle of least astonishment.</p>



<p>ChaCha20-Poly1305 won’t save you here either, since this is a property that message authentication codes based on cryptographic hash functions (e.g. HMAC) provide, but polynomial MACs (GMAC, Poly1305, etc.) do not.</p>



<p>So, if every standardized and widely-supported AEAD construction fails to provide RKR security, what’s a software engineer to do?<em> <a href="https://vnhacker.blogspot.com/2020/08/so-you-want-to-roll-your-own-crypto.html">Roll their own crypto</a>?!</em></p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="61" data-permalink="https://soatok.blog/glitch-ecb/" data-orig-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/glitch-ecb.png" data-orig-size="224,224" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="glitch-ecb" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/glitch-ecb.png?w=224" data-large-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/glitch-ecb.png?w=224" src="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/glitch-ecb.png" alt=""><figcaption>Don’t actually do that. (Art by <a href="https://twitter.com/SwizzlestixUK">Swizz</a>.)</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>If you’re always on a well-tread path with a well-defined, standard threat model (i.e. client-server application accessible via TLS 1.3, possibly storing hashed passwords server-side), then rolling your own crypto isn’t just dangerous; it’s wholly unnecessary.</p>



<h2 id="coping-with-nonstandard-threat-models">Coping with Non-Standard Threat Models</h2>



<p>Systems that require Random Key Robustness do not fall within the standard threat model of AEAD cipher constructions.</p>



<p>However, RKR is far from the only scenario in which application developers might find themselves without a clear solution. Another example that comes up a lot:</p>



<blockquote><p>“I need to encrypt data in a relational database, but still somehow use it in SELECT queries.”</p><cite>— Far too many damn developers who haven’t heard of <a href="https://ciphersweet.paragonie.com/">CipherSweet</a>.</cite></blockquote>



<p>The first thing that you should do is clearly document your requirements and what attacks your system must protect against. Any undefined attack vector in your model should be assumed to be a vulnerability in your design. (This gets into <a href="https://www.cryptofails.com/post/75204435608/write-crypto-code-dont-publish-it">Unknown Unknowns</a> territory quickly.)</p>



<p>And then you should have a cryptographer review your design, and then have a cryptography engineer build it for you.</p>



<p><strong><em>But where’s the fun in that?</em></strong></p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="1332" data-permalink="https://soatok.blog/soatoktelegrams2020-07/" data-orig-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-07.png" data-orig-size="512,512" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="SoatokTelegrams2020-07" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-07.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-07.png?w=512" src="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-07.png?w=512" alt="" srcset="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-07.png 512w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-07.png?w=150 150w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-07.png?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px"><figcaption>This would be a very boring blog post if I left it at that! (Art by <a href="https://twitter.com/lynxvsjackalope">Khia</a>.)</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Instead of copping out with sane and reasonable advice, let’s actually walk through the process. At the end of this post, I’ll share a toy example I cooked up for this blog post.</p>



<h2 id="designing-new-cryptography">Designing New Cryptography</h2>



<h3 id="understand-the-problem">First, Understand the Problem</h3>



<p>Why don’t AES-GCM, etc. provide Random Key Robustness? Because they’re built with universal hash functions rather than cryptographic hash functions.</p>



<p>Cryptographic hash functions have different properties (i.e. preimage resistance and collision resistance) that make it significantly difficult to calculate two different authentication tags under two different keys. Attacking HMAC-SHA-256 in this way is about <a href="https://pthree.org/2016/06/19/the-physics-of-brute-force/">as expensive as brute forcing a 128-bit AES key</a>. (Good luck with that!)</p>



<p>However, cryptographic hash functions are much slower than polynomial MACs, and using them in a construction like HMAC approximately doubles the slowness.</p>



<p>You might be tempted to just hash they key and the message together to save on CPU cycles, but that’s actually <a href="https://blog.skullsecurity.org/2012/everything-you-need-to-know-about-hash-length-extension-attacks">not safe for the hash functions nearly everybody uses</a> (due to length extension attacks).</p>



<p>It logically follows that, <strong>if we had an AEAD cipher construction based on a hash function, we could have RKR security</strong>.</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="1331" data-permalink="https://soatok.blog/soatoktelegrams2020-06/" data-orig-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-06.png" data-orig-size="512,512" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="SoatokTelegrams2020-06" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-06.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-06.png?w=512" src="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-06.png?w=512" alt="OwO *notices your cryptogrpahic robustness*" srcset="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-06.png 512w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-06.png?w=150 150w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-06.png?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px"><figcaption>Now we’re getting somewhere! (Art by <a href="https://twitter.com/lynxvsjackalope">Khia</a>.)</figcaption></figure></div>



<h3 id="prior-art">Look At Prior Art</h3>



<p>Before the days of AES-GCM and ChaCha20-Poly1305, there were a lot of ad hoc constructions used everywhere based on <a href="https://soatok.blog/2020/07/12/comparison-of-symmetric-encryption-methods/#aes-gcm-vs-aes-cbc">AES-CBC and HMAC</a>. (In that era, everyone used HMAC-SHA1, but don’t do that.)</p>



<p>However, there are a number of problems with ad hoc CBC+HMAC that we don’t want to reintroduce in modern systems:</p>



<ol><li>If you forget to include the initialization vector in the HMAC tag, you give attackers free reign over the first 16 bytes of the decrypted plaintext without having to break the MAC.</li><li>The order of operations (Encrypt-then-MAC, MAC-then-Encrypt, Encrypt and MAC) matters tremendously.</li><li>CBC+HMAC is usually implemented in application-layer code, but the security of such a construction depends heavily on the availability and utilization of <a href="https://soatok.blog/2020/08/27/soatoks-guide-to-side-channel-attacks/#string-comparison">constant-time functions</a>.</li><li>There is no standard format for CBC+HMAC, nor the order of operations for what gets fed into the MAC.<ul><li>IV + ciphertext? Ciphertext + IV?</li></ul><ul><li>Append the MAC, or prepend it?</li></ul></li><li>CBC+HMAC is only an AE mode, there is no room for additional authenticated data. If you try to naively shove extra data into the HMAC, <em>now you have to worry about canonicalization attacks</em>!</li><li>CBC mode requires padding (usually PKCS #7 padding), whereas cipher modes based on CTR do not.</li></ol>



<p>This is among the long list of reasons why cryptographers have spent the past decade (or longer) pushing developers towards AEAD modes.</p>



<p>Boring cryptography is good cryptography!</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="1210" data-permalink="https://soatok.blog/soatok_stickerpack_ind_cca2/" data-orig-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatok_stickerpack_ind_cca2.png" data-orig-size="512,512" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Soatok_STICKERPACK_IND_CCA2" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatok_stickerpack_ind_cca2.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatok_stickerpack_ind_cca2.png?w=512" src="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatok_stickerpack_ind_cca2.png?w=512" alt="This isn't IND-CCA2 Secure!" srcset="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatok_stickerpack_ind_cca2.png 512w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatok_stickerpack_ind_cca2.png?w=150 150w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatok_stickerpack_ind_cca2.png?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px"><figcaption>You never want to hear this about your design. (Art by <a href="https://twitter.com/lynxvsjackalope">Khia</a>.)</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Make sure you clearly understand the risks of the components other constructions have used.</p>



<h3 id="sketch-first-draft">Sketch Out A First Draft</h3>



<p>By now, it should be clear that if we have an Encrypt-then-MAC construction, where the MAC is based on a cryptographic hash function (e.g. SHA-256), we may be able to attain RKR security.</p>



<p>With that in mind, our sketch will probably look something like this:</p>



<ul><li>Encrypt(K1, M, N) -&gt; C<ul><li>Where Encrypt() is AES-CTR or equivalent</li></ul></li><li>Auth(K2, C, A) -&gt; T<ul><li>Where Auth() wraps HMAC-SHA2 or equivalent</li><li>How we feed C and A into the underlying MAC is important</li></ul></li><li>???? -&gt; K1, K2</li></ul>



<p>We still have to define some way of splitting a key (K) into two distinct keys (K1, K2). You never want to use a cryptographic key for more than one purpose, after all.</p>



<h3>Key-Splitting and Robustness</h3>



<p>Your encryption key and authentication key should be different, but they should also derived from the same input key! This is mainly to protect implementors from having independent keys and accidentally creating a forgery vulnerability.</p>



<p>There are several different ways you can split keys:</p>



<ol><li>Just use SHA-512(k), then cut it in half. Use one half for encryption, the other for authentication.</li><li>Use HMAC-SHA256(k, c1) and HMAC-SHA256(k, c2), where c1 and c2 are distinct (yet arbitrary) constants.</li><li>Use HKDF. This works with any secure cryptographic hash function, and was specifically designed for situations like this. HKDF also supports salting, which can be used to randomize our derived keys.</li></ol>



<p>We can really pick any of these three and be safe, but I’d advise against the first option. HKDF uses HMAC under-the-hood, so either of the latter options is fine.</p>



<h3 id="speed">Can We Make it Faster?</h3>



<p>What if, instead of HMAC-SHA256, we used <a href="https://github.com/BLAKE3-team/BLAKE3">BLAKE3</a>?</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="1362" data-permalink="https://soatok.blog/blake3/" data-orig-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/blake3.png" data-orig-size="1251,913" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="blake3" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/blake3.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/blake3.png?w=580" src="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/blake3.png" alt=""><figcaption>BLAKE3’s performance compared with other hash functions.</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>BLAKE3’s advertised 6.8 GiB/s can be even faster than <a href="https://crypto.stackexchange.com/a/60269">Poly1305 or GHASH</a> (and BLAKE3’s speed really shines through with long messages, due to its extreme parallelism through Merkle trees).</p>



<h3 id="chacha-vs-aes">In Favor of ChaCha over AES</h3>



<p>It’s no secret that <a href="https://soatok.blog/2020/05/13/why-aes-gcm-sucks/">I’m not a fan of AES</a>. It’s not the mathematical properties of AES that bother me, it’s the 128-bit block size and the fact that software implementations have to decide between being fast or being secure.</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="116" data-permalink="https://soatok.blog/soatok_stickerpack-facepaw/" data-orig-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-facepaw.png" data-orig-size="512,512" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Facepaw!" data-image-description="<p>Facepaw!</p>
" data-medium-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-facepaw.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-facepaw.png?w=512" src="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-facepaw.png?w=512" alt="Facepaw" srcset="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-facepaw.png 512w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-facepaw.png?w=150 150w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-facepaw.png?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px"><figcaption>Me, whenever I find an insecure software AES implementation. (Art by <a href="https://twitter.com/lynxvsjackalope">Khia</a>.)</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>ChaCha’s 256-bit security level is easier to justify: The underlying PRF state is 512 bits (which implies an approximately 256-bit security level) and the keys are always 256 bits.</p>



<p><s>Furthermore, if you’re building ChaCha and BLAKE3 in the same codebase, you could reuse some components (i.e. the compression function, G). This is very desirable if you’re trying to ship a small amount of code (e.g. embedded systems).</s> EDIT: <a href="https://twitter.com/veorq">One of the BLAKE3 authors</a> informed me that I’m mistaken about this: “[N]ope, not exactly the same logic (rotations in different direction)”.</p>



<h3 id="other-desirable-properties">Other Desirable Security Properties</h3>



<h4 id="nonces">Nonce Nonsense</h4>



<p>One of the biggest problems with standard AEAD modes is that they explode gloriously when you reuse a nonce. There are two ways out of this peril:</p>



<ol><li>Use a nonce misuse resistant AEAD construction (AES-GCM-SIV, etc.).<ul><li>For prior art on nonce-misuse resistant cipher modes based on ChaCha, check out <a href="https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/067">DAENCE</a>.</li></ul></li><li>Use large nonces (e.g. XChaCha20 uses 192-bit nonces) and generate them randomly, so the probability of nonce reuse becomes negligible.</li></ol>



<p>Since we’re already planning on using a hash function to derive subkeys (one for encryption, one for authentication), it makes sense to also accept a longer nonce than our stream cipher demands. The excess bytes can be passed to our KDF without significant risk or additional overhead.</p>



<p>Since the IETF’s ChaCha20 variant expects a 96-bit nonce, designing our construction to support 256-bit nonces means we can pass the first 160 bits of the nonce to the KDF and the latter 96 bits to the stream cipher. You can expect a single KDF collision after 2^80 encryptions, but it will almost certainly occur with a different nonce.</p>



<h4 id="safe-mac-canonicalization">Safe MAC Canonicalization</h4>



<p>We want to ensure it’s …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://soatok.blog/2020/09/09/designing-new-cryptography-for-non-standard-threat-models/">https://soatok.blog/2020/09/09/designing-new-cryptography-for-non-standard-threat-models/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://soatok.blog/2020/09/09/designing-new-cryptography-for-non-standard-threat-models/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24421073</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 14:03:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: XML Fiddler – tool for quick XML exploration]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 59 | Comments 17 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24419947">thread link</a>) | @masa331
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://masa331.github.io/xml_fiddler/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://masa331.github.io/xml_fiddler/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://masa331.github.io/xml_fiddler/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24419947</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 11:45:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How WebAssembly Changes Software Distribution]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 82 | Comments 66 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24419081">thread link</a>) | @ingve
<br/>
September 9, 2020 | https://desiatov.com/why-webassembly/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://desiatov.com/why-webassembly/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-reactid="51"><p>If you had any experience with Windows and Internet Explorer in the 90s,
quite probably you remember <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ActiveX">ActiveX</a> controls. Most
frequently this involved bulky popups on pages with these controls having to display something
more complex than a few blocks of text.</p>
<p><img src="https://desiatov.com/activex-0f260342e5426a0cc883966575235fe3.gif" alt="Internet Explorer displaying an alert that requires ActiveX controls to be installed"></p>
<p>Or, remember <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Java_applet">Java applets</a>? They became
available in 1995, and later they weren’t limited to just Windows and Internet Explorer. I remember
I had to use Java applets on macOS as recently as 2013, which chronologically is closer to the
present time than the 90s are. (Feeling so old anyway! 👴)</p>
<p>
  <a href="https://desiatov.com/static/java-d07ca75d3ee42f845ec400952480dcd3-86a48.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
  
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="Microsoft's Application and Network Access Portal that displays a warning about user's browser not
allowing Java applets to run" title="" src="https://desiatov.com/static/java-d07ca75d3ee42f845ec400952480dcd3-f8fb9.jpg" srcset="https://desiatov.com/static/java-d07ca75d3ee42f845ec400952480dcd3-e8976.jpg 148w,
https://desiatov.com/static/java-d07ca75d3ee42f845ec400952480dcd3-63df2.jpg 295w,
https://desiatov.com/static/java-d07ca75d3ee42f845ec400952480dcd3-f8fb9.jpg 590w,
https://desiatov.com/static/java-d07ca75d3ee42f845ec400952480dcd3-86a48.jpg 624w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px">
    </span>
  </span>
  
  </a>
    </p>
<p>Seems like ActiveX and Java applets were necessities mostly in the enterprise world, but
Macromedia Flash (later known as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adobe_Flash">Adobe Flash</a>)
was certainly much more widely known to consumers. It was a requirement in the early days of streaming
video (even <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/1/27/7926001/youtube-drops-flash-for-html5-video-default">YouTube required
Flash</a>
to work back then!), but also a major driver in browser gaming in late 2000s and early 2010s.
We certainly could blame Flash for making our browser windows look like this:</p>
<p>
  <a href="https://desiatov.com/static/flash-38961528058b4baa72341cf48381d93c-02110.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
  
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="Browser page warning about Adobe Flash Player not being installed" title="" src="https://desiatov.com/static/flash-38961528058b4baa72341cf48381d93c-f8fb9.jpg" srcset="https://desiatov.com/static/flash-38961528058b4baa72341cf48381d93c-e8976.jpg 148w,
https://desiatov.com/static/flash-38961528058b4baa72341cf48381d93c-63df2.jpg 295w,
https://desiatov.com/static/flash-38961528058b4baa72341cf48381d93c-f8fb9.jpg 590w,
https://desiatov.com/static/flash-38961528058b4baa72341cf48381d93c-02110.jpg 606w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px">
    </span>
  </span>
  
  </a>
    </p>
<p>While ActiveX has seemingly failed to reach a significant adoption, Microsoft made yet another
attempt with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_Silverlight">Silverlight</a>:</p>
<p>
  <a href="https://desiatov.com/static/silverlight-b8600e7fe201dbc24998a9aacecd3684-da6d6.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
  
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="Microsoft Silverlight page with an installation button" title="" src="https://desiatov.com/static/silverlight-b8600e7fe201dbc24998a9aacecd3684-f8fb9.jpg" srcset="https://desiatov.com/static/silverlight-b8600e7fe201dbc24998a9aacecd3684-e8976.jpg 148w,
https://desiatov.com/static/silverlight-b8600e7fe201dbc24998a9aacecd3684-63df2.jpg 295w,
https://desiatov.com/static/silverlight-b8600e7fe201dbc24998a9aacecd3684-f8fb9.jpg 590w,
https://desiatov.com/static/silverlight-b8600e7fe201dbc24998a9aacecd3684-da6d6.jpg 831w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px">
    </span>
  </span>
  
  </a>
    </p>
<p>In the meantime, Google was working on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Native_Client">its own thing for
Chrome</a>:</p>
<p>
  <a href="https://desiatov.com/static/chrome_nacl-14dd7527a35d3d99235e94e99ca4ae06-5d9c9.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
  
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="Google Native Client plug-in settings in the Chrome browser" title="" src="https://desiatov.com/static/chrome_nacl-14dd7527a35d3d99235e94e99ca4ae06-fb8a0.png" srcset="https://desiatov.com/static/chrome_nacl-14dd7527a35d3d99235e94e99ca4ae06-1a291.png 148w,
https://desiatov.com/static/chrome_nacl-14dd7527a35d3d99235e94e99ca4ae06-2bc4a.png 295w,
https://desiatov.com/static/chrome_nacl-14dd7527a35d3d99235e94e99ca4ae06-fb8a0.png 590w,
https://desiatov.com/static/chrome_nacl-14dd7527a35d3d99235e94e99ca4ae06-5d9c9.png 650w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px">
    </span>
  </span>
  
  </a>
    </p>
<p>It would be fair to say that these attempts failed to establish wide adoption, especially
after both consumers and businesses started shifting to mobile. Here’s how all these forays ended
according to Wikipedia:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Microsoft dropped ActiveX support from the Windows Store edition of Internet Explorer 10 in
Windows 8. In 2015 Microsoft released Microsoft Edge, the replacement for Internet Explorer with
no support for ActiveX, this marked the end of the technology in Microsoft’s web browser
development.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><small><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=ActiveX&amp;oldid=969259090#Platform_support">“ActiveX”</a>
article on Wikipedia.</small></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Beginning in 2013, major web browsers began to phase out support for the underlying technology
applets used to run, with applets becoming completely unable to be run by 2015–2017. Java applets
were deprecated since Java 9 in 2017 and removed from Java SE 11 (18.9), released in September
2018.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><small><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Java_applet&amp;oldid=972322018">“Java applet”</a>
article on Wikipedia.</small></p>
<blockquote>
<p>In July 2017, Adobe announced that it would declare Flash to be end-of-life at the end of 2020,
and will cease support, distribution, and security updates for Flash Player.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><small><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adobe_Flash#End_of_life">“Adobe Flash”</a> article on
Wikipedia.</small></p>
<blockquote>
<p>There is no Silverlight plugin available for Microsoft Edge. It has not been supported by Google
Chrome since September 2015 or by Firefox since March 2017.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><small><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_Silverlight#Demise">“Microsoft Silverlight”</a>
article on Wikipedia.</small></p>
<blockquote>
<p>On October 12, 2016, a comment on the Chromium issue tracker indicated that Google’s Pepper and
Native Client teams had been destaffed.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><small><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Google_Native_Client&amp;oldid=973604804">“Google Native
Client”</a> article on
Wikipedia.</small></p>
<h2>But JavaScript solved all these problems, didn’t it?</h2>
<p>Most of these browser add-ons were introduced before modern JavaScript and HTML5 became available,
so one could argue you no longer need browser add-ons at all. Well, <a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2017/06/27/web-without-javascript">some
purists</a> even say browsers
should have never supported JavaScript or any scripting whatsoever in the first place. Nevertheless,
there are enough use cases for browser scripting and browser apps in general that are hard to avoid.
When looking at the history of browser plugins in general, it’s hard not to notice a few themes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Distributing productivity apps via browsers is convenient in a lot of cases.</li>
<li>Browser gaming made a lot of sense, especially for casual games.</li>
<li>In both of these scenarios browsers had to display something more complex than text and a few
static images.</li>
</ul>
<p>
  <a href="https://desiatov.com/static/flashelementtd-d00aec3e17cce46cb27a2b1662672bcf-d5c50.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
  
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="Flash Element TD game screenshot with a classic tower defense battle field" title="" src="https://desiatov.com/static/flashelementtd-d00aec3e17cce46cb27a2b1662672bcf-d5c50.jpg" srcset="https://desiatov.com/static/flashelementtd-d00aec3e17cce46cb27a2b1662672bcf-399a3.jpg 148w,
https://desiatov.com/static/flashelementtd-d00aec3e17cce46cb27a2b1662672bcf-d5c50.jpg 288w" sizes="(max-width: 288px) 100vw, 288px">
    </span>
  </span>
  
  </a>
    </p>
<p><small>The modern casual <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tower_defense">tower defense game genre</a>
arguably was reborn due to the popularity of Adobe Flash and browser gaming, with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flash_Element_TD">Flash Element
TD</a> being a classic example.</small></p>
<p>Even though native apps were (and in many situations still are) objectively better for users, early
browser apps were attempting to build their own ad-hoc app stores before the App Store existed.
You didn’t have to buy a CD with an application and install it and manage it on your disk. You
didn’t have to install updates manually and migrate your data. There was no need to uninstall apps,
you just close a corresponding browser tab and forget about it.</p>
<p>And when browser scripting capabilities became advanced enough, some people started seeing the
allure of making a browser version of their app the only version they provided. Browsers are
cross-platform, aren’t they? Just wrap your JavaScript app code in a browser-like container (say
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electron_(software_framework)">Electron</a>) and distribute that instead
of your native app. </p>
<p>But eventually not only the JavaScript APIs became more complex, the language itself could no longer
accommodate what developers wanted. Not everyone liked JavaScript syntax (remember
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CoffeeScript">CoffeeScript</a>?) or semantics (I couldn’t help but
notice that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TypeScript">TypeScript</a> has grown in popularity in recent
years). But it’s hard to transpile an arbitrary programming language to JavaScript, the latter was
not built with that goal in mind.</p>
<p>Corollary, the JavaScript interpreter itself has both memory and performance overhead. Having a
garbage collector built in makes it even harder to transpile languages with different memory models
to JavaScript. The allure of having only one language to write all your apps for all platforms is
still there, but why do you have to be confined to JavaScript itself, even as a target language?</p>
<h2>How WebAssembly actually started</h2>
<p>With the death of browser plugins, at least we can praise the interoperability efforts of browser
vendors. Some lowest common denominator of JavaScript is supported in all browsers, and there is a
clear incentive for the vendors to keep up. With the demand to go beyond JavaScript, there were
initial attempts to support low level programming with asm.js in 2013:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Much of this performance gain over normal JavaScript [with asm.js was] due to 100% type consistency
and virtually no garbage collection (memory is manually managed in a large typed array).</p>
</blockquote>
<p><small><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Asm.js">“asm.js”</a> article on Wikipedia.</small></p>
<p>Syntactically this still looked pretty much like JavaScript, but when you have a lot of low level code,
the resulting file can get big pretty quickly, and the size of your code is pretty important when your
users download it frequently. As you weren’t supposed to write asm.js code manually most of the time,
and it was designed primarily as compilation target, it made sense to invent a binary format for it.
That’s basically how WebAssembly started:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>WebAssembly was first announced in 2015, and the first demonstration was executing Unity’s Angry
Bots in Firefox, Google Chrome, and Microsoft Edge. The precursor technologies were asm.js from
Mozilla and Google Native Client, and the initial implementation was based on the feature set of
asm.js.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><small><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WebAssembly#History">“WebAssembly”</a> article on
Wikipedia.</small></p>
<p>
  <a href="https://desiatov.com/static/angrybots-af143aa014afd3462b9ef4d25875af9f-5b672.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
  
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="Angry Bots is a 3rd-person shooter demo that features a marine-like character that walks
through some futuristic research base and defends from suicidal four-legged robots" title="" src="https://desiatov.com/static/angrybots-af143aa014afd3462b9ef4d25875af9f-fb8a0.png" srcset="https://desiatov.com/static/angrybots-af143aa014afd3462b9ef4d25875af9f-1a291.png 148w,
https://desiatov.com/static/angrybots-af143aa014afd3462b9ef4d25875af9f-2bc4a.png 295w,
https://desiatov.com/static/angrybots-af143aa014afd3462b9ef4d25875af9f-fb8a0.png 590w,
https://desiatov.com/static/angrybots-af143aa014afd3462b9ef4d25875af9f-526de.png 885w,
https://desiatov.com/static/angrybots-af143aa014afd3462b9ef4d25875af9f-fa2eb.png 1180w,
https://desiatov.com/static/angrybots-af143aa014afd3462b9ef4d25875af9f-08f6a.png 1770w,
https://desiatov.com/static/angrybots-af143aa014afd3462b9ef4d25875af9f-5b672.png 2567w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px">
    </span>
  </span>
  
  </a>
    </p>
<p><small>Angry Bots is still available to play on the <a href="https://beta.unity3d.com/jonas/AngryBots/">Unity
website</a>.</small></p>
<h2>What WebAssembly got right</h2>
<p>Now you’re no longer restricted to JavaScript as a target language for browser apps. As soon as
<a href="https://llvm.org/">LLVM</a> got WebAssembly backend more or less ready, it allowed compilers built
on top of LLVM (for C, C++, Rust, Swift and many more) to adopt it without rewriting everything from
scratch. This unlocked the browser environment to a huge amount of pre-existing software that can
also run close to native speed if optimized well.</p>
<p>Not only can you run fun little projects such as <a href="https://sandspiel.club/">Sandspiel</a> and
<a href="https://orb.farm/">orb.farm</a> in your browser tab, but complex games such as <a href="https://www.continuation-labs.com/projects/d3wasm/">Doom
3</a> (at least its demo version) are available too.
Both <a href="https://blogs.unity3d.com/2018/08/15/webassembly-is-here/">Unity</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/unrealengine/status/932624595722559490">Unreal
Engine</a> announced their support for
WebAssembly, and while we may not see AAA games running in browsers on their initial release date,
this still gives enough confidence in the maturity of the platform.</p>
<p>
  <a href="https://desiatov.com/static/orbfarm-d5127e6241542d4c77ee0faf5d5e8d41-9c30a.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
  
  <span>
    <span>
      <img alt="A pixel-art spherical fish tank filled with water, sand, algae, daphnia and fish." title="" src="https://desiatov.com/static/orbfarm-d5127e6241542d4c77ee0faf5d5e8d41-fb8a0.png" srcset="https://desiatov.com/static/orbfarm-d5127e6241542d4c77ee0faf5d5e8d41-1a291.png 148w,
https://desiatov.com/static/orbfarm-d5127e6241542d4c77ee0faf5d5e8d41-2bc4a.png 295w,
https://desiatov.com/static/orbfarm-d5127e6241542d4c77ee0faf5d5e8d41-fb8a0.png 590w,
https://desiatov.com/static/orbfarm-d5127e6241542d4c77ee0faf5d5e8d41-526de.png 885w,
https://desiatov.com/static/orbfarm-d5127e6241542d4c77ee0faf5d5e8d41-fa2eb.png 1180w,
https://desiatov.com/static/orbfarm-d5127e6241542d4c77ee0faf5d5e8d41-08f6a.png 1770w,
https://desiatov.com/static/orbfarm-d5127e6241542d4c77ee0faf5d5e8d41-9c30a.png 3730w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px">
    </span>
  </span>
  
  </a>
    </p>
<p><small>According to its creator, <a href="https://orb.farm/">orb.farm</a> is “a virtual ecosystem where different
species of creature can live, grow and die as part of a self-contained food chain”.</small></p>
<p>It’s obviously not limited to games, as we can see Apple folks compiling their <a href="https://twitter.com/lrz/status/1250453967957561344">C++ and Objective-C
code from iWork</a> to Wasm<sup id="fnref-1"><a href="#fn-1">1</a></sup>, or
<a href="https://1password.com/">1Password</a> using it in their browser extension getting substantial
performance improvements as a result:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>With our move to WebAssembly, page filling and analysis now runs at least twice as fast as before,
and those websites with a large number of fields are up to 13x faster in Chrome and up to 39x
faster in Firefox! It’s blazing fast. 🔥</p>
</blockquote>
<p><small><a href="https://blog.1password.com/1password-x-may-2019-update/">“1Password X: May 2019 update”</a>
article on <a href="https://blog.1password.com/">the 1Password blog</a>.</small></p>
<h2>Wasm is a general purpose virtual machine</h2>
<p>Not only you get performance improvements with WebAssembly compared to JavaScript, as it was
designed to run arbitrary code in your browser, it’s one of the most widely available secure sandbox
environments. And as a general purpose virtual machine, Wasm is not limited only to browsers.
<a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/">Cloudflare</a> uses it for edge computing on their CDN:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We’re excited by the possibilities that WebAssembly opens up. Perhaps, by integrating with
Cloudflare Spectrum, we could allow existing C/C++ server code to handle arbitrary TCP and UDP
protocols on the edge, like a sort of massively-distributed inetd. Perhaps game servers could
reduce latency by running on Cloudflare, as close to the player as possible. Maybe, with the help
of some GPUs and OpenGL bindings, you could do 3D rendering and real-time streaming directly from
the edge.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><small><a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/webassembly-on-cloudflare-workers/">“WebAssembly on Cloudflare
Workers”</a> on <a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/">the Cloudflare
blog</a>.</small></p>
<p>With people realizing the wide applicability of the Wasm tech stack, it was no surprise when
<a href="https://wasi.dev/">WASI</a> (stands for WebAssembly System Interface) appeared. Where WebAssembly
itself is a “bare metal” platform, it does not supply any primitives such as memory allocation or
filesystem access, which WASI does provide. As Solomon Hykes, creator of Docker, <a href="https://twitter.com/solomonstre/status/1111004913222324225">puts
it</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If WASM+WASI existed in 2008, we wouldn’t have needed to created Docker. That’s how important it
is. Webassembly on the server is the future of computing. A standardized system …</p></blockquote></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://desiatov.com/why-webassembly/">https://desiatov.com/why-webassembly/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://desiatov.com/why-webassembly/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24419081</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 09:26:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why Bayesian Stats Needs Monte-Carlo Methods]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 177 | Comments 96 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24416908">thread link</a>) | @laplacesdemon48
<br/>
September 8, 2020 | https://www.countbayesie.com/blog/2020/8/16/why-bayesian-stats-need-monte-carlo-methods | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.countbayesie.com/blog/2020/8/16/why-bayesian-stats-need-monte-carlo-methods">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site">
		<div id="canvas">

			<!-- / headerWrapper -->

			<div id="pageWrapper" role="main">
				<section id="page" data-content-field="main-content">
					<article id="article-5f3999dd551f15457784cec9" data-item-id="5f3999dd551f15457784cec9">

	<div>
  <!--SPECIAL CONTENT-->

    

    <div>

    <!--POST HEADER-->

			<header>
				
				
			</header>

    <!--POST BODY-->

      <div><div data-layout-label="Post Body" data-type="item" data-updated-on="1597610547002" id="item-5f3999dd551f15457784cec9"><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-ce72701dbc5d55959e37"><div><div><p>This post emerged from a series of question surrounding a Twitter comment that brought up some very interesting points about how Bayesian Hypothesis testing works and the inability of analytic solutions to solve even some seemingly trivial problems in Bayesian statistics. </p><p>Comparing Beta distributed random variables is something that comes up pretty frequently on this blog (and in my book as well). The set up is fairly straight forward: model an A/B test as sampling from two beta distributions, sample from each distribution a lot, then compare the results.</p><p>This simulation approach often first appears as a clever little trick to solve a more complex math problem, but in fact is a primative form of Monte-Carlo Integration and turns out to one of the only ways to really solve this problem. By exploring this topic deeper in this post we'll see some of the myths that many people have about analytic solutions as well as demonstrating why Monte-carlo methods are so essential to Bayesian statistics.</p></div><h2>Background: A conversation about election results</h2><div><p>An interesting conversation happened on Twitter recently. It started with a retweet of mine regarding Nate Silver (well know author and election forecaster) posting his latest predictions for the 2020 presidential election showing that Biden has a 71% probability of winning versus Trump's 29%</p></div></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_4659"><div><div><p>After the last election there was quite a lot of criticism about Nate Silver's forecasting since his company (538) predicted that <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/2016-election-forecast/">Hilary Clinton would win with a probability of 71%</a> in the 2016 presidential election.</p><p>This criticism has always annoyed me personally since, in statistical terms, 71% is generally not considered a strong belief in anything. So it is not inconsistent, nor suprising for someone to believe a candidate has 71% chance of success and they still lose. Even when looking at typical p-values, we wait for 95% percent certainty before making claims (and many feel this is a pretty weak belief). But for some reason whenever election polls come up, it seems even very statistically minded people suddenly think that 51% chance is a high probability.</p><p>I retweeted Nate Silver's forecast, mentioned my annoyance and provided an example of another case with a similar probability of winning:</p></div></div></div><div data-block-json="{&quot;cache_age&quot;:&quot;3153600000&quot;,&quot;authorUrl&quot;:&quot;https://twitter.com/willkurt&quot;,&quot;width&quot;:550,&quot;height&quot;:null,&quot;hSize&quot;:null,&quot;resolveObject&quot;:&quot;Tweet&quot;,&quot;html&quot;:&quot;<blockquote class=\&quot;twitter-tweet\&quot;><p dir=\&quot;ltr\&quot; lang=\&quot;en\&quot;>This time can we all remember that rarely in statistics would we judge P(H|D) = 0.71 as a strong belief in anything. <br><br>For comparison if in an A/B test we had these results:<br><br>A has 2 successes in 15 trials<br>B has 3 successes in 14 trials<br><br>This roughly how strong our belief in B is <a href=\&quot;https://t.co/bB4PiB5Tao\&quot;>https://t.co/bB4PiB5Tao</a></p>\u2014 Will Kurt (@willkurt) <a href=\&quot;https://twitter.com/willkurt/status/1293575032975884288?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw\&quot;>August 12, 2020</a></blockquote>\n<script async=\&quot;\&quot; src=\&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js\&quot; charset=\&quot;utf-8\&quot;></script>&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;https://twitter.com/willkurt/status/1293575032975884288&quot;,&quot;resolvedBy&quot;:&quot;twitter&quot;,&quot;floatDir&quot;:null,&quot;authorName&quot;:&quot;Will Kurt&quot;,&quot;version&quot;:&quot;1.0&quot;,&quot;resolved&quot;:true,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;rich&quot;,&quot;providerName&quot;:&quot;Twitter&quot;,&quot;providerUrl&quot;:&quot;https://twitter.com&quot;}" data-block-type="22" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_6372"><div><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>This time can we all remember that rarely in statistics would we judge P(H|D) = 0.71 as a strong belief in anything. </p><p>For comparison if in an A/B test we had these results:</p><p>A has 2 successes in 15 trials<br>B has 3 successes in 14 trials</p><p>This roughly how strong our belief in B is <a href="https://t.co/bB4PiB5Tao">https://t.co/bB4PiB5Tao</a></p></div>— Will Kurt (@willkurt) <a href="https://twitter.com/willkurt/status/1293575032975884288?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 12, 2020</a></blockquote>
</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_6436"><div><div><p>If you were running an A/B test and your A variant had 2 success in 15 trials and your B variant had 3 successes in 14 trails, you would be roughly 71% confident that B was the superior variant.</p><p>Even someone without much statistical training would likely be very skeptical of such a claim, but somehow during election forecasts even experience statisticians can look at Silver's post and think that Biden winning is a sure thing.</p></div><h2> How do we arrive at P(B &gt; A)?</h2><p><br>Twitter user <a href="https://twitter.com/mbarras_ing">@mbarras_ing</a> ask a really important follow up question, asking to explain this result:</p></div></div><div data-block-json="{&quot;cache_age&quot;:&quot;3153600000&quot;,&quot;authorUrl&quot;:&quot;https://twitter.com/mbarras_ing&quot;,&quot;width&quot;:550,&quot;height&quot;:null,&quot;hSize&quot;:null,&quot;resolveObject&quot;:&quot;Tweet&quot;,&quot;html&quot;:&quot;<blockquote class=\&quot;twitter-tweet\&quot;><p dir=\&quot;ltr\&quot; lang=\&quot;en\&quot;>I may be a bit slow but could you elaborate on how that is? How would one compute 0.71, from the info \&quot;A has 2 successes in 15 trials, B has 3 successes in 14 trials\&quot;?</p>\u2014 Matthew Rhys Barras (@mbarras_ing) <a href=\&quot;https://twitter.com/mbarras_ing/status/1293928326579589121?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw\&quot;>August 13, 2020</a></blockquote>\n<script async=\&quot;\&quot; src=\&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js\&quot; charset=\&quot;utf-8\&quot;></script>&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;https://twitter.com/mbarras_ing/status/1293928326579589121&quot;,&quot;resolvedBy&quot;:&quot;twitter&quot;,&quot;floatDir&quot;:null,&quot;authorName&quot;:&quot;Matthew Rhys Barras&quot;,&quot;version&quot;:&quot;1.0&quot;,&quot;resolved&quot;:true,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;rich&quot;,&quot;providerName&quot;:&quot;Twitter&quot;,&quot;providerUrl&quot;:&quot;https://twitter.com&quot;}" data-block-type="22" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_7791"><div><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">I may be a bit slow but could you elaborate on how that is? How would one compute 0.71, from the info "A has 2 successes in 15 trials, B has 3 successes in 14 trials"?</p>— Matthew Rhys Barras (@mbarras_ing) <a href="https://twitter.com/mbarras_ing/status/1293928326579589121?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 13, 2020</a></blockquote>
</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_7855"><div><div><p>I very strongly believe that all statistics, even quick off the cuff estimates, should be reproducible and explainable.</p><p>I've written a fair bit about approaching similar problems both <a href="https://www.countbayesie.com/blog/2015/4/25/bayesian-ab-testing">on this blog</a> and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bayesian-Statistics-Fun-Will-Kurt/dp/1593279566">in my book</a>. The big picture is that we're going to come up with parameter estimates for the rate that A and B convert users and then compute the probability that B is greater than A. </p><p>Since we're estimating conversion rates we're going to use <a href="https://www.countbayesie.com/blog/2015/3/17/interrogating-probability-distributions">the Beta distribution</a> as the distribution of our parameter estimate. In this example I'm also assume a \(\text{Beta}(1,1)\) prior for our A and B variants.</p><p>The likelihood for A is \(\text{Beta}(2,13)\) and for B is \(\text{Beta}(3,11)\) so we can represent A and B as two random variables samples form these posteriors:</p><p>$$A \sim \text{Beta}(2+1, 13+1)$$<br>$$B \sim \text{Beta}(3+1,11+1)$$</p></div><p>We can now represent this in R, and sample from these distributions:</p></div></div><div data-block-type="23" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_9136"><div><pre><span>N</span> <span>&lt;</span><span>-</span> <span>10000</span>
<span>a_samples</span> <span>&lt;</span><span>-</span> <span>rbeta</span>(<span>N</span>,<span>2</span><span>+</span><span>1</span>,<span>13</span><span>+</span><span>1</span>)
<span>b_samples</span> <span>&lt;</span><span>-</span> <span>rbeta</span>(<span>N</span>,<span>3</span><span>+</span><span>1</span>,<span>11</span><span>+</span><span>1</span>)</pre></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_9202"><p>And finally we can look at the results of this to compute the probability that B is greater than A:</p></div><div data-block-type="23" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_10612"><div><pre><span>sum</span>(<span>b_samples</span> <span>&gt;</span> <span>a_samples</span>)<span>/</span><span>N</span></pre></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_10678"><div><p>In this case we get 0.7028 pretty close to 71% for Nate Silver’s problem.</p><h2><p>Can we solve this without R?</p></h2><p><br>This explains where we get our probabilities from, but there is an obvious question that comes up when you see this result, one raised by <a href="https://twitter.com/little_rocko">@little_rocko</a></p></div></div><div data-block-json="{&quot;cache_age&quot;:&quot;3153600000&quot;,&quot;authorUrl&quot;:&quot;https://twitter.com/little_rocko&quot;,&quot;width&quot;:550,&quot;height&quot;:null,&quot;hSize&quot;:null,&quot;resolveObject&quot;:&quot;Tweet&quot;,&quot;html&quot;:&quot;<blockquote class=\&quot;twitter-tweet\&quot;><p dir=\&quot;ltr\&quot; lang=\&quot;en\&quot;>this is an awesome example. is there an easy way (as in non-brute force) to finding the beta parameters that'll match a probability?</p>\u2014 Rocko (@little_rocko) <a href=\&quot;https://twitter.com/little_rocko/status/1294938572299018242?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw\&quot;>August 16, 2020</a></blockquote>\n<script async=\&quot;\&quot; src=\&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js\&quot; charset=\&quot;utf-8\&quot;></script>&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;https://twitter.com/little_rocko/status/1294938572299018242&quot;,&quot;resolvedBy&quot;:&quot;twitter&quot;,&quot;floatDir&quot;:null,&quot;authorName&quot;:&quot;Rocko&quot;,&quot;version&quot;:&quot;1.0&quot;,&quot;resolved&quot;:true,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;rich&quot;,&quot;providerName&quot;:&quot;Twitter&quot;,&quot;providerUrl&quot;:&quot;https://twitter.com&quot;}" data-block-type="22" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_12117"><div><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">this is an awesome example. is there an easy way (as in non-brute force) to finding the beta parameters that'll match a probability?</p>— Rocko (@little_rocko) <a href="https://twitter.com/little_rocko/status/1294938572299018242?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 16, 2020</a></blockquote>
</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_12181"><div><div><p>This question is interesting because it asks two questions that don't necessarily have to be related:</p><p>- is there an easy way to solve this<br>- is there a non-"brute force" way solve this</p><p>Before moving on I want to mention that this little snippet of R involves a lot more abstraction then it seems at first glance. What we are really doing here is equalivant to using a Monte-Carlo simulation to integrate over the distribution of the difference between two Beta distributed random variables. After the next two sections it will be more clear that what's happening here is a surprisingly sophisticated operation that is, in my opinion, the easiest method of solving this problem as well as not truly a brute force solution.</p></div><h2><br>Analytic versus Easy</h2><div><p>When we see computational solutions to mathematical problems our first instinct is typically to feel that we are avoiding solving the problem <em>analytically.</em> An analytical solution is one that uses mathematical analysis to find a closed form solution.</p><p>A strivial example, suppose I wanted to find the value that minimized \(f(x) = (x+3)^2\)</p><p>In R I could brute force this by looking over a range of answers like this:</p></div></div></div><div data-block-type="23" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_13626"><div><pre><span>f</span> <span>&lt;</span><span>-</span> <span>function</span>(<span>x</span>){  
  (<span>x</span><span>+</span><span>3</span>)<span>^</span><span>2</span>
}
<span>xs</span> <span>&lt;</span><span>-</span> <span>seq</span>(<span>-</span><span>6</span>,<span>6</span>,<span>by</span><span>=</span><span>0.031</span>)
<span>xs</span>[<span>which</span>.<span>min</span>(<span>f</span>(<span>xs</span>))]</pre></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597610689295_13692"><div><div><p>As expected we get our answer of -3, but this solution takes a bit of work: we need to know how to code and we need a computer. It's also a bit messy because if we had iterated by an incredment that didn't include -3 exactly (say by 0.031) we would not get the exact answer.</p><p>If we know some basic calculus we know that our minimum has to be where the derivative is at 0. We can very easily work out that</p><p>$$f'(x) = 2(x+3)$$<br>And that</p><p>$$2(x + 3) = 0 $$</p><p>When</p><p>$$ x = -3 $$</p><p>Knowning basic calculus this later solution becomes much easier. </p><p>But even with the calculus is part is hard, often solving it once makes future solutions much easier. Take for example if you wanted to find the maximum likelihood for a normal distribution with a mean of \(\mu\) and standard deviation of \(\sigma\)</p><p>To solve this we start with our PDF for the normal distribution \(\varphi\):</p><p>$$\varphi(x) = \frac{1}{\sigma \sqrt{2\pi}}e^{-\frac{1}{2}(\frac{x-\mu}{\sigma})^2}$$</p><p>Now computing the derivative of this is not necessarily "easy" but it's certainly something we can do. All we really care about is when</p><p>$$\varphi'(x) = 0$$</p><p>Which we can find out happens when (computing the deriviative of course is left as an exercise for the reader):</p><p>$$\frac{\mu-x}{\sigma}$$</p></div><div><p>This allows us to reallize the amazing fact that for any normal distribution we come across, we know that the maximum likelihood estimate is the sample is when \(x = \mu\)!</p><p>Even though our calculus might take us a bit of work, once this is done the problem of doing maximum likelihood estimation for any Normal distribution truly does become easy!</p></div><h3><br>Proposing an Analytic solution to our problem</h3><div><p>Let's revisit our original problem this time attempting to find an analytic solution. This is a very interesting case because arguably this is the simplest Bayesian hypothesis test you can imagine.</p><p>Recall that we have two random variable representing our beliefs in each test. These are distributed according the the posterior which we described earlier.</p><p>$$A \sim \text{Beta}(2+1, 13+1)$$<br>$$B \sim \text{Beta}(3+1,11+1)$$</p><p>Here is where I skipped some steps in reasoning. What we want to know is:</p><p>$$P(B &gt;A)$$</p></div><div><p>Which is not expressed in a particularly useful mathematical way. A better way to solve this is to consider this as the sum (or difference in this case) of two random variables. What we really want to know is:</p><p>$$P(B - A &gt; 0)$$</p><p>In order to solve this problem we can think of a new random variable \(X\) which is going to be the difference between B and A:</p><p>$$X = B - A$$</p><p>Finally we'll suppose we have a probability density function for \(X\) we'll call \(\text{pdf}_X\). If we know \(\text{pdf}_X\) our solution is pretty close, we just need to integrate between 0 and the max domain of this distribution:</p><p>$$P(B &gt; A) = P(B - A &gt; 0) = \int_{x=0}^{\text{max}}\text{pdf}_{X}(x)$$</p><p>Already this is starting to look a bit complicated, but there's one big problem ahead. Unlike Normally distributed random variables, we have no equivalent of the Normal sum theorem (we'll cover this in a bit) for Beta distributed random variables. </p><p>What does \(\text{pdf}_X\) look like? For starters we know it's not a Beta distribution itself. We can see this because we know the domain (or support) of this distribution is not \([0,1]\). Because they are Beta distributed, A and B can both take on values from 0 to 1, which means the maximum result of this difference is 1 but the minimum is -1. So whatever this distribution is, its domain is \([-1,1]\) meaning it cannot be a Beta distribution.</p><p>We can use various rules about sum of random variables to determine the mean and variance of this distribution, but without knowing the exact form of this distribution we are unable to solve the integral analytically. </p><p>Here we can see that even in this profoundly simple problem the analytical solution is frustratingly …</p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></article></section></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.countbayesie.com/blog/2020/8/16/why-bayesian-stats-need-monte-carlo-methods">https://www.countbayesie.com/blog/2020/8/16/why-bayesian-stats-need-monte-carlo-methods</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.countbayesie.com/blog/2020/8/16/why-bayesian-stats-need-monte-carlo-methods</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24416908</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 03:54:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[AMD PSB Vendor Locks EPYC CPUs for Enhanced Security at a Cost]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 337 | Comments 252 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24416005">thread link</a>) | @virgulino
<br/>
September 8, 2020 | https://www.servethehome.com/amd-psb-vendor-locks-epyc-cpus-for-enhanced-security-at-a-cost/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.servethehome.com/amd-psb-vendor-locks-epyc-cpus-for-enhanced-security-at-a-cost/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <!-- image --><div><figure><a href="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/AMD-Platform-Secure-Boot-Feature-Cover.jpg" data-caption="AMD Platform Secure Boot Feature Cover"><img width="696" height="465" src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/AMD-Platform-Secure-Boot-Feature-Cover-696x465.jpg" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/AMD-Platform-Secure-Boot-Feature-Cover-696x465.jpg 696w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/AMD-Platform-Secure-Boot-Feature-Cover-400x268.jpg 400w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/AMD-Platform-Secure-Boot-Feature-Cover-628x420.jpg 628w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/AMD-Platform-Secure-Boot-Feature-Cover.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px" alt="AMD Platform Secure Boot Feature Cover" title="AMD Platform Secure Boot Feature Cover"></a><figcaption>AMD Platform Secure Boot Feature Cover</figcaption></figure></div>
            <!-- content --><p>Today we are going to discuss a change to server security that is going to make waves in the home lab and secondary markets for servers and components in the future. During our recent <a href="https://www.servethehome.com/dell-emc-poweredge-c6525-review-2u4n-amd-epyc-kilo-thread-server/">Dell EMC PowerEdge C6525 review</a> we briefly mentioned that AMD EPYC CPUs in the system are vendor locked to Dell EMC systems. This is not a Dell-specific concern. We have confirmed that other vendors are supporting the feature behind this. For the large vendors, their platform security teams are pushing to build more secure platforms for their customers, and that is going to have future impacts on the secondary server market and home labs.</p>
<p>In this article, we are going to cover the basics of what is happening. We are going to discuss the motivations, and why this is going to be more common in the future. Finally, we are going to discuss what those in the industry can do to keep the secondary server market operating well. If you work with partners or resellers who dip into used parts bins or even have the potential to purchase grey market CPUs, send them this article or accompanying video. The current market has a large disconnect between what some large customers are asking for, and large vendors are delivering on and what others in the market know is happening.<span id="more-46716"></span></p>
<h2>Accompanying Video</h2>
<p>This is an important topic. To ensure that we can cover those who like to read/ skim and those who like to get information via audio, we have an accompanying video:</p>
<p><iframe title="Vendor Locking AMD EPYC CPUs Great for Security at a Cost" width="696" height="392" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kNVuTAVYxpM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Feel free to pop open that video on YouTube and check it out or to send to those who prefer not to read.</p>
<h2>Background: How we learned this was a “thing”</h2>
<p>In 2018 we did a <a href="https://www.servethehome.com/dell-emc-poweredge-r7415-review/">Dell EMC PowerEdge R7415 review</a> and as part of that review, we started our normal process of trying different CPUs in the system. Early in that process, we used an AMD EPYC 7251 CPU, the low-end 8-core model, and noticed something curious. It would not work in our other test systems after.</p>
<p>After a bit of research, we found it was because Dell EMC was vendor locking the chips to Dell systems. We did not know exactly why, but we were told was a security feature. At this point, and even to this day two years later, not every vendor takes advantage of all of the AMD EPYC security features. What that practically means is that what we saw with the Dell EMC system is not what we saw with other systems. For example, we were able to interchangeably use CPUs in Supermicro and Tyan systems, but we could not use those systems once they went into a Dell EMC server.</p>
<figure id="attachment_24514" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-24514"><a href="https://www.servethehome.com/dual-amd-epyc-7251-linux-benchmarks-least-expensive-2p-epyc/amd-epyc-7251-in-socket-and-carrier/" rel="attachment wp-att-24514"><img src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/AMD-EPYC-7251-in-Socket-and-Carrier.jpg" alt="AMD EPYC In Socket And Carrier" width="800" height="533" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/AMD-EPYC-7251-in-Socket-and-Carrier.jpg 800w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/AMD-EPYC-7251-in-Socket-and-Carrier-400x267.jpg 400w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/AMD-EPYC-7251-in-Socket-and-Carrier-696x464.jpg 696w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/AMD-EPYC-7251-in-Socket-and-Carrier-630x420.jpg 630w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-24514">AMD EPYC In Socket And Carrier</figcaption></figure>
<p>We found we were not alone. Laboratories, VARs, and other organizations were finding that transferring AMD EPYC CPUs from one vendor’s system to another, was not the simple process it was on the Intel Xeon side. It did not always work.</p>
<p>We knew it was a security feature and thought that most who are buying servers would be informed of this by their sales reps or channel partners. After I personally got a lot of texts, e-mails, instant messaging, and comments on our C6525 video and article, I realized that this actually may be a situation where many people do not know what is going on.</p>
<figure id="attachment_46531" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-46531"><a href="https://www.servethehome.com/dell-emc-poweredge-c6525-review-2u4n-amd-epyc-kilo-thread-server/dell-emc-poweredge-c6525-internal-view-nodes-partially-out/" rel="attachment wp-att-46531"><img src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Dell-EMC-PowerEdge-C6525-Internal-View-Nodes-Partially-Out.jpg" alt="Dell EMC PowerEdge C6525 Internal View Nodes Partially Out" width="800" height="519" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Dell-EMC-PowerEdge-C6525-Internal-View-Nodes-Partially-Out.jpg 800w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Dell-EMC-PowerEdge-C6525-Internal-View-Nodes-Partially-Out-400x260.jpg 400w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Dell-EMC-PowerEdge-C6525-Internal-View-Nodes-Partially-Out-696x452.jpg 696w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Dell-EMC-PowerEdge-C6525-Internal-View-Nodes-Partially-Out-647x420.jpg 647w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-46531">Dell EMC PowerEdge C6525 Internal View Nodes Partially Out</figcaption></figure>
<p>This experience that we had, apparently is one that is not overly common yet. That makes sense because the systems that utilize the enhanced security levels are still largely new, and being used by their first buyers. Also, AMD still has a smaller market share than Intel. A big reason, by the way, that Intel Xeon does not have this issue is that they do not have the security feature that AMD has. Vendors have come out and stated that their AMD EPYC systems are more secure than their Intel Xeon systems, and this behavior is a byproduct of that enhanced security.</p>
<p>Next, we are going to dive into the feature of AMD processors (and what will be more common in future CPUs from other vendors.)</p>
<h2>AMD EPYC Secure Processor Platform Secure Boot (PSB)</h2>
<p>Let us start with the high-level slide. This is effectively the same slide on the AMD Secure Processor that we saw with the AMD EPYC 7001 series launch, but this is from the EPYC 7002 series. AMD EPYC CPUs may be x86, but they have an embedded Arm Cortex-A5 microcontroller that runs its own OS that is independent of the main system. This AMD Secure Processor is the backbone of AMD’s security push as it provides features such as key management and hardware root of trust for the platform.</p>
<figure id="attachment_36705" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-36705"><a href="https://www.servethehome.com/amd-epyc-7002-series-rome-delivers-a-knockout/amd-epyc-7002-platform-secure-processor/" rel="attachment wp-att-36705"><img src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Processor.jpg" alt="AMD EPYC 7002 Platform Secure Processor" width="1792" height="918" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Processor.jpg 1792w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Processor-400x205.jpg 400w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Processor-800x410.jpg 800w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Processor-696x357.jpg 696w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Processor-1068x547.jpg 1068w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Processor-820x420.jpg 820w" sizes="(max-width: 1792px) 100vw, 1792px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-36705">AMD EPYC 7002 Platform Secure Processor</figcaption></figure>
<p>AMD spends time <a href="https://www.servethehome.com/amd-confirms-cts-labs-exploits-requiring-admin-access/">patching this solution</a>&nbsp;to make it more secure, but it is generally fairly hard to reach without some extremely low-level access in a system. We are going to come back to the “Enables hardware validated boot” line shortly, but it is important to understand that this secure processor underpins many of AMD’s best security features.</p>
<p>For example, at STH we use EPYC’s Secure Memory Encryption and Secure Encrypted Virtualization heavily. With AMD EPYC, we do not have to manually manage keys. Instead, the ephemeral keys are managed for us by the AMD Secure Processor. This is the basis for what is really the building wave of confidential computing offerings such as&nbsp;<a href="https://www.servethehome.com/google-cloud-confidential-computing-enabled-by-amd-epyc-sev/">Google Cloud Confidential Computing Enabled by AMD EPYC SEV</a>. Intel has its secure boot features and SGX that will be enhanced greatly with <a href="https://www.servethehome.com/the-2021-intel-ice-pickle-how-2021-will-be-crunch-time/">Ice Lake Xeons</a>, but for now, AMD has this capability while Intel does not. When big vendors say AMD is more secure, the AMD Secure Processor is a cornerstone of those offerings.</p>
<figure id="attachment_36704" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-36704"><a href="https://www.servethehome.com/amd-epyc-7002-series-rome-delivers-a-knockout/amd-epyc-7002-platform-secure-memory-encryption/" rel="attachment wp-att-36704"><img src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Memory-Encryption.jpg" alt="AMD EPYC 7002 Platform Secure Memory Encryption" width="1769" height="890" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Memory-Encryption.jpg 1769w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Memory-Encryption-400x201.jpg 400w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Memory-Encryption-800x402.jpg 800w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Memory-Encryption-696x350.jpg 696w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Memory-Encryption-1068x537.jpg 1068w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/AMD-EPYC-7002-Platform-Secure-Memory-Encryption-835x420.jpg 835w" sizes="(max-width: 1769px) 100vw, 1769px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-36704">AMD EPYC 7002 Platform Secure Memory Encryption</figcaption></figure>
<p>Let us discuss that “Enables hardware validated boot” line. While traditionally CPUs just fire up in whatever platform they are in, AMD has intelligence in their CPU due to the Arm-based AMD Secure Processor. EPYC CPUs are designed to be a bit more intelligent about the platforms they are in, and interact with server platform security to act as this root of trust that would not be possible if they effectively just booted up in any system.</p>
<p>Here is a statement from AMD describing the AMD Platform Secure Boot.</p>
<p><em>The AMD Platform Secure Boot Feature (PSB) is a mitigation for firmware Advanced Persistent Threats. It is a defense-in-depth feature. PSB extends AMD’s silicon root of trust to protect the OEM’s BIOS.&nbsp; This allows the OEM to establish an unbroken chain of trust from AMD’s silicon root of trust to the OEM’s BIOS using PSB, and then from the OEM’s BIOS to the OS Bootloader using UEFI secure boot. This provides a very powerful defense against remote attackers seeking to embed malware into a platform’s firmware.</em></p>
<p><em>An OEM who trusts only their own cryptographically signed BIOS code to run on their platforms will use a PSB enabled motherboard and set one-time-programmable fuses in the processor to bind the processor to the OEM’s firmware code signing key. AMD processors are shipped unlocked from the factory, and can initially be used with any OEM’s motherboard. But once they are used with a motherboard with PSB enabled, the security fuses will be set, and from that point on, that processor can only be used with motherboards that use the same code signing key. (<strong>Source</strong>: AMD statement to STH)</em></p>
<p>That is a lot to take in. We asked HPE about this. Their response mirrored what the above was describing. HPE firmware, when a system is first turned on, performs this binding process where the AMD EPYC CPU expects to see HPE signed firmware. If you alter the HPE firmware on the system, the check fails and the system will not work. That means if your HPE motherboard fails, you can replace it and put your CPU in another HPE motherboard with signed HPE firmware. It also means if the server platform’s firmware is not signed by HPE, the processor will see it as evidence of tampering and not work.</p>
<p><strong>Edit: 2020-09-09</strong> – HPE clarified that they are doing this in a different manner than Dell after initially confirming that they were using the AMD PSB feature. After this went live, HPE sent us the following:</p>
<p><em>HPE does not use the same security technique that Dell is using for a BIOS hardware root of trust. HPE does not burn, fuse, or permanently store our public key into AMD processors which ship with our products. HPE uses a unique approach to authenticate our BIOS and BMC firmware: HPE fuses our hardware – or silicon – root of trust into our own BMC silicon to ensure only authenticated firmware is executed.&nbsp; Thus, while we implement a hardware root of trust for our BIOS and BMC firmware, the processors that ship with our servers are not locked to our platforms. (<strong>Source</strong>: HPE)</em></p>
<p>What is at least interesting there is that HPE was initially claiming feature parity with Dell to us, and from the comments on this article were saying they used this feature in sales pitches, but now are saying they are not blowing the eFuses.</p>
<figure id="attachment_39258" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-39258"><a href="https://www.servethehome.com/pcie-gen4-hpe-proliant-dl325-gen10-plus-and-dl385-gen10-plus-amd-epyc-7002/hpe-proliant-dl325-gen10-plus-at-sc19-cpu-cover/" rel="attachment wp-att-39258"><img src="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/HPE-ProLiant-DL325-Gen10-Plus-at-SC19-CPU-Cover.jpg" alt="HPE ProLiant DL325 Gen10 Plus At SC19 CPU Cover" width="800" height="600" srcset="https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/HPE-ProLiant-DL325-Gen10-Plus-at-SC19-CPU-Cover.jpg 800w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/HPE-ProLiant-DL325-Gen10-Plus-at-SC19-CPU-Cover-400x300.jpg 400w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/HPE-ProLiant-DL325-Gen10-Plus-at-SC19-CPU-Cover-80x60.jpg 80w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/HPE-ProLiant-DL325-Gen10-Plus-at-SC19-CPU-Cover-265x198.jpg 265w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/HPE-ProLiant-DL325-Gen10-Plus-at-SC19-CPU-Cover-696x522.jpg 696w, https://www.servethehome.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/HPE-ProLiant-DL325-Gen10-Plus-at-SC19-CPU-Cover-560x420.jpg 560w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-39258">HPE ProLiant DL325 Gen10 Plus At SC19 CPU Cover</figcaption></figure>
<p>Here is where the concern develops, and not necessarily for AMD, the OEM, or most of the initial customer base. Customers want more security. The OEMs want to create a secure hardware environment because that is what their customers want. AMD is implementing an advanced security solution beyond what Intel Xeons have giving the OEMs and end-customers what they want. Effectively, when these are sold as new systems, this is exactly what everyone involved wants.</p>
<p>If everyone is getting what they want, then where is the concern, that is what we are going to cover next.</p>
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.servethehome.com/amd-psb-vendor-locks-epyc-cpus-for-enhanced-security-at-a-cost/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24416005</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 02:02:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
