<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 10]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 10. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 08:16:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-10.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 08:16:36 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Blog Anonymously]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 38 | Comments 53 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23789621">thread link</a>) | @bradley_taunt
<br/>
July 10, 2020 | https://uglyduck.ca/blog-anonymously/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://uglyduck.ca/blog-anonymously/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <section>
            <blockquote>
                <p><strong>This is not fool-proof by any means.</strong> This is merely a good starting point for casual bloggers who wish to keep their identities hidden from the general public. If you are:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>worried for your safety</li>
                    <li>trying to avoid malicious groups / attackers</li>
                    <li>fearful of government persecution</li>
                </ul>
                <p>then please look into <a href="https://tcij.org/">The Centre for Investigative Journalism</a> or contact a security specialist for help.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <h2>Required Hardware</h2>
            <ol>
                <li><strong>Burner Laptop</strong>
                    <ul>
                        <li>You don't need a high-end laptop, since most of your work will only take place in a browser. Snagging a cheap or used device is a good option. (Chromebooks that allow USB booting are a solid option as well)</li>
                        <li><i>Bonus Points</i>: purchase this burner with cash (preferably through a local marketplace like craigslist, etc.) No credit card = no paper trail.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><strong>USB Flash Drive (8GB+)</strong>
                    <ul>
                        <li>Any will do. Larger storage is only really useful if you wish to use <i>persistence</i> (more on that below).</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </section>
        <section>
            <h2>Required Software</h2>
            <ol>
                <li><strong>Tails OS</strong>
                    <ul>
                        <li>Simply follow the <a href="https://tails.boum.org/install/index.en.html">install instructions</a> to get Tails OS setup properly on your USB flash drive. (Instructions might look more daunting than they truly are)</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <h2>Instructions</h2>
            <ol>
                <li>Boot into Tails OS via the USB flash drive on your burner laptop</li>
                <li>Connect to a Tor circuit (top menu bar for quick access)</li>
                <li>Using the Tor browser, navigate to <a href="">ProtonMail</a> or <a href="">Tutanota</a> and setup a new, free account. Make the email address completely random with no association to yourself.</li>
                <li>Navigate to <a href="https://wordpress.com/">WordPress.com</a> and setup a free account with that new email address.</li>
                <li>Setup your new blog and start writing!</li>
            </ol>
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <h2>Important &amp; Helpful Notes</h2>
            <ol>
                <li>Never use a custom domain name - these require some of your personal information when being registered. Even with whois privacy protection, certain law enforcement can demand for these credentials.</li>
                <li>Feel free to use a VPN, though Tor is more than enough for your needs.</li>
                <li>Whenever you boot Tails OS, it will load with a fresh install. To keep files on the USB even when shutdown, look into using <a href="https://tails.boum.org/doc/first_steps/persistence/index.en.html">Encrypted Persistent Storage </a>. Please note: <i>this is not recommended</i> for obvious security risks.</li>
                <li>Run your articles through multiple translation converters. Edit minor mistakes afterwards. This avoids engines and tools picking up on your writing style.</li>
                <li>Always backup your articles. The safest bet is to use <a href="https://archive.org/">archive.org</a></li>
                <li>Don't expect to collect revenue with your blog. It is extremely difficult to accept payment without some form of tracking to your personal information. If anything, maybe allow your users to donate to a charity you would like to support.</li>
                <li>WordPress is the suggested blog platform but there are others to choose from:
                    <ul>
                        <li><a href="https://pages.github.com/">Github Pages</a></li>
                        <li><a href="https://www.blogger.com/">Blogger</a></li>
                        <li><a href="https://www.tumblr.com/">Tumblr</a></li>
                        <li><a href="https://write.as/">Write.as</a></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Try your best to avoid publishing articles on your home or work network. Make a trip to the local coffee shop during busy hours and post it then.</li>
                <li>Randomly select different times to publish articles. Avoid creating a trackable pattern.</li>
                <li>Never work on anything related to your blog unless using the burner laptop and Tails OS. This might seem simple, but one little slip-up is all it takes.</li>
            </ol>
        </section>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://uglyduck.ca/blog-anonymously/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23789621</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 09:21:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[France to introduce controversial age verification system for adult websites]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 98 | Comments 133 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23789309">thread link</a>) | @docdeek
<br/>
July 10, 2020 | https://www.politico.eu/article/france-to-introduce-controversial-age-verification-system-for-adult-pornography-websites/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.politico.eu/article/france-to-introduce-controversial-age-verification-system-for-adult-pornography-websites/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
							<div>
            <figure><div><div><p><img src="https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/GettyImages-1183467726-714x475.jpg"></p></div></div><figcaption><p>The French audiovisual regulator CSA will be granted new powers to audit and sanction companies | Ed Jones/AFP via Getty Images</p></figcaption></figure>        <div>
        <header>
                        
                        <p>Macron made the protection of children against adult content online a high-profile issue.</p>
                    </header>
                
<!--/.meta-->
    </div><!--/.summary-->
</div><!--/.story-intro-->

							
							
							<p>PARIS — The French Parliament unanimously agreed on Thursday to introduce a nationwide age verification system for pornography websites, months after President Emmanuel Macron pledged to protect children against such content.</p>
<p>Macron made the protection of children against adult content online a high-profile issue well before the coronavirus crisis hit. In January, tech companies, internet services providers and the adult movies industry <a href="https://www.lefigaro.fr/secteur/high-tech/les-fournisseurs-d-acces-des-acteurs-du-web-et-marc-dorcel-s-engagent-pour-proteger-les-mineurs-du-porno-20200117" target="_blank">signed a voluntary charter</a>, pledging to roll out tools to help ensure minors don’t have access to pornographic content.</p>
<p>Within a broader law on domestic violence, the Senate decided <a href="https://www.publicsenat.fr/article/parlementaire/porno-le-senat-bloque-l-accessibilite-des-sites-aux-mineurs-183097" target="_blank">in June</a> to introduce an amendment requiring pornography websites to implement an age verification mechanism.</p>
<p>In order to enforce the law, the French audiovisual regulator CSA will be granted new powers to audit and sanction companies that do not comply — sanctions could go as far as blocking access to the websites in France with a court order.</p>
<p>The choice of verification mechanisms will be left up to the platforms. But lawmakers have suggested using credit card verification — a system first adopted by the U.K., which mulled similar plans to control access to pornography but <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2019/oct/16/uk-drops-plans-for-online-pornography-age-verification-system" target="_blank">had to drop them</a> in late 2019 because of technical difficulties and privacy concerns. Italy also approved a <a href="https://www.gazzettaufficiale.it/eli/gu/2020/06/29/162/sg/pdf" target="_blank">similar bill in late June</a>, which raised the same concerns over its feasibility and <a href="https://www.key4biz.it/filtro-anti-porno-nicita-agcom-limiti-tecnici-norma-pillon-a-rischio-disapplicazione/312167/" target="_blank">compliance with the EU laws</a>.</p>
<p>As private actors could implement their own solutions, the new law also highlights the challenges of digital identification. In Brussels, there are growing calls to introduce an EU-wide digital ID system that would allow users to bypass Google and Facebook’s identification ecosystem. For politicians, including French Junior Digital Minister Cédric O, systems of identification online are <a href="https://www.zdnet.fr/actualites/identite-numerique-le-cnnum-veut-soutenir-l-effort-deja-engage-par-le-gouvernement-39905257.htm" target="_blank">a matter of digital sovereignty</a>.</p>
<p>The Senate has already voted on the bill. Following an agreement today between senators and lawmakers from the lower house National Assembly, a final vote will be held again in the Senate where the bill is expected to pass.</p>
<p>Senators have also suggested using FranceConnect, a tool developed by the state to help users connect to public services such as tax collection and health insurance.</p>
<p>In the face of skepticism and privacy concerns from campaigners, O has since <a href="https://www.zdnet.fr/actualites/identite-numerique-le-cnnum-veut-soutenir-l-effort-deja-engage-par-le-gouvernement-39905257.htm" target="_blank">denied</a> that the national connection tool would be used.</p>
<p>"We voted on one principle, which is to give the CSA the obligation to monitor the protection of minors, but the CSA is free to find the right way for sites to comply with their injunction," the text’s rapporteur in the Senate Marie Mercier told POLITICO.</p>
<h3><strong>Minitel rose</strong></h3>
<p>Key actors from the French porn industry have long called for new measures to modernize a French law which was drafted at the time of the “Minitel rose,” a very popular pornography service in the 1980s.</p>
<p>“[With this law] we can already fine up to 75,000 euros and three years of prison, but no one applies it,” said Mercier.</p>
<p>The conservative politician worked on the amendment after hearings with French pornography producer Marc Dorcel, ex-adult actress-turned-documentary-director Ovidie and child protection NGOs.</p>
<p>“Most of those who abide by the law feel that it’s unfair that the [sites] keep doing their business without restriction," Mercier added.</p>
<p>For years, one of the most difficult tasks for French regulators has been finding a way to enforce local laws on foreign services.</p>
<p>With this new law, if the site does not comply within 15 days after a first warning from the audiovisual regulator CSA, the regulator will be able to ask the Paris Court of Justice to send an order to telecom operators to block the access to these sites from France.</p>
<p><em>Giorgio Leali contributed reporting.</em></p>
<p><em>This article is part of </em><span>POLITICO</span><em>’s premium Tech policy coverage: Pro Technology. Our expert journalism and suite of policy intelligence tools allow you to seamlessly search, track and understand the developments and stakeholders shaping EU Tech policy and driving decisions impacting your industry. Email <a href="mailto:pro@politico.eu" target="_blank">pro@politico.eu</a> with the code ‘TECH’ for a complimentary trial.</em></p>

														<!--/.story-supplement-->
							
							
							<!--/.story-supplement-->

						</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.politico.eu/article/france-to-introduce-controversial-age-verification-system-for-adult-pornography-websites/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23789309</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 08:16:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pinboard Turns Eleven]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 115 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23788599">thread link</a>) | @bishnu
<br/>
July 9, 2020 | https://blog.pinboard.in/2020/07/pinboard_is_eleven/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.pinboard.in/2020/07/pinboard_is_eleven/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <p><a href="https://blog.pinboard.in/2019/07/i_cant_stop_winning/">Pinboard is Eleven</a></p>       
        
         <p>
Pinboard is eleven years old today! Every year when I don't forget I try to publish the same stats:

</p><table>
    <tbody><tr>
      <th></th>
      
      <th>2010</th>

      <th>2011</th>

      <th>2012</th>
      <th>2013</th>
      <th>2014</th>
      <th>2015</th>
      <th>2016</th>
      <th>2017</th>
      <th>2018</th>
      <th>2019</th>
      <th>2020</th>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>bookmarks</td>

      <td>3.5 </td>

      <td>27 </td>

      <td>53 </td>

      <td>76 </td>
      <td>97 </td>
      <td>122 </td>
      <td>148 </td>
      <td>173 </td>
      <td>  </td>
      <td>224 </td>
      <td>244 </td>
    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>tags (M)</td>

      <td>11 </td>

      <td>76 </td>

      <td>135 </td>
      <td>178 </td>
      <td>212 </td>
      <td>251 </td>
      <td>291 </td>
      <td>291 </td>
    	<td> </td>
      <td>405 </td>
      <td>426 </td>

    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>active users (K)</td>

      <td>2.8 </td>

      <td>16 </td>
      
      <td>23 </td>
      <td>23 </td>
      <td>24 </td>
      <td>25 </td>
      <td>24 </td>
      <td>29 </td>
      <td> </td>
    <td>21 </td>
      <td>19 </td>


    </tr>

    <tr>
      <td>archives (T)</td>

      <td>0.2</td>

      <td>3.0 </td>

      <td>5.9 </td>
      <td>8.8 </td>
      <td>14.2 </td>
      <td>20.9 </td>
      <td>24.8 </td>
      <td>31.8 </td>
            <td> </td>

      <td>57 </td>
      <td>82 </td>

    </tr>

    

    <tr>
      <td>URLs (M)</td>

      <td>2.5 </td>

      <td>16 </td>

      <td>32 </td>
      <td>48 </td>
      <td>63 </td>
      <td>82 </td>
      <td>104 </td>
      <td>126 </td>
            <td>  </td>

      <td>173 </td>
      <td>192 </td>

    </tr>
    
     <tr>
      <td>revenue (K)</td>

      <td> 117 </td>

      <td>178 </td>

      <td>181 </td>
      <td>175 </td>
      <td>193 </td>
      <td>160 </td>
      <td>234 </td>
      <td>259 </td>
            <td>253 </td>

      <td>222 </td>
      <td>212 </td>

    </tr>
 <tr>
      <td>funding (M)</td>

      <td> 0 </td>

      <td>0 </td>

      <td>0 </td>
      <td>0 </td>
      <td>0 </td>
      <td>0 </td>
      <td>0 </td>
      <td> 0</td>
            <td> 0</td>

      <td> 0</td>
      <td>0 </td>

    </tr>
<tr>
      <td>acquisitions</td>

      <td> </td>

      <td> </td>

      <td> </td>
      <td> </td>
      <td> </td>
      <td> </td>
      <td> </td>
      <td>1 </td>
            <td> </td>

      <td> </td>
      <td> </td>

    </tr>
    

  </tbody></table>
  
<p>This has been an interesting year! When the pandemic came and left us all housebound, I used it as an excuse to do some remedial work I’d been dreading—moving Pinboard onto modern versions of PHP and MySQL. Things had gotten to the point where I couldn’t even run a bug-for-bug identical copy of the site on a modern laptop, and the servers themselves were overdue for system upgrades. 

</p><p>Much of the core code on the site dated back to 2009-2010 and was written by Past Me, a vindictive, inscrutable nemesis who devoted his life to sabotaging Present Me. 

</p><p><img src="https://idlewords.com/images/past_me.jpg">

</p><p><i>Past Me laying his snares in 2009.</i></p>

<p>Doing this on a live system is like performing kidney transplants on a playing mariachi band. The best case is that no one notices a change in the music; you chloroform the players one at a time and try to keep a steady hand while the band plays on.  The worst case scenario is that the music stops and there is no way to unfix what you broke, just an angry mob. It is very scary.

</p><p>But I got it done! It helped in this process that I was in Japan, since I could do most work at night while my US/European customers slept or wept into their phones or whatever it is people do at night nowadays. 

</p><p>The site is now on a 2020 foundation (specifically, it’s on PHP 7 and a current MySQL), and with everything less brittle I can start making bigger changes. One of those is to make the site look okay on mobile phones, now that I’m finally convinced they aren’t a fad. You can see the beginnings of this reworking on the <a href="https://pinboard.in/about/">about page</a> and in other corners of the site.

</p><p>Another is to finish the new API. The current one was designed to be a drop-in replacement for the old Delicious API and lacks important features, like any way to say “show me stuff that has changed since timestamp X”, or interact with Pinboard features that weren’t present in Delicious.

</p><p>Another analogy I’d use for this kind of upgrade work is clearing a disused garden. In the process you may unearth remarkable stuff—an old wagon wheel, a Roman urn—hiding among the weeds. But it’s mostly interesting to you, and not to the people who are waiting in line at your vegetable stand.

</p><p>In my case, I found the skeletons of dead features (remember placemarks?) as well as spectral ghosts of defunct services like Google Reader, Readability, and of course Delicious itself, which now slumbers peacefully while I try to figure out a way to bring it up without dealing with the waves of automated spam still pointed at the site. But I’ll save that for another post.

</p><p>Now that I have a fresher memory of how the site works, and am not so afraid of touching anything, I look forward to doing some long-delayed feature development.
 
</p><p>Meanwhile, thanks to everyone for using the site for another year! Not everyone gets to be around long enough to have to do major upgrades, and I am grateful to be in that position, thanks to all of you.

  
 </p><p>Previous anniversary posts:

</p><ul>
<li><a href="https://blog.pinboard.in/2019/07/i_cant_stop_winning/">I can't stop winning!</a> (10 years)</li>
<li><a href="https://blog.pinboard.in/2017/07/eight_years_of_victory/">Eight Years of Victory</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blog.pinboard.in/2016/07/pinboard_turns_seven/">Pinboard Turns Seven</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blog.pinboard.in/2015/07/pinboard_turns_six/">Pinboard Turns Six</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blog.pinboard.in/2014/07/pinboard_turns_five/'%3EPinboardTurns%20Five%3C/a%3E%3C/li%3E%3Cli%3E%3Ca%20href=" https:="" blog.pinboard.in="" 2013="" 07="" pinboard_is_four_years_old="" "="">Pinboard Is Four Years Old</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blog.pinboard.in/2012/07/pinboard_turns_three/">Pinboard Turns Three</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blog.pinboard.in/2011/07/two_years_of_pinboard/">Two Years of Pinboard</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blog.pinboard.in/2010/07/one_year_of_pinboard/">One Year of Pinboard</a></li>
 </ul>
        <p>—maciej on <a href="https://blog.pinboard.in/2020/07/pinboard_is_eleven/">July 09, 2020</a></p>
       </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.pinboard.in/2020/07/pinboard_is_eleven/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23788599</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 05:59:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pulsar vs. Kafka]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 56 | Comments 28 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23787958">thread link</a>) | @ceohockey60
<br/>
July 9, 2020 | https://streamnative.io/blog/tech/pulsar-vs-kafka-part-1 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://streamnative.io/blog/tech/pulsar-vs-kafka-part-1">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://streamnative.io/blog/tech/pulsar-vs-kafka-part-1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23787958</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 03:48:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ExSaaSperated: A blog about the struggle to start a sustainable SaaS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 113 | Comments 25 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23787666">thread link</a>) | @con-cat
<br/>
July 9, 2020 | https://exsaasperated.com/2020/06/20/hello-world.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://exsaasperated.com/2020/06/20/hello-world.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
<div>
<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

<div itemprop="articleBody">
<p>Another new blog on the internet – aren’t there already enough of
those? <a href="http://tttthis.com/blog/if-i-could-bring-one-thing-back-to-the-internet-it-would-be-blogs">Some would say
no</a>.
I, for one, am a fan of the open, interoperable, indie web,
even if that seems to stack the cards against you.<sup id="fnref:indie-disadvantage"><a href="#fn:indie-disadvantage">1</a></sup></p>
<p>I’ll keep this introductory post brief. We<sup id="fnref:we"><a href="#fn:we">2</a></sup> want to start a SaaS
product, and while there seem to be awfully many “founder stories”
around of people magically getting 50k downloads, $10k MRR, etc., we
don’t often hear about the long, rocky path to sustainable success.
There’s often scant detail about the initial steps: ideation,
validation, etc. Also, all these whiz-bang success stories suffer
from enormous survivorship bias. Not to mention they leave us normal
folks feeling quite inadequate, when in reality there’s enormous luck
involved, too.<sup id="fnref:luck"><a href="#fn:luck">3</a></sup></p>
<p>Unfortunately, “failure” isn’t sexy. As a result there seem to be few
resources online talking about the things people have tried that
<em>haven’t</em> worked. We want to take a more optimistic view. From each
“failure” we hope to learn things, get better at what we’re trying to
do, so that 10 years from now, looking back, we can point at all the
hustle that goes into trying to Build Something.</p>
<p>We figured we might as well challenge ourselves to get something out
there, right now, instead of waiting until perhaps one day if and/or
when we manage to create something successful. This way, at the very
least we’re keeping ourselves accountable by publicly writing about
what we’re trying, and who knows, we might be able to say something
that someone somewhere finds useful. We’re also very keen for
feedback, so any and all input is more than welcome. Ideas, critique,
links to resources, we want it, our inboxes are open. Have a look at
the <a href="https://exsaasperated.com/contact/">Contact us page</a> if you want to get in touch, or try our
low-budget comments box down below!</p>
<p>We’re just trying to muddle along making our own way here, so we’re
bound to have many a false start, but we are trying something new to
us – <a href="https://exsaasperated.com/mailing-list/">join us for the ride</a>, and we’ll see what happens!</p>

<hr>

</div>
</article>
</div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://exsaasperated.com/2020/06/20/hello-world.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23787666</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 02:49:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The most important part of a product is actually the text]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 18 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23782400">thread link</a>) | @jessouyang
<br/>
July 9, 2020 | https://blog.dittowords.com/the-most-important-part-of-your-design-is-actually-the-text/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.dittowords.com/the-most-important-part-of-your-design-is-actually-the-text/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			
<p>Design is about constantly closing the gap between what users expect from your product and what it actually does. Product teams try to close this chasm every day, whether by user testing, tracking metrics and behavior, or seeking feedback. In attempts to bridge this user experience communication gap, teams often forget the most important thing — the text.</p>



<p>Product copy, or the text found on user interfaces, is the most under-leveraged part of product development today. Here are a few reasons why.</p>



<h5>Editing copy is your highest ROI lever</h5>



<p>Unlike almost anything else in product development, editing copy doesn’t require any engineering or design lift. Working on copy is about <em>maximizing the utility of your existing feature set</em>.</p>



<p>In many cases, the cheapest and most practical solution to a problem is well-written copy. Rather than committing a team’s time to building an entirely new feature, editing the copy goes a long way in user retention and engagement.</p>



<p>Whether it’s a clearer error state that helps users self-correct or an empty state that helps users get started, editing text can directly affect metrics. [1] It’s easy for the conversation around copy to revolve around marketing copy (thinking about text on a landing page or a marketing email and whether or not it converts), but this conversation around the importance of text needs to shift to product as well.</p>



<p>Of course, there’s no substitute for poor design, but bad copy can make even the best designs ineffective.</p>



<h5>Product copy is your most direct line of communication to users</h5>



<p>As John Maeda expressed with his <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://vimeo.com/208035080" target="_blank">2017 Design in Tech report</a>, “Words are really important because the graphics don’t make sense sometimes.”</p>



<p>Product copy makes expected user behavior <em>explicit</em>. It’s your chance to communicate intent. In being what your users actually read, the text anchors the user experience and bridges gaps in expectation. As UX writer Ryan Cordell&nbsp;points out:</p>



<div><p>“Microcopy is how your product communicates. It provides answers, feedback, comfort, guidance, encouragement and more. If we fail to design the words we use, this still communicates something to the user. It says we can’t or don’t want to help. It says we don’t care as much as we should. And that’s catastrophic for the customer experience.” [2]</p></div>



<p>Ultimately in building a product, you’re optimizing for user understanding — to surface the value of the features that your team spent so long to build.</p>



<h5>Text is what guides users when they venture off the happy path</h5>



<p>It’s often easy for designers and PM’s to optimize for the happy path: the user experience that most closely aligns with their own expectations of how the product should be used. However, we all know that expectations often exist in isolation from how people actually use your product — and much of the burden of steering users back on track <em>relies on the text</em>.</p>



<p>Copy serves as your product’s guardrails. Whether it’s an error message, a new user experience, or an empty state, it’s often <em>text</em> that guides users when they don’t know what to expect. In a study conducted by Microsoft Azure’s design team, user test errors<em> decreased by 44%</em> after copy changes alone. [3]</p>



<p>It’s in these moments of mismatched expectations that clarity is most critical. This is especially true as the role of software expands. From health-tech to purchasing houses and cars, the sole responsibility of guiding people through complex and important decisions is now carried by the digital experience.</p>



<p>Often times, however, because these non-ideal users journeys don’t get designed, users are greeted with generic text written ad-hoc by the last person that touches it.</p>



<h5>Copy exists from end to end</h5>



<p>Almost every single step of the product development process works in verticals — designers work in design tools and then pass designs off to developers that work in devtools. The same verticalization of tooling and work applies to almost every other step of building a software product with a team.</p>



<p>The <em>exception</em> to this verticalization of product development is the copy, which exists from the very beginning (specs, drafts) all the way to the very end (in the final product) and is touched by everyone from design to engineering to legal to marketing.</p>



<p>Rather than existing as one-offs, the product text works in a system to build trust for users. Like the narrator in a story, copy sets the context and defines the goals. [4] Thinking about copy early means being intentional about the information you convey to users — and drives design decisions like progressive disclosure and information architecture.</p>



<hr>



<p>Let’s be clear: writing good copy is <em>hard</em>. It might not be glanceably flashy the same way a Dribbble post might be. Text often “looks” the same in a design at first- and second-pass, even after edits. Reworking copy can be painstaking — and requires an in-depth understanding of both the product and the user.</p>



<p>But as we want to build and design products that shape how people interact with the world, we shouldn’t overlook the obvious when communicating: the words.</p>



<hr>



















<p><strong>Footnotes:</strong></p>



<div><div>
<div><p>[0] In full disclosure, our belief that text should be first-class in building product has led Jolena and I to building <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://dittowords.com/" target="_blank">Ditto</a>. 🤗</p></div>
</div></div>



<p>[1] Even really simple copy changes change produce enormous ROI. <a href="https://www.directyourbookings.com/blog/marketing/convert-better-with-ux-writing-hotel-case-study-by-google/">One example</a> of many is the 17% increase in engagement when Google Travel replaced “Book a Room” with “Check Availability”.</p>



<p>[2] You can find more great excerpts from Ryan’s post on communication theory and microcopy <a href="https://uxdesign.cc/3-communication-theories-that-will-help-you-write-better-microcopy-and-make-better-products-4df25571ca6f">here</a>.</p>



<p>[3] In addition to decreased user test errors, the metrics-driven insights found by <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kyliehansen">Kylie Hansen</a>‘s team impacted NPS, customer retention, active users, and more. She goes over some of it <a href="https://ellessmedia.com/csi/kylie-hansen/">here</a>.</p>



<p>[4a] A scenario that often requires high trust is a monetary transaction. Increasing transparency by clearly surfacing what to expect is something that <a href="https://uxplanet.org/this-is-ux-writing-at-its-very-best-2806f3f386e0">both Airbnb and Amazon do well</a>.</p>



<p>[4b] Over coffee, <a href="https://medium.com/@jsaito">John Saito</a> once mentioned to us that the product of Dropbox itself had more words than a Harry Potter novel!</p>
		</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.dittowords.com/the-most-important-part-of-your-design-is-actually-the-text/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23782400</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 17:09:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Offline Voice AI in a Web Browser]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 12 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23782302">thread link</a>) | @dbartle
<br/>
July 9, 2020 | https://picovoice.ai/blog/offline-voice-ai-in-a-web-browser/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://picovoice.ai/blog/offline-voice-ai-in-a-web-browser/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div><div><p><b>July 09, 2020</b></p><h2 id="why-offline-when-youre-online">Why offline when you're online?</h2><p>Offline Voice AI in a browser may seem contradictory. Doesn’t using a web browser mean you’re online? But even if you’re connected to the Internet, running Voice AI offline, in-browser, means eliminating both minimum and variable latency, and that the speech data is intrinsically private: it does not need to leave the device.</p><p>Offline AI also allows the voice functionality to work consistently with progressive apps. And from a business perspective, it can let you determine cost based on customer seats instead of unbounded number of calls to a cloud provider.</p><h2 id="demo-application-smart-lighting">Demo Application: Smart Lighting</h2><p>Here is a web demonstration application that uses <a href="https://picovoice.ai/products/porcupine">Porcupine</a> (wake word detection) and <a href="https://picovoice.ai/products/rhino">Rhino</a> (Speech-to-Intent) engines to control smart lights in a home.</p><p><span><div><div><div><div><div><div><div><div><p>Welcome to the smart home! Using your voice, you can control various aspects of the lights in this house.</p><p>To start any command, say <strong>"Pico House"</strong> or <strong>"Pico Home"</strong> to wake the device.</p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Here are some example phrases:</p><p><strong>"Turn the lights in the Living Room on"</strong></p><p><strong>"Shut off the lights in the Bathroom"</strong></p><p><strong>"Switch on all lights"</strong></p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Here are some example phrases:</p><p><strong>"Turn the lights in the Kitchen Blue"</strong></p><p><strong>"Make the closet lights green"</strong></p><p><strong>"Switch all lights purple"</strong></p><p>Possible Colors:<br><span>Red</span><span>Orange</span><span>Yellow</span><span>Green</span><span>Blue</span><span>Purple</span><span>Pink</span><span>White</span></p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p>Here are some example phrases:</p><p><strong>"Turn the lights in the hallway up"</strong></p><p><strong>"Make the closet lights brighter"</strong></p><p><strong>"Dim all the lights"</strong></p></div></div></div></div></div></div><div><p><svg viewBox="0 0 480 400"><defs><radialGradient id="livingRoomGradient" cx="50%" cy="50%" r="50%" fx="50%" fy="50%"><stop offset="0%" stop-color="#fcec03" stop-opacity="1"></stop><stop offset="50%" stop-color="#fcec03" stop-opacity="0.5"></stop><stop offset="100%" stop-color="#fcec03" stop-opacity="0"></stop></radialGradient><radialGradient id="bedroomGradient" cx="50%" cy="50%" r="50%" fx="50%" fy="50%"><stop offset="0%" stop-color="#fcec03" stop-opacity="1"></stop><stop offset="50%" stop-color="#fcec03" stop-opacity="0.5"></stop><stop offset="100%" stop-color="#fcec03" stop-opacity="0"></stop></radialGradient><radialGradient id="bathroomGradient" cx="50%" cy="50%" r="50%" fx="50%" fy="50%"><stop offset="0%" stop-color="#fcec03" stop-opacity="1"></stop><stop offset="50%" stop-color="#fcec03" stop-opacity="0.5"></stop><stop offset="100%" stop-color="#fcec03" stop-opacity="0"></stop></radialGradient><radialGradient id="hallwayGradient" cx="50%" cy="50%" r="50%" fx="50%" fy="50%"><stop offset="0%" stop-color="#fcec03" stop-opacity="1"></stop><stop offset="50%" stop-color="#fcec03" stop-opacity="0.5"></stop><stop offset="100%" stop-color="#fcec03" stop-opacity="0"></stop></radialGradient><radialGradient id="kitchenGradient" cx="50%" cy="50%" r="50%" fx="50%" fy="50%"><stop offset="0%" stop-color="#fcec03" stop-opacity="1"></stop><stop offset="50%" stop-color="#fcec03" stop-opacity="0.5"></stop><stop offset="100%" stop-color="#fcec03" stop-opacity="0"></stop></radialGradient><radialGradient id="closetGradient" cx="50%" cy="50%" r="50%" fx="50%" fy="50%"><stop offset="0%" stop-color="#fcec03" stop-opacity="1"></stop><stop offset="50%" stop-color="#fcec03" stop-opacity="0.5"></stop><stop offset="100%" stop-color="#fcec03" stop-opacity="0"></stop></radialGradient><radialGradient id="pantryGradient" cx="50%" cy="50%" r="50%" fx="50%" fy="50%"><stop offset="0%" stop-color="#fcec03" stop-opacity="1"></stop><stop offset="50%" stop-color="#fcec03" stop-opacity="0.5"></stop><stop offset="100%" stop-color="#fcec03" stop-opacity="0"></stop></radialGradient></defs><polyline points="224,397.6 2.4,397.6 2.4,2.4 477.6,2.4 477.6,397.6 258,397.6" id="outer-wall"></polyline><polyline points="160,224 2.4,224 2.4,2.4 240,2.4 240,128"></polyline><polyline points="240,128 240,2.4 477.6,2.4 477.6,176 470,176"></polyline><polyline points="224,397.6 2.4,397.6 2.4,224 167.2,224 167.2,250"></polyline><polyline points="475.2,272 320,272 320,176 448,176"></polyline><polyline points="310,272 477.6,272 477.6,397.6 258,397.6"></polyline><polyline points="310,176 320,176 320,224 240,224 240,176 250,176"></polyline><polyline points="250,272 240,272 240,224 320,224 320,272 310,272"></polyline><rect x="20" y="20" width="15" height="70" rx="5" fill="#76838E"></rect><rect x="170" y="15" width="60" height="100" rx="5" fill="#dbdbdb"></rect><rect x="172" y="25" width="40" height="80" rx="5" fill="#F8F9FA"></rect><rect x="20" y="150" width="90" height="50" fill="#DDECFA"></rect><path d=" M 45,145 L 30,120 L60,120 Z" fill="#76838E"></path><ellipse cx="45" cy="135" rx="15" ry="10" fill="#dbdbdb"></ellipse><path d=" M 85,145 L 70,120 L100,120 Z" fill="#76838E"></path><ellipse cx="85" cy="135" rx="15" ry="10" fill="#dbdbdb"></ellipse><rect x="330" y="15" width="140" height="110" rx="5" fill="#dbdbdb"></rect><rect x="330" y="15" width="90" height="110" rx="5" fill="#DDECFA"></rect><rect x="433" y="22" width="25" height="45" rx="5" fill="#F8F9FA"></rect><rect x="433" y="72" width="25" height="45" rx="5" fill="#F8F9FA"></rect><rect x="4.8" y="226.4" width="50" height="168.8" fill="#dbdbdb"></rect><rect x="4.8" y="226.4" width="160" height="50" fill="#dbdbdb"></rect><rect x="9.4" y="290" width="35" height="50" fill="#F8F9FA"></rect><rect x="14.4" y="295" width="25" height="40" fill="#76838E"></rect><rect x="70" y="232.4" width="50" height="35" fill="#F8F9FA"></rect><circle cx="85" cy="243" r="7" fill="#76838E"></circle><circle cx="85" cy="258" r="7" fill="#76838E"></circle><circle cx="105" cy="243" r="7" fill="#76838E"></circle><circle cx="105" cy="258" r="7" fill="#76838E"></circle><rect x="322.4" y="178.4" width="50" height="91.2" fill="#F8F9FA"></rect><rect x="327.4" y="183.4" width="40" height="81.2" fill="#dbdbdb"></rect><rect x="435.2" y="239.6" width="40" height="30" fill="#dbdbdb"></rect><rect x="440.2" y="245" width="30" height="20" fill="#76838E"></rect><rect x="415.2" y="370.2" width="60" height="25" fill="#dbdbdb"></rect><rect x="0" y="0" width="224" height="224" id="living-room"></rect><rect x="272" y="0" width="176" height="176" id="bedroom"></rect><rect x="0" y="224" width="160" height="160" id="kitchen"></rect><rect x="352" y="176" width="96" height="96" id="bathroom"></rect><rect x="305" y="272" width="128" height="128" id="hallway"></rect><rect x="256" y="176" width="48" height="48" id="closet"></rect><rect x="256" y="224" width="48" height="48" id="pantry"></rect><text x="40" y="35">LIVING ROOM</text><text x="247" y="35">BEDROOM</text><text x="250" y="210">CLOSET</text><text x="375" y="230">BATHROOM</text><text x="250" y="250">PANTRY</text><text x="380" y="360">HALLWAY</text><text x="60" y="380">KITCHEN</text></svg></p></div></div></div></span></p><p>All of the speech processing is performed privately, offline, in-browser. You can see more web demos <a href="https://picovoice.ai/demos/">here</a>.</p><h2 id="how-to-embed-voice-ai-in-the-browser">How to embed Voice AI in the browser</h2><p>To achieve offline voice AI, we can use speech technology from Picovoice. Picovoice engines run in modern web browsers via WebAssembly. A typical use case involves providing the engines realtime audio input from the microphone, and receiving events back (e.g. hotword detected).</p><p>The core of running any Picovoice engine in the browser is simply three files: a WebAssembly module, its wrapper, and a binding file. The binding provides a factory method for creating an instance of the engine. The engine fires a callback to signal that the WASM has finished loading, accepts frames of audio, and returns the engine results.</p><p>We will expand on this foundation with additional steps to setup streaming audio, request microphone permission, and downsample audio to the required format. We’ve provided demo code to assist with those tasks.</p><h3 id="web-audio-api-and-microphone-access">Web Audio API and Microphone access</h3><p>Picovoice uses the <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Web_Audio_API">Web Audio API</a> to process streaming audio. The <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/MediaDevices">MediaDevices API</a> is used to access the microphone. The user must explicitly grant permission to access the microphone before any audio processing can occur. This is mandatory due to browsers’ security model. Additionally, the browser requires an HTTPS connection to allow microphone access (for testing locally, HTTP will suffice).</p><h3 id="web-voice-processor">Web Voice Processor</h3><p>Picovoice engines accept industry standard 16KHz audio for speech processing. When accessing microphone audio, we need to downsample it to this format. We also need to ask for permission from the user to access their microphone, and connect the input to the downsampler. To handle these tasks we have provided the <a href="https://github.com/Picovoice/web-voice-processor">Web Voice Processor</a> package. It is also available on <a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/@picovoice/web-voice-processor">npm</a>.</p><h3 id="web-workers">Web Workers</h3><p>Picovoice recommends using <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Web_Workers_API">Web Workers</a> to run the engines in the background. Workers separate the speech processing from the main JavaScript thread.</p><p><img src="https://picovoice.ai/static/callbacks-c8a5873581c231ecd10793ca212b2f8d.svg" alt="Callbacks and Workers"></p><p>The demo code includes Porcupine and Rhino web worker scripts. They communicate with managers in the main thread using <code>postMessage()</code>. In addition, the Web Voice Processor performs downsampling via its own dedicated worker.</p><h3 id="open-source-demo-applications">Open Source Demo Applications</h3><p>We have provided demo code for the Porcupine and Rhino engines (including running both together) that will run in a recent web browser without transpilation required.</p><p>The Porcupine demo allows you to control a smart lamp with always-listening commands.</p><p>The Smart Lighting demo uses Rhino to handle smart home lighting with natural language commands like “dim the living room lights”. There’s also an always listening version of this demo that uses Porcupine as a trigger to wake the smart home lighting and then use the natural language commands.</p><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/Picovoice/porcupine/tree/master/demo/javascript">Porcupine Smart Lamp</a></li><li><a href="https://github.com/Picovoice/rhino/tree/master/demo/javascript/standalone">Rhino Smart Home Lighting</a> (standalone push-to-talk)</li><li><a href="https://github.com/Picovoice/rhino/tree/master/demo/javascript/always-listening">Rhino Smart Home Lighting</a> (always-listening using Porcupine)</li></ul><p><span><p>The code provided is for demonsration purposes and we do not recommend or support linking to the source code directly. Only the binding, wrapper, and WebAssembly files (i.e. files in the /lib/ and /binding/ folders) are meant to be used and linked directly.</p></span></p><h2 id="common-questions">Common Questions</h2><h3 id="how-do-i-use-picovoice-engines-with-react-angular-vue-">How do I use Picovoice engines with React, Angular, Vue, …?</h3><p>Fundamentally, the engines do not care which framework you are using. That said, we have an <a href="https://github.com/Picovoice/rhino/tree/master/demo/javascript/react-app">open source sample</a> of how to use Picovoice with React in the browser with a <a href="https://picovoice.ai/tutorials/using-picovoice-engines-with-react/">companion tutorial</a> that explains the details.</p><h3 id="what-about-es6-and-modules-how-do-i-use-this-with-eg-webpack">What about ES6 and modules? How do I use this with e.g. Webpack?</h3><p>The JavaScript code provided is fairly conservative and does not use ES6 and newer language features, notably modules (that said, a modern browser is required to work with all of the aforementioned Audio, Worker, and WASM APIs). You may wish to e.g. convert one of the <a href="https://github.com/Picovoice/rhino/blob/master/demo/javascript/shared/ppn_rhn_manager.js">Manager IIFEs</a> to a class and provide a module export which would allow you to elegantly integrate it with a typical Webpack/Babel setup.</p><p>Alternatively, you can simply add the scripts as-is to the HTML document head using something like <a href="https://github.com/nfl/react-helmet">React Helmet</a>, and provide them in a static/public folder with your web application.</p><h3 id="which-picovoice-engines-run-in-the-browser">Which Picovoice Engines run in the browser?</h3><p>All of them.</p><table><thead><tr><th>Engine</th><th>Purpose</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><a href="https://picovoice.ai/products/porcupine/">Porcupine</a></td><td>Wake word detection</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://picovoice.ai/products/rhino/">Rhino</a></td><td>Speech-to-intent (NLU)</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://picovoice.ai/products/cheetah/">Cheetah</a></td><td>Speech-to-text (realtime; live feedback)</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://picovoice.ai/products/cheetah/">Leopard</a></td><td>Speech-to-text (file-based; accuracy boost)</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://picovoice.ai/products/octopus/">Octopus</a></td><td>Speech-to-index (voice search)</td></tr></tbody></table><h3 id="how-do-i-create-custom-wake-words-or-speech-to-intent-contexts-for-the-web">How do I create custom wake words or speech-to-intent contexts for the web?</h3><p>You can use the <a href="https://picovoice.ai/console/">Picovoice Console</a> to create wake words and design and train speech-to-intent contexts. Personal use accounts are free and enterprise accounts are available with a 30-day trial.</p><p><span><p>Note that to train custom wake words or contexts for the Web (WASM) platform, you must be <a href="https://picovoice.ai/contact/">commercially engaged</a> with Picovoice.</p></span></p></div></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://picovoice.ai/blog/offline-voice-ai-in-a-web-browser/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23782302</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 17:01:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A dev, designer, and a PM are asked the same question: What is UX?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 33 | Comments 47 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23782089">thread link</a>) | @ProcrastiNathan
<br/>
July 9, 2020 | https://blog.codelitt.com/what-is-ux/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.codelitt.com/what-is-ux/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section id="Post__Main-Content">
        <div>
          <p>Some weeks ago I asked a few of the Codelitt team members a simple question:</p><blockquote>“What is UX?”</blockquote><p>I was happy that no one shied away from answering, and the difference in their responses was incredible:</p><p><strong>Engineers</strong> focused their answers in very pragmatic areas that all revolved around <em>friction</em> and how to reduce it. The experience “behind the curtain” that helps make interactions smooth was what they thought of. Things like loading times or making sure that buttons were clickable came to their minds.</p><p><strong>Designers</strong> saw the importance of researching both the users and business who would be investing in the product. They cared about making sure that the brand’s values were enhancing the experience. They wanted the users &amp; customers to know exactly what to expect when interacting with their products.</p><p><strong>Project Managers</strong> focused on understanding and empathizing with the users so that the end product is intuitive and useful to the user.</p><figure><img src="https://res-2.cloudinary.com/hepw4b4yn/image/upload/q_auto/v1/ghost-blog-images/codelitt-user-experience.jpg"></figure><p>Simply put, UX means “User Experience”: it’s the experience that a user has while interacting with a product. UX <em>Design</em> is, by definition, the process by which we determine what that experience will be.</p><p>UX Design always happens. Whether it’s intentional or not, somebody makes the decisions about how the human and the product will interact. <em>Good</em> UX Design happens when we make these decisions in a way that understands and fulfills the needs of both our users and our business.</p><p>UX encompasses so many disciplines that it’s unfair to think of it as a sphere within visual design. Quite the contrary! The building of an interface is a <em>subset</em> of that product’s experience design.</p><figure><img src="https://res-3.cloudinary.com/hepw4b4yn/image/upload/q_auto/v1/ghost-blog-images/codelitt-ux.jpg"></figure><p><strong>UX happens whenever a human interacts with a product</strong>. Any product. Take a pencil, for example. There’s the way that the wood, plastic or metal feels on your hand, the way it falls on your fingers, the feel of the graphite against the paper. Does it have a rubber end or a button you have to press to get the graphite out? In every case, it’s all been thoroughly thought out and designed, each component a part of the experience of writing with a pencil.</p><p>From the business objective, to the product’s stakeholders, designers, engineers and project managers, the experience encompasses every person working on it. It is the culmination of a multitude of disciplines working together. Every decision we make when building a product shapes that experience. UX is at the heart of everything we do.</p>
        </div>
      </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.codelitt.com/what-is-ux/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23782089</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 16:45:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Screenr – Automated Workflow for Your Email]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 104 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23782053">thread link</a>) | @charles_f
<br/>
July 9, 2020 | https://www.feval.ca/posts/screenr/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.feval.ca/posts/screenr/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
    
    



<p>I tried <a href="https://www.hey.com/">Hey</a>, the new e-mail service built by Basecamp. It is great, simple, smart. They’ve put a lot of thoughts behind re-inventing email. There are some pretty interesting features but fundamentally what is different is the opinionated workflow on which it operates.</p>

<p>The only mail that lends into the “Imbox” (how they name the important inbox) is from senders the user allowed. The first time they receive an email from someone, it ends in a staging zone, and then the user need to screen senders and decide if they want to receive emails from them, and where they want these email to lend: 1. in the imbox, 2. in a set of “feeds” (email that is casually read), 3. in the “paper trail” (receipts, …).</p>

<p>I liked the overall experience of Hey, and was about to subscribe. However there are two things that are a no-go for me. It doesn’t support custom domains for email addresses (yet)<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup>, and there is no “archive” feature<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2">2</a></sup>. So I decided against that.</p>

<p>But I really liked the workflow, and I figured it shouldn’t be that big of a deal to re-create something similar in a plain-old mailbox.</p>



<p>Here’s what I need:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Senders need to be screened for their spam to be allowed in my inbox. I figured this can probably be done by redirecting mail from senders I never screened into a sub-folder and reviewing that occasionally.</li>
  <li>Screening senders need to be dead easy. That’s the beauty of Hey: screening is done by clicking on a thumbs-up or thumbs-down button. That’s why it works, no non-sense of creating or editing rules.</li>
  <li>Support the same kind of classifying structure. I already had a <em>newsletter</em> folder with a few manually created rules, and a <em>reference</em> folder in which I would occasionally put a mail that I wanted to retrieve easily - this is just automating that.</li>
  <li>Works from my computer or my phone, using existing apps. There is no point in starting a multi-month project and implement a working email UI, this needs to fit within my limited evenings and kids naps.</li>
  <li>Low maintenance, for the same reason.</li>
</ol>



<p>So I built <a href="https://github.com/cfe84/screenr">Screenr</a>.</p>

<p>Screenr plugs to an email server<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3">3</a></sup>, monitors email in folders, and classifies email into a set of folders.</p>

<p>Incoming emails from unknown senders (i.e. with an email address that has not been seen yet) are moved to a “For screening” folder. Emails from screened senders are moved based on configuration: either leave in the inbox, or move it to a particular folder.</p>

<pre><code>graph TD
	A[Inbound mail] --&gt; B(Inbox)
	B --&gt; C["Sender screened?"]
	C --&gt;|No| D("Move to 'For Screening'")
	C --&gt;|Yes| E(Move to configured folder)
</code></pre>

<p>To configure the tool, I just need to screen emails in the “For screening” folder occasionally, and move them based on where I want these to land: move emails from senders I still want in my inbox to a <em>Screened</em> folder (which then gets moved back into the inbox once Screenr registered the decision). Move emails I want to reject to a <em>Rejected</em> folder. Move emails I barely care about, such as newsletters, promotions, etc. into a <em>newsletter</em> folder. Move receipts, booking confirmations, order tracking info, tax documents, etc. into a <em>Reference</em> folder. If I move a single email between two monitored folder, then Screenr will move all of the mail from that sender into the new folder.</p>

<pre><code>graph TD
	A[For screening] --&gt; C[Decide what to do with this sender]
	C --&gt;|Allow in inbox| D("Move to 'Screened'")
	C --&gt;|Ok but classify elsewhere| E(Move to the folder you want)
	C --&gt;|Don't want mail from them| F(Move to 'Rejected')
</code></pre>

<p>Screenr supports two configurations (at the folder level) to classify email: either move the email directly to the target folder, or through an intermediary “classification” folder (like the “Screened” folder for email for inbox). The reason for that is that you might want to occasionally classify email without creating a rule: e.g. if my spouse forwards me a booking confirmation it’s nice to file it into the <em>Reference</em> folder without automatically classifying everything she sends me as reference<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4">4</a></sup>.</p>

<p>Bonus points: now I can change my default behavior for new email based on where I’m at. I archive email in my inbox - the reduced amount of email there makes inbox 0 much easier to attain - and delete email in the “newsletter” folder. Less thinking, inmore better.</p>



<p>There are 4 folders I’m watching:</p>

<p><img src="https://www.feval.ca/img/2020/screenr/folders.jpg" alt="The folders I'm monitoring"></p>

<ul>
  <li><em>Inbox</em> is the email that I (probably) care about. Once I read it, I archive it.</li>
  <li><em>Newsletter</em> is the stuff that I’m occasionally browsing, but it’s mostly composed of automatically sent emails and newsletters and there’s likely no required action. Once I read it, I (most likely) delete it.</li>
  <li><em>Papertrail</em> receives all my order confirmation, plane tickets, vouchers, etc. It usually just stays there. I used to call it <em>Reference</em> but I like Hey’s name better. Some of the mail I manually move there, mostly when my parents send me a scan of a bank record, or my wife sends me some reservation, because I don’t want to classify them there.</li>
  <li><em>For screening</em> is all the mail that I’m receiving from senders I haven’t reviewed yet.</li>
</ul>

<p>When something arrives in <em>For screening</em>, first I get excited because that’s proof that Screenr still does its job. Then I decide what to do with it by moving it in one of the folders:</p>

<p><img src="https://www.feval.ca/img/2020/screenr/screening.jpg" alt="The folders I use for screening"></p>

<ul>
  <li><em>Screened</em> is for emails I want in my inbox, like people I know, notifications I care about, etc. Screener registers my decision then move it (and potentially other emails by that sender) back into the inbox</li>
  <li><em>File in papertrail</em> is the same as screened, but for my <em>papertrail</em> folder.</li>
  <li><em>Rejected</em> is for what’s not exactly a spam, but I don’t actually want. Examples are emails from my car dealership, which is mostly spam, but which also sends me service confirmation once in a while, which I then go fishing in that folder and redirect to reference. Or companies who want me to wish them happy birthday:</li>
</ul>

<p><img src="https://www.feval.ca/img/2020/screenr/spam.jpg" alt="Example of some spammy email"></p>



<p>I wanted reasonable portability, my email provider recently released a bare-bones nodejs hosting and I figured I could give it a shot, so I settled for typescript. That host was hardly controllable, so I ended giving up and re-hosting onto the Kubernetes cluster from which you retrieved this static HTML page in a vastly over-complicated setup instead (more on this in <a href="https://www.feval.ca/posts/k8s-static/">this blog post</a>).</p>

<p>The application itself is decomposed into 4 layers following the onion architecture:</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>domain</code>, contains the actual classification logic</li>
  <li><code>contracts</code>, contains interfaces and data exchange structures for the dependencies that the domain will need an implementation for, such as <code>IMailbox</code> which allows retrieving emails or moving them around, <code>Mails</code> which are those mails, or <code>IScreeningStorage</code> which provides interfaces to store screening behavior or retrieve it based on sender.</li>
  <li><code>infrastructure</code>, which are the particular implementations for those dependencies: an <code>IMAPMailbox</code> implementing <code>IMailbox</code> which provides said features for an IMAP server.</li>
  <li><code>application</code> which binds all the stuff together: loads configuration, instantiate infrastructure, inject in domain, then kick off the process.</li>
</ul>

<p>For the storage of screening results, I settled on a file-based system which stores everything in memory and serializes it back to a file in storage when new rules are detected.</p>

<p>Building the IMAP connector was the most painful. The client libraries in the node ecosystem are not super well maintained and documented<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5">5</a></sup>, I tried two, and diagnosing some issues I was having<sup id="fnref:7"><a href="#fn:7">6</a></sup> was a straight pain that almost made me abandon. In retrospect I would probably pick .Net Core instead, given that the IMAP libraries are much more solid. If I want to make evolutions on that, I don’t exclude a rewrite ; the languages are sufficiently close that this wouldn’t be a big thing to do.</p>

<p>As mentioned, the hosting is done on a k8s cluster. A Helm chart specifies a single deployment with no service, and mounting a file share inside the container to store and retrieve the settings. Here is the extent of the infrastructure:</p>

<pre><code>graph TD
	  A[Pod] --&gt; C[File share]
</code></pre>



<p>To run Screenr, you need a computer that can run node ; ideally a server that you don’t turn off.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Source is on <a href="https://github.com/cfe84/screenr">GitHub</a> and the Readme explains how to configure it. Clone the repo locally, then run <code>npm install</code> and <code>npm run build</code>. To start it, go with <code>npm run start</code>.</li>
  <li>Compiled version is on <a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/screenr">npm</a>.</li>
  <li>Docker image is on <a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/cfe84/screenr">DockerHub</a> (or <code>docker pull cfe84/screenr</code>). Kubernetes Helm Chart are available in the git repo.</li>
</ul>



<p>There are some optimizations that could be done. For starters, this could use IMAP notifications to actually listen for new mail, rather than reconnecting and checking every 20s. I went for the straight forward thing right now, not sure if it’ll be a problem. Also this could be extended to support more rules, but it might require some more UI work which I don’t want to do, so that’s it for now.</p>





  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.feval.ca/posts/screenr/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23782053</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 16:42:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Subway-style maps of roads of the Roman Empire]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 157 | Comments 22 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23781879">thread link</a>) | @bookofjoe
<br/>
July 9, 2020 | https://sashamaps.net/docs/maps/roman-roads-index/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://sashamaps.net/docs/maps/roman-roads-index/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <header>
        
  <p><label for="menu-control">
    <img src="https://sashamaps.net/svg/menu.svg" alt="Menu">
  </label>

  <strong>Roman Roads Index</strong>

  <label for="toc-control">
    <img src="https://sashamaps.net/svg/toc.svg" alt="Table of Contents">
  </label>
</p>


  
 
      </header>

      
      
  <article>
<p>The Roman roads diagram project is a series of maps driven by an unconventional idea: what if we represented Ancient Rome’s famed road network in the style of a modern transit map?</p>
<p>So far I’ve made five diagrams (below). Click for more information.</p>
<p>You can see how my style has evolved since I made the first map back in 2017. My ultimate goal is to make a book out of these. I’ll probably have to redesign a few of them.






<!-- Photo Grid -->
</p><div name="photogrid"> 
  <div>
    <p><a href="https://sashamaps.net/docs/maps/roman-roads-original">1. Empire (Original)<img src="https://sashamaps.net/images/thumbs/roman_roads_original_small.png" title="CDMX: iPhone vs. Android"></a>
    <a href="https://sashamaps.net/docs/maps/roman-roads-of-italy">3. Italy<img src="https://sashamaps.net/images/thumbs/roman_roads_italy_v1_lat-eng_140-1_small.png" title="Roman Roads of Italy"></a>
    <a href="https://sashamaps.net/docs/maps/roman-roads-of-gaul">5. Gaul<img src="https://sashamaps.net/images/thumbs/gaul_vthick_140-2_small.png" title="Roman Roads of Gaul"></a>
  </p></div>
  <div>
    <p><a href="https://sashamaps.net/docs/maps/roman-roads-of-britain">2. Britain<img src="https://sashamaps.net/images/thumbs/roman_roads_of_britain_small.png" title="Roman Roads of Britain"></a>
    <a href="https://sashamaps.net/docs/maps/roman-roads-of-iberia">4. Iberia<img src="https://sashamaps.net/images/thumbs/roman_roads_iberia_v2.5_thumb.png" title="Roman Roads of Britain"></a>
  </p></div>
</div>




</article>
 
      

      

      
  
  
  
 

      </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://sashamaps.net/docs/maps/roman-roads-index/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23781879</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 16:25:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[PostgreSQL Templates]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 182 | Comments 31 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23781786">thread link</a>) | @kiwicopple
<br/>
July 9, 2020 | https://supabase.io/blog/2020/07/09/postgresql-templates/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://supabase.io/blog/2020/07/09/postgresql-templates/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article><header><p><time datetime="2020-07-09T00:00:00.000Z">July 9, 2020</time></p><div><p><a href="https://github.com/dragarcia" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img src="https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/26374889?s=400&amp;u=f5e35e9b47a50fa2b4d8c4bb96babd921071bcf1&amp;v=4" alt="Angelico de los Reyes"></a></p></div></header><section><p>Whenever you create a new database in Postgres, you are actually <a href="https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/manage-ag-templatedbs.html">basing it off an already present database</a> in your cluster. </p><p>This database, <code>template1</code>, and another, called <code>template0</code>, are standard system databases that exist in every newly created database cluster. Don't believe me? Why not quickly <a href="https://supabase.io/docs/postgres/postgres-intro">spin up a database</a> and see it for yourself with this query:</p><div><div><div tabindex="0"><div><p><span>SELECT</span><span> </span><span>*</span><span> </span><span>FROM</span><span> pg_database</span><span>;</span></p></div></div></div></div><p>In this post, we'll explore these template databases and see how we can make full use of their potential. We'll even look into creating a template database of our own.</p><h2>template1</h2><p>By default, running:</p><div><div><div tabindex="0"><div><p><span>CREATE</span><span> </span><span>DATABASE</span><span> new_db_name</span><span>;</span></p></div></div></div></div><p>simply copies everything from the database <code>template1</code>. We can modify this template database in any way: add a table, insert some data, create new extensions, or install procedural languages. Any of these actions would be propagated to subsequently created databases.</p><p>This, however, is <strong>not</strong> advisable. Removing any one of these modifications would need you to manually uninstall or drop these changes from <code>template1</code>. You do have the option to drop and recreate the entire <code>template1</code> database altogether. This unfortunately comes at the risk of committing a mistake along the way, effectively breaking <code>CREATE DATABASE</code>. It would be better to leave <code>template1</code> alone and create a template database of your own.</p><h2>Custom Template Databases</h2><p>To set an existing database as a template database:</p><div><div><div tabindex="0"><div><p><span>ALTER</span><span> </span><span>DATABASE</span><span> template_db_name </span><span>WITH</span><span> is_template </span><span>TRUE</span><span>;</span></p></div></div></div></div><p>Doing this allows any user or role with the <code>CREATEDB</code> privilege to utilize it as a template. If not, only superusers or owners of the database would be allowed to do so.</p><p>To create a new database with this template:</p><div><div><div tabindex="0"><div><p><span>CREATE</span><span> </span><span>DATABASE</span><span> new_db_name TEMPLATE template_db_name</span><span>;</span></p></div></div></div></div><h3>Advantages</h3><ul><li>With this, you can now have customized templates without the need to worry about polluting <code>template1</code>.</li><li>You can safely drop the entire custom template database without the risk of breaking <code>CREATE DATABASE</code>.</li><li>If you wish, you can create multiple template databases for various use cases.</li></ul><h3>Limitations</h3><ul><li>To properly create a database from a custom template database, there should be no other connections present. <code>CREATE DATABASE</code> immediately fails if any connections exist at the start of the query.</li><li>As such, if you are looking to replicate a database while maintaining your connections (eg. a production database), it would be more ideal to use the Postgres utility <a href="https://www.postgresql.org/docs/12/app-pgdump.html">pg_dump</a>.</li></ul><h2>template0</h2><p><code>template0</code> contains the same data as <code>template1</code>. We could think of this template database as a fallback if anything irreversible happens to <code>template1</code>. As such, this template database should never be modified in any way as soon as the database cluster has been initialized. To create a database with <code>template0</code> as the template database:</p><div><div><div tabindex="0"><div><p><span>CREATE</span><span> </span><span>DATABASE</span><span> new_db_name TEMPLATE template0</span><span>;</span></p></div></div></div></div><h3>Applications</h3><ul><li>If anything goes wrong with <code>template1</code>, It can be dropped and recreated with <code>template0</code> as the template database.</li><li>We can also create a clean database that does not contain any modifications present in <code>template1</code>. This would be useful when restoring from pg_dump. Any conflicts brought about by modifications not present in the dump are eliminated.</li><li><code>template0</code> can be used to specify new encodings. As pointed out in this <a href="https://hashrocket.com/blog/posts/exploring-the-default-postgres-template-databases#:~:text=we%20can't%20edit%20the%20locale%20or%20encoding%20of%20a%20database%20copied%20from%20template1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">article</a>, creating a new database with <code>template1</code> and new encodings would result in an error.</li></ul><div><div><div tabindex="0"><div><p><span></span><span>CREATE</span><span> </span><span>DATABASE</span><span> new_db_name TEMPLATE template0 ENCODING </span><span>'SQL_ASCII'</span><span>;</span><span></span></p><p><span></span><span>CREATE</span><span> </span><span>DATABASE</span><span> new_db_name ENCODING </span><span>'SQL_ASCII'</span><span>;</span></p></div></div></div></div><h2>Conclusion</h2><p>To quickly sum things up, we found out that new databases are, by default, created from a template database called <code>template1</code>. <code>template1</code> can be modified in any way we please and the changes would be present in any database created afterward. We can also create custom template databases and base new databases from them instead. If things go awry, <code>template0</code> is always there to help.</p></section><section><a href="http://eepurl.com/gPWkwn">SUBSCRIBE TO OUR NEWSLETTER</a></section></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://supabase.io/blog/2020/07/09/postgresql-templates/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23781786</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 16:16:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Math Behind SaaS Marketing Teams]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 18 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23780723">thread link</a>) | @krackpipio
<br/>
July 9, 2020 | https://kracov.co/writing/the-math-behind-saas-marketing-teams | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://kracov.co/writing/the-math-behind-saas-marketing-teams">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Marketing teams should scale alongside new business revenue. As the company generates new business, the marketing budget gets bigger and the team scales accordingly.&nbsp;<br></p><p>Companies often think about go-to-market (GTM) spend in terms of payback periods - if we put a dollar into the business today, how long will it take to get that dollar back in terms of revenue. For example, if we spent $15m on GTM in 2019 and generated $15m new business ARR in 2019 that would be a 12 month payback period. A 12 month payback is considered great for most SaaS businesses.&nbsp;<br></p><p>When you combine the idea of payback periods along with industry benchmarks for marketing spend you start to get a picture of what marketing budgets look like as you scale. According to <a href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5ea5d85d88b3bd3fa7481aab/5f0721b9c8fbf34510ac1da7_image%20(73).png" target="_blank">Keybanc</a>, SaaS companies spend between 15% and 50% of their go-to-market budget on marketing. </p><p>When you map out this percentage spend against payback periods, you start to get a sense of what your marketing budget at different revenue targets should look like.&nbsp;</p><figure id="w-node-5ab1cbc8e47a-32481ab0"><p><img src="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5ea5d85d88b3bd7015481ab4/5f06ab4c328260ba3799a145_marketngteam2.001.jpeg" alt=""></p></figure><div><p>The mix is largely determined by the sales motion. Generally, Self-serve SMB businesses require more marketing spend whereas enterprise sales heavy businesses require less marketing.&nbsp;</p></div><p>From here you can start to get a sense of what you can afford and how big your marketing team could be at each point in scale. Generally, marketing teams (full-time-employees) account for 35-40% of your marketing budget.&nbsp;<br></p><div><p>Another helpful datapoint comes from <a href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5ea5d85d88b3bd3fa7481aab/5f065bbf2b3d6331272bc36f_Insight_s_SaaS_Marketing_Spend_Benchmarks_Report.pdf" target="_blank">Insight Partners</a>, where they provide benchmarks for new logo bookings per marketing employee (FTE).&nbsp;</p></div><figure id="w-node-41bc96697126-32481ab0"><p><img src="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5ea5d85d88b3bd7015481ab4/5efbd440b708739085e5a3a8_qRW2yCCH9-9IoVtU_Y-tknGhkcROR8xbPL1pOipXzzoNWAsGs6gNpv4ESyzI4tmnSpsPOs-QmT6yTV9i_m7UjJ66d4d7wHRzTCwu6GzT_e-U3IC3iT33pJVrd_J5fNgBMMGu5ApO.png" alt=""></p></figure><p>As companies target bigger customers, individual marketers are able to support more revenue scaling from $498k/FTE to $1,238k/FTE. Bigger ACV companies typically have smaller marketing teams as the go-to-market strategy is more outbound sales led, rather than through digital growth marketing tactics.&nbsp;</p><p>By taking these benchmarks and extrapolating them against new business targets, you start to get a clear picture of what your marketing team should look like over time.&nbsp;<br>‍</p><figure id="w-node-b9a4ea7d9877-32481ab0"><p><img src="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5ea5d85d88b3bd7015481ab4/5f06ab6f3dc1fef5342db03a_marketngteam2.002.jpeg" alt=""></p></figure><p>‍<br></p><p>So for example, if I want to generate $9m in new business this year, and most of my customers pay me $50k each, then i’ll want to have a marketing team of around 11 people, but if i mainly focus on SMB customer then i’ll likely need a team of 18 people.&nbsp;<br></p><p>Of course, benchmarks and extrapolations only tell part of the story. Some companies index higher on programs vs. people. The exact mix depends on what you’ve found to work for your business in the past and what you want to experiment with in the future. Additionally,&nbsp; your capital position will naturally change your level of investment.</p><p>From personal experience, I found the above benchmarks to be a bit inflated to how we’ve built the team at Lattice.&nbsp; Historically, we’ve tended to operate a lean team of generalists, hire more contractors and indexed towards more program spend. But as we’ve added more specialization on the team, the numbers start to even out towards the above benchmarks.&nbsp;<br>‍</p><p>Regardless, understanding the relationship between new business targets, size of customer contracts, and go-to-market motion will help you to determine the size of your marketing team as the business grows.&nbsp;<br></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://kracov.co/writing/the-math-behind-saas-marketing-teams</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23780723</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 14:35:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to track and display profile views on GitHub]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 202 | Comments 106 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23780530">thread link</a>) | @rushter
<br/>
July 9, 2020 | https://rushter.com/blog/github-profile-markdown/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rushter.com/blog/github-profile-markdown/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>As part of recent design changes, GitHub has introduced READMEs for profiles. By <a href="https://dev.to/web/design-github-profile-using-readme-md-8al">creating a repo</a> with your name and adding <code>README.md</code> file with markdown to it, you can now add a rich description of yourself.</p><p>Here is an example of how it looks like:</p><p><img alt="Python reference count graph" src="https://rushter.com/static/uploads/img/github_profile.jpg" width="650"></p><p>This feature may not be available to your profile yet. GitHub uses selectively rolling.</p><p>Unlike the old plain-text bio field, the new feature supports external links and images. This is where it gets interesting.</p><h2>Tracking profile views</h2><p>Since Github's markdown can display images from external sources, you can now track and display views of your profile.</p><p>To do so, you need to host an image on your server and display it via Markdown syntax:</p><div><pre><span></span><span>!</span><span>[</span><span>image</span> <span>title</span><span>](</span><span>https</span><span>:</span><span>//rushter.com/counter.svg)</span>
</pre></div><p>On the server-side, each image request can be treated as a view of your profile. The rest of the story is simple — you need to store a counter in the database and return an SVG image with the number of views as a response. Of course, there will be some extra requests from bots, but having such statistics is better than nothing.</p><p>To prevent IP and User Agent leaking, GitHub caches all images via special proxy. To avoid being cached on Github servers after the first image request, your image must specify cache headers or return non-200 response (e.g., an HTTP 404 page).</p><p>Here is the HTTP header that disables caching:</p><div><pre><span></span>Cache-Control: max-age=0, no-cache, no-store, must-revalidate
</pre></div><p>This is not something new for repositories since they had this ability for a long time, and GitHub allows this kind of use of images for <a href="https://github.com/dwyl/repo-badges#github-repo-hit-counter-">interactive badges</a>. Unlike profiles, repositories have access to traffic statistics too.</p><p>Here is how it can <a href="https://github.com/rushter">look like</a> when you have access to the new feature:</p><p><img alt="Python reference count graph" src="https://rushter.com/static/uploads/img/github_counter.png" width="700"></p><p><br> There are libraries and services that can do <a href="https://github.com/brentvollebregt/hit-counter">this for you</a>. You can also use <a href="https://pipedream.com/@tod/github-profile-view-counter-p_G6CNmN/readme">Pipedream</a> if you want to have more control over the counter logic.</p><h3>Security aspects</h3><p>For a lot of people, allowing external images on their websites sounds like not a big deal. I've been using this technique to track profiles views on various platforms for more than 10 years. I've seen how recruiters constantly refresh my profiles when they need to make a decision :).</p><p>Unlike GitHub, most of them don't even bother proxying the image to hide IP, referrer, and browser agent. If you want to allow external images on your site, you <strong>must</strong> proxy them and hide everything about a person who requested it.</p><p>A person with bad intentions can trick a victim into opening your profile that looks completely legit and detect his IP and a browser. You can also set a cookie to track user visits on other websites, but browsers <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/14/21064698/google-third-party-cookies-chrome-two-years-privacy-safari-firefox">will soon stop</a> doing it.</p><p>A single-pixel image can provide you a lot of information. This is how the whole AD industry works when it tracks your visits on various websites.</p><h3>Conclusion</h3><p>According to my tests, profile views do not count as repo views, and I hope, in the future, we will be able to see traffic stats in the repository that hosts the README file.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rushter.com/blog/github-profile-markdown/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23780530</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 14:21:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to launch when the app directory rejects you]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 43 | Comments 26 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23779616">thread link</a>) | @jsmoov
<br/>
July 9, 2020 | https://directmemo.io/blog/how-to-launch-when-the-app-store-rejects-you?ref=HackerNews | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://directmemo.io/blog/how-to-launch-when-the-app-store-rejects-you?ref=HackerNews">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <p><span>Step 1:</span> Make something people want.<br>
        <span>Step 2:</span> Get rejected.<br>
        <span>Step 3:</span> Get scrappy.
      </p>
      <p>
        It happened.
      </p>
      <p>
        The email every app developer dreads:
      </p>
      <p><img src="https://directmemo.io/images/blog/1/rejection-e2a3c6a88dbf773961f19d543c955055.png?vsn=d" alt=""></p><p>
        I had done everything right:
      </p>
      <p>
        -- I tackled a problem I had from my 5 years of working remotely: <span>the difficulty of privately sharing team-wide tasks, announcements, and reminders.</span>
      </p>
      <p>
        -- I found my first customer on Twitter before writing a line of code.
      </p>
      <p>
        -- I even shipped quickly and iterated.
      </p>
      <p><img src="https://directmemo.io/images/blog/1/tweet-1c7e0b96d0e0d70d03aa4b661afb9531.png?vsn=d" alt=""></p><p>
        I checked all the boxes they teach you in Startup School!
      </p>
      <p>
        I tried to reason with them, or get some direction on how to get approval:
      </p>
      <p><img src="https://directmemo.io/images/blog/1/reply-21300b820e0a2a254072eca09fee544e.png?vsn=d" alt=""></p><p>
        No dice.
      </p>
      <p>Time to get scrappy.</p>
      <p>In a moment of brash inspiration, I tweeted at Stewart Butterfield (Slack's CEO) basically pleading my case</p>
      <p>No response.</p>
      <p>Sidenote: I deleted that tweet, but Stewart - if you’re reading this, give me a 5-minute chat any time, any place!</p>
      <p>My next move was to scour Twitter for phrases related to “Slack team tasks”, “Slack mass-messaging”, etc. and reach out directly to as many people as possible.</p>
      <p><img src="https://directmemo.io/images/blog/1/tweet2-9e15582f560fc65c73ec2c8461ff9e5a.png?vsn=d" alt=""></p><p>I ended up finding a 2-year-old tweet by Ryan Hoover (Founder of Product Hunt) about a browser plugin that served a similar purpose, but not very well.</p>
      <p>To get his attention, I posted the app to Product Hunt, and asked him for feedback as a reply to his original tweet:</p>
      <p><img src="https://directmemo.io/images/blog/1/hoover-fa7a1492ebc3de3e203a5b3f80d7cac7.png?vsn=d" alt=""></p><p>No response, again :/</p>
      <p>Next I created <a href="https://www.indiehackers.com/product/direct-memo" target="_blank">an Indie Hackers profile</a> with a post linking to the Product Hunt page, which led to a good number of upvotes.</p>
      <p>Sidenote: I’ve found the IndieHacker community to be one of the most supportive and welcoming on the internet - a testament to the leadership team and Rosie Sherry, the community manager. If you’re interested in community building, <a href="https://rosieland.substack.com/" target="_blank">her newsletter</a> is a must-read.</p>
      <p>Upvotes trickled in, until something awesome and unexpected happened. Ryan upvoted my post!</p>
      <p><img src="https://directmemo.io/images/blog/1/upvote-5751a7e7165c8c5e0cb3245eda22e5bb.png?vsn=d" alt=""></p><p>Obviously, app signups surged.</p>
      <p>Users signed up from large corporations, small businesses, universities, and everything in between.</p>
      <p>Industries ranged from watch-makers to fantasy sports commissioners, to CEOs.</p>
      <p>The thrill was intoxicating, and it hasn’t died down. A month later I still jump out of bed to check on new signups every morning!</p>
      <p>Moral of the story: When things don't go as planned, get scrappy and put yourself in a position to get lucky.</p>
      <p>Next I’ll be experimenting with other ways to grow, like social media ads. Are there any courses or websites you recommend for learning how to do them well?</p>
      <p>Let me know on <a href="https://twitter.com/jamilabreu">Twitter</a> or <a href="mailto:hi@directmemo.com">shoot me an email</a>!</p>
      <p>
<a href="https://slack.com/oauth/v2/authorize?user_scope=channels:read,chat:write,groups:read,im:write&amp;scope=chat:write,chat:write.public,commands,im:write&amp;client_id=1044574672421.1033527150930">          Try Direct Memo free for 7 days</a>
      </p>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://directmemo.io/blog/how-to-launch-when-the-app-store-rejects-you?ref=HackerNews</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23779616</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 12:51:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Hard is not defensible (2017)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 75 | Comments 50 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23778961">thread link</a>) | @saadalem
<br/>
July 9, 2020 | https://www.alexcrompton.com/blog/2017/05/26/hard-is-not-defensible | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.alexcrompton.com/blog/2017/05/26/hard-is-not-defensible">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-block-type="2" id="block-6c08b430531381f46d95"><div><p>In startups, being defensibile means competitors can’t catch you once you’re ahead. It’s an important characteristic of successful tech companies, so investors often ask about it when you try to raise money.</p><p>Defensibility questions sound like <em>‘once you’re big, how will you stay big?’</em>, <em>‘once you’re&nbsp;winning, how will you keep winning?’</em>, or the slightly misleading <em>‘what stops other people doing this?’</em>.</p><p>Founders tend to think a good answer might be <em>‘what we do is hard to do’</em>. They mix hard with defensible. But hard is not defensible.</p><p>Why? There are two kinds of hardness: Math hard – the hardness of working something out; and Bodybuilding hard – the intrinsic hardness of doing certain things. Both can buy you time, but are never enough.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-70effda3d90febe5484b"><div><p>Working new things out is hard, but that doesn’t mean once something has been worked out it’s hard to do. Things that are hard to come up with but easy to copy are ‘Math hard'.</p><p>Many mathematics problems take a long time to figure out how to solve. But, once you have a method, often the answer can be verified quickly and the method can be learned easily. Pythagoras needed to be smart to invent his theorem, but now children learn it in school. Other Math Hard things include recipes, designs, and new ideas.</p><p>Unless Pythagoras could have kept his method a secret, which is difficult to do, his theorem wouldn’t have helped him build a defensible company. Even school kids can copy it.</p><p>This is like startup ideas for a new kind of user experience or interface – they’re hard to figure out, hard to keep secret (especially if your users experience the secret), and easy to copy.</p><p>But what if you could keep the secret? After all, ‘trade secrets’ can be kept for a while if you’re careful.</p><p>The problem is, the more success you have with your secret, the more effort other people will put in to discover it. You might be really smart, and have worked really hard, but there are lots of smart people who will work hard to be successful. It’s unrealistic to think that you’ll ever have a totally unique insight, let alone one other people couldn’t come up with if they really wanted to.</p><p>If this kind of insight were the defensibility criterion necessary for starting a successful company, by definition almost no-one would ever start one. No matter the ingenuity of your invention, you’re going to end up competing on some other dimension.</p><p>Math Hardness, the hardness of working stuff out, at best buys you time. How much time? Sadly, some amount of time that’s inversely proportional to how much success you’re having. The more valuable your secret turns out to be, the less time you have left.</p><p>The other kind of hardness is the intrinsic hardness of doing certain things. Some things are difficult to do, even if everyone knows how to do them. This is Bodybuilding Hard.</p><p>Achieving a bodybuilder’s physique isn’t complicated, no matter what the endless range of supplements suggests. You need to: exercise frequently with heavy weights; and consistently eat a protein rich diet. Neither is a secret or complicated to understand. Most people, in shape or not, know this stuff. The problem is that doing these things is intrinsically hard. It requires strenuous activity that’s much less fun than seeing friends over beers and burgers.</p><p>Most valuable achievements are Bodybuilding Hard. Learning a new skill, becoming wealthy, being a good partner – all require effort. Practically everyone knows more or less how to achieve these things, but few actually do. That’s why there is a supplement shortcut for every industry: pointy guitars; self help books; and magazines with fancy bedroom techniques.</p><p>Bodybuilding Hard startups are everywhere. On demand services, marketplaces, ecommerce – they’re the backbone of Rocket Internet’s portfolio. They don’t have Pythagorean secrets. These businesses are a pain to run, requiring the coordination of thousands of people and complex operations.</p><p>Without a secret, beating everyone else is hard. But bodybuilding isn’t economically self-sustaining&nbsp;if&nbsp;you’re&nbsp;just&nbsp;good: you need to be the best. Despite small differences, the winner still takes it all.</p><p>Hence, bodybuilding is riddled with steroids and techniques to eek out tiny advantages. Bodybuilding startups are no different — only their steroids are cash, experience, and thousands of traumatised former bankers and consultants.</p><p>The more success you have through doing something Bodybuilding Hard, the more people are going to be incentivised to try to do the same thing. If it’s a startup worth starting, eventually the payoff must outweigh the hardness. And once it’s clear it does, your competition will bring steroids.</p><p>Bodybuilding Hardness, like Math Hardness, buys you time. How much time? Once again, some amount of time inversely proportional to how much success you’re having. The better it’s going, the less time you have left.</p><p>Both types of hardness are good ways to get started. Doing something hard buys you a window of opportunity to succeed. But, once you’re big, something else has to keep you there.</p><p>Defensibility doesn’t imply hardness in the long run, even if hardness is useful in the beginning. For the best companies, things get easier after the hard part.</p><p>Their long term advantage doesn’t require new insights or ongoing effort: it’s too hard to compete like this once the stakes are high enough. Their advantage is unique resource accumulation – like Google’s datasets or Apple’s brand, or scale-enabled product differentiation – like Uber’s liquidity or Amazon’s delivery infrastructure. You need to snowball.</p><p>Doing something hard can put you ahead of your competition, but it isn’t the hardness that will keep you there.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1553598693305_327084"><div><p>Thanks to the EF team for reading drafts of this. If you want to do something hard, and ideally defensible, start&nbsp;<a href="http://www.joinef.com/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><p>PS. My colleague Zefi Hennessy Holland raised an insightful point about hard to find market secrets that&nbsp;I&nbsp;can’t&nbsp;phrase better&nbsp;myself.</p><p>He said&nbsp;<em>‘If Math Hard is finding the solution to a problem many people know about, Market Hard means finding an industry problem that few people know about through a lot of hard work… Your competition can copy your moves but not the underlying insights that made you make them.’</em></p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.alexcrompton.com/blog/2017/05/26/hard-is-not-defensible</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23778961</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 11:20:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Unit Testing Is Overrated]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 473 | Comments 384 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23778878">thread link</a>) | @ingve
<br/>
July 9, 2020 | https://tyrrrz.me/blog/unit-testing-is-overrated | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://tyrrrz.me/blog/unit-testing-is-overrated">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><span>
      <span></span>
  <img alt="cover" title="cover" src="https://tyrrrz.me/static/d9c976fbc290d0715efec59d3cd8b3cb/00d43/Cover.png" srcset="https://tyrrrz.me/static/d9c976fbc290d0715efec59d3cd8b3cb/72799/Cover.png 320w,
https://tyrrrz.me/static/d9c976fbc290d0715efec59d3cd8b3cb/6af66/Cover.png 640w,
https://tyrrrz.me/static/d9c976fbc290d0715efec59d3cd8b3cb/00d43/Cover.png 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" loading="lazy">
    </span></p>
<p>The importance of testing in modern software development is really hard to overstate. Delivering a successful product is not something you do once and forget about but is rather a continuous recurring process. With every line of code that changes, software must remain in a functional state, which implies the need for rigorous testing.</p>
<p>Over time, as the software industry evolved, testing practices have matured as well. Gradually moving towards automation, testing approaches have also influenced software design itself, spawning mantras like test-driven development, emphasizing patterns such as dependency inversion, and popularizing high-level architectures that are built around it.</p>
<p>Nowadays, automated testing is embedded so deeply within our perception of software development, it’s hard to imagine one without the other. And since that ultimately enables us to produce software quickly without sacrificing quality, it’s hard to argue that it’s not a good thing.</p>
<p>However, despite there being many different approaches, modern “best practices” primarily push developers specifically towards <em>unit testing</em>. Tests, whose scope lies higher on <a href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/practical-test-pyramid.html#TheTestPyramid">Mike Cohn’s pyramid</a> are either written as part of a wider suite (often by completely different people) or even disregarded entirely.</p>
<p>The benefit of this approach is often supported by the argument that unit tests provide the most value during development because they’re able to catch errors quickly and help enforce design patterns that facilitate modularity. This idea has become so widely accepted that the term “unit testing” is now somewhat conflated with automated testing in general, losing part of its meaning and contributing to confusion.</p>
<p>When I was a less experienced developer, I believed in following these “best practices” to the letter, as I thought that would make my code better. I didn’t particularly enjoy writing unit tests because of all the ceremony involved with abstractions and mocking, but it was the recommended approach after all, so who am I to know better.</p>
<p>It was only later, as I’ve experimented more and built more projects, that I started to realize that there are much better ways to approach testing and that <strong>focusing on unit tests is</strong>, in most cases, <strong>a complete waste of time</strong>.</p>
<p>Aggressively popularized “best practices” often have a tendency of manifesting cargo cults around them, enticing developers to apply design patterns or use specific approaches without giving them a much needed second thought. In the context of automated testing, I find this prevalent when it comes to our industry’s unhealthy obsession with unit testing.</p>
<p>In this article I will share my observations about this testing technique and go over why I believe it to be inefficient. I’ll also explain which approaches I’m currently using instead to test my code, both in open source projects and day-to-day work.</p>
<p><em>Note: this article contains code examples which are written in C#, but the language itself is not (too) important to the points I’m making.</em></p>
<p><em>Note 2: I’ve come to realize that programming terms are completely useless at conveying meanings because everyone seems to understand them differently. In this article I will be relying on the “standard” definitions, where unit testing targets smallest separable parts of code, end-to-end testing targets software’s outermost entry points, while integration testing is for everything in-between.</em></p>
<p><em>Note 3: if you don’t feel like reading the entirety of the article, you can skip to the end for the summary.</em></p>
<h2>Fallacies of unit testing</h2>
<p>Unit tests, as evident by the name, revolve around the concept of a “unit”, which denotes a very small isolated part of a larger system. There is no formal definition of what a unit is or how small it should be, but it’s mostly accepted that it corresponds to an individual function of a module (or method of an object).</p>
<p>Normally, when the code isn’t written with unit tests in mind, it may be impossible to test some functions in complete isolation because they can have external dependencies. In order to <em>work around</em> this issue, we can apply the dependency inversion principle and replace concrete dependencies with abstractions. These abstractions can then be substituted with real or fake implementations, depending on whether the code is executing normally or as part of a test.</p>
<p>Besides that, unit tests are expected to be pure. For example, if a function contains code that writes data to the file system, that part needs to be abstracted away as well, otherwise the test that verifies such behavior will be considered an integration test instead, since its coverage extends to the unit’s integration with the file system.</p>
<p>Considering the factors mentioned above, we can reason that <strong>unit tests are only useful to verify pure business logic inside of a given function</strong>. Their scope does not extend to testing side-effects or other integrations because that belongs to the domain of integration testing.</p>
<p>To illustrate how these nuances affect design, let’s take a look at an example of a simple system that we want to test. Imagine we’re working on an application that calculates local sunrise and sunset times, which it does through the help of the following two classes:</p>
<div data-language="csharp"><pre><code><span>public</span> <span>class</span> <span>LocationProvider</span> <span>:</span> <span>IDisposable</span>
<span>{</span>
    <span>private</span> <span>readonly</span> <span>HttpClient</span> _httpClient <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>HttpClient</span><span>(</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>

    
    <span>public</span> <span>async</span> Task<span>&lt;</span>Location<span>&gt;</span> <span>GetLocationAsync</span><span>(</span><span>string</span> locationQuery<span>)</span> <span>{</span>  <span>}</span>

    
    <span>public</span> <span>async</span> Task<span>&lt;</span>Location<span>&gt;</span> <span>GetLocationAsync</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>  <span>}</span>

    <span>public</span> <span>void</span> <span>Dispose</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span> _httpClient<span>.</span><span>Dispose</span><span>(</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>public</span> <span>class</span> <span>SolarCalculator</span> <span>:</span> <span>IDiposable</span>
<span>{</span>
    <span>private</span> <span>readonly</span> <span>LocationProvider</span> _locationProvider <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>LocationProvider</span><span>(</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>

    
    <span>public</span> <span>async</span> Task<span>&lt;</span>SolarTimes<span>&gt;</span> <span>GetSolarTimesAsync</span><span>(</span><span>DateTimeOffset</span> date<span>)</span> <span>{</span>  <span>}</span>

    <span>public</span> <span>void</span> <span>Dispose</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span> _locationProvider<span>.</span><span>Dispose</span><span>(</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Although the design above is perfectly valid in terms of OOP, neither of these classes are actually unit-testable. Because <code>LocationProvider</code> depends on its own instance of <code>HttpClient</code> and <code>SolarCalculator</code> in turn depends on <code>LocationProvider</code>, it’s impossible to isolate the business logic that may be contained within methods of these classes.</p>
<p>Let’s iterate on that code and replace concrete implementations with abstractions:</p>
<div data-language="csharp"><pre><code><span>public</span> <span>interface</span> <span>ILocationProvider</span>
<span>{</span>
    Task<span>&lt;</span>Location<span>&gt;</span> <span>GetLocationAsync</span><span>(</span><span>string</span> locationQuery<span>)</span><span>;</span>

    Task<span>&lt;</span>Location<span>&gt;</span> <span>GetLocationAsync</span><span>(</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>public</span> <span>class</span> <span>LocationProvider</span> <span>:</span> <span>ILocationProvider</span>
<span>{</span>
    <span>private</span> <span>readonly</span> <span>HttpClient</span> _httpClient<span>;</span>

    <span>public</span> <span>LocationProvider</span><span>(</span><span>HttpClient</span> httpClient<span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span>
        _httpClient <span>=</span> httpClient<span>;</span>

    <span>public</span> <span>async</span> Task<span>&lt;</span>Location<span>&gt;</span> <span>GetLocationAsync</span><span>(</span><span>string</span> locationQuery<span>)</span> <span>{</span>  <span>}</span>

    <span>public</span> <span>async</span> Task<span>&lt;</span>Location<span>&gt;</span> <span>GetLocationAsync</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>public</span> <span>interface</span> <span>ISolarCalculator</span>
<span>{</span>
    Task<span>&lt;</span>SolarTimes<span>&gt;</span> <span>GetSolarTimesAsync</span><span>(</span><span>DateTimeOffset</span> date<span>)</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>public</span> <span>class</span> <span>SolarCalculator</span> <span>:</span> <span>ISolarCalculator</span>
<span>{</span>
    <span>private</span> <span>readonly</span> <span>ILocationProvider</span> _locationProvider<span>;</span>

    <span>public</span> <span>SolarCalculator</span><span>(</span><span>ILocationProvider</span> locationProvider<span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span>
        _locationProvider <span>=</span> locationProvider<span>;</span>

    <span>public</span> <span>async</span> Task<span>&lt;</span>SolarTimes<span>&gt;</span> <span>GetSolarTimesAsync</span><span>(</span><span>DateTimeOffset</span> date<span>)</span> <span>{</span>  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre></div>
<p>By doing so we were able to decouple <code>LocationProvider</code> from <code>SolarCalculator</code>, but in exchange our code nearly doubled in size. Also note that we had to drop <code>IDisposable</code> from both classes because they <strong>no longer own their dependencies</strong> and thus have no business taking responsibility for their lifecycle.</p>
<p>While these changes may seem as an improvement to some, it’s important to point out that the interfaces we’ve defined serve <strong>no practical purpose other than making unit testing possible</strong>. There’s no need for actual polymorphism in our design, so, as far as our code is concerned, these abstractions are <em>autotelic</em> (i.e. abstractions for the sake of abstractions).</p>
<p>Let’s try to reap the benefits of all that work and write a unit test for <code>SolarCalculator.GetSolarTimesAsync</code>:</p>
<div data-language="csharp"><pre><code><span>public</span> <span>class</span> <span>SolarCalculatorTests</span>
<span>{</span>
    <span>[</span><span>Fact</span><span>]</span>
    <span>public</span> <span>async</span> <span>Task</span> <span>GetSolarTimesAsync_ForKyiv_ReturnsCorrectSolarTimes</span><span>(</span><span>)</span>
    <span>{</span>
        
        <span>var</span> location <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>Location</span><span>(</span><span>50.45</span><span>,</span> <span>30.52</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>
        <span>var</span> date <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>DateTimeOffset</span><span>(</span><span>2019</span><span>,</span> <span>11</span><span>,</span> <span>04</span><span>,</span> <span>00</span><span>,</span> <span>00</span><span>,</span> <span>00</span><span>,</span> TimeSpan<span>.</span><span>FromHours</span><span>(</span><span>+</span><span>2</span><span>)</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>

        <span>var</span> expectedSolarTimes <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>SolarTimes</span><span>(</span>
            <span>new</span> <span>TimeSpan</span><span>(</span><span>06</span><span>,</span> <span>55</span><span>,</span> <span>00</span><span>)</span><span>,</span>
            <span>new</span> <span>TimeSpan</span><span>(</span><span>16</span><span>,</span> <span>29</span><span>,</span> <span>00</span><span>)</span>
        <span>)</span><span>;</span>

        <span>var</span> locationProvider <span>=</span> Mock<span>.</span><span><span>Of</span><span>&lt;</span><span>ILocationProvider</span><span>&gt;</span></span><span>(</span>lp <span>=&gt;</span>
            lp<span>.</span><span>GetLocationAsync</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>==</span> Task<span>.</span><span>FromResult</span><span>(</span>location<span>)</span>
        <span>)</span><span>;</span>

        <span>var</span> solarCalculator <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>SolarCalculator</span><span>(</span>locationProvider<span>)</span><span>;</span>

        
        <span>var</span> solarTimes <span>=</span> <span>await</span> solarCalculator<span>.</span><span>GetSolarTimesAsync</span><span>(</span>date<span>)</span><span>;</span>

        
        solarTimes<span>.</span><span>Should</span><span>(</span><span>)</span><span>.</span><span>BeEquivalentTo</span><span>(</span>expectedSolarTimes<span>)</span><span>;</span>
    <span>}</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Here we have a basic test that verifies that <code>SolarCalculator</code> works correctly for a known location. Since unit tests and their units are tightly coupled, we’re following the recommended naming convention, where the test class is named after the class under test, and the name of the test method follows the <code>Method_Precondition_Result</code> pattern.</p>
<p>In order to simulate the desired precondition in the arrange phase, we have to inject corresponding behavior into the unit’s dependency, <code>ILocationProvider</code>. In this case we do that by substituting the return value of <code>GetLocationAsync()</code> with a location for which the correct solar times are already known ahead of time.</p>
<p>Note that although <code>ILocationProvider</code> exposes two different methods, from the contract perspective <strong>we have no way of knowing which one actually gets called</strong>. This means that by choosing to mock a specific one of these methods, we are making an <strong>assumption about the underlying implementation</strong> of the method we’re testing (which was deliberately hidden in the previous snippets).</p>
<p>All in all, the test does correctly verify that the business logic inside <code>GetSolarTimesAsync</code> works as expected. However, let’s expand on some of the observations we’ve made in the process.</p>
<hr>
<ol>
<li>Unit tests <strong>have a limited purpose</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>It’s important to understand that the purpose of any unit test is very simple: …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://tyrrrz.me/blog/unit-testing-is-overrated">https://tyrrrz.me/blog/unit-testing-is-overrated</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://tyrrrz.me/blog/unit-testing-is-overrated</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23778878</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 11:06:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Developing Computer Self-Reliance]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 50 | Comments 19 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23778614">thread link</a>) | @sT370ma2
<br/>
July 9, 2020 | https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/computer-self-reliance.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/computer-self-reliance.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

   <!-- Picture -->

   <center>
      <img src="https://cheapskatesguide.org/pics/motherboard-and-hands-500.jpg" alt="Motherboard and hands">
   </center>
   <!-- Title -->
   
   

   <p><!--<img align="left" src="../pics/motherboard-and-hands-320.jpg" alt="Motherboard and Hands" style="max-width:100%;height:auto; padding:15px;">-->I think Covid-19 has re-emphasized the value of self-reliance
      to many of us.  During this pandemic, we have been through
      periods when we couldn't simply pick up a phone and call someone 
      to come to our home to make repairs.  We may also have been 
      unable to go to a local shop to get help.  Since so much of our 
      personal business must now be conducted on line, finding inexpensive 
      computers and making basic repairs to our own computers 
      are becoming important life skills.  Without them, we may be unable 
      to stay connected to the world, to attend school, to work, or even to 
      buy food without risking exposure to a potentially deadly disease.</p>

   <p>Fortunately, repairing a computer or buying a cheap used one is not as 
      difficult as many people seem to believe.  All that is needed is the 
      will to learn to do these things in a hands-on way.  Individuals must 
      be willing to take the risks associated with trying to repair 
      their own computers or buying used computers on line.  For most people, 
      I think this is the stumbling block that they never overcome.  
      What separates the people who can do these things from those who 
      cannot is not intelligence.  It is nothing more than need and 
      interest sufficient to get them past the stumbling block.  
      If you are willing to learn, you will win the battle for 
      computer self-reliance.  I will not tell you that you will not be 
      frustrated at times.  I will only say that, if you keep trying, you 
      will learn these skills.</p>

   <p>In this article, I will outline the knowledge and skills that are 
      necessary to solve most basic computer repair problems.  But first, I 
      will explain one simple step that you can take right now to have a 
      working computer in your home at all times.</p>

   <p>Have a working backup computer in your home to use in the event of 
      the death or loss of your primary 
      computer.  A backup computer need not be expensive.  In fact, you can 
      buy a useful, used computer on Ebay for around $50.  The role of this 
      computer is only to get you on line to do research or to buy parts or 
      other necessities until you can get your primary computer working 
      again, or until you can buy another computer.  A rather 
      <a href="https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/surf-internet.html">old computer</a> is capable of meeting 
      these needs.  Some of you may want to use a cellphone for this, and 
      that will work if your cellphone service includes a data plan.  However, 
      for reasons that will become clear later, a fully-functioning computer 
      would be better.  I have written several articles on 
      cheapskatesguide.org that explain how to buy a cheap computer on 
      line.  For suggestions about multiple approaches to getting a cheap 
      laptop, read <a href="https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/how-to-get-a-cheap-laptop.html">this 
      article</a>.  For recommendations regarding the best used laptops to 
      buy for less than $100 in the year 2020, read 
      <a href="https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/best-laptops-in-2020.html">this</a>.  To obtain a more 
      in-depth understanding of the art of buying a computer that meets your
      needs, go to the <a href="https://cheapskatesguide.org/helper/core-page.html">Core 
      Articles</a> page and read the articles there in chronological order.</p>

   <p>Now, let me talk about what you need to know to make basic computer 
      repairs.  If you take good care of your computer, the only computer 
      repair that you are likely to need that is not basic is the 
      replacement of your motherboard.  So, if your computer is completely 
      dead or stops booting at the BIOS screen (both symptoms of a bad 
      motherboard), it is most likely time to buy another computer.  If any 
      life at all remains in your computer--if you hear beep codes (beeping 
      sounds when you turn on your computer), see a repeating 
      pattern of flashing 
      lights, or see an error message on the monitor--you may be looking at 
      a computer that you can repair with basic skills.  Below, are the 
      skills that everyone can learn and then use to make basic computer 
      repairs.  Everyone should be able to:</p>
   <br>

   <div>
   <center><h2>Basic Computer Repair Skills Everyone should have</h2></center>
   <ul>
      <li>Diagnose basic computer problems</li>
      <li>Identify compatible parts for a computer</li>
      <li>Research repair methods on line</li>
      <li>Make basic changes to a computer's BIOS settings</li>
      <li>Create a bootable Linux USB drive</li>
      <li>Re-install software</li>
      <li>Replace a hard drive or solid state drive</li>
   </ul>
   </div>
   <p>When you think about it, that is a rather short list.  I think that a
      simple lack 
      of desire is the only thing that prevents most people from obtaining 
      these skills.  In this article, I will not teach you these skills.  I 
      will tell you what you need to know and a little about how to find 
      that knowledge.  I will tell you how to develop the skills.  And, in 
      some cases, I will outline basic repair procedures and tell you how 
      to fill in the details yourself.</p>
   <h2>Diagnosing Basic Computer Problems</h2>
   <p>Most symptoms of computer problems are pretty obvious.  Your keyboard 
      stops working.  A USB connector stops working.  Your computer's monitor 
      doesn't light up.  A message appears on your monitor saying that no 
      operating system was found.  Your computer's sound stops working.  
      The question is not whether a problem exists but whether it is 
      a software problem or a hardware problem.</p><p>The easiest way to rule out a hardware problem is to boot your 
      computer from a reliable, bootable Linux USB flash drive.  If the 
      problem does not go away, then you most likely have a hardware 
      problem.  One obvious exception is that the problem will go away if 
      your hard drive is bad.  I recommend creating a bootable Linux Mint 
      USB flash drive, making sure it works with every piece of hardware on 
      your computer, and setting it aside for when you need it.  Another
      benefit of having a Linux USB flash drive is that if your hard
      drive dies, you will still be able to use your computer to get online.</p>

   <p>If the problem is caused by software, an online search will give you 
      possible sources and procedures to follow to narrow down the problem 
      to one source.  If an error message appears, use an online search 
      engine to search for that exact error message with quotes around it.  
      If you have no error message, you may have more difficulty finding 
      information about the exact source of your problem.  This process can 
      sometimes take several hours, but you are likely to eventually find 
      hints that will lead you to solutions for most computer software 
      problems, especially if the software is common.</p><h2>Identifying Compatible Parts for Your Computer</h2>
   <p>On a modern laptop computer, the battery and hard drive are the only 
      parts that are likely to fail that you can replace with basic 
      skills.  In over 30 years of owning computers, I have never had a 
      single stick of RAM fail.  I have had RAM sticks that have become 
      unseated from their connectors and needed to be pushed back into 
      place.  Beep codes or flashing lights can give you a hint that RAM 
      has become unseated.  Search on line for "computer beep codes" to find 
      the specific beep codes for your computer.</p> 

   <p>You generally only need to know three things to locate a 
      hard drive or Solid State Drive (SSD) that is compatible with your 
      computer: the hard drive's width, its thickness, and the type of 
      connector to which it connects.  You need to buy a replacement hard 
      drive that will physically fit into the space in your computer, and  
      the connector of the hard drive must connect to the connector on your 
      computer's motherboard.  These days, all spinning hard drives are 
      either 2.5 or 3.5 inches wide with SATA connectors.  Most 
      regular-sized desktop computers have 3.5 inch hard drives, but a 
      laptop will never have a 3.5 inch hard drive.  Laptops have either 2.5 
      inch spinning hard drives or some kind of SSD.  If your computer has 
      an SSD, you will have to open up your computer and look at the SSD's
      connector.  Unfortunately, these days, there are a small number of 
      solid state drive connector types that have the same physical 
      connections but are different electrically.  In my opinion, this was 
      a very poor design decision.  Luckily, these SSD's are the only 
      example in the computer industry of which I am aware of this being 
      allowed to occur.  Find a picture of your SSD's connector online and see 
      what type of connector the online source says it is.  Wikipedia is 
      a good place to look for this type of information.  Once you have 
      identified the type of connector on your SSD, see what Wikipedia says 
      about its electrical arrangement.  Do not try to use an SSD with a 
      different type of electrical arrangement, because this is likely to 
      damage the replacement SSD and your computer.</p>
   <h2>Researching Computer Repair Methods on Line</h2>
   <p>When your computer develops a problem, you can almost always find a 
      procedure on line for solving it.  First, you need to know <i>what</i> to 
      do to repair a generic computer with the specific problem you are 
      seeing.  You can read on line about <i>what</i> to do to repair the 
      problem on a generic Windows, Mac, or Linux computer.  Then, if the 
      problem is a hardware problem, you need to know <i>how</i> to 
      physically accomplish the repair of your specific model of computer.  
      A Youtube video can be beneficial for this.  An example of 
      what I mean by "<i>how</i> to physically repair" is the following.  When 
      you open the back of your laptop, what screws do you have to unscrew 
      to release the hard drive?  Do you pull the hard drive straight out 
      perpendicularly from the back of the laptop?  Or, do you slide it 
      parallel to the back of the laptop …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/computer-self-reliance.html">https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/computer-self-reliance.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/computer-self-reliance.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23778614</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 10:13:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Markdig and Error-Free Programming in F#]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 42 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23778525">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
July 9, 2020 | https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/post/80708/technical-tuesdays-markdig-and-error-free-programming-in-f | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/post/80708/technical-tuesdays-markdig-and-error-free-programming-in-f">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <div>
        <header>
            <p><a href="https://locals.com/" target="_blank" title="locals.com">
                    <img src="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/images/locals-logo-transparent.svg" alt="locals logo">
                </a>
            </p>
            <div>
                <div>
                    <p><a href="https://locals.com/" target="_blank" title="locals.com">
                        <img src="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/images/locals-logo-transparent.svg" alt="locals logo">
                    </a></p><div>
                        <p><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/login">
                            Login
                        </a>
                        <a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/">
                            Signup
                        </a>
                    </p></div>
                    
                </div>
            </div>
            <div>
                <div>
                    <p><a href="https://locals.com/" target="_blank" title="locals.com">
                        <img src="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/images/locals-logo-transparent.svg" alt="locals logo">
                    </a></p><div>
                        <p><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/login">
                            Login
                        </a>
                        <a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/">
                            Signup
                        </a>
                    </p></div>
                    
                </div>
            </div>
        </header>
        <section>
            <div>
                
            </div>
            <div>
                <div>
                    <div>
                        <p><span>
                            Shared post from
                        </span></p><p>
                            DanielBMarkham <br>
                            Community
                        </p>
                    </div>
                    <p><img src="https://cdn.rubinreport.com/images/avatars/92269/92269_xsgujuxuwvuchvt_thumb.jpeg" alt="community logo">
                    </p>
                </div>
                <article>
                    

<div>
    

<div>
    <div>
        <p><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/member/DanielBMarkham">
                <span>
                    <span>
                        <img src="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/images/creator-label.svg?v=0.01" alt="" title="">                    </span>
                </span>
        </a></p><div>
            <p><span><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/member/DanielBMarkham"><span><span>Daniel Markham</span><span><span>@DanielBMarkham</span></span></span></a></span></p><p>July 08, 2020</p>
        </div>
    </div>
    
</div>



    <div>
        <div>
                    <p>
                Technical Tuesdays: Markdig and Error-Free Programming in F            </p>
                    <div>
                 <p>Technical Tuesdays: Markdig, error-free programming, and coding for fun.</p>
<p>Code for this can be found here: <a href="https://github.com/DanielBMarkham/LeanPubX" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://github.com/DanielBMarkham/LeanPubX</a></p>
<p>Couple of things to note:</p>
<ul>
<li>There's nothing here to test, ie, if I wanted to add tests they would all be acceptance tests, not system tests. That's good. That's what we want.</li>
<li>The application itself is acting like a function that the OS calls. That's also what we want. It enables supercompilers (see Info-Ops 2)</li>
</ul>            </div>
                    </div>

            </div>


    
    



    <ul>
                    <li>
                <a href="https://github.com/DanielBMarkham/LeanPubX" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">
                    <p><img src="https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/12704908?s=400&amp;v=4" alt="DanielBMarkham/LeanPubX"></p>
                    <div>
                        <p>GITHUB.COM</p>
                        <p>DanielBMarkham/LeanPubX</p>
                        <p>Translator For Authors Using LeanPub/Markura Into Other Formats - DanielBMarkham/LeanPubX...</p>
                    </div>
                </a>
            </li>
            </ul>

                                <div>
                    
                <div data-player="vPlayer-5f0ac7078d015" videojs="true">
                    
                </div>
            </div>
    
    


    <div>
        <div>

            <p><span>    <a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/">
        <span>
            <span>
                <svg width="14" height="13" viewBox="0 0 14 13" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">
                                <path d="M0 13H2.54545V5.2H0V13ZM14 5.85C14 5.135 13.4273 4.55 12.7273 4.55H8.71182L9.31636 1.5795L9.33545 1.3715C9.33545 1.105 9.22727 0.858 9.05545 0.6825L8.38091 0L4.19364 4.2835C3.95818 4.5175 3.81818 4.8425 3.81818 5.2V11.7C3.81818 12.415 4.39091 13 5.09091 13H10.8182C11.3464 13 11.7982 12.675 11.9891 12.207L13.9109 7.6245C13.9682 7.475 14 7.319 14 7.15V5.85Z" fill="currentColor"></path>
                            </svg>
            </span>
            <span>
                0        
            </span>
            <span data-type="qid" data-id="80708"></span></span></a><div><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/"></a></div>
            </span>
        
                
            <a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/">
                <i></i>
                0            </a>
                    </p></div>

        <div>
            
            
                            <p><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/">
                    
                    Reply
                </a>
                    </p></div>
        
    </div>
</div>



                    
                </article>
                <div><p>
                    Connect with DanielBMarkham and other
                    members of DanielBMarkham community.

                    </p><div>
                        <p><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/login">Log in</a> or <a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/">Sign up</a> for FREE to start
                    </p></div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </section>
            <section>
            <h5>
                See what else the community is up to...
            </h5>
            <div>
                

<div>
    

<div>
    <div>
        <p><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/member/DanielBMarkham">
                <span>
                    <span>
                        <img src="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/images/creator-label.svg?v=0.01" alt="" title="">                    </span>
                </span>
        </a></p><div>
            <p><span><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/member/DanielBMarkham"><span><span>Daniel Markham</span><span><span>@DanielBMarkham</span></span></span></a></span></p><p>July 06, 2020</p>
        </div>
    </div>
    
</div>



    <div>
        <div>
                    
                    </div>

            </div>


    
                    <p><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/">
                <img src="https://cdn.rubinreport.com/images/posts/originals/92269/92269_l2ritvbuuuj3l6x.jpeg" alt="post photo preview">
            </a></p>



    <ul>
            </ul>

        
    
    


    <div>
        <div>

            <p><span>    <a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/">
        <span>
            <span>
                <svg width="14" height="13" viewBox="0 0 14 13" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">
                                <path d="M0 13H2.54545V5.2H0V13ZM14 5.85C14 5.135 13.4273 4.55 12.7273 4.55H8.71182L9.31636 1.5795L9.33545 1.3715C9.33545 1.105 9.22727 0.858 9.05545 0.6825L8.38091 0L4.19364 4.2835C3.95818 4.5175 3.81818 4.8425 3.81818 5.2V11.7C3.81818 12.415 4.39091 13 5.09091 13H10.8182C11.3464 13 11.7982 12.675 11.9891 12.207L13.9109 7.6245C13.9682 7.475 14 7.319 14 7.15V5.85Z" fill="currentColor"></path>
                            </svg>
            </span>
            <span>
                0        
            </span>
            <span data-type="qid" data-id="78763"></span></span></a><div><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/"></a></div>
            </span>
        
                
            <a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/">
                <i></i>
                0            </a>
                    </p></div>

        <div>
            
            
                            <p><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/">
                    
                    Reply
                </a>
                    </p></div>
        
    </div>
</div>




<div>
    

<div>
    <div>
        <p><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/member/DanielBMarkham">
                <span>
                    <span>
                        <img src="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/images/creator-label.svg?v=0.01" alt="" title="">                    </span>
                </span>
        </a></p><div>
            <p><span><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/member/DanielBMarkham"><span><span>Daniel Markham</span><span><span>@DanielBMarkham</span></span></span></a></span></p><p>July 05, 2020</p>
        </div>
    </div>
    
</div>



    <div>
        <div>
                    <p>Random: Bertrand Russell's Ten Commandments</p>
                    </div>

            </div>


    
                    <p><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/">
                <img src="https://cdn.rubinreport.com/images/posts/originals/92269/92269_2solxrot7ooevld.jpeg" alt="post photo preview">
            </a></p>



    <ul>
            </ul>

        
    
    


    <div>
        <div>

            <p><span>    <a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/">
        <span>
            <span>
                <svg width="14" height="13" viewBox="0 0 14 13" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">
                                <path d="M0 13H2.54545V5.2H0V13ZM14 5.85C14 5.135 13.4273 4.55 12.7273 4.55H8.71182L9.31636 1.5795L9.33545 1.3715C9.33545 1.105 9.22727 0.858 9.05545 0.6825L8.38091 0L4.19364 4.2835C3.95818 4.5175 3.81818 4.8425 3.81818 5.2V11.7C3.81818 12.415 4.39091 13 5.09091 13H10.8182C11.3464 13 11.7982 12.675 11.9891 12.207L13.9109 7.6245C13.9682 7.475 14 7.319 14 7.15V5.85Z" fill="currentColor"></path>
                            </svg>
            </span>
            <span>
                1        
            </span>
            <span data-type="qid" data-id="79214"></span></span></a><div><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/"></a></div>
            </span>
        
                
            <a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/">
                <i></i>
                0            </a>
                    </p></div>

        <div>
            
            
                            <p><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/">
                    
                    Reply
                </a>
                    </p></div>
        
    </div>
</div>




<div>
    

<div>
    <div>
        <p><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/member/DanielBMarkham">
                <span>
                    <span>
                        <img src="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/images/creator-label.svg?v=0.01" alt="" title="">                    </span>
                </span>
        </a></p><div>
            <p><span><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/member/DanielBMarkham"><span><span>Daniel Markham</span><span><span>@DanielBMarkham</span></span></span></a></span></p><p>July 06, 2020</p>
        </div>
    </div>
    
</div>



    <div>
        <div>
                    <p>
                Technical Tuesdays: Immutable Variables            </p>
                    <p>Why the heck would I want to make an object or variable immutable/constant?</p>
                    </div>

            </div>


    
    



    <ul>
            </ul>

                                <div>
                    
                <div data-player="vPlayer-5f0ac7079a093" videojs="true">
                    
                </div>
            </div>
    
    


    <div>
        <div>

            <p><span>    <a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/">
        <span>
            <span>
                <svg width="14" height="13" viewBox="0 0 14 13" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">
                                <path d="M0 13H2.54545V5.2H0V13ZM14 5.85C14 5.135 13.4273 4.55 12.7273 4.55H8.71182L9.31636 1.5795L9.33545 1.3715C9.33545 1.105 9.22727 0.858 9.05545 0.6825L8.38091 0L4.19364 4.2835C3.95818 4.5175 3.81818 4.8425 3.81818 5.2V11.7C3.81818 12.415 4.39091 13 5.09091 13H10.8182C11.3464 13 11.7982 12.675 11.9891 12.207L13.9109 7.6245C13.9682 7.475 14 7.319 14 7.15V5.85Z" fill="currentColor"></path>
                            </svg>
            </span>
            <span>
                0        
            </span>
            <span data-type="qid" data-id="79531"></span></span></a><div><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/"></a></div>
            </span>
        
                
            <a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/">
                <i></i>
                0            </a>
                    </p></div>

        <div>
            
            
                            <p><a href="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/">
                    
                    Reply
                </a>
                    </p></div>
        
    </div>
</div>


            </div>
            <div>
                <p>
                    View More
                
            </p></div>
            <div>
                <p>
                    View More
                
            </p></div>
        </section>
            <foolter>
            <div>
                <p><a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/locals-com/id1511032007">
                        <img src="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/images/app-store-badge.png" alt="app store">
                    </a>
                                                    <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.locals.localsapp">
                        <img src="https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/images/google-play-badge.png" alt="google store">
                    </a>
                                </p>
            </div>
            <div><p>
                Powered by <a href="https://locals.com/" target="_blank" title="locals.com">Locals</a>
            </p></div>
        </foolter>
    </div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://danielbmarkham.locals.com/post/80708/technical-tuesdays-markdig-and-error-free-programming-in-f</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23778525</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 09:50:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News RSS Feeds]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 205 | Comments 53 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23778510">thread link</a>) | @tejado
<br/>
July 9, 2020 | https://edavis.github.io/hnrss/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://edavis.github.io/hnrss/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
<header>

</header>
<h2 id="overview">Overview</h2>
<p>hnrss.org provides custom, realtime RSS feeds for <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/">Hacker News</a>.</p>
<p>The following feed types are available:</p>
<table>
<colgroup>
<col>
<col>
</colgroup>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><a href="#firehose-feeds"><strong>Firehose</strong></a></td>
<td>New <a href="https://hnrss.org/newest">posts</a> and <a href="https://hnrss.org/newcomments">comments</a> as they arrive.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="#firehose-feeds"><strong>Front Page</strong></a></td>
<td>New <a href="https://hnrss.org/frontpage">posts</a> as they appear on the front page.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="#search-feeds"><strong>Searches</strong></a></td>
<td>New <a href="https://hnrss.org/newest?q=redis">posts</a> and <a href="https://hnrss.org/newcomments?q=linux">comments</a> matching a given search term.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="#reply-feeds"><strong>Replies</strong></a> <sup>new</sup></td>
<td>New comments in reply to a particular <a href="https://hnrss.org/replies?id=jerf">user</a> or <a href="https://hnrss.org/replies?id=17752464">comment</a>.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="#activity-parameters"><strong>Points</strong></a></td>
<td>New <a href="https://hnrss.org/newest?points=300">posts</a> with more than N points.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="#activity-parameters"><strong>Activity</strong></a></td>
<td>New <a href="https://hnrss.org/newest?comments=250">posts</a> with more than N comments.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="#self-post-feeds"><strong>Self-posts</strong></a></td>
<td>New “<a href="https://hnrss.org/ask">Ask HN</a>” and “<a href="https://hnrss.org/show">Show HN</a>” posts, along with <a href="https://hnrss.org/polls">polls</a>.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="#job-feeds"><strong>Jobs</strong></a></td>
<td>New <a href="https://hnrss.org/jobs">hiring posts</a> made by YC startups along with comments from the monthly <a href="https://hnrss.org/whoishiring/jobs">“Who is hiring?”</a> threads.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="#user-feeds"><strong>Users</strong></a></td>
<td>New <a href="https://hnrss.org/submitted?id=jacquesm">posts</a> and <a href="https://hnrss.org/threads?id=tptacek">comments</a> made by a given user.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="#thread-feeds"><strong>Threads</strong></a></td>
<td>New comments made <a href="https://hnrss.org/item?id=17821181">in a given thread</a>.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="#feed-formats"><strong>Formats</strong></a> <sup>new</sup></td>
<td>In addition to RSS, all of the above are also available in <a href="https://hnrss.org/newest.atom">Atom</a> and <a href="https://hnrss.org/newest.jsonfeed">JSON Feed</a> formats.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="details">Details</h2>
<p>Each feed is <a href="https://validator.w3.org/feed/check.cgi?url=https%3A%2F%2Fhnrss.org%2Fnewest">valid RSS</a> served over <a href="https://www.ssllabs.com/ssltest/analyze.html?d=hnrss.org">HTTPS</a>.</p>
<h3 id="firehose-feeds">Firehose Feeds</h3>
<p>The “firehose” feeds contain all new posts and comments as they appear on Hacker News:</p>
<pre>https://hnrss.org/newest
https://hnrss.org/newcomments
</pre>
<p>For just the posts that have appeared on the front page:</p>
<pre>https://hnrss.org/frontpage
</pre>
<p>If the firehose feeds are a bit too noisy for you, <a href="#activity-parameters">read below</a> on filtering them with the <code>points</code> and/or <code>comments</code> parameters.</p>
<h3 id="search-feeds">Search Feeds</h3>
<p>You can get a feed of new posts and/or comments containing keywords by using the <code>q=KEYWORD</code> parameter. For example:</p>
<pre>https://hnrss.org/newest?q=Django
https://hnrss.org/newcomments?q=WordPress
</pre>
<p>If you want a single search feed but multiple keywords, separate the keywords with " OR ":</p>
<pre>https://hnrss.org/newest?q=git+OR+linux
</pre>
<h3 id="reply-feeds">Reply Feeds <sup>new</sup></h3>
<p>Keep an eye on replies to your comments:</p>
<pre>https://hnrss.org/replies?id=jerf
</pre>
<p>Use a comment ID to follow replies to a particular comment:</p>
<pre>https://hnrss.org/replies?id=17752464
</pre>
<h3 id="self-post-feeds">Self Post Feeds</h3>
<p>Ask HN, Show HN, and polls are available:</p>
<pre>https://hnrss.org/ask
https://hnrss.org/show
https://hnrss.org/polls
</pre>
<h3 id="job-feeds">Job Feeds</h3>
<p>Job opportunities from YC funded startups:</p>
<pre>https://hnrss.org/jobs
</pre>
<p>Top level comments in threads created by the whoishiring bot:</p>
<pre># Comments from "Who is hiring?" threads
https://hnrss.org/whoishiring/jobs

# Comments from "Who wants to be hired?" threads
https://hnrss.org/whoishiring/hired

# Comments from "Freelancer? Seeking freelancer?" threads
https://hnrss.org/whoishiring/freelance

# All of the above
https://hnrss.org/whoishiring
</pre>
<p><span>new</span> If you’re interested in something in particular, you can apply a <code>q=KEYWORD</code> parameter to only return relevant comments. For example, filter the top-level “Who is hiring?” comments to only those containing “React Native”:</p>
<pre>https://hnrss.org/whoishiring/jobs?q=React+Native
</pre>
<h3 id="user-feeds">User Feeds</h3>
<p>If you don’t want to miss a post or comment by a given user, you can subscribe to that user’s feed:</p>
<pre>https://hnrss.org/submitted?id=USERNAME # posts
https://hnrss.org/threads?id=USERNAME   # comments
https://hnrss.org/user?id=USERNAME      # everything
</pre>
<h3 id="thread-feeds">Thread Feeds</h3>
<p>A feed of new comments on a particular post can be found at:</p>
<pre>https://hnrss.org/item?id=THREAD_ID
</pre>
<p>With <code>THREAD_ID</code> the numerical ID found in the URL when viewing the comments page.</p>
<h3 id="feed-options">Feed Options</h3>
<p>You can modify any feed’s output using URL parameters. Multiple parameters can be applied at the same time by joining them with an ampersand.</p>
<h4 id="activity-parameters">Activity Parameters</h4>
<p>You can apply a <code>points=N</code> or <code>comments=N</code> parameter to any feed to filter the results so only entries with more than N points or comments are shown:</p>
<pre>https://hnrss.org/newest?points=100
https://hnrss.org/ask?comments=25
</pre>
<p>You can also combine both parameters:</p>
<pre>https://hnrss.org/show?points=100&amp;comments=25
</pre>
<p>Unfortunately, <code>/newcomments</code> <a href="https://github.com/algolia/hn-search/issues/55#issuecomment-73599729">does not work</a> with a <code>points=N</code> parameter.</p>
<h4 id="search-parameter">Search Parameter</h4>
<p>By default, searches on posts only look at titles. If you want to search against the submitted URLs themselves, use the <code>search_attrs</code> parameter.</p>
<p>Here are some examples:</p>
<pre># Search for posts with "WordPress" in the title only
https://hnrss.org/newest?q=WordPress

# Search for posts with 'WordPress' in the URL only
https://hnrss.org/newest?q=WordPress&amp;search_attrs=url

# Search for posts with 'WordPress' in the title or URL
https://hnrss.org/newest?q=WordPress&amp;search_attrs=title,url

# Don't restrict search attributes at all. This searches for posts
# containing 'WordPress' in all attributes indexed by Algolia. This was
# the behavior of searches prior to June 3, 2015
https://hnrss.org/newest?q=WordPress&amp;search_attrs=default
</pre>
<h4 id="link-parameter">Link Parameter</h4>
<p>By default, the RSS <code>&lt;link&gt;</code> element points to the submitted article’s URL. The <code>&lt;link&gt;</code> element can be changed to point to the Hacker News comment page by appending <code>link=comments</code> to the end of the URL. For example:</p>
<pre>https://hnrss.org/newest?link=comments</pre>
<h4 id="description-parameter">Description Parameter</h4>
<p>You can disable the <code>&lt;description&gt;</code> element entirely by passing the <code>description=0</code> parameter:</p>
<pre>https://hnrss.org/newest?description=0</pre>
<h4 id="count-parameter">Count Parameter</h4>
<p>By default, feeds return 20 RSS items. This can be increased via the <code>count=N</code> parameter:</p>
<pre>https://hnrss.org/newest?count=50</pre>
<p>There is a hardcoded limit of 100 entries, so keep that in mind.</p>
<h4 id="feed-formats">Feed Formats <sup>new</sup></h4>
<p>By default, feeds come back as RSS. But if you add “.atom” or “.jsonfeed” to any endpoint you’ll receive the contents in <a href="https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/atom.html">Atom</a> or <a href="https://jsonfeed.org/">JSON Feed</a>, respectively.</p>
<pre># The front page as Atom
https://hnrss.org/frontpage.atom

# "Ask HN" with 10 or more comments as JSON Feed
https://hnrss.org/ask.jsonfeed?comments=10
</pre>
<p>Note: These formats are a lot less battle-tested than the RSS format. If you see any wonkiness or they don’t play nicely with your feed reader, please <a href="https://github.com/edavis/hnrss/issues/new">open an issue</a> with as much information as possible. Thanks!</p>
<h2 id="changelog">Changelog</h2>
<h3 id="section">2018</h3>
<ul>
<li>August/September 2018
<ul>
<li>Full changelog entry coming soon</li>
</ul></li>
<li>January 2018
<ul>
<li>Add /whoishiring endpoint (h/t <a href="https://github.com/edavis/hnrss/pull/23">@jaredandrews</a>)</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="section-1">2017</h3>
<ul>
<li>October 2017
<ul>
<li>Add /jobs endpoint.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>April 2017
<ul>
<li>Add python3 support.</li>
<li>Improve handling of search feeds with multiple queries.</li>
<li>Cleanup docs and move them to Hugo.</li>
<li>Fix warnings from the w3.org feed validator.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>March 2017
<ul>
<li>Add support for multiple keywords when searching.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>February 2017
<ul>
<li>Add gzip support.</li>
<li>Leave Rackspace, deploy on DigitalOcean.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="section-2">2016</h3>
<ul>
<li>September 2016
<ul>
<li>Add support for HTTP caching headers.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>July 2016
<ul>
<li>Leave Heroku, deploy on Rackspace.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>April 2016
<ul>
<li>Add /frontpage.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="section-3">2015</h3>
<ul>
<li>June 2015
<ul>
<li>Set <code>isPermaLink=false</code> on <code>&lt;guid&gt;</code>.</li>
<li>By default, searches now look at post titles.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="section-4">2014</h3>
<ul>
<li>June 2014
<ul>
<li>Major rewrite, use different URL structure.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>May 2014
<ul>
<li>Launched hnrss.org on Heroku.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="support">Support</h2>
<p>If hnrss.org has made your job or hobby project easier, and you want to show some gratitude, <a href="https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;hosted_button_id=ZP9Q7QUNS3QYY">donations are very much appreciated</a>.</p>
<p><span>new</span> Another way to support hnrss.org is to use this <a href="https://m.do.co/c/1c19f7d73361">DigitalOcean referral link</a> and receive $10 in credit. Once you’ve spent $25 with DigitalOcean, hnrss.org will receive $25 in credit.</p>
<p>Thanks!</p>
<h2 id="credits">Credits</h2>
<p>Thanks to <a href="https://www.algolia.com/">Algolia</a> for providing their <a href="https://hn.algolia.com/api">REST API</a>. Without it, hnrss.org simply would not exist.</p>
<p>Thanks to <a href="https://github.com/jaredandrews">Jared Andrews</a> for the <a href="https://github.com/edavis/hnrss/pull/23">PR</a> that created the /whoishiring/ endpoints.</p>
<p>Thanks to <a href="https://github.com/zmwangx">Zhiming Wang</a> for adding Python 3 support.</p>
<p>Thanks to <a href="https://github.com/grantjenks">Grant Jenks</a> for the idea of adding the Article URL and Points to the description.</p>
<p>Thanks to <a href="https://github.com/cagrimmett">Chuck Grimmett</a> for being a sounding board when it comes to adding new features to hnrss.org as well as suggesting the /jobs endpoint.</p>
<p>And many, many thanks to all those who have donated in support of the project over the years. You all mean the world to me.</p>
<h2 id="colophon">Colophon</h2>
<p>hnrss.org is served by nginx on DigitalOcean. HTTPS is provided by Let’s Encrypt. DNS is provided by Namecheap.</p>
<p>As of September 2018, the feeds are generated using the <a href="https://gin-gonic.github.io/gin/">Gin</a> web framework. From May 2014 to August 2018, the feeds were generated using the <a href="http://flask.pocoo.org/">Flask</a> web framework.</p>
<h2 id="repositories">Repositories</h2>
<p>A brief primer on the various repositories that make up hnrss.org:</p>
<p>When hnrss.org was created in May 2014, code and documentation lived inside the <a href="https://github.com/edavis/hnrss">edavis/hnrss</a> repository.</p>
<p>In April 2017, the documentation was revamped, migrated into Hugo, and was given its own repository at <a href="https://github.com/edavis/hnrss-docs">edavis/hnrss-docs</a>. The built assets were copied into the <code>docs/</code> folder on <a href="https://github.com/edavis/hnrss">edavis/hnrss</a> and published at <a href="https://edavis.github.io/hnrss/">https://edavis.github.io/hnrss/</a>.</p>
<p>In August/September 2018, hnrss.org underwent a rewrite from Flask to Gin. This new code lives at <a href="https://github.com/edavis/go-hnrss">edavis/go-hnrss</a>.</p>
<p>So, as of September 2018, that’s the state of play. The documentation source lives at <a href="https://github.com/edavis/hnrss-docs">edavis/hnrss-docs</a>. The Gin source that powers hnrss.org lives at <a href="https://github.com/edavis/go-hnrss">edavis/go-hnrss</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/edavis/hnrss">edavis/hnrss</a> contains the Flask code that powered the site from May 2014 to August 2018 as well as the <code>docs/</code> folder that contains the built HTML copied from <a href="https://github.com/edavis/hnrss-docs">edavis/hnrss-docs</a>.</p>
<p>At some point I’d like to simplify all of this and run everything out of one repository, but it’ll do for now.</p>


</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://edavis.github.io/hnrss/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23778510</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 09:48:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Build a Scalable SDK the Right Way (Learnings from AWS SDKs)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 11 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23778420">thread link</a>) | @imshashank
<br/>
July 9, 2020 | https://dailyjag.com/technology/how-to-build-a-scalable-sdk-the-right-way-learnings-from-aws-sdks/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dailyjag.com/technology/how-to-build-a-scalable-sdk-the-right-way-learnings-from-aws-sdks/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>AWS SDK maintains and publishes SDK for over 110+ services with simultaneous and multiple updates on all SDKs each day. They have achieved what interestingly all big companies strive for, launching new APIs seamlessly and effortlessly. During AWS’s flagship entertainment packed conference <strong>“Re</strong><strong>:Invent</strong><strong>,</strong> the SDKs are updated with new APIs that were just announced in less than 2 hours for the world to use.</p><p>To interact with any of AWS services you need to use a AWS SDK in either python, JAVA or any other language your software is in.</p><p>I have been an engineer in the PHP SDK for AWS which is open-sourced on Github and anyone can look at the code published by the AWS teams. AWS manages over 8 SDKs including SDK for <a href="https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-java">JAVA</a>, <a href="https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-ruby">ruby</a>, <a href="https://github.com/boto/boto3">python</a>, <a href="https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-js">javascript</a>, <a href="https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-php">PHP</a>, <a href="https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go">go</a>, <a href="https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-cpp">C++</a> and few other languages.</p><p>Generally, it requires a significant number of engineers to manage just one SDK. To make sure all APIs and features are available across all SDKs is a big feat. In this post, we are going to talk about how to scale the SDK and how AWS is able to achieve perfect synchronicity across all SDKs without sloshing the SDKs team with manually updating each SDK.</p><h2>How does the AWS SDK works?</h2><p>All of the SDKs have two parts one is the core and another one has all the service-specific code. The core of the SDK handles various features such as “Signing each request using AWS’s Sigv4 protocol”, security features, SSL handling, multi-threading, asynchronous requests, waiters, paginators, and a ton more features.</p><p>The other part of each SDK is based on “model” files specific to each service. All model files are exactly similar across each SDK.</p><p>The difference is very evident in AWS’s python SDK which is divided into two different repositories “boto” and “botocore”.</p><p>All the model files are built on <a href="https://www.openapis.org/">OpenApi</a> protocol to some extent and are compatible with <a href="https://swagger.io/">Swagger</a> API Protocols.</p><p>Here is a JSON definition for DynamoDB in AWS PHP SDK with name “<a href="https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-php/blob/master/src/data/dynamodb/2012-08-10/api-2.json">api-2.json</a>” and &nbsp;the exact same file also exists in Boto SDK as well with name “<a href="https://github.com/boto/botocore/blob/develop/botocore/data/dynamodb/2012-08-10/service-2.json">service-2.json</a>“</p><p>At AWS each service will release these JSON model files which specify all information related to each API &amp; service. Each SDK handles these files a bit differently as compared to other SDKs. PHP SDK loads these JSON files dynamically in each client to allow various APIs while JAVA SDK will pre-build each of these methods into concrete classes.</p><p>Each AWS team maintains and releases these service-specific model file, which are then consumed by each SDK team in the way they would like.</p><h2>Show Me The Code!</h2><p>I am sure these look like magic to you like it looked to me when I first saw it. So let’s dig into the code. We will look at PHP SDK example as that is team I was part of for over a year and know in and out of the SDK.</p><p>We will look at the AWS Lambda’s invoke method.</p><pre><code>"Invoke":{
      "name":"Invoke",
      "http":{
        "method":"POST",
        "requestUri":"/2015-03-31/functions/{FunctionName}/invocations"
      },
      "input":{"shape":"InvocationRequest"},
      "output":{"shape":"InvocationResponse"},
      "errors":[
        {"shape":"ServiceException"},
        {"shape":"ResourceNotFoundException"},
        {"shape":"InvalidRequestContentException"},
        {"shape":"RequestTooLargeException"},
        {"shape":"UnsupportedMediaTypeException"},
        {"shape":"TooManyRequestsException"},
        {"shape":"InvalidParameterValueException"},
        {"shape":"EC2UnexpectedException"},
        {"shape":"SubnetIPAddressLimitReachedException"},
        {"shape":"ENILimitReachedException"},
        {"shape":"EC2ThrottledException"},
        {"shape":"EC2AccessDeniedException"},
        {"shape":"InvalidSubnetIDException"},
        {"shape":"InvalidSecurityGroupIDException"},
        {"shape":"InvalidZipFileException"},
        {"shape":"KMSDisabledException"},
        {"shape":"KMSInvalidStateException"},
        {"shape":"KMSAccessDeniedException"},
        {"shape":"KMSNotFoundException"},
        {"shape":"InvalidRuntimeException"}
      ]
    }</code></pre><p>The above API is expecting an “InvocationRequest” object and returns a “InvocationResponse” object.</p><p>This is how the “InvocationRequest” is defined.</p><pre><code>"InvocationRequest":{
      "type":"structure",
      "required":["FunctionName"],
      "members":{
        "FunctionName":{
          "shape":"NamespacedFunctionName",
          "location":"uri",
          "locationName":"FunctionName"
        },
        "InvocationType":{
          "shape":"InvocationType",
          "location":"header",
          "locationName":"X-Amz-Invocation-Type"
        },
        "LogType":{
          "shape":"LogType",
          "location":"header",
          "locationName":"X-Amz-Log-Type"
        },
        "ClientContext":{
          "shape":"String",
          "location":"header",
          "locationName":"X-Amz-Client-Context"
        },
        "Payload":{"shape":"Blob"},
        "Qualifier":{
          "shape":"Qualifier",
          "location":"querystring",
          "locationName":"Qualifier"
        }
      },
      "payload":"Payload"
    }</code></pre><p>This is the response object.</p><pre><code> "InvocationResponse":{
      "type":"structure",
      "members":{
        "StatusCode":{
          "shape":"Integer",
          "location":"statusCode"
        },
        "FunctionError":{
          "shape":"String",
          "location":"header",
          "locationName":"X-Amz-Function-Error"
        },
        "LogResult":{
          "shape":"String",
          "location":"header",
          "locationName":"X-Amz-Log-Result"
        },
        "Payload":{"shape":"Blob"},
        "ExecutedVersion":{
          "shape":"Version",
          "location":"header",
          "locationName":"X-Amz-Executed-Version"
        }
      },
      "payload":"Payload"
    },</code></pre><p>The PHP SDK auto-generates code for each of these request and response object and here how the code would look:</p><pre><code>$result = $client-&gt;invoke(array(
    // FunctionName is required
    'FunctionName' =&gt; 'string',
    'InvocationType' =&gt; 'string',
    'LogType' =&gt; 'string',
    'ClientContext' =&gt; 'string',
    'Payload' =&gt; 'mixed type: string|resource|\Guzzle\Http\EntityBodyInterface',
    'Qualifier' =&gt; 'string',
));</code></pre><p>Even the docs are automatically generated from the model files.</p><p>So the various SDK team will not need to write any code “manually” at all for any of these service updates. The service teams,( in this case, AWS Lambda) just needs to make sure that the model file they are creating is error free. The SDK will be able to auto-generate any updates to existing clients as well as auto-generating code for new APIs and services.</p><p>The best part of the SDK team is that is is completely open-sources and is directly integrated into various AWS services.</p><p>API Gateway allows you to deploy Swagger (also knows as OpenAPI Standards) models and then use the APIs to directly generate SDKs with all the features that are already inbuilt into the AWS SDKs.</p><p>I hope this will prove helpful in designing your SDKs for your services. In any SDK the focus should be on creating a model file that is compliant with “OpenApi” standards. By having a standard model for APIs, it will get super easy and fast to launch various SDKs in various languages with very little development time.</p><div><div><div><p><a href="https://dailyjag.com/profile/admin/" rel="author"> <img alt="" src="https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/33563973b6f338002e574f30a3f94788?s=80&amp;d=mm&amp;r=g" srcset="https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/33563973b6f338002e574f30a3f94788?s=160&amp;d=mm&amp;r=g 2x" height="80" width="80"> </a></p><div> <p><span>  </span> <span> <span>Member since</span> <time datetime="2019-02-25 10:02"> August 16, 2011 </time> </span></p></div></div><p><span>I am an android developer, hacker, web developer, professional blogger and a complete tech freak. I love computers and everything related to computers. I love learning new things and sharing the knowledge with the world.</span> <a href="https://www.facebook.com/agarwal.shashank">https://www.facebook.com/agarwal.shashank</a></p></div></div><p><a href="https://pipfeed.com/" target="_blank"> <img src="https://256057-797351-2-raikfcquaxqncofqfm.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/White_Feature_image_2.jpg"> </a></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dailyjag.com/technology/how-to-build-a-scalable-sdk-the-right-way-learnings-from-aws-sdks/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23778420</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 09:28:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Between Workaholism and Procrastination (2015)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 54 | Comments 42 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23778307">thread link</a>) | @jamalx31
<br/>
July 9, 2020 | https://www.jamalx31.com/post/between-workaholism-procrastination | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.jamalx31.com/post/between-workaholism-procrastination">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h3>February 2015</h3><p>I was working for a startup based in Jerusalem called Curiyo. Back then I had a nice routine: I wake up around 6 am, go to the gym with my buddy, come back to my room to take a shower, eat a bowl of salad and then leave for work. I get to work around 9 am, leave around 5 to meet friends, hang out, or do whatever activity I was planning for that evening.</p><p>In September of the same year, I went on my first trip abroad. I went with my best friend from high school on a 2-week trip to Italy. And as they say, I caught the travel bug. After that trip, all I could think about was planning the next ones and when I could fly again. And since then, I started traveling literally every month.</p><p>One day, I found a blog post about digital nomads and remote work. "This is it, this is what I want!", I said to myself, and the race began to figure out how I could make that happen. A couple of months later, I landed my first remote job with Toptal and signed up for a 3-month trip around southeast Asia (SEA). And in September 2016 -a year after my first trip- I was in Thailand working remotely, enjoying the beach, drinking fresh coconut water, and calling myself a digital nomad.</p><p>"Work hard, play harder": that is the digital nomad slogan. Each day’s schedule looked different from the day before, depending on what I felt like doing or what the group I’m with is planning. In other words, it’s impossible to have a fixed routine, you have to be flexible and dynamic. Otherwise, you will either have to choose between FOMO or doing a shitty job at your work so you don’t miss whatever fun others are having.</p><h3>February 2017</h3><p>After my 3-month trip to SEA, it was time to go back to Jerusalem to see my family and plan the next move. I wasn’t excited to go back, I grew up in Jerusalem and till that point, it’s where I spent all my life. It was so hard and boring after what I’ve experienced, I just came back after spending 3 months in heaven.</p><p>Suddenly there were no more beaches, no more parties, or random strangers to hang out with. There was a lot of free time thatI had no idea what to do with. All I was doing every day was leaving my parents’ house, go to the university campus where I spent five years getting my computer engineering degree, and work till it’s so hard to keep my eyes open.</p><p>I filled all the free time I had with work. I created an outsource web development company with a friend and worked 14h a day 7 days a week, I became a workaholic. I was hoping that by creating a successful business I will have the means to escape my city and move elsewhere to go back to the heavenly life I had for a short period.</p><p>After 3 months of long days and restless nights mishmash, I realized that wasn’t what I wanted. Of course, I still wanted to build my own business, but I didn’t like the path I was taking. And one day I found myself writing this:</p><p>I woke up late, as usual, tried to open my exhausted eyelids. I had skipped the usual question “What’s the plan for today?” and left my bed. It has been almost 3 months since the last time I answered that question, after the first week of going back to Jerusalem it was the same day repeating itself over and over again. Wake up, go to the university campus, meet the same people, and work for 12-14 hours.</p><p>Everything was the same that day except one thing, one thought. When suddenly I found myself shouting out loud to myself “Oh shit, I’m not happy, FUCK!” after a voice inside my head asked: “Are you happy?”. The answer was obviously no. I just realized I was on auto-pilot and forgot to ask myself such a trivial question. “If you are not happy, what is the point?” I kept asking myself for the rest of the day.</p><p>Work was just my way to escape reality and fill my free time. All that made me wonder: do I have to bury myself in work and live miserably now so that my future self can be happy?&nbsp;</p><p>Probably many of you will say “yes”, or maybe you will hesitate a bit before saying “no”. But that doesn’t change the fact that it is actually what we all do somehow. All of us work hard today hoping that tomorrow, next week, next month, or a year from now we will be happy, satisfied, and fulfilled.</p><p>This led me to another question that has changed everything: <strong>what is the point of chasing big dreams and goals if I'm not enjoying the way to get there?&nbsp;</strong></p><p>I didn’t have a clear answer to this question so, in a way or another, my answer was <strong>procrastination</strong>. On one side, I wanted to build a business and create great things. On the other side, I didn’t want to work (hard) on anything as long as I don’t know how to be happy while doing it!</p><h3>June 2017</h3><p>After several months and hustling paperwork, I moved to Germany, and my digital nomad life was on again. Since then, I’ve spent the last 3+ years, traveling around the world, exploring, having fun, and creating memories. I was living the dream that many people dream of. A was living a life with no routine whatsoever, wake up whenever I want, work whenever I want, and tomorrow is always an unplanned adventure.</p><p>You can say everything was perfect, but still, the old dream was bugging me, I want to build and create a successful business, my own business. I never liked the idea of working for someone and trading my time for money. And between fun and procrastination, I was trying to build stuff and bootstrap ideas, but things were always falling between the cracks. With a lifestyle like that, it’s really hard to say no to the sunny beach outside and go work 10 hours on a side project. So as a result, procrastination became my new lifestyle.</p><h3>March 2020</h3><p>I left Mexico for a 2-week trip to San Francisco, I had a lot of traveling planned for this year. Things would have stayed on the same path as before for at least another couple of years if it wasn’t for COVID-19.<br></p><p>Two weeks into the pandemic, I found myself without work and without anything else to do. No travel, no friends around, nothing. This time, I didn’t only have a lot of free time, but all my time became free time. History got a chance to repeat itself, and I had a decision to make. Do I want to re-live 2017 all over again? Do I want to keep myself busy with side projects and endless work?&nbsp;<br></p><p>The feeling from 3 years ago was still fresh in my memory that I didn’t want to fall into that trap again. That was an opportunity I had to take advantage of. I was living alone with no distraction of any kind, It was a chance to rediscover myself and what I really want.</p><p>My goal was to bootstrap a business while having a work life balance. I didn’t want to spend 14 hours on my laptop and feel like it was sucking the life out of me. I believed it was possible to bootstrap without falling into the workaholism swamp.</p><figure><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5eed2ff36d85f3277043492b/5f06d0eb03257a01af20a5e4_iZLNJNTTrlnhbqu6GYvnavIObyReSuyqU1-_DJxGfOeSpFmF8hzwy3AryXXXt0pxgt7dn0EkcqU2AAEDMG8i5AS7HAfEUP0GlsyIOdpqtN07TOSJopLFwNzxQ3HwUjMJw5YSN36s.png" alt=""></p></figure><p>Earlier this year I was somewhere on the bottom left side. To shift toward the right I had to deal with my procrastination problem. Since nothing I’ve tried before worked for me, I decided to learn everything I can about the subject and challenge myself to write a book about it, this book! I’m trying to prove to myself (and others) that it’s possible to live in the middle, a place where you can be productive and happy.</p><p><strong>“A bird in the hand is worth t̶w̶o̶ ten in the bush”</strong></p><p>My best friend, who is running an online business with ~$300k ARR, is on the opposite side of the curve. He is the most dedicated hard working person I know, but he’s not happy. When I asked him about it, he said he doesn’t believe it’s possible to have that balance. For him, you can’t be productive (grow fast enough) and happy at the same time. His goal is to have a big stable business by age 40 so he can relax and enjoy life then.</p><p>I don’t want that, I don't want to build a business if my happiness is the price. I don't want to live on 30% happiness for the promise that my future self will be 100% in five or ten years. It's not only that 100% happiness is not realistic, but I also believe my future self will still be stuck on the same hamster wheel convincing himself that he needs another 5 years to get to the imaginary perfect happiness.</p><figure><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5eed2ff36d85f3277043492b/5f06d0edf9a94c0bc0e6cd9f_Ngrb7PW6OqzpCoN3VZ8zAT8vHN_BKz_ZRkF_1Ze-89S6gTlwS6qyz89AWZIy-r5M6aleCzSf5xq-qp0OG1qkgdq14HcQdSlY1F6TkBny8CtjNETh2sdP4f0dgcuKCAnqFIVf3wiu.gif" alt=""></p></figure><p>Workaholism will blind you, you no longer see the big picture, you have no time to think and re-think, and you work for the sake of the work itself. And without a proper system and regular stops where you pause to double-check where you are heading, the wheel will just spin faster and faster until it eventually spits you out and throws you against the wall.</p><p>I know, sometimes you have something you are so excited about and it doesn’t feel like work. But pure excitement doesn’t last forever. Eventually, you will have to work on other boring and less exciting parts of your project. And once that initial excitement fades away, you either quit or close your eyes and hit the gas pedal to become a workaholic zombie.</p><p>However, life is not easy and you can’t always accomplish things while relaxing and taking it easy. Sometimes you have no other option but to push so hard, for days, weeks, or even months. The problem starts when you have no idea when you are going to lift your foot off the gas pedal to look around and see where you are going and check if you should make a turn and change directions.</p><p>So let’s glue all pieces together. A Procrastinator has this <strong>Instant Gratification Monkey (1)</strong> who wants immediate rewards, to have fun, and enjoy the moment without giving a shit about the future. A workaholic has a <strong>Panic Monster (2)</strong> who wants to work so hard and sacrifice everything today so you can be happy tomorrow.</p><p>The answer to the question: “How do you chase big dreams and without depriving yourself happiness?” is the same answer to the question: “Where could your instant gratification monkey meet your panic monster?” You need both.The monkey is as important as the monster, we’ll see that in the chapter “The Productive Procrastinator”. While in other chapters, we try to find that meeting point, as the sole purpose of this book is not to help you just be a productive person but a <strong>happy</strong> productive person.</p><p>1,2:&nbsp;originally presented in Tim Urban's <a href="https://waitbutwhy.com/2013/10/why-procrastinators-procrastinate.html">blog post</a></p><p>‍<br></p><figure><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5eed2ff36d85f3277043492b/5ef900053c15adf3558a9fb8_1*Bx1xIfh3q-_hY0LzmbLePg.png" alt=""></p></figure><p>📕 This chapter is …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.jamalx31.com/post/between-workaholism-procrastination">https://www.jamalx31.com/post/between-workaholism-procrastination</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.jamalx31.com/post/between-workaholism-procrastination</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23778307</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 09:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Data WhiteOps collects]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 34 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23777537">thread link</a>) | @yuchi
<br/>
July 8, 2020 | https://smitop.com/post/whiteops-data/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://smitop.com/post/whiteops-data/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article" id="content">By  · <span itemprop="datePublished" content="2020-07-08">Jul 8, 2020</span> · 8 minute read<div><article itemprop="articleBody" id="content"><p>Today I noticed <a href="https://reddit.com/">New Reddit</a> was asking to use DRM. So I went on a source code analysis journey! See the <a href="https://smitop.com/post/reddit-whiteops.md">main post</a> for more details.</p><p>It appears Reddit uses <a href="https://whiteops.com/">White Ops</a> for fingerprinting and ad fraud prevention (but only sometimes, I think it’s an A/B test). See this beautified code:</p><div><pre><code data-lang="js"><span>const</span> <span>t</span> <span>=</span> <span>e</span>.<span>user</span>.<span>account</span> <span>?</span> <span>Jt</span>()(<span>e</span>.<span>user</span>.<span>account</span>.<span>id</span>).<span>toString</span>() <span>:</span> <span>void</span> <span>0</span>,
    <span>s</span> <span>=</span> document.<span>createElement</span>(<span>"script"</span>);
<span>s</span>.<span>src</span> <span>=</span> Object(<span>es</span>.<span>a</span>)(<span>"https://s.udkcrj.com/ag/386183/clear.js"</span>, {
    <span>dt</span><span>:</span> <span>"3861831591810830724000"</span>,
    <span>pd</span><span>:</span> <span>"acc"</span>,
    <span>mo</span><span>:</span> <span>0</span>,
    <span>et</span><span>:</span> <span>0</span>,
    <span>ti</span><span>:</span> <span>$t</span>()(),
    <span>ui</span><span>:</span> <span>t</span>,
    <span>si</span><span>:</span> <span>"d2x"</span>
}), document.<span>head</span>.<span>appendChild</span>(<span>s</span>)
</code></pre></div><p>This code is only run if the <code>show_white_ops</code> feature flag is enabled (don’t know how to force this to be true), which is why I assume the tracking is done by <a href="https://www.whiteops.com/">WhiteOps</a>.
Further research into the <code>https://s.udkcrj.com/ag/386183/clear.js</code> file reveals that it ends up loading another script, <code>https://s.udkcrj.com/2/4.71.0/main.js</code>. For reference, here is <a href="https://smitop.com/whiteops-main.js">the beautified source code I saw and analyzed</a>.</p><p>Note: here is a function I used to deobfuscate many strings in the code:</p><div><pre><code data-lang="js"><span>const</span> <span>deob</span> <span>=</span> <span>x</span> =&gt; <span>x</span>.<span>replace</span>(<span>/[A-Za-z]/g</span>, <span>function</span>(<span>e</span>) {
    <span>return</span> String.<span>fromCharCode</span>(<span>e</span>.<span>charCodeAt</span>(<span>0</span>) <span>+</span> (<span>e</span>.<span>toUpperCase</span>() <span>&lt;=</span> <span>"M"</span> <span>?</span> <span>13</span> <span>:</span> <span>-</span><span>13</span>))
})
</code></pre></div><p>Note 2: Ozoki appears to be some sort of internal codename used by WhiteOps.</p><p>This very obfuscated script does many things, including (this is an incomplete list, I have missed many things):</p><ul><li>Communicates with <code>vprza.com</code> and <code>minkatu.com</code></li><li>Does device/OS detection</li><li>Attempts to detect if DevTools is open (looks at <code>__IE_DEVTOOLBAR_CONSOLE_COMMAND_LINE</code>)</li><li>Something weird with the <code>text-underline-offset</code> CSS property</li><li>Has the names of a bunch of ad servers, presumably as to not serve ads to bots</li><li>Attempts to create an <code>ActiveXObject</code> (only exists in old IE versions), and checks if the created ActiveX object <code>isSandboxed</code></li><li>Checks for <code>maxConnectionsPerServer</code> and <code>onhelp</code> properties on <code>window</code> (for browser engine detection I think)</li><li>Attempts to exploit an IE11 vuln!<ul><li>it checks the value of <code>document.documentMode</code>, which in IE11 is <code>11</code>. If it is, then it runs the obfuscated code:</li></ul></li></ul><div><pre><code data-lang="js"><span>// o == document.documentMode == 11
</span><span></span><span>"}o|B65niitbmd,ahg)Z[i$_g"</span>.<span>replace</span>(<span>/./g</span>, <span>function</span>(<span>e</span>) {
    <span>return</span> String.<span>fromCharCode</span>(<span>e</span>.<span>charCodeAt</span>(<span>0</span>) <span>-</span> <span>o</span><span>--</span>)
})
</code></pre></div><ul><li>this evaluates to <code>res://ieframe.dll/acr.js</code>, but only on IE. This string has only one purpose, exploiting the fact that you can put arbitrary HTML in the hash part of the URL and have it get evaluated, I beleive in a privledged context of some sort. This file actually resolves in IE to a internal Windows system file, which is only accessible in JS due to a bug.</li><li>tries to run VBScript:</li></ul><div><pre><code data-lang="js"><span>execScript</span>(<span>"e71012934811a=false::On Error Resume Next::"</span> <span>+</span> <span>e</span> <span>+</span> <span>"::if Err.Number=-2147024891 or Err.Number=5002 then e71012934811a=true::Err.Clear"</span>, <span>"VBScript"</span>), <span>t</span> <span>=</span> <span>"e71012934811a"</span> <span>in</span> window <span>?</span> window.<span>e71012934811a</span> <span>?</span> <span>o</span>.<span>EXISTS</span> <span>:</span> <span>o</span>.<span>MISSING</span> <span>:</span> <span>o</span>.<span>UNKNOWN</span>
</code></pre></div><ul><li>checks for these strings on window (de-obfuscated, I also have the original obfuscated ones in case you are also looking through the source):<ul><li><code>boltsWebViewAppLinkResolverResult</code>, <code>GoogleJsInterface</code>, <code>googleAdsJsInterface</code>, <code>accessibilityTraversal</code>, <code>accessibility</code>, <code>FbPlayableAd</code>, <code>__REACT_WEB_VIEW_BRIDGE</code></li><li>obfuscated in code as <code>obygfJroIvrjNccYvaxErfbyireErfhyg</code>, <code>TbbtyrWfVagresnpr</code>, <code>tbbtyrNqfWfVagresnpr</code>, <code>npprffvovyvglGenirefny</code>, <code>npprffvovyvgl</code>, <code>SoCynlnoyrNq</code>, <code>__ERNPG_JRO_IVRJ_OEVQTR</code></li></ul></li><li>checks the screen’s <code>availHeight</code>, <code>availWidth</code>, <code>width</code>, and `height</li><li>checks the screen’s <code>colorDepth</code>, <code>pixelDepth</code>, and <code>devicePixelRatio</code></li><li>checks for these automation-related properties on <code>window</code>: <code>domAutomation</code>, <code>domAutomationController</code>, <code>_WEBDRIVER_ELEM_CACHE</code>, <code>_phantom</code>, <code>callPhantom</code>, <code>window.chrome._commandLineAPI</code>, <code>window.Debug.debuggerEnabled</code>, <code>__BROWSERTOOLS_CONSOLE</code>, <code>window._FirebugCommandLine</code>, and also if <code>document.documentElement.hasAttribute("webdriver")</code> is true</li><li>checks if <code>"function () { return Function.apply.call(x.log, x, arguments); }" == window.console.log.toString()</code> (also to check for browser automation I guess</li><li>tries to check if the browser is headless with <code>isExternalUrlSafeForNavigation</code>, <code>window.opera._browserjsran</code>, <code>window.opera.browserjsran</code></li><li>checks if <code>navigator.onLine</code> is true</li><li>check the <code>window.chrome</code> object if in Chrome</li><li>extracts data from <code>window.FirefoxInterfaces("wdICoordinate", "wdIMouse", "wdIStatus")</code></li><li>checks if <code>window.XPCOMUtils</code> exists</li><li>checks if <code>window.netscape.security.privilegemanager</code> exists</li><li>appears to check browser console timing</li><li>checks referer against <code>"https://www.google.com", "https://apps.skype.com", "http://apps.skype.com", "https://www.youtube.com", "http://en.wikipedia.org/", "https://en.wikipedia.org/", "https://www.netflix.com", "http://www.netflix.com", "http://www3.oovoo.com"</code></li><li>checks for these properties in <code>window.external</code>: <code>["AddChannel", "AddDesktopComponent", "AddFavorite", "AddSearchProvider", "AddService", "AddToFavoritesBar", "AutoCompleteSaveForm", "AutoScan", "bubbleEvent", "ContentDiscoveryReset", "ImportExportFavorites", "InPrivateFilteringEnabled", "IsSearchProviderInstalled", "IsServiceInstalled", "IsSubscribed", "msActiveXFilteringEnabled", "msAddSiteMode", "msAddTrackingProtectionList", "msClearTile", "msEnableTileNotificationQueue", "msEnableTileNotificationQueueForSquare150x150", "msEnableTileNotificationQueueForSquare310x310", "msEnableTileNotificationQueueForWide310x150", "msIsSiteMode", "msIsSiteModeFirstRun", "msPinnedSiteState", "msProvisionNetworks", "msRemoveScheduledTileNotification", "msReportSafeUrl", "msScheduledTileNotification", "msSiteModeActivate", "msSiteModeAddButtonStyle", "msSiteModeAddJumpListItem", "msSiteModeAddThumbBarButton", "msSiteModeClearBadge", "msSiteModeClearIconOverlay", "msSiteModeClearJumpList", "msSiteModeCreateJumpList", "msSiteModeRefreshBadge", "msSiteModeSetIconOverlay", "msSiteModeShowButtonStyle", "msSiteModeShowJumpList", "msSiteModeShowThumbBar", "msSiteModeUpdateThumbBarButton", "msStartPeriodicBadgeUpdate", "msStartPeriodicTileUpdate", "msStartPeriodicTileUpdateBatch", "msStopPeriodicBadgeUpdate", "msStopPeriodicTileUpdate", "msTrackingProtectionEnabled", "NavigateAndFind", "raiseEvent", "setContextMenu", "ShowBrowserUI", "menuArguments", "onvisibilitychange", "scrollbar", "selectableContent", "version", "visibility", "mssitepinned", "AddUrlAuthentication", "CloseRegPopup", "FeatureEnabled", "GetJsonWebData", "GetRegValue", "Log", "LogShellErrorsOnly", "OpenPopup", "ReadFile", "RunGutsScript", "SaveRegInfo", "SetAppMaximizeTimeToRestart", "SetAppMinimizeTimeToRestart", "SetAutoStart", "SetAutoStartMinimized", "SetMaxMemory", "ShareEventFromBrowser", "ShowPopup", "ShowRadar", "WriteFile", "WriteRegValue", "summonWalrus"</code> and also <code>"AddSearchProvider", "IsSearchProviderInstalled", "QueryInterface", "addPanel", "addPersistentPanel", "addSearchEngine"</code></li><li>checks <code>maxConnectionsPerServer</code> (on Window I think)</li><li>attempts to detect Brave Browser with <code>window.brave</code></li><li>checks for a bunch more properties on <code>window</code>:</li></ul><div><pre><code data-lang="js">                <span>m</span>(<span>"document_referrer"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"performance_timing"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>function</span>(<span>e</span>) {
                    <span>return</span> <span>x</span>.<span>qKjvb</span>(<span>e</span>)
                }), <span>m</span>(<span>"maxConnectionsPerServer"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"status"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"defaultStatus"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"performance_memory"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>_</span>.<span>flatten</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"screen"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>function</span>(<span>e</span>) {
                    <span>return</span> <span>e</span> <span>||</span> {}
                }), <span>m</span>(<span>"devicePixelRatio"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"mozPaintCount"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"styleMedia_type"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"history_length"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"opener"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>"top_opener"</span>, <span>function</span>(<span>e</span>) {
                    <span>return</span> <span>null</span> <span>!==</span> <span>e</span> <span>?</span> <span>typeof</span> <span>e</span> <span>:</span> <span>"null"</span>
                }), <span>m</span>(<span>"navigator_userAgent"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"fileCreatedDate"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"fileModifiedDate"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"fileUpdatedDate"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"lastModified"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"location_href"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"RemotePlayback"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"Permissions"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"Notification"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"MediaSession"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"name"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>function</span>(<span>e</span>) {
                    <span>return</span> <span>e</span>.<span>substr</span>(<span>0</span>, <span>128</span>)
                }), <span>m</span>(<span>"defaultView"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>"document_defaultView"</span>, <span>function</span>(<span>e</span>) {
                    <span>return</span> <span>void</span> <span>0</span> <span>===</span> <span>e</span> <span>?</span> <span>"undefined"</span> <span>:</span> <span>e</span> <span>===</span> window
                }), <span>m</span>(<span>"console"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>_</span>.<span>flatten</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"localStorage"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>v</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"webkitNotifications"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>v</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"webkitAudioContext"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>v</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"chrome"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>k</span>.<span>Keys</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"opera"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>k</span>.<span>Keys</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"navigator_standalone"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"navtype"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>"performance_navigation_type"</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"navredirs"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>"performance_navigation_redirectCount"</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"loadTimes"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>"chrome_loadTimes"</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"vendor"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>"navigator_vendor"</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"codename"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>"navigator_appCodeName"</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"navWebdriver"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>"navigator_webdriver"</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"navLanguages"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>"navigator_languages"</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"ServiceWorker"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"ApplePaySetup"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"ApplePaySession"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"Cache"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"PaymentAddress"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"MerchantValidationEvent"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"mediaDevices"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>"navigator_mediaDevices"</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"share"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>"navigator_share"</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"onorientationchange"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"document_defaultView_safari"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"navigator_brave"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"navigator_brave_isBrave"</span>, <span>h</span>), <span>le</span>.<span>hco</span> <span>&amp;&amp;</span> <span>m</span>(<span>"navHardwareConc"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>"navigator_hardwareConcurrency"</span>), <span>le</span>.<span>ndm</span> <span>&amp;&amp;</span> <span>m</span>(<span>"navDevMem"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>"navigator_deviceMemory"</span>), <span>le</span>.<span>nvl</span> <span>&amp;&amp;</span> (<span>m</span>(<span>"navLocks"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>"navigator_locks"</span>, <span>function</span>(<span>e</span>) {
                    <span>var</span> <span>t</span> <span>=</span> <span>typeof</span> <span>e</span>;
                    <span>return</span> <span>"undefined"</span> <span>===</span> <span>t</span> <span>?</span> <span>"undefined"</span> <span>:</span> <span>"object"</span> <span>===</span> <span>t</span> <span>?</span> <span>"obj"</span> <span>:</span> <span>e</span>
                }), <span>m</span>(<span>"navLocksR"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>"navigator_locks_request"</span>, <span>function</span>(<span>e</span>) {
                    <span>return</span> <span>"undefined"</span> <span>===</span> <span>typeof</span> <span>e</span> <span>?</span> <span>"undefined"</span> <span>:</span> <span>e</span>
                })), <span>le</span>.<span>wor</span> <span>&amp;&amp;</span> <span>m</span>(<span>"origin"</span>, <span>h</span>, <span>"origin"</span>), <span>"object"</span> <span>==</span> <span>typeof</span> <span>location</span> <span>&amp;&amp;</span> <span>m</span>(<span>"protocol"</span>, <span>location</span>), <span>"object"</span> <span>==</span> <span>typeof</span> document <span>&amp;&amp;</span> (<span>m</span>(<span>"hidden"</span>, document), <span>m</span>(<span>"documentMode"</span>, document), <span>m</span>(<span>"compatMode"</span>, document), <span>m</span>(<span>"visibilityState"</span>, document), <span>m</span>(<span>"d_origin"</span>, document, <span>"origin"</span>), <span>m</span>(<span>"ddl_origin"</span>, document, <span>"defaultView_location_origin"</span>));
</code></pre></div><ul><li>checks <code>mozIsLocallyAvailable</code> (which is only available on FF &lt;= 35, and could be for checking if someone is trying to debug this script offline)</li><li>checks how rounding of large and small numbers works, with <code>Math.round(.49999999999999994)</code> and <code>Math.round(Math.pow(2, 52))</code></li><li>checks the installed plugins (with <code>navigator.plugins</code>)</li><li>checks the browser viewport</li><li>attempts to get the “frame depth” (not sure what exactly that is)</li><li>checks for various status bars on <code>window</code> …</li></ul></article></div></section></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://smitop.com/post/whiteops-data/">https://smitop.com/post/whiteops-data/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://smitop.com/post/whiteops-data/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23777537</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 06:30:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[XP Paint – A Web-Based Version of Window XP's MS Paint]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 215 | Comments 92 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23776576">thread link</a>) | @chowderman
<br/>
July 8, 2020 | https://chowderman.github.io/xp-paint.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://chowderman.github.io/xp-paint.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://chowderman.github.io/xp-paint.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23776576</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 03:09:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Moving from TypeScript to Rust / WebAssembly]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 483 | Comments 384 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23776514">thread link</a>) | @nicolodavis
<br/>
July 8, 2020 | https://nicolodavis.com/blog/typescript-to-rust/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nicolodavis.com/blog/typescript-to-rust/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I recently decided to switch the engine of
<a href="https://boardgamelab.app/">Boardgame Lab</a> from TypeScript
to Rust. The application itself is an SPA written in Svelte.
I only switched the logic that updates the game state to Rust.
Here is a summary of my experience with the transition:</p><h2>Isomorphic Architecture</h2><p>One of the advantages of using JavaScript or TypeScript is
that you can run the same code on both client and server.
For <a href="https://boardgamelab.app/">Boardgame Lab</a>, this means
that the game state can be updated independently on both sides.
This results in a lag-free experience on the client
while still using the server as the authoritative source of
data.</p><p>With <a href="https://webassembly.org/">WebAssembly</a> taking off, you can get the same advantage
writing Rust. Instead of pushing client-side code to the server, we push server-side code to the client by compiling Rust
to WebAssembly.</p><p>This <a href="https://github.com/wasm-tool/rollup-plugin-rust">Rollup</a>
plugin allows you to import a <em>Cargo.toml</em> file into your
TypeScript codebase, allowing a seamless integration between
Rust and TypeScript code. The dev experience is almost as smooth
as writing TypeScript itself (for example, the browser refreshes
automatically when you change a line of Rust code).</p><p><a href="https://github.com/rustwasm/wasm-bindgen">wasm-bindgen</a>
facilitates serialization of Rust structs into JSON objects
and vice-versa.</p><h2>Limitations of TypeScript</h2><p>Coding in TypeScript has been a largely pleasant experience,
but switching to Rust immediately brought to light some of the
limitations of TypeScript.</p><h4>Strict Typing</h4><p>TypeScript is more of a type-hinter than a type-checker.
It primarily ensures that you’re not accessing fields that
you aren’t declaring via the type system (which is quite expressive). It also enables nicer autocomplete for your IDE.</p><p>However, it does not actually ensure that the data you are
manipulating corresponds to the type that you have declared
to represent it. For example, the data might contain <strong>additional fields</strong> or
even <strong>incorrect</strong> values for declared types.</p><h4>Data Validation</h4><p>You have to write data validation code to ensure that you’re
operating on correct data in TypeScript. You get this for
free in Rust, which will throw an error if you parse data
that doesn’t line up with the struct that is to hold it in
memory.</p><h4>Error Handling</h4><p>Rust’s <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/book/ch06-02-match.html">pattern matching</a> and <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/book/ch09-02-recoverable-errors-with-result.html">error handling</a> make it easy to
handle every code path that could result in an error, leading
to very robust code.</p><p>This leads to a great degree of confidence that if it compiles,
it’s probably not going to throw an error at runtime.</p><h2>Performance</h2><h4>WebAssembly is faster than JavaScript</h4><p>The initial rewrite without any performance optimizations
is already faster than the previous TypeScript codebase.
This doesn’t matter too much yet, but
<a href="https://boardgamelab.app/">Boardgame Lab</a> will eventually
ship with bots, so the performance will matter once
game trees need to be searched.</p><h4>The Rust server is leaner</h4><p>The multiplayer server receives updates from clients via
WebSockets and then:</p><ul><li>Updates its copy of the game state.</li><li>Broadcasts the client update to other clients.</li></ul><p>The previous server used <a href="https://github.com/websockets/ws">ws</a>, a popular library for NodeJS. The new version uses <a href="https://github.com/seanmonstar/warp">Warp</a> (Rust), which uses less memory
under the same load.</p><h2>Conclusion</h2><p>Overall, I’m pretty happy with the switch. I haven’t really
encountered much resistance from the borrow checker despite
being fairly new to Rust (I come from a C++ background, so
maybe that helps).</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nicolodavis.com/blog/typescript-to-rust/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23776514</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 02:52:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Seeking Truth in a Time of Misinformation]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 60 | Comments 51 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23776176">thread link</a>) | @crawshaw
<br/>
July 8, 2020 | https://raphlinus.github.io/covid/2020/07/08/seeking-truth.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://raphlinus.github.io/covid/2020/07/08/seeking-truth.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>Online abuse of trust is one of the topics I’ve studied deeply, including significant work toward an unfinished <a href="https://levien.com/thesis/thesis.pdf">PhD</a>, and over two years working on a spam and abuse team at Google. These days my main work is on 2D graphics, but seeing patterns of misinformation about Covid-19 is bringing back interest and motivation to think about these topics.</p>

<p>As Covid-19 has been unfolding, I’ve spent significant time and energy trying to understand it, as I tend to do with threats in general. In so doing, I’ve developed some insight on how to tune media consumption patterns towards more truthful content and less misinformation.</p>

<h2 id="america-is-broken">America is broken</h2>

<p>The astonishingly poor national response to Covid-19 is heartbreaking. Given our incredible richness of resources, it is surprising that many of the failure modes resemble those from low-income countries: superstition, cult of personality, suppression of science, and straight up corruption. A common thread is misinformation and disinformation.</p>

<p>Our response to Covid-19 has been very much like driving a car with poorly-maintained brakes. We’ve done the equivalent of neglecting regular maintenance, ignoring the brake light on the dashboard, and choosing to not to pay attention to the squishy feeling of the brake pedal. It’s as if there’s a devil on our shoulder saying, “oh no, don’t get the brakes fixed, it might cost hundreds of dollars.”</p>

<p>I think it’s worth trying to understand <em>why</em> we’re in that position, but it’s beyond the scope of this blog post. Mass behavior of humans is pretty predictable, but individual choices can probably make some difference. I have no answers for those who <em>want</em> to listen to that devil (a big challenge in and of itself), but for those would prefer to listen to the angel instead, I have some tips.</p>

<h2 id="it-is-a-partisan-issue">It is a partisan issue</h2>

<p>I often see the plea “it is not a partisan issue” attached to factual arguments. I think this represents an aspiration: it <em>should</em> not be partisan. In 2020 America, the reality is that there is a powerful anti-science, anti-truth faction, and that faction makes up a large part of the composition of one of the political parties. It’s not 100% alignment, and I want to give credit where credit is due: for example, the moderate Republican governor of Massachusetts has embraced science and investment in public health, and the results in that state are one of the best in the country.</p>

<p>But in general, any factual argument that has bearing on a political question such as “should we invest in public health” or “should we restructure the economy away from carbon consumption” is now inherently partisan.</p>

<p>Much of the partisan content in media is around issues that are not very consequential, either pure entertainment, or (at least traditionally) between candidates or parties that have comparable ability to govern. I was hopeful that the life or death nature of Covid-19 would motivate the people who decide what appears in media to higher standards. But apparently, it’s just the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Scorpion_and_the_Frog">nature of the scorpion</a>, they either can’t help themselves or just don’t care. Almost certainly, the media organization with the most blood on its hands is Fox News, which actively promotes an anti-health, pro-infection agenda. I don’t understand how they sleep at night.</p>

<p>Truth threatens a lot of existing power structures. If everybody woke up tomorrow and decided they were tired of being lied to, there would be seismic shifts of power. It’s worth thinking about who might be most affected by such a thing, and the kinds of things they do to keep it from happening.</p>

<h2 id="high-end-science-journalism">High-end science journalism</h2>

<p>I’m going to cover a range of information sources in this post, but there is a tl;dr: read up on actual science journalism by people who know what they’re talking about. Coverage by Science, Nature, and STAT News has been uniformly excellent. Good journalism is always teamwork, but I’ll also raise up the voices of particularly insightful individuals: <a href="https://twitter.com/sciencecohen">Jon Cohen</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/kakape">Kai Kupferschmidt</a> of Science, <a href="https://twitter.com/amymaxmen">Amy Maxmen</a> of Nature, <a href="https://twitter.com/HelenBranswell">Helen Branswell</a> of STAT News. These are science journalists who have invested years in honing their craft.</p>

<p>I’ve also been impressed by coverage in The Atlantic. Their science content is quite good (thanks to top-notch contributors such as <a href="https://twitter.com/edyong209">Ed Yong</a>), but they also put the science in the context of American culture and politics. It is for this reason, I believe, that our President has <a href="https://www.washingtonian.com/2020/05/27/the-atlantic-saw-subscriptions-surge-after-trump-tweet/">singled them out</a> for criticism.</p>

<p>It’s interesting that these sources tend to be publications that have been around for a while (STAT News is a brand of the Boston Globe media group). It’s not exactly rocket science how to do this, you just need to find experienced, capable writers and pay them to do journalism, with editorial and institutional support. But in today’s hyper-capitalist society, sustaining such efforts is a struggle. If you can, try to support publications that do good work by subscribing, or donating in the case of non-profits.</p>

<p>For someone with a limited budget of time and attention, good science journalism is absolutely the best bang for the buck. The other recommendations in this post are for people who want to spend a little more effort to gain, hopefully, a little more insight.</p>

<h2 id="twitter">Twitter</h2>

<p>By far the most interesting experience I’ve had has been Twitter. What makes Twitter unique is its extremely wide dynamic range of information quality: both the worst of the worst and the best of the best are well represented. (An example of an information source of low dynamic range is an encyclopedia: almost every article is pretty good, garbage and brilliance both being rare)</p>

<p>A well-curated Twitter feed is one of the best information sources available today, and following random people on Twitter is one of the worst.</p>

<p>Even though it has no formal structure such as subreddits, Twitter functions as a set of overlapping communities, often described as “X Twitter” or “Y Twitter” (incidentally, a good explanation of how communities work on Twitter can be had in Jeff Jarvis’ <a href="https://buzzmachine.com/2020/05/11/a-conversation-with-nathan-allebach-steak-umms-voice/">interview of the voice behind Steak-umm</a>). There are many experts who generously share their knowledge and thoughts with us, and I’ve found that with a modest investment of time, it’s possible to follow along.</p>

<p>In one of the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCud8VIawWp17jKl2Lp0VvlQ">Jeff Jarvis interviews</a>, they jokingly referred to “idiot Twitter,” and, though it was a joke, the concept has stuck with me. Twitter, like all social media properties, works by engaging very large numbers of people with content that appeals emotionally. The expert communities are far too small a fraction of Twitter’s traffic to be profitable for them, but they support them as a way to maintain the prestige of the platform. The replies of any popular post are filled with all manner of conspiracy theory, miracle cure, denial, blame, and, I think at least sometimes, active disinformation by those who would do us harm (it’s hard to tell the difference and the outcome is the same). I think of all that as “idiot Twitter” and just do my best to avoid it. I also see it everywhere, of course, not just Twitter, and the quantity of it is a good measure of the value in a social media platform.</p>

<p>Twitter has a delicate balance to maintain, as there are many aspects of the site design that push you toward “idiot Twitter” even when you’re trying to curate your experience to avoid it. One example that consistently frustrates me is the trending panel, as that seems to be about half composed of idiot Twitter. It’s addictive, even so, because it tempts you with the thrill of discovering things early. I’ve also found that it’s easier to avoid junk on the desktop site than the mobile app. I’m worried the experience will degrade; Quora stands as a cautionary tale of what can happen to a relatively respectable site when they pursue clicks at the cost of all else.</p>

<p>Whether it would be viable to develop a social network designed for quality of discussion is another topic beyond this blog. I’m not especially hopeful on this front, as it’s hard to see how it would be profitable. In any case, there’s not much value in wishing for the possibly impossible, as somebody seeking quality information can find it even today.</p>

<h3 id="list-curation">List curation</h3>

<p>One of the interesting features of Twitter is that people will curate and share lists of people they feel are worth following. My <a href="https://twitter.com/i/lists/1239639611694911489">covid-19 list</a> is one such, and a lot of thought went into it: I’ve intentionally included people with a wide range of expertise (including, for example, <a href="https://twitter.com/j_g_allen">Joseph Allen</a> for his insight into healthy buildings and <a href="https://twitter.com/uche_blackstock">Dr. Uché Blackstock</a> for expertise on health equity). I’ve also deliberately excluded people from this list who express strong political views or often use an emotional tone. Because of the latter criterion, it’s missing people I personally feel are worth listening to, especially <a href="https://twitter.com/gregggonsalves">Gregg Gonsalves</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/JeremyKonyndyk">Jeremy Konyndyk</a>. As always, your mileage may vary. The goal of this particular list is not to be comprehensive, it’s to select a set of voices that have excellent signal to noise ratio; for a much more comprehensive list, see <a href="https://twitter.com/i/lists/1237834151694303234">this one curated by Jeff Jarvis</a>.</p>

<p>One phenomenon I’ve noticed is that people at the top of these lists tend to recommend each other. I wouldn’t be surprised if some automated evaluation (perhaps based on eigenvalues) could yield a good curated list. That said, in my past research, I’ve found that any automatic metric with an incentive will be <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Goodhart%27s_law">gamed</a>, and invariably will lift up self-promoters over quiet, thoughtful voices.</p>

<p>Speaking of self-promoters, two names do not belong on lists of top experts, but are often found there: Eric Feigl-Ding &amp; Laurie Garrett. Both are good communicators, but are also sloppy enough with their science to get called out regularly. Inclusion of these names is a sign that a list of experts is not especially carefully curated.</p>

<p>Another important warning sign is lack of inclusion of women and people of color; mainstream media is often guilty of this. Health equity is an especially important part of the …</p></div></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://raphlinus.github.io/covid/2020/07/08/seeking-truth.html">https://raphlinus.github.io/covid/2020/07/08/seeking-truth.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://raphlinus.github.io/covid/2020/07/08/seeking-truth.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23776176</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 01:40:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
