<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 10]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 10. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 08:28:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-10.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 08:28:19 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[We need a FrontPage that lets common folk retake the internet with creativity]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 19 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25218794">thread link</a>) | @pmlnr
<br/>
November 26, 2020 | https://invisibleup.com/articles/33/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://invisibleup.com/articles/33/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
	
	
	<img src="https://invisibleup.com/articles/33/thumb.png" alt="FrontPage: The Good, The Bad, and The Ugly thumbnail">
	
	

	<p>PLEASE don't use FrontPage for modern web development! It's filled with security vulnerabilities and obsolete standards. The goal of this is not to convince you otherwise. The newest version came out almost two decades ago!</p>

<p>Microsoft FrontPage. The mere mention of that name is making most (if not all) of you seasoned web devs groan. "FrontPage was utter rubbish from dark ages of GeoCities" you say. "Everything it touched was ruined with horrific output and proprietary nonsense!" And yes, it was.</p>
<p>But... FrontPage as a concept. As a dream of what could have been, and a window into what <em>was</em>. Letting the typical home user at the time create websites, express creativity, and conquer the world by storm, all without being forced to learn HTML or CSS or JavaScript... In that regard, FrontPage couldn't be beat.</p>
<p>Let's talk about why Microsoft FrontPage was for a brief period of time the ultimate content creation tool of the Internet, and why it later fell from grace.</p>
<h2>History</h2>
<p>Before we can talk about goodness and ugliness, we need to talk about carphones and business meetings. Because this was 1994, when the Internet was still really new. At that point in time most internet chatter occured on Usenet groups (think something like Reddit) or BBS systems (think something like <a href="https://invisibleup.com/articles/5/">old AOL</a>; example pictured below). If you needed buisness stuff, like stocks or the such, you had to log onto the BBS of whoever had what you needed. This was kind of a pain.</p>
<p><img alt="A picture of a BBS (tilde.town) as of today" src="https://invisibleup.com/articles/33/BBS.png"></p>
<p>Enter Randy Forgaard and Charles H. Ferguson. Ferguson, renowned computer industry consultant, contacted MIT graduate Forgaard (over carphone, in case you were wondering) to discuss starting a new, internet-based company.</p>
<p>His idea was that many corporations such as the Dow Jones, Bloomberg, Apple, etc. were sinking millions into building their own, completely incompatible dial-in Internet services. Therefore, they should create a standardized, completely open server/client combo to replace all the independent efforts. This hopefully would reduce the cost of development for those corporations, and provide a market for growth by making buisnesses <em>want</em> to have an Interent presence.</p>
<p>The two decided to found their own company, Vermeer Technologies, Inc. A month later, still in the planning stages, they caught wind of the brand new World Wide Web out of CERN. It was decentralized, open, and even more robust than they were planning. It was just about perfect. The only issue was that it was rather a pain to make websites if you were just some lowly advertising manager or whoever. The web needed an authoring tool for websites.</p>
<p><img alt="FrontPage 1.0a, taken from WinWorldPC.com" src="https://invisibleup.com/articles/33/FP-1.0.png"></p>
<p>So, somehow, they managed to hire many professional coders for no salary whatsoever to work on FrontPage. (Early start-up culture, perhaps?) Evidently it worked, as FrontPage was released (only!) a week behind schedule on October of 1995. By then the World Wide Web was exploding, with a 20% increase in sites <em>per month</em>. FrontPage also managed to explode, receiving many awards and positive reviews. In fact, it was so good that Microsoft ended up buying them out. According to them, not only did it feel like a native Office application, it was perfect for their ongoing plan to become more internet centric.</p>
<p><img alt="FrontPage 97, taken from WinWorldPC.com" src="https://invisibleup.com/articles/33/FP-97.png"></p>
<p>FrontPage over the years got integrated into the Office suite and made a flagship product for Microsoft productivity products. By Office 2000, FrontPage had more Office integration than you should shake a stick at; nailing down the Office user interface and allowing imports and exports across the whole suite. There's... other stuff as well, but let's stay positive for now.</p>
<p>I'll be covering FrontPage 2002, as that's the version I own, and the one I have the most experience with.</p>
<h2>The Good</h2>
<p>The interface... is (in my opinion) one of the best interfaces for any program ever. No hyperbole. I think only the other Microsoft applications of the era like PowerPoint and Visio can top it. I can <em>see</em> why it won awards.</p>
<p><img alt="FrontPage's start screen with no webs open" src="https://invisibleup.com/articles/33/FP-Start.png"></p>
<p>Like any other Microsoft Office XP program, there's the sidebar on the right with common tasks. What you'll probably want to do is, of course, make a new site.</p>
<p>FrontPage's equivalent to "projects" are called "Webs". These Webs contain the files (all your HTML, CSS, images, etc.) and preferences (such as which web server to sync up with or what compatibility settings to use) for that website.</p>
<p><img alt="FrontPage's template selector" src="https://invisibleup.com/articles/33/FP-NewWeb.png"></p>
<p>Start by selecting a new "Empty Web". Up pops a bunch of templates, including the "Empty Web" template. A bit odd, but sure.</p>
<p><img alt="The &quot;Personal Homepage&quot; template in action" src="https://invisibleup.com/articles/33/FP-Template.png"></p>
<p>If you <em>were</em> to choose a template, it would give you a pre-populated fill-in-the-blanks site ready for your words and pictures. It takes some of the layout work and design originality out of it, but that <em>is</em> the purpose of a template after all. (Although, as a word of advice, <em>don't use these.</em> They're rather awfully designed from a web standards point of view. You can see it barely fitting in my window there. Imagine that on a smartphone.)</p>
<p><img src="https://invisibleup.com/articles/33/FP-BlankWeb.png" alt="FrontPage open to a new blank web. Folder list and Views bar are visible."></p>
<p>Anyways, once you open your blank web, you get... nothing! (That's what you asked for, isn't it?) No worries. Really, if you think about it, it would be rather silly to start making a page off the bat. You see, FrontPage takes a <em>project oriented</em> approach to things. While you easily <em>could</em> just sit down and start banging stuff out, that's really not the way FrontPage wants you to go.</p>
<p><img alt="FrontPage Navigation editor with some pages created and linked up." src="https://invisibleup.com/articles/33/FP-NavView.png"></p>
<p>Here's probably my favorite FrontPage feature: the Navigation editor. Here you create blank pages and link them together in a logical hierarchy. This closely resembles the process you'd usually take on paper when designing a website.</p>
<p><img alt="Navigation bar settings dialog" src="https://invisibleup.com/articles/33/FP-Navbar.png"></p>
<p>With this hierarchy, you can automatically create a navigation bar in all your pages that are properly linked. If you decide to make a new top-level page, for instance, every page on your site will be updated to feature that page. (To replicate that feature on this site, I had to use some pretty tricky template scripting with my custom Flask server. I'd vastly prefer something like this.)</p>
<p>This feature is also nice because it forces you to <em>think about your site</em>. You can't just sit down like it's Microsoft Word and bang out some pages. You need a coherent plan. Before you can even start, you need to sit down with your client/team/self and ask "What do you want on your website?" To most people it's obvious that you need a website. Everybody has a website. What's significantly less obvious is <em>what</em> needs to be on the website. And FrontPage's web editor allows you to play around with hierarchies and layouts before commiting to anything.</p>
<p><img alt="PowerPoint Slide Sorter mode&quot;" src="https://invisibleup.com/articles/33/PPT-SlideSorter.png"></p>
<p>One thing that's intersting is that Word, PowerPoint and Access all (vaguely) follow a similar model. Word has the Outline editor, PowerPoint has the Slide Sorter mode (pictured above, showing an interactive game I made when I was 11), and Access, being a typical database program, requires you to declare your tables before you can work on them.</p>
<p>What's even more interesting is that, with the exception of Access (which not many people used, mostly due to its cost and relative rarity), you were never <em>required</em> to have a plan before starting. Most people I've seen use Word just do straight typing, or perhaps work off another document with an outline. But the option was there! One could do their outline <em>in their document</em> and flesh out around that. Likewise with PowerPoint, as well.</p>
<p><img alt="Highlighted template include code" src="https://invisibleup.com/articles/33/FP-TemplateInclude.png"></p>
<p>Another common task in web design is defining a "template" page where you fill all your content into. For example, every page on this site you're reading on now has the same header and footer, and every article has the same sort of thumbnail image at the top. That was all scripted using template features.</p>
<p>FrontPage, being an Office product, supports templates. The implementation admittedly is <em>super</em> janky, but it's there. You can include pages within other pages just fine, it's just a little tricky to set up. (FYI, Word, Excel, and PowerPoint do templates too. It's one of their lesser-known features, IMHO.)</p>
<p><img alt="Report view window" src="https://invisibleup.com/articles/33/FP-Reports.png"></p>
<p>Another really neat feature: reports. Like a compiler in an IDE, FrontPage produces warnings, errors, and statistics for your site. At a glance I can view all broken links, orphaned pages, oversized images, etc. This is a <em>fantastic</em> feature, something that modern web dev software just <em>doesn't</em> have.</p>
<p><img alt="Hyperlinks view window" src="https://invisibleup.com/articles/33/FP-Links.png"></p>
<p>In the same vein as the Reports, you can see at a glance what links to what. It's a lot like the call chart in a software development IDE. I can see quickly every site linked from any page (shown here is <a href="https://invisibleup.com/articles/24/">the Sonic R color fix article</a>) and any subpages.</p>
<p><img alt="Tasks view, showing a task labeled &quot;Write FrontPage article&quot;" src="https://invisibleup.com/articles/33/FP-Tasks.png"></p>
<p>Last feature, although this isn't nearly as useful in the year 2020. In the tasks view, you can put up a list of tasks that needs to be accomplished. Already that seems rather nice for keeping track of what you need to do. It's a lot like GitHub or GitLab's issue tracker, in a sense.</p>
<p>However, if you connect to a server with FrontPage Web Extensions (I'll get to that...), you can share this task list with other people. You can (again, like an issue tracker) put up a task to be done by someone else and work on a task that somebody else put up. It's a <em>very</em> nice feature for web development, but nowadays this is normally handled by source control providers like GitHub or GitLab.</p>
<p><img alt="FrontPage editing the Sonic R color mod article" src="https://invisibleup.com/articles/33/FP-Editor.png"></p>
<p>And, of course, there's the webpage editor. This works almost exactly like Microsoft Word, with some web-flavored spice. You type words and they appear in the page. You make those words blue, they're blue. <em>That said</em>, when you edit elements like that, it inserts an HTML 3.2 style <code>&lt;FONT&gt;</code> tag instead of trying to match it to a CSS rule. There's ways around this, but you have to be very diligent in doing so. This is mostly just due to FrontPage being a product of its time, though.</p>
<p>FrontPage is a program about planning, executing, and reviewing. Take the Navigation editor. You plan out the content of your site. You sketch up the layout. Then you reflect on if your layout matches your requirements. Or the Reports. Create content, check reports. Or the Tasks. Plan out what you need to do, do that, and then check if the task is complete. That, right …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://invisibleup.com/articles/33/">https://invisibleup.com/articles/33/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://invisibleup.com/articles/33/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25218794</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 10:53:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[EmacsConf 2020: State of Retro Gaming in Emacs]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 44 | Comments 10 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25218177">thread link</a>) | @sohkamyung
<br/>
November 26, 2020 | https://emacsconf.org/2020/schedule/27/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://emacsconf.org/2020/schedule/27/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div class="page">



<div id="pagebody">







<div id="content" role="main">





<p>Back to the <a href="https://emacsconf.org/2020/schedule/">schedule</a><br>
Previous: <a href="https://emacsconf.org/2020/schedule/26">Emacs as a Highschooler: How It Changed My Life</a><br>
Next: <a href="https://emacsconf.org/2020/schedule/28">Welcome To The Dungeon</a></p>

<p>Sunday, Nov 29 2020,  1:16 PM -  1:26 PM EST<br>
Sunday, Nov 29 2020, 10:16 AM - 10:26 AM PST<br>
Sunday, Nov 29 2020,  6:16 PM -  6:26 PM UTC<br>
Sunday, Nov 29 2020,  7:16 PM -  7:26 PM CET<br>
Monday, Nov 30 2020,  2:16 AM -  2:26 AM +08</p>



<p>Vasilij "wasamasa" Schneidermann</p>

<p>Many jokes have been made about the true nature of Emacs, such as it
being a fully-fledged operating system.  This talk will demonstrate
its suitability for playing retro games, then explore the inner
workings of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CHIP-8">CHIP-8</a> emulator capable of smooth video game emulation.</p>

<p>Back to the <a href="https://emacsconf.org/2020/schedule/">schedule</a><br>
Previous: <a href="https://emacsconf.org/2020/schedule/26">Emacs as a Highschooler: How It Changed My Life</a><br>
Next: <a href="https://emacsconf.org/2020/schedule/28">Welcome To The Dungeon</a></p>

<p>All times are approximate, and we might shuffle talks around as needed.
Please check <a href="https://emacsconf.org/2020">https://emacsconf.org/2020</a> a few days before the start of the
conference for instructions on how to watch and participate. See you then!</p>

</div>







</div>



</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://emacsconf.org/2020/schedule/27/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25218177</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 08:53:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Your Move, iPad]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 95 | Comments 114 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25218050">thread link</a>) | @rcarmo
<br/>
November 26, 2020 | https://beckyhansmeyer.com/2020/11/25/your-move-ipad/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://beckyhansmeyer.com/2020/11/25/your-move-ipad/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Hear that? It’s the sound of Mac fans. No, not your shiny new M1 Mac’s fans—chances are, you’ll never hear those—but rather, the sound of <em>excitement</em> rippling through the Mac community. This is something big. Really big. Now, I’m only 33, but someday when I go full fuddy-duddy I will speak of this: the great Intel/Apple Silicon transition. The beginning of a new era at Apple.</p>



<p>All that sounds dramatic, of course, but it’s interesting to trace all of the different paths that led us to this point. The A-Series chips, the introduction of Metal, rapid machine learning gains, the gradually degrading repairability scores as components became more integrated, the Secure Enclave, a new super fast emulation layer, new unified memory architecture, and 5nm process… years and years of work have now come to fruition with the first Apple Silicon chips for Mac. And our minds are blown.</p>



<p>Suddenly, we’re handed a thin, entry-level fanless laptop that performs better than almost every other Mac computer out there, and a low-end MacBook Pro and Mac Mini that make current Mac Pro owners sweat and clutch their wheels. So many questions abound. What new hardware designs will these gains make possible? What on earth does Apple have in store for its high-end Macs? Will anyone else even be able to compete? It’s an exciting time to be a Mac lover, but, surprise: this post isn’t really about the Mac. It’s about the iPad.</p>



<p>There’s no question that Apple has struggled to craft a cohesive, compelling narrative for the iPad. For a long time, there seemed to be a distinct lack of product vision. Everyone likes to speculate over what role Steve Jobs ultimately intended the iPad to have in people’s lives, but not only is that pointless, it’s also irrelevant. We don’t need Steve to tell us what the iPad is good for. We know what it’s good for, and we can easily imagine what it <em>could</em> be good for, if only Apple would set it free.</p>



<p>Just as Apple left us with great expectations for its Pro Mac line-up, the latest iPad Air also raises the bar in new and interesting ways. The Air served as sort of an appetizer for the new M1 chips, while also receiving a generous trickle-down of features from the iPad Pro, including USB-C and support for the latest keyboard and Pencil accessories. There have been rumors of new mini-LED displays for the next-gen iPad Pros, but it’s going to take a lot more than new display tech to set the Pros apart.</p>



<p>Francisco Tolmasky (<a href="https://twitter.com/tolmasky/status/1330033394349125642?s=20">@tolmasky</a>) recently tweeted:</p>



<blockquote><p>“A sad but inescapable conclusion from the impressive launch of the M1 is just how much Apple squandered the potential of the iPad. The iPad has had amazing performance for awhile, so why is the M1 a game changer? Because it’s finally in a machine we can actually <em>do things on</em>.”</p></blockquote>



<p>Francisco is right: Power and performance aren’t the bottleneck for iPad, and haven’t been for some time. So if raw power isn’t enough, and new display tech isn’t enough, where does the iPad go from here? Will it be abandoned once more, lagging behind the Mac in terms of innovation, or will Apple continue to debut its latest tech in this form factor? Is it headed toward functional parity with the Mac or will it always be hamstrung by Apple’s strict App Store policies and seemingly inconsistent investment in iPadOS?</p>



<p>It’s clear that Apple <em>wants</em> the iPad Pro to be a device that a wide variety of professionals can use to get work done. And since so many people use web apps for their work, the introduction of “desktop” Safari for iPad was an important step toward that goal. The Magic Keyboard and trackpad was another step.</p>



<p>Here are ten more steps I believe Apple could and should take to help nudge the iPad into this exciting next era of computing.</p>



<ol><li>Give the iPad Pro another port. Two USB 4.0 ports would be lovely.</li><li>Adopt a landscape-first mindset. Rotate the Apple logo on the back and move the iPad’s front-facing camera on the side beneath the Apple Pencil charger to better reflect how most people actually use their iPad Pros.</li><li>Introduce Gatekeeper and app notarization for iOS. The process of side-loading apps should <em>not</em> be as simple as downloading them from the App Store. Bury it in Settings, make it slightly convoluted, whatever: just have an officially-sanctioned way of doing it.</li><li>Ruthlessly purge the App Store Guidelines of anything that prevents the iPad from serving as a development machine. Every kind of development from web to games should be possible on an iPad. And speaking of games—emulators should be allowed, too.</li><li>Release a suite of professional first-party apps at premium prices. If someone can edit 4K videos in Final Cut on their M1 MacBook Air, they should be able to edit 4K videos in Final Cut on their iPad Pro. I refuse to believe that these pro apps can’t be re-imagined and optimized for a touch experience. If Apple leads the way in developing premium software for iPad, others will follow.</li><li>Make it possible to write, release, and install plug-ins (if appropriate) for the aforementioned first party apps.</li><li>Bring App Library to the iPad and allow widgets to be positioned anywhere on the Home Screen. This isn’t groundbreaking, it just annoys the heck out of me.</li><li>Release a new keyboard + trackpad case accessory that allows the iPad to be used in tablet mode without removing it from the case.</li><li>Introduce Time Machine backups for iPadOS.</li><li>5G, ofc.</li></ol>



<p>In the end, fostering a vibrant community of iPad app developers can only stand to benefit the Mac (and vice-versa).</p>



<p>It’s simple: people love their iPads. They love them so much they wish they could do even more with them. The new M1 Macs should give iPad fans reason to be excited; now that we’ve seen hints of what future Macs can be, it’s time for the iPad to reassert itself—to remind us once again who it’s for, and what makes it special.</p>



<p>In other words: Your move, iPad.</p>
			</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://beckyhansmeyer.com/2020/11/25/your-move-ipad/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25218050</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 08:28:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Cracks in the Great Stagnation?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 16 | Comments 31 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25216017">thread link</a>) | @edward
<br/>
November 25, 2020 | https://www.agglomerations.tech/cracks-in-the-great-stagnation/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.agglomerations.tech/cracks-in-the-great-stagnation/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">
    <div>

        <article>

            

            <figure>
                <img srcset="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1602611061438-ca00df2a4319?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;q=80&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;w=2000&amp;fit=max&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ 300w,
                            https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1602611061438-ca00df2a4319?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;q=80&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;w=2000&amp;fit=max&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ 600w,
                            https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1602611061438-ca00df2a4319?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;q=80&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;w=2000&amp;fit=max&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ 1000w,
                            https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1602611061438-ca00df2a4319?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;q=80&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;w=2000&amp;fit=max&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 400px,
                        (max-width: 1170px) 1170px,
                            2000px" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1602611061438-ca00df2a4319?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;q=80&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;w=2000&amp;fit=max&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ" alt="Cracks in the Great Stagnation">
            </figure>

            <section>
                <div>
                    <p>For the last 60 years, we’ve seen consistently low productivity growth rates in the US and across the Western world. Meanwhile, recent scientific discoveries seem to be <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2018/11/diminishing-returns-science/575665/">less fundamental</a> to our understanding of the world than previous breakthroughs have been. While the growth of digital technology has been tremendous since the 1990s, it’s the only significant part of our world that seems to have been changing. To look up from our smartphones is to see a physical environment that looks basically the same as it did in 1970. Innovation has been constrained to the world of bits and left the world of atoms mostly untouched.</p><p>This might finally be changing. Last month, the economist Tyler Cowen <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2020-10-05/how-much-worse-can-things-get-that-question-may-be-a-good-sign">speculated</a> that we may be seeing signs that this <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Great-Stagnation-Low-Hanging-Eventually-eSpecial-ebook/dp/B004H0M8QS">Great Stagnation</a> is ending. Since his article was published, we’ve already seen almost a dozen announcements that have only driven home the point further. There seem to be cracks in the Great Stagnation and light is peeking through on the other end. </p><p><strong>Innovation in the physical world</strong><br>Most obviously, the recent announcement of the <a href="https://www.statnews.com/2020/11/09/covid-19-vaccine-from-pfizer-and-biontech-is-strongly-effective-early-data-from-large-trial-indicate/">successful development of several vaccines</a> to the novel coronavirus are a sign that America (with some help from Germany) is still capable of achieving Big Things when we are pushed to it. Despite consistent failings of the US regulatory state in <a href="https://slatestarcodex.com/2020/04/14/a-failure-but-not-of-prediction/">delaying the adoption</a> of face masks and in <a href="https://thedispatch.com/p/timeline-the-regulationsand-regulatorsthat">slowing the rollout</a> of mass testing, the US essentially bet the farm that our strong biotech clusters would be able to create a vaccine to a new disease in record time, and it looks like we’re going to be able to do it in under a year! </p><p>It’s worth highlighting just how speedy this development timeline is when compared to the vaccines for diseases like polio and measles. </p><figure><img src="https://www.agglomerations.tech/content/images/2020/11/Vaccination-innovation-chart.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.agglomerations.tech/content/images/size/w600/2020/11/Vaccination-innovation-chart.png 600w, https://www.agglomerations.tech/content/images/size/w1000/2020/11/Vaccination-innovation-chart.png 1000w, https://www.agglomerations.tech/content/images/size/w1600/2020/11/Vaccination-innovation-chart.png 1600w, https://www.agglomerations.tech/content/images/size/w2400/2020/11/Vaccination-innovation-chart.png 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption>https://ourworldindata.org/vaccination</figcaption></figure><p>And not only did we develop a new vaccine, we developed a new *type* of vaccine. mRNA vaccines have long been speculated to work, but this is the <a href="https://www.bostonherald.com/2020/11/20/pfizer-and-moderna-vaccines-showing-potential-success-of-mrna-platform-a-first/">first instance</a> of a successful vaccine application in humans using this technique. </p><p>In transportation, the promise of driverless cars has long been a centerpiece for a tech-optimistic vision of safer roads, better-designed cities, and eliminating the drudgery of a morning commute through traffic. But the technical delays of the last few years (when compared to the most optimistic timelines) have become a rallying cry for the <a href="https://blog.piekniewski.info/2018/05/28/ai-winter-is-well-on-its-way/">tech-skeptic</a> as well. </p><p>It seems like they may finally be getting here. A few weeks ago, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2020/10/waymo-finally-launches-an-actual-public-driverless-taxi-service/">Waymo announced</a> that their long-running pilot program in Arizona is going to be open to the public <a href="https://twitter.com/jjricks_/status/1316318196375330816">without any safety driver</a> in the front seat. Days later, Elon Musk and Tesla rolled out a new self-driving beta program. </p><figure><blockquote data-width="550"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">These two guys used a drone to make a video of Tesla's new "full self-driving" software in action. The drone, the self-driving car, and the global video-steaming service were all been science fiction when I was born. Living in the future is neat. <a href="https://t.co/4QqGcjFXsc">https://t.co/4QqGcjFXsc</a></p>— Timothy B. Lee (@binarybits) <a href="https://twitter.com/binarybits/status/1321102111883579397?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 27, 2020</a></blockquote>

</figure><p>This is a remarkable engineering feat, especially on Waymo’s end. It shows the company can successfully lead product development in an industry that relies on more stringent safety-critical engineering instead of the release-and-iterate model that its parent company grew up with. Waymo is evidence that Silicon Valley can “move at a moderate pace and not break things” when it needs to.</p><p>Granted, it’s unclear how long until and at what pace deployment of AVs to the rest of the country and the world will happen. If the Waymo model looks to be successful, it will be a steady, resource-intensive process of region-by-region expansion as the cars learn to handle new operational design domains and are rigorously validated in each city before the keys are turned over to the AI. In other words, expansion could look more like a cell phone coverage map than a software update that is instantaneously available everywhere. </p><p>But still, this is a significant, tangible mile marker that the industry has passed. AVs are operating in the wild now. We get to talk about *when* we reach the driverless future, not *if*. </p><p>In addition to the almost ho-hum daily progress in solar, wind, and battery technology where prices have fallen <a href="https://www.greentechmedia.com/articles/read/solar-pv-has-become-cheaper-and-better-in-the-2010s-now-what">90</a>, <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/energyinnovation/2020/01/21/renewable-energy-prices-hit-record-lows-how-can-utilities-benefit-from-unstoppable-solar-and-wind/?sh=491f10ec2c84">70</a>, and <a href="https://about.bnef.com/blog/battery-pack-prices-fall-as-market-ramps-up-with-market-average-at-156-kwh-in-2019">87</a> percent over the last ten years, we’ve also started to hear very promising reports about the development of more fundamental breakthroughs. The NYT reports that a compact nuclear fusion reactor is “<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/09/29/climate/nuclear-fusion-reactor.html?action=click&amp;module=News&amp;pgtype=Homepage">Very Likely to Work</a>” after a major theoretical advancement. There was also a fantastic David Robert’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2020/10/21/21515461/renewable-energy-geothermal-egs-ags-supercritical">deep dive into geothermal energy</a> and the promise of advanced geothermal (whereby water pumped into the ground through a closed loop reaches a high enough temperature that it becomes “supercritical” and can carry 10x more energy per unit mass), in particular. Either technology, if perfected, would provide abundant, zero-carbon, baseload energy that is available anywhere around the world. </p><p>Cowen mentions briefly the huge market growth we’ve seen in lab-grown meat and plant-based alternatives. A few weeks ago it was announced that Impossible Foods, one of the largest actors in the industry is <a href="https://venturebeat.com/2020/10/20/impossible-foods-will-double-rd-to-eliminate-animal-farming/">doubling their R&amp;D team</a> as they seek to take on plant-based milk, steak, and fish as well as improve the supply chains for plant proteins. In tandem, McDonald’s <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/food/2020/11/10/mcdonalds-mcplant-sandwich/">just announced</a> that in 2021 they are going to be testing out a new McPlant menu.</p><p><strong>Digital innovation continues apace</strong></p><p>Not to be left out, in the digital world we’ve been seeing impressive progress as well. AI techniques like deepfakes which have been heralded as the <a href="https://www.sundayguardianlive.com/opinion/deepfakes-destroy-democracy">death knell for democracy</a> are now being <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2020/11/nvidia-used-neural-networks-to-improve-video-calling-bandwidth-by-10x/">deployed by NVIDIA</a> to increase video fidelity while cutting bandwidth transmission for video calls by a factor of 10. In general, techniques to reduce bandwidth use are greatly underrated, and it’s going to be exciting to see the ways in which smarter compression can perhaps bring similar efficiency gains across the board. </p><p>And now factor in the steady rollout of 5G network technologies which promise to increase the raw bandwidth available to all mobile devices. With the combination of smarter compression and vastly increased bandwidth we could be looking at a baseline 50x increase in network capacity over the next decade. It’s hard to predict ahead of time what new applications will be enabled by all this new capacity, but in retrospect it could look like another example of <a href="https://diff.substack.com/p/how-bubbles-and-megaprojects-parallelize">parallel innovation</a> that both enables and is driven by the growth of VR/AR, driverless vehicles, and telehealth.*</p><p><em>*For those who are skeptical that increased capacity will generate new applications because a few cities have tried gigabit broadband<a href="https://www.wsj.com/graphics/faster-internet-not-worth-it/"> without much effect</a>, I would argue that both hardware and app developers are optimizing for the baseline user experience and we won’t see a ton of investment in new applications until we’ve changed the baseline capacity that developers can expect a sizeable user base to have. </em></p><p>Equally as impressive, Apple’s new M1 chip that was launched on November 10th seems to have taken the world by storm. As John Gruber <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2020/11/the_m1_macs">summarizes</a>: “To acknowledge how good they are — and I am here to tell you they are astonishingly good — you must acknowledge that certain longstanding assumptions about how computers should be designed, about what makes a better computer better, about what good computers need, are wrong.” Just as interesting is <a href="https://medium.com/pcmag-access/what-is-the-apple-m1-chip-613935ea0903">how they did it</a>. By miniaturizing the whole system architecture and integrating it onto a single chip (no discrete RAM, graphics card, etc.) Apple has managed to pump out massive efficiency gains both in processing power and in battery life. (There’s perhaps a metaphor here for the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/breaking-up-big-tech-is-hard-to-do-1532290123">value of integration</a> for large tech firms as well…)</p><figure><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/tXP4ZnW93TIsJ_dJe3NVmevfz5eMUnNC6CS40Dz_S0568BDiQKr8K8LqT5Ja-kLnXUKnS1UkDQf_6WYzBhfGa4c99lQDfqudhQaDF-XCYBEkxNoP3Vo3FlGtLl3sGFQcdtHBlGbv" alt=""><figcaption>https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/yeah-apples-m1-macbook-pro-is-powerful-but-its-the-battery-life-that-will-blow-you-away/</figcaption></figure><p>Finally, the virtual reality space has seen its most impressive entrant in years with the arrival of the Quest 2 from Facebook on October 13th. There is no VR headset that matches it on a performance/cost basis, and the relative simplicity and elegance of the system makes it an ideal entry point. The deliberately low entry barrier of $299 is meant to entice a large enough user base that it kickstarts the virtuous cycle of having a significant enough market for dedicated VR developers to make significant investments in new applications, which then drives new user growth. Facebook believes we finally have a minimum viable product for VR that means this kind of two-sided market is possible, and it is betting billions of dollars to make it happen. Early signs seem to show that it is working as intended with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/30/21541535/oculus-quest-2-preorders-sales-developers-zuckerberg">pre-orders reportedly 5x</a> larger than the original Quest, popular applications like Beat Saber seeing record growth, and all this with the upcoming holiday rush and a massive advertising blitz to come. </p><p>Notably, all of these announcements/developments I’ve outlined have occurred in just the last few months. This is by no means a comprehensive look at the exciting progress being made in many other fields. But the sheer scope and pace of tangible changes to our physical and digital words is something to be excited about.</p><p><strong>A few caveats </strong></p><p>Some of these innovations will boost productivity in the traditional ways that show up in economic growth statistics. We should strive for and celebrate those achievements. But some of these innovations won’t necessarily, instead they make human civilization more durable and sustainable in a variety of ways. In response, we should start to think of increased sustainability as a type of productivity. </p><p>A vaccine to the COVID pandemic is the most obvious example. While economic statistics won’t show a boost in productivity compared to the pre-COVID economy because of the vaccine, the ability to return to trend is itself incredibly valuable. In fact, measured labor productivity from the vaccine will likely fall as lower-wage …</p></div></section></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.agglomerations.tech/cracks-in-the-great-stagnation/">https://www.agglomerations.tech/cracks-in-the-great-stagnation/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.agglomerations.tech/cracks-in-the-great-stagnation/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25216017</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 01:14:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Discord bans me for using their official client]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 51 | Comments 52 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25214777">thread link</a>) | @jkcclemens
<br/>
November 25, 2020 | https://annaclemens.io/discord | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://annaclemens.io/discord">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
    <section>
      

      <p>
        Quick note: I don't really have a blog, but I wanted to publish this
        on my site, so this just has some quick styles applied.
      </p>

      <hr>

      <p>
	<strong>Resolution</strong>: My Discord account has been unbanned. After posting this page on Hacker News, the head of Discord's anti-abuse team saw it and looked into the issue. It turns out that my use of a third-party Discord client called Ripcord was the reason for my ban. At the time of the ban, I had been using this client for years, but I wasn't actively using it. I was actually using the official client, hence the older title of this page, but the third-party client was open on my laptop in the background. I leave this page here to chronicle how unacceptable Discord's response to this was.
      </p>

      <hr>

      <p>
        It's true: Discord banned me for using their own client. On 1
        November, I was scrolling through my old DMs. It was kind of messy, so
        I started to close some of them (which really just <em>hides</em>
        them). After closing maybe around seven of them, Discord booted me
        back to the login screen. I thought that was weird, but I grabbed my
        phone to scan the QR code to log in, but it didn't work. Annoyed, I
        manually typed in my login details only to find that my account has
        been disabled.
      </p>

      <h2>1 November</h2>

      <p>
        On the same day, 1 November, I opened a ticket (9765093) stating that
        I wasn't sure why my account was disabled and that I would like to
        know. They had sent me an email telling me that my account had been
        disabled, but the email only listed a vague list of reasons that could
        have caused the ban, and I didn't feel that I had done any of them.
      </p>

      <h2>3 November <small>2 days</small></h2>

      <p>
        On 3 November, two days later, Discord got back to me and let me know
        that I had received an email stating why my account was disabled
        (false) and that they had reviewed my ban and would not be reinstating
        my account.
      </p>

      <p>
        The same day, I responded to their email, stating that their
        explanation wasn't good enough and that I hadn't done anything
        wrong. I demanded they give me an actual reason and reinstate my
        account.
      </p>

      <h2>6 November <small>5 days</small></h2>

      <p>
        Three days go by with no response from Discord. On 6 November, I send
        another response to their email, reiterating my desires and asking
        that I at least be able to transfer power of my larger servers if they
        insist on being corrupt.
      </p>

      <h2>12 November <small>11 days</small></h2>

      <p>
        Another six days without a peep from Discord. 12 November: I send yet
        another response, reiterating what I had said in previous emails and
        asking to be put in contact with a GDPR officer to get the data I
        want.
      </p>

      <h2>14 November <small>13 days</small></h2>

      <p>
        After two more days, Discord <em>still</em> has <strong>not</strong> responded outside of
        the initial email I received. On 14 November, I file a new ticket
        (9984772) and mention my previous ticket number and restate that I
        would like a reason why my account was banned and to have my account
        reinstated, considering I hadn't actually done anything besides <em>use
        their official client</em>.
      </p>

      <h2>17 November <small>16 days</small></h2>

      <p>
        After three days, on 17 November, the new ticket gets a
        response. Discord gives me the same list of reasons (a list of bullet
        points that count as "spam and/or platform abuse") and assure me that
        they understand "you may not have malicious intent, [but] we have to
        protect Discord as a whole, and this behavio[u]r can hurt Discord and
        its users." They also go on to mention that as a "one-time gesture",
        they "went ahead" (past tense) and lifted the ban on my account.
      </p>

      <p>
        Hooray, I guess. I go to log in to Discord and it turns out that was a
        lie. My account is still disabled. I figure maybe it needs some time
        to propagate the change, but after hours and then days of trying, my
        account remains disabled. During these initial attempts on 17
        November, I sent a response to Discord, stating that I would like to
        know the real reason I was banned, since what I was doing while I was
        banned wasn't spam or platform abuse, it was closing old DMs manually
        with the official client, a supported use-case. I also made note that my
        account had not been unbanned.
      </p>

      <h2>18 November <small>17 days</small></h2>

      <p>
        On 18 November, my account is still banned despite Discord saying they
        would lift the ban, so I send a quick response asking when the ban
        will be lifted.
      </p>

      <h2>19 November <small>18 days</small></h2>

      <p>
        On 19 November, I ask again, noting that this is the third time I've
        replied to this ticket and still not received a response.
      </p>

      <h2>20 November <small>19 days</small></h2>

      <p>
        On 20 November, I open yet another new ticket (10088193), reference
        the old one, and ask why I haven't been unbanned, demanding that they
        honour their word and lift my ban.
      </p>

      <h2>25 November <small>24 days</small></h2>

      <p>
        On 25 November, <em>eight days</em> after I was told my account would be
        unbanned and <em>twenty-four days</em> after the ban in question, I still
        have not heard from Discord. I was (and am still) banned for doing
        nothing wrong. Discord did not deign to reply to my last ticket at
        all, but I'm filing another one today (25 Nov, 10166788). I will
        continue to update this log of communications as time goes on.
      </p>
    </section>
  

</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://annaclemens.io/discord</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25214777</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 22:01:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Ten Commandments of Egoless Programming]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 11 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25213591">thread link</a>) | @kiyanwang
<br/>
November 25, 2020 | https://blog.codonomics.com/2020/11/ten-commandments-of-egoless-programming.html?m=1 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.codonomics.com/2020/11/ten-commandments-of-egoless-programming.html?m=1">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="post-body-1360687395129563554" itemprop="articleBody">
<p><span>We are nothing but the values we carry. All through my life thus far, I tried to influence people around me with the virtues I value. Thanks to some good reading habits I had inculcated, and the fortune of being in good community of peers and mentors alike, I managed to have read some real good books. This post is about the 10 commands of egoless programming in Weinberg's book. I shall explain the commandments based on my experience here.</span></p><p data-pm-slice="1 1 []"><span>So very many decades ago, Gerald M. Weinberg authored&nbsp;<a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2229333.Psychology_of_Computer_Programming"><u>The Psychology of Computer Programming</u></a>. In it, he listed <strong>The Ten Commandments of&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Egoless_programming"><strong><u>Egoless Programming</u></strong></a>, which remains relevant even today for us as not just programmers but as team-members.</span></p><p><span>Weinberg is regarded as a pioneer in taking a people-centric approach to computing, and his work endures as a good guide to intelligence, skill, teamwork, and problem-solving power of a developer. When they appear to inspire and instruct, we find that they can apply to just about every business area, and even to life itself.</span></p><p><span>Here are the 10 important lessons developers, project managers, and stakeholders would do well to keep in mind during the project lifecycle.</span></p><ol><li><p><span><strong>Understand and accept that you will make mistakes.</strong><br>Mistakes are rarely fatal in our industry, so find them early, before they make it into production, learn from them, and move on.</span></p></li><li><p><span><strong>You are not your code.</strong><br>The point of a review is to find problems. Don't take it personally when one is found. Remember&nbsp;<a href="https://olxpeople.atlassian.net/wiki/spaces/OPETE/pages/940179552">my words</a>, “To err is only human, repeating it is what makes you either evil or insane”.</span></p></li><li><p><span><strong>No matter how much "karate" you know, someone else will always know more.</strong><br>Seek and accept input from others. You can learn new techniques if you just ask. Always remember, it is never too late to learn.</span></p></li><li><p><span><strong>Don't rewrite code without consultation.</strong><br>It is always a good idea to pair-up and have conversations on the code that you are tempted to re-write because you think it is bad. Your risks are much lesser if the code is backed by Unit tests. The least you can do is get it code reviewed before pushing code to main-stream branch.</span></p></li><li><p><span><strong>Treat people who know less than you with respect and patience.</strong><br>Don’t be a bully. Seriously, just don’t be one. Grow up!</span></p></li><li><p><span><strong>The only constant in the world is change.</strong><br>Things change, sometime for better and sometimes for worse. There are some things in your control which you can leverage to change things for better. Be the change that you wish for good. Also be willing to accept change for the overall good of the team.</span></p></li><li><p><span><strong>The only true authority stems from knowledge, not from position.</strong><br>Don't wield a title like a badge of "rightness."&nbsp;<span>If you want to be loved and respected in an egoless environment, cultivate knowledge. It may or may not lead to authority, but sure leads to love and respect from others. </span></span></p></li><li><p><span><strong>Fight for what you believe, but gracefully accept defeat.</strong><br>Open culture is not being polite in the front and back-bitching in the back. Rise up, voice your concerns, be heard, and make your point of view by doing your homework, all with an intent to help and learn otherwise. You can’t accept defeat, if you carry the burden of your ego. </span></p></li><li><p><span><strong>Don't be "the guy in the room".</strong><br>There are so many beer buddies, movie mates, cigarette companions, and what not, who can come together or fight fiercely on any non-professional topics by respecting each other; but definitely not discuss and debate openly, work related matters for team’s betterment. Just don’t be that guy in the room.  </span></p></li><li><p><span><strong>Critique code instead of people – be kind to the coder, not to the code.</strong><br>Pour your frustration on lifeless things instead of on emotional beings. Corollary, if someone were to show his frustrations on you instead of your work, be a little polite to him, discounting it as emotional down syndrome. I have been on both sides, and so will you sometime. Let us support one another and grow together.</span></p></li></ol><p><span>Just to re-iterate, these commandments are still incredibly relevant. Put it to deliberate practice and with time they will bring out a better developer and co-worker in you.</span></p><p><span>You can get this book from <a href="https://amzn.to/3lZvXr9" target="_blank">Amazon</a>.</span></p>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.codonomics.com/2020/11/ten-commandments-of-egoless-programming.html?m=1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25213591</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 19:59:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[This is how Google will collapse]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 62 | Comments 64 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25213493">thread link</a>) | @partingshots
<br/>
November 25, 2020 | http://www.sfu.ca/olc/blog/engage/how-google-will-collapse | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.sfu.ca/olc/blog/engage/how-google-will-collapse">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p><em>Previously published in&nbsp;<a href="https://hackernoon.com/how-google-collapsed-b6ffa82198ee">HACKERNOON</a>. Originally written by SFU Masters of Digital Media student Daniel Colin James.&nbsp;Re-published with permission of the writer.</em></p>
<p><em>Illustration Credit:&nbsp;</em><a href="https://mandelasmith.artstation.com/">Mandela Smith</a></p>
<hr>
<p>Google made almost all its money from ads. It was a booming business — until it wasn’t. Here’s how things looked right before the most spectacular crash the technology industry had ever seen.</p>
<div>
<h3>The crumbling of Google’s cornerstone</h3>
<p>Search was Google’s only unambiguous win, as well as its&nbsp;<a href="http://www.cnbc.com/2017/01/26/googlealphabet-reports-fourth-quarter-2016-earnings-q4.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.cnbc.com/2017/01/26/googlealphabet-reports-fourth-quarter-2016-earnings-q4.html">primary source of revenue</a>, so when Amazon&nbsp;<a href="http://www.geekwire.com/2017/amazon-continues-grow-lead-google-starting-point-online-shoppers/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.geekwire.com/2017/amazon-continues-grow-lead-google-starting-point-online-shoppers/">rapidly surpassed Google</a>&nbsp;as the top product search destination, Google’s foundations began to falter.&nbsp;As&nbsp;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/08/11/google-isnt-safe-from-yahoos-fate/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/08/11/google-isnt-safe-from-yahoos-fate/">many noted</a>&nbsp;at the time, the online advertising industry experienced a major shift from search to discovery in the mid-2010s.</p>
<p>While Google protected its monopoly on the dying search advertising market, Facebook — Google’s biggest competitor in the online advertising space — got on the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.emarketer.com/Article/Google-Facebook-Increase-Their-Grip-on-Digital-Ad-Market/1015417" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://www.emarketer.com/Article/Google-Facebook-Increase-Their-Grip-on-Digital-Ad-Market/1015417">right side of the trend</a>&nbsp;and dominated online advertising with its in-feed native display advertising.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.sfu.ca/olc/sites/default/files/1.1.jpeg" width="533" height="239"></p>
<p><em><span>The people who turned to Amazon over Google? <a href="https://cdn.geekwire.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Screen-Shot-2017-01-13-at-10.40.08-AM.png">The 18-29 led the way</a></span></em></p>
<p>In late 2015, Apple — Google’s main competitor in the mobile space — added a feature to their phones and tablets that allowed users to block ads.</p>
<p>Devices running iOS were responsible for an&nbsp;<a href="http://appleinsider.com/articles/15/05/27/apples-ios-drives-75-of-googles-mobile-advertising-revenue" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://appleinsider.com/articles/15/05/27/apples-ios-drives-75-of-googles-mobile-advertising-revenue">estimated 75%</a>&nbsp;of Google’s revenue from mobile search ads, so by making this move, Apple was simultaneously weighing in decisively on the great ad blocking debate of the 2010s and dealing a substantial blow to the&nbsp;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/07/24/apple-lays-the-groundwork-to-kill-online-advertising/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/07/24/apple-lays-the-groundwork-to-kill-online-advertising/">future of online advertising</a>.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.sfu.ca/olc/sites/default/files/1.3.jpeg" width="533" height="196"></p>
<p><em><sub>The rising number of users blocking ads on mobile showed no signs of slowing down</sub></em></p>
</div>
<div>
<p>A year later, as the internet went mobile, so too did ad blocking. The number of people blocking ads on a mobile device grew&nbsp;<a href="https://pagefair.com/blog/2016/mobile-adblocking-report/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://pagefair.com/blog/2016/mobile-adblocking-report/">102% from 2015 to 2016</a>; by the end of 2016, an estimated 16% of smartphone users globally were&nbsp;<a href="https://pagefair.com/blog/2016/mobile-adblocking-report/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://pagefair.com/blog/2016/mobile-adblocking-report/">blocking ads</a>&nbsp;when browsing the internet on a mobile device. The number was&nbsp;<a href="https://www.emarketer.com/Article/Why-More-than-Quarter-of-US-Internet-Users-Block-Ads/1014333" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://www.emarketer.com/Article/Why-More-than-Quarter-of-US-Internet-Users-Block-Ads/1014333">as high as 25%</a>&nbsp;for desktop and laptop users in the United States, a country that accounted for&nbsp;<a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/266250/regional-distribution-of-googles-revenue/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/266250/regional-distribution-of-googles-revenue/">47% of Google’s revenue</a>.</p>
<p>The people most likely to block ads were also the most valuable demographic:&nbsp;<a href="http://marketingland.com/ad-blocker-usage-highest-among-key-advertiser-demos-millennials-and-high-earners-143546" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://marketingland.com/ad-blocker-usage-highest-among-key-advertiser-demos-millennials-and-high-earners-143546"><em>millennials and high earners</em></a><em>.</em></p>
<p><em><img src="http://www.sfu.ca/olc/sites/default/files/1.4.png" width="533" height="300"><br></em></p>
</div>
<div>
<p><em><sub>Young users are a good indicator for the future of technology, and&nbsp;<a href="http://marketingland.com/ad-blocker-usage-highest-among-key-advertiser-demos-millennials-and-high-earners-143546" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://marketingland.com/ad-blocker-usage-highest-among-key-advertiser-demos-millennials-and-high-earners-143546">they were heavy users of ad blocking&nbsp;software</a></sub></em></p>
<p><strong>Internet users had spoken, and they hated ads.</strong></p>
<p>In early 2017, Google announced its plans to build an ad blocker into its popular Google Chrome browser. Google’s ad blocker would only block ads that were deemed unacceptable by the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.thedrum.com/news/2016/09/16/procter-gamble-unilever-google-facebook-and-more-form-coalition-better-ads" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.thedrum.com/news/2016/09/16/procter-gamble-unilever-google-facebook-and-more-form-coalition-better-ads">Coalition For Better Ads</a>, effectively allowing the company to use its dominant web browser to strengthen its already dominant advertising business.</p>
<p>Even after making this desperate and&nbsp;<a href="http://fortune.com/2017/04/20/google-ad-blocker/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://fortune.com/2017/04/20/google-ad-blocker/">legally questionable</a>&nbsp;move, it would quickly become clear to Google that even though ads were getting better, ad blocking numbers would&nbsp;<a href="http://adage.com/article/digital/ad-blocking-increases-consumers-improving/305978/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://adage.com/article/digital/ad-blocking-increases-consumers-improving/305978/">continue to rise</a>. Google had given even more people a small taste of what an ad-free internet experience could look like.&nbsp;<strong>The company discovered that it wasn’t just annoying ads that people didn’t like; it was ads in general.</strong></p>
<p><strong><img src="http://www.sfu.ca/olc/sites/default/files/1.5.png" width="533" height="300"></strong></p>
<p><em><sub>The advertising industry trying to figure out why people hated ads so much</sub></em><strong><br></strong></p>
</div>
<p>A key platform where Google served ads was YouTube, which it bought in 2006 and quickly turned into one of its biggest entities. But even with a&nbsp;<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/youtube-stats_n_2922543.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/youtube-stats_n_2922543.html">sixth of the world</a>&nbsp;visiting this video-sharing behemoth every month, YouTube&nbsp;<a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/viewers-dont-add-up-to-profit-for-youtube-1424897967" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/viewers-dont-add-up-to-profit-for-youtube-1424897967">never became profitable</a>. In an attempt to combat the effect of ad blockers, YouTube launched an ad-free subscription model in late 2015, but the subscription numbers were&nbsp;<a href="http://www.theverge.com/2016/11/2/13498470/youtube-red-subscribers-video-content-music" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.theverge.com/2016/11/2/13498470/youtube-red-subscribers-video-content-music">underwhelming</a>.</p>
<p>YouTube’s already insurmountable problems multiplied in early 2017 as advertisers&nbsp;<a href="http://www.fiercepharma.com/marketing/google-scrambling-for-solutions-after-advertiser-departures-youtube" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.fiercepharma.com/marketing/google-scrambling-for-solutions-after-advertiser-departures-youtube">began to pull out amid ad placement controversies</a>, and huge revenue generators began to&nbsp;<a href="http://www.ibtimes.com/pewdiepie-starts-weekly-twitch-show-uploads-youtube-over-party-video-2523797" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.ibtimes.com/pewdiepie-starts-weekly-twitch-show-uploads-youtube-over-party-video-2523797">leave the site</a>. Even those who weren’t blocking ads had trained themselves to ignore them entirely. Researchers dubbed this phenomenon “<a href="http://www.tobiipro.com/fields-of-use/marketing-consumer-research/advertising/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.tobiipro.com/fields-of-use/marketing-consumer-research/advertising/">banner blindness</a>”. The average banner ad was clicked on by a dismal&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thinkwithgoogle.com/intl/en-gb/planning-tool/display-benchmarks/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://www.thinkwithgoogle.com/intl/en-gb/planning-tool/display-benchmarks/">0.06% of viewers</a>, and of those clicks, roughly&nbsp;<a href="http://www.goldspotmedia.com/fat-finger-report/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.goldspotmedia.com/fat-finger-report/">50% were accidental</a>.</p>
<p>Research showed that&nbsp;<a href="http://www.bannersnack.com/blog/build-trust-display-ads/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.bannersnack.com/blog/build-trust-display-ads/">54% of users</a>&nbsp;reported a lack of trust as their reason for not clicking banner ads and 33% found them completely&nbsp;<a href="http://downloads.pagefair.com/reports/adblocking_goes_mainstream_2014_report.pdf" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://downloads.pagefair.com/reports/adblocking_goes_mainstream_2014_report.pdf">intolerable</a>. These figures painted a pretty grim picture for the sustainability of online advertising, but especially for Google’s position within the industry.</p>
<p><em>Google’s mighty engine had started to sputter.</em></p>
<p><strong>A chance to pivot, and how Google missed&nbsp;it</strong></p>
<p>If losing a major portion of their audience and annoying the rest wasn’t bad enough, Google also failed to get ahead of one of the biggest shifts in technology’s history. They recognized the importance of artificial intelligence but their approach missed the mark. Since Google’s search pillar had become unstable, a lot was riding on the company’s strategy for artificial intelligence.</p>
<p><em>“We will move from mobile first to an AI first&nbsp;world.”</em></p>
<p>Google’s then-CEO Sundar Pichai&nbsp;<a href="https://blog.google/topics/inside-google/this-years-founders-letter/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://blog.google/topics/inside-google/this-years-founders-letter/">famously predicted</a>&nbsp;in 2016 that “<em>the next big step will be for the very concept of the ‘device’ to fade away”&nbsp;</em>and that<em>&nbsp;“over time, the computer itself — whatever its form factor — will be an intelligent assistant helping you through your day. We will move from mobile first to an AI first world.”</em></p>
<p>Google’s ability to acknowledge the coming trend and still fail to land in front of it reminded many observers of its catastrophic failures in the booming industries of social media and instant messaging.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.sfu.ca/olc/sites/default/files/1.6.jpeg" width="533" height="296"></p>
<p><em><sub>Sundar Pichai wondering how to monetize a virtual assistant</sub></em></p>
<p><strong>Google vs.&nbsp;Amazon</strong></p>
<p>Meanwhile, in 2014, Amazon released a product called Amazon Echo, a small speaker that could sit in your home and answer questions, perform tasks, and buy things online for you. The Echo was a&nbsp;<a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/amazon-echo-success-could-spell-big-trouble-for-google-2017-1" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.businessinsider.com/amazon-echo-success-could-spell-big-trouble-for-google-2017-1">smash success</a>. Google released its copycat product, Google Home, two years later, but it was already&nbsp;<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/jan/22/home-battleground-amazon-google-voice-technology" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/jan/22/home-battleground-amazon-google-voice-technology">too late to catch up</a>, and had no clear revenue strategy.</p>
<p>Alexa — the assistant that lived inside the Echo — on the other hand, was quickly integrated into several products and services, and its monetization model was clear, viable, and most importantly future-friendly. The Echo made it easy to order products through Amazon, and every time someone used an Echo to purchase something, Amazon made money.</p>
<p>Google extended the reach of their virtual assistant by building it into Android, but doing so still didn’t provide an answer for how the technology would generate enough revenue to sustain Google’s expanding repertoire of expensive innovations.</p>
<p>Google’s ads relied on screens, yet voice interaction subverted screens entirely. Google briefly tried playing audio ads with the Google Home, but consumers were&nbsp;<a href="https://www.engadget.com/2017/03/17/google-home-ads-bad-precedent/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://www.engadget.com/2017/03/17/google-home-ads-bad-precedent/">far from receptive</a>. Investors&nbsp;<a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/google-ceo-sundar-pichai-responds-to-concerns-over-monetizing-voice-search-2017-1" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.businessinsider.com/google-ceo-sundar-pichai-responds-to-concerns-over-monetizing-voice-search-2017-1">started to voice their concerns in 2017</a>, but Sundar Pichai told them not to worry, leaving them to assume that Google would use their age-old strategy and analyze users’ voice searches so that users could be shown more suitable ads on devices with screens.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.sfu.ca/olc/sites/default/files/1.7.jpeg" width="533" height="336"></p>
<p><em><sub>Alexa celebrating its victory over Google</sub></em></p>
<p>Headlines in early 2017&nbsp;<a href="https://www.wired.com/2017/01/ces-alexa-in-everything/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://www.wired.com/2017/01/ces-alexa-in-everything/">proclaimed</a>&nbsp;that “Alexa Just Conquered CES. The World is Next.” Amazon then made their technology&nbsp;<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/article/amazon-opens-echo-microphone-tech-to-third-party-alexa-devices/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.zdnet.com/article/amazon-opens-echo-microphone-tech-to-third-party-alexa-devices/">available</a>&nbsp;to third party manufacturers, putting even more distance between the two companies. Amazon&nbsp;<a href="http://www.investors.com/news/technology/amazon-confronts-microsoft-google-ibm-in-cloud-computing-wars/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.investors.com/news/technology/amazon-confronts-microsoft-google-ibm-in-cloud-computing-wars/">had already beaten Google once before</a>, holding 54% of the cloud computing market (compared to Google’s 3%) in 2016, and they were just getting started. By early 2017, Amazon&nbsp;<a href="http://www.cnbc.com/2017/03/31/competing-with-amazon-is-crushing-retailers.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.cnbc.com/2017/03/31/competing-with-amazon-is-crushing-retailers.html">had begun closing in</a>&nbsp;on&nbsp;<a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/groupthink/2017/02/03/amazon-go-is-the-future-plus-4-reasons-why-amazon-might-just-win-retail" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/groupthink/2017/02/03/amazon-go-is-the-future-plus-4-reasons-why-amazon-might-just-win-retail">the entire</a>&nbsp;<a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/retailers-are-going-bankrupt-at-a-staggering-rate-2017-4" rel="noopener" target="_blank" data-href="http://www.businessinsider.com/retailers-are-going-bankrupt-at-a-staggering-rate-2017-4">retail industry</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Ads weren’t&nbsp;forever</strong></p>
<p>At its peak, Google had a massive and loyal user-base across a staggering number of products, but advertising revenue was the glue that held everything together. As the numbers waned, Google’s core began to buckle under the weight of its vast empire.</p>
<p>Google was a driving force in the technology industry ever since its disruptive entry in 1998. But in a world where people despised ads, Google’s business model was not innovation-friendly, and they missed several opportunities to pivot, ultimately rendering their numerous grand and ambitious projects unsustainable. Innovation costs money, and Google’s main stream of revenue had started to dry up.</p>
<p>In a few short years, Google had gone from a fun, commonplace verb to a reminder of how quickly a giant can fall.</p>
<h2><img src="http://www.sfu.ca/~sfuolc/OLC/Website/Forall/About-Author-Top.png" width="517" height="16"></h2>
<p><em><img src="http://www.sfu.ca/olc/sites/default/files/1.2.jpg" width="90" height="90"></em><em>Daniel is a Master of Digital Media student, currently completing his internship as a product manager at a Vancouver-based blockchain startup called Covalent. Daniel likes writing code and writing words, and he’s not sure what’s next, but he’s excited about it. You can find out what he’s up to now by checking out&nbsp;</em><em><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/danielcolinjames/">his LinkedIn page</a></em><em>.</em></p>
<hr>
<h2><strong>Beyond the Article</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>Check out how Daniel's article led him to get recommended by Google's VP of Design <a href="https://danielcolinjames.com/how-google-collapsed">here</a></li>
<li>See some of his other work on his <a href="https://danielcolinjames.com/">portfolio site</a></li>
</ul>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.sfu.ca/olc/blog/engage/how-google-will-collapse</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25213493</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 19:51:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Sit Straight Up: How Dieting Is Like Posture]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 17 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25211957">thread link</a>) | @pbw
<br/>
November 25, 2020 | https://www.kmeme.com/2020/11/sit-up-straight-dieting-is-like-posture.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.kmeme.com/2020/11/sit-up-straight-dieting-is-like-posture.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="post-body-6117893139176476722" itemprop="description articleBody">
<p>After years of struggling to lose weight, I've lost 30 pounds this year. My number one takeaway has been realizing I need to be mindful of what I eat all day, from eyes open to going to bed.</p>

<p>For years I'd been giving up single things. No soda or juice. No desserts. No chips. No fries. Yet incredibly, whatever I did it didn't make a dent, at least not for long. Which seemed totally impossible.</p>

<p>I'd just cut out thousands of calories! And... nothing. Eventually, I realized it was like pushing down on a waterbed. I'd just end up eating the calories somewhere else. Automatically and without fail.</p>

<div><p><a href="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-U2RZSjyEQRU/X8B4u5G8aVI/AAAAAAAFHHQ/_OawWuIiGL0lKvmMWlJnnVeqdd-SUMzJACLcBGAsYHQ/image.png"><img data-original-height="381" data-original-width="750" height="326" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-U2RZSjyEQRU/X8B4u5G8aVI/AAAAAAAFHHQ/_OawWuIiGL0lKvmMWlJnnVeqdd-SUMzJACLcBGAsYHQ/w640-h326/image.png" width="640"></a></p><p>Maintaining good posture is easy: when you notice you are slumping, sit up straight. The hard part is noticing. What's going on at that moment when you start to slump? The exact moment when your head tilts down or your back starts to curve? Where is your mind right at that moment? How are you letting this happen? I mean what the hell, who is minding the store here?</p></div>

<p>I feel like that's exactly where my mind was when I was making a late-night snack, or grabbing another handful of chips, or digging into another piece of pizza. I was there for those moments in a way, but also not there.</p><p>Honestly, sometimes I felt like a spectator. I'd look at the snack I fixed myself and say, “Boy I should not be eating this,” then I’d sit down and eat it. Afterward, I'd say, “I should not have eaten that”. Can I talk to a manager, is there no one in charge here?</p>

<p>What finally worked was pushing the desire to lose weight down deeply into every fiber of my being, so in those moments I was present, the “I” that I wanted to be was present. Once present, the choice was actually easy. If I'm trying to lose weight, which I am, should I eat this handful of M&amp;M's? No, no I should not.</p>

<p>How to stay present? I did mindfulness meditation for several years, and I think mindfulness is what we are talking about. It's the opposite of mindlessness, and mindlessness is the enemy. What they don't advertise is there are ways to increase mindfulness without meditation. They are just... a little weird.</p>

<p>When you have an itch, even an intense one, just observe it for a while. See what happens. Often it will go away. If it's unbearable then scratch it, but not every time, and not right away.</p>

<p>If you are doing anything rushed, like writing or cleaning or typing your password in wrong, once in a while do it really slow. Like impossibly slow. The other day I was tearing a perforated piece of paper such that I waited for each single pop, then pulled it a bit more. One time I shaved so slowly that I was enjoying listening to the individual whiskers snap.</p>

<p>The goal is not just “do things slowly”. The goal is to catch yourself doing something on auto-pilot and intervene with some deliberate action. To be aware of what you were doing, then modify what you were doing mindfully. It's best to do this for different activities, sporadically. Sense that the auto-pilot has taken over, then do something to disrupt that automatic behavior.</p><p><a href="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-fievTLupx7M/X76Ld1UoftI/AAAAAAAFHG8/qIy8zP7hJ3IFRLtE0MkjzJQpY7YMIONlgCLcBGAsYHQ/image.png"><img data-original-height="282" data-original-width="425" height="424" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-fievTLupx7M/X76Ld1UoftI/AAAAAAAFHG8/qIy8zP7hJ3IFRLtE0MkjzJQpY7YMIONlgCLcBGAsYHQ/w640-h424/image.png" width="640"></a></p>

<p>Sometimes if I'm on a mostly empty road, but I'm following someone too closely, I'll slow WAY down, until they are far in front of me. I've learned that for me this “following behavior” is very automatic.</p>

<p>After there's a gap I resume my exact same speed, but now I'm a constant five seconds behind. It's less stressful and safer, and the only downside is I'll arrive a whopping five seconds after they will. Notice you are doing something, then modify what you are doing.</p>

<p>When I finally put it together there was no grit your teeth effort required, it was just being consistently mindful of my goal, and therefore mindful as to whether my behavior was aligned with my goal. It required a light touch, not a heavy lift. If “I” was there, I'd make the right decision. If I was on auto-pilot, I'd make the wrong decision. So my goal was no longer really to lose weight, it was simply to always be there.</p>

<p><b>Related Posts on kmeme</b></p>
<ul><li><a href="https://www.kmeme.com/2020/09/lose-weight-with-nightmare-fuel.html">The Hungry Ancestor Diet</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.kmeme.com/2019/09/mindfulness-is-driving-without-texting.html">Mindfulness is driving without texting</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.kmeme.com/2016/03/mindfull-reps.html">Mindul Reps</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.kmeme.com/2016/07/waking-up.html">Waking Up</a></li>
</ul>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.kmeme.com/2020/11/sit-up-straight-dieting-is-like-posture.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25211957</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 17:49:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What is Breach and Attack Simulation]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 19 | Comments 6 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25209359">thread link</a>) | @dkccit
<br/>
November 25, 2020 | https://www.cloudcape.de/en/what-is-breach-and-attack-simulation/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cloudcape.de/en/what-is-breach-and-attack-simulation/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-id="35cb009c" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="theme-post-content.default">
				<div>
			<p>In recent years, more and more providers of so-called Breach and Attack Simulation platforms have emerged in the market. In 2017, Gartner included Breach and Attack Simulation as a new category in the “Hype Cycle for Threat-Facing Technologies” and it was even attested that Breach and Attack Simulation has the potential to become mainstream within the next 10 years. Some even speak of a technological revolution that will fundamentally change the way companies analyze their security status in the future.</p>
<p>In this blog article I would like to answer the following questions about Breach and Attack Simulation:</p>
<ul>
<li>What is behind this new technology?</li>
<li>What problems does BAS try to solve?</li>
<li>For which companies are BAS solutions particularly suitable?</li>
<li>Which solutions are on the market and how do they differ from each other?</li>
<li>How does Breach and Attack Simulation relate to classical <a href="https://www.cloudcape.de/en/penetration-testing/">penetration testing of enterprise networks</a>?</li>
</ul>
<p>So, here we go!</p>
<h2>What is Breach and Attack Simulation?</h2>
<p>Breach and Attack Simulation is a new way of testing IT security efforts that mimics real-world attack actions to determine if the company’s various security measures actually serve their purpose. There are three different types of BAS solutions:</p>
<p><strong>Agent-based BAS solutions:</strong></p>
<p>Agent-based solutions are the simplest form of BAS. Agents are deployed across the LAN and vulnerabilities are identified to determine which routes are open to a potential attacker to move around the network. An agent-based BAS solution is very similar to vulnerability scanning, but offers much more context.</p>
<p><strong>BAS solutions based on “malicious” traffic</strong></p>
<p>These BAS solutions generate intrusive traffic within the network between dedicated virtual machines that serve as targets for a wide range of attack scenarios. An overview is then created of which events have not been detected and blocked by the company’s own security controls. As with agent-based BAS solutions, you get information about how an attacker could move if he enters the network.</p>
<p><strong>Cloud-based BAS solutions</strong></p>
<p>BAS solutions that are cloud-based are the closest to a real attack. They simulate numerous attack scenarios from the outside via different entry points. (so-called multi-vector attacks) and thus also the network perimeter of the company. The cloud platforms are fed with the latest threats from a wide variety of sources and are therefore always very up-to-date. Being SaaS solutions, they can be implemented very quickly.</p>
<h2>What problems do BAS tools attempt to solve?</h2>
<p>BAS solutions give companies an answer to the question “Do our cybersecurity programs really work? Large companies invest heavily in security products, but still do not have the confidence that they can withstand increasingly sophisticated attacks. For financial and practical reasons it is also not possible to test entire enterprise production environments permanently and manually for security vulnerabilities. Breach and Attack Simulation fills exactly this gap and allows companies to get more out of their existing security solutions by enabling continuous testing of the enterprise network at low risk.</p>
<h2>For which companies are BAS solutions suitable?</h2>
<p>If you have a look around the BAS market, you will find that many offers are tailored to large enterprise customers with high security requirements, such as financial institutions and insurance companies. It is not surprising that Breach and Attack Simulation is especially interesting for this kind of companies. They typically have numerous security products in use, a dynamic IT landscape and a high level of IT maturity. In addition, there are high demands on IT security and high compliance pressure. High-end solutions like Breach and Attack Simulation are predestined for this environment.</p>
<p>However, there is also the possibility for smaller companies to use BAS technology. Some solution providers have made their BAS tools multi-tenant ready so that smaller companies can also benefit from them via partner companies.</p>
<p>Which products are on the market and how do they differ from each other? In the still very young BAS market, a number of companies and start-ups, mainly from Israel and the USA, are thriving. In the following I would like to introduce some selected solution providers:</p>
<p><strong>SafeBreach (Israel/USA)</strong></p>
<p>SafeBreach was founded in 2014 in Tel Aviv and is therefore one of the “older” players on the market. SafeBreach describes their product as a Continuous Security Validating Platform, which takes over the role of a virtual ethical hacker. The platform consists of two components: the cloud management console and on-premise virtual machines called “Breach Simulators”, which play so-called “War Games” among each other. SafeBreach’s solution is in fact based on “malicious” traffic that flows between the Breach Simulators themselves and the cloud.</p>
<p>SafeBreach is the pioneer in the BAS industry and now has an extensive “Hacker’s Playbook” with thousands of attack methods, which is constantly updated by the SafeBreach Lab.</p>
<p><strong>Cymulate (Israel)</strong></p>
<p>Cymulate was also founded in Israel in 2016. In 2018, Cymulate was named a “Cool Vendor” by Gartner and is probably the platform in the BAS market that gets the biggest hype. Among its successes, Cymulate has raised considerable amounts of funds from well-known venture capitalists. Cymulate advertises with particularly easy deployment and operation. Only a single agent is required in the network itself. The platform offers numerous attack vectors (e-mail gateway, web gateway, web application firewall, lateral movement, data loss prevention and endpoint security control) and can therefore simulate an Advanced Persistent Threat (APT). Great are the integrations to other security products, such as <strong><a href="https://www.cloudcape.de/en/vulnerability-management-as-a-service-en/">vulnerability management</a></strong>, SIEM and EDR solutions. Cymulate is very pricy. Currently, the <strong><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/marketplace/pp/B0882VSXXY?ref_=srh_res_product_title">7-Vector bundle costs 7000 USD per month via the AWS Marketplace</a></strong>. However, there is also a light version with fewer attack vectors available. On Youtube, you can get a good impression of the platform:</p>
<p><iframe title="Cymulate Immediate Threats Intelligence Module - Training" width="1200" height="675" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TzEdImSxNc0?start=29&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>

<p><strong>XM Cyber (Israel)</strong></p>
<p>XM Cyber is in my opinion another notable player in the BAS market. Since its foundation in 2016 by top leaders of the Israeli cyber intelligence community, the company has gained some attention and is currently expanding globally. The HaXM platform is relatively easy to roll out. A lightweight software agent must be installed on all critical assets, and the platform itself is delivered as Software-as-a-Service. For very security-conscious companies, the solution can also be set up on-premise. The simulations are performed in three steps:</p>
<ul>
<li>First, all critical assets are selected</li>
<li>Secondly, attacks are simulated and all attack vectors to critical assets are revealed (this is done very clearly in the platform’s “Battle Ground” dialogue box)</li>
<li>Lastly, detailed remediation reports and security evaluations can be exported</li>
</ul>
<p>This 3-minute demo of XM Cyber gives a very good impression of the platform and shows the impressive user interface.</p>
<p><iframe title="XM Cyber Breach and Attack Simulation Demo Video" width="1200" height="675" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/inDj1MFxzvg?start=73&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>

<h2>How does Breach and Attack Simulation relate to manual penetration testing?</h2>
<p>The interesting question remains whether Breach and Attack Simulation can replace traditional penetration testing of networks in the future. Currently, the market adoption of Breach and Attack Simulation is not very widespread. As a penetration tester, I believe that you will not have to fear for your job any time soon. In addition, compliance requirements still demand the conducting of classic penetration tests. Last but not least, Breach and Attack Simulation is also a question of your budget – many small and medium-sized companies are already struggling to invest in a small penetration test, so it is quite doubtful if these companies will invest in an expensive BAS solution.</p>
<p>Some BAS tools on the market only offer attack scenarios that do not include exploits and should therefore be supplemented with manual pentesting in case of doubt. It should not be forgotten that a simulation remains a simulation and collected data is analyzed externally to determine what would happen in reality. This increases the probability of false positives and false negatives.</p>
<p>Despite the obstacles that BAS solution providers still have to overcome, I am very confident that Breach and Attack Simulation will, as it matures, greatly reduce the need for traditional network pentesting. With good BAS solutions, it is possible to “execute” exploits that cannot cause any damage. A conscientious pentester would not even address such exploits with typical pentesting tools, because there is always the danger of damaging the customer environment. In addition, Breach and Attack Simulation provides consistent results regardless of a person’s abilities, continuously and not just as a snapshot. I am very confident that soon there will be pentest-as-a-service offerings powered by Breach and Attack Simulation that will be available to organizations of all sizes.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>It is worth keeping an eye on the developments on the BAS market. In the future, the importance of BAS solutions will most likely increase significantly. In my opinion, Breach and Attack Simulation has the potential to become a viable alternative to classical Network Penetration Testing with increasing technological maturity and decreasing costs.</p>
		</div>
				</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cloudcape.de/en/what-is-breach-and-attack-simulation/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25209359</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 14:09:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Libgen Storage Decentralization on IPFS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 269 | Comments 108 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25209246">thread link</a>) | @jerheinze
<br/>
November 25, 2020 | https://freeread.org/ipfs/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://freeread.org/ipfs/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-md-component="container">
      
        
      
      
        
      
      <main data-md-component="main">
        <div>
          
            
              
            
            
              
            
          
          <div>
            <article>
              
                
                
                  
                
                
                
<p>IPFS is here. IPFS is a de-centralized file and webhosting protocol founded on ideals of freedom and openness. The Library Genesis collection is live on IPFS as of today, accessible via <a href="http://libgen.rs/">libgen.rs</a> and <a href="https://libgen.fun/">libgen.fun</a>. IPFS is like BitTorrent but has a single global swarm, and it's accessible on the web. You can learn about the IPFS project from <a href="https://ipfs.io/">IPFS.io</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/InterPlanetary_File_System">Wikipedia</a>.</p>
<p>IPFS is the next technical revolution in peer-to-peer networking, allowing people like you to share books with readers who request them. IPFS is the next best weapon in the fight against domain take-downs and internet censorship.</p>
<p>We can now each become a founding shelf for a free, global library. Let's start.</p>
<h2 id="get-started">Get started</h2>
<p>IPFS is simple. <em>Hosts</em> (you) <em>Pin</em> files (books) using <em>Content Identifiers</em> (CID Hashes) to share them on the IPFS network. CID Hashes can represent individual files or an entire folder. Pinning saves the files to your local computer so you can share them, and others can Pin them from you.</p>
<p>Each CID Hash for Library Genesis represents 1,000 books, or about 5 gigabytes of local file storage. 100 pins = 100,000 books! Who ever told you that you couldn't start your own library?</p>
<h2 id="copyright-warning">Copyright warning</h2>
<p>Before you begin, make sure you understand <a href="https://www.nolo.com/legal-encyclopedia/what-to-do-if-your-named-bit-torrent-lawsuit.html">the legal implications of hosting and sharing copyrighted material.</a></p>
<h2 id="installing-ipfs">Installing IPFS</h2>
<p>Are you a power-user or run a server? Jump to the section on <a href="#docker-for-servers">getting started with Docker.</a></p>
<p>If you're not, just install the <a href="https://ipfs.io/#install">IPFS Desktop client</a>. Make sure to read the <a href="#system-requirements">desktop system requirements.</a></p>
<h2 id="desktop-client">Desktop client</h2>
<h3 id="system-requirements">System requirements</h3>
<p>Note that IPFS Desktop client is an alpha-stage software still in development. The command line version of the software for servers/home servers is more mature.</p>
<ul>
<li>Requires internet serice provider with unlimited bandwidth. Do not install IPFS if you have a monthly bandwidth or data cap.</li>
<li>Recommended at least 16GB RAM and Intel i5 or equivalent processor</li>
<li>Recommended at least 100 mbps, gigabit connection preferred</li>
<li>Recommended <a href="#port-forwarding">port forwarding</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="get-started_1">Get started</h3>
<h4 id="pin-your-first-cid-hash">Pin your first CID Hash</h4>
<p>Click Files &gt; Import &gt; From IPFS</p>
<p>Then copy and paste in your first CID Hash containing 1,000 books (about 6GB). Once it's complete, jump to the <a href="#cid-hash-index">CID Hash index</a>.</p>
<pre><code>
bafykbzaceaeofefgje22l7rhgtcgs22m32f4ysw5nqa3ty5zawfovqam7pj2c

</code></pre>

<p><img alt="Screenshot" src="https://freeread.org/img/ipfs.2.png"></p>
<h2 id="docker-for-servers">Docker for servers</h2>
<p>Previously downloaded the Library Genesis torrents for the Library Genesis Seeding Project? Follow these steps then jump to <a href="#torrents">torrents</a>.</p>
<h3 id="system-requirements_1">System requirements</h3>
<ul>
<li>Docker (<a href="https://docs.docker.com/get-docker/">docker.com/get-docker</a>)</li>
<li>Requires internet serice provider with unlimited bandwidth. Do not install IPFS if you have a monthly bandwidth or data cap.</li>
<li>Requires between 10GB or more of hard-drive space. For more information refer to the <a href="https://cryptpad.fr/sheet/#/2/sheet/view/I5UinPRnv2LNZlMQcNODieaoo7W9L1KDbJMX36OKvdE/">CID Hash index with file sizes.</a></li>
<li>Recommended at least 16GB RAM and Intel i5 or equivalent processor</li>
<li>Recommended at least 100 mbps, gigabit connection preferred</li>
<li>Recommended <a href="#port-forwarding">port forwarding</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="get-started_2">Get started</h3>
<h4 id="create-your-docker-container">Create your docker container</h4>
<p>You can more documentation for the Go-based IPFS Docker container at <a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/ipfs/go-ipfs/">Docker Hub.</a>.</p>
<p>/export will store your downloaded files, while the books from pinned CID Hashes will be located in /ipfs/data/blocks.</p>
<pre><code>docker run -d \
--name go-ipfs \
-v $HOME/ipfs/export:/export \
-v $HOME/ipfs/data:/data/ipfs \
-p 4001:4001 \
-p 127.0.0.1:8080:8080 \
-p 127.0.0.1:5001:5001 \
ipfs/go-ipfs:latest 
</code></pre>

<pre><code>docker start go-ipfs
</code></pre>

<h4 id="pin-your-first-cid-hash_1">Pin your first CID Hash</h4>
<p>This 'docker exec' command runs your 'go-ipfs' container with container command 'ipfs pin add'. This CID Hash contains 1,000 books, to add it run:</p>
<pre><code>docker exec go-ipfs ipfs pin add bafykbzaceaeofefgje22l7rhgtcgs22m32f4ysw5nqa3ty5zawfovqam7pj2c --progress
</code></pre>

<p>Once it's complete, jump to the <a href="#cid-hash-index">CID Hash index</a>.</p>
<p>You can also access the WebUI and add or manage pins from there. Port 5001 is the API port of the IPFS docker container and contains the same UI as IPFS desktop. You can access the webui in your browser at <a href="http://127.0.0.1:5001/webui">http://127.0.0.1:5001/webui</a>.</p>
<h4 id="cid-hash-index">CID Hash index</h4>
<p>Once you've pinned your first 1,000 you can add the next 100,000 books of the Library Genesis Scitech collection here:</p>


<h4 id="port-forwarding">Port forwarding</h4>
<p>The IPFS swarm peer port is 4001. Opening it up will help you connect, but it is optional if you can't do so. To learn how to port forward port 4001 search your <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=ac1750+port+forwarding"><em>router model + port forward.</em></a></p>
<h2 id="torrents">Torrents</h2>
<p>Many volunteers have helped seed the torrents with the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/DataHoarder/comments/ed9byj/library_genesis_project_update_25_million_books/">Library Genesis Seeding Project</a>.</p>
<p>If you already downloaded the torrents you can add torrent folders to IPFS using <code>ipfs add</code></p>
<p>Start go-ipfs normally with <code>docker start go-ipfs</code></p>
<p>Configure go-ipfs to allow you link folders to the Filestore:</p>
<pre><code>docker exec go-ipfs ipfs config --json Experimental.FilestoreEnabled true
</code></pre>

<p>Restart with <code>docker stop go-ipfs &amp;&amp; docker start go-ipfs</code></p>
<p>Add the folders from where you saved them, starting with folder 1000:</p>
<pre><code>docker exec go-ipfs ipfs add $home/books/1000/ -r -w --nocopy --hash=blake2b-256 &gt;&gt;  $home/books/ipfs-add.log
</code></pre>

<p>Watch the log and check out the network activity:</p>
<pre><code>docker exec go-ipfs tail -f $home/books/ipfs-add.log
docker exec go-ipfs ipfs stats bw --poll=true --interval=1s
</code></pre>
                
              
              
                


              
            </article>
          </div>
        </div>
      </main>
      
        

      
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://freeread.org/ipfs/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25209246</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 13:58:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[View of Andromeda over Patagonia]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 13 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25207824">thread link</a>) | @jayass
<br/>
November 25, 2020 | https://misspellede.com/us/andromeda-over-patagonia/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://misspellede.com/us/andromeda-over-patagonia/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
        <div> 
                            <p><img loading="lazy" src="https://apod.nasa.gov/apod/image/2011/M31Horizon_Ferrarino_1080.jpg" alt="Andromeda over Patagonia cover image"></p>
            <p><a href="https://misspellede.com/us/cosmos/">cosmos</a></p><p>Gerardo Ferrarino • 2020-11-25</p><p>How far can you see?  The Andromeda Galaxy at 2.5 million light years away is the most distant object easily seen with your unaided eye.  Most other apparent denizens of the night sky -- stars, clusters, and nebulae -- typically range from a few hundred to a few thousand light-years away and lie well within our own Milky Way Galaxy.  Given its distance, light from Andromeda is likely also the oldest light that you can see.  Also known as M31, the Andromeda Galaxy dominates the center of the featured zoomed image, taken from the dunes of Bahía Creek, Patagonia, in southern Argentina.  The image is a combination of 45 background images with one foreground image -- all taken with the same camera and from the same location within 90 minutes.  M110, a satellite galaxy of Andromenda is visible just below and to the left of M31's core. As cool as it may be to see this neighboring galaxy to our Milky Way with your own eyes, long duration camera exposures can pick up many faint and breathtaking details.  Recent data indicates that our Milky Way Galaxy will collide and combine with the similarly-sized Andromeda galaxy in a few billion years.</p>

        </div>
    </article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://misspellede.com/us/andromeda-over-patagonia/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25207824</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 10:43:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Getting Graphical Output from Our Custom RISC-V Operating System in Rust]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 27 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25206221">thread link</a>) | @azhenley
<br/>
November 24, 2020 | https://blog.stephenmarz.com/2020/11/11/risc-v-os-using-rust-graphics/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.stephenmarz.com/2020/11/11/risc-v-os-using-rust-graphics/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
								
								<div>
									
<p>An operating system is used to make our job easier when using graphics. In our instance, in addition to everything else. In this post, we will be writing a GPU (graphics processing unit) driver using the VirtIO specification. In here, we will allow user applications to have a portion of the screen as RAM–with what is commonly known as a <em>framebuffer</em>.</p>



<hr>



<h2>Contents</h2>



<ol><li><a href="#overview">Overview</a></li><li><a href="#pixels">Pixels and Resolution</a></li><li><a href="#virtio">The GPU VirtIO Device</a></li><li><a href="#init">Initialization</a></li><li><a href="#invalid">Invalidation and Transfer</a></li><li><a href="#response">Device Responses</a></li><li><a href="#user">User Space</a></li><li><a href="#api">Simple Graphics API</a></li><li><a href="#conclusion">Conclusions and Further Reading</a></li></ol>



<hr>



<h2 id="overview">Overview</h2>



<p>We command the virtual GPU (virtio-gpu) by sending certain commands to the host (the device). The guest (the OS driver) has an allocation of RAM that becomes the framebuffer. The driver then tells the device, “hey, here’s the RAM that we’re going to use to store pixel information.”</p>



<p>The RAM is contiguous in our OS, but according to the specification, this isn’t strictly required. We will give the driver a rectangle. Everything that falls within that rectangle will be copied to the host. We don’t want to keep copying the entire buffer over and over again.</p>



<p>We will be using the virtio protocol that we used for the block driver here, so I won’t rehash the general virtio protocol. However, the device-specific structures are a bit different, so we’ll cover that part more in depth.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="pixels">Pixels and Resolution</h2>



<p>A framebuffer must be large enough to store \(\text{width}\times\text{height}\times\text{pixel size}\) number of bytes. There are \(\text{width}\times\text{height}\) number of pixels. Each pixel has a 1-byte red, green, blue, and alpha channels. So, each pixel is exactly 4 bytes with the configuration we’re going to specify.</p>



<p>The framebuffer for our junior GPU driver is going to support a fixed resolution of \(640\times 480\). If you’re a child of the 90s, you saw this resolution a lot. In fact, my first computer, a Laser Pal 386, had a 16-color monitor with a resolution of 640 pixels wide with 480 pixels tall.</p>



<div><figure><a href="https://blog.stephenmarz.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/image-13.png"><img loading="lazy" src="https://blog.stephenmarz.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/image-13.png" alt="" width="458" height="281" srcset="https://blog.stephenmarz.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/image-13.png 611w, https://blog.stephenmarz.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/image-13-300x184.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 458px) 100vw, 458px"></a></figure></div>



<p>There are red, green, and blue pixels so close together that by varying the intensity of these three channels, we can change the color. The closer we get to our monitors, the easier a pixel is to see.</p>



<div><figure><a href="https://blog.stephenmarz.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/image-14.png"><img loading="lazy" src="https://blog.stephenmarz.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/image-14.png" alt="" width="285" height="288" srcset="https://blog.stephenmarz.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/image-14.png 380w, https://blog.stephenmarz.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/image-14-297x300.png 297w" sizes="(max-width: 285px) 100vw, 285px"></a><figcaption>Pixels on a Viewsonic VX2770SMH-LED monitor.</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>You can see these little squares. If you squint enough, you can see that they aren’t pure white. Instead, you can see bits of red, blue, and green. That’s because each one of these little squares is subdivided into three colors: yep, red, green, and blue! To make white, these pixels are turned up to 11 (get the joke?). To make black, we turn off all three channels of that pixel.</p>



<p>The resolution refers to how many of these squares are on our monitor. This is a 1920×1080 monitor. That means that there are 1920 of these squares going left to right, and there are 1080 of these squares from top to bottom. All in all, we have \(1920\times 1080=2,073,600\) number of pixels. Each one of these pixels is expressed using 4 bytes in the framebuffer, meaning we need \(2,073,600\times 4=8,294,400\) bytes in RAM to store the pixel information.</p>



<p>You can see why I limited our resolution to 640×480, which only requires \(640\times 480\times 4=1,228,800\) bytes–a bit over a megabyte.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="virtio">The GPU VirtIO Device</h2>



<p>The GPU device requires us to read a more up-to-date VirtIO specification. I’ll be reading from version 1.1, which you can get a copy here: <a href="https://docs.oasis-open.org/virtio/virtio/v1.1/virtio-v1.1.html">https://docs.oasis-open.org/virtio/virtio/v1.1/virtio-v1.1.html</a>. Specifically, chapter 5.7 “GPU Device”. This is an <em>unaccelerated</em> 2D device, meaning that we must use the CPU to actually form the framebuffer, then we transfer our CPU formulated memory location to the host GPU, which is then responsible for drawing it to the screen.</p>



<p>The device uses a request/response system, where we the driver make a command to request something from the host (the GPU).  We add a bit of extra memory into our request so that the host can formulate its response. When the GPU interrupts us, we can take a look at this response memory location to see what the GPU told us. This is much like the <em>status</em> field on the block driver, where the block device tells us the status of our last request.</p>



<p>Each request starts with a <em>Command Header</em>, which in Rust looks as follows:</p>



<pre data-enlighter-language="rust" data-enlighter-theme="" data-enlighter-highlight="" data-enlighter-linenumbers="" data-enlighter-lineoffset="" data-enlighter-title="" data-enlighter-group="">#[repr(C)]
struct CtrlHeader {
	ctrl_type: CtrlType,
	flags: u32,
	fence_id: u64,
	ctx_id: u32,
	padding: u32
}</pre>



<p>The header is common for all requests and all responses. We can differentiate by the CtrlType enumeration, which is:</p>



<pre data-enlighter-language="rust" data-enlighter-theme="" data-enlighter-highlight="" data-enlighter-linenumbers="" data-enlighter-lineoffset="" data-enlighter-title="" data-enlighter-group="">#[repr(u32)]
enum CtrlType {
	/* 2d commands */
	CmdGetDisplayInfo = 0x0100,
	CmdResourceCreate2d,
	CmdResourceUref,
	CmdSetScanout,
	CmdResourceFlush,
	CmdTransferToHost2d,
	CmdResourceAttachBacking,
	CmdResourceDetachBacking,
	CmdGetCapsetInfo,
	CmdGetCapset,
	CmdGetEdid,
	/* cursor commands */
	CmdUpdateCursor = 0x0300,
	CmdMoveCursor,
	/* success responses */
	RespOkNoData = 0x1100,
	RespOkDisplayInfo,
	RespOkCapsetInfo,
	RespOkCapset,
	RespOkEdid,
	/* error responses */
	RespErrUnspec = 0x1200,
	RespErrOutOfMemory,
	RespErrInvalidScanoutId,
	RespErrInvalidResourceId,
	RespErrInvalidContextId,
	RespErrInvalidParameter,
}</pre>



<p>I took this directly from the specification, but Rust-ified the names to avoid getting yelled at by the linter.</p>



<h3>Pixel Formats</h3>



<p>Recall that the framebuffer is just a bunch of bytes in memory. We need to put a structure behind the framebuffer so the host (the GPU) knows how to interpret your sequence of bytes. There are several formats, but all-in-all, they just re-arrange the red, green, blue, and alpha channels. All are exactly 4 bytes, which makes the <em>stride</em> the same. The stride is the spacing from one pixel to another–4 bytes.</p>



<pre data-enlighter-language="rust" data-enlighter-theme="" data-enlighter-highlight="" data-enlighter-linenumbers="" data-enlighter-lineoffset="" data-enlighter-title="" data-enlighter-group="">#[repr(u32)]
enum Formats {
	B8G8R8A8Unorm = 1,
	B8G8R8X8Unorm = 2,
	A8R8G8B8Unorm = 3,
	X8R8G8B8Unorm = 4,
	R8G8B8A8Unorm = 67,
	X8B8G8R8Unorm = 68,
	A8B8G8R8Unorm = 121,
	R8G8B8X8Unorm = 134,
}</pre>



<p>The type, <em>unorm</em>, is an 8-bit (1-byte) unsigned value from 0 through 255, where 0 represents no intensity and 255 represents full intensity, and a number in between is a linear-interpolation between no and full intensity. Since there are three color (and one alpha), that gives us \(256\times 256\times 256=16,776,216\) different colors or levels of colors.</p>



<p>For this tutorial, I selected <code>R8G8B8A8Unorm = 67</code>, which has red first, green second, blue third, and alpha fourth. This is a common ordering, so I’ll select it to make it easy to follow along.</p>



<p>Our selected format makes the pixel structure look as follows:</p>



<div><figure><a href="https://blog.stephenmarz.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/image-21.png"><img loading="lazy" src="https://blog.stephenmarz.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/image-21-1024x614.png" alt="" width="512" height="307" srcset="https://blog.stephenmarz.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/image-21-1024x614.png 1024w, https://blog.stephenmarz.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/image-21-300x180.png 300w, https://blog.stephenmarz.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/image-21-768x461.png 768w, https://blog.stephenmarz.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/image-21-1536x921.png 1536w, https://blog.stephenmarz.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/image-21-2048x1228.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px"></a></figure></div>



<p>Recall that each individual component R, G, B, and A are each one byte a piece, so each Pixel referred to by (x, y) is 4 bytes. This is why our memory pointer is a Pixel structure instead of a byte.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="init">Initialization</h2>



<p>Just like all other virtio devices, we set up the virtqueues first and then we work on device-specific initialization. In my code, I just directly copied-and-pasted from the block driver into the gpu driver. The only thing I added to the Device structure was the framebuffer and dimensions of the framebuffer.</p>



<pre data-enlighter-language="rust" data-enlighter-theme="" data-enlighter-highlight="" data-enlighter-linenumbers="" data-enlighter-lineoffset="" data-enlighter-title="" data-enlighter-group="">pub struct Device {
	queue:        *mut Queue,
	dev:          *mut u32,
	idx:          u16,
	ack_used_idx: u16,
	framebuffer:  *mut Pixel,
	width:        u32,
	height:       u32,
}</pre>



<p>The specification tells us to do the following in order to initialize the device and get things ready to draw. I Rust-ified some of the content to match our enumerations.</p>



<h4>Create a framebuffer and configure scanout</h4>



<ol><li>Create a host resource using <code>CmdResourceCreate2d</code>.</li><li>Allocate a framebuffer from guest ram, and attach it as backing storage to the resource just created, using <code>CmdResourceAttachBacking</code>.</li><li>Use <code>CmdSetScanout</code> to link the framebuffer to a display scanout.</li></ol>



<h3>A Request Structure</h3>



<p>Recall that our request and response come packaged together. We will put them in separate descriptors, but whenever we get a response back from the device, it is going to be easier if we free just once to free both the request and response. So, in Rust, I created the Request structure to support doing this.</p>



<pre data-enlighter-language="rust" data-enlighter-theme="" data-enlighter-highlight="" data-enlighter-linenumbers="" data-enlighter-lineoffset="" data-enlighter-title="" data-enlighter-group="">struct Request&lt;RqT, RpT&gt; {
	request: RqT,
	response: RpT,
}
impl&lt;RqT, RpT&gt; Request&lt;RqT, RpT&gt; {
	pub fn new(request: RqT) -&gt; *mut Self {
		let sz = size_of::&lt;RqT&gt;() + size_of::&lt;RpT&gt;();
		let ptr = kmalloc(sz) as *mut Self;
		unsafe {
			(*ptr).request = request;
		}
		ptr
	}
}</pre>



<h4>Step 1: Create host resource</h4>



<pre data-enlighter-language="rust" data-enlighter-theme="" data-enlighter-highlight="" data-enlighter-linenumbers="" data-enlighter-lineoffset="" data-enlighter-title="" data-enlighter-group="">let rq = Request::new(ResourceCreate2d {
	hdr: CtrlHeader {
		ctrl_type: CtrlType::CmdResourceCreate2d,
		flags: 0,
		fence_id: 0,
		ctx_id: 0,
		padding: 0,
	},
	resource_id: 1,
	format: Formats::R8G8B8A8Unorm,
	width: dev.width,
	height: dev.height,
});
let desc_c2d = Descriptor {
	addr: unsafe { &amp;(*rq).request as *const ResourceCreate2d as u64 },
	len: size_of::&lt;ResourceCreate2d&gt;() as u32,
	flags: VIRTIO_DESC_F_NEXT,
	next: (dev.idx + 1) % VIRTIO_RING_SIZE as u16,
};
let desc_c2d_resp = Descriptor {
	addr: unsafe { &amp;(*rq).response as *const CtrlHeader as u64 },
	len: size_of::&lt;CtrlHeader&gt;() as u32,
	flags: VIRTIO_DESC_F_WRITE,
	next: 0,
};
unsafe {
	let head = dev.idx;
	(*dev.queue).desc[dev.idx as usize] = desc_c2d;
	dev.idx = (dev.idx + 1) % VIRTIO_RING_SIZE as u16;
	(*dev.queue).desc[dev.idx as usize] = desc_c2d_resp;
	dev.idx = (dev.idx + 1) % VIRTIO_RING_SIZE as u16;
	(*dev.queue).avail.ring[(*dev.queue).avail.idx as usize % VIRTIO_RING_SIZE] = head;
	(*dev.queue).avail.idx = (*dev.queue).avail.idx.wrapping_add(1);
}</pre>



<p>All we’re really telling the GPU here is our resolution and the format of the framebuffer. When we create this, the host gets to configure itself, such as allocating an identical buffer to make transfers from our OS.</p>



<h4>Step 2: Attach framebuffer backing.</h4>



<pre data-enlighter-language="rust" data-enlighter-theme="" data-enlighter-highlight="" data-enlighter-linenumbers="" data-enlighter-lineoffset="" data-enlighter-title="" data-enlighter-group="">let rq = Request3::new(AttachBacking {
	hdr: CtrlHeader {
		ctrl_type: CtrlType::CmdResourceAttachBacking,
		flags: 0,
		fence_id: 0,
		ctx_id: 0,
		padding: 0,
	},
	resource_id: 1,
	nr_entries: 1,
},
MemEntry {
	addr: dev.framebuffer as u64,
	length: dev.width * dev.height * size_of::&lt;Pixel&gt;() as u32,
	…</pre></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.stephenmarz.com/2020/11/11/risc-v-os-using-rust-graphics/">https://blog.stephenmarz.com/2020/11/11/risc-v-os-using-rust-graphics/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.stephenmarz.com/2020/11/11/risc-v-os-using-rust-graphics/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25206221</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 05:14:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Remember when you could reboot your computer without rebooting your phone first?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 77 | Comments 56 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25205031">thread link</a>) | @mdoms
<br/>
November 24, 2020 | https://annoying.technology/posts/7b574a72da90e5cd/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://annoying.technology/posts/7b574a72da90e5cd/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/31a8603310fa498ae382fe6140ad8db20c277711/6bc2e/media/neustartdoeswell.png"></p><p>Remember when you could reboot your computer without rebooting your phone first?</p><p>I’m not even kidding: I needed to reboot my Mac because I was unable to navigate character by character using the arrow keys when composing new iMessages in Big Sur, but Finder refused to quit during the reboot with the above error message. It was still syncing my iPhone. (Remember when we thought the iTunes rewrite would be a good thing? <a href="https://twitter.com/manu_faktur/status/1260099839511212032">Good Times</a>!) I tried quite a few things on both devices, but was unable to cancel said sync in any other way than to reboot the phone.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://annoying.technology/posts/7b574a72da90e5cd/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25205031</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 01:30:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
