<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 20]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 20. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 12:21:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-20.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 12:21:08 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Things I Wish I’d Known About CSS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 131 | Comments 47 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23868355">thread link</a>) | @harshamv22
<br/>
July 17, 2020 | https://cssfordesigners.com/articles/things-i-wish-id-known-about-css | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://cssfordesigners.com/articles/things-i-wish-id-known-about-css">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                
                    <section>
                <p>I learned how to build websites the old fashioned way: looking at website source code and trying to replicate the things I saw. I threw in the odd book for the stuff I couldn’t <em>see</em> (like PHP/MySQL), and I was on my way.</p>

<p>This was back in 1999, when we’d write things like <code>&lt;font size="4" color="#000000"&gt;</code> and DHTML was a <em>thing</em>.</p>

<p>When CSS came along my approach to learning didn’t differ. But I <em>really</em> wish I’d taken the time to learn CSS properly: there was so much fundamental stuff I missed.</p>

<p>Here are some things I didn’t know that I wish I’d learned earlier.</p>

            </section>
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
                        
<h2 id="block-inline-and-inline-block">Block, inline and inline-block</h2> 
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
                    <section>
                <p>Even though I <em>knew</em> about these properties, I didn’t fully understand them for a long time.</p>

<p>Here’s a breakdown:</p>

<ul>
<li><code>block</code> elements expand horizontally to take up a whole line (like a heading). We can apply vertical margin to these.</li>
<li><code>inline</code> elements expand horizontally just enough to contain their content (like <code>strong</code> or <code>em</code> elements). We <strong>cannot apply vertical margins to these</strong> and they should usually be placed inside a <code>block</code> element.</li>
<li><code>inline-block</code> elements are like <code>inline</code> elements, <strong>but you can apply vertical margins to these</strong> (making them useful for things like buttons).</li>
</ul>

<p>In the example below, <code>block</code> elements have a blue border, <code>inline</code> elements have an orange background, and our <code>inline-block</code> element has a red border.</p>

            </section>
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
                    <section>
                <p data-height="400" data-theme-id="37523" data-default-tab="css,result" data-user="websmyth" data-slug-hash="9cc40d6abf5c7f24360ec58c75c91fd3" data-editable="true" data-pen-title="Boxes –&nbsp;Example #1">
                        <span>See the Pen <a href="https://codepen.io/websmyth/pen/9cc40d6abf5c7f24360ec58c75c91fd3">
                        Boxes –&nbsp;Example #1</a> by Dave Smyth (<a href="https://codepen.io/websmyth">@websmyth</a>)
                        on <a href="https://codepen.io/">CodePen</a>.</span>
                        </p>
                
            </section>
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
                        
<h2 id="images-are-inline">Images are inline</h2> 
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
                    <section>
                <p>Images <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Element/img#Styling_with_CSS">being inline by default</a> isn’t a problem, but it can cause confusion when trying to position them or add vertical margins.</p>

<p>If your CSS reset doesn’t include this already, I’d suggest adding the following rule:</p>

<pre><code>img {
    display: block;
}
</code></pre>

<p>That will make their behaviour much more predictable. You might also want to add <code>max-width: 100%;</code> to stop them breaking out of their container, too.</p>

            </section>
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
                        
<h2 id="how-height-and-width-are-calculated">How height and width are calculated</h2> 
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
                    <section>
                <p>By default, the width/height of a box is calculated by adding together the dimensions of the:</p>

<ul>
<li>Content area</li>
<li>Padding area</li>
<li>Border area</li>
</ul>

<p>This isn’t usually a problem for an element’s height: we’re usually not too bothered about how content reflows vertically. The problems usually occur when trying to calculate an element’s width, especially if there’s more than one element in a row.</p>

<p>If we had the following CSS:</p>

<pre><code>.some-class {
    width: 50%;
    padding: 2em;
    border: 0.1rem;
}
</code></pre>

<p>The total calculated <code>width</code> for <code>.some-class</code> would be:</p>

<p><code>50% + 4em + 0.2rem</code></p>

<p>That’s because of a property called <code>box-sizing</code> which has a default value of <code>content-box</code>. This value means the <code>width</code> property <strong>applies to the content area</strong>: everything else is added on top of this.</p>

<p>We can change this for all elements with the following rule:</p>

<pre><code>* {
    box-sizing: border-box;
}
</code></pre>

<p>Returning to our example, the element’s width would now apply to the <code>border</code>, so our element’s total <code>width</code> would be <code>50%</code>.</p>

<p>What happens to the <code>border</code> and <code>padding</code>? Those properties/values still apply, but they don’t affect the total <code>width</code> of the element: they sit within the defined area.</p>

<p>Check out this Codepen to see this in action:</p>

            </section>
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
                    <section>
                <p data-height="400" data-theme-id="37523" data-default-tab="css,result" data-user="websmyth" data-slug-hash="a4b49c52737aacbfc70342ff2753b5b0" data-editable="true" data-pen-title="Boxes –&nbsp;Example #1">
                        <span>See the Pen <a href="https://codepen.io/websmyth/pen/a4b49c52737aacbfc70342ff2753b5b0">
                        Boxes –&nbsp;Example #1</a> by Dave Smyth (<a href="https://codepen.io/websmyth">@websmyth</a>)
                        on <a href="https://codepen.io/">CodePen</a>.</span>
                        </p>
                
            </section>
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
        
        
        
        
                    <section>
                                    <header>
                        <h3>Margin</h3>
                    </header>
                                <article>
                    <p>We haven’t discussed <code>margin</code> here because <strong>margin is the space between elements</strong>. For that reason, it is never part of this calculation.</p>

                                    </article>
            </section>
        
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
                        
<h2 id="padding-margin-arent-the-same">Padding &amp; margin aren’t the same</h2> 
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
                    <section>
                <p>If an element has no <code>background</code> or <code>border</code>, it can appear that <code>padding</code> and <code>margin</code> are the same. They are not!</p>

<ul>
<li><code>margin</code> is the space <strong>between</strong> elements</li>
<li><code>padding</code> is space <strong>inside</strong> an element</li>
</ul>

<p>That makes <code>padding</code> useful for elements that have a <code>background</code>. We often don’t want the content to be close to the edge of the element’s box and <code>padding</code> helps us achieve that.</p>

            </section>
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
                        
<h2 id="margins-collapse">Margins collapse</h2> 
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
                    <section>
                <p>This has been the source of frustration for CSS newcomers for a long time. Rachel Andrew <a href="https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2019/07/margins-in-css/#margin-collapsing">describes the behaviour</a> as:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>When margins collapse, they will combine so that the space between the two elements becomes the larger of the two margins. The smaller margin essentially ending up inside the larger one.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>If we have two block elements with <code>margin-bottom: 1em</code> on one element and <code>margin-top: 1.5em</code> on the element directly below it, the total space between the two elements would be <code>1.5em</code>.</p>

<p>We can see that here:</p>

            </section>
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
                    <section>
                <p data-height="400" data-theme-id="37523" data-default-tab="css,result" data-user="websmyth" data-slug-hash="43f1491b85413fd9af705ccad492aa7f" data-editable="true" data-pen-title="Boxes –&nbsp;Example #1">
                        <span>See the Pen <a href="https://codepen.io/websmyth/pen/43f1491b85413fd9af705ccad492aa7f">
                        Boxes –&nbsp;Example #1</a> by Dave Smyth (<a href="https://codepen.io/websmyth">@websmyth</a>)
                        on <a href="https://codepen.io/">CodePen</a>.</span>
                        </p>
                
            </section>
        
        
        
        
            
                    <section>
                <p>When two margins meet, the larger margin absorbs the smaller margin. If the margins are the same value, they absord each other.</p>

<p>As soon as we know this, <code>margin</code> calculations become easier. It might also change our approach to managing them, and that’s where something like <a href="https://cssfordesigners.com/articles/managing-vertical-margins-in-css">the Lobotomised Owl selector can be useful</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Note:</strong> Margins don’t collapse when the parent element is set to <code>display: grid</code> or <code>display: flex</code>.</p>

            </section>
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
                        
<h2 id="browsers-have-a-default-stylesheet">Browsers have a default stylesheet</h2> 
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
                    <section>
                <p>CSS stands for <strong>Cascading Style Sheets</strong>. It’s no surprise therefore that the <strong>cascade</strong> is one of the fundamental concepts of CSS.</p>

<p>Though we might be aware of how our own stylesheets interact with each other, we have to remember that there’s <strong>always a default browser stylesheet</strong>. This is loaded <em>before</em> any custom stylesheets, making it easy to redeclare existing values.</p>

<p>The declared styles vary by browser, but they’re the reason that, by default:</p>

<ul>
<li>Headings have different sizes</li>
<li>Text is black</li>
<li>Lists have bullet points</li>
<li>Elements have any <code>display</code> property (such as <code>block</code> or <code>inline</code>)</li>
</ul>

<p>And many other things.</p>

<p>Even if a website only has a single stylesheet, that stylesheet will always be merged with the browser’s default styles.</p>

            </section>
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
                        
<h2 id="use-relative-units-everywhere">Use relative units everywhere</h2> 
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
                    <section>
                <p>Using pixels (<code>px</code>) is tempting because they’re simple to understand: declare <code>font-size: 24px</code> and the text will be <code>24px</code>. But that won’t provide a great user experience, particularly for users who resize content at <a href="https://adrianroselli.com/2019/12/responsive-type-and-zoom.html#Update02">the browser level</a> or zoom into content.</p>

<p>I started using <code>em</code> (and later <code>rem</code>) for font sizing early. It took much longer to feel comfortable using <code>em</code> and <code>rem</code> for other things such as <code>padding</code>, <code>margin</code>, <code>letter-spacing</code> and <code>border</code>.</p>

<p>Understanding the difference between <code>em</code> and <code>rem</code> is critical to making relative units manageable. For instance, we might use <code>em</code> for <code>@media</code> queries and vertical margins, but <code>rem</code> for consistent <code>border-width</code>.</p>

<p>The benefits of going all-in on relative sizing are well-worth the small adjustment in thinking that requires.</p>

            </section>
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
                        
<h2 id="before-and-after-need-content">::before and ::after need content</h2> 
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
                    <section>
                <p>When using either …</p></section></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://cssfordesigners.com/articles/things-i-wish-id-known-about-css">https://cssfordesigners.com/articles/things-i-wish-id-known-about-css</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://cssfordesigners.com/articles/things-i-wish-id-known-about-css</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23868355</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 08:17:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: A completely different way to write responsive, vanilla, CSS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 166 | Comments 32 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23865900">thread link</a>) | @James0x57
<br/>
July 16, 2020 | https://propjockey.github.io/css-media-vars/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://propjockey.github.io/css-media-vars/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>
        css-media-vars adds several --custom-css-variables, all namespaced with "--media-" and based on media queries, onto the HTML tag. These vars act as universal mixins for your CSS values. If the media query is true, your value will be used. If it's false, the var(..., fallback) will be used.</p><p>
        
        For example, there are several named breakpoints that respond to the width of the screen, such as <code>--media-lte-sm</code>.</p><p>
        
        In your CSS, if you want a value to only apply when the screen is less than or equal to the "small" breakpoint range, you mix it into your value:<br>
        <code>--my-small-value: var(--media-lte-sm) 2px;</code><br>
        From this point, you can use your variable anywhere and it will only be "2px" if the media query is true. Else, it uses the fallback you provide, like so:<br>
        <code>border: var(--my-small-value, 15px) solid green;</code><br>
        <img src="https://propjockey.github.io/css-media-vars/suchborder.gif" alt="Border changing size at 900px breakpoint"><br>
        Here's a link to the jsbin pictured in the gif: <a href="https://jsbin.com/giqedowale/edit?css,output">https://jsbin.com/giqedowale/edit?css,output</a></p><p>
        
        If you need multiple break points, all you have to do is mix a different breakpoint into another variable and use it in the first fallback:<br>
        <code>
          --my-small-value: var(--media-lte-sm) 2px;<br>
          --my-medium-value: var(--media-md) 15px;<br>
          border: var(--my-small-value, var(--my-medium-value, 30px)) solid green;<br>
        </code><br>
        In this case, because the small values are listed first, this approach is <b>mobile-first</b>! CSS Variables don't compile the fallback unless it's used (similar to the expected short-circuting of conditionals in JavaScript).</p><p>
        
        This is all vanilla CSS. No JS or build step is necessary.<br>
        The library is small and built on a CSS trick called "Space Toggle" discovered in the development of <a href="http://augmented-ui.com/">augmented-ui</a>. You can read more about Space Toggle in these tweets which contain links to JSBins you can explore further with:<br>
        <a href="https://twitter.com/James0x57/status/1283596399196680192">Second Tweet, a simple demo</a><br>
        <a href="https://twitter.com/James0x57/status/1282303255826046977">First Tweet, an advanced demo</a></p><p>
        
        Browser support for CSS Variables is currently 94% globally according to <a href="https://caniuse.com/#feat=css-variables">caniuse</a>.<br>
        Each of the --media-* vars are using the actual media query in CSS to switch them to the "true" state. Browser support depends on the feature but will always behave as if it's "false" if the media query isn't supported in the user's browser, such as <code>--media-prefers-light</code> which only recently gained traction.
      </p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://propjockey.github.io/css-media-vars/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23865900</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 01:14:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Next Steps for Single Ownership and RAII]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 80 | Comments 27 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23865674">thread link</a>) | @verdagon
<br/>
July 16, 2020 | https://vale.dev/blog/next-steps-raii | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://vale.dev/blog/next-steps-raii">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://vale.dev/blog/next-steps-raii</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23865674</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:41:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[EdgeDB 1.0 Alpha 4 - A new DB with GraphQL support and more]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 21 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23864499">thread link</a>) | @1st1
<br/>
July 16, 2020 | https://edgedb.com/blog/edgedb-1-0-alpha-4-barnard-s-star | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://edgedb.com/blog/edgedb-1-0-alpha-4-barnard-s-star">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="---post-root---"><section><div><p><img src="https://edgedb.com/static/alpha4-b651c7a247989c1d37881c5fd244baf7.jpg" width="100%" height="100%"></p></div></section>
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<section id="edgedb-1-0-alpha-4-barnard-s-star">
<!-- -->
<p>After six weeks of work since <a href="https://edgedb.com/blog/edgedb-1-0-alpha-3">Alpha 3</a>, we are happy to
            announce the immediate release of EdgeDB 1.0 Alpha 4 “Barnard’s Star”. You
            can <a href="https://edgedb.com/download">download</a> it in a number of ways or try it out in our
            <a href="https://tutorial.edgedb.com/">interactive tutorial</a> without the need to install anything.</p>

<p>This time around we focused on making the database more intuitive from
            both the server and the client perspective.  While there’s fewer changes
            due to our newly adopted six-week release cycle, we’re able to deliver them
            to you much quicker.  Let’s go through some highlights of the release!</p>
<h4>What’s EdgeDB</h4>
<p>EdgeDB is an advanced <a href="https://github.com/edgedb/edgedb">open source</a> relational database based on
            PostgreSQL.  The project aims to give developers and data engineers a highly
            efficient and productive database technology while addressing the
            <a href="https://edgedb.com/blog/we-can-do-better-than-sql">shortcomings of SQL</a> and its surrounding ecosystem:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>high-level data model and type system;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>a powerful, expressive and extensible query language that allows working
                    with complex data relationships easily;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>first-class support for schema migrations;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>support for converting arbitrary strictly typed data to and from JSON
                    via a simple cast operator;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>out-of-the-box interoperability via REST and GraphQL.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<div id="improved-usability-of-server-instance-maintenance">
<h2 id="improved-usability-of-server-instance-maintenance"><a href="https://edgedb.com/blog/edgedb-1-0-alpha-4-barnard-s-star#improved-usability-of-server-instance-maintenance"><svg width="35" height="35" viewBox="0 0 35 35"><path d="M2.694 6.631h19.085v3.961h-1.944V8.574H4.636v10.962h15.199V17.52h1.944v3.96H2.694V6.632zM13.3 13.085h19.086v14.848H13.3v-3.962h1.942v2.019h15.2V15.027h-15.2v2.017H13.3v-3.96z" fill="#047CFF"></path></svg></a>Improved Usability of Server Instance Maintenance</h2>
<p>One of the ways in which we’re setting EdgeDB apart from previous generation
                databases is the focus on usability of day-to-day tasks.  One particularly
                gnarly topic is maintenance of server instances: installing a new version,
                upgrading existing databases to a new version, setting up an instance to
                run properly as a service daemon, accessing logs, and so on.  It gets
                especially tricky when multiple operating systems provide their own unique
                ways to achieve those tasks.  Even better if the user needs to keep
                a few versions running concurrently.</p>
<p>We looked at how efficient <a href="https://rustup.rs/">rustup</a> is in ensuring the user
                has a fully functional up-to-date installation of the Rust toolchain,
                and got inspired: what if we can provide <em>this</em> experience for a database?</p>
<p>The end result is the new <code>edgedb server</code> group of commands that ships with
                the default EdgeDB CLI. Its design was planned and discussed as part of an
                RFC process which, as the rest of EdgeDB, is open. <a href="https://github.com/edgedb/rfcs/blob/master/text/1001-edgedb-server-control.rst">Check it out</a>!</p>
<p>The most visible change related to <code>edgedb server</code> is that it is now
                the new recommended way to install EdgeDB servers on your operating
                system.  See <code>edgedb server install --help</code> for details.  The
                underlying installer will still use your operating system’s package
                manager but it provides instance configuration in ways that allow for
                running multiple EdgeDB versions concurrently on one machine.  And with
                <code>edgedb server upgrade</code> you can easily bump the version on an existing
                installation without having to redo configuration or dump and restore
                data manually.</p>
<p>And how do you get the new CLI tool on your machine?  We redesigned the
                <a href="https://edgedb.com/download">Download</a> page to be more inviting, providing a new
                cross-platform way to install EdgeDB with a single-liner in the terminal.
                And if you’re a macOS user, you might want to use our new Homebrew tap!</p>
</div>
<div id="javascript-bindings-got-more-powerful">

<p>We supercharged <a href="https://github.com/edgedb/edgedb-js/">edgedb-js</a>, our JavaScript client for EdgeDB,
                with an efficient <a href="https://edgedb.com/docs/clients/01_js/usage#connection-pools">connection pooling</a> implementation. This
                allows users write faster applications with less code.</p>

<pre><span><span><span>import</span> <span>{</span>createPool<span>}</span> <span>from</span> <span>'edgedb'</span><span>;</span>




<span>const</span> pool <span>=</span> <span>await</span> <span>createPool</span><span>(</span><span>{</span>
  connectOptions<span>:</span> <span>{</span>
    user<span>:</span> <span>"edgedb"</span><span>,</span>
    host<span>:</span> <span>"x.x.x.x"</span><span>,</span>
  <span>}</span><span>,</span>
  minSize<span>:</span> <span>5</span><span>,</span>  
  maxSize<span>:</span> <span>50</span>  
<span>}</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>




<span>await</span> pool<span>.</span><span>query</span><span>(</span><span>'SELECT 42'</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>



<span>await</span> pool<span>.</span><span>run</span><span>(</span><span>async</span> <span>(</span>conn<span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
  conn<span>.</span><span>execute</span><span>(</span><span>'START TRANSACTION'</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>
  <span>try</span> <span>{</span>
    conn<span>.</span><span>query</span><span>(</span><span>'SELECT business_logic(10 / $num)'</span><span>,</span> <span>{</span>num<span>:</span> <span>42</span><span>}</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>
  <span>}</span> <span>finally</span> <span>{</span>
    conn<span>.</span><span>execute</span><span>(</span><span>'ROLLBACK'</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>



<span>const</span> conn <span>=</span> <span>await</span> pool<span>.</span><span>acquire</span><span>(</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>
<span>try</span> <span>{</span>
  conn<span>.</span><span>query</span><span>(</span><span>'SELECT datetime_current();'</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span> <span>finally</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>await</span> pool<span>.</span><span>release</span><span>(</span>conn<span>)</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span></span></span></pre>
<p>We also thought hard about the API and decided that <code>fetch*()</code> function
                names don’t really sound very natural when you’re trying to insert or update
                data. We renamed them to <code>query*()</code> which is the obvious name in hindsight:</p>
<pre><span><span><span>async</span> <span>function</span> <span>example</span><span>(</span>conn<span>)</span> <span>{</span>
  
  <span>await</span> conn<span>.</span><span>query</span><span>(</span><span><span>`
    INSERT User {
      name := 'Alice'
    }
  `</span></span><span>)</span>
<span>}</span></span></span></pre>
<p>The change actually originated in our Python client and this is <a href="https://github.com/edgedb/edgedb-python/issues/51">where the
                    change was discussed</a>.</p>
</div>
<div id="describe-is-worth-a-thousand-greps">
<h2 id="describe-is-worth-a-thousand-greps"><a href="https://edgedb.com/blog/edgedb-1-0-alpha-4-barnard-s-star#describe-is-worth-a-thousand-greps"><svg width="35" height="35" viewBox="0 0 35 35"><path d="M2.694 6.631h19.085v3.961h-1.944V8.574H4.636v10.962h15.199V17.52h1.944v3.96H2.694V6.632zM13.3 13.085h19.086v14.848H13.3v-3.962h1.942v2.019h15.2V15.027h-15.2v2.017H13.3v-3.96z" fill="#047CFF"></path></svg></a>DESCRIBE Is Worth a Thousand Greps</h2>
<p>As part of the usability sprint we made <code>DESCRIBE</code> better.  When
                describing objects, it will now list all matches for the specified name
                if available.  This is particularly interesting in case of user functions
                masking user types or standard types/functions.</p>
<p><code>DESCRIBE ROLES</code> and <code>DESCRIBE SYSTEM CONFIG</code> in turn allow you to
                quickly assess the respective areas of the database, and make dumping an
                entire server instance easier.</p>
</div>
<div id="stored-migrations-are-coming">

<p>The back-end implementation for the much improved workflow for migrations
                is mostly complete.  The next step is providing a CLI for it, which we
                plan to release as part of Alpha 5.</p>
<p>We think this set of features will be an important foundation of successful
                EdgeDB adoption. You can read more about them in our <a href="https://github.com/edgedb/rfcs/blob/master/text/1000-migrations.rst">open RFC document</a> on the topic.</p>
</div>
<div id="you-can-talk-to-us-right-on-github">

<p>GitHub is introducing a new feature called <a href="https://github.com/orgs/edgedb/discussions">Discussions</a>, a
                way to keep conversations happen close to the code which don’t really belong
                in Issues or Pull Requests.</p>
<p>We used to use Spectrum Chat for this purpose but as soon as we tried out
                Discussions, we knew this is a natural fit for us and our community.
                We’re an open product with a strong GitHub presence and you probably already
                have a GitHub account… so <a href="https://github.com/orgs/edgedb/discussions">come talk to us!</a></p>
</div>
<div id="summary">

<p>Barnard’s Star is the first release under our new release cycle. Our ambition
                is to always deliver frontpage-worthy new features, but we also understand
                those never get built in one development sprint.  At the same time, frequent
                milestones have many advantages both for us and our users.</p>
<p>With this in mind we’re proud to share Barnard’s Star with you, a release
                which is a step forward that tells a story.  We hope you’ll enjoy the
                improvements we’ve made, and just as importantly, come along for the
                ride and witness how they’re built <em>as they are being built</em>.</p>
<p>As usual, the <a href="https://edgedb.com/docs/changelog/1_0_a4">change log</a> provides a detailed story of the
                changes in this release.</p>
<p>If you have any questions, feel free to join the conversation <a href="https://github.com/orgs/edgedb/discussions">on GitHub
                    Discussions</a>, or ask in form of <a href="https://github.com/edgedb/edgedb">a bug report or a feature
                    request</a>.</p>
<p>If you’d like to learn more about our tech stack, we recently started <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/EdgeDB">a
                    YouTube channel</a>. At the moment we’re running a series
                introducing Python’s <code>asyncio</code>.</p>
<p>For future announcements, you can <a href="https://twitter.com/edgedatabase">find us on Twitter</a>.</p>
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
<!-- -->
</div>
</section>
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://edgedb.com/blog/edgedb-1-0-alpha-4-barnard-s-star</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23864499</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 22:19:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How Pulse Oximeters Work (2015)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 160 | Comments 100 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23863322">thread link</a>) | @zealotsm
<br/>
July 16, 2020 | https://www.howequipmentworks.com/pulse_oximeter/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.howequipmentworks.com/pulse_oximeter/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
		<a href="#content">Skip to content</a>

	<div id="boxed-wrapper">
		
		<div id="wrapper">
			
			
			<header>
				<div>
					


<div> <!-- start fusion sticky header wrapper -->
	<div>
		<div>
							<div data-margin-top="10px" data-margin-bottom="10px" data-margin-left="0px" data-margin-right="0px">
			<a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/">

						<!-- standard logo -->
			<img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/how_yellow_header_banner.gif" srcset="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/how_yellow_header_banner.gif 1x" width="736" height="87" alt="How Equipment Works Logo" data-retina_logo_url="">

			
					</a>
		</div>
										
					</div>
	</div>
	
</div> <!-- end fusion sticky header wrapper -->
				</div>
				
			</header>
						
			
		
				
			
			

						<main id="main">
				<div>
<section id="content">
					<div id="post-12735" class="page">
			<span>How pulse oximeters work explained simply</span><span><span><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/author/prastila/" title="Posts by prastila" rel="author">prastila</a></span></span><span>2020-07-18T15:06:56+00:00</span>
			
			<div>
				<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/pulse_oximeter_header.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/pulse_oximeter_header.gif" alt="pulse_oximeter_header" width="800" height="332"></a></p>
<hr>
<p>We will discuss&nbsp;the following aspects. Please scroll down and start reading.</p>
<ul>
<li>Introduction</li>
<li>Oxygen Saturation</li>
<li>Physical properties used in pulse oximetry</li>
<li>Calibration</li>
<li>Pulse oximeters measure pulsatile arterial blood</li>
<li>Signal is very small</li>
<li>Plethysmographic trace (pleth)</li>
<li>Light source</li>
<li>Coping with ambient light</li>
<li>Problems associated with using pulse oximeters.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/test_page_21_2_2018/" rel="attachment wp-att-16968"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/trust_fred.gif" alt="" width="850" height="265"></a></p>
<hr>
<h3>Introduction</h3>
<p>Pulse oximeters measure how much of the hemoglobin in blood is carrying oxygen (oxygen saturation).</p>
<p>If you work in healthcare (or have been patient !) you are very likely to have come across pulse oximeters. You can find them in areas such as operating rooms, recovery, critical care, wards, and ambulances.</p>
<p>Pulse oximeters are in common use because they are:</p>
<ul>
<li>non invasive</li>
<li>cheap to buy and use</li>
<li>can be very compact</li>
<li>detects hypoxaemia earlier than you using your eyes to see cyanosis.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3>Oxygen Saturation</h3>
<p>Pulse oximeters measure oxygen saturation. Before we learn the principles of how pulse oximeters work, we need to have an understanding of what oxygen saturation is.</p>
<p>We all know that we need oxygen for life. ( Some of you may find this section a little too basic. In that case, to skip this short section, click this link to go to next section Physical properties used in pulse oximetry )</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/solo_oxygen.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/solo_oxygen.gif" alt="solo_oxygen" width="800" height="332"></a></p>
<p>Oxygen enters the lungs and then is passed on into blood. The blood carries the oxygen to the various organs in our body. The main way oxygen is carried in our blood is by means of hemoglobin. You can imagine hemoglobin molecules( Hb) as “cars” and the “roads” being our blood vessels. The oxygen molecules get into these cars and travel around the body till they reach their destination.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/cars_wikipedia.jpg"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/cars_wikipedia.jpg" alt="cars_wikipedia" width="800" height="431" srcset="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/cars_wikipedia-300x162.jpg 300w, https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/cars_wikipedia.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px"></a></p>
<p>Let us consider these ” hemoglobin cars”.</p>
<p>The hemoglobin without oxygen we will call de oxygenated hemoglobin (deoxy Hb). The hemoglobin with oxygen, we will call oxygenated hemoglobin (oxy Hb).</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/oxy_car.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/oxy_car.gif" alt="oxy_car" width="800" height="332"></a></p>
<p>Oxygen saturation simply refers to the percentage of the available hemoglobin that carries oxygen. Take the situations below. There are 16 hemoglobin units and none of the 16 have oxygen. The oxygen saturation is therefore 0 %.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/zero_car.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/zero_car.gif" alt="zero_car" width="800" height="332"></a></p>
<p>Here, 8 of the 16 Hb have oxygen. The oxygen saturation is therefore 50 %.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/fifty_car.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/fifty_car.gif" alt="fifty_car" width="800" height="332"></a></p>
<p>Similarly for 75 % …</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/seventy_five_car.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/seventy_five_car.gif" alt="seventy_five_car" width="800" height="332"></a></p>
<p>And of course , when all the Hb have oxygen, the saturation is 100 %</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/hundred_car.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/hundred_car.gif" alt="hundred_car" width="800" height="332"></a></p>
<p>So in summary, oxygen saturation tells you the percentage of the total hemoglobin that is carrying oxygen.</p>
<hr>
<h3>Physical properties used in pulse oximetry</h3>
<p>Pulse oximetry uses light to work out oxygen saturation. Light is emitted from light sources which goes across the pulse oximeter probe and reaches the light detector.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/red_intro.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/red_intro.gif" alt="red_intro" width="800" height="332"></a></p>
<p>If a finger is placed in between the light source and the light detector, the light will now have to pass through the finger to reach the detector. Part of the light will be absorbed by the finger and the part not absorbed reaches the light detector.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/red_finger_intro.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/red_finger_intro.gif" alt="red_finger_intro" width="800" height="332"></a></p>
<p>The amount of light that is absorbed by the finger depends on many physical properties and these properties are used by the pulse oximeter to calculate the oxygen saturation.</p>
<p>The amount of light absorbed depends on the following:</p>
<p>1. concentration of the light absorbing substance.</p>
<p>2. length of the light path in the absorbing substance</p>
<p>3. oxyhemoglobin and deoxyhemoglobin absorbs red and infrared light differently</p>
<p>Don’t worry ! All the above will be explained in the next sections:</p>
<p>The physical properties that a pulse oximeter employs will be explained using the probe shown below. A finger is shown inserted into the probe. Above the finger are the light sources that emit light. In the finger is an artery which carries the blood the pulse oximeter is interested in and a vein through which the blood leaves the finger. Below the finger is the light detector.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/av_intro.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/av_intro.gif" alt="av_intro" width="800" height="332"></a></p>
<hr>
<h4>Physical property No.1 : Amount of light absorbed is proportional to the concentration of the light absorbing substance</h4>
<p>Hemoglobin (Hb) absorbs light. The amount of light absorbed is proportional to the concentration of Hb in the blood vessel. In the diagram below, the blood vessels in both fingers have the same diameter. However, one blood vessel has a low Hb concentration ( i.e. low number of Hb in each unit volume of blood) and the other blood vessel has a high Hb concentration ( i.e. high number of Hb in each unit volume of blood). Each single Hb absorbs some of the light, so more the Hb per unit area, more is the light is absorbed. This property is described in a law in physics called “Beer’s Law”.</p>
<p>Beer’s Law: Amount of light absorbed is proportional to the concentration of the light absorbing substance</p>
<p>By measuring how much light reaches the light detector, the pulse oximeter knows how much light has been absorbed. More the Hb in the finger , more is the light absorbed.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/conc_absorb.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/conc_absorb.gif" alt="conc_absorb" width="800" height="437"></a></p>
<h4>Physical property No.2 : Amount of light absorbed is proportional to the length of the light path.</h4>
<p>Look at the two fingers shown below. Both arteries have the same concentration (same Hb per unit area, blue square) However, the artery on right is wider than the one on the left.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/square_frames.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/square_frames.gif" alt="square_frames" width="800" height="437"></a></p>
<p>The light emitted from the source has to travel through the artery. The light travels in a shorter path in the narrow artery and travels through a longer path in the wider artery ( paths are shown as green lines below). Though the concentration of Hb is the same in both arteries, the light meets more Hb in the wider artery, since it travels in a longer path. Therefore, longer the path the light has to travel, more is the light absorbed. This property is described in a law in physics called “Lambert’s Law”.</p>
<p>Lambert’s Law: Amount of light absorbed is proportional to the length of the path that the light has to travel in the absorbing substance.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/light_path.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/light_path.gif" alt="light_path" width="800" height="437"></a></p>
<h4>Physical property No.3 : oxyhemoglobin absorbs more infrared light than red light &amp; deoxyhemoglobin absorbs more red light than infrared light (this is explained below !)</h4>
<p>We have seen how concentration and light path affect the absorbance of light. In addition to these, the pulse oximeter makes use of another important property to calculate oxygen saturation. That is, oxy hemoglobin and deoxy hemoglobin absorb light of different wavelengths in a specific way.</p>
<p>Before we go further, we need to remember what wavelength is. All light is composed of waves. The distance between the “tips” of the waves is equal to the wavelength.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/wavelength.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/wavelength.gif" alt="wavelength" width="800" height="332"></a></p>
<p>Light wavelengths are very short, and the unit of measurement is nanometer (nm) ( 1 meter = 1,000,000,000 nanometers !). For an example, the wave on the left has a wavelength of 650 nm and the wave on the right has a longer wavelength of 950 nm.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/wavelength_number.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/wavelength_number.gif" alt="wavelength_number" width="800" height="332"></a></p>
<p>Different “colors” of light have their own wavelength.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/wave_show.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/wave_show.gif" alt="wave_show" width="800" height="437"></a></p>
<p>The pulse oximeter uses the property that oxyhemoglobin and deoxyhemoglobin absorb light of different wavelengths in a specific way. This property can be demonstrated in a laboratory as will be now described. We can first demonstrate how oxyhemoglobin absorbs light of different wavelengths in a specific way. We use a special light source of which we can adjust the wavelength of the light it emits. This light source sequentially passes light of different wavelengths through a sample of oxy Hb. The detector notes how much light, at each wavelength, has been absorbed.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/red_multiwavelength.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/red_multiwavelength.gif" alt="red_multiwavelength" width="246" height="403"></a></p>
<hr>
<p>A graph for the absorbance of oxy hemoglobin at different wavelengths will look like this. It shows that oxy Hb doesn’t absorb the same amount of light at different wavelengths.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/oxy_curve.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/oxy_curve.gif" alt="oxy_curve" width="800" height="437"></a></p>
<p>We can repeat the same demonstration using deoxy Hb.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/blue_multiwavelength.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/blue_multiwavelength.gif" alt="blue_multiwavelength" width="246" height="403"></a></p>
<hr>
<p>Again notice , how like oxy Hb, Deoxy Hb absorbs different amount of light at different wavelengths.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/deoxy_curve.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/deoxy_curve.gif" alt="deoxy_curve" width="800" height="437"></a></p>
<p>Now let us see the absorbance graph of oxy Hb and the absorbance graph of deoxy Hb together so you can compare them. Note how each of them absorbs light of different wavelengths very differently.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/combined_curve.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/combined_curve.gif" alt="combined_curve" width="800" height="437"></a></p>
<p>The pulse oximeter uses two lights to analyze hemoglobin.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/r_ir_finger.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/r_ir_finger.gif" alt="r_ir_finger" width="800" height="437"></a></p>
<p>One is a red light, which has a wavelength of approximately 650 nm. The other is an infrared light, which has a wavelength of 950 nm. (Throughout our description, we will show the infrared light in light blue. In reality, infrared light is invisible to the human eye.)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/labelled_led.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/labelled_led.gif" alt="labelled_led" width="800" height="332"></a></p>
<p>Now look at the oxy Hb absorbance graph again, but this time paying attention to the wavelengths of light used in pulse oximeters. You will see that oxy Hb absorbs more infrared light than red light.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/oxy_absorb.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/oxy_absorb.gif" alt="oxy_absorb" width="800" height="437"></a></p>
<p>Below is the graph that shows the absorbance of deoxy Hb. It is seen from the graph that deoxy Hb absorbs more Red light than Infrared light.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/deoxy_aborb.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/deoxy_aborb.gif" alt="deoxy_aborb" width="800" height="437"></a></p>
<p>To make the comparison of absorbance of oxy Hb and deoxy Hb easier, here is a composite graph showing the absorbance of both. You will see that :</p>
<p>Oxy Hb absorbs more infrared light than red light</p>
<p>Deoxy Hb absorbs more red light than infrared light</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/combined_absorb.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/combined_absorb.gif" alt="combined_absorb" width="800" height="437"></a></p>
<p>You might find the memory aide below useful to remember the wavelengths absorbed by oxy Hb and deoxy Hb.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/absorb_memory.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/absorb_memory.gif" alt="absorb_memory" width="800" height="437"></a></p>
<p>The pulse oximeter works out the oxygen saturation by comparing how much red light and infra red light is absorbed by the blood. Depending on the amounts of oxy Hb and deoxy Hb present, the ratio of the amount of red light absorbed compared to the amount of infrared light absorbed changes.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/oxy_ratio.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/oxy_ratio.gif" alt="oxy_ratio" width="800" height="437"></a></p>
<p>Using this ratio, the pulse oximeter can then work out the oxygen saturation.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/ratio_computer.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/ratio_computer.gif" alt="ratio_computer" width="800" height="332"></a></p>
<p>For an example, at 100 % saturation, the absorbance ratio ( i.e. comparing how much red light and infrared light is absorbed) will be same as that seen with the oxy Hb absorbance curve that we saw earlier.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/hundred_ratio.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/hundred_ratio.gif" alt="hundred_ratio" width="800" height="437"></a></p>
<p>At 0 % saturation, there is only deoxy Hb. The absorbance ratio ( i.e. comparing how much red light and infrared light is absorbed) will therefore be same as that seen with the de oxy Hb absorbance curve that we saw earlier.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/zero_ratio.gif"><img src="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/zero_ratio.gif" alt="zero_ratio" width="800" height="437"></a></p>
<p>Now look at when the patient has an oxygen saturation of 75 %. The blood has both , oxy Hb and deoxy Hb. The absorbance pattern is now somewhere in between the oxy Hb curve and deoxy Hb …</p></div></div></section></div></main></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.howequipmentworks.com/pulse_oximeter/">https://www.howequipmentworks.com/pulse_oximeter/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.howequipmentworks.com/pulse_oximeter/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23863322</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 20:12:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Homemade Analytics with Ecto and Elixir]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 85 | Comments 11 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23861547">thread link</a>) | @lobo_tuerto
<br/>
July 16, 2020 | https://dashbit.co/blog/homemade-analytics-with-ecto-and-elixir | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dashbit.co/blog/homemade-analytics-with-ecto-and-elixir">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <article>
    
<ul>
  <li>
    <i></i> José Valim
  </li>
  <li>
    <i></i> July 16th, 2020
  </li>
  <li>
    <i></i><a href="https://dashbit.co/blog/tags/ecto">ecto</a>, <a href="https://dashbit.co/blog/tags/processes">processes</a>, <a href="https://dashbit.co/blog/tags/elixir">elixir</a>
  </li>
</ul>
<p>
For the Dashbit website, we wanted to avoid tracking users as much as possible. This means no cookies and unfortunately most analytics use cookies for tracking and/or fingerprinting. However, we still want to see which pages on our website are being frequently accessed. For this purpose, we have decided to roll our own analytics system.</p>
<p>
In this article, we will cover how we implemented the analytics system with Ecto upserts and how we have used the Elixir registry and Elixir processes to reduce the pressure on the database.</p>
<h2>
Tracking with upserts</h2>
<p>
The idea is very simple: every time someone accesses a page, we will store this information in the database. However, we don’t need to track each access at the instant they happen. For us, tracking how many accesses a page had in a day is completely fine. Therefore, every time a page is accessed on a given date, we will attempt to insert an entry in the database. If an entry already exists, we update its counter instead.</p>
<p>
Luckily, this can be done with an upsert in Ecto. Let’s first define the schema for the database resource:</p>
<pre><code><span>defmodule</span><span> </span><span>MyApp.Metrics.Metric</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="6781915709-1">do</span><span>
  </span><span>use</span><span> </span><span>Ecto.Schema</span><span>

  </span><span>@primary_key</span><span> </span><span>false</span><span>
  </span><span>schema</span><span> </span><span>"metrics"</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="6781915709-2">do</span><span>
    </span><span>field</span><span> </span><span>:date</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>:date</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>primary_key</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>true</span><span>
    </span><span>field</span><span> </span><span>:path</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>:string</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>primary_key</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>true</span><span>
    </span><span>field</span><span> </span><span>:counter</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>:integer</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>default</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>0</span><span>
  </span><span data-group-id="6781915709-2">end</span><span>
</span><span data-group-id="6781915709-1">end</span></code></pre>
<p>
It has three fields: a date, the page path, and the counter (number of accesses). The date and path make a composite primary key. Our migration looks like this:</p>
<pre><code><span>defmodule</span><span> </span><span>Dashbit.Repo.Migrations.CreateMetrics</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="1237551938-1">do</span><span>
  </span><span>use</span><span> </span><span>Ecto.Migration</span><span>

  </span><span>def</span><span> </span><span>change</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="1237551938-2">do</span><span>
    </span><span>create</span><span> </span><span>table</span><span data-group-id="1237551938-3">(</span><span>:metrics</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>primary_key</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>false</span><span data-group-id="1237551938-3">)</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="1237551938-4">do</span><span>
      </span><span>add</span><span> </span><span>:date</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>:date</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>primary_key</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>true</span><span>
      </span><span>add</span><span> </span><span>:path</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>:string</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>primary_key</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>true</span><span>
      </span><span>add</span><span> </span><span>:counter</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>:integer</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>default</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>0</span><span>
    </span><span data-group-id="1237551938-4">end</span><span>
  </span><span data-group-id="1237551938-2">end</span><span>
</span><span data-group-id="1237551938-1">end</span></code></pre>
<p>
Now we execute the following command whenever we want to count one page access:</p>
<pre><code><span>defp</span><span> </span><span>upsert!</span><span data-group-id="9701504210-1">(</span><span>path</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>counter</span><span data-group-id="9701504210-1">)</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="9701504210-2">do</span><span>
  </span><span>import</span><span> </span><span>Ecto.Query</span><span>
  </span><span>date</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>Date</span><span>.</span><span>utc_today</span><span data-group-id="9701504210-3">(</span><span data-group-id="9701504210-3">)</span><span>
  </span><span>query</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>from</span><span data-group-id="9701504210-4">(</span><span>m</span><span> </span><span>in</span><span> </span><span>Dashbit.Metrics.Metric</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>update</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="9701504210-5">[</span><span>inc</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="9701504210-6">[</span><span>counter</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>^</span><span>counter</span><span data-group-id="9701504210-6">]</span><span data-group-id="9701504210-5">]</span><span data-group-id="9701504210-4">)</span><span>

  </span><span>Dashbit.Repo</span><span>.</span><span>insert!</span><span data-group-id="9701504210-7">(</span><span>
    </span><span data-group-id="9701504210-8">%</span><span data-group-id="9701504210-8">Dashbit.Metrics.Metric</span><span data-group-id="9701504210-8">{</span><span>date</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>date</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>path</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>path</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>counter</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>counter</span><span data-group-id="9701504210-8">}</span><span>,</span><span>
    </span><span>on_conflict</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>query</span><span>,</span><span>
    </span><span>conflict_target</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="9701504210-9">[</span><span>:date</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>:path</span><span data-group-id="9701504210-9">]</span><span>
  </span><span data-group-id="9701504210-7">)</span><span>
</span><span data-group-id="9701504210-2">end</span></code></pre>
<p>
The code above performs an upsert, incrementing the number of accesses in a page by the value of <code>counter</code>, which is typically 1. If an entry does not exist, one is immediately created.</p>
<p>
This is the core of our analytics. It is a very straight-forward solution, but it does have a strong requirement on the database accepting all of our writes. While most applications heavily rely on a database, the analytics system is the only place in our website that uses a database, so we believe it is important to show an article, such as this blog post, even if there is an error when talking to the storage layer. To address this, we have decided to move the upserts to separate processes.</p>
<h2>
Async and batched writes with processes</h2>
<p>
As laid out in the previous section, we want to move all the database writes done by our analytics code to a separate process. Another concern we have with our solution so far is how it will handle overloads. If there is a huge spike in traffic, could we end up putting too much pressure in the database? In this sense, would it be a good idea to batch our writes?</p>
<p>
To be honest, our application will be just fine with spikes. Most of our page loads are within hundreds of microseconds, thanks to Phoenix, and our database usage is minimal. On the other hand, such a small project is a perfect opportunity to experiment, so we decided to explore how our analytics solution would look like if we performed writes asynchronously and in batches.</p>
<p>
Here is what we came up with. Every time a user accesses a page, we will spawn an Elixir process that tracks all accesses to that page. If a process already exists for said page, we will message the existing process instead. The goal of this process is to collect all accesses within a time interval, writing to the database after X seconds.</p>
<p>
We are going to call this the <code>Worker</code> process and it starts like this:</p>
<pre><code><span>defmodule</span><span> </span><span>Dashbit.Metrics.Worker</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="5734826703-1">do</span><span>
  </span><span>use</span><span> </span><span>GenServer</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>restart</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>:temporary</span></code></pre>
<p>
We define a module for the process and declare it as a <a href="https://hexdocs.pm/elixir/GenServer.html"><code>GenServer</code></a>. We also say that this process is <code>:temporary</code>. I.e. if it dies, we don’t want the supervisor to restart it. That’s because we are assuming that, if the process dies, our logic that dynamically spawns processes for each page will eventually start a new one anyway.</p>
<p>
Next we define the <code>init</code> callback of the process:</p>
<pre><code><span>  </span><span>@impl</span><span> </span><span>true</span><span>
  </span><span>def</span><span> </span><span>init</span><span data-group-id="1587488502-1">(</span><span>path</span><span data-group-id="1587488502-1">)</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="1587488502-2">do</span><span>
    </span><span>Process</span><span>.</span><span>flag</span><span data-group-id="1587488502-3">(</span><span>:trap_exit</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>true</span><span data-group-id="1587488502-3">)</span><span>
    </span><span data-group-id="1587488502-4">{</span><span>:ok</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="1587488502-5">{</span><span>path</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>_counter</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>0</span><span data-group-id="1587488502-5">}</span><span data-group-id="1587488502-4">}</span><span>
  </span><span data-group-id="1587488502-2">end</span></code></pre>
<p>
The <code>init</code> callback traps exits and sets the process state to <code>{path, 0}</code>. The first element is the page path, the second element is the number of page visits.</p>
<p>
Our process should be able to receive a <code>:bump</code> message. This message is sent whenever we need to bump the counter and is handled by the <code>handle_info</code> callback:</p>
<pre><code><span>  </span><span>@impl</span><span> </span><span>true</span><span>
  </span><span>def</span><span> </span><span>handle_info</span><span data-group-id="7044761336-1">(</span><span>:bump</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="7044761336-2">{</span><span>path</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>0</span><span data-group-id="7044761336-2">}</span><span data-group-id="7044761336-1">)</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="7044761336-3">do</span><span>
    </span><span>schedule_upsert</span><span data-group-id="7044761336-4">(</span><span data-group-id="7044761336-4">)</span><span>
    </span><span data-group-id="7044761336-5">{</span><span>:noreply</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="7044761336-6">{</span><span>path</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>1</span><span data-group-id="7044761336-6">}</span><span data-group-id="7044761336-5">}</span><span>
  </span><span data-group-id="7044761336-3">end</span><span>

  </span><span>@impl</span><span> </span><span>true</span><span>
  </span><span>def</span><span> </span><span>handle_info</span><span data-group-id="7044761336-7">(</span><span>:bump</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="7044761336-8">{</span><span>path</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>counter</span><span data-group-id="7044761336-8">}</span><span data-group-id="7044761336-7">)</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="7044761336-9">do</span><span>
    </span><span data-group-id="7044761336-10">{</span><span>:noreply</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="7044761336-11">{</span><span>path</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>counter</span><span> </span><span>+</span><span> </span><span>1</span><span data-group-id="7044761336-11">}</span><span data-group-id="7044761336-10">}</span><span>
  </span><span data-group-id="7044761336-9">end</span></code></pre>
<p>
If we receive the <code>:bump</code> when the page had no access (i.e. counter is zero), we will bump the counter to 1 and we will also schedule an upsert event, so we eventually write those accesses to the database. If the counter is more than 0, we simply bump it and return an updated state.</p>
<p>
The scheduling and upsert code will look like this:</p>
<pre><code><span>  </span><span>defp</span><span> </span><span>schedule_upsert</span><span data-group-id="6238594391-1">(</span><span data-group-id="6238594391-1">)</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="6238594391-2">do</span><span>
    </span><span>Process</span><span>.</span><span>send_after</span><span data-group-id="6238594391-3">(</span><span>self</span><span data-group-id="6238594391-4">(</span><span data-group-id="6238594391-4">)</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>:upsert</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>Enum</span><span>.</span><span>random</span><span data-group-id="6238594391-5">(</span><span>10</span><span>.</span><span>.</span><span>20</span><span data-group-id="6238594391-5">)</span><span> </span><span>*</span><span> </span><span>1_000</span><span data-group-id="6238594391-3">)</span><span>
  </span><span data-group-id="6238594391-2">end</span><span>

  </span><span>@impl</span><span> </span><span>true</span><span>
  </span><span>def</span><span> </span><span>handle_info</span><span data-group-id="6238594391-6">(</span><span>:upsert</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="6238594391-7">{</span><span>path</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>counter</span><span data-group-id="6238594391-7">}</span><span data-group-id="6238594391-6">)</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="6238594391-8">do</span><span>
    </span><span>upsert!</span><span data-group-id="6238594391-9">(</span><span>path</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>counter</span><span data-group-id="6238594391-9">)</span><span>
    </span><span data-group-id="6238594391-10">{</span><span>:noreply</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="6238594391-11">{</span><span>path</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>0</span><span data-group-id="6238594391-11">}</span><span data-group-id="6238594391-10">}</span><span>
  </span><span data-group-id="6238594391-8">end</span><span>

  </span><span>defp</span><span> </span><span>upsert!</span><span data-group-id="6238594391-12">(</span><span>path</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>counter</span><span data-group-id="6238594391-12">)</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="6238594391-13">do</span><span>
    </span><span># same function as the previous section</span><span>
  </span><span data-group-id="6238594391-13">end</span></code></pre>
<p>
The <code>schedule_upsert()</code> function schedules a message to the current process (<code>self()</code>). The message will be named <code>:upsert</code> and it will be delivered in a random value between 10s to 20s. The reason we picked a random value is to avoid a scenario where multiple processes for different pages are spawned at the same time and they all write to the database at the same time.</p>
<p>
Next we define another <code>handle_info</code> clause, this time to handle the scheduled <code>:upsert</code> message. This clause simply invokes the <code>upsert!</code> function, defined in the previous section, and resets the state back to <code>{path, 0}</code>. This makes it so that, once there is a new bump, we will schedule a new upsert.</p>
<p>
Finally, we implement the <code>terminate</code> callback, which will be invoked whenever our application is shutting down:</p>
<pre><code><span>  </span><span>@impl</span><span> </span><span>true</span><span>
  </span><span>def</span><span> </span><span>terminate</span><span data-group-id="1299229119-1">(</span><span>_</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="1299229119-2">{</span><span>_path</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>0</span><span data-group-id="1299229119-2">}</span><span data-group-id="1299229119-1">)</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>do</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>:ok</span><span>
  </span><span>def</span><span> </span><span>terminate</span><span data-group-id="1299229119-3">(</span><span>_</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="1299229119-4">{</span><span>path</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>counter</span><span data-group-id="1299229119-4">}</span><span data-group-id="1299229119-3">)</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>do</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>upsert!</span><span data-group-id="1299229119-5">(</span><span>path</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>counter</span><span data-group-id="1299229119-5">)</span><span>
</span><span>end</span></code></pre>
<p>
If our application is shutting down, we may have pending writes in our worker, so we want to send them to the database as part of our termination logic. One important thing to remember is that the <code>terminate</code> callback is not called by default when shutting down, unless you are trapping exits. That’s why we called <code>Process.flag(:trap_exit, true)</code> in the <code>init</code> function.</p>
<p>
The process we just implemented delivers all of the requirements we have so far: writes are now asynchronous, as they happen in a separate process, and they are also batched, using intervals between 10s and 20s. The last step we need to implement is to actually spawn those processes on the fly as users navigate through the website.</p>
<h2>
Dynamic processes with the Elixir registry</h2>
<p>
In order to spawn and find processes for each page, we are going to use <a href="https://hexdocs.pm/elixir/Registry.html">Elixir’s <code>Registry</code></a>. We also need a dynamic supervisor which is going to be the parent of all worker processes. Let’s implement this logic in the overaching <code>Metrics</code> module, alongside our <code>bump(page)</code> function.</p>
<p>
Let’s get started with the basics:</p>
<pre><code><span>defmodule</span><span> </span><span>Dashbit.Metrics</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="8546136914-1">do</span><span>
  </span><span>use</span><span> </span><span>Supervisor</span><span>

  </span><span>@worker</span><span> </span><span>Dashbit.Metrics.Worker</span><span>
  </span><span>@registry</span><span> </span><span>Dashbit.Metrics.Registry</span><span>
  </span><span>@supervisor</span><span> </span><span>Dashbit.Metrics.WorkerSupervisor</span></code></pre>
<p>
Our <code>Dashbit.Metrics</code> module is a <a href="https://hexdocs.pm/elixir/Supervisor.html"><code>Supervisor</code></a>, which will have two children: the registry and the supervisor of all workers. Since the workers are started dynamically, as requests come, we will use a <code>DynamicSupervisor</code>. We store the names of the worker, registry and dynamic supervisor processes in module attributes for convenience.</p>
<p>
Next we will define how our supervisor is started and its <code>init</code> callback:</p>
<pre><code><span>  </span><span>def</span><span> </span><span>start_link</span><span data-group-id="8570317183-1">(</span><span>_opts</span><span data-group-id="8570317183-1">)</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="8570317183-2">do</span><span>
    </span><span>Supervisor</span><span>.</span><span>start_link</span><span data-group-id="8570317183-3">(</span><span>__MODULE__</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>:ok</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>name</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>__MODULE__</span><span data-group-id="8570317183-3">)</span><span>
  </span><span data-group-id="8570317183-2">end</span><span>

  </span><span>@impl</span><span> </span><span>true</span><span>
  </span><span>def</span><span> </span><span>init</span><span data-group-id="8570317183-4">(</span><span>:ok</span><span data-group-id="8570317183-4">)</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="8570317183-5">do</span><span>
    </span><span>children</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="8570317183-6">[</span><span>
      </span><span data-group-id="8570317183-7">{</span><span>Registry</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>keys</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>:unique</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>name</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>@registry</span><span data-group-id="8570317183-7">}</span><span>,</span><span>
      </span><span data-group-id="8570317183-8">{</span><span>DynamicSupervisor</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>name</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>@supervisor</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>strategy</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>:one_for_one</span><span data-group-id="8570317183-8">}</span><span>
    </span><span data-group-id="8570317183-6">]</span><span>

    </span><span>Supervisor</span><span>.</span><span>init</span><span data-group-id="8570317183-9">(</span><span>children</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>strategy</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>:one_for_all</span><span data-group-id="8570317183-9">)</span><span>
  </span><span data-group-id="8570317183-5">end</span></code></pre>
<p>
With the registry and dynamic supervisor in place, we can write the bump function:</p>
<pre><code><span>  </span><span>def</span><span> </span><span>bump</span><span data-group-id="1140714578-1">(</span><span>path</span><span data-group-id="1140714578-1">)</span><span> </span><span>when</span><span> </span><span>is_binary</span><span data-group-id="1140714578-2">(</span><span>path</span><span data-group-id="1140714578-2">)</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="1140714578-3">do</span><span>
    </span><span>pid</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span>
      </span><span>case</span><span> </span><span>Registry</span><span>.</span><span>lookup</span><span data-group-id="1140714578-4">(</span><span>@registry</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>path</span><span data-group-id="1140714578-4">)</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="1140714578-5">do</span><span>
        </span><span data-group-id="1140714578-6">[</span><span data-group-id="1140714578-7">{</span><span>pid</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>_</span><span data-group-id="1140714578-7">}</span><span data-group-id="1140714578-6">]</span><span> </span><span>-&gt;</span><span>
          </span><span>pid</span><span>

        </span><span data-group-id="1140714578-8">[</span><span data-group-id="1140714578-8">]</span><span> </span><span>-&gt;</span><span>
          </span><span>case</span><span> </span><span>DynamicSupervisor</span><span>.</span><span>start_child</span><span data-group-id="1140714578-9">(</span><span>@supervisor</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="1140714578-10">{</span><span>@worker</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>path</span><span data-group-id="1140714578-10">}</span><span data-group-id="1140714578-9">)</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="1140714578-11">do</span><span>
            </span><span data-group-id="1140714578-12">{</span><span>:ok</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>pid</span><span data-group-id="1140714578-12">}</span><span> </span><span>-&gt;</span><span> </span><span>pid</span><span>
            </span><span data-group-id="1140714578-13">{</span><span>:error</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span data-group-id="1140714578-14">{</span><span>:already_started</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>pid</span><span data-group-id="1140714578-14">}</span><span data-group-id="1140714578-13">}</span><span> </span><span>-&gt;</span><span> </span><span>pid</span><span>
          </span><span data-group-id="1140714578-11">end</span><span>
      </span><span data-group-id="1140714578-5">end</span><span>

    </span><span>send</span><span data-group-id="1140714578-15">(</span><span>pid</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>:bump</span><span data-group-id="1140714578-15">)</span><span>
  </span><span data-group-id="1140714578-3">end</span><span>
</span><span>end</span></code></pre>
<p>
The <code>bump</code> function looks up in the registry if there is a process for the given path and returns its process identifier (<code>pid</code>). If one does not exist, we ask the worker supervisor to start a worker dynamically. We expect two possible outcomes from <code>start_child</code>:</p>
<ul>
  <li>
    <p>
<code>{:ok, pid}</code> - the worker was started    </p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>
<code>{:error, {:already_started, pid}}</code> - a worker for the given <code>path</code> already exists    </p>
  </li>
</ul>
<p>
We need the second branch to address a potential race condition where two users may access a page for the first time at the same time. In this scenario, the <code>Registry.lookup/2</code> will fail for both them, and both will attempt to spawn the worker. One of them will succeed and the other will return the “already started” error. Once we find the <code>pid</code>, we send it the <code>:bump</code> message.</p>
<p>
We are almost there. There are just two steps left. …</p></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://dashbit.co/blog/homemade-analytics-with-ecto-and-elixir">https://dashbit.co/blog/homemade-analytics-with-ecto-and-elixir</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dashbit.co/blog/homemade-analytics-with-ecto-and-elixir</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23861547</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 17:43:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Let's make a Teeny Tiny compiler]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 36 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23861398">thread link</a>) | @pavehawk2007
<br/>
July 16, 2020 | http://austinhenley.com/blog/teenytinycompiler1.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://austinhenley.com/blog/teenytinycompiler1.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<div>


<br><h3>Let's make a Teeny Tiny compiler, part 1</h3><p><small>5/5/2020</small></p><p>

<img src="http://austinhenley.com/blog/images/knightdragon.jpg"></p><p><i>This is the first post in a three part series. Check out <a href="http://web.eecs.utk.edu/~azh/blog/teenytinycompiler2.html">part 2</a> and <a href="http://web.eecs.utk.edu/~azh/blog/teenytinycompiler3.html">part 3</a> when you are ready.</i></p>

<p>It is a beautiful day outside, so let's make a compiler. You don't need any knowledge of how compilers work to follow along. We are going to use Python to implement our own programming language, Teeny Tiny, that will compile to C code. It will take about 500 lines of code and provide the initial infrastructure needed to customize and extend the compiler into your own billion dollar production-ready compiler.</p>

<p>This tutorial is a series of posts that go step by step in building a working compiler. All of the source code can be found in the GitHub <a href="https://github.com/AZHenley/teenytinycompiler">repo</a>. If you follow along with all the posts, I guesstimate that it will take you only a few hours.

</p><p>The Teeny Tiny language we are going to implement is a dialect of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BASIC">BASIC</a>. The syntax is clean and simple. If you prefer a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/C_(programming_language)">C</a>-like syntax then it will be trivial to modify the compiler at the end.  Here is an example program in our Teeny Tiny language:</p>

<pre>PRINT "How many fibonacci numbers do you want?"
INPUT nums

LET a = 0
LET b = 1
WHILE nums &gt; 0 REPEAT
    PRINT a
    LET c = a + b
    LET a = b
    LET b = c
    LET nums = nums - 1
ENDWHILE	
</pre>

<p>This program prints out terms of the fibonacci sequence based on the user's input: 0 1 1 2 3 5 13...</p>

<p>Our language will allow a variety of the basic operations that you'd expect from a programming language. In particular, it will support:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Numerical variables</li>
	<li>Basic arithmetic</li>
	<li>If statements</li>
	<li>While loops</li>
	<li>Print text and numbers</li>
	<li>Input numbers</li>
	<li>Labels and goto</li>
	<li>Comments</li>
</ul>

<p>Although this is a standard subset of features, you may notice that there are no functions, no arrays, no way to read/write from a file, and not even an else statement. But with just this small set of constructs, you can actually do a lot. It will also setup the compiler in such a way that many other features will be straight forward to add later.</p>

<h4>Compiler Overview</h4>

<p><img src="http://austinhenley.com/blog/images/compilersteps.png"></p><p>Our compiler will follow a three step process that is illustrated above. First, given the inputted source code, it will break the code up into <i>tokens</i>. These are like words and punctuation in English. Second, it will <i>parse</i> the tokens to make sure they are in an order that is allowed in our language. Just like English sentences follow specific structures of verbs and nouns. Third, it will <i>emit</i> the C code that our language will translate to.</p>

<p>We will use these three steps as the main organization for our code. The lexer, parser, and emitter will each have their own Python code file. This tutorial is broken up into 3 parts based on these steps as well. If you were to extend the compiler, there are some additional steps you would add, but we will hold off on discussing those.</p>



<h4>Lexer Overview</h4>

<p>The first module of our compiler is called the <i>lexer</i>. Given a string of Teeny Tiny code, it will iterate character by character to do two things: decide where each token starts/stops and what type of token it is. If the lexer is unable to do this, then it will report an error for an invalid token.</p>

<p><img src="http://austinhenley.com/blog/images/tokens.png"></p><p>The figure demonstrates an example input and output of the lexer. Given the Teeny Tiny code, the lexer must determine where the tokens are along with the type (e.g., keyword). You can see that spaces aren't recognized as tokens, but the lexer will use them as one way to know when a token ends.</p>

<p>Let's finally get into some code, starting with the structure of the lexer in the file <b>lex.py</b>:</p>

<pre>class Lexer:
    def __init__(self, input):
        pass

    # Process the next character.
    def nextChar(self):
        pass

    # Return the lookahead character.
    def peek(self):
        pass

    # Invalid token found, print error message and exit.
    def abort(self, message):
        pass
		
    # Skip whitespace except newlines, which we will use to indicate the end of a statement.
    def skipWhitespace(self):
        pass
		
    # Skip comments in the code.
    def skipComment(self):
        pass

    # Return the next token.
    def getToken(self):
        pass
</pre>

<p>I like to sketch out all the functions that I think I will need, then go back and fill them in. The function <b>getToken</b> will be the meat of the lexer. It will be called each time the compiler is ready for the next token and it will do the work of classifying tokens. <b>nextChar</b> and <b>peek</b> are helper functions for looking at the next character. <b>skipWhitespace</b> consumes the spaces and tabs that we don't care about. <b>abort</b> is what we will use to report an invalid token.</p>

<p>The lexer needs to keep track of the current position in the input string and the character at that position. We will initialize these in the constructor:</p>

<pre>    def __init__(self, input):
        self.source = input + '\n' # Source code to lex as a string. Append a newline to simplify lexing/parsing the last token/statement.
        self.curChar = ''   # Current character in the string.
        self.curPos = -1    # Current position in the string.
        self.nextChar()
</pre>

<p>The lexer needs the input code and we append a newline to it (this just simplifies some checks later on). <b>curChar</b> is what the lexer will constantly check to decide what kind of token it is. Why not just do <i>source[curPos]</i>? Because that would litter the code with bounds checking. Instead we do this in <b>nextChar</b>:</p>

<pre>    # Process the next character.
    def nextChar(self):
        self.curPos += 1
        if self.curPos &gt;= len(self.source):
            self.curChar = '\0'  # EOF
        else:
            self.curChar = self.source[self.curPos]
</pre>

<p>This increments the lexer's current position and updates the current character. If we reach the end of the input, set the character to the end-of-file marker. This is the only place we will modify curPos and curChar. But sometimes we want to look ahead to the next character without updating curPos:</p>

<pre>    # Return the lookahead character.
    def peek(self):
        if self.curPos + 1 &gt;= len(self.source):
            return '\0'
        return self.source[self.curPos+1]
</pre>

<p>We should make sure these functions work. Let's test them by create a new file <b>teenytiny.py</b>:</p>

<pre>from lex import *

def main():
	input = "LET foobar = 123"
	lexer = Lexer(input)

	while lexer.peek() != '\0':
		print(lexer.curChar)
		lexer.nextChar()

main()
</pre>

<p>Run this and the output should be every character of the input string, <i>LET foobar = 123</i>, on a new line:</p>

<pre>L
E 
T 

f 
o 
o 
b 
a 
r 

= 

1 
2 
3 

</pre>

<h4>Classifying Tokens</h4>

<p>But we don't just want characters, we want tokens! We need to plan how combining individual characters together makes a token, which works much like a state machine. Here are the main lexer rules for the Teeny Tiny language:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Operator. One or two consecutive characters that matches: + - * / = == != &gt; &lt; &gt;= &lt;=</li>
	<li>String. Double quotation followed by zero or more characters and a double quotation. Such as: "hello, world!" and ""</li>
	<li>Number. One or more numeric characters followed by an optional decimal point and one or more numeric characters. Such as: 15 and 3.14</li>
	<li>Identifier. An alphabetical character followed by zero or more alphanumeric characters.</li>
	<li>Keyword. Exact text match of: LABEL, GOTO, PRINT, INPUT, LET, IF, THEN, ENDIF, WHILE, REPEAT, ENDWHILE</li>
</ul>

<p>Next we will start our <b>getToken</b> function in our <b>Lexer</b> class:</p>

<pre>    # Return the next token.
    def getToken(self):
        # Check the first character of this token to see if we can decide what it is.
        # If it is a multiple character operator (e.g., !=), number, identifier, or keyword then we will process the rest.
        if self.curChar == '+':
            pass	# Plus token.
        elif self.curChar == '-':
            pass	# Minus token.
        elif self.curChar == '*':
            pass	# Asterisk token.
        elif self.curChar == '/':
            pass	# Slash token.
        elif self.curChar == '\n':
            pass	# Newline token.
        elif self.curChar == '\0':
            pass	# EOF token.
        else:
            # Unknown token!
            pass
			
        self.nextChar()
</pre>

<p>This will detect a few possible tokens, but doesn't do anything useful yet. What we need next is a <b>Token</b> class to keep track of what type of token it is and the exact text from the code. Place this in <b>Lex.py</b> for now:</p>

<pre># Token contains the original text and the type of token.
class Token:   
    def __init__(self, tokenText, tokenKind):
        self.text = tokenText   # The token's actual text. Used for identifiers, strings, and numbers.
        self.kind = tokenKind   # The TokenType that this token is classified as.
</pre>

<p>To specify what type a token is, we will create the <b>TokenType</b> class as an enum. It looks long, but it just specifies every possible token our language allows. Add <i>import enum</i> to the top of <b>Lex.py</b> and add this class:</p>

<pre># TokenType is our enum for all the types of tokens.
class TokenType(enum.Enum):
	EOF = -1
	NEWLINE = 0
	NUMBER = 1
	IDENT = 2
	STRING = 3
	# Keywords.
	LABEL = 101
	GOTO = 102
	PRINT = 103
	INPUT = 104
	LET = 105
	IF = 106
	THEN = 107
	ENDIF = 108
	WHILE = 109
	REPEAT = 110
	ENDWHILE = 111
	# Operators.
	EQ = 201  
	PLUS = 202
	MINUS = 203
	ASTERISK = 204
	SLASH = 205
	EQEQ = 206
	NOTEQ = 207
	LT = 208
	LTEQ = 209
	GT = 210
	GTEQ = 211
</pre>

<p>Now we can expand <b>getToken</b> to actually do something when it detects a specific token:</p>

<pre>    # Return the next token.
    def getToken(self):
        token = None

        # Check the first character of this token to see if we can decide what it is.
        # If it is a multiple character operator (e.g., !=), number, identifier, or keyword then we will process the rest.
        if self.curChar == '+':
            token = Token(self.curChar, TokenType.PLUS)
        elif self.curChar == '-':
            token = Token(self.curChar, TokenType.MINUS)
        elif self.curChar == '*':
            token = Token(self.curChar, TokenType.ASTERISK)
        elif self.curChar == '/':
            token = Token(self.curChar, TokenType.SLASH)
        elif self.curChar == '\n':
            token = …</pre></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://austinhenley.com/blog/teenytinycompiler1.html">http://austinhenley.com/blog/teenytinycompiler1.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://austinhenley.com/blog/teenytinycompiler1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23861398</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 17:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[No, you couldn't have made more money than the Twitter hacker]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 235 | Comments 273 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23860584">thread link</a>) | @fortenforge
<br/>
July 16, 2020 | https://fortenf.org/e/security/2020/07/15/twitter-hack.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://fortenf.org/e/security/2020/07/15/twitter-hack.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <div>
  
  <p><span>Jul 15, 2020</span></p><p>Picture this: you’ve stumbled across the vulnerability of the year. You figured out how to gain access to any verified Twitter user’s account: Joe Biden, Kim Kardashian, Kanye West, XXXTentacion, Apple, you name it. That was step 1 of your evil plan. What should step 2 be?</p>

<p>Maybe you log into the president’s account and post a fake tweet about launching missiles to North Korea. I’m not convinced that you can start a world war just by sending out a few fake tweets, but for the sake of argument let’s say that you can. But you’re not interested in watching the world burn anyway; no, your goal is to <strong>make as much money as possible</strong>. What should you do?</p>

<p>The people who carried out today’s Twitter hack had one answer: post variants of the message “send 1 BTC to this address and I’ll send 2 BTC back”  on famous accounts, and then (here’s the kicker) <em>don’t actually send 2 BTC back</em>.</p>

<p><img src="https://video-images.vice.com/test-uploads/_uncategorized/1594848885006-image.png" alt="image"></p>

<p>They managed to run off with a little over <a href="https://www.blockchain.com/btc/address/bc1qxy2kgdygjrsqtzq2n0yrf2493p83kkfjhx0wlh?page=2">$100,000</a> before Twitter got the situation under control. Several people (on Twitter, on Hacker News, everywhere really) scoffed at this and claimed that they would have done something much more interesting with this kind of power. Let’s explore some of their ideas to see if we really can do better.</p>

<!--more-->

<h2 id="stock-market-manipulation">Stock Market Manipulation</h2>

<p>This is the first thing that comes to most people’s minds. It sounds easy: buy a bunch of Tesla stock, log into Elon Musk’s account, tweet “Taking $TSLA private at $2000,” and sell in the time between the rise in price and when Musk/Twitter/the whole world realizes the hack.</p>

<p>This requires a fair amount of capital to buy the underlying stock, which the hacker may not have had, but there are other options: maybe you short the stock and then tweet (fake) damaging information about Tesla’s new line of cars. Maybe you just short Twitter’s own stock, which will surely take a huge hit in the market tomorrow (the hack was executed after trading hours).</p>

<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">oh lol i'd buy HTZ, that's the trade. "i've decided that Tesla will buy Hertz out of bankruptcy at $69 per share and make its fleet entirely self-driving," i'd be a billionaire and Money Stuff would end on the highest possible note</p>— Matt Levine (@matt_levine) <a href="https://twitter.com/matt_levine/status/1283503080978489344?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 15, 2020</a></blockquote>


<p>The big issue with all of these is that it’s very difficult to participate in the stock market anonymously. The SEC has all sorts of monitoring in place to catch more common forms of insider trading and fraud and you can guarantee that they would conduct a long, thorough investigation into a hypothetical hack-based market fraud. Unlike Bitcoin transactions, wire transfers and stock purchases can be reversed after the fact, and the exposure and risk go way up when you’re actually working with US dollars.</p>

<h2 id="blackmail">Blackmail</h2>

<p>The hackers got <em>full access</em> to all Twitter-verified accounts, meaning that they should have had access to their direct messages. Surely this is much more valuable than just posting a fake tweet? Think about the incalculable damage caused by the <a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2019/10/the-untold-story-of-the-sony-hack">Sony leaks</a> or watch this hypothetical-but-still-terrifying <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y4GB_NDU43Q">Tom Scott video</a> about a world in which Gmail password-checking was turned off for a day.</p>

<p>It’s definitely true that there are gobs of interesting material lurking in verified users’s DMs that they wouldn’t want seeing the light of day, but it’s a little tricky to make money from this. The most obvious method is blackmail. Exfiltrate the messages from the most popular users and threaten that you’ll release them in full if they don’t send X BTC to Y address.</p>

<p>This would definitely make some amount of money, but I’m not convinced it’s worth the effort. Firstly, it’s hard to judge ahead of time which accounts have the juicy DMs. Large, high-profile accounts like Joe Biden’s are run by a whole social media team and probably don’t exchange sensitive information via Twitter. Smaller accounts probably do have more interesting gossip, but might be less willing or able to pay as a result.</p>

<p>Then there’s the problem of actually exfiltrating and storing all the data, sending individual messages to each of the users you hack, tracking who has and hasn’t paid, and actually releasing the leaked material publicly. It’s a lot of operational overhead that may, in the end, net you less money than the dumb Bitcoin scam.</p>

<h2 id="sell-it-on-the-dark-web">Sell it on the dark web</h2>

<p>Leave aside the challenge of actually finding a buyer (you can’t just make a post on a forum, the Feds read the dark web too). How much should a buyer be willing to pay you for this bug? Either the buyer is planning to monetize the exploit for more than $100k (the whole point of this post is to prove that that’s really hard!), or the buyer wants to use the exploit for other purposes, like surveillance or intelligence gathering.</p>

<p>This isn’t out of the question. Countries spy on each other all the time, and I’m sure that China would love to be able to read the DMs of journalists or Hong Kong activists. The issue is that this particular exploit wasn’t terribly suited to the business of long-term surveillance. Logging into the account required actually the email associated with it and triggering a password reset (that somehow also bypassed 2FA). The password reset triggered a notification email to the original address on file, which basically announced the account takeover. The hacker had a matter of hours before the whole world knew about the vulnerability.</p>

<p>Intelligence agencies want <em>persistent</em> access, and they want to surveil without their targets learning that they were surveilled. This exploit wouldn’t have accomplished that.</p>

<h2 id="bug-bounty">Bug Bounty</h2>

<p>Now we’re getting somewhere… Large companies <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnkoetsier/2020/05/31/hacker-finds-huge-apple-security-hole-apple-pays-100000-bug-bounty/#576388b36894">routinely</a> pay out vast sums of money to white hat hackers reporting flaws that are less damaging than this one. Even if Twitter wouldn’t pay out 100% as much money as was made via the Bitcoin scam, bug bounty programs have the added benefit of being 100% legal, which should change the risk calculus significantly. So why didn’t our hacker take this route?</p>

<p>One theory is that if the hacker was already a known criminal, it’s tricky to collect the bug bounty payout without revealing their identity to Twitter, which might still end them up in some trouble. I’m not sure I buy this (can’t they just use a third party?).</p>

<p>More plausibly, perhaps Twitter wouldn’t actually have paid out $100k?</p>

<blockquote><p lang="und" dir="ltr">🤔 <a href="https://t.co/I902KoaZwe">pic.twitter.com/I902KoaZwe</a></p>— LiveOverflow 🔴 (@LiveOverflow) <a href="https://twitter.com/LiveOverflow/status/1283511782380908545?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 15, 2020</a></blockquote>


<p>This tweet suggests that OAuth takeovers were valued at $7.7k (and after taxes you’re left with chump change). If so, this a big issue with Twitter’s bug bounty program! You need to ensure that the incentives make reporting more worth it than exploiting.</p>

<p><em>Update: more reporting about how the account takeovers were executed <a href="https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/jgxd3d/twitter-insider-access-panel-account-hacks-biden-uber-bezos">has emerged</a>, and it suggests that there wasn’t any technical vulnerability that was ever exploited. Social engineering and insider risk (which can obviously be quite damaging) tend not to be eligible for bounties on most programs.</em></p>

<h2 id="phishing">Phishing</h2>

<p>OK how about this: log into Coinbase’s twitter account, craft a tweet announcing some snazzy new feature and include a bit.ly link that actually goes to a phishing website. Execute a <a href="https://fortenf.org/e/2018/05/29/coinbase-phishing.html">relay phishing attack</a> that gives you access to their Coinbase account while bypassing 2FA, and then send all their Bitcoin and Ethereum and Dogecoin to your own account.</p>

<p>There are a few flaws, but most are surmountable with some effort. First, Twitter would probably take down the tweet pretty fast, so you’d probably want to target several different accounts of famous cryptocurrency enthusiasts (not just Coinbase). Second, bit.ly would probably disable that specific URL and Google would definitely add the phishing site to their <a href="https://safebrowsing.google.com/">Safe Browsing</a> list (which is shared by all major browsers). This would result in big scary red warning banners appearing before users could access your site. Also, whatever registrar you purchased your domain from would probably revoke it.</p>

<p>OK, so instead of having one phishing site and one domain and one URL you’d want to set up several of these in advance and hop from one to the other as each gets taken down by various actors in turn. This would probably work! Would it net you more than $100k? Maybe?! It’s hard to say and probably depends a lot on luck and timing. The people with the most cryptocurrency in their Coinbase accounts are probably the least likely to fall for this kind of thing in the first place, so it’s unclear how much more money you’d make than the dumb 2-for-1 scam, but still, it might be worth it in case you manage to compromise an account with huge reserves.</p>

<p>Still, all this requires some legitimately difficult software engineering work and the whole point of this was to make easy money! I understand that today’s attack was almost painfully lame in its execution, but it really may have been the smartest choice tactically.</p>

<p>This is not to say that they did everything right: I still can’t explain why they seem to have used only 1 BTC address throughout the process (Coinbase and other exchanges quickly blocked transactions to this address), and the wording on some of their tweets was stilted and awkward (surely they could have paid for a Grammarly subscription). But in the end, I think there’s no evidence that the twitter posts were just a “cover” for the real attack or that this hack had anything to do with a foreign government. I think this tweet sums it up well:</p>

<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">High impact bugs can sometimes be found and exploited by anyone, even dogs who have no idea what to do with the car they caught. There really doesn't have to be more to it than that.</p>— Brad Hill (@hillbrad) <a href="https://twitter.com/hillbrad/status/1283597241685438464?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 16, 2020</a></blockquote>


<p><em>Thanks to Akshay, Kim, and Varun for reading drafts of this.</em></p>

</div>


  
  
  



      </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://fortenf.org/e/security/2020/07/15/twitter-hack.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23860584</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 16:27:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Twitter hack has profound national security implications]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 136 | Comments 187 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23860533">thread link</a>) | @elsewhen
<br/>
July 16, 2020 | https://www.getrevue.co/profile/caseynewton/issues/a-catastrophe-at-twitter-263960 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.getrevue.co/profile/caseynewton/issues/a-catastrophe-at-twitter-263960">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.getrevue.co/profile/caseynewton/issues/a-catastrophe-at-twitter-263960</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23860533</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 16:22:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Who is the greatest knife steel metallurgist of all time?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 122 | Comments 124 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23860362">thread link</a>) | @severine
<br/>
July 16, 2020 | https://knifesteelnerds.com/2020/06/29/who-is-the-greatest-knife-steel-metallurgist-of-all-time/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://knifesteelnerds.com/2020/06/29/who-is-the-greatest-knife-steel-metallurgist-of-all-time/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			<p>Thanks to Blade HQ and Dale D. Miller for becoming <a href="https://www.patreon.com/Knifesteelnerds">Knife Steel Nerds Patreon</a> supporters!</p>
<p><strong>Metallurgists</strong></p>
<p>I have enjoyed writing many articles about the history of different knife steels over the past couple years of this website. It has been very challenging to track down the history of different steels to see where they came from and how. I decided to write an article about some of the greats who have made contributions to knife steel and knife tests. Many of these metallurgists didn’t know they were developing steels that would be used in knives. Some were developing tool steels or high speed steels. However, their steels have since been used in knives or their steel designs influenced other steels which have been used in knives. To keep this article manageable in size I have focused on those that developed steel or tests of knives. In other words, those that studied different aspects of steel are not included. Some notable people that were omitted for this reason include:</p>
<p>1) Marcus Grossman and Edgar Bain who discovered bainite and wrote a couple influential books on steel metallurgy</p>
<p>2) Many metallurgists who are less directly applicable but discovered many fundamentals of steel and general metallurgy, such as Henry Clifton Sorby (microscopy), Dmitry Chernov (phase transitions in steel), and William Roberts-Austen (iron-carbon phase diagram).</p>
<p>3) Metallurgists who studied heat treatment techniques. Taylor and White in the list below are a possible exception to this, however.</p>
<p>4) Influential teachers of metallurgy, some even directly to knifemakers like Kevin Cashen. Some on this list are also known for their teaching, but make the list primarily for other specific contributions.</p>
<p>So that list of categories may mean that some people you may think of as great metallurgists did not make the list. However, even with those omissions I think you will find some interesting information about the contributions of certain individuals and groups that developed the steel products we use in knives today.</p>
<p><strong>Robert Forester Mushet</strong></p>
<p>Mushet developed the first tool steel in 1868 which had several important characteristics. One was that it was the first commercially produced “alloy steel” meaning it had intentional alloy additions including manganese and tungsten to achieve certain properties, rather than being a simple carbon steel. The high tungsten in the steel gave it very high wear resistance for longer tool life. It was also the first “air hardening” steel meaning it could be allowed to cool in air from high temperature rather than quenching in oil or water. This steel was the basis of experiments from Taylor and White that led to the development of high speed steels and the explosion of development in other tool steels. Mushet is actually better known for making improvements to the “Bessemer process” which allowed the production of steel at much lower costs. But for his contributions to the future of knife steel his “Mushet steel” is huge. You can read more in <a href="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2018/03/22/the-history-of-the-first-tool-steel/">this article</a>.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="4414" data-permalink="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2020/06/29/who-is-the-greatest-knife-steel-metallurgist-of-all-time/mushet-composition/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/mushet-composition.jpg?fit=615%2C49&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="615,49" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="mushet composition" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/mushet-composition.jpg?fit=300%2C24&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/mushet-composition.jpg?fit=615%2C49&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/mushet-composition.jpg?resize=615%2C49&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="615" height="49" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/mushet-composition.jpg?w=615&amp;ssl=1 615w, https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/mushet-composition.jpg?resize=300%2C24&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 615px) 100vw, 615px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="4425" data-permalink="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2020/06/29/who-is-the-greatest-knife-steel-metallurgist-of-all-time/robert_forester_mushet/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Robert_Forester_Mushet.jpg?fit=228%2C280&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="228,280" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Robert_Forester_Mushet" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Robert_Forester_Mushet.jpg?fit=228%2C280&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Robert_Forester_Mushet.jpg?fit=228%2C280&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i1.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Robert_Forester_Mushet.jpg?resize=228%2C280&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="228" height="280" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p>Mushet</p>
<p><strong>Frederick Winslow Taylor and Maunsel White</strong></p>
<p>These Bethlehem Steel metallurgists started modern steel development in many ways. Prior to their contributions, steel was heat treated in a fairly narrow temperature range, such as 1400-1600°F. Overheating would lead to grain growth and poor toughness. However, they discovered that when Mushet steel was heated to very high temperatures prior to quenching, that it could last much longer as a high speed tool, because it maintained high hardness at high speeds and therefore high temperatures. Their discovery of “high speed steel” was presented at the 1900 Paris Exhibition (a world’s fair) and led to a T1-type high speed steel by 1903. The knowledge developed and the excitement generated led to the development of many other tool steels. Read more about Taylor and White in <a href="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2018/03/22/the-history-of-the-first-tool-steel/">this article</a>.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="4426" data-permalink="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2020/06/29/who-is-the-greatest-knife-steel-metallurgist-of-all-time/frederick_winslow_taylor/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Frederick_Winslow_Taylor.jpg?fit=483%2C972&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="483,972" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Frederick_Winslow_Taylor" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Frederick_Winslow_Taylor.jpg?fit=149%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Frederick_Winslow_Taylor.jpg?fit=483%2C972&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i1.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Frederick_Winslow_Taylor.jpg?resize=300%2C604&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="300" height="604" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Frederick_Winslow_Taylor.jpg?w=483&amp;ssl=1 483w, https://i1.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Frederick_Winslow_Taylor.jpg?resize=149%2C300&amp;ssl=1 149w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p>Taylor</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="4427" data-permalink="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2020/06/29/who-is-the-greatest-knife-steel-metallurgist-of-all-time/maunsel-white-picture/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/maunsel-white-picture.jpg?fit=654%2C801&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="654,801" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="maunsel white picture" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/maunsel-white-picture.jpg?fit=245%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/maunsel-white-picture.jpg?fit=654%2C801&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/maunsel-white-picture.jpg?resize=300%2C367&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="300" height="367" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/maunsel-white-picture.jpg?w=654&amp;ssl=1 654w, https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/maunsel-white-picture.jpg?resize=245%2C300&amp;ssl=1 245w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p>White</p>
<p><strong>Harry Brearley</strong></p>
<p>While there were several people working on inventing stainless steel in a similar time period, Brearley is credited with being the first to commercialize it. And what type of stainless steel did he commercialize? A knife steel! For several years afterward, stainless steel was known as being for knives and many people didn’t even realize it could be used for other things. The steel he developed was 420 stainless. This steel may have a relatively poor reputation among knife enthusiasts today, but it has been used in as many knives as any steel, perhaps the most used knife steel. And it has very good corrosion resistance. This steel was the basis for all future stainless knife steels, especially those like 420HC and AEB-L with the similar chromium content of 13%. The original name for S90V was 420V because the same chromium content of 420 was used in its development. Read more about the introduction of stainless steel <a href="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2018/07/16/first-stainless-steel-for-knives/">in this article</a>.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="4415" data-permalink="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2020/06/29/who-is-the-greatest-knife-steel-metallurgist-of-all-time/brearley-composition/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Brearley-composition.jpg?fit=375%2C49&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="375,49" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Brearley composition" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Brearley-composition.jpg?fit=300%2C39&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Brearley-composition.jpg?fit=375%2C49&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i1.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Brearley-composition.jpg?resize=375%2C49&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="375" height="49" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Brearley-composition.jpg?w=375&amp;ssl=1 375w, https://i1.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Brearley-composition.jpg?resize=300%2C39&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 375px) 100vw, 375px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="975" data-permalink="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2018/07/16/first-stainless-steel-for-knives/brearley/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Brearley.jpg?fit=313%2C428&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="313,428" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Brearley" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Brearley.jpg?fit=219%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Brearley.jpg?fit=313%2C428&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Brearley.jpg?resize=313%2C428&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="313" height="428" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Brearley.jpg?w=313&amp;ssl=1 313w, https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Brearley.jpg?resize=219%2C300&amp;ssl=1 219w" sizes="(max-width: 313px) 100vw, 313px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p><strong>James P. Gill</strong></p>
<p>Gill was a metallurgist working for VASCO which is a company largely forgotten by knife collectors now, but made many significant contributions to tool steels. Gill developed the first commercially available high vanadium steels, such as the first 2% vanadium high speed steel in 1937 which evolved to become M2, and also M4 with its 4% vanadium and T15 with 5% vanadium. Many knife steels today continue to have high vanadium contents for improved wear resistance. Gill also wrote one of the first books on Tool Steels in 1934, which continued with new editions up until the 5th in 1998. These books on Tool Steels have been used by metallurgists for decades. Read more about James Gill in <a href="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2018/04/16/the-development-of-first-tool-steels-book/">this article</a>. Gill also developed the 5% Cr + Mo alloying approach that led to the common <a href="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2019/04/22/a2-steel-history-and-properties/">knife steel A2</a>&nbsp;and continues to be used by many non-stainless tool steels.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="4416" data-permalink="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2020/06/29/who-is-the-greatest-knife-steel-metallurgist-of-all-time/gill-compositions/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Gill-compositions.jpg?fit=825%2C97&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="825,97" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Gill compositions" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Gill-compositions.jpg?fit=300%2C35&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Gill-compositions.jpg?fit=825%2C97&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Gill-compositions.jpg?resize=825%2C97&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="825" height="97" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Gill-compositions.jpg?w=825&amp;ssl=1 825w, https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Gill-compositions.jpg?resize=300%2C35&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Gill-compositions.jpg?resize=768%2C90&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 825px) 100vw, 825px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="465" data-permalink="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2018/04/16/the-development-of-first-tool-steels-book/james-gill-photo/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/James-gill-photo.jpg?fit=411%2C599&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="411,599" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="James gill photo" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/James-gill-photo.jpg?fit=206%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/James-gill-photo.jpg?fit=411%2C599&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/James-gill-photo.jpg?resize=300%2C437&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="300" height="437" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/James-gill-photo.jpg?w=411&amp;ssl=1 411w, https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/James-gill-photo.jpg?resize=206%2C300&amp;ssl=1 206w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p>Gill</p>
<p><strong>John A. Mathews</strong></p>
<p>Mathews worked for Crucible and Halcomb steel in the early 1900s and was highly influential for his steel developments and contributions to steel research. He patented the original T1 high speed steel with a small vanadium addition which improved the properties of early high speed steels. Vanadium additions were basically unheard of at the time but became very popular for various uses afterward. Mathews also developed the first “oil-hardening” steels including the popular O1 in 1905 which continues to be used in knives today. Read more about O1 and Mathews in <a href="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2019/08/26/o1-steel-history-properties-and-how-to-heat-treat/">this article</a>.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="4417" data-permalink="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2020/06/29/who-is-the-greatest-knife-steel-metallurgist-of-all-time/mathews-composition/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Mathews-composition.jpg?fit=615%2C73&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="615,73" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Mathews composition" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Mathews-composition.jpg?fit=300%2C36&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Mathews-composition.jpg?fit=615%2C73&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Mathews-composition.jpg?resize=615%2C73&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="615" height="73" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Mathews-composition.jpg?w=615&amp;ssl=1 615w, https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Mathews-composition.jpg?resize=300%2C36&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 615px) 100vw, 615px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="4428" data-permalink="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2020/06/29/who-is-the-greatest-knife-steel-metallurgist-of-all-time/mathews-picture/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/mathews-picture.jpg?fit=530%2C791&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="530,791" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="mathews picture" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/mathews-picture.jpg?fit=201%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/mathews-picture.jpg?fit=530%2C791&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/mathews-picture.jpg?resize=300%2C448&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="300" height="448" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/mathews-picture.jpg?w=530&amp;ssl=1 530w, https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/mathews-picture.jpg?resize=201%2C300&amp;ssl=1 201w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p>Mathews</p>
<p><strong>Harry Johnstin</strong></p>
<p>Johnstin developed the steels Vasco Wear and Vasco Die in 1964. Vasco Wear is probably better known now as CruWear (Crucible branding of the same steel), though it is known by many names such as PD#1, Lescowear, and Z-Wear. Vasco Wear saw use in knives by the 70s and continues to be a popular choice in its various versions. A relatively unknown fact is that CPM-3V is in fact a powder metallurgy version of Vasco Die. Surprisingly, Crucible metallurgists were able to patent the powder metallurgy of Vasco Die despite the composition being previously patented (and expired), because the change to the microstructure and properties were deemed to be significant enough. Vasco Die and Vasco Wear also created the “8% Cr” tool steel category which became future steels like Vanadis 4 (before Vanadis 4 Extra), Vanadis 10, Sleipner, A8 Mod, DC53, Z-Tuff, CD#1, and others. You can read more about these steels in <a href="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2019/06/03/the-history-of-3v-cru-wear-and-z-tuff-steel/">this article</a>.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="4418" data-permalink="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2020/06/29/who-is-the-greatest-knife-steel-metallurgist-of-all-time/johnstin-composition/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Johnstin-composition.jpg?fit=615%2C97&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="615,97" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Johnstin composition" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Johnstin-composition.jpg?fit=300%2C47&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Johnstin-composition.jpg?fit=615%2C97&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Johnstin-composition.jpg?resize=615%2C97&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="615" height="97" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Johnstin-composition.jpg?w=615&amp;ssl=1 615w, https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Johnstin-composition.jpg?resize=300%2C47&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 615px) 100vw, 615px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="4429" data-permalink="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2020/06/29/who-is-the-greatest-knife-steel-metallurgist-of-all-time/johnstin-picture/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Johnstin-picture.jpg?fit=129%2C238&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="129,238" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Johnstin picture" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Johnstin-picture.jpg?fit=129%2C238&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Johnstin-picture.jpg?fit=129%2C238&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Johnstin-picture.jpg?resize=129%2C238&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="129" height="238" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p>Johnstin</p>
<p><strong>David J. Giles</strong></p>
<p>David Giles was a metallurgist who developed many tool steels for Latrobe steel. Giles developed several steels which have seen use in knives, including 440A in 1926 [1]. 440A has been used extensively in consumer knives ever since, and served as the basis for the higher carbon 440C, which was incredibly popular in production and custom knives in the 70s and 80s, and continues to be used today. 154CM was originally called “440C Mod” because they reduced the Cr in 440C and replaced it with Mo. Read more about 154CM history <a href="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2018/05/21/154cm-development-properties-legacy/">in this article</a>. This 17-19% Cr base&nbsp; composition of 440A/440C served as the starting point for many future steels such as Elmax and S60V. Giles also developed 4-5% vanadium cold work steels A7 and D7 (as opposed to Gill who developed high speed steels) which served as a basis for future steels like CPM-10V. The patent-holder of 10V, Walter Haswell, previously worked at Latrobe steel and was a co-patent holder on several vanadium steels there as well, which used the same carbon-vanadium ratio equations that Giles had previously proposed [2]. D7 became Bohler’s powder metallurgy K190, which was further modified to <a href="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2020/06/15/what-is-the-best-budget-knife-steel/">develop the popular stainless M390</a>.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="4419" data-permalink="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2020/06/29/who-is-the-greatest-knife-steel-metallurgist-of-all-time/giles-composition/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Giles-composition.jpg?fit=535%2C97&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="535,97" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Giles composition" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Giles-composition.jpg?fit=300%2C54&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Giles-composition.jpg?fit=535%2C97&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Giles-composition.jpg?resize=535%2C97&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="535" height="97" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Giles-composition.jpg?w=535&amp;ssl=1 535w, https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Giles-composition.jpg?resize=300%2C54&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 535px) 100vw, 535px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="4430" data-permalink="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2020/06/29/who-is-the-greatest-knife-steel-metallurgist-of-all-time/giles-picture/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Giles-picture.jpg?fit=403%2C481&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="403,481" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Giles picture" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Giles-picture.jpg?fit=251%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Giles-picture.jpg?fit=403%2C481&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Giles-picture.jpg?resize=300%2C358&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="300" height="358" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Giles-picture.jpg?w=403&amp;ssl=1 403w, https://i0.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Giles-picture.jpg?resize=251%2C300&amp;ssl=1 251w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p>Giles</p>
<p><strong>Kenneth Pinnow and William Stasko</strong></p>
<p>These two metallurgists were prolific tool steel patenters in the 1990s and developed several significant knife steels. One is CPM-3V, previously mentioned under Harry Johnstin. They also developed S90V [3], which is popular in knives in its own right but also led to S110V which is essentially a modified S90V, developed by Al Kajinic. The biggest contribution of S90V was the discovery that using 14% Cr (as opposed to 17-18% Cr in earlier steels like S60V and Elmax), led to a better utilization of vanadium additions for improved properties. This led to a “14% Cr plus vanadium” basis for several future Crucible steels like S30V. The S90V patent also lays out how they explored different levels of nitrogen in S90V, which wasn’t really utilized in the final composition, but increased nitrogen (~0.15-0.20%) was used in S30V, S110V, and S45VN. Pinnow and Stasko also patented CPM-15V which continues to be one of the highest wear resistance steels available [4]. Stasko was also co-listed with Andrzej Wojcieszynski for patenting CPM Rex 86 and CPM Rex 121 steels [5].</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="4420" data-permalink="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2020/06/29/who-is-the-greatest-knife-steel-metallurgist-of-all-time/stasko-and-pinnow-composition/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Stasko-and-Pinnow-composition.jpg?fit=535%2C97&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="535,97" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Stasko and Pinnow composition" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Stasko-and-Pinnow-composition.jpg?fit=300%2C54&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Stasko-and-Pinnow-composition.jpg?fit=535%2C97&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Stasko-and-Pinnow-composition.jpg?resize=535%2C97&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="535" height="97" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Stasko-and-Pinnow-composition.jpg?w=535&amp;ssl=1 535w, https://i2.wp.com/knifesteelnerds.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Stasko-and-Pinnow-composition.jpg?resize=300%2C54&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 535px) 100vw, 535px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p><strong>Dick Barber</strong></p>
<p>Barber is best known for developing CPM-S30V steel, which has been one of the most popular steels used in high end production knives for nearly two decades. S30V was the first steel produced by Crucible to have an intentionally increased nitrogen content of about 0.20%. S30V also served as the starting point for the popular <a href="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2020/01/13/s35vn-steel-properties-and-how-to-heat-treat/">S35VN</a>, and the more recent <a href="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2020/01/15/spyderco-exclusive-cpm-spy27-steel-analysis/">SPY27</a> and <a href="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2019/11/01/crucible-s45vn-steel/">S4…</a></p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://knifesteelnerds.com/2020/06/29/who-is-the-greatest-knife-steel-metallurgist-of-all-time/">https://knifesteelnerds.com/2020/06/29/who-is-the-greatest-knife-steel-metallurgist-of-all-time/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://knifesteelnerds.com/2020/06/29/who-is-the-greatest-knife-steel-metallurgist-of-all-time/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23860362</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 16:05:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Zulip 3.0: Threaded Open Source Team Chat]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 459 | Comments 118 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23860338">thread link</a>) | @nicholasjbs
<br/>
July 16, 2020 | https://blog.zulip.com/2020/07/16/zulip-3-0-released/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.zulip.com/2020/07/16/zulip-3-0-released/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">
    <div>

        <article>

            


            <section>
                <div>
                    <!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>We’re excited to announce the release of Zulip Server 3.0, containing hundreds of new features and bug fixes to help distributed and remote teams stay productive and focused.</p>
<p><a href="https://zulip.com/">Zulip</a> is the open-source threaded team chat app, used by thousands of teams globally. Zulip’s unique <a href="https://zulip.com/why-zulip/">topic-based threading experience</a> combines the immediacy of real-time chat with the asynchronous efficiency of email-style threading.</p>

<p><img src="https://blog.zulip.com/content/images/2020/07/16102948y9dIHsQN-2.png">
<img src="https://blog.zulip.com/content/images/2020/07/16102948y9dIHsQN-2.png"></p><!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>Zulip Server 3.0 contains major visual design improvements, dramatic scalability and performance improvements, a new logo, and several of Zulip's most requested features to help users efficiently read, skim, search, and refer back to their messages. Zulip is 100% free and open-source software, and ships with translations for 16 languages.</p><p>Zulip 3.0 is our largest release ever, with over 4100 new commits since December's Zulip 2.1 release. A total of 110 people contributed commits to Zulip 3.0, bringing <a href="https://github.com/zulip/zulip/">the Zulip server project</a> to 619 distinct code contributors. With <a href="https://zulip.com/team">54 people</a> who’ve contributed 100+ commits, Zulip has by far the most active open-source development community of any team chat software.</p><p>Huge thanks to everyone who's contributed to Zulip over the last few months, whether by writing code and docs, reporting issues, testing changes, translating, posting feedback on <a href="https://zulip.readthedocs.io/en/latest/contributing/chat-zulip-org.html">chat.zulip.org</a>, or just suggesting ideas! We could not do this without the hundreds of people giving back to the Zulip community.</p><h2 id="project-highlights"><strong>Project highlights</strong></h2><p>Today marks a release of the Zulip server, but lots of exciting work has happened outside the server codebase over the last several months as well. Highlights include:</p><ul><li>Zulip has experienced an extraordinary increase in usage in 2020 as a result of the ongoing pandemic changing how people work. &nbsp;It's been incredibly gratifying to <a href="https://monadical.com/posts/how-to-make-remote-work-part-two-zulip.html">hear from users</a> about how Zulip has helped them make remote work, conferences, teaching, and meetups successful. &nbsp;We now sponsor free Zulip Cloud Standard hosting for hundreds of worthy <a href="https://zulip.com/for/open-source/">open-source projects</a>, non-profits, <a href="https://zulip.com/for/research/">research groups</a>, and similar non-commercial organizations. &nbsp;New organizations can apply during the <a href="https://zulip.com/new">signup flow</a> or on the billing page.</li><li>Zulip Cloud has introduced <a href="https://blog.zulip.com/2020/05/27/zulip-responds-to-pandemic-with-60-day-free-trial/">60-day free trials</a> for commercial users to help ensure that budget freezes aren't a barrier to experimenting with Zulip. &nbsp;Zulip has robust data import tools for <a href="https://zulip.com/help/import-from-slack">Slack</a>, <a href="https://zulip.com/help/import-from-mattermost">Mattermost</a>, and <a href="https://zulip.com/help/import-from-gitter">Gitter</a>.</li><li>Zulip has a new logo! Constructed from two chat bubbles that together form a Z (with a second Z in the negative space between them!), it replaces our aging “green Z inside a circle” logo created in 2013.</li></ul><figure><img src="https://blog.zulip.com/content/images/2020/07/zulip-logo-gradient.png" alt="" srcset="https://blog.zulip.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/zulip-logo-gradient.png 600w, https://blog.zulip.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/07/zulip-logo-gradient.png 1000w, https://blog.zulip.com/content/images/size/w1600/2020/07/zulip-logo-gradient.png 1600w, https://blog.zulip.com/content/images/2020/07/zulip-logo-gradient.png 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><ul><li>Our primary domain is now <a href="https://zulip.com/">https://zulip.com</a>. We’ll be migrating organizations from <code>subdomain.zulipchat.com</code> to <code>subdomain.zulip.com</code> in the coming weeks, taking care to avoid breaking existing API integrations and permalinks.</li><li>The Zulip mobile apps for iOS and Android have fixed numerous bugs and gained features like displaying math formulas with LaTeX—a frequently requested feature for the many organizations who do machine learning or other work best expressed in the language of mathematics.</li><li>We’re having an excellent <a href="https://summerofcode.withgoogle.com/archive/2019/organizations/4652389204754432/">Google Summer of Code</a> this year, with 18 amazing students spending their summer working on Zulip. Many of the features advertised here and in our full changelog were built by current GSoC students or alumni of the program.</li></ul><h2 id="release-highlights"><strong>Release highlights</strong></h2><p>Because this is such a huge release, just listing the hundreds of important changes in this release makes our <a href="https://zulip.readthedocs.io/en/latest/overview/changelog.html" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">changelog</a> incredibly long. Here are just some highlights:</p><p><strong>Core user experience</strong></p><ul><li>Added <a href="https://zulipchat.com/help/rename-a-topic" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">support for moving topics (or messages within topics) between streams</a>. This was by far our most requested feature.</li><li>Redesigned the top navbar/search area to be much cleaner and show stream descriptions. This was our second most requested feature, and removes what had been Zulip’s most visible UI wart.</li></ul><figure><img src="https://paper-attachments.dropbox.com/s_1E7A3465D8563B08C899BE809773AB4DB2AEE627A10B56FB07707A14E1AA0EC0_1594859150872_image.png" alt=""><figcaption>Stream descriptions can contain Zulip markdown such as links, emoji, and even LaTeX!</figcaption></figure><ul><li>Added “Recent Topics”, a useful new interface for browsing conversations. Feedback so far has been extremely positive, and we plan to make a version of this the default view in Zulip Server 4.0.</li></ul><figure><img src="https://blog.zulip.com/content/images/2020/07/Screenshot_2020-07-16--6--Goals---Zulip-Dev---Zulip-1.png" alt="" srcset="https://blog.zulip.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/Screenshot_2020-07-16--6--Goals---Zulip-Dev---Zulip-1.png 600w, https://blog.zulip.com/content/images/2020/07/Screenshot_2020-07-16--6--Goals---Zulip-Dev---Zulip-1.png 891w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><ul><li>Essentially every widget in the Zulip UI received significant polish work in this release.</li></ul><p><strong>Message formatting</strong></p><ul><li>Zulip has an innovative new feature for scheduling meetings with global participants. Instead of doing gymnastics to clearly communicate a meeting time to an audience across the globe, you can <a href="https://zulipchat.com/help/format-your-message-using-markdown#mention-a-time" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">use a date picker to write a time</a> which Zulip will show in each reader’s own timezone.</li><li>Zulip’s markup now supports <a href="https://zulipchat.com/help/format-your-message-using-markdown#spoilers" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">spoiler blocks</a>.</li><li><a href="https://zulipchat.com/help/quote-and-reply" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">Quote-and-reply</a> now generates a handy link to the referenced message.</li></ul><p><strong>Server</strong></p><ul><li>This release adds support for Ubuntu 20.04 Focal, and ends support for Ubuntu 16.04 Xenial and Debian 9 Stretch (both of which were based on Python 3.5, which reaches EOL in September). See our documentation for <a href="https://zulip.readthedocs.io/en/latest/production/upgrade-or-modify.html#upgrading-the-operating-system" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">upgrading the operating system</a>.</li><li>Zulip now defaults to using PostgreSQL 12 on new installs, with support for PostgreSQL 10–12. (Previously, Zulip always used whatever PostgreSQL version came with the base OS release.) This release also adds a convenient new tool to <a href="https://zulip.readthedocs.io/en/latest/production/upgrade-or-modify.html#upgrading-postgresql" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">upgrade </a><a href="https://zulip.readthedocs.io/en/latest/production/upgrade-or-modify.html#upgrading-the-operating-system" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">PostgreSQL</a>.</li><li>Numerous major performance improvements. Zulip’s server-to-client push system scales 4x better than in Zulip 2.x, and several of the most common queries are much faster. Performance has improved dramatically for organizations like our own Zulip development community with 10,000s of user accounts.</li><li>We upgraded Django from 1.11.x to the latest LTS series, 2.2.x. We continue to love how every major Django release comes with great features that we hadn't realized we needed!</li><li>We're moving to a new versioning scheme with only 2 digits; the next maintenance release will be Zulip Server 3.1 and the next major release will be Zulip Server 4.0.</li></ul><p><strong>API and API Documentation</strong></p><ul><li>Zulip’s <a href="https://zulip.com/api" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">REST API documentation</a> received a major overhaul both of content and presentation. Most importantly, our automated tests now validate every API request, response, and example against the OpenAPI schemas used to generate the API documentation. Because the Zulip server has nearly 100% test coverage, this ensures the API documentation is always consistent with the implementation.</li><li>Zulip now has <a href="https://zulip.com/api/changelog" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">a detailed API changelog</a> which documents exactly when each API change was introduced. The <code>zulip_feature_level</code> field in <a href="https://zulipchat.com/api/get-server-settings" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">the server settings API</a> (which is more fine-grained than a server release), when combined with the changelog, allows client applications to know exactly what any given Zulip server supports. This should make it easier for developers (including developers of the official desktop, mobile, and terminal clients) to write full-featured client apps directly off of the API documentation, without needing to investigate server internals.</li><li>Documenting the API provided a natural audit of Zulip’s API for obscure quirks and mistakes that would be better cleaned up than documented. As a result, this release contains dozens of changes to the Zulip API, which had previously been quite stable for years. Because of careful backwards-compatibility work, these shouldn’t cause any disruption (Zulip mobile app releases from 6 months ago work unmodified against this release!)</li></ul><p><strong>Integrations</strong></p><ul><li>New external authentication method integrations: <a href="https://zulip.readthedocs.io/en/latest/production/authentication-methods.html#plug-and-play-sso-google-github-gitlab" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">GitLab</a> and <a href="https://zulip.readthedocs.io/en/latest/production/authentication-methods.html#sign-in-with-apple" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">Sign in with Apple</a>.</li><li>The Zulip desktop apps now do social authentication (Google, GitHub, etc.) via an external browser, which improves security and provides a more pleasant single sign-on experience.</li><li>Added <a href="https://www.zulipchat.com/integrations/doc/slack_incoming" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">a new incoming webhook API</a> that accepts messages in the format used by Slack’s incoming webhooks API. This means that some third-party products that integrate with Slack but don’t have a generic outgoing-webhook feature can now easily integrate with Zulip.</li><li><a href="https://zulip.readthedocs.io/en/stable/production/authentication-methods.html#saml" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">Zulip’s popular SAML integration</a> now supports login initiated from the SAML Identity Provider.</li><li>BigBlueButton joins Jitsi and Zoom as a supported video call provider. We also rewrote the Zoom integration to have a much better OAuth user experience. The Google Hangouts video call integration was removed due to Google Hangouts reaching end of life. (Its replacement, Google Meet, does not offer a similar API for third-party apps to create calls.)</li><li><a href="https://www.zulipchat.com/integrations/" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">New native integrations</a> for ErrBit, Grafana, Thinkst Canary, and Prometheus Alertmanager, with improvements to the integrations for GitHub, GitLab, Sentry, Taiga, Semaphore, and many more.</li></ul><p><strong>Settings</strong></p><ul><li>Zulip now uses the <code>prefers-color-scheme</code> CSS property to determine whether to default to the day theme or the popular night theme, based on the operating system’s theme.</li><li>Zulip’s notification settings UI has been redesigned around an intuitive table format, displaying all individual streams that have non-default settings. This makes it much easier to configure, and is also important preparation for upcoming features like subscribing to notifications on a topic.</li></ul><figure><img src="https://paper-attachments.dropbox.com/s_1E7A3465D8563B08C899BE809773AB4DB2AEE627A10B56FB07707A14E1AA0EC0_1594859186960_image.png" alt=""></figure><ul><li>Added support for <a href="https://zulipchat.com/help/message-retention-policy" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">programmable message retention policies</a>. This has long been one of Zulip’s most-requested features, both from enterprises and privacy enthusiasts.</li><li>New settings: <a href="https://zulip.com/help/format-your-message-using-markdown#code" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">default code block language</a>, <a href="https://zulipchat.com/help/restrict-private-messages" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">who can use private messages</a>, <a href="https://zulipchat.com/help/status-and-availability#disable-updating-availability" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">disable presence availability</a>, and many more.</li></ul><p><strong>Internationalization</strong></p><ul><li>Zulip now has complete or nearly-complete translations for 16 languages: Chinese, Czech, Finnish, French, German, Italian, Japanese, Korean, Persian, Portuguese, Romanian, Russian, Spanish, Turkish, and Ukrainian, as well as English. Another 8 languages have partial translations which cover the majority of the strings in the project: Bulgarian, Catalan, Dutch, Hindi, Hungarian, Indonesian, Polish, and Swedish.</li><li>Zulip’s missed-message emails, one of the last parts of the Zulip core experience that was not yet internationalized, are now tagged for translation.</li></ul><p>See the <a href="https://zulip.readthedocs.io/en/latest/changelog.html" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">detailed changelog</a> for dozens of other notable improvements, including new features, performance optimizations, and bug fixes. If you administer a Zulip server, we encourage you to read at least the list of added features at the top, since there are a number of useful …</p></div></section></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.zulip.com/2020/07/16/zulip-3-0-released/">https://blog.zulip.com/2020/07/16/zulip-3-0-released/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.zulip.com/2020/07/16/zulip-3-0-released/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23860338</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 16:02:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Shipping Const Generics in 2020]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 103 | Comments 10 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23858916">thread link</a>) | @steveklabnik
<br/>
July 16, 2020 | https://without.boats/blog/shipping-const-generics/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://without.boats/blog/shipping-const-generics/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
			<p>It’s hard to believe that its been more than 3 years since I opened <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs/pull/2000">RFC 2000</a>, which defined
the const generics for Rust. At the same time, reading the RFC thread, there’s also been a huge
amount of change in this area: for one thing, at the time the RFC was written, const fns weren’t
stable, and consts weren’t even being evaluated using miri yet. There’s been a lot of work over the
years on the const generics feature, but still nothing has shipped. However, I think we have defined
a very useful subset of const generics which is stable enough to ship in the near term.</p>
<p>For those who don’t know, <strong>const generics</strong> refers to generics that are constant values, rather
than types. This allows types to be parameterized by, for example, specific integer values. In
stable Rust, only the special array type - <code>[T; N]</code> - has a const parameter (the length of the
array), and there is no way to be abstract over all values of <code>N</code>, even for arrays. Const generics
will allow creating new types parameterized by values, as well as implementing traits and functions
that are abstract over those values. For example:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>// This is a custom type which is parameterized by a `usize`
</span><span></span><span>pub</span><span> </span><span>struct</span> <span>Foo</span><span>&lt;</span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>N</span>: <span>usize</span><span>&gt;</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span> 
</span><span>    </span><span>bytes</span>: <span>[</span><span>u8</span><span>;</span><span> </span><span>N</span><span>],</span><span>
</span><span></span><span>}</span><span>
</span><span>
</span><span>
</span><span></span><span>// This is a trait which has been implemented for arrays of
</span><span>// any length.
</span><span></span><span>impl</span><span>&lt;</span><span>T</span>: <span>Debug</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>N</span>: <span>usize</span><span>&gt;</span><span> </span><span>Debug</span><span> </span><span>for</span><span> </span><span>[</span><span>T</span><span>;</span><span> </span><span>N</span><span>]</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span>
</span><span></span><span>}</span><span>
</span></code></pre></div><p>We’ve been using the const generics feature to <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/primitive.array.html#implementations">implement traits for arrays</a> for over a
year, artificially limiting the implementations to arrays of length 32. We are planning to <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/74060">lift
that limitation on those impls</a> in an upcoming release. By stabilizing const
generics, we could start to allow external crates to implement traits for all arrays as well, and
many other interesting use cases. There will be two important limitations, however.</p>
<h2 id="only-integral-primitive-types-for-const-generics">Only integral primitive types for const generics</h2>
<p>The initial types that a const generic can have will be limited to the integral primitive types.
That means the signed and unsigned integer types, booleans, and chars. For now, no compound or
user-defined types will be allowed, and no references (meaning no strings as well). This is a
relatively easy shortcoming of the current implementation to fix, and user defined types for const
generics will be possible in the nearer, rather than longer term.</p>
<p>I want to mention, since a lot of people aren’t aware of this, that not <em>any</em> type can be used as a
const parameter, even setting aside the current limitations of rustc. Importantly, in order for
Rust’s type system to be sound, equality between two types must be deterministic, reflexive,
symmetric, and so on. That is, if your custom type implements equality by flipping a coin, two
values of that type will sometimes be equal to one another and sometimes not. This will mean, two
types parameterized by those values will sometimes be the same type and sometimes a different type.
This would be quite troubling for the type system.</p>
<p>(As a concrete example, floating point numbers present challenges with the fact that <code>Foo&lt;NaN&gt;</code>, for
example, would not be considered the same type as itself, because <code>NaN</code> is not equal to itself.)</p>
<p>The long term solution to this is a notion of “structural equality,” which is a strictly correct
subset of <code>Eq</code> types that meet the properties needed for use in the type system. Rust already uses
this structural equality property when implementing matching. If you derive Eq and PartialEq for
your type and all its members, it should meet the structural equality property needed to be used in
matches and const generics.</p>
<h2 id="no-complex-expressions-based-on-generic-types-or-consts">No complex expressions based on generic types or consts</h2>
<p>The other limitation will be that only two kinds of expressions can be used to fill in a const
generic position:</p>
<ol>
<li>A const generic parameter. For example, in an <code>impl&lt;const N: usize&gt;</code>, where an const generic has
been introduced, that value can be used literally to fill a const generic.</li>
<li>An expression that can be used in a const context which does not depend on any type or const
parameters. This means literals, math equations, using consts, calling const fns, etc, as long
as no free generics are involved.</li>
</ol>
<p>This limits a lot of the more exotic and interesting things users want to do with const generics.
You can’t, for example, combine two array lengths together to form an array with type
<code>[T; N + M]</code>, or even double an array length with <code>[T; N * 2]</code>. You basically can’t have a type
that depends on computation that depends on other generics. Implementing this behavior soundly and
correctly is really the hard part of implementing const generics, and while work is ongoing, it
isn’t ready yet.</p>
<p>This also means that const generics can’t be filled in based on associated types, associated consts,
or generic methods. No functions that return <code>[u8; mem::size_of::&lt;T&gt;()]</code>, no use of <code>Self</code> like
<code>[u8; Self::LEN]</code>, etc.</p>
<p>This will mean, for example, that use cases like cryptographic hash traits which allow each
implementation to specify a different length for the hash they output will still be out of scope for
the MVP. This is a shame, but this feature will come eventually.</p>
<h2 id="what-you-will-be-able-to-do">What you <em>will</em> be able to do</h2>
<p>All of these restrictions might sound like the feature is pretty limited, but I think users will
find a lot of really powerful use cases for it once they can play around with it. For one thing,
traits that today might be implemented only by some array types, or not at all, will begin to be
implemented by all arrays, making arrays a much more first class part of the language. And <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/74373">we’re
already finding awesome use cases</a>. Look at this code sample.</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>let</span><span> </span><span>data</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>[</span><span>1</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>2</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>3</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>4</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>5</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>6</span><span>];</span><span>
</span><span>
</span><span></span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>sum1</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>data</span><span>.</span><span>array_chunks</span><span>().</span><span>map</span><span>(</span><span>|&amp;</span><span>[</span><span>x</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>y</span><span>]</span><span>|</span><span> </span><span>x</span><span> </span><span>*</span><span> </span><span>y</span><span>).</span><span>sum</span>::<span>&lt;</span><span>i32</span><span>&gt;</span><span>();</span><span>
</span><span></span><span>assert_eq</span><span>!</span><span>(</span><span>sum1</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>1</span><span> </span><span>*</span><span> </span><span>2</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>+</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>3</span><span> </span><span>*</span><span> </span><span>4</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>+</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>5</span><span> </span><span>*</span><span> </span><span>6</span><span>));</span><span>
</span><span>
</span><span></span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>sum2</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>data</span><span>.</span><span>array_chunks</span><span>().</span><span>map</span><span>(</span><span>|&amp;</span><span>[</span><span>x</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>y</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>z</span><span>]</span><span>|</span><span> </span><span>x</span><span> </span><span>*</span><span> </span><span>y</span><span> </span><span>*</span><span> </span><span>z</span><span>).</span><span>sum</span>::<span>&lt;</span><span>i32</span><span>&gt;</span><span>();</span><span>
</span><span></span><span>assert_eq</span><span>!</span><span>(</span><span>sum2</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>1</span><span> </span><span>*</span><span> </span><span>2</span><span> </span><span>*</span><span> </span><span>3</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>+</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>4</span><span> </span><span>*</span><span> </span><span>5</span><span> </span><span>*</span><span> </span><span>6</span><span>));</span><span>
</span></code></pre></div><p>Based on the <em>pattern</em> passed to the map function, the compiler figures out that the first call to
<code>array_chunks</code> should chunk the data into an iterator of arrays with length 2, and in the second
call it should be an iterator of arrays with length 3. It’s so cool!</p>
<h2 id="next-steps">Next steps</h2>
<p>Now that we’ve worked out what we could stabilize in the near future, I am working up hype and
consensus aroud the vision of stabilizing this feature - that’s what this blog post is for! The next
steps will be for someone to carve out a feature gate which is this limited set of const generics
(as opposed to the existing whole <code>const_generics</code> feature gate) and then for us to go through the
standard procedure for documenting and stabilizing that feature gate.</p>
<h2 id="credit">Credit</h2>
<p>My own involvement in const generics between the RFC and now has been minimal to non-existent.
Essentially, my role (both in the RFC and now) has been to identify a scope we can get consensus on
moving forward with. However, the hard work of implementing const generics has been going on for
years in between then, and I want to credit especially the contributors <a href="http://github.com/eddyb">eddyb</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/varkor">varkor</a>, <a href="https://github.com/lcnr">lcnr</a>, and <a href="https://github.com/oli-obk">oli-obk</a> for their work on implementing this highly
requested feature.</p>

		</section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://without.boats/blog/shipping-const-generics/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23858916</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 13:47:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Let’s avoid talk of ‘chemical imbalance’: it’s people in distress]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 483 | Comments 360 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23858294">thread link</a>) | @rbanffy
<br/>
July 16, 2020 | https://psyche.co/ideas/lets-avoid-talk-of-chemical-imbalance-its-people-in-distress | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://psyche.co/ideas/lets-avoid-talk-of-chemical-imbalance-its-people-in-distress">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><strong>After Jenna discovered</strong> that her boyfriend was cheating on her, she went into an emotional tailspin. She was â€˜crying all the timeâ€™, struggled to attend her university classes, slept a lot and avoided situations she normally enjoyed.</p><p>In recounting her emotional reaction, Jenna stressed to me its unreasonableness. Given that she and her boyfriend hadnâ€™t been dating for long, she felt that she shouldnâ€™t have been so upset. After a month, she decided that something was seriously amiss and that she needed professional help. She recalled her psychiatrist diagnosing depression and telling her the problem might be caused by a chemical imbalance in her brain, for which she was prescribed an antidepressant.</p><p>Jenna found her emotional reactions jarring. They defied her basic assumptions about herself as confident, mature and self-sufficient. She told me she welcomed the diagnosis of a neurobiological disorder, which confirmed her problem was â€˜realâ€™ â€“ brought on by a physiological force external to her volition â€“ and that it showed sheâ€™s not â€˜just a slackerâ€™.</p><p>At the same time, Jenna was careful to distance her experience from that of people who are, in her words, â€˜crazyâ€™ or â€˜nutsâ€™. Their illness means a loss of control and ability to function. By contrast, she sees her problem as a common and minor glitch in neurochemistry. No one, she insisted, should mistake her for the mentally ill.</p><p>Jenna was one of 80 diverse volunteers that a research team at the University of Virginia and I interviewed in Chicago, Baltimore, Boston and two small cities in central Virginia. We wanted to find out how people deal with common forms of psychological distress and challenging circumstances, such as: shyness and nervousness in social situations; underperformance at work or school; struggles after the loss of a significant relationship; and disappointment with how their lives are unfolding. A majority of our interviewees had received some form of psychotherapy and/or been diagnosed with a condition such as depression, social anxiety disorder or attention deficit disorder, and prescribed a psychiatric medication.</p><p>It was striking that many (though not all) at least partly explained their distress in terms of biological causes, particularly a neurochemical imbalance. Yet thinking of their problems in this way was a fraught process. Like Jenna, many interviewees sharply distinguished themselves from the mentally ill and cast the mentally ill in a very negative light. This stigmatising of people with serious mental illness wasnâ€™t based on any first-hand experiences; rather, it was motivated by a desire to protect their own dignity and social standing. To justify the distinction between their own situation and mental illness, our interviewees rejected the idea that they had an â€˜illnessâ€™ as such, detached themselves from any formal diagnosis using statements such as â€˜thatâ€™s what the doctor calls itâ€™ or, in some cases, they avoided seeking medical help altogether.</p><p>For people like Jenna, who embraced a neurobiological explanation for their problems, this created a conundrum, which many of them resolved by creating a separate classification for their own experience â€“ what I have called a â€˜third conditionâ€™. The people we spoke to did not give this â€˜conditionâ€™ a name or explicit meaning. Rather it emerged in the rhetorical space opened up by the way they framed their personal struggle, distinguishing it from mental illness, on the one hand, and normality, on the other.</p><p><strong>Consider the perspective</strong> of another of our interviewees, a young woman Iâ€™ll call Piper, who had been diagnosed with depression. When â€˜you think mental illnessâ€™, according to Piper, â€˜you think schizophrenia and crazy people, and Iâ€™m not crazy, I just get really nervous.â€™ In making this distinction, interviewees like Piper and Jenna not only claimed that they were less impaired than the seriously mentally ill, they also insisted that their experience was categorially different. Piper said of herself that biologically something is just â€˜a little offâ€™. She has â€˜too little or too much or whatever it is that makes you have these issuesâ€™. Distinct from â€˜crazy peopleâ€™, she has control over her mind and her story. All she needs is a little pill. Yet at the same time, her â€˜conditionâ€™ is also different from the mundane challenges that normal people might face. Piper was adamant that her nervousness in social situations is different from ordinary shyness. Her taking of medication is warranted. She has a third condition caused by an â€˜imbalanceâ€™.</p><p>The â€˜crazy peopleâ€™ are shadowy, depersonalised figures â€“ the damaged, uncontrolled â€˜otherâ€™ </p><p>To reconcile their perspective with the fact that they had received a psychiatric diagnosis, many interviewees credited a medical professional or a confidant for suggesting something like this third condition idea to them. Others emphasised the ordinariness of their experience and compared it to the types of routine problems that regular physicians treat. As one interviewee put it, â€˜all you have to do is take a pillâ€™.</p><p>There are echoes here of the messages conveyed in direct-to-consumer advertising for psychiatric medication. Iâ€™ve analysed the content of these adverts and found that distress, as listed in symptoms and portrayed in the patientsâ€™ stories, is often presented as a â€˜real medical conditionâ€™ and yet unlike mental illness. The ads contain no references to psychiatrists or to the diagnostic manual of mental disorders from the American Psychiatric Association (APA), nor use of phrases such as â€˜mental illnessâ€™ or â€˜mental disorderâ€™, and no depictions of those affected as anything but productive and successful citizens. In the words of our interviewees and in the advertising messages, the â€˜crazy peopleâ€™ are shadowy, depersonalised figures â€“ the damaged, uncontrolled â€˜otherâ€™ against whom the implicit comparisons are being drawn.</p><p>The views we encountered in our interviews are consistent with national surveys of public opinion about mental health. Today, with respect to mental health problems, the lay public much more freely endorses biological causes, the seeking of medical help and the use of psychoactive medications than in the past. Their views have converged with the biological perspectives long promoted in public campaigns to reduce the stigma of mental illness. According to the American anti-stigma organisation Bring Change to Mind, for instance: â€˜The fact is, a mental illness is a disorder of the brain â€“ your bodyâ€™s most important organ.â€™ Among anti-stigma researchers and activists, the evolution in public attitudes toward biological psychiatry has been celebrated as a sign that the public has at long last become â€˜literateâ€™, with a â€˜more scientificâ€™ even â€˜sophisticatedâ€™ understanding of mental illness.</p><p>In promoting a biogenetic causal theory, anti-stigma campaigners â€“ as well as psychiatrists, the popular media, and others â€“ hoped to convince people that mental illnesses are â€˜just likeâ€™ other chronic physical ailments, such as â€˜heart disease or diabetesâ€™, to <a href="https://www.psychiatry.org/patients-families/what-is-mental-illness" target="_blank">quote</a> the APA, and could be medically addressed. This approach would, in turn, alleviate mental illness stigma and foster tolerance by reducing the (allegedly common) tendency to hold sufferers responsible for their condition. The result, it was confidently believed, would promote treatment optimism and increased help-seeking.</p><p>But something unexpected happened. The public embrace of neurobiology has not led to a more benevolent orientation toward the mentally ill. Rather, according to an <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4409431/" target="_blank">editorial</a> in the <em>Journal of Psychiatry and Neuroscience</em> in 2015, â€˜well-conducted studies have concluded, almost uniformlyâ€™ that the stigma-reduction strategy of recent decades, informed by â€˜biogenetic attribution of all mental disordersâ€™, has â€˜not only not worked, but also may have worsened public attitudes and behaviour toward those with mental illnessesâ€™. Such studies have shown that the growing endorsement of biological causation has continued to exacerbate the stigmatising of mental illness among the <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/the-british-journal-of-psychiatry/article/biogenetic-explanations-and-public-acceptance-of-mental-illness-systematic-review-of-population-studies/E6078EED07031B5828DB84FCDC90657F" target="_blank">general public</a>, <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20493559/" target="_blank">patients</a> and <a href="https://www.pnas.org/content/111/50/17786" target="_blank">professionals</a>.</p><p>What accounts for this paradoxical result?</p><p><strong>I believe that </strong>our interviews reveal a crucial reason. While people accepted a neurobiological explanation for their problems, they struggled against the dehumanising notion that their thoughts, feelings or behaviour were mechanistically <em>caused.</em> Drawing on clinicians, drug ads and the popular media, the caricature of the seriously mentally ill served as a pivotal image by which to contrast and affirm their own control and self-determination. Millions of Americans â€“ and countless others in Western countries â€“ likely find themselves sharing this or a similar perspective.</p><p>The idea that oneâ€™s distress is primarily caused by a neurochemical deficiency that can be corrected by a drug is a fiction</p><p>As I argue in my <a href="https://press.uchicago.edu/ucp/books/book/chicago/C/bo48408677.html" target="_blank">book</a> <em>Chemically Imbalanced</em> (2020), to defeat this othering and reduce stigma, clinical practice needs to move away from biogenetic causal language. Psychiatric research doesnâ€™t support the notion of simple cause and effect in mental health, instead uncovering a far more complex and indeterminate picture of vulnerabilities. There is no evidence to justify the continued promotion of one-dimensional theories such as â€˜chemical imbalanceâ€™. Nor does the beneficial use of psychiatric medicines require it. In fact, their precise mechanism of action and relation to troublesome experience <a href="https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fpsyt.2019.00407/full" target="_blank">remains</a> a mystery. It would be more truthful for mental health professionals and public health campaigns to acknowledge this.</p><p>Itâ€™s true, as interviewees such as Jenna made clear, that patients often find biogenetic language appealing. It provides a way to establish their suffering as both tangible and unfeigned, and it offers a simple account and positive prognosis for their struggles. However, the …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://psyche.co/ideas/lets-avoid-talk-of-chemical-imbalance-its-people-in-distress">https://psyche.co/ideas/lets-avoid-talk-of-chemical-imbalance-its-people-in-distress</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://psyche.co/ideas/lets-avoid-talk-of-chemical-imbalance-its-people-in-distress</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23858294</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 12:30:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Ending at-will employment: a better remedy for cancel culture?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 65 | Comments 107 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23856918">thread link</a>) | @dgellow
<br/>
July 16, 2020 | https://www.persuasion.community/p/a-better-remedy-for-cancel-culture | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.persuasion.community/p/a-better-remedy-for-cancel-culture">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a target="_blank" href="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F9a172446-edcd-47f6-8d44-f467e59ebe25_4000x2223.jpeg"><img src="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F9a172446-edcd-47f6-8d44-f467e59ebe25_4000x2223.jpeg" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/9a172446-edcd-47f6-8d44-f467e59ebe25_4000x2223.jpeg&quot;,&quot;height&quot;:809,&quot;width&quot;:1456,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:null,&quot;bytes&quot;:5515692,&quot;alt&quot;:null,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;image/jpeg&quot;,&quot;href&quot;:null}" alt=""></a></p><p>The U.S. Constitution offers very broad protections for freedom of speech. While criticizing the government, or even waving the wrong flag, <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-china-53244862">could get you imprisoned</a> in any territory under Chinese rule, your right to freedom of expression is sacrosanct under the First Amendment—until you step into your place of work, that is. While the government is not entitled to punish political dissent, in most parts of America it is perfectly legal for your boss to fire you if they happen to dislike the person you voted for in the last election. </p><div><p>This restriction on political expression is especially harmful at a time when, nearly every day, somebody is accused of having transgressed against some commonly (or even not so commonly) held taboo. In many of these cases, employees—from senior staff at prominent institutions to working-class laborers—have been fired. Even outside of working hours, it would now be perfectly reasonable for most Americans to think twice before speaking their minds about hot-button issues.</p><p> In their attempts to remedy the most pernicious aspects of cancel culture, critics have mostly concentrated on advocating less punitive social norms. This is good as far as it goes. Our political culture will only become more liberal if we all stop demanding that people be punished or fired for imaginary transgressions. Yet, this emphasis on culture ignores the important role that legislative reform could play in defending the most vulnerable: If it were harder for employers to fire people for frivolous reasons, Americans would have less reason to fear that expressing their views might cost them their livelihoods.</p></div><p><strong>The Problem with At-Will Employment</strong></p><p>At the moment, most American workers are subject to “at-will” contracts. As long as their employers do not fire them on the basis of a narrow set of protected characteristics, such as gender, race, and sexual orientation, they can lose their jobs at any time, for any reason. Nor is there a due process requirement: Companies are under no legal obligation to investigate whether the ostensible reasons for axing an employee are grounded in reality. (The only state that categorically prohibits at-will employment, after six months on the job, <a href="https://spoonlaw.com/437-2/">is Montana</a>). </p><div><p> The prevalence of at-will employment makes it easier for employers to engage in knee-jerk reactions to short-lived social media controversies. For instance, a Hispanic electrician working for the San Diego Gas and Electric company was fired for cracking his knuckles in a photograph because a <a href="https://www.nbcsandiego.com/news/local/sdge-worker-fired-over-alleged-racist-gesture-says-he-was-cracking-knuckles/2347414/">social media mob believed that he was</a> flashing a white power sign. The man who took the picture has since admitted that he probably misinterpreted the interaction, and thousands of people have now <a href="https://www.change.org/p/sdge-reinstate-emmanuel-caffertys-job-sdge">signed a petition</a>, asking the electrician’s former employer to reverse the mistake. But since the employee has already lost his job, it will be hard for him to obtain justice. As in many other cases, both parties would have been better off if the law had required the company to afford due process to an accused worker <em>before</em> deciding whether or not to fire him. </p><p> There is a better alternative: Contracts negotiated by labor unions often provide so-called “just cause” protections for employees. The tests of just cause <a href="https://www.massnurses.org/labor-action/labor-education-resources/grievances-101/just-cause#:~:text=Just%20cause%20is%20the%20standard,must%20be%20just%20and%20fair.&amp;text=The%20concept%20of%20just%20cause%20is%20well%20established%20in%20labor%20law.">typically include questions</a> such as whether the employee was forewarned of the consequences of his or her actions, whether the rules were applied evenly, and whether there was an objective investigation into the employee’s conduct. In other words, it forces employers to conduct a fair process before firing their employees, which gives the accused a real chance to defend themselves. If we really care about free speech and due process, these protections should be available to every American.</p></div><div><p>Opponents of these reforms have long argued that they would come at a heavy cost to the economy. But scholars who have studied the impact of wrongful discharge protections have obtained mixed results. <a href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w12860.pdf">One 2007 study of U.S. employers</a>, for example, found that the introduction of such protections resulted in some loss of productivity, but also led to strong growth in overall employment numbers.</p></div><p><strong>Stop Employers From Discriminating Against Views They Don’t Like</strong></p><p> Just cause legislation would help to reduce the number of capricious firings. But, as long as bosses can legally terminate employees because they dislike their political views, such legislation would only go partway towards remedying the chilling effects on free speech. That’s why those of us who worry about cancel culture should also push for the inclusion of political affiliation in the rubric of anti-discrimination laws. </p><p> The Civil Rights Act has long prohibited employers from discriminating on the basis of race, color, religion, gender, pregnancy, or national origin. In June, the Supreme Court <a href="https://www.npr.org/2020/06/15/863498848/supreme-court-delivers-major-victory-to-lgbtq-employees">ruled that this provision</a> also protects gay, lesbian, and transgender employees. But there are no equivalent federal protections to prevent employees from being disadvantaged because of their political views.</p><div><p>This is a missed opportunity, as the success of local ordinances mandating such protections has shown. In Washington D.C., for example, the <a href="https://ohr.dc.gov/sites/default/files/dc/sites/ohr/publication/attachments/LawsAndRegs-HumanRightsAct-1977-English.pdf">Human Rights Act</a> prohibits employment discrimination based on political affiliation, defined as “the state of belonging to or endorsing any political party.” As Edgar Njatou, Executive Director of Workplace Fairness, told me in an interview, this ensures that your boss can’t fire you if they “find out you voted for Hillary or that you’re a Republican.”</p><p> Seattle has even more ambitious protections for workers’ political views. Its laws prohibit discrimination based on “<a href="https://library.municode.com/wa/seattle/codes/municipal_code?nodeId=TIT14HURI_CH14.06UNPUACPR&amp;showChanges=true">political ideology</a>,” which is defined as “any idea or belief … relating to the purpose, conduct, organization, function or basis of government institutions and activities, whether or not characteristic of any political party or group.” But even this law mostly serves to protect people with relatively common political views. After the 2016 election, for example, local rental listings began to discourage Trump supporters from applying. “If you are a landlord,” city government spokesperson Elliot Bronstein, <a href="https://www.king5.com/article/news/local/seattle/no-trump-clause-is-new-requirement-for-some-seattle-renters/416269805">wrote in response</a>, “you cannot discriminate on political status.” (Like other protections against discrimination, this does not apply to housemates, who share an apartment or living space.) </p></div><p>There are two obvious objections—both of which could easily be addressed. First, some organizations have a legitimate interest in ensuring that their employees share a broad worldview: It would make no sense, for example, to stop a political campaign group from discriminating against a job applicant who opposes the organization’s goals. Explicitly political organizations should therefore enjoy a carve-out from the stricture against discriminating on the basis of political beliefs (though they would still have to afford existing employees the due process protections guaranteed under “just cause” provisions). </p><p>Second, employers have a legitimate interest in protecting their staff from the hateful conduct of colleagues: Clearly, for example, no member of an ethnic minority should have to endure racist taunts at their place of work. But this could also be addressed through carefully worded legislation. Seattle already offers exemptions for political conduct that would cause “substantial and material disruption of the property rights of the provider of a place of public accommodation.” Employers also have an affirmative obligation to protect employees from racist harassment.</p><p>Balancing competing goods is one of the core purposes of any legal system. There is no reason to think that our laws could not protect the speech of political minorities, without hampering the operation of overtly political organizations or burdening ethnic, religious, or sexual minorities with the fear of harassment.</p><p><strong>We Can Make It Happen</strong></p><p>New employment regulations always face an especially tough uphill battle in Congress. But, though it will not be easy to win legislative approval for such reforms, every major faction of American political life has its own reasons for supporting them. </p><p>The left should be sympathetic to the wish to expand job protections for American workers, which lag significantly behind those of other developed countries. While conservatives are usually hostile to such regulations, they should recognize that these reforms would help to protect them against the growing influence of cancel culture. And philosophical liberals—those of us who believe in a pluralistic society that encourages ideological diversity—have the most principled reason to get on board.</p><p>Hatred of any form of wrong think now <a href="https://www.vox.com/2015/12/7/9790764/partisan-discrimination">threatens the foundations</a> of our social fabric. Since the stakes of public policy debates are high, it is understandable—and even admirable—for citizens to subject each other’s views to vigorous criticism. But, if ordinary people fear that a minor misunderstanding or a deeply held difference of opinion might cost them their jobs, freedom of speech—the cornerstone of any liberal order—is under serious threat. </p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.persuasion.community/p/a-better-remedy-for-cancel-culture</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23856918</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 08:19:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Power of Dopey Ideas]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 26 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23855806">thread link</a>) | @NaOH
<br/>
July 15, 2020 | https://techreflect.net/2020/07/15/the-power-of-dopey-ideas/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://techreflect.net/2020/07/15/the-power-of-dopey-ideas/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main" role="main">

							
<article id="post-1128">

	
	
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>
	
<p><em>After a protracted move to Portland (Oregon), I’m back to writing about parrots.</em></p>



<blockquote><p>Steve used to say to me, and he used to say this a lot. Hey Jony, here’s a dopey idea. And sometimes they were. Really dopey. Sometimes they were truly dreadful. But sometimes they took the air from the room. And they left us both completely silent. Bold, crazy, magnificent ideas. Or quiet, simple ones. Which in their subtlety, their detail, they were utterly profound. </p><cite>Jony Ive, Steve Jobs memorial service, Apple Campus, 2011</cite></blockquote>



<p>One of the secrets of Apple’s success comes in this wonderful quote from Jony Ive. The part he didn’t mention—partly because it wasn’t relevant to the story—is that sometimes the magnificent ideas came out of the dopey ideas. </p>



<p>All of us are capable of bold, crazy, or magnificent ideas, but if we’re not allowed the freedom to have dopey ideas and voice them, some of these potential ideas may never come to fruition.</p>



<p>The more years I worked at Apple, the more timid I felt people had become to bring up ideas that they had. I finally figured out that it was likely due to the average tenure of an employee dropping dramatically as hiring went increased exponentially.</p>



<p>Someone that has been at Apple for 10 years is certainly very secure in voicing ideas, whereas someone that has only been there less than 2 years is understandably more reticent.</p>



<p>So, I don’t think Apple’s culture of being open to dopey ideas has changed, but the average employee is less likely to bring them up. I think this is probably true of any company that has experienced insane growth.</p>



<p>But back to dopey ideas.</p>



<p>Imagine being in a meeting with several people that each have dopey ideas. If no one says anything, nothing happens. But if one brings theirs up, it could either be combined with another dopey idea or tacked on to an existing good idea.</p>



<p>Perhaps the dopey idea sits on the back burner and simmers for years and then suddenly it becomes a brilliant idea because of the market or products changing.</p>



<p>If you work for Apple or any other company, be sure to encourage people to have dopey ideas and voice them. </p>



<p>Steve would want you to.</p>
<!-- relpost-thumb-wrapper --><!-- close relpost-thumb-wrapper -->
	</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->
</article><!-- #post-## -->
			</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://techreflect.net/2020/07/15/the-power-of-dopey-ideas/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23855806</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 04:35:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Two Beautiful Rust Programs]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 29 | Comments 9 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23855477">thread link</a>) | @yannikyeo
<br/>
July 15, 2020 | https://matklad.github.io//2020/07/15/two-beautiful-programs.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://matklad.github.io//2020/07/15/two-beautiful-programs.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<div>
<div>
<pre><code data-lang="rust"><table><tbody><tr><td><pre> 1
 2
 3
 4
 5
 6
 7
 8
 9
10
11
12
13
14
15
16
17
18
19
20
</pre></td><td><pre><span>use</span> <span>crossbeam</span><span>::</span><span>scope</span><span>;</span>
<span>use</span> <span>parking_lot</span><span>::{</span><span>Mutex</span><span>,</span> <span>MutexGuard</span><span>};</span>

<span>fn</span> <span>main</span><span>()</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>let</span> <span>mut</span> <span>counter</span> <span>=</span> <span>Mutex</span><span>::</span><span>new</span><span>(</span><span>0</span><span>);</span>

  <span>scope</span><span>(|</span><span>s</span><span>|</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>for</span> <span>_</span> <span>in</span> <span>0</span><span>..</span><span>10</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>s</span><span>.spawn</span><span>(|</span><span>_</span><span>|</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>for</span> <span>_</span> <span>in</span> <span>0</span><span>..</span><span>10</span> <span>{</span>
          <span>let</span> <span>mut</span> <span>guard</span><span>:</span> <span>MutexGuard</span><span>&lt;</span><span>i32</span><span>&gt;</span> <span>=</span> <span>counter</span><span>.lock</span><span>();</span>
          <span>*</span><span>guard</span> <span>+=</span> <span>1</span><span>;</span>
        <span>}</span>
      <span>});</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>})</span><span>.unwrap</span><span>();</span>

  <span>let</span> <span>total</span><span>:</span> <span>&amp;</span><span>mut</span> <span>i32</span> <span>=</span> <span>counter</span><span>.get_mut</span><span>();</span>
  <span>println!</span><span>(</span><span>"total = {}"</span><span>,</span> <span>*</span><span>total</span><span>)</span>
<span>}</span>
</pre></td></tr></tbody></table></code></pre>
</div>
</div>
<p>This program creates an integer counter protected by a mutex, spawns 10 threads, increments the counter 10 times from each thread, and prints the total.</p>
<p>The <code>counter</code> variable lives on the stack, and  a pointer to these stack data is shared with other threads.
The threads have to lock the mutex to do the increments.
When printing the total, the counter is read bypassing the mutex, without any synchronization.</p>
<p>The beauty of this program is that it relies on several bits of subtle reasoning for correctness, each of which is checked by compiler:</p>
<div>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Child threads don’t escape the <code>main</code> function and so can read <code>counter</code> from its stack.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Child threads only access <code>counter</code> through the mutex.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Child threads will have terminated by the time we read <code>total</code> out of <code>counter</code> without mutex.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<p>If any of these constraints is broken, the compiler rejects the code.
There’s no need for <code>std::shared_ptr</code> just to defensively make sure that the memory isn’t freed under your feet.</p>
<p>Rust allows doing dangerous, clever, and fast things without fear of introducing undefined behavior.</p>
<p>If you like what you see, here are two books I recommend for diving deeper into Rust:</p>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://matklad.github.io//2020/07/15/two-beautiful-programs.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23855477</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 03:35:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Topology Illustrated (2015)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 118 | Comments 17 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23854329">thread link</a>) | @Koshkin
<br/>
July 15, 2020 | https://calculus123.com/wiki/Topology_Illustrated | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://calculus123.com/wiki/Topology_Illustrated">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="mw-content-text" lang="en" dir="ltr"><div><p><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/File:Front_cover.png"><img alt="Front cover.png" src="https://calculus123.com/images/thumb/a/ab/Front_cover.png/250px-Front_cover.png" width="250" height="361" srcset="https://calculus123.com/images/thumb/a/ab/Front_cover.png/375px-Front_cover.png 1.5x, https://calculus123.com/images/a/ab/Front_cover.png 2x" data-file-width="386" data-file-height="557"></a></p>
<p><i>Topology Illustrated</i> by <a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Peter_Saveliev" title="Peter Saveliev">Peter Saveliev</a>
</p><p>Contains 1000 illustrations.
</p><p>Sold on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/1495188752">Amazon.com</a>. If you are an instructor considering using the book for your class, contact me about a copy.
</p><p>Below are some sections of an early online draft (11/15/2015). Because of the extensive editing that had happened prior to publication, some of the sections had to be omitted.
</p><p>A bird's-eye view of discrete calculus is given in Chapter 4. I recently created an article <a rel="nofollow" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discrete_calculus">“Discrete calculus” for Wikipedia</a>. It’ll need a lot of work. 
</p><p>If you have any questions, please email me or try the <a rel="nofollow" href="http://facebook.com/topologybook/">facebook page</a> (until a better place is found).
</p><p><b>CONTENTS</b>
</p><p><br>
<a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Preface" title="Preface">Preface</a> 1
</p>
<div><p><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/File:Tunnels_in_foam.png"><img alt="Tunnels in foam.png" src="https://calculus123.com/images/thumb/a/aa/Tunnels_in_foam.png/220px-Tunnels_in_foam.png" width="220" height="120" srcset="https://calculus123.com/images/a/aa/Tunnels_in_foam.png 1.5x" data-file-width="275" data-file-height="150"></a></p>
<p><b>Chapter 1. Cycles</b>
</p>
<ol><li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Topology" title="Topology">Topology around us</a> 13</li>
<li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Homology_classes" title="Homology classes">Homology classes</a> 15</li>
<li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Topology_of_graphs" title="Topology of graphs">Topology of graphs</a> 12</li>
<li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Homology_groups_of_graphs" title="Homology groups of graphs">Homology groups of graphs</a> 19</li>
<li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Maps_of_graphs" title="Maps of graphs">Maps of graphs</a> 19</li>
<li>Binary calculus on graphs 11</li></ol>
</div>
<div><p><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/File:Topology_convergent_sequence.png"><img alt="Topology convergent sequence.png" src="https://calculus123.com/images/thumb/1/18/Topology_convergent_sequence.png/200px-Topology_convergent_sequence.png" width="200" height="163" srcset="https://calculus123.com/images/1/18/Topology_convergent_sequence.png 1.5x" data-file-width="245" data-file-height="200"></a></p>
<p><b>Chapter 2. Topologies</b>
</p>
<ol><li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/A_new_look_at_continuity" title="A new look at continuity">A new look at continuity</a> 10</li>
<li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Neighborhoods_and_topologies" title="Neighborhoods and topologies">Neighborhoods and topologies</a> 13</li>
<li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Topological_spaces" title="Topological spaces">Topological spaces</a> 15</li>
<li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Continuous_functions" title="Continuous functions">Continuous functions</a> 24</li>
<li>Subspaces 20</li></ol>
</div>
<div><p><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/File:Cube_with_holes.png"><img alt="Cube with holes.png" src="https://calculus123.com/images/5/54/Cube_with_holes.png" width="200" height="205" data-file-width="146" data-file-height="150"></a></p>
<p><b>Chapter 3. Complexes</b> 
</p>
<ol><li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/The_algebra_of_cells" title="The algebra of cells">The algebra of cells</a> 19</li>
<li>Cubical complexes 19</li>
<li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/The_algebra_of_oriented_cells" title="The algebra of oriented cells">The algebra of oriented cells</a> 14</li>
<li>Simplicial complexes 19</li>
<li>Simplicial homology 19</li>
<li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Simplicial_maps" title="Simplicial maps">Simplicial maps</a> 22</li>
<li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Parametric_complexes" title="Parametric complexes">Parametric complexes</a> 14</li></ol>
</div>
<div><p><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/File:View_through_quotient_door_manifold_1.png"><img alt="View through quotient door manifold 1.png" src="https://calculus123.com/images/thumb/2/21/View_through_quotient_door_manifold_1.png/170px-View_through_quotient_door_manifold_1.png" width="170" height="230" srcset="https://calculus123.com/images/2/21/View_through_quotient_door_manifold_1.png 1.5x" data-file-width="185" data-file-height="250"></a></p>
<p><b>Chapter 4. Spaces</b>
</p>
<ol><li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Compact_spaces" title="Compact spaces">Compacta</a> 12</li>
<li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Quotients" title="Quotients">Quotients</a> 20</li>
<li>Cell complexes 24</li>
<li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Triangulations" title="Triangulations">Triangulations</a> 16</li>
<li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Manifolds" title="Manifolds">Manifolds</a> 29</li>
<li>Products 29</li></ol>
</div>
<div><p><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/File:Algebra_of_spheres.png"><img alt="Algebra of spheres.png" src="https://calculus123.com/images/thumb/3/3d/Algebra_of_spheres.png/220px-Algebra_of_spheres.png" width="220" height="131" srcset="https://calculus123.com/images/3/3d/Algebra_of_spheres.png 1.5x" data-file-width="251" data-file-height="150"></a></p>
<p><b>Chapter 5. Maps</b>
</p>
<ol><li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Homotopy" title="Homotopy">Homotopy</a> 27</li>
<li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Cell_maps" title="Cell maps">Cell maps</a> 26</li>
<li>Maps of polyhedra 29</li>
<li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Euler_and_Lefschetz_numbers" title="Euler and Lefschetz numbers">The Euler and Lefschetz numbers</a> 18</li>
<li>Set-valued maps 15</li></ol>
</div>
<div><p><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/File:Forms_as_functions_dim_2.png"><img alt="Forms as functions dim 2.png" src="https://calculus123.com/images/thumb/3/36/Forms_as_functions_dim_2.png/300px-Forms_as_functions_dim_2.png" width="300" height="85" srcset="https://calculus123.com/images/thumb/3/36/Forms_as_functions_dim_2.png/450px-Forms_as_functions_dim_2.png 1.5x, https://calculus123.com/images/thumb/3/36/Forms_as_functions_dim_2.png/600px-Forms_as_functions_dim_2.png 2x" data-file-width="704" data-file-height="200"></a></p>
<p><b>Chapter 6. Forms</b>
</p>
<ol><li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Discrete_forms_and_cochains" title="Discrete forms and cochains">Discrete forms and cochains</a> 21</li>
<li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Calculus_on_cubical_complexes" title="Calculus on cubical complexes">Calculus on cubical complexes</a> 23</li>
<li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Cohomology" title="Cohomology">Cohomology</a> 25</li>
<li>Metric tensor 27</li></ol>
</div>

<div><p><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/File:Waves_2d.png"><img alt="Waves 2d.png" src="https://calculus123.com/images/thumb/8/81/Waves_2d.png/250px-Waves_2d.png" width="250" height="186" srcset="https://calculus123.com/images/thumb/8/81/Waves_2d.png/375px-Waves_2d.png 1.5x, https://calculus123.com/images/8/81/Waves_2d.png 2x" data-file-width="403" data-file-height="300"></a></p>
<p><b>Chapter 7. Flows</b>
</p>
<ol><li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Geometric_complexes" title="Geometric complexes">Metric complexes</a> 12</li>
<li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/ODEs" title="ODEs">ODEs</a> 29</li>
<li>PDEs 24</li>
<li>Social choice 26</li></ol>
</div>

<ul><li>Appendix: <a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Notation" title="Notation">Notation</a> 4</li>
<li>Appendix: <a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Student%27s_guide_to_proof_writing" title="Student's guide to proof writing">Student's guide to proof writing</a> 3</li>
<li><a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Topology_Illustrated_--_Index" title="Topology Illustrated -- Index">Index</a></li></ul><ul><li>Link: <a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Spreadsheets" title="Spreadsheets">Spreadsheets</a></li>
<li>Link: <a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Topology_Illustrated_--_Errata" title="Topology Illustrated -- Errata">Errata</a></li>
<li>Link: <a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Topology_Illustrated_--_Addenda" title="Topology Illustrated -- Addenda">Addenda</a></li>
<li>Addendum: <a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/The_political_spectrum_is_a_circle" title="The political spectrum is a circle">The political spectrum is a circle</a></li>
<li>Addendum: <a href="https://calculus123.com/wiki/Integer-valued_calculus" title="Integer-valued calculus">Integer-valued calculus</a></li></ul><p></p>

<!-- 
NewPP limit report
Cached time: 20200719105442
Cache expiry: 86400
Dynamic content: false
CPU time usage: 0.028 seconds
Real time usage: 0.035 seconds
Preprocessor visited node count: 1/1000000
Preprocessor generated node count: 4/1000000
Post‐expand include size: 0/2097152 bytes
Template argument size: 0/2097152 bytes
Highest expansion depth: 1/40
Expensive parser function count: 0/100
Unstrip recursion depth: 0/20
Unstrip post‐expand size: 0/5000000 bytes
-->
<!--
Transclusion expansion time report (%,ms,calls,template)
100.00%    0.000      1 -total
-->

<!-- Saved in parser cache with key yeahuaftgb:pcache:idhash:525-0!canonical and timestamp 20200719105442 and revision id 7218
 -->
</div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://calculus123.com/wiki/Topology_Illustrated</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23854329</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:35:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
