<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 09:05:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 09:05:42 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Most surgeries are ineffective]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 51 | Comments 19 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25857435">thread link</a>) | @pvsukale3
<br/>
January 21, 2021 | https://invertedpassion.com/most-surgeries-are-ineffective/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://invertedpassion.com/most-surgeries-are-ineffective/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-1496">
		<!-- .entry-header -->
	<div>
		
		
<p>Do surgeries work? Most of us assume they do, but is there any scientific evidence that they do?</p>

<p>In this episode, I talk to <a href="https://twitter.com/drianharris">Dr Ian Harris</a> who is a Professor of Orthopaedic Surgery at the University of New South Wales in Australia. He is a practicing orthopedic surgeon specializing in trauma surgery. Outside his practice, his research interests broadly cover the topic of surgical effectiveness and clinical research.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<iframe title="#2 Ian Harris - Most surgeries are ineffective" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jCG3tzgGV2A?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p>
</figure>

<h3>What we talk about</h3>

<p><strong>1:38</strong> – Science as a way of knowing things<br><strong>9:15</strong> –&nbsp;Why medical professionals refuse to believe scientific evidence?<br><strong>15:05 </strong>– What is a<strong> </strong>placebo?<br><strong>19:16</strong> – How strong is the placebo effect in surgeries?<br><strong>22:05</strong> – History of bloodletting in medicine and how we stopped this practice<br><strong>24:31</strong> – The myths of knee surgery<br><strong>28:26</strong> – Why doctors need to be held accountable<br><strong>32:26</strong> – Why are there no regulatory authorities in surgery like there are in new medicine?<br><strong>35:14</strong> – Latest studies on why half of the surgeries are ineffective<br><strong>41:00</strong> – Need for randomized trials for discovering which surgeries actually work<br><strong>44:48</strong> – Why is surgery the ultimate placebo?<br><strong>47:12</strong> – How much effort does it take to do a meta-analysis or a systematic review?<br><strong>47:29</strong> – How to improve meta-reviews via living systematic reviews<br><strong>49:54</strong> – What should you be asking your doctor if you are recommended a surgery?</p>

<h3>Dive into Dr Ian Harris’ research</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28592661-surgery-the-ultimate-placebo">Book</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IzueFu1cq5U">Lecture</a></li>
<li><a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=HSd2K4IAAAAJ&amp;hl=en&amp;oi=ao">Papers</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.bmj.com/content/348/bmj.g3253">Relevant paper</a> backing the claim that most surgeries are ineffective</li>
</ul>

<h3>Notes and key insights</h3>

<p>1/ <strong>What is a placebo surgery?</strong> It’s where you make an incision but not do anything. </p>

<p>It’s analogous to traditional placebo in medicine, where a sugar or salt pill is given instead of an active chemical to see whether the intended medicine has an actual impact.</p>

<p>2/ <strong>Majority of surgeries that Dr Ian Harris and other researchers have studied in fact are not more effective than placebos</strong>. This is shocking because even when we have no proof that they work, many of these surgeries are happening even today.</p>

<p>3/ <strong>Examples of such ineffective surgeries include back pain surgeries and knee pain surgeries.</strong> For such surgeries, randomized control trials have found that if you make an incision in the knee but don’t do anything, it’s as effective as actually conducting the surgery of the knee.</p>

<p>4/ Why do patients get better if the surgery doesn’t work? It’s because<strong> many diseases or pain have a natural progression</strong>, and we generally seek surgical/medicinal intervention when we’re in the worst condition. If the body heals / condition becomes better after that, we attribute improvement to the intervention rather than thinking it could have happened anyway (due to the natural course of the condition).</p>

<p>5/ As Dr Ian Harris said, the unsaid attitude could be stated like: “<strong>you have to operate on patients quickly before they get better</strong>“.</p>

<p>Remember: in many cases, if you get sick, you get better after that. And that is why placebos seem to work.</p>

<p>6/ It’s shocking to hear that randomized controlled trials (RCT) for many surgical interventions end up finding that they’re ineffective.</p>

<p>But what’s most shocking is that <strong>many other interventions have never been subjected to an RCT against a placebo</strong>. For many of the common procedures traditionally practiced, we don’t know whether they work at all or not.</p>

<p>7/ For sure, there are many studies that study variations of surgical methods. That is, they try to find out whether an incision from the left is better or from the right. </p>

<p>But very few studies try to find out whether the incision does anything at all for the patient. Shocking, but that’s the truth.</p>

<p>8/ In that sense, <strong>surgery is different than medicine</strong>. All new pharmaceutical molecules are subjected to rigorous clinical trials where they’re tested against placebo or doing nothing. In many countries, there’s no such procedure for surgical treatments. If there is a procedure for new surgical procedures, nobody is testing old ones that have been getting performed every day without evidence.</p>

<p>8/ If research indicates many of the currently practiced surgeries don’t work, why are they still practiced?</p>

<p>Well, <strong>if your salary depends on not believing something, you won’t believe it.</strong></p>

<p>9/ And such <strong>denial is not new</strong>. The most common surgical procedure in history was bloodletting. This practice which lasted for thousands of years was only questioned in mid 19th century, and even after randomized trials showed that it hurt the patient, it wasn’t abandoned suddenly. It died a slow death as its practitioners started dying. </p>

<p>10/ Even today, the fact that practices like Homeopathy survive suggests that <strong>seeking evidence of what works isn’t a big priority for society</strong>. Perhaps keeping traditions is a bigger priority.</p>

<p>11/ But because it’s costly and risky to perform surgeries, the urgent question is: <strong>what surgical procedures are today’s equivalent of bloodletting</strong>? And those that we know are bloodletting, how do we get rid of them as a society?</p>

<p>12/ As a patient, what should you do? Dr Ian Harris recommends that every time your doctor recommends a medical procedure, <strong>ALWAYS ask for risks and benefits</strong>. </p>

<p>Risks are a given and doctors generally are happy to talk about them. But nobody asks for benefits because they’re assumed to be there. </p>

<p>Ask and confirm about benefits explicitly.</p>

<p>13/ What if the pain isn’t going away at all? Should you then get surgery?</p>

<p>Golden advice by Dr Ian -&gt;  “<strong>the severity of your symptoms does not change the effectiveness of the operation</strong>“</p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/paraschopra" data-show-count="true">Follow @paraschopra</a></p>
<p><span><strong>Have an opinion on this essay?</strong></span> You can send your feedback on <a href="https://invertedpassion.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#601001120113515958574b0910060505040201030b20070d01090c4e030f0d">email</a> to me.</p>





			</div><!-- .entry-content -->
						<!-- .entry-footer -->
		</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://invertedpassion.com/most-surgeries-are-ineffective/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25857435</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 10:26:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Management by metrics leads us astray]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 134 | Comments 95 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25856257">thread link</a>) | @jakobgreenfeld
<br/>
January 20, 2021 | https://jakobgreenfeld.com/metrics | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jakobgreenfeld.com/metrics">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p>Let’s say my goal this year is to get to 10k monthly recurring revenue (MRR).</p>

<p>MRR first, everything else second. I would ruthlessly cut out all activities that don’t lead to a measurable MRR increase. For example, I would stop writing blog posts like the one you’re currently reading. I certainly wouldn’t create fun projects like What to Tweet or take the time for non-transactional Zoom calls.</p>

<p>I would focus on my revenue generating projects, crank up the advertising machinery and do everything I can think of that potentially increases my MRR.
I’m fairly confident that I would reach 10k MRR by the end of the year. But at what price?</p>

<p>Let’s take a step back for a second.</p>

<p>You know who manages by metrics? Big companies like Google, Amazon and LinkedIn.</p>

<p>And what do they have in common?</p>

<p>Their core product got notably worse over time.</p>

<p>Google’s search results are dominated by ads and many users now use workarounds to find what they’re looking for (“Best headphone reddit”). LinkedIn looks like Minesweeper. Facebook was a fun place to meet friends. And if you search for an electronics product on Amazon, you immediately feel like you’re at a flea market in the middle of Shenzhen.
This is the result of hundreds of decisions that were motivated by a short-term focus on specific metrics like revenue and click rates. And while these decisions most likely optimized the metrics, they made the user experience worse.</p>

<p>The problem is that we don’t have the technology to measure the right thing. Or maybe the “right thing” is inherently immeasurable.</p>

<p>Or, and that’s my personal favorite, we’re dealing with a Schrödinger’s cat like situation. The “right thing” is only the right thing as long as we’re not trying to optimize it.
This is known as Goodhart’s law. “When a measure becomes a target, it ceases to be a good measure.“</p>

<p>Let’s consider another example.</p>

<p>Who else manages by metrics? Politicians!</p>

<p>Instead of some boring historic example (there are plenty, just read “Seeing like a State”), I’m going to spice things up by talking about something that’s happening right now.
It’s not hard to anticipate what I want to talk about since there’s precisely one thing that’s currently happening: Covid-19.</p>

<p>Politicians try to manage the situation by focusing on metrics like the “R number”. At least here in Germany the motto is: let’s lower the R number at all costs.
Turns out the cost of this strategy is incredibly high. It’s just not immediately measurable.</p>

<p>For example, everyone’s getting fatter since all gyms and sport clubs are closed. Most people are developing unhealthy eating habits because there’s simply nothing else to do. Social connections are rapidly degregating even though everyone knows how important they’re for the human wellbeing.</p>

<p>I’m not a doctor and don’t play one on the internet, but I can easily imagine that there are lots of further unintended consequences of the current lockdown policy. For example, since most people now spend most of their time indoors alone and wear masks when they leave their homes, their immune system isn’t stressed regularly like it usual is. Hence I wouldn’t be surprised if many people will get sick of other diseases once the lockdown ends as a result of weakened immune systems.</p>

<p>Just to clarify, I’m all for taking Covid seriously. In fact, I’ve been hoarding masks since 2009. I spent the summer of 2009 with a bunch of friends in Lloret de Mar (a party hotspot in Spain) just when news of the swine flu started to emerge. Long story short, everyone in our group got sick (20+ people) except for my girlfriend and me because we’ve been wearing masks.
Now the most famous example how focusing on metrics can have unhealthy consequences is the cobra effect. I’ll just quote from Wikipedia:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“The term cobra effect originated in an anecdote that describes an occurrence during India under British rule. The British government was concerned about the number of venomous cobras in Delhi. The government therefore offered a bounty for every dead cobra. Initially, this was a successful strategy; large numbers of snakes were killed for the reward. Eventually, however, enterprising people began to breed cobras for the income. When the government became aware of this, the reward program was scrapped. When cobra breeders set their now-worthless snakes free, the wild cobra population further increased.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>There is one more example I always have to talk about when the topic comes up: academia.</p>

<p>Stagnation apologists love to argue that the lack of progress in science is simply a result of the fact that all low-hanging fruit are gone.</p>

<p>That’s complete nonsense. There’s still plenty of low-hanging fruit. It’s just that everyone is so busy chasing meaningless metrics that they can’t see them.</p>

<p>In academia the metric of choice usually has something to do with the number of citations. But just like Google’s backlink-driven algorithm (which was in fact inspired by academia’s citation metrics) was quickly gamed by savvy webmasters, academia’s algorithm is gamed by careerists.</p>

<p>And I’m not talking about some tiny minority here. If you want to survive in academia, you have to play the citation game. And if everyone is cheating, at the very least you have to do the same to stand a chance.</p>

<p>You have to partner up with others because five people can write five times as many papers. You agree to constantly cite each other. Likewise, you focus on incremental additions to established ideas because that’s the safest way to new publications regularly. You work on the stuff everyone else is working on because how else are you going to get citations?</p>

<p>And one thing you absolutely have to avoid like the plague is the risky and deep kind of research that leads to real progress in the field.</p>

<p>The problem isn’t that citations are a bad metric, and we need to come up with smarter ones. Instead, it’s just Goodhart’s law in action.
Every attempt to manage academia makes it worse.</p>

<p>As soon a new metric is introduced it will misdirect the attention of scientists towards playing the game, instead of progressing science.</p>

<p>I talked about three areas, but the same pattern occurs almost everywhere. For example, just remember when everyone started minimizing fat in their diet or how grades are used to measure “learning”.</p>

<p>Crucially the problem is not the specific metric that’s being used. Whatever new metric gets introduced will soon again be made useless by Goodhart’s law. The metrics game will always be akin to Whac-A-Mole.</p>

<p>Now where does this leave us? If management by metrics doesn’t work, what else should we do?</p>

<p>First of all, I think that looking at metrics can be helpful. They just shouldn’t be the sole yardstick decisions are measured against.</p>

<p>And while the map never will be the territory, the picture you’re looking at gets more accurate the more metrics you consider. For example, if politicians would not just consider the R number but hundreds of metrics that take different aspects of a population’s wellbeing into account, the decisions would be better ones.</p>

<p>The obvious problem is that decisions become much harder if you consider more than one metric.</p>

<p>But more importantly there are so many factors we can’t measure that nevertheless should be taken into account.</p>

<p>The more I think about it the more I become convinced that it all boils down to talking to people.</p>

<p>And I’m not talking about surveys that distill thousands of standardized “conversations” into a few numbers or analytics tools that do similar things for behavior. I’m talking about real one-on-one interactions.</p>

<p>Just imagine if Jeff Bezos would talk to hundreds of real (non pre-vetted) Amazon customers each month and take what he hears in these conversations seriously. Or if politicians would have long conversations with regular people from all wakes of life. Or if academic committees would actually talk to applicants before filtering them out based on citation metrics.</p>

<p>In our hyper rational world it’s extremely hard to justify decisions based on the mere gut feeling you got from a few conversations. But this is exactly what people should be doing.</p>

<p>Engagement metrics will never tell you if users are genuinely happy when they use your product. But a few genuine conversations will.</p>

<p>A resume will never tell you if a person is genuinely interested in uncovering unknown truths about nature. But a 30-minute conversation will.</p>

<p>Yes, it’s so much easier to reach a consensus if you just hire the candidate with the highest citation metrics or implement the feature that will lead to the largest revenue increase in the next quarter. But while it’s the easiest decision it’s usually not the best one.</p>

<p>And I think the same applies not just to managing organizations but also to managing ourselves.</p>

<p>Just by listening to my own body I’ll always know better than any fitness tracker if I slept well, better than any blood test if my diet is healthy, and better than my bank account if I’m happy.
That doesn’t mean that I’ll not use a fitness tracker, make regular blood tests, or check my bank account. But I certainly won’t allow them to dictate my decisions.</p>

<p>I’ll look at all the facts and take everything in, even the stuff that can’t be measured, and then I’ll just go with my gut.</p>


  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jakobgreenfeld.com/metrics</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25856257</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 06:52:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[90% of Everything Is Crap]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 148 | Comments 84 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25851932">thread link</a>) | @mcrittenden
<br/>
January 20, 2021 | https://critter.blog/2021/01/20/90-of-everything-is-crap/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://critter.blog/2021/01/20/90-of-everything-is-crap/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="page">
	<p><a href="#content">Skip to content</a></p><!-- #masthead -->

	
	<div id="content">

	<div id="primary">
		<main id="main">

		

<article id="post-6232">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>
		
<p>Today is the day I discovered <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sturgeon%27s_law">Sturgeon’s law</a>:</p>



<figure><blockquote><p>Ninety percent of everything is crap.</p><cite>Sturgeon’s law</cite></blockquote></figure>



<p>I like this for a lot of reasons. But most of all, I like it as a nudge to try harder to enjoy things. </p>



<p>Think you hate poetry? Roller coasters? Banjo music? Thai food? Maybe you haven’t discovered the good 10% yet. Keep looking.</p>



<p>How about work? Think QA engineers are <a href="https://critter.blog/2021/01/04/dont-flip-the-bozo-bit/">useless</a>? Code review is a <a href="https://critter.blog/2020/06/10/spotting-broken-processes/">waste of time</a>? <a href="https://critter.blog/2020/11/16/the-2-responsibilities-of-a-manager/">Managers</a> hurt more than they help? Maybe you’ve been stuck with the crap 90% of them. Keep looking.</p>



<p>Then there’s relationships. Think there’s no one out there who can make you <a href="https://critter.blog/2020/12/08/the-key-to-happiness-is-to-stop-getting-upset-all-the-dang-time/">happy</a>? Maybe you haven’t climbed out of your 90% of crappy relationships yet. Keep looking.</p>



<p>It reminds me of a <a href="https://ideopunk.com/2020/12/22/100-tips-for-a-better-life/">quote I read </a>recently:</p>



<blockquote><p>Keep your identity small. “I’m not the kind of person who does things like that” is not an explanation, it’s a trap. It prevents nerds from working out and men from dancing.&nbsp;</p><cite>Conor Barnes</cite></blockquote>



<p>Remember: <a href="https://critter.blog/2020/10/16/strong-opinions-loosely-held-sure-but-why/">strong opinions, loosely held</a>. If you think you hate something, hold that opinion loosely by putting it to the test. Try to prove it false. </p>



<p>Don’t be so quick to accept that something is not for you. <a href="https://critter.blog/2020/09/21/experimenting-on-myself/">Keep looking</a>.</p>




	</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->
</article><!-- #post-6232 -->
			<!-- .post-nav-wrapper -->
		
		</main><!-- #main -->
	</div><!-- #primary -->


<!-- #secondary -->

	</div><!-- #content -->

	
	<!-- #colophon -->
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://critter.blog/2021/01/20/90-of-everything-is-crap/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25851932</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 21:00:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The harmful assumptions we make about tasks]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 53 | Comments 10 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25850042">thread link</a>) | @croshan
<br/>
January 20, 2021 | https://blog.cyrusroshan.com/post/task-management-assumptions/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.cyrusroshan.com/post/task-management-assumptions/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>Most task managers make two assumptions. Do you make them too?</p>
<ol>
<li><em>A task manager needs to remember all of your tasks</em> <br>(Would you buy a task manager that lost data?)</li>
<li><em>All tasks can use a similar creation workflow</em> <br>(You hit the ‘create issue’ button, and fill in some fields. Simple, obvious, how could it be better?)</li>
</ol>
<p>It’s not obvious that they’re wrong—they actually seem <em>useful</em>. But both at work, and at home, making these assumptions will reduce your effectiveness.</p>
<p>And if you have trouble context-switching, procrastinate tasks, or have an ever-growing task backlog that looms over your head, these assumptions have likely caused you unnecessary pain.</p>
<p>Here’s how they hurt us, and how to stop it from happening.</p>
<h2 id="permanent-tasks-cause-fatigue">Permanent tasks cause fatigue</h2>
<p>Before starting Tandem, my manager Tim previously co-founded <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/05/01/yahoo-acquires-to-do-app-astrid/">Astrid</a>, a personal task manager, which he later sold to Yahoo.</p>
<p>At Astrid, Tim tried an interesting re-engagement email. Users who had been inactive for 6 weeks were asked: “want to delete all your tasks and start fresh?”</p>
<p>The hypothesis was that these inactive users had tasks that overwhelmed them. Either the amount, the complexity, or the low importance of backlogged tasks, caused users to put tasks off. So every time these users visited Astrid, they saw tasks they couldn’t do, felt bad, and eventually stopped visiting—procrastination in action. Astrid’s re-engagement email offered the users a chance to start fresh.</p>
<p>It was impressively compelling. Most re-engagement emails get a 1% response rate. This email had about 5%.</p>
<p>I imagine those users had the same feeling you get when you move from one browser to another, or from one task manager to another, and leave your bookmarks, open tabs, backlogged tasks, to start fresh in the name of increased productivity.</p>
<p>But simply deleting the backlog doesn’t end the cycle.</p>
<hr>
<p>Nowadays, Tim uses a simpler task manager—a notebook. He uses a page a day, adds some tasks from JIRA, and when tasks come in during the day, he writes them down and works on them when he’s available. These are mostly small tasks, things that are easy to forget. If he gets a bug (important to track) or a task he can delegate, he puts it in JIRA.</p>
<p>The notebook isn’t meant to store issues forever. The pages get turned, and previous information becomes less accessible. So the next day, if he needs to carry over something that hasn’t been completed, he needs to make the conscious decision to do so.</p>
<p>This solution solves task-management fatigue. And incidentally, it solves another problem:</p>
<h2 id="not-all-tasks-are-created-the-same">Not all tasks are created the same</h2>
<p>There is a gap in task management. When we look at the tools used for tracking tasks and goals, there’s something for every level of the company:</p>
<br>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Level</th>
<th>Goal</th>
<th>Tool</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Company quarter-level</td>
<td>Quarterly Goals</td>
<td>Notion/Gdocs</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Org quarter-level</td>
<td>KPIs</td>
<td>Notion/Gdocs, JIRA Epics</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Team sprint-level</td>
<td>Tickets</td>
<td>JIRA Tasks/Bugs</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Personal day-level</td>
<td>???</td>
<td>???</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Except at the personal day-level, where you’re working on tickets, getting requests for feature updates from your PM, bug discoveries from QA, and breaking down your actual tickets into different tasks, which may require subtasks that weren’t anticipated.</p>
<p>One proposal is that you should track all of these tasks, no matter how small, in JIRA. But the teams I see successful at implementing this are those that can afford to work at a slower, more “enterprise” pace. Which isn’t a problem—at least for engineering—but it’s often not an option at smaller startups, when learning cycles must be fast.</p>
<p><em>Even if you work at a larger company, at a slower pace, you may relate when it comes to personal life: tasks come from a variety of directions, at all times. You can’t toss every minor task in a task manager.</em></p>
<p>You can’t fix every task before the next one comes in. If you only use JIRA, you choose between possibly forgetting these small tasks, or breaking your train of thought to search, categorize, and fill out a form every time you get a small task.</p>
<p>On the flip side, quickly writing these down in a temporary place means that <strong>you don’t need to</strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Spend mental effort remembering minor tasks,</li>
<li>or take significant time to file minor issues.</li>
<li>Have your task manager filled with minor issues you’ve forgotten to close,</li>
<li>or leave hastily-written issues for later, when you forget what the vaguely titled issue is for.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="correcting-for-the-mistakes">Correcting for the mistakes</h2>
<p>The solution is not complicated: use a temporary, personal task manager.</p>
<p>Don’t go out and buy something new. You already have something you can use at home. Tim’s notebook is a good example. I personally message myself on Slack (and iMessage, for personal use).</p>
<details zgotmplz="">
<summary>An example of how I Slack myself</summary>
<div>
<h4 id="using-slack-for-daily-personal-tasks">Using Slack for daily personal tasks</h4>
<p>When I’m working, and get a non-urgent task that would otherwise interrupt me, it goes in my Slack DMs. This is what it looks like:</p>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<p><img src="https://blog.cyrusroshan.com/img/task-management-assumptions/IMG_7647.jpg">
</p>
<p>Some days are quiet</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><img src="https://blog.cyrusroshan.com/img/task-management-assumptions/IMG_7644.jpg">
</p>
<p>And some are hectic</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>In the morning, to re-build yesterday’s context, I just look at yesterday’s list. If there are unfinished items, I can carry them over. But it’s a conscious decision. I don’t need to carry over optional, low-priority tasks.</p>
<p>And if you’ve got a bad memory, there’s a huge benefit for team stand-ups. I used to write JQL filters to search JIRA (doesn’t work—and misses tasks), now I just take a look at Slack.</p>
</div>
</details>
<p>The important requirements are just that your task manager:</p>
<ol>
<li>Requires effort to carry over old tasks.</li>
<li>Makes writing down tasks quick.</li>
<li>Isn’t used for notes <em>(anecdotally, this adds noise, and forces you to parse notes from tasks)</em>.</li>
</ol>
<p>If a task is critical, long term, or requires cooperation, file it in your normal issue tracker. Otherwise, it’s probably a daily, personal task, and you can file it in here.</p>
<p>So take out a notebook, open Slack, pick what works for you. And see if you don’t feel calmer and more in control of your tasks.</p>
<hr>


<p>I think these tools have interesting ideas to help individuals manage tasks.</p>
<h3 id="amna">Amna</h3>
<p>Ravi, my old college roommate and friend since high school, left Microsoft to build <a href="https://www.getamna.com/">Amna</a>, a personal task manager with tight browser integration.</p>
<p>I resonate with the thesis: recently I switched away from Firefox Tree Style Tabs, because I noticed that by organizing my tabs (which were part of tasks), it inadvertently became a de-facto task manager. But it wasn’t built for that!</p>
<p>Amna solves that exact problem: each task you do spawns a browser that keeps all of your relevant tabs.</p>
<div>
<p><img src="https://blog.cyrusroshan.com/img/task-management-assumptions/amna1.jpg">
</p>
<p>All the tabs in this browser window are related to the same task, and Amna keeps their state when I close the browser.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><img src="https://blog.cyrusroshan.com/img/task-management-assumptions/amna2.jpg">
</p>
<p>After I'm done with a task, I can go back and look at the tabs I had open.</p>
</div>
<p>It helps prevent:</p>
<ul>
<li>Muscle-memory opening HN, clicking an interesting blog post, and leaving it open “to read later” for several weeks</li>
<li>The pain of trawling through bookmarks and browser history, when you realize you forgot something</li>
<li>The clutter of leaving tabs open to prevent forgetting something</li>
</ul>
<p>If you’ve forgotten a time when you had less than five tabs open, <a href="https://www.getamna.com/">try using Amna</a>.</p>
<h3 id="jam">Jam</h3>
<p>Two of my ex-Cloudflare friends, Dani and Irtefa, started <a href="https://jam.dev/">Jam</a>. It’s probably the fastest way for PMs/designers to directly make comments on a website. So you get less minor interruptions, and more clarity on the requested change.</p>
<div>
<p><img src="https://blog.cyrusroshan.com/img/task-management-assumptions/jam2.jpg">
</p>
<p>All you do is type `jam` on the page, click an element, and type the comment</p>
</div>
<p>But I don’t include Jam here just for that. Jam also allows you to <a href="https://words.jam.dev/introducing-jam-wand/">offload the actual copy changes</a> to your PM, which flat-out decreases your minor tasks. If this sounds exciting, get on the waitlist <a href="https://jam.dev/">here</a>.</p>
<hr>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.cyrusroshan.com/post/task-management-assumptions/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25850042</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 18:30:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I tried creating a web browser and Google blocked me (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 463 | Comments 172 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25849800">thread link</a>) | @gu5
<br/>
January 20, 2021 | https://blog.samuelmaddock.com/posts/google-widevine-blocked-my-browser/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.samuelmaddock.com/posts/google-widevine-blocked-my-browser/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p><img src="https://blog.samuelmaddock.com/images/google-widevine-gmail.png" alt="I’m sorry but we’re not supporting an open source solution like this"></p><p>After 4 months of waiting, that is the response I got from <a href="https://www.widevine.com/">Widevine</a>, Google’s DRM for web browsers, regarding a <a href="https://github.com/castlabs/electron-releases#verified-media-path-vmp">license agreement</a>. For the last 2 years I’ve been working on a web browser that now cannot be completed because Google, the creators of the <em>open source</em> browser Chrome, won’t allow DRM in an <em>open source</em> project.</p><p>The browser I’m building, called <a href="https://github.com/samuelmaddock/metastream">Metastream</a>, is an Electron-based (Chromium derived), MIT-licensed browser hosted on GitHub. Its main feature is the ability to playback videos on the web, synchronized with other peers. Each client runs its own instance of the Metastream browser and transmits playback information to keep them in sync—no audio or video content is sent.</p><p>If someone is creating a browser that wants to playback media, they’ll soon discover the requirement of DRM for larger web media services such as Netflix and Hulu. There are a few DRM providers for the web including Widevine, PlayReady, and FairPlay.</p><p>As far as I’m aware, Widevine is the only available DRM for a Chromium-based browser, especially so for Electron. Chromium accounts for roughly <strong>70% market share</strong> of all web browsers, soon to include <a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/microsoft-building-chromium-powered-web-browser-windows-10">Microsoft’s upcoming Edge browser rewrite</a>. Waiting 4 months for a minimal response from a vendor with such a large percentage of the market is unacceptable.</p><p>This isn’t something I’m alone in either, <a href="https://github.com/electron/electron/issues/12427">several Electron users</a> have waited months for a response. More prominently, the creators of Brave Browser also had <a href="https://github.com/brave/browser-laptop/issues/10449#issuecomment-323800130">issues waiting for replies from Google Widevine</a>.</p><blockquote><p>“This is a prime example for why free as in beer is not enough. Small share browsers are at the mercy of Google, and Google is stalling us for no communicated-to-us reason.”<br>- Brian Bondy, Co-founder &amp; CTO of Brave</p></blockquote><p>I’m now only left with two options regarding the fate of Metastream: stop development of a desktop browser version, or pivot my project to a browser extension with reduced features. The latter requiring publishing to the Google Chrome Web Store which would further entrench the project into a Google walled garden.</p><p>If you know of any way to help out, <a href="https://blog.samuelmaddock.com/contact">please get in touch</a>.</p><p><strong>April 4th edit:</strong> No response from Google Widevine yet. Because a few folks asked, here is the <a href="https://blog.samuelmaddock.com/widevine/gmail-thread.html">full email exchange I had with Widevine</a>. The initial response was received after getting in contact with another browser vendor to ping a Widevine contact they have. If you intend to inquire about a license agreement for your project, including the information they requested upfront could help.</p><p><em><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19553941" target="_blank">Discuss on Hacker News</a><br><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/b8jekq/i_tried_creating_a_web_browser_and_google_blocked/" target="_blank">Discuss on Reddit</a><br><a href="https://github.com/samuelmaddock/blog.samuelmaddock.com/commits/master/content/posts/google-widevine-blocked-my-browser.md" target="_blank">View changelog</a></em></p><ul><li><a href="https://blog.samuelmaddock.com/tags/browser">browser</a></li><li><a href="https://blog.samuelmaddock.com/tags/drm">drm</a></li><li><a href="https://blog.samuelmaddock.com/tags/google">google</a></li><li><a href="https://blog.samuelmaddock.com/tags/widevine">widevine</a></li></ul></section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.samuelmaddock.com/posts/google-widevine-blocked-my-browser/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25849800</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 18:13:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Flow-Based Programming]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 200 | Comments 97 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25848542">thread link</a>) | @hypomnemata
<br/>
January 20, 2021 | https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/index.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/index.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <section>
            <article>
                <p>In computer programming, Flow-Based Programming (FBP) is a programming paradigm, discovered/invented by <a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/index.html">J. Paul Rodker Morrison</a> in the late '60s, that uses a "data processing factory" metaphor for designing and building applications.  FBP defines applications as networks of "black box" processes, which communicate via data chunks (called Information Packets) travelling across predefined connections (think "conveyor belts"), where the connections are specified externally to the processes. These black box processes can be reconnected endlessly to form different applications without having to be changed internally. FBP is thus naturally component-oriented.</p>
                <p>FBP is a special case of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dataflow">dataflow</a> programming characterized by asynchronous, concurrent processes "under the covers", Information Packets with defined lifetimes, named ports, "bounded buffer" connections, and definition of connections external to the components - it has been found to support improved development time and maintainability, reusability, rapid prototyping, simulation, improved performance, and good communication among developers,  maintenance staff, users, systems people, and management - not to mention that FBP naturally takes advantage of multiple cores... without the programmer having to struggle with the intricacies of multitasking!</p>
               <p>FBP exhibits "data coupling", described in the article on coupling as the loosest type of coupling between components. The concept of loose coupling is in turn related to that of service-oriented architectures, and FBP fits a number of the criteria for such an architecture, albeit at a more fine-grained level than most examples of this architecture.</p>
					<p>FBP promotes high-level, functional style of specifications that simplify reasoning about system behavior. An example of this is the distributed data flow model for constructively specifying and analyzing the semantics of distributed multi-party protocols.</p>
                <p><img src="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/bottling_factory.png" alt="Bottling factory" height="400"> </p>
                
                <p>
                    FBP involves a significant "paradigm shift" from conventional programming, as it uses an "assembly line" image of data processing, which really has to be used to experience its advantages.  Not surprisingly given the hold that the so-called "von Neumann" paradigm has over programming technology, over the last 40+ years a number of companies have come out with FBP-like or "FBP-inspired" systems (to borrow a term coined by Joe Witt of Cloudera), which do not involve this paradigm shift, including some of the biggest and most successful companies in the industry, such as IBM, Microsoft, Facebook, Google, and the New York Times (see <a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/links_external.html">FBP External References</a>).  Unfortunately, without the FBP paradigm shift, these systems cannot fully achieve the advantages listed above, although most of them combine a visual notation with some degree of componentry.  We have therefore been forced to use the term "classical FBP" to refer to the FBP architecture described in this web site.  It is hard for someone reading documentation to tell whether a given product calling itself "FBP- like" is "classical" or not,  but, roughly, multiple input ports, "back pressure", and asynchronism, constitute a sort of litmus test to check whether systems should be classed as "classical" FBP systems. While the FBP paradigm shift may cause some trouble at first, given the prevalence of the older programming approaches, in fact it embodies a simple mental model (not "simple" as in easy but "simple" as in elegant, to quote Joe Witt), and has proven over several decades to result in applications that are more understandable and maintainable than those built using the conventional (von Neumann) paradigm.
                </p>
	    <p>If you <i>have</i> come across Flow-Based Programming by way of NoFlo, Flowhub, Node-RED, or similar packages, it is recommended that you read <a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/fbp-inspired-vs-real-fbp.html"><i>FBP vs. FBP-inspired Systems</i></a>, which attempts to highlight the differences and similarities between FBP proper, or "classical" FBP, (the subject of this web site) on the one hand, and NoFlo and other similar "FBP-inspired" systems on the other. </p>
                <p>FBP is described in J. Paul Morrison's book, <a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/book.html">Flow-Based Programming: A New Approach to Application Development"</a>, now in its 2nd edition, which can be obtained in paperback form from <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Flow-Based-Programming-2nd-Application-Development/dp/1451542321">Amazon</a>, or in 2 e-book formats: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Flow-Based-Programming-J-Paul-Morrison-ebook/dp/B004PLO66O">Kindle</a> and <a href="http://www.lulu.com/shop/j-paul-morrison/flow-based-programming-2nd-edition/ebook/product-21172063.html">epub</a>.</p>
                <p>Further down on this web page you will find a bunch of useful links, including some videos demonstrating the use of the FBP diagramming tool, <a href="https://github.com/jpaulm/drawfbp/blob/master/README.md">DrawFBP</a>.  During FBP's early days, networks were coded by hand, and initially we used pencil and paper, followed by more sophisticated graphical tools, whether or not they played well with FBP software.  However, with the advent of good graphical support, we now have a powerful graphical tool (<a href="https://github.com/jpaulm/drawfbp">DrawFBP</a>), and in recent years the emphasis has been shifting to doing the diagramming on-line, and then generating the network code (we can see this progression with other flow tools on the market).  Now that compile and run functions (for Java and C#) have been added to DrawFBP, the developer can do much of the development graphically, and on-line.
                </p>    
                <p>We are in the process of "growing" a <a href="https://github.com/jpaulm/fbp-tutorial-filter-file">tutorial</a> which will introduce the reader to the basic concepts of FBP by means of a series of "steps", which use the diagramming tool DrawFBP to progressively expand an application diagram and generate and run code at many of those steps.  </p>            
            <p>There is a Google group on FBP, with almost 800 members, and a Slack channel has recently been set up - here is the invitation link, if you are interested in joining: <a href="https://join.slack.com/t/fbphq/shared_invite/enQtOTM4ODkzMTYyODE3LTJiMmNlZjhiMWY1MDY1ODA4Y2YzNDBlNDZlMTBkMDNlMjcwNzg2MGZhZjA2NjJjYTliYTM0OTIyYmM0Yzk0MDQ">Slack invitation</a>.</p>

                <!--<p>We know you are tired of Powerpoint presentations, but <a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/FBPnew.ppt">this one</a> (from 2007) gives quite a good overview of FBP - as it was at that time.  There is also a <a href="http://player.vimeo.com/video/79329015">video</a> (not very professional, I'm afraid!), where I present this at a Meetup in Toronto in Sept. 2013 organized by Paul Tarvydas, CEO of Tarvydas-Sanford Controls Inc., and Dann Toliver. It has a few jokes and reminiscences, and may be more accessible than the straight Powerpoint presentation!   The Paul referred to in the video is Paul Tarvydas. Towards the end (at 40:12) there is a brief demo of the FBP diagramming tool, <a href="..\graphicsstuff\index.shtml">DrawFBP</a>.</p>-->
                
        <h3>FBP Tenets (open-ended)</h3>
        <ul>
                <li>If work is boring, let a robot do it!</li>
                <li>Corollary: using a design tool should be fun! </li>
                <li>No one language should try to do <i>everything</i>!</li>
                <li>The world is asynchronous - don't try to force the systems we build into a synchronous framework!</li>
                <li>The von Neumann paradigm is only appropriate within a <i>single</i> process!  Duh!</li>
                <li>A process needs to be able to have more than one input port, and needs to be able to choose which one to receive from! </li>
                <li>If a process's upstream connection fills up, the process feeding it will be suspended (unless the connection is marked "DropOldest")  ("back pressure")</li>
            </ul>
        
        <h3>Links</h3> 
        <ol>
                        <!--<li><a href="introduction.html">Introduction</a></li>-->
                        <li><a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/history.html">History</a></li>
                        <li><a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/concepts.html">Concepts</a></li>
                        <li><a href="https://github.com/jpaulm/fbp-tutorial-filter-file">Tutorial</a> (under development)</li>
                        <li>
                            <a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/software.html">Software</a>:
                            <ul>
                                <li>
                                    <a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/software.html#JavaFBP">JavaFBP</a>
                                    <ul>
                                        <li>
                                            <a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/software.html#JavaFBPWS">JavaFBP Web Sockets</a>
                                        </li>
                                    </ul>
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                    <a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/software.html#C#FBP">C#FBP</a>
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                    <a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/software.html#CppFBP">CppFBP (C++ and Lua)</a>
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                    <a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/software.html#JSFBP">JSFBP</a> (JavaScript FBP, using Marcel Laverdet's <a href="https://github.com/laverdet/node-fibers">node-fibers</a>)
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                    <a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/software.html#DrawFBP">DrawFBP</a>
                                </li>
                            </ul>
                        </li>
                        <br>
                        <li><a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/examples.html">Examples</a></li>
                        <li><a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/oops.html">Comparison with OO</a></li>
                        <li><a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/comparison.html">Comparison with other paradigms and methodologies</a></li>
			<li><a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/FBP-and-multithreading.html">FBP and multithreading</a></li>
			<li><a href="https://fbp.twyoung.com/">Tom Young's FBP web site, including categorization of FBP and FBP-like systems</a></li>
                        <li><a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/FBPnew.ppt">PowerPoint presentation on FBP (2007)</a></li>
                        <li><a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/knol_flow-based-programming.htm">Justin Bozonier's "knol" re FBP (2009)</a></li>
                        <li><a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/fbp-inspired-vs-real-fbp.html">FBP vs. FBP-inspired Systems</a></li>
                        <li><a href="http://www.jpaulmorrison.com/cgi-bin/wiki.pl">Old C2-style FBP Wiki</a></li>
                        <li><a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/morrison_2005.htm">Patterns in Flow-Based Programming</a></li>
                        <li><a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/biblio.html">Bibliography</a></li>
                        <li><a href="https://jpaulmorrison.com/fbp/1stedchaps.html">Chapters from the first edition - online</a></li>
                        <li><a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/links_external.html">External links</a></li>
                    </ol>
                


                <!-- <p> <iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/up2yhNTsaDs" width="500" height="420" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=true></iframe> </p> -->

                <p><object width="500" height="420" data="https://www.youtube.com/embed/up2yhNTsaDs"></object> </p>

                <p><i>Video Interview with J. Paul Rodker Morrison, Summer 2013 </i></p>

                <p>
                    In addition, there are six Youtube videos about DrawFBP, illustrating a number of basic ("classical") FBP concepts (what we are now calling "FBP-inspired" or "FBP-like" systems do not necessarily contain all of these, although DrawFBP should be able to support most of these systems):
                    </p><ol>
                        <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OrKenPOV4Js">DrawFBP video #1</a></li>
                        <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9NXYNxDjFWY">DrawFBP video #2</a></li>
                        <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-AmzfhV2hIU">DrawFBP video #3</a></li>
                        <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F0lKQpIjfVE">DrawFBP video #4</a></li>
                        <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5brTDk8cpNo">DrawFBP video #5</a> - concept of "subnets", both at design and implementation time</li>
                        <li><a href="https://youtu.be/IvTAexROKSA">DrawFBP video #6</a> - simple interactive systems using WebSockets, with demo of JavaFBP-WebSockets (JavaFBP and HTML5)</li>
                    </ol>
                
                <p>
                    Finally, a <a href="http://player.vimeo.com/video/79329015">video</a> presentation at a Meetup in Toronto in Sept. 2013 organized by Paul Tarvydas, CEO of Tarvydas-Sanford Controls Inc., and Dann Toliver, also containing a few jokes and reminiscences...
                </p>
                <p>Google group on <a href="http://groups.google.com/group/flow-based-programming">Flow-Based Programming</a></p>

                <p>C2-style <a href="http://www.jpaulmorrison.com/cgi-bin/wiki.pl">Flow-Based Programming Wiki</a> (last maintained in 2010)</p>

                <p>More general <a href="https://github.com/flowbased/flowbased.org/wiki">FBP Wiki</a> by Vladimir Sibirov, et al., intended to cover both "classical" FBP and FBP-inspired approaches (still under development )</p>
                <p><a href="https://flow-based.org/">FBP Specification wiki</a> - under development by Vladimir Sibirov

                </p>
                <p>Twitter hashtag: <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23FlowBased&amp;src=hash">#FlowBased</a></p>
		<p><a href="https://fbphq.slack.com/">Slack Channel</a></p>



            </article>


            <article>
                <!--
                <p style="text-align:center"><img style="width: 800px;"
                        alt="Schematic Brokerage app" src="EB2a.jpg"></p>
                <p>Schematic Brokerage application (expand blocks, add caches, multiplexing, to taste)</p>  -->

                <figure>
                    <img src="https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/EB2a.jpg" alt="Schematic Brokerage app" width="800px" <figcaption="">Schematic Brokerage application (expand blocks, add caches, multiplexing, etc.)
                </figure>

                <p>
                    <a href="https://jpaulm.github.io/index.html">J Paul Rodker Morrison</a>
                </p>

            </article>
        </section>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jpaulm.github.io/fbp/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25848542</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 16:42:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why outsource your auth system?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 57 | Comments 78 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25848349">thread link</a>) | @mooreds
<br/>
January 20, 2021 | https://fusionauth.io/blog/2021/01/20/why-outsource-auth/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://fusionauth.io/blog/2021/01/20/why-outsource-auth/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            
              <p>You’re a software engineering leader, and you’re great at your job. You know that the optimal path for software development lies in figuring out which components of your design to implement from scratch and which have already been implemented by specialists and can be reused.</p>

<!--more-->

<p>You also know that these aren’t decisions that you can only make once – you have to keep reevaluating based on environment changes and the needs of new products.</p>

<p>Authentication is one of those components that you deal with all the time. Auth is a necessary part of any software product, but how you implement auth is not necessarily always the same. Careful consideration is needed, because your decision to outsource will not only impact speed of development, but also long-term product maintenance – you don’t want to slow down time to market because you re-implemented an entire auth system unnecessarily, but you also don’t want to use an auth system that is going to cause problems down the road.</p>

<p>So what are the primary considerations when making your decision?</p>

<h2 id="speed-to-market">Speed to market</h2>

<p>This is the most obvious consideration. Depending on the features you need, it could literally take months to implement auth in-house, whereas it could take less than a day to incorporate an outsourced solution.</p>

<p>You could say “but what if we only need a bare-bones implementation? Some salted hashes in a database and we’re good to go!” That’s a totally valid point, and if you don’t anticipate needing sophisticated auth features then your best bet might be to do a quick in-house implementation and move on.</p>

<p>However, time and time again I’ve seen product developers underestimate the sophistication of features that will be required when their userbases grow. Most of the time development organizations then fall prey to the sunk costs fallacy and double down on augmenting their in-house solution, even when it may be more efficient to abandon the home-grown effort and replace it with an outsourced solution. This will cause huge issues for maintainability, which I’ll talk about further below.</p>

<h2 id="consequences-of-an-auth-breach">Consequences of an auth breach</h2>

<p>Planning for the worst possible case can prevent total financial ruin for your company or division. If a breach of security happens and PII (Personally Identifiable Information) is leaked from your in-house auth system, it can not only cause your company reputational damage but also significant financial penalties (not to mention potential jail time if you try to cover up the breach).</p>

<p>If you outsource your auth system you can limit your liability, and also protect your reputation – if there is a breach on your auth provider’s side, it’s likely that the breach will extend beyond your company. A breach in an outsourced auth provider that is used by many different companies will be big news, and customers will be more likely to forgive you for making a mistake in your choice of auth provider than for implementing a poor auth system yourself.</p>

<p>A not-insignificant addendum is that I believe your in-house system is much more likely to suffer a breach than an outsourced provider who is an expert in security. I have no studies to support this claim, but I have never seen a major auth provider compromised, and I’ve definitely seen companies suffer breaches due to their own in-house auth implementations – <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/01/hacked-and-dumped-online-773-million-records-with-plaintext-passwords/">this article discusses a compilation of 21 million plaintext passwords collected from various breaches</a> wherein passwords were not hashed and salted by auth systems.</p>

<p>Properly storing passwords is an incredibly low bar, and yet companies that manage their own auth still do it incorrectly all the time.</p>

<h2 id="consequences-of-an-auth-outage">Consequences of an auth outage</h2>

<p>While less damaging than breaches, outages can still cause reputational damage and liability issues if your SLAs make uptime guarantees. Similarly to breaches, if you outsource your auth system it’s likely that any auth outage will extend beyond your company.</p>

<p>As an example, when Microsoft’s Azure Active Directory (AAD) <a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/microsofts-azure-ad-authentication-outage-what-went-wrong/">went down for a good portion of the afternoon late last year</a>, logins for applications across the internet stopped working.</p>

<p>When your competitors’ authorization systems are down at the same time yours are, nobody blames you for it, but when you’re the only company having issues, you suffer reputationally. No matter what your outsourced auth system is (FusionAuth, Cognito, AAD, etc), you can be almost certain that you won’t be alone in the event of an outage.</p>

<h2 id="maintainability">Maintainability</h2>

<p>There are trade-offs here. The benefits to an in-house system include:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Your engineers can design the exact system to fit your needs, and you’ll have unrestricted ability to add very specific features if requirements change over time.</li>
  <li>If the same engineers who built the system are maintaining it, then they’ll have the context required to anticipate issues as they add features.</li>
</ul>

<p>However, the drawbacks can be large:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Complex new features can take significant time to build. Outsourced auth systems likely have these features already built (things like multi-factor authentication, user management interfaces, analytics and audit logs, and brute force hack detection, among others).</li>
  <li>With an in-house solution, you’ll have to budget time to monitor new security threats and patch your system in a rapidly evolving threat landscape.</li>
  <li>You won’t get the benefits of a dedicated team that are constantly improving your auth system. This is actually a bigger deal than it seems, because if you outsource auth then other companies will also be filing issue reports and feature requests on your behalf, so you reap the benefits of those extra eyes as well.</li>
  <li>In the case of mergers or acquisitions, an in-house solution is likely to be terrible at combining different databases of users and managing things like duplicates or incomplete data. Such enterprise identity unification efforts can founder on internal auth systems. FusionAuth, on the other hand, supports modeling different user bases with tenants.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="cost-of-in-house-vs-outsourced-auth">Cost of in-house vs outsourced auth</h2>

<p>When building an in-house auth system your costs are all ostensibly sunk (engineer salaries). However, if building your system in-house delays time to market or prevents creation of other features, the build could cost you a significant amount of real income. There will also be on-going maintenance costs with an in-house solution.</p>

<p>When making cost calculations, you should compare:</p>

<p><strong>Revenue lost by slower time-to-market PLUS engineering cost to implement in-house solution PLUS on-going maintenance costs of in-house solution PLUS increased risk of data breach PLUS increased risk of outage PLUS increased risk during a merger or acquisition</strong></p>

<p>vs</p>

<p><strong>The monthly cost incurred by an outsourced provider PLUS the lack of complete control</strong></p>

<p>When evaluating different auth providers, you’ll also want to consider whether an outsourced provider charges on a sliding scale based on number of users or if the cost is fixed. AWS Cognito, for instance, will continue to charge more as your application gains more users. FusionAuth, in contrast, has options that charge a single rate for unlimited users. If your app is small and you don’t expect it to grow much, a sliding scale may be better for you. If you don’t want a large unexpected bill as you gain more users, a provider that allows for fixed costs may be more appealing.</p>



<p>As a final consideration, you may want to evaluate if your engineers even have the ability to implement a secure in-house auth system without a significant investment in education. This is something that many leaders dismiss, since they have great faith in the intelligence and skill of their people.</p>

<p>However, knowledge and intelligence aren’t the same, and just because your engineers are capable of becoming auth experts doesn’t mean you want them to spend the time to do so.</p>

<p>As an engineering leader, you have a responsibility to ensure that your engineers are spending their time on efforts that will optimally contribute to the long-term success of your organization. Auth is a necessary component, but is it really a differentiator for your application?</p>

<p>Only you have the context to make the best decisions for your company, but I hope this article has helped you think through some of the considerations involved in outsourcing your auth.</p>


            
          </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://fusionauth.io/blog/2021/01/20/why-outsource-auth/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25848349</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 16:29:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I no longer trust The Great Suspender]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 856 | Comments 345 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25846504">thread link</a>) | @davidfstr
<br/>
January 20, 2021 | https://dafoster.net/articles/2021/01/20/i-no-longer-trust-the-great-suspender/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dafoster.net/articles/2021/01/20/i-no-longer-trust-the-great-suspender/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    
    
    
    <p>I know a number of folks use <strong>The Great Suspender</strong> to automatically suspend
inactive browser tabs in Chrome. Apparently recent versions of this extension
have been <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/KyleTaylor/comments/jowlt2/open_source_development_the_great_suspender_saga/">taken over by a shady anonymous entity</a> and is now
<a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/great-suspender-extension-now-flagged-malware-edge-has-built-replacement">flagged by Microsoft as malware</a>. Notably the most recent
version of the extension (v7.1.8) has added integrated analytics that can
track all of your browsing activity across all sites. Yikes.</p>

<p><strong>Recommendations for users of The Great Suspender (7.1.8):</strong></p>

<h3>Temporary easy fix</h3>

<ul>
<li>Disable analytics tracking by opening the extension options for
The Great Suspender and checking the box
“Automatic deactivation of any kind of tracking”.</li>
<li>Pray that the shady developer doesn’t issue a malicious update to The Great Suspender later.
(There’s no sensible way to disable updates of an individual extension.)</li>
</ul>


<h3>Permanent harder fix <small>(👈 <strong>Recommended!</strong>)</small></h3>

<ul>
<li>Close as many unneeded tabs as you can.</li>
<li>Unsuspend all remaining tabs. ⏳</li>
<li>Uninstall The Great Suspender.</li>
<li>Download the <a href="https://github.com/greatsuspender/thegreatsuspender/releases/tag/v7.1.6">latest good version</a> of The Great Suspender (7.1.6) from GitHub,
and move it to some permanent location outside your Downloads folder.
(It should be commit 9730c09.)</li>
<li>Load your downloaded copy as <a href="https://lifehacker.com/how-you-can-still-download-chrome-extensions-without-us-1826796797">an unpacked extension</a>.
(This copy will not auto-update to future untrusted versions of the extension.)</li>
<li>All done! 🎉</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Caveat:</strong> My understanding is that installing an unpacked extension in this way
will cause Chrome to <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25847171">issue a new kind of security prompt</a> every time it is
launched, which you’ll have to ignore. 😕</p>

<h3>Other options</h3>

<p>Other browser extensions for suspending tabs exist, as mentioned in the
<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25846504">Hacker New discussion</a> for this article. However I have not conducted my own
security review on any of those other extensions, so buyer beware.</p>

  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dafoster.net/articles/2021/01/20/i-no-longer-trust-the-great-suspender/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25846504</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 14:01:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Bison rangers wanted to oversee U.K. herd]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 88 | Comments 69 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25846480">thread link</a>) | @BayAreaEscapee
<br/>
January 20, 2021 | https://www.cbc.ca/radio/asithappens/as-it-happens-wednesday-edition-1.5871385/bison-rangers-wanted-to-oversee-u-k-herd-no-bison-experience-necessary-1.5871386 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/radio/asithappens/as-it-happens-wednesday-edition-1.5871385/bison-rangers-wanted-to-oversee-u-k-herd-no-bison-experience-necessary-1.5871386">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>A small group of wild, European bison will be introduced to a woodland reserve in England, and the group overseeing the project is looking for two rangers to manage the herd, no previous experience required.</p><div><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5871733.1610571184!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/european-bison.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>European bison, like this one, will be introduced to roam in the wild in the Blean woods near Canterbury, England, next spring. This bison is one of two males in captivity at the Wildwood Trust. <!-- --> <!-- -->(Tom Cawdron)</figcaption></figure><p><span><div><div role="button" tabindex="0" title="Bison rangers wanted to oversee U.K. herd — no bison experience necessary"><div><p><img src="https://thumbnails.cbc.ca/maven_legacy/thumbnails/233/507/AsItHappens-podcast-640x360.jpg" alt=""></p><p><span>As It Happens</span><span>6:31</span><span>Bison rangers wanted to oversee U.K. herd — no bison experience necessary</span></p></div></div></div></span></p><p><span><p><a href="https://www.cbc.ca/radio/asithappens/as-it-happens-wednesday-edition-1.5871385/january-13-2021-episode-transcript-1.5872935">Read Story Transcript</a></p>  <p>It's a&nbsp;job in the great outdoors that doesn't require applicants to have done it before, but the successful candidates will need to be comfortable with horns, hooves and fur.</p>  <p>A conservation project in England is seeking to hire two rangers&nbsp;to oversee&nbsp;a small herd of four to 10 European bison that will be introduced to the&nbsp;ancient Blean Woods near Canterbury in the spring of 2022. The area hasn't seen&nbsp;bison roaming&nbsp;the wild&nbsp;for an estimated 6,000 years.&nbsp;</p>  <p>Stan Smith is the wilder landscapes manager at the Kent Wildlife Trust, a group that has partnered with the Wildwood Trust to create the Wilder Blean&nbsp;project&nbsp;to reintroduce the bison. He hopes the initiative will increase ecological diversity there&nbsp;and is looking for humans to help make it happen.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>  <p>"We're not expecting people to have bison experience in the U.K., that's for sure, because you couldn't get any yet. There aren't any here," he told <em>As It Happens</em> host Carol Off&nbsp;from Hastings, England.&nbsp;</p>  <p>"But what we're looking for in people is somebody who has a really good sort of empathy with animals, that they're probably used to managing large grazing herbivores, things like cattle or horses, and somebody who really understands ...&nbsp;the ecology of the area," he said.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5871772.1610566565!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/blean-woods.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5871772.1610566565!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/blean-woods.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5871772.1610566565!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/blean-woods.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5871772.1610566565!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/blean-woods.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5871772.1610566565!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/blean-woods.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5871772.1610566565!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/blean-woods.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>The West Blean Woods will be home to the bison herd, one of the biggest areas of ancient woodland in the United Kingdom, according to the Kent Wildlife Trust.  <!-- --> <!-- -->(Ray Lewis)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>Smith says that previously, the area would have been home to the steppe bison, which is&nbsp;extinct.&nbsp;</p>  <p>The new bison herd will have about 200 hectares of land to graze — about half of the woodland's 400 hectares. They'll be kept in by an electric fence, according to Smith.</p>  <p>"It's a really nice big size of woodland, one of our largest areas of ancient woodland that we still have ... in the south of England," said Smith.</p>  <h2>Bison are 'ecosystem engineers'</h2>  <p>The hope is that the animals will benefit the woodland's ecosystem through their natural grazing behaviours.</p>  <p>Smith says bison are natural "ecosystem engineers" that modify their habitats just by being there.</p>    <blockquote><span><span><svg version="1.1" focusable="false" x="0px" y="0px" width="30px" height="25px" viewBox="0 0 52.157 39.117" enable-background="new 0 0 52.157 39.117" space="preserve"><g><g><path fill="000000" d="M22.692,10.113c-5.199,1.4-8.398,4.4-8.398,8.801c0,2.4,2,3,3.6,4.199c2.2,1.602,3.4,3.4,3.4,6.602   c0,3.799-3.4,6.799-7.4,6.799c-4.6,0-8.8-3.199-8.8-10.6c0-13.6,7-20,17.599-21.799V10.113z M45.692,10.113   c-5.199,1.4-8.399,4.4-8.399,8.801c0,2.4,2,3,3.601,4.199c2.2,1.602,3.399,3.4,3.399,6.602c0,3.799-3.399,6.799-7.399,6.799   c-4.601,0-8.8-3.199-8.8-10.6c0-13.6,7-20,17.599-21.799V10.113z"></path></g></g><g display="none"><g display="inline"> <path fill="000000" d="M6.648,29.759c5.199-1.4,8.398-4.4,8.398-8.801c0-2.398-2-3-3.599-4.199c-2.2-1.6-3.399-3.4-3.399-6.6   c0-3.801,3.399-6.801,7.399-6.801c4.599,0,8.8,3.201,8.8,10.6c0,13.6-7,20-17.6,21.801V29.759z M29.648,29.759   c5.199-1.4,8.398-4.4,8.398-8.801c0-2.398-2-3-3.599-4.199c-2.2-1.6-3.401-3.4-3.401-6.6c0-3.801,3.401-6.801,7.401-6.801   c4.599,0,8.8,3.201,8.8,10.6c0,13.6-7,20-17.6,21.801V29.759z"></path></g></g></svg>They also obviously produce a lot of dung. And that's fantastic for invertebrates and for fungi.<svg focusable="false" x="0px" y="0px" width="23px" height="22px" viewBox="0 0 52.157 39.117" enable-background="new 0 0 52.157 39.117" space="preserve"><g display="none"><g display="inline"><path fill="000000" d="M22.692,10.113c-5.199,1.4-8.398,4.4-8.398,8.801c0,2.4,2,3,3.6,4.199c2.2,1.602,3.4,3.4,3.4,6.602   c0,3.799-3.4,6.799-7.4,6.799c-4.6,0-8.8-3.199-8.8-10.6c0-13.6,7-20,17.599-21.799V10.113z M45.692,10.113   c-5.199,1.4-8.399,4.4-8.399,8.801c0,2.4,2,3,3.601,4.199c2.2,1.602,3.399,3.4,3.399,6.602c0,3.799-3.399,6.799-7.399,6.799   c-4.601,0-8.8-3.199-8.8-10.6c0-13.6,7-20,17.599-21.799V10.113z"></path></g></g><g><g><path fill="000000" d="M6.648,29.759c5.199-1.4,8.398-4.4,8.398-8.801c0-2.398-2-3-3.599-4.199c-2.2-1.6-3.399-3.4-3.399-6.6   c0-3.801,3.399-6.801,7.399-6.801c4.599,0,8.8,3.201,8.8,10.6c0,13.6-7,20-17.6,21.801V29.759z M29.648,29.759   c5.199-1.4,8.398-4.4,8.398-8.801c0-2.398-2-3-3.599-4.199c-2.2-1.6-3.401-3.4-3.401-6.6c0-3.801,3.401-6.801,7.401-6.801   c4.599,0,8.8,3.201,8.8,10.6c0,13.6-7,20-17.6,21.801V29.759z"></path></g></g></svg></span><cite>- Stan Smith, Kent Wildlife Trust</cite></span></blockquote>    <p>"They are Europe's largest remaining land mammal and ...&nbsp;they love to do things like eat bark off trees, which can sort of selectively kill off certain trees, allowing more light to the woodland floor — the sort of thing that we try to do with chainsaws quite frequently," said Smith.</p>  <p>"They also obviously produce a lot of dung. And that's fantastic for invertebrates and for fungi and things like that," he said.&nbsp;</p>  <p>The bison may also benefit a type of woodland butterfly, the Heath Fritillary, which emerges in&nbsp;late spring and early summer and relies on a plant called the common cow-wheat for food.</p>  <p>Smith explained that the plant requires freshly-cleared woodland areas to grow, which&nbsp;the bison could provide through grazing on vegetation and stripping bark.</p>  <p>"So you've got Europe's largest land mammal having a beneficial impact on this on this tiny, tiny little butterfly," he said.&nbsp;</p>  <p>The Netherlands have had wild bison for about 15 years now, Smith says, and he personally noticed a huge improvement in habitat health when he visited bison projects there.</p>  <p>"You just can't help but notice the birdsong that's there ...&nbsp;the mushrooms that are growing everywhere and the lizards and reptiles that are all around, " he said.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5871767.1610566447!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_300/bison-at-slikken-van-de-heen-nature-reserve.jpeg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5871767.1610566447!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_460/bison-at-slikken-van-de-heen-nature-reserve.jpeg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5871767.1610566447!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_620/bison-at-slikken-van-de-heen-nature-reserve.jpeg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5871767.1610566447!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_780/bison-at-slikken-van-de-heen-nature-reserve.jpeg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5871767.1610566447!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/bison-at-slikken-van-de-heen-nature-reserve.jpeg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5871767.1610566447!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/original_780/bison-at-slikken-van-de-heen-nature-reserve.jpeg"></p></div><figcaption>Bison at Slikken van de Heen Nature Reserve in Zeeland, Netherlands. <!-- --> <!-- -->(Amanda Fegan)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <h2>Dung samples key to herd management</h2>  <p>A key part of the job for the rangers will be&nbsp;to keep the animals wild.</p>  <p>"We want them to be behaving entirely naturally and not&nbsp;[become]&nbsp;used to humans," said Smith.</p>  <p>The bison managers will&nbsp;monitor the animals from a distance, collecting dung samples to assess their health without approaching them. Smith said the managers will have to track and follow the herd to keep up with what they're doing and where they're going.</p>  <p>Smith says they are starting small at first to make sure the bison will have enough food year-round.</p>  <p>"That way we can really test the impact that they're having on the environment and tweak things as we go along if we have to," he said.</p>  <p>He also noted that bison breed slowly, at most one calf per female, per year, so they don't expect the herd size to balloon rapidly — one of many factors he says has helped foster support for the project locally.&nbsp;</p>  <p>"Everyone's actually very, very happy with it. It seems everyone's really excited to see the bison come."&nbsp;</p>  <hr>  <p><em>Written by </em><em>Andrea Bellemare. Interview produced by Chloe Shantz-Hilkes.&nbsp;</em></p></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/radio/asithappens/as-it-happens-wednesday-edition-1.5871385/bison-rangers-wanted-to-oversee-u-k-herd-no-bison-experience-necessary-1.5871386</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25846480</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 13:58:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Update: YouTube-dl reinstated thanks to EFF (2020)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 423 | Comments 48 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25846262">thread link</a>) | @ericdanielski
<br/>
January 20, 2021 | https://assassinate-you.net/posts/2020/11/youtube-dl-update/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://assassinate-you.net/posts/2020/11/youtube-dl-update/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  <div>
    <div>
      <article role="main">
        <p>In October, the popular and famous archivist tool <a href="https://youtube-dl.org/">youtube-dl</a> was taken down by GitHub due to a DMCA request by the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recording_Industry_Association_of_America#Criticism">Recording Industry Association of America</a>. I posted a <a href="https://assassinate-you.net/posts/2020/10/youtube-dl-takedown/">detailed analysis</a> explaining the relation between international, US, EU and German law, and showing why this request was very different from what most people know as the “classic” DMCA takedown request. I felt this was necessary since there were a lot of rumor and wrong claims out on the Internet (not just in forums or on the (anti)social media, but also on media offerings), which did not help the discussion at all. The repository is back now, thanks to the EFF and its team. They <a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/11/github-reinstates-youtube-dl-after-riaas-abuse-dmca">filed a counter-notice</a> on behalf of the youtube-dl maintainers, which allowed GitHub to reinstantiate the repository.</p>
<h2 id="eff-helps-out-by-writing-a-counter-notice">EFF helps out by writing a counter notice</h2>
<p>The <a href="https://eff.org/">Electronic Frontier Foundation</a>, a non-governmental organization based in the U.S. dedicated to defending civil liberties and especially digital rights, helped out the youtube-dl maintainers by filing a very informative <a href="https://www.eff.org/files/2020/11/17/eff_letter_to_github_re_youtube-dl_11152020.pdf">counter notice</a> with GitHub. This notice explained why the request itself is an abuse of the DMCA and the takedown was not justified at all. It allowed GitHub to reinstantiate the repository and, more importantly, all the metadata (for example, issues and pull requests) that was posted on the platform by users, developers and maintainers. Such information is invaluable to a project, and a takedown of the <em>entire</em> repository with all this data can hurt a project very badly.</p>
<p>The takedown was widely regarded as abuse of the DMCA by the RIAA, given that the youtube-dl code repository did not contain any infringing material. The argumentation was made up by claiming that the primary purpose was to infringe copyright of some songs whose artists are apparently represented by the RIAA. They cited some automated unit tests for this, which do not download the entire songs, and would not be seen or executed by regular users. The EFF argues that these are likely a form of “fair use” and thus allowed legally.</p>
<p>The request also cited an obscure German court decision which considered YouTube’s “rolling cipher” an “effective technological measure”, whose bypassing would be prohibited by copyright laws around the world. The EFF explains that the decision was “wrongly decided and is not binding nor even persuasive under U.S. law”.</p>
<p>The EFF further questions the effectivity of the algorithm in general, given that YouTube delivers the code for decryption in a readable form (and also, the code can be executed outside browsers, too). On top of that, the streams are freely accessible once you have the URLs. YouTube only hides the URLs, but not in an effective way. Therefore, this algorithm cannot be considered a “technological measure”, and thus, the RIAA request is baseless.</p>
<p>In the context of this debate, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DeCSS">DeCSS controversy</a> was mentioned a lot, as there’s been some similarities with how copyright holders reacted to the existence of software to bypass their (arguably not very secure) CSS protection. Their first actions focused on software hosting sites, pressurizing them to take down the software by threatening them with legal steps. This led to a mirroring campaign, due to what we call the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Streisand_effect">Streisand effect</a> nowadays.
There’s been some litigation in the early 2000s, where judges ruled in favor of the copyright holders.
However, this has little relevance to the case of youtube-dl, as the EFF explains. Reverse-engineering YouTube’s code doesn’t enable users to save copies of the material, they already can do so in many other ways. Also, youtube-dl doesn’t bypass DRM technologies like Google’s Widevine. Also, there’s many resources under free licenses on the video platform, which users are explicitly allowed to download and share. And in the U.S., the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Library_of_Congress">Library of Congress</a> may even <a href="https://www.eff.org/de/deeplinks/2018/10/new-exemptions-dmca-section-1201-are-welcome-dont-go-far-enough">issue exemptions of Section 1201</a> of the DMCA, under which bypassing anti-circumvention is fine legally.</p>
<p>EFF’s notice summarizes the situation as follows:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In summary, youtube-dl does not violate either the Copyright Act or the DMCA. EFF  and  the  youtube-dl  maintainers  thank  GitHub  for  standing  up  for  the  rights  of developers whose projects it hosts. We hope this explanation will allow you to restore the youtube-dl repository so that GitHub can continue to be the home for development of this popular and important tool.</p>
<p>– <a href="https://www.eff.org/files/2020/11/17/eff_letter_to_github_re_youtube-dl_11152020.pdf">EFF letter to GitHub on youtube-dl takedown</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Thanks, EFF! You did not just helped a tool that is crucial to journalists, activists, lawyers and so many other people. You also destroyed the RIAA’s wrong claims, which will hopefully prevent similar attacks on other tools in the future.</p>
<h2 id="githubs-reactions">GitHub’s reactions</h2>
<p>Regarding GitHub, it is sad that they took down the repository at all. It’s a well-known pattern: platforms rather comply with such requests than risking litigation, requiring projects to invest time and money to fund lawyers themselves (or hope for an association such as the EFF to pick up their case). The moment they published the request and took down the repositories, many experts immediately raised concerns that the request itself is illegal. It remains questionable why GitHub’s legal team didn’t recognize this. They likely were not prepared well enough for such a situation. GitHub did not stand up for the community that made them the most popular hosting platform for software in the world.</p>
<p>Nat Friedman, CEO of GitHub, later apparently reached out to the youtube-dl team personally, expressing his sympathy, and offering some support. However, the damage was already done then. The team lost its primary communication channel to their users and each other, as well as the entire history.</p>
<p>It seems more likely that their PR department recognized they are criticised heavily for taking down the project in the first place, putting their (actually pretty good) relation to the open-source community at risk, and thus creating a serious threat to their business.</p>
<p>At least this case prompted them to rethink their strategy on future lawsuits. They posted a <a href="https://github.blog/2020-11-16-standing-up-for-developers-youtube-dl-is-back/">blog article</a>, excusing their takedown with compliance, as expected. They promised changes for the benefit of projects threatened by similar requests in the future at least, such as donating to a “developer defense fund” dedicated to helping out projects threatened by such anti-circumvention takedown requests.</p>
<p>Furthermore, they recognized that there is a strong need for maintainers to access the issues and pull requests. They promised to ensure that developers can export those after a takedown (even if requests are valid). The real question however is why they wouldn’t just keep showing them, and just hide the code repository. Introducing such an option globally for every repository would be an even bigger improvement, allowing developers to always create backups of those data.</p>
<p>As GitHub state themselves, among all DMCA takedown requests, these circumvention ones are quite rare. We will have to see whether it is going to have a lot of effect. It would be better if they just donated money to defend developers of projects for which they receive <em>any</em> kind of unwarranted takedown request, rather than limiting it to this edge case.</p>
<p>By the way: in the end, it’s up to the people to request better copyright laws from the politics. They tend to get worse, not better. Make sure your voice is heard. Call your representatives (that’s better than sending a mail, as a phone call can hardly be ignored). Go on the streets and protest against changes and for improvements <em>for you as a user</em>. Support campaigns of civil rights organizations trying to change the laws.</p>
<h2 id="lessons-learned">Lessons learned</h2>
<p>Maintainers who host their projects on large proprietary platforms like GitHub or GitLab’s cloud offering should always have a strategy for such situations. They should set up mirrors of the code proactively. Backing up metadata is significantly harder (especially if platforms don’t provide import/export tools, which most of the big ones do not). Some people use the project import features in tools like <a href="https://gitea.io/">Gitea</a>, but as those are one-off features, one would have to repeat the process every now and then. For the issues, there is an experimental tool called <a href="https://github.com/MichaelMure/git-bug">git-bug</a>, which allows offline backups and migrations, and comes with bridges to import and export to a variety of tools (and is <a href="https://github.com/MichaelMure/git-bug#help-needed">looking for contributors</a> to add new bridges and extend the functionality).</p>
<p>It looks like the free software community should prepare themselves better in the future. We should develop better tools to back up our metadata, also allowing us to move between platforms more easily.
If GitHub wants to remain the most popular hosting platform, they should consider adding such functionality out of the box (ideally in a standardized format). Offering such functionality doesn’t mean that projects would just leave for other platforms automatically. It would rather show that GitHub is really committed to the idea of open-source software, whose development can take place everywhere. After all, we are the ones who helped GitHub become the number one platform for software development in the world.</p>
<p>There is one thing that has been and is always going to be counterproductive, especially in such situations: blind actionism. Many people flooded the Internet (read: forums, Reddit, bug trackers of projects), inciting panic and suggesting to move to some other “free” hosted platform. This is clearly not a solution. Any hosting platform will sooner or later have to comply with such a request. It can become very expensive if you end up in court. The true solution, as we have seen in this situation, is to stay calm, analyze the situation, assess the threat to your own project and remove code and text that could be abused to justify such a request (e.g., if you are developing a similar project and also use such songs in a unit test, you can change your test to content under free licenses). Moving to another platform does not solve the root issue, and …</p></article></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://assassinate-you.net/posts/2020/11/youtube-dl-update/">https://assassinate-you.net/posts/2020/11/youtube-dl-update/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://assassinate-you.net/posts/2020/11/youtube-dl-update/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25846262</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 13:39:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: SOUL Language 1.0 – A platform for writing and running audio code]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 116 | Comments 74 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25845002">thread link</a>) | @julesrms
<br/>
January 20, 2021 | https://soul-lang.github.io/SOUL/docs/SOUL_V1_Release.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://soul-lang.github.io/SOUL/docs/SOUL_V1_Release.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      
      
      

      <h3 id="soul-a-new-language-now-in-v10-makes-audio-coding-vastly-more-accessible">SOUL, a new language now in V1.0, makes audio coding vastly more accessible</h3>

<h5 id="january-20-2021">January 20, 2021</h5>

<p>London — Today’s release of SOUL, the new universal language for audio applications, will dramatically lower barriers and expand access for developers creating any apps that depend on audio, as well as providing a more efficient architecture for audio processing.</p>

<p>SOUL has reached version 1.0 status with its language, compiler, and “SOUL patch” format all stable, tested, and ready to use in a wide variety of audio-related projects.. The team, led by JUCE and Tracktion creator Julian Storer, is already at work on an array of other SOUL tools including a visual editor and a developer portal.</p>

<p>“SOUL will revolutionize audio app development, eliminating challenges that have impeded developers for too long,” said Julian Storer, Head of Software Architecture at ROLI. “The need for a radical rethink of how audio apps are made has only become more urgent since I started the SOUL project in 2016. I’m tremendously excited about the V1.0 released today and the additional tools to come.”</p>

<p>Both a programming language and a platform for creating audio plugins and apps, SOUL will solve four fundamental problems facing audio developers today:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Easy to learn and use: C++, the standard language for audio app coding, is extremely difficult to learn. The SOUL language is much simpler and more intuitive. Browser-based tools and fast live testing make it even easier to use and master.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>More secure: Sandboxing untrusted third-party code adds performance overheads that are a particular problem for audio coding. SOUL uses an intermediate assembly language called HEART that is safe to run without sandboxing, making SOUL code far more secure.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Optimized for power and performance: CPU-intensive power consumption is a constant problem for developers. The SOUL language is far more efficient. It is specifically designed for performance, with its JIT engine matching an equivalent program written in native C++.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Achieves lowest latency: Latency in audio apps is another deep-rooted issue that to date is solved by running audio on dedicated audio hardware. SOUL unlocks ultra-low latency on devices without the need for embedded CPUs and DSPs.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Since debuting SOUL at ADC 2018, the team has continuously welcomed feedback through the open-source repository at https://soul.dev. This feedback has helped SOUL reach its V1.0 state today.</p>

<p>The SOUL team encourages developers to explore the language on soul.dev, read the documentation on the SOUL repository on Github, and give more feedback as the SOUL toolset continues to grow this year.</p>

<hr>

<h4 id="further-reading">Further reading:</h4>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://soul-lang.github.io/SOUL/docs/SOUL_Overview.html">Project Overview</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://soul-lang.github.io/SOUL/docs/SOUL_FAQ.html">FAQ</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://soul-lang.github.io/SOUL/docs/SOUL_Language.html">Language Guide</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://soul-lang.github.io/SOUL/docs/soul_library.html">Library Reference</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://soul.dev/examples">Code Examples</a></li>
</ul>


      
      
      
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://soul-lang.github.io/SOUL/docs/SOUL_V1_Release.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25845002</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 11:11:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Errors vs. exceptions in Go and C++ in 2020]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 62 | Comments 68 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25843748">thread link</a>) | @yuribro
<br/>
January 19, 2021 | https://dr-knz.net/go-errors-vs-exceptions-2020.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dr-knz.net/go-errors-vs-exceptions-2020.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            
            

<div id="introduction">
<h2><a href="#id8">Introduction</a></h2>
<p>Back in 2018, we compared empirically the performance overheads of Go
and C++ with regards to the low-level calling convention: to <a href="https://dr-knz.net/measuring-argument-passing-in-go-and-cpp.html">pass
arguments</a>,
to <a href="https://dr-knz.net/measuring-multiple-return-values-in-go-and-cpp.html">return multiple values</a>, and
<a href="https://dr-knz.net/measuring-errors-vs-exceptions-in-go-and-cpp.html">when propagating exceptions</a>.</p>
<p>Those results were obtained with Go 1.10 and Clang 6.0. Since then,
compilers have evolved and we are now running with Go 1.15 and Clang
11.0. Have the findings changed since&nbsp;then?</p>
<p>The question of interest&nbsp;was:</p>
<blockquote>
What is cheaper: handling exceptions via <code>panic</code> / <code>recover</code>, or
passing and testing error results with <code>if err := <span>...;</span> err != nil {
return err }</code>?</blockquote>
<p>In fact, as we will see below, the conclusions are stronger today than
they were two years&nbsp;ago.</p>
</div>
<div id="methodology">
<h2><a href="#id9">Methodology</a></h2>
<p>The reader is first invited to familiarize themselves with the
discussion of Go’s low-level calling convention as compared with C++’s
in the previous chapters of this series: <a href="https://dr-knz.net/go-calling-convention-x86-64.html">as of 2018</a> and <a href="https://dr-knz.net/go-calling-convention-x86-64-2020.html">as of 2020</a>. The 2018
analysis is still largely valid in 2020—the C++ calling convention did
not change, and Go introduced a few optimizations on the
implementation of <code>defer</code>.</p>
<p>There were three analyses&nbsp;previously:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>to measure argument passing and returning multiple values, we will
use exactly the same methodology as the previous two analyses <a href="https://dr-knz.net/measuring-argument-passing-in-go-and-cpp.html">here</a> and
<a href="https://dr-knz.net/measuring-multiple-return-values-in-go-and-cpp.html">here</a>.</p>
<p>These analyses contain their benchmark source code, which is also
provided at <a href="https://github.com/knz/callbench/tree/2018-results">github.com/knz/callbench</a>. The
derivation of plots was entirely automated via <a href="https://jupyter.org/">Jupyter notebooks</a>,
which we can thus&nbsp;re-run.</p>
</li>
<li><p>for the <a href="https://dr-knz.net/measuring-errors-vs-exceptions-in-go-and-cpp.html">third analysis</a>,
which measures and compares the cost of error returns with that of
throwing and catching exceptions, we are going to reuse the same
methodology, but a diffence source code for the benchmark. The new
source code has been uploaded to <a href="https://github.com/knz/callbench/tree/2020-results">github.com/knz/callbench</a> as
well. This difference is motivated&nbsp;below.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>We will also use an upgraded benchmark system, configured as&nbsp;follows:</p>
<ul>
<li><span>CPU</span>: <span>AMD</span> Ryzen 7 3950X 3700.07MHz Family=0x17 Model=0x71&nbsp;Stepping=0</li>
<li><span>OS</span>: FreeBSD 13.0-<span>CURRENT</span>&nbsp;r366805</li>
<li>go version 1.15.5&nbsp;freebsd/amd64</li>
<li>C++ FreeBSD clang version 11.0.0&nbsp;(llvmorg-11.0.0-0-g176249bd673)</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div id="experimental-results">
<h2><a href="#id10">Experimental&nbsp;results</a></h2>
<p>All the generated data files and Jupyter notebooks <a href="https://dr-knz.net/go-errors-vs-exceptions-2020/notebook.zip">can be downloaded
here</a>.</p>
<div id="findings-for-argument-passing-and-returning-multiple-values">
<h3><a href="#id11">Findings for argument passing and returning multiple&nbsp;values</a></h3>
<p>Here the findings are largely unchanged from 2018: for the selected
benchmark code, the code generation by our selected compilers has not
changed&nbsp;significantly.</p>
<p>Only the new hardware <span>CPU</span> influences the measurements: the new <span>CPU</span> has
a higher clock frequency than previously, so for an equivalent
mix of instructions we expect and observe a 10-40% raw performance
improvement. Additionally, the Ryzen 7 3950X architecture has a
somewhat more powerful superscalar execution unit than the 1800X, and
is able to detect inter-instruction dependencies across more memory
accesses. This causes more measurements artifacts when the workload is
extremely small, and erases the performance differences between 1 and
5 function arguments or return&nbsp;values.</p>
<p>The main conclusions thus remain&nbsp;unchanged:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>Go uses memory to pass function arguments and return values. This
makes Go code perform about twice slower than equivalent C++ code on
function calls, where C++ compilers use register-based calling
conventions&nbsp;instead.</p>
<p>The particular <span>CPU</span> we used this year uses a micro-architecture able
to more aggressively optimize memory-heavy code, and so the Go
performance overhead relative to C++ is erased for very small
functions; unfortunately, these optimizations become ineffective with
more realistic, wider function&nbsp;bodies.</p>
</li>
<li><p>In Go, memory is used for return values even when there is just one
or two words worth of data. In these cases, a C++ compiler also
typically uses registers. This choice in the Go compiler is
unfortunate, as it mandates copying the return values through memory
at every call level when functions return each other’s value in a
cascade. This cost thus multiplies the overhead of the memory-based
return by the call depth, in a way that does not occur, or much
less, with a typical C++ code&nbsp;generator.</p>
</li>
<li><p>As previously, we can discuss what is the proportion of function
calls relative to other types of code. Arguably, in
computation-heavy algorithms, functions often get inlined so that calls
disappear. In that case, it is possible for the Go compiler,
assisted by the <span>CPU</span> micro-architecture, to reach similar instruction
throughputs as the equivalent C++&nbsp;code.</p>
<p>However, we can also point out that Go still promotes the use of
dynamic dispatch (via interface methods) as an idiomatic approach to
software design. For example, string composition via
<code>bytes.Buffer</code> interfaces with the <code>fmt</code> packages using
interface calls (<code>io.Writer</code>), and the proportion of
cross-interface calls is relatively high in that case compared to
the computation&nbsp;load.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The reader is invited to review the more detailed summaries from the
previous analyses, where the situation is presented in more&nbsp;detail.</p>
</div>
<div id="measuring-errors-vs-panics-reminder-and-code-tweak">
<h3><a href="#id12">Measuring errors vs panics: reminder and code&nbsp;tweak</a></h3>
<p>This analysis calls for a benchmark which performs a “unit of work” in
a loop, with the size of the loop configurable as&nbsp;“workload”.</p>
<p>We are modeling the extremely common case where any error inside a
unit of work aborts the entire workload: the error may or may not be
generated inside the unit of work, but needs only be detected once for
the entire outer workload&nbsp;loop.</p>
<p>In Go, we originally used the following code as&nbsp;benchmark:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>//go:noinline</span>
<span>func</span> <span>leafErr</span><span>(</span><span>arg</span> <span>int</span><span>)</span> <span>(</span><span>int</span><span>,</span> <span>error</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>if</span> <span>arg</span> <span>==</span> <span>0</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>// Unlikely error case.</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>0</span><span>,</span> <span>errObj</span>
  <span>}</span>
  <span>// Common non-error case.</span>
  <span>return</span> <span>id</span><span>(</span><span>arg</span><span>),</span> <span>nil</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>//go:noinline</span>
<span>func</span> <span>workErr</span><span>(</span><span>work</span> <span>int</span><span>)</span> <span>int</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>var</span> <span>n</span> <span>int</span>
  <span>for</span> <span>i</span> <span>:=</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span> <span>i</span> <span>&lt;</span> <span>work</span><span>;</span> <span>i</span><span>++</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>val</span><span>,</span> <span>err</span> <span>:=</span> <span>leafErr</span><span>(</span><span>work</span><span>)</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>err</span> <span>!=</span> <span>nil</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>return</span> <span>42</span>
    <span>}</span>
    <span>n</span> <span>+=</span> <span>val</span>
  <span>}</span>
  <span>return</span> <span>n</span>
<span>}</span>
</pre></div>
<p>In this code, <code>leafErr</code> represents the “unit of work”, where errors
can originate. The <code>workErr</code> represents the main work computation,
where <code>leafErr</code> is called&nbsp;repeatedly.</p>
<p>(The <code>go:noinline</code> annotation is explained in more detail in the previous&nbsp;analysis.)</p>
<p>In the case where the <code>error</code> return is used, we need to check the
<code>err</code> return on every iteration of the loop. If we used exception
instead, we could factor the exception check out of the&nbsp;loop:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>//go:noinline</span>
<span>func</span> <span>workExc</span><span>(</span><span>work</span> <span>int</span><span>)</span> <span>(</span><span>res</span> <span>int</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>// Exception check factored out of the loop:</span>
  <span>defer</span> <span>func</span><span>()</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>r</span> <span>:=</span> <span>recover</span><span>();</span> <span>r</span> <span>!=</span> <span>nil</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>res</span> <span>=</span> <span>42</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}()</span>
  <span>// Main workload follows:</span>
  <span>var</span> <span>n</span> <span>int</span>
  <span>for</span> <span>i</span> <span>:=</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span> <span>i</span> <span>&lt;</span> <span>work</span><span>;</span> <span>i</span><span>++</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>n</span> <span>+=</span> <span>leafExc</span><span>(</span><span>work</span> <span>+</span> <span>1</span><span>)</span>
  <span>}</span>
  <span>return</span> <span>n</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>//go:noinline</span>
<span>func</span> <span>leafExc</span><span>(</span><span>arg</span> <span>int</span><span>)</span> <span>int</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>if</span> <span>arg</span> <span>==</span> <span>0</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>// Unlikely error case.</span>
    <span>panic</span><span>(</span><span>errObj</span><span>)</span>
  <span>}</span>
  <span>// Common non-error case.</span>
  <span>return</span> <span>id</span><span>(</span><span>arg</span><span>)</span>
<span>}</span>
</pre></div>
<p>(The accompanying C++ code is implemented similarly, using
<code><span>std::tuple</span></code> for error returns and <code>try/catch/throw</code> for&nbsp;exceptions.)</p>
<p>Just looking at the shape of the source code, we can already suspect
the findings that follow: there is less work inside the workload loop
when using exceptions. So as the workload increases, the cost of
setting up the “catch” logic gets&nbsp;amortized.</p>
<p>Indeed, this is exactly what was observed in 2018. (<a href="https://dr-knz.net/measuring-errors-vs-exceptions-in-go-and-cpp.html#summary-and-conclusions">Summary and
conclusions
here.</a>)</p>
<p>However, when running the same experiment in 2020 on our new test
machine, with Go 1.15, the measurements are all over the place, the
results appear chaotic, and the difference we observed last time is
nearly entirely erased. What&nbsp;happened?</p>
<p>It turns out that the new <span>CPU</span> used to run the benchmark really has a
much better micro-architecture. It is able to peek through the call
from the <code>work</code> function to the <code>leaf</code> function, analyze
inter-instruction dependencies across the call, and fully pipeline the
processing of the <code>leaf</code> function across multiple iterations of the
<code>work</code> loop. This effectively invalidates the model we used: in a
realistic application, there is enough complexity in the code inside
the “workload”, when it contains function calls, that the <span>CPU</span> cannot
pipeline loop&nbsp;iterations.</p>
<p>To restore a valid model, we should thus tweak the benchmark program
by adding just enough additional complexity in the “unit of
work”. Here, we achieve that by adding just one extra level of
intermediate&nbsp;call:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>//go:noinline</span>
<span>func</span> <span>leafErr</span><span>(</span><span>arg</span> <span>int</span><span>)</span> <span>(</span><span>int</span><span>,</span> <span>error</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>if</span> <span>arg</span> <span>==</span> <span>0</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>// Unlikely error case.</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>0</span><span>,</span> <span>errObj</span>
  <span>}</span>
  <span>// Common non-error case.</span>
  <span>return</span> <span>id</span><span>(</span><span>arg</span><span>),</span> <span>nil</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>//go:noinline</span>
<span>func</span> <span>intermediateErr</span><span>(</span><span>arg</span> <span>int</span><span>)</span> <span>(</span><span>int</span><span>,</span> <span>error</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>return</span> <span>leafErr</span><span>(</span><span>arg</span><span>)</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>//go:noinline</span>
<span>func</span> <span>workErr</span><span>(</span><span>work</span> <span>int</span><span>)</span> <span>int</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>var</span> <span>n</span> <span>int</span>
  <span>for</span> <span>i</span> <span>:=</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span> <span>i</span> <span>&lt;</span> <span>work</span><span>;</span> <span>i</span><span>++</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>val</span><span>,</span> <span>err</span> <span>:=</span> <span>intermediateErr</span><span>(</span><span>work</span><span>)</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>err</span> <span>!=</span> <span>nil</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>return</span> <span>42</span>
    <span>}</span>
    <span>n</span> <span>+=</span> <span>val</span>
  <span>}</span>
  <span>return</span> <span>n</span>
<span>}</span>
</pre></div>
<p>(Likewise for the benchmark using&nbsp;exceptions.)</p>
<p>This program, at least on the <span>CPU</span> considered, is “complex” enough to
stop the superscalar unit from peeking across the function call. The
resulting code then behaves regularly in&nbsp;measurements.</p>
</div>
<div id="findings-for-error-returns-vs-exceptions">
<h3><a href="#id13">Findings for error returns vs&nbsp;exceptions</a></h3>
<p>The Jupiter notebook for this experiment contains the data processing steps
and the logic to generate comparison plots, with some detailed analysis
of the intermediate&nbsp;results.</p>
<p>The key result is the&nbsp;following:</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://dr-knz.net/go-errors-vs-exceptions-2020/err-comparison.png"></p><p>What we see&nbsp;here:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>For an equivalent workload (e.g. 1000 “units of work”), the Go code
is 40% slower than the equivalent C++ code. This is generally
expected as Go is much more memory-heavy than&nbsp;C++.</p>
</li>
<li><p>Regardless of the language considered, the cost of setting up an
exception “catch” can be reliably amortized across an entire
workload: the performance of code using exception-based error
reporting asymptotically converges to become the same as code using
no error handling&nbsp;whatsoever.</p>
<p>In comparison, code that propagates errors as return values is
systematically slower as the workload increases; between 1-3% for
C++, up to 4-10% for&nbsp;Go.</p>
<p>This is one of the two main&nbsp;results.</p>
</li>
<li><p>The cost of setting up an exception “catch” is not entirely
negligible. Back in 2018, the mandatory fixed cost of the <code>defer</code>
setup and testing <code>recover()</code> in the <code>work</code> function was 50ns;
such that it took about 500 nanoseconds worth of “workload” to fully
offset this one-time&nbsp;cost.</p>
<p>In …</p></li></ul></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://dr-knz.net/go-errors-vs-exceptions-2020.html">https://dr-knz.net/go-errors-vs-exceptions-2020.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dr-knz.net/go-errors-vs-exceptions-2020.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25843748</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 07:57:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Tailscale on NixOS: A New Minecraft Server in Ten Minutes]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 102 | Comments 43 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25843609">thread link</a>) | @tutfbhuf
<br/>
January 19, 2021 | https://tailscale.com/blog/nixos-minecraft/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://tailscale.com/blog/nixos-minecraft/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <p>NixOS is a Linux distribution built from the ground up to make it easy to deploy
services. Tailscale is a peer-to-peer VPN built to make it easy to connect
machines. In this article I will show how to set up a Java Edition
Minecraft server (exposed only over Tailscale) in ten minutes on Digital Ocean.</p>
<p>Before you begin this guide, you’ll need the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>A <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/">Digital Ocean</a> account</li>
<li>A <a href="https://www.minecraft.net/en-us/">Minecraft</a> Java Edition account</li>
</ul>
<p>You’ll also need <a href="https://tailscale.com/start">a Tailscale account</a>. You can
make a free solo account using an <code>@gmail.com</code> address.</p>
<p>In NixOS one of the core principles is that the entire system is configurable
with a modular language called Nix. This allows you to configure everything
using a common syntax so you don’t need to remember every configuration file
format for every service you use. As such, you can configure an entire system
from a single file.</p>
<p>Let’s make a new configuration file called <code>host.nix</code> and set up a system that
has Tailscale start up on boot:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="nix"><span>{</span> <span>config</span><span>,</span> <span>pkgs</span><span>,</span> <span>...</span> <span>}:</span>

<span>{</span>
  <span># make the tailscale command usable to users</span>
  <span>environment</span><span>.</span><span>systemPackages</span> <span>=</span> <span>[</span> <span>pkgs</span><span>.</span><span>tailscale</span> <span>];</span>

  <span># enable the tailscale service</span>
  <span>services</span><span>.</span><span>tailscale</span><span>.</span><span>enable</span> <span>=</span> <span>true</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div><p>This will have Tailscale start up, however to authenticate to Tailscale we need
to take a few more steps. First, head to the <a href="https://login.tailscale.com/admin/authkeys">Pre-Auth Keys page in the admin
panel</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://tailscale.com/files/images/docs/guides/nixos-minecraft/preauth-key.png" alt="The key creation screen from the Tailscale adminUI"></p>
<p>Create a new one-time use key and then copy it to your notes. We will use it
below.</p>
<p>With this key we can write a <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/understanding-systemd-units-and-unit-files#the-service-section">systemd oneshot
unit</a>
that will log in to Tailscale using this key.</p>
<p>A systemd oneshot job is something that systemd expects to be run once as
opposed to being a persistent service. The above Digital Ocean link explains
this in more detail.</p>
<p>Copy this configuration below the <code>services.tailscale.enable</code> line in your
<code>host.nix</code> file:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="nix">  <span># ...</span>

  <span># create a oneshot job to authenticate to Tailscale</span>
  <span>systemd</span><span>.</span><span>services</span><span>.</span><span>tailscale-autoconnect</span> <span>=</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>description</span> <span>=</span> <span>"Automatic connection to Tailscale"</span><span>;</span>

    <span># make sure tailscale is running before trying to connect to tailscale</span>
    <span>after</span> <span>=</span> <span>[</span> <span>"network-pre.target"</span> <span>"tailscale.service"</span> <span>];</span>
    <span>wants</span> <span>=</span> <span>[</span> <span>"network-pre.target"</span> <span>"tailscale.service"</span> <span>];</span>
    <span>wantedBy</span> <span>=</span> <span>[</span> <span>"multi-user.target"</span> <span>];</span>

    <span># set this service as a oneshot job</span>
    <span>serviceConfig</span><span>.</span><span>Type</span> <span>=</span> <span>"oneshot"</span><span>;</span>

    <span># have the job run this shell script</span>
    <span>script</span> <span>=</span> <span>with</span> <span>pkgs</span><span>;</span> <span>''
</span><span>      # wait for tailscaled to settle
</span><span>      sleep 2
</span><span>
</span><span>      # check if we are already authenticated to tailscale
</span><span>      status="$(</span><span>${</span><span>tailscale</span><span>}</span><span>/bin/tailscale status -json | </span><span>${</span><span>jq</span><span>}</span><span>/bin/jq -r .BackendState)"
</span><span>      if [ $status = "Running" ]; then # if so, then do nothing
</span><span>        exit 0
</span><span>      fi
</span><span>
</span><span>      # otherwise authenticate with tailscale
</span><span>      </span><span>${</span><span>tailscale</span><span>}</span><span>/bin/tailscale up -authkey tskey-examplekeyhere
</span><span>    ''</span><span>;</span>
  <span>};</span>
</code></pre></div><p>Make sure to replace <code>tskey-examplekeyhere</code> with the key you got from the Admin
panel. Without this key your VPS cannot connect to Tailscale.</p>
<p>Now that we have Tailscale configured to authenticate and connect to your
network, let’s enable the lightweight NixOS firewall so that we can only allow
Minecraft traffic over Tailscale. The <a href="https://nixos.org/manual/nixos/stable/index.html#sec-firewall">NixOS
manual</a> has more
details, but at a high level we need to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Enable the firewall</li>
<li>Mark tailscale0 as a trusted interface</li>
<li>Allow anyone on the internet to connect to Tailscale’s UDP port (don’t worry,
they will be rejected if they are not a part of your network)</li>
<li>Allow anyone on the internet to connect to your server’s SSH port (this will
also work over Tailscale, but having it exposed over the public internet can
help when debugging issues that happen before tailscale starts)</li>
</ul>
<p>We can do that with the following configuration added to the end of your
<code>host.nix</code> file:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="nix">  <span># ...</span>
  <span>networking</span><span>.</span><span>firewall</span> <span>=</span> <span>{</span>
    <span># enable the firewall</span>
    <span>enable</span> <span>=</span> <span>true</span><span>;</span>

    <span># always allow traffic from your Tailscale network</span>
    <span>trustedInterfaces</span> <span>=</span> <span>[</span> <span>"tailscale0"</span> <span>];</span>

    <span># allow the Tailscale UDP port through the firewall</span>
    <span>allowedUDPPorts</span> <span>=</span> <span>[</span> <span>config</span><span>.</span><span>services</span><span>.</span><span>tailscale</span><span>.</span><span>port</span> <span>];</span>

    <span># allow you to SSH in over the public internet</span>
    <span>allowedTCPPorts</span> <span>=</span> <span>[</span> <span>22</span> <span>];</span>
  <span>};</span>
</code></pre></div><p>Now we can configure the Minecraft server. The <a href="https://search.nixos.org/options?channel=20.09&amp;show=services.minecraft-server.dataDir&amp;from=0&amp;size=30&amp;sort=relevance&amp;query=services.minecraft-server">Minecraft
options</a>
expose a number of settings you can use to configure your server however you
want. Please note that you <em>must</em> set the EULA agreement to <code>true</code> yourself. The
Minecraft server is a closed-source program, so you must give NixOS permission
to use closed source packages.</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="nix">  <span># ...</span>
  <span>services</span><span>.</span><span>minecraft-server</span> <span>=</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>enable</span> <span>=</span> <span>true</span><span>;</span>
    <span>eula</span> <span>=</span> <span>false</span><span>;</span> <span># set to true if you agree to Mojang's EULA: https://account.mojang.com/documents/minecraft_eula</span>
    <span>declarative</span> <span>=</span> <span>true</span><span>;</span>

    <span># see here for more info: https://minecraft.gamepedia.com/Server.properties#server.properties</span>
    <span>serverProperties</span> <span>=</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>server-port</span> <span>=</span> <span>25565</span><span>;</span>
      <span>gamemode</span> <span>=</span> <span>"survival"</span><span>;</span>
      <span>motd</span> <span>=</span> <span>"NixOS Minecraft server on Tailscale!"</span><span>;</span>
      <span>max-players</span> <span>=</span> <span>5</span><span>;</span>
      <span>enable-rcon</span> <span>=</span> <span>true</span><span>;</span>
      <span># This password can be used to administer your minecraft server.</span>
      <span># Exact details as to how will be explained later. If you want</span>
      <span># you can replace this with another password.</span>
      <span>"rcon.password"</span> <span>=</span> <span>"hunter2"</span><span>;</span>
      <span>level-seed</span> <span>=</span> <span>"10292992"</span><span>;</span>
    <span>};</span>
  <span>};</span>

  <span># enable closed source packages such as the minecraft server</span>
  <span>nixpkgs</span><span>.</span><span>config</span><span>.</span><span>allowUnfree</span> <span>=</span> <span>true</span><span>;</span>
</code></pre></div><p>Now we have everything we need. We set up Tailscale, we configured an automatic
login to Tailscale, we set up the firewall so that it rejects all incoming
traffic (except for traffic from you Tailscale network) and finally we
configured the Minecraft server so that your can play in survival mode.</p>
<p>Now let’s get this put into a new Digital Ocean server. Open a new text editor
window and create a file called <code>user-data.yaml</code>. Copy this template into it:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="yaml"><span>#cloud-config</span><span>
</span><span></span><span>write_files</span><span>:</span><span>
</span><span>  </span>- <span>path</span><span>:</span><span> </span>/etc/nixos/host.nix<span>
</span><span>    </span><span>permissions</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"0644"</span><span>
</span><span>    </span><span>content</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>|
</span><span>      { pkgs, config, ... }:</span><span>
</span><span>
</span><span>      </span>{<span>
</span><span>
</span><span>      </span>}<span>
</span><span>
</span><span></span><span>runcmd</span><span>:</span><span>
</span><span>  </span>- curl<span> </span>https<span>:</span>//raw.githubusercontent.com/elitak/nixos-infect/master/nixos-infect<span> </span>|<span> </span>PROVIDER=digitalocean<span> </span>NIXOS_IMPORT=./host.nix<span> </span>NIX_CHANNEL=nixos<span>-20.09</span><span> </span>bash<span> </span><span>2</span>&gt;<span>&amp;1</span><span> </span>|<span> </span>tee<span> </span>/tmp/infect.log<span>
</span></code></pre></div><p>At the time of this article being written, Digital Ocean doesn’t have a NixOS
image by default. So we will use
<a href="https://github.com/elitak/nixos-infect">nixos-infect</a> in order
to automatically replace an Ubuntu installation with a NixOS one. We are also
going to use it to automatically configure the server with the <code>host.nix</code> file
we just made.</p>
<p>Copy the contents of <code>host.nix</code> into the <code>content</code> value of the <code>write_files</code>
block. Be sure to indent the file by four spaces so that it will work as yaml
user data. When you are done you should have a file that looks something like
<a href="https://gist.github.com/Xe/b2f26ae62e7ff6f6030e4a94ed3e2707">this reference file</a>.</p>
<p>Now that you have the cloud config, let’s launch the server in the cloud.</p>
<p>Open the Digital Ocean control panel and click Create and then click Droplets.
Choose an Ubuntu 20.04 image and a plan with at least 4 GB of ram (the Minecraft
server needs a lot of resources, unfortunately).</p>
<p><img src="https://tailscale.com/files/images/docs/guides/nixos-minecraft/droplet-tier.png" alt="The droplet config using Ubuntu 20.04 and a droplet with 4 GB ofram"></p>
<p>Then choose a datacenter near you and enable the IPv6 and User Data options.
Paste the contents of your <code>user-data.yaml</code> file into the text box that shows
up. Choose your SSH key in the list of SSH keys that shows up and then give the
droplet a hostname, such as “minecraft”. If you want you can enable backups.</p>
<p><img src="https://tailscale.com/files/images/docs/guides/nixos-minecraft/user-data.png" alt="The droplet user data pasted into the user datafield"></p>
<p>Once you have everything set up, click the large green button labeled Create
Droplet. It may take up to 10 minutes to install and configure NixOS, however
you will be able to see the machine in your Tailscale network once everything is
done setting up. Go grab a cup of your favorite caffeinated beverage.</p>
<p>After it shows up in your network list, you can fire up your Minecraft
client and connect to your new server. You may need to select a slightly older
version of Minecraft if the in-game UI tells you to use an older version of
Minecraft. You can adjust the Minecraft version you are running using
<a href="https://help.minecraft.net/hc/en-us/articles/360034754852-Changing-game-versions-">the launcher UI</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://tailscale.com/files/images/docs/guides/nixos-minecraft/host-info.png" alt="The host information in the Tailscale controlpanel"></p>
<p><img src="https://tailscale.com/files/images/docs/guides/nixos-minecraft/server-connect.png" alt="The minecraft server connectionUI"></p>
<p><img src="https://tailscale.com/files/images/docs/guides/nixos-minecraft/minecraft-world.png" alt="An in-game screenshot of the author’s Minecraft avatar in a forestbiome"></p>
<p>If you want to administer your minecraft server, you can add the <code>mcrcon</code>
package to your system config next to the <code>tailscale</code> package:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="nix">  <span>environment</span><span>.</span><span>systemPackages</span> <span>=</span> <span>with</span> <span>pkgs</span><span>;</span> <span>[</span> <span>tailscale</span> <span>mcrcon</span> <span>];</span>
</code></pre></div><p>Then you can connect to the Minecraft server command line with this command:</p>
<pre><code data-lang="console">$ mcrcon -p hunter2
</code></pre><p>If you adjusted the rcon password above, you will need to adjust this command to
include that new password. From there you can change gamemodes, adjust the time
of day and anything else you want.</p>
<p>Once <a href="https://tailscale.com/kb/1084/sharing">node sharing</a> is generally
available, you can use it to invite people you trust to your server. (Node
sharing is still in private beta.) Generate an invite link in the admin panel
and they can use that to join your adventure.</p>
<p>If you want to make configuration changes to your server after you provision it,
edit the <code>/etc/nixos/host.nix</code> file in your favorite text editor (such as nano).
The <a href="https://nixos.org/manual/nixos/stable/index.html#ch-configuration">NixOS
manual</a>
should help guide you if you want to install more services (such as backups
using <a href="https://christine.website/blog/borg-backup-2021-01-09">borgbackup</a> or
anything else listed in the <a href="https://search.nixos.org/options">options</a>). The
cloud’s the limit!</p>

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://tailscale.com/blog/nixos-minecraft/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25843609</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 07:38:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Unauthorized Story of Andreessen Horowitz]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 168 | Comments 54 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25841263">thread link</a>) | @DLay
<br/>
January 19, 2021 | https://www.newcomer.co/p/the-unauthorized-story-of-andreessen | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.newcomer.co/p/the-unauthorized-story-of-andreessen">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure><a target="_blank" href="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F808c0f60-f287-48aa-a1d2-8cac89b2d775_2925x2024.jpeg"><img src="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F808c0f60-f287-48aa-a1d2-8cac89b2d775_2925x2024.jpeg" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/808c0f60-f287-48aa-a1d2-8cac89b2d775_2925x2024.jpeg&quot;,&quot;height&quot;:1008,&quot;width&quot;:1456,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:null,&quot;bytes&quot;:1495938,&quot;alt&quot;:null,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;image/jpeg&quot;,&quot;href&quot;:null}" alt=""></a></figure></div><p><strong>Benedict Evans</strong>, Andreessen Horowitz’s former in-house analyst, has <a href="https://twitter.com/benedictevans/status/651587754938118144">mused</a> over the <a href="https://twitter.com/benedictevans/status/869685056196956160?s=20&amp;fbclid=IwAR1AOJf8nkKJbP3nN5CSonf2yjp-eiDf4Plpd8EqOgD9oecQEmmXqSJOUQo">years</a> that “A16Z is a media company that monetizes through VC.”</p><p>That observation becomes truer by the day. </p><p>While there’s a lot of loose talk on Twitter about cutting out the media and “going direct” – publishing your own story to the world without the press as an intermediary – Andreessen Horowitz is really doing it, consciously and methodically. The firm’s strategy has dramatic implications for the future of media and the venture capital industry. </p><p>This is the story of how Andreessen Horowitz disrupted the world of venture capital by cozying up to the media and then, how they purposefully threw that relationship away.</p><p>Let me tell you the story from the beginning.</p><p>About a decade ago, <strong>Margit Wennmachers</strong> sent an email to reporter <strong>Kara Swisher</strong>. </p><p>Swisher took a break from horseback riding to <a href="http://allthingsd.com/20100614/outcasts-wennmachers-joins-andreessen-horowitz-as-partner/">write that Wennmachers was leaving Outcast</a>, the communications agency she co-founded with <strong>Caryn Marooney</strong>. Wennmachers was joining the one-year-old venture capital firm Andreessen Horowitz as a full partner – a rare title for a woman in Silicon Valley, especially in 2010.</p><p>Wennmachers explained her strategy for positioning the firm in the early days, <a href="https://a16z.com/2019/11/20/brand-building-a16z-ideas-people-marketing/">in an interview</a> on Andreessen Horowitz’s in-house podcast. “I wanted to try and get a cover story because – this sounds old fashioned now, because everybody reads their news on Twitter and it's all online whatever – but there's still a statement that comes with a cover story that is in print, that you see at the airport,” she recalled. </p><p>With Wennmachers’ press savvy, <strong>Marc Andreessen</strong>’s idea-a-second patter, and <strong>Ben Horowitz</strong>’s gravitas, the trio took Silicon Valley by storm. The firm outbid competitors for sought-after companies, spun up a slew of services for founders, and pitched its story relentlessly to the press.</p><p>With Wennmachers’ encouragement Andreessen penned a now <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/SB10001424053111903480904576512250915629460">historic Op-Ed</a> in the <em>Wall Street Journal</em> in 2011, titled, “Why Software is Eating the World.” The phrase became so ubiquitous that it can seem like everything eats the world these days. </p><p>“Margit is really a hidden founder of this firm,” a startup founder who has raised money from the firm told me. “The power dynamics there is, Marc, Ben, and Margit.” </p><p>Communications executives and reporters alike are in awe of Wennmachers for her sway with the media. “Comms in the Valley – she's the number 1 draft pick. She's very good,” one public relations person said. “I would never want to be crosswise with her.” </p><p>While Wennmachers’ strategy in that early period would have been familiar to many in Hollywood and Washington, it was less common in clubby and decorous Silicon Valley at the time. “She would say that was her job – to manage information so that she could shape the narrative,” one person who knows Wennmachers said. </p><p>Wennmachers deployed industry gossip and access to her firm’s partners to stay in the good favor of many reporters. </p><p>One communications executive at an Andreessen Horowitz portfolio company recalled Wennmachers fishing for information about an upcoming story on behalf of reporters. Wennmachers pushed to deliver the information to the reporters herself, this executive said. </p><p>A high-powered rival PR executive described Wennmachers as an enforcer: “<em>You don't cross us and if you do, we shut off the information flow.</em>”</p><p>One member of the press recalled Wennmachers chasing down a potential bit of news. When Wennmachers returned the call and threw cold water on the story, the reporter took it in stride. Wennmachers told the reporter that they were now a “friend of the firm.” The comment struck the reporter as odd. They were just trying to get the facts right. But Wennmachers’ attitude seemed to reflect a coziness that she had come to expect from reporters dutifully covering Silicon Valley. </p><p>Wennmachers regularly hosted salon-style dinners at her home near the Presidio in San Francisco with reporters, portfolio companies, and the firm’s partners. While it’s not unusual for a venture capital firm to host reporters for a dinner, Wennmachers did it better than anyone else. When I attended one of her dinners in 2014, it felt like I’d finally gotten invited inside the Silicon Valley. &nbsp;</p><p>“I was invited to dinner at her house with members of the media. It was incredible,” one founder recalled. “That was like a cool invitation. If you were in the press you were really excited about getting dinner at Margit’s house, which is kind of mind-blowing if you think about it.” </p><p>Wennmachers can put on a friendly façade, but if you spend much time with her you come to realize that she’s a profoundly serious person. She doesn’t win over reporters because she’s fun. It’s because she cuts through the bullshit. She fundamentally understands what makes a good story. She knows what motivates reporters better than many reporters. That’s part of what makes the firm’s turn against the media so worrying.</p><p>Back in that early media heyday, Wennmachers doled the firm’s partners out to media companies who were eager to have them speak at lucrative conferences. And the firm’s partners were game to prophesize in audacious terms about what the future might look like, filling column inches.</p><p>Swisher and Wennmachers – two women who climbed their way to dominance in an industry overrun with men – are friendly to this day. Many Silicon Valley insiders strongly suspect that Wennmachers was one of Swisher’s sources when she covered Silicon Valley’s day-to-day dramas. But Swisher describes Wennmachers as fiercely loyal to her own companies, though Wennmachers “also did not pretend a problem I might call about was not one.” </p><p>Marc Andreessen himself had a cozy relationship with reporters like Swisher. "Marc is fully in charge of his own communications and has over time stopped wanting to deal with the press for lots of reasons, including some mistakes he made.” </p><p>From 2009 through 2015, Andreessen Horowitz earned a run of truly phenomenal press coverage, catapulting itself into the very top echelon of venture capital firms – at least based on its reputation. The media loved that bald headed internet geek and his gruff business guru sidekick. And over cocktails or lunch at the Battery, reporters probed Wennmachers for information, even if she rarely earned a mention in their stories. </p><p>Then the magazine writer <strong>Tad Friend </strong>pitched a profile of Marc Andreessen for the <em>New Yorker</em>. Wennmachers already saw the firm’s position in the popular consciousness beginning to shift. The firm was no longer an exciting upstart. “At that point I was at a stage where it was like ‘enough.’ ‘We're done talking about ourselves,’” Wennmachers said in the podcast interview. On the other hand, she reasoned, “The <em>New Yorker</em> is the <em>New Yorker</em>, so how often is the <em>New Yorker</em> going to write the definitive piece on venture capital? Once in a decade? Maybe? Well, do I want that to be about whoever or do I want that to be about us? At that point, I want to occupy that spot?” </p><p>She decided to do the story – though of course <em>she</em> wouldn’t occupy it. She merited a single passing mention. Marc Andreessen’s shiny head was the focus instead.</p><p>The story ran in May 2015, with the title, “<a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2015/05/18/tomorrows-advance-man">Tomorrow’s Advance Man</a>.” The glowing portrait instantly became one of the seminal stories on the venture capital industry.</p><p>Despite running more than 10,000 words, the article made a single passing mention of one of Andreessen Horowitz’s most important investments, Zenefits. The firm had backed up the truck to invest in <strong>Parker Conrad’s</strong> human resources software company and hyped it in the press. But cracks had started to appear. By the end of 2015, Buzzfeed reporter <strong>Will Alden</strong> had planted the seeds of Zenefit’s unraveling, raising questions about whether the company’s health insurance brokers were properly licensed. </p><p>That same year, John Carreyrou revealed that Theranos had “<a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/theranos-has-struggled-with-blood-tests-1444881901">struggled with its blood testing technology</a>.” Theranos had mostly raised money outside of Silicon Valley. But some venture capitalists tied their reputations to defending the company anyway. Marc Andreessen, who tweeted prolifically at the time, appeared to develop an affinity for blocking people who tweeted negatively about Theranos. </p><p>For reporters – and especially their editors – the Theranos story was a sign that tech reporters needed to take a more critical eye towards the startups they covered. Carreyrou was an investigative reporter, not on the Silicon Valley beat at all. Tech reporters shouldn’t have missed Theranos’s shortcomings. So, they redoubled their efforts.</p><p>Then, indeed, Andreessen Horowitz found itself with a troubled portfolio company of its own. In May 2016, I reported<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/features/2016-zenefits/?sref=WS92jZg5"> in Businessweek</a> about Zenefit’s self-disruption. Many other tech reporters also dug into the company’s failings.  </p><p>Behind the scenes, <strong>Kim Milosevich</strong>, then Wennmachers’ top lieutenant, went to task pointing much of the blame for the company’s implosion on its co-founder <strong>Parker Conrad</strong> – who certainly deserved a big portion of the credit for the company’s problems. </p><p>But Andreessen Horowitz partner <strong>Lars Dalgaard</strong> had cheered Conrad on, telling Conrad to double the company’s revenue growth target, I reported back then. Zenefits was the company Andreessen Horowitz wanted to grow, grow, grow. Years earlier, Ben Horowitz himself had <a href="https://a16z.com/2010/03/17/the-case-for-the-fat-startup/">penned an essay</a> making the case for “fat startups,” ones that spend aggressively to block out their competitors. Zenefits seemed to be running that playbook. </p><p>But as the company’s business started to falter and with mounting regulatory risk, Horowitz stepped in to help push Conrad to step aside. The firm laid the blame at Conrad’s feet. And <strong>David Sacks</strong>, who had been the company’s chief operating officer, was sold to the world as a turnaround CEO. </p><p>That same year, the press started to turn its attention to Andreessen Horowitz itself, wondering if this firm really lived up to all the hype we’d been fed over the years. </p><p>My occasional bridge partner, <em>Wall Street Journal</em> reporter <strong>Rolfe Winkler</strong>, wrote in …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.newcomer.co/p/the-unauthorized-story-of-andreessen">https://www.newcomer.co/p/the-unauthorized-story-of-andreessen</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.newcomer.co/p/the-unauthorized-story-of-andreessen</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25841263</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 01:03:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
