<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 1]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 1. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 01:12:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-1.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 01:12:25 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The first beer is free]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26383773">thread link</a>) | @ohduran
<br/>
March 8, 2021 | https://alvaroduran.com/essays/free-first-beer | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://alvaroduran.com/essays/free-first-beer">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article><p>It just feels natural because it is: you get up in the morning on your bed, have your breakfast, wear your clothes. We live surrounded by things we own.
But ownership is nothing more than a form of restricted freedom: everyone else acts as if they believed that it's not OK to just crash your door and pour some of your coffee,
even though they could, if they tried to. Societies are functional because, among other things, we have come to terms with the idea of someone "owning" stuff, and it has been working fine for a long time.</p><p>Until the invention of means to sell intellectual property, that is.</p><p>In 1980, Richard Stallman and some other software engineers at MIT were frustrated by the fact that they just could
not tinker with the software that ran the Xerox 9700 laser printer that they had. They owned it (or at least the MIT had paid for it), and yet, they could not do
as they pleased with it. It's as if you were sold a bottle of wine that could only pour in crystal glasses. For physical objects, the fact
that something is in your posession, under your control, means <strong>complete control</strong>: they might refuse to help you if you break it, but as far as you're concerned,
there's nothing that's stopping you from looking under the hood.</p><p>This experience was what convinced Stallman of people's need to be free to modify the software they use. That is, he believed that society should treat intellectual
property as if it were physical: control is either <em>complete</em>, once purchased, <em>or it isn't control at all</em>.</p><p>Ah, but there's an obvious point to be made: software isn't physical. It's not <em>stuff</em>, in the sense that there are no limits to your ability to copy paste it endlessly<sup>1</sup>. </p><p><sup>1</sup> Thanks <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Larry_Tesler">Larry Tesler</a>.</p>
The economics of redistribution is the first thing that goes out the window, because it used to be prohibitively expensive to buy something, figure out how to make it, and turn around and find people to sell it to.
Non-physical properties do not operate under that paradigm. But, then, in what paradigm do they operate?<hr><p>There's a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uIQmbjUngf0&amp;t=1m20s">remarkable moment in The Mentalist</a> where the star character offers advice on how to seduce a woman.
"Seduction is easy once you know the basic principles". And then, he says: <em>It'll cost you a dollar, so you pay attention</em>. It's the perfect metaphor of how
informational products are sold online: there's the platitude, followed by the sale. The platitude is free; it's a form of marketing and proof of credentials: it's as important
to say something true as it is for it to be just actionable enough and said in a confident way, leaving you curious.</p><p>Again and again, we keep on mistaking the platitude for the product. Google isn't a search engine. It sells ads. Search results are the bait.
The Internet is what transmits the platitude at lightning speed to global audiences. What you do with that is what cannot be replicated. What's free
on the Internet is nothing like 'free beer'; it's more like "the first beer is free".</p><hr><p>In 1995, CD sales peaked. As soon as a cheaper means to transmit music became widespread, forcing people to buy circular plastic to listen to music wasn't a viable business anymore. And that cheaper means was the relentless copy machine we call The Internet.</p><blockquote><p>At its most foundational level, <!-- -->[the Internet]<!-- --> copies every action, every character, every thought we make while we ride upon it.</p><ul><li><strong>Kevin Kelly</strong>, <a href="https://kk.org/thetechnium/better-than-fre/">Better than Free</a></li></ul></blockquote><p>I know it's sort of an obvious thing to say, but humour me: the Internet changed everything. For those of us who create intellectual property for a living (writers of words meant to be read either by humans or machines),
there is simply no way to approach a market just by showing up: everyone is just one click away. Copies of what you sell are not Made-in-China cheap; they are Designed-in-California free.</p><p>And yet, we still think that what we sell is unique in some way. As if that mattered. As if there wasn't a kid that speaks just good enough broken English to do what you do
better, faster, and for peanuts. As if the guys who invented the Xerox 9700 that Stallman wanted to tinker with were still around. As if <a href="https://opensource.google/">Google</a>
or <a href="https://opensource.facebook.com/projects">Facebook</a>, or even <a href="https://www.techrepublic.com/article/why-microsoft-and-google-are-now-leading-the-open-source-revolution/">Microsoft</a><sup>2</sup>, </p><p><sup>2</sup> Of all places!</p>
weren't furiously churning tools to accelerate this everything-is-free trend even more.<p>When thinking of selling music, it always brings me back to a younger version of me, paying for alcohol when I wanted to get into a club.
Music was free to dance to, as long as you paid for a minimum number of drinks.</p><p>Everything is free. Free as in "you don't pay anything upfront". But not as in "free beer". What I want you to consider is that those companies in the business of giving you things for free
so that you click ads are the ones most eager to share open source tools, contribute to projects that are meant to be free, and commoditize products that used to have more straightforward,
single-purchase business models. Everything is free in the Internet because we have been taught that the only appropriate business model online is free consumption under commercial barrage.</p><p>Stallman didn't win; information was never meant to be free on its own. We're just paying for it somewhere else.</p></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://alvaroduran.com/essays/free-first-beer</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26383773</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 09:36:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: API Routing Layer for Financial Service (Remittance)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26383734">thread link</a>) | @jonsantillan
<br/>
March 8, 2021 | https://denarii.com/developers | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://denarii.com/developers">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div _ngcontent-sc61=""><h2 _ngcontent-sc61=""> Hassle-free money transfer in minutes </h2><!----><!----><!----><p _ngcontent-sc61=""> Denarii API offers an easier way for Fintechs, MTOs, and Banks to integrate multiple APIs from global settlement networks. Denarii provides a key-turn solution for all remittance providers. </p><!----><div _ngcontent-sc61=""><div _ngcontent-sc61=""><div _ngcontent-sc61=""><div _ngcontent-sc61=""><form _ngcontent-sc61="" novalidate="" target="_blank" action="https://denariicash-alternate.app.link/SotCDJuvIdb?__branch_flow_type=deepview_tmta&amp;__branch_flow_id=887725203650834274&amp;__branch_desktop_deepview_type=1" method="post" onsubmit="sendSMS(this); return false;"><span _ngcontent-sc61=""></span></form><!----><p><a _ngcontent-sc61="" target="_blank" href="https://denariicash.app.link/">Get the app </a></p></div><div _ngcontent-sc61=""><div _ngcontent-sc61=""><p><a _ngcontent-sc61="" target="_blank" href="https://apps.apple.com/ae/app/denarii-cash/id1352790694"><i _ngcontent-sc61=""></i>App Store</a><a _ngcontent-sc61="" target="_blank" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.fintech.denariicash"><i _ngcontent-sc61=""><svg _ngcontent-sc61="" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" x="0px" y="0px" width="50" height="50" viewBox="0 0 50 50" style="fill: #000000; max-height: 14px; width: auto;"><path _ngcontent-sc61="" d="M 7.125 2 L 28.78125 23.5 L 34.71875 17.5625 L 8.46875 2.40625 C 8.03125 2.152344 7.5625 2.011719 7.125 2 Z M 5.3125 3 C 5.117188 3.347656 5 3.757813 5 4.21875 L 5 46 C 5 46.335938 5.070313 46.636719 5.1875 46.90625 L 27.34375 24.90625 Z M 36.53125 18.59375 L 30.1875 24.90625 L 36.53125 31.1875 L 44.28125 26.75 C 45.382813 26.113281 45.539063 25.304688 45.53125 24.875 C 45.519531 24.164063 45.070313 23.5 44.3125 23.09375 C 43.652344 22.738281 38.75 19.882813 36.53125 18.59375 Z M 28.78125 26.3125 L 6.9375 47.96875 C 7.300781 47.949219 7.695313 47.871094 8.0625 47.65625 C 8.917969 47.160156 26.21875 37.15625 26.21875 37.15625 L 34.75 32.25 Z"></path></svg></i>Google Play</a></p></div></div><!----><p><a _ngcontent-sc61="" target="_blank" href="https://apps.apple.com/ae/app/denarii-cash/id1352790694"><img _ngcontent-sc61="" alt="" src="https://denarii.cash/en/assets/frontend/images/app-store.png"></a><a _ngcontent-sc61="" target="_blank" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.fintech.denariicash"><img _ngcontent-sc61="" alt="" src="https://denarii.cash/en/assets/frontend/images/google-play-store.png"></a></p></div></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://denarii.com/developers</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26383734</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 09:30:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Blogging Changed My Programming Career]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 3 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26383713">thread link</a>) | @pawurb
<br/>
March 8, 2021 | https://pawelurbanek.com/blog-developer-career | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://pawelurbanek.com/blog-developer-career">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
<p><img title="Concurrency and parallelism in Ruby is represented by threads Photo by James Pond on Unsplash" alt="Concurrency and parallelism in Ruby is represented by threads Photo by James Pond on Unsplash" data-src="https://pawelurbanek.com/assets/blog-programmer-career-18155fbc6d64b4ad8c85a62653eb5217f37a0fc200f8bd2eba49f28a7040af8b.jpg" src="https://pawelurbanek.com/assets/blog-programmer-career-thumb-5dfe2957a055e776e69e8fe31b4a0390e79d214b17bb96a7d7bd487cf837a108.jpg">
</p>
<br>


<p>This is my 50th post published on this blog. To celebrate, I’ll go all meta and describe the ins and outs of my <em>“blogger’s career”</em>. Read on if you ever wanted to start writing but never got around to actually hitting the publish button. This post aims to encourage you that blogging can be loads of fun and open up a whole range of opportunities for your career.</p>
<h3 id="your-best-online-portfolio">Your best online portfolio</h3>
<p>I’ve started blogging when I failed to score the <em>“dream”</em> job. I’ve decided to increase my future chances by appearing more professional as an author of a technical blog. My first posts were answers to questions that kept popping up during interviews.</p>
<p>I know that some companies, e.g., software houses, forbid their employees to share details about clients that they’ve worked for. It means that after spending a couple of years in the software house, you could have not much to show to score a better job. A collection of technical blog posts could be your ticket to a more senior/lead/principal position.</p>
<h3 id="the-value-of-being-wrong-on-the-internet">The value of being wrong on the internet</h3>
<p>Working on a blog post allows you to investigate different technical topics deeper than you would otherwise. There’s no better way to learn something than to try to explain it to random strangers from the internet. I often setup throwaway projects, submit open-source PRs, and read up on eBooks when doing the research for my posts.</p>
<p>I send most of my posts for proofreading to friends before publication. They usually catch most of the errors, but it’s not a tragedy even if they don’t.</p>
<p>If you publish a technical post and someone points out your error, you’ve just learned something new. I regularly improve my posts based on comments from social platforms. For me, especially <a href="https://reddit.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reddit</a> and <a href="https://lobste.rs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lobsters</a> are a great source of valuable comments. By publishing online, you can easily trigger internet experts to share their wisdom with you.</p>
<h3 id="build-it-on-your-own-ground">Build it on your own ground</h3>
<p>I think it’s critical to publish your content on the platform that you own. For the first one or two posts, you could use something like Medium. Once you decide you enjoy the process of blogging, then migrating to your custom domain and server is the only reasonable choice.</p>
<p>I’d recommend registering a domain that’s somewhat related to your real name. Fancy brands and pseudonyms come and go, and we’re talking a long game here.</p>
<p>Just please, please don’t stay on Medium! It’s terrible for your personal brand and SEO. Regularly publishing there is a wasted effort. Check out <a href="https://pawelurbanek.com/medium-blogging-platform-seo">this blog post</a> for more info about why.</p>
<p>There are many cases of arbitrary censorship on social media nowadays. If you publish on a platform that you don’t control, you risk losing the results of your hard work for whatever strange reason. It’s significantly less probable to lose your domain, but you still could get banned by Google and lose all organic traffic.</p>
<p>The only resource that no IT giant could take away from you is a mailing list. Unfortunately, I’m not an expert on building one. I’ve only managed to gather a couple of hundred subscribers in over three years.</p>
<h3 id="jump-start-any-new-project">Jump-start any new project</h3>
<p>I quit my full-time job half a year ago. I’ve since been paying my bills from the sponsorship of this blog and profit from <a href="https://abot.app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Abot for Slack</a>. Having those two sources of base <em>“passive”</em> income allowed me to take a step towards working as a consultant instead of a developer. Check out this <a href="https://jonathanstark.com/hbin" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">excellent book by Jonathan Start</a> for more info about the difference between the two.</p>
<p>I’m pretty sure that if it wasn’t for <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16616991" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the <em>viralish</em> blog post</a> my Slack bot would have never taken off. Based on the comments it received, I’ve refined the app’s features and business model to a much more profitable format.</p>
<p>Currently, the primary commercial purpose of this blog is to serve as a content-marketing platform to advertise my <a href="https://pawelurbanek.com/#rails-performance-tuning">Rails performance and security audits</a>. It has been slowly picking up speed, and if this keeps up, I might not have to come back to working 9 to 5 anytime soon. Currently, my Rails audit adverts on this blog receive clicks every single day. I’d have to spend significant $$$ on Google Ads to generate similar paid traffic.</p>
<p>This domain also allows me to keep the SEO gods happy by backlinking to my other projects and passing some of its authority.</p>
<p>What I’m trying to say is that a domain getting steady organic visitors is an invaluable resource. It allows you to pour traffic towards any future project that you might come up with. When you start writing, you won’t know the ultimate purpose of your blog. The possibilities are kind of endless.</p>
<h3 id="summary">Summary</h3>
<p>Gradually growing your own place on the internet could be the single best investment in your future career. Just do it a single step at a time. When I published my first post three years ago, I never thought blogging would become a significant part of my everyday work and income. Or that I’d ever reach 50th blog post and keep going.</p>
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://pawelurbanek.com/blog-developer-career</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26383713</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 09:26:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[React Without Build Tools]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26383549">thread link</a>) | @roosgit
<br/>
March 8, 2021 | https://blog.jim-nielsen.com/2020/react-without-build-tools/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.jim-nielsen.com/2020/react-without-build-tools/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <p>First off: this is mostly a reference for myself. I find myself quite often needing to prototype something really quick, sometimes even build an “MVP” of something I can put out into the world for feedback. Using a framework like React can make doing that incredibly easy—as long as there is no build tooling involved. The moment configurations, build processes, and what not get involved, <em>those</em> become the focus of my attention. It’s like I immediately forget that I was trying to build something useful and instead it becomes a fight of nerd vs. computer—“can I get this working?”—and I find that I’ll move heaven and earth just to see something work only to realize that what I wanted to do was building something usable in a browser, not optimize and streamline my “DX”.</p>
<p>Ok, so, with that context in mind, I have this little boilerplate I’ve pieced together from a couple different sources (big thanks to <a href="https://preactjs.com/guide/v10/getting-started#no-build-tools-route">the preact docs</a>). It allows me to leverage React and write JSX-like syntax without any dependence on a build tool. The code I write is the code that ships to the browser. This is a great place to start with an idea. If it becomes viable longer term, I then consider factoring in a build process, removing my dependence on React, etc.</p>
<p>First, I have my root HTML file (<code>index.html</code>):</p>
<pre><code><span>&lt;!DOCTYPE <span>html</span>&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;<span>html</span>&gt;</span>
  <span>&lt;<span>head</span>&gt;</span>
    <span>&lt;<span>meta</span> <span>charset</span>=<span>"UTF-8"</span> /&gt;</span>
    <span>&lt;<span>title</span>&gt;</span>Title of Your Page<span>&lt;/<span>title</span>&gt;</span>
    <span>&lt;<span>meta</span> <span>name</span>=<span>"viewport"</span> <span>content</span>=<span>"width=device-width, initial-scale=1"</span> /&gt;</span>
  <span>&lt;/<span>head</span>&gt;</span>
  <span>&lt;<span>body</span>&gt;</span>
    <span>&lt;<span>div</span> <span>id</span>=<span>"root"</span>&gt;</span>
      Loading...
      <span>&lt;<span>noscript</span>&gt;</span>JavaScript is required.<span>&lt;/<span>noscript</span>&gt;</span>
    <span>&lt;/<span>div</span>&gt;</span>
    <span>&lt;<span>script</span> <span>type</span>=<span>"module"</span> <span>src</span>=<span>"/index.js"</span>&gt;</span><span>&lt;/<span>script</span>&gt;</span>
  <span>&lt;/<span>body</span>&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;/<span>html</span>&gt;</span>
</code></pre>
<p>Then my <code>index.js</code> file:</p>
<pre><code><span>import</span> { React, ReactDOM, html } <span>from</span> <span>"./deps.js"</span>;

<span>const</span> App = <span>(<span>props</span>) =&gt;</span> {
  <span>return</span> html`<span><span>&lt;<span>div</span>&gt;</span>Hello World! foo: </span><span>${props.foo}</span><span><span>&lt;/<span>div</span>&gt;</span>`</span>;
}

ReactDOM.render(
  html`<span>&lt;</span><span>${App}</span><span> foo=</span><span>${<span>"bar"</span>}</span><span> /&gt;`</span>,
  <span>document</span>.getElementById(<span>"root"</span>)
);
</code></pre>
<p>Lastly, I list all my dependencies in a single file (<code>deps.js</code>):</p>
<pre><code><span>import</span> React <span>from</span> <span>"https://unpkg.com/es-react@latest/dev/react.js"</span>;
<span>import</span> ReactDOM <span>from</span> <span>"https://unpkg.com/es-react@latest/dev/react-dom.js"</span>;
<span>import</span> PropTypes <span>from</span> <span>"https://unpkg.com/es-react@latest/dev/prop-types.js"</span>;
<span>import</span> htm <span>from</span> <span>"https://unpkg.com/htm@latest?module"</span>;

<span>const</span> html = htm.bind(React.createElement);

<span>export</span> {
    React,
    ReactDOM,
    PropTypes,
    html, 
    autosize    
}
</code></pre>
<p>This kind of setup is nice because it sets me up, right off the bat, with a nice modular setup for my JavaScript files. I can very easily create a new file/component at any time, import any dependencies, and export any functions/components. It scales quite effortlessly for prototyping ideas.</p>
<p>You can see <a href="https://codepen.io/jimniels/pen/jOrBJWQ">an example of this setup on my codepen</a>. A few notes:</p>
<ul>
<li>I am using <code>es-react</code> because <a href="https://github.com/facebook/react/issues/11503#issuecomment-407122820">React still doesn’t provide official ESM exports</a>, which means you can’t import the library directly from the official react repo on a CDN.<ul>
<li><code>/dev</code> in the URL is what makes the development version of the build work so you get better logging and warnings during prototyping. If you’re building something for “production” the easiest way to get around this is to commit URLs without the <code>/dev</code> URL, then whenever you’re developing locally just add the <code>/dev</code> back in those URLs in <code>deps.js</code> and never commit those changes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><code>htm</code> is cool because it let's you author JSX-like syntax without requiring a build step (which JSX requires). You can compile it away for production if you really want.</li>
</ul>
<p>And if you really wanted to put it all on one page, you could.</p>
<pre><code><span>&lt;!DOCTYPE <span>html</span>&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;<span>html</span>&gt;</span>
  <span>&lt;<span>head</span>&gt;</span>
    <span>&lt;<span>meta</span> <span>charset</span>=<span>"UTF-8"</span> /&gt;</span>
    <span>&lt;<span>title</span>&gt;</span>Title of Your Page<span>&lt;/<span>title</span>&gt;</span>
    <span>&lt;<span>meta</span> <span>name</span>=<span>"viewport"</span> <span>content</span>=<span>"width=device-width, initial-scale=1"</span> /&gt;</span>
  <span>&lt;/<span>head</span>&gt;</span>
  <span>&lt;<span>body</span>&gt;</span>
    <span>&lt;<span>div</span> <span>id</span>=<span>"root"</span>&gt;</span>
      Loading...
      <span>&lt;<span>noscript</span>&gt;</span>JavaScript is required.<span>&lt;/<span>noscript</span>&gt;</span>
    <span>&lt;/<span>div</span>&gt;</span>
    <span>&lt;<span>script</span> <span>type</span>=<span>"module"</span>&gt;</span><span>
      <span>import</span> React <span>from</span> <span>"https://unpkg.com/es-react@latest/dev/react.js"</span>;
      <span>import</span> ReactDOM <span>from</span> <span>"https://unpkg.com/es-react@latest/dev/react-dom.js"</span>;
      <span>import</span> PropTypes <span>from</span> <span>"https://unpkg.com/es-react@latest/dev/prop-types.js"</span>;
      <span>import</span> htm <span>from</span> <span>"https://unpkg.com/htm@latest?module"</span>;
      <span>const</span> html = htm.bind(React.createElement);

      <span>const</span> App = <span>(<span>props</span>) =&gt;</span> {
        <span>return</span> html`<span><span>&lt;<span>div</span>&gt;</span>Hello World! foo: </span><span>${props.foo}</span><span><span>&lt;/<span>div</span>&gt;</span>`</span>;
      };

      ReactDOM.render(
        html`<span>&lt;</span><span>${App}</span><span> foo=</span><span>${<span>"bar"</span>}</span><span> /&gt;`</span>,
        <span>document</span>.getElementById(<span>"root"</span>)
      );
    </span><span>&lt;/<span>script</span>&gt;</span>
  <span>&lt;/<span>body</span>&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;/<span>html</span>&gt;</span>
</code></pre>
<p>But as I mentioned, I like splitting the JavaScript out into individual modules because it helps me expand and grow the functionality over time. For example, having a <code>deps.js</code> file makes it so I don’t have to write out those long CDN URLs all the time. I import the libraries in one place and export them for use in other files. (Once we get stuff like <a href="https://blog.jim-nielsen.com/2020/es-modules-there-is-no-registry/">import maps</a> you wouldn’t even have to do this.)</p>
<p>Granted, you can author in JSX and ship it directly to the browser. At the time of this writing, that’s what the React docs show you how to do it for basic examples, i.e.:</p>
<pre><code><span>&lt;<span>script</span> <span>src</span>=<span>"https://unpkg.com/react@17/umd/react.development.js"</span>&gt;</span><span>&lt;/<span>script</span>&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;<span>script</span> <span>src</span>=<span>"https://unpkg.com/react-dom@17/umd/react-dom.development.js"</span>&gt;</span><span>&lt;/<span>script</span>&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;<span>script</span> <span>src</span>=<span>"https://unpkg.com/@babel/standalone/babel.min.js"</span>&gt;</span><span>&lt;/<span>script</span>&gt;</span>

<span>&lt;<span>div</span> <span>id</span>=<span>"root"</span>&gt;</span><span>&lt;/<span>div</span>&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;<span>script</span> <span>type</span>=<span>"text/babel"</span>&gt;</span><span>
  ReactDOM.render(
    <span><span>&lt;<span>h1</span>&gt;</span>Hello, world!<span>&lt;/<span>h1</span>&gt;</span></span>,
    <span>document</span>.getElementById(<span>'root'</span>)
  );
</span><span>&lt;/<span>script</span>&gt;</span>
</code></pre>
<p>But this imports babel into the browser and transforms on the fly. Plus it doesn’t give you the ability to start splitting out your components into individual JavaScript modules. So pick your poison.</p>
<p>Anyway, this might be a long-winded way of stating something most folks already know. But for those who don’t, try this setup. I think you’ll find it quite refreshing to use React A) with a JSX-like syntax, and B) without any kind of build tooling.</p>

      </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.jim-nielsen.com/2020/react-without-build-tools/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26383549</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 08:54:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Data Processing Support in Ray]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26382968">thread link</a>) | @robertnishihara
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://www.anyscale.com/blog/data-processing-support-in-ray | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.anyscale.com/blog/data-processing-support-in-ray">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p>This blog post highlights two features in the latest <a href="https://github.com/ray-project/ray/releases/tag/ray-1.2.0">Ray 1.2 release</a>: native support for <a href="https://docs.ray.io/en/master/memory-management.html#object-spilling"><b>spilling to external storage</b></a>, and support for libraries from the Python data processing ecosystem, including integrations for <a href="https://docs.ray.io/en/master/raydp.html"><b>PySpark</b></a><b> </b>and<b> </b><a href="https://docs.ray.io/en/master/dask-on-ray.html"><b>Dask</b></a>. This is the first blog post of a series on data processing support in Ray.</p><p>Over the past couple years, we’ve heard from many Ray users that they wish to incorporate parallel data processing more directly into their Python applications. These use cases range from processing input CSVs faster to shuffling hundreds of terabytes of ML input data (distributed ETL). The common desire is to stitch together an application with data processing and ML components in a single Python program, without needing to worry about setting up, maintaining, and gluing together separate clusters or services.</p><p>Rather than write another DataFrames library for Ray, we're focusing on supporting the integration of other frameworks so that you can</p><ol><li><p><b>Break down compute silos: </b>Invoke data processing APIs like Dask DataFrames directly from application code alongside ML libraries like Tune, XGBoost, and Horovod.</p></li><li><p><b>Leverage distributed memory: </b>Automatic object spilling enables data library developers and users to take advantage of Ray’s shared-memory object store.</p></li></ol><h3>A single substrate for distributed data processing and machine&nbsp;learning</h3><p>The status quo for many teams today is to use <i>workflow orchestrators</i> such as <a href="https://airflow.apache.org/">Airflow</a> or <a href="http://kubeflow.org/">Kubeflow</a> to stitch distributed programs together. This enables use cases such as:</p><ul><li><p>Running training jobs on the results of batch ETL jobs (e.g., distributed training, XGBoost on Ray).</p></li><li><p>Composing pipelines together (e.g., connecting Spark =&gt; PyTorch) from separately written operators (tasks).</p></li></ul><p>However, in many cases the use of workflow orchestrators adds costs, due to the compute silo effect, in terms of <b>system efficiency</b> and <b>operations</b>.</p><p>System efficiency:</p><ol><li><p>The setup overhead of workflow tasks adds latency and reduces the cost efficiency of the job.</p></li><li><p>Intermediate data must be materialized to external storage (e.g., HDFS or S3), also adding latency.</p></li></ol><p>Operationally:</p><ol><li><p>There is high operational overhead maintaining separate distributed systems for data processing.</p></li><li><p>The pipeline itself must be written and configured in a separate configuration language (vs. a single Python program). This also limits expressivity.</p></li></ol><blockquote><p>Our goal for supporting data processing in Ray is to enable distributed applications with less glue code, increasing expressivity and reducing system overheads.</p></blockquote><p>In the remainder of this blog we’ll cover the new object spilling feature in Ray and library integrations.</p><h3>Object Spilling</h3><p>We’re happy to announce that Ray now supports <a href="https://docs.ray.io/en/master/memory-management.html#object-spilling"><i>automatic object spilling</i></a> to local disk and Cloud object stores (e.g., S3). This feature is available starting in <a href="https://github.com/ray-project/ray/releases/tag/ray-1.2.0">Ray 1.2</a> and will be enabled by default in the next release.</p><p>Object spilling enables libraries already using Ray’s object store to work with datasets that may not fit in memory. It also allows Ray programs to operate directly on big datasets. For example, you can now write a simple <a href="https://github.com/ray-project/ray/blob/master/python/ray/experimental/shuffle.py">out-of-core distributed shuffle</a> in just a few dozen lines of Python:</p><div><div><p><img src="https://images.ctfassets.net/xjan103pcp94/7t3kvc0SRuUHdJXovN33yO/39bff881583c8d251e9016f6eaaf75e6/objectSpilling1.png" alt="Object Spilling 1"></p></div><p><span>Simple shuffle example written in Ray with different object store memory limits on a single 32-core machine (AWS i3.8xlarge). The maximum working set size for this shuffle is 2x the input data size, so a memory limit less than that will require spilling. You can try running this yourself on Ray master with `python -m ray.experimental.shuffle - help`.</span></p></div><p>Here’s an example of using Ray’s object spilling to enable out-of-core workloads for Dask-on-Ray. Note that this code does a full sort of the dataset, so we will not compare it directly to the simple shuffle above.</p><div><div><p><img src="https://images.ctfassets.net/xjan103pcp94/XXDVOdoRYTSmBAn2bKldF/41211e942f6ec3d8c5db4b1b8ee66c8d/objectSpilling2.png" alt="objectSpilling2"></p></div><p><span>Dask-on-Ray sort with Ray's object spilling disabled vs. enabled. This is run on a 32-core machine (AWS i3.8xlarge) with a 30GB memory limit for Ray's object store. With object spilling disabled, the application receives an out-of-memory error on 100GB.</span></p></div><p>Note that standalone systems like Spark already have native support for object spilling. However, this is a significant effort for libraries like Modin and Mars. This is where integration with Ray can reduce burden for library developers and enable new workloads for end users. We’ll cover how this works in the next section.</p><p>Note: To reproduce these benchmarks, you will need to run on the <a href="https://docs.ray.io/en/latest/installation.html#daily-releases-nightlies">nightly wheels</a>. You can also do this by installing <a href="https://github.com/ray-project/ray/releases/tag/ray-1.2.0">Ray v1.2</a> (<code>pip install -U ray</code>) and running <code>ray install-nightly</code> from the command line.</p><h3>Library Integrations</h3><p>All of the following examples are runnable with <a href="https://github.com/ray-project/ray/releases/tag/ray-1.2.0">Ray v1.2</a>, unless otherwise noted.</p><h3>PySpark on&nbsp;Ray</h3><p>With PySpark support in <a href="https://github.com/oap-project/raydp">RayDP</a>, you can leverage the power of Spark with just a few lines of code. Once RayDP is initialized, you can use any PySpark API you want:</p><p><b>Installation:</b></p><p><b>Example:</b></p><div><pre><code><span>import</span><span> ray
</span><span></span><span>import</span><span> raydp
</span>
<!-- -->ray.init()
<!-- -->
<span></span><span>@ray.remote</span><span>
</span><span></span><span>class</span><span> </span><span>PySparkDriver</span><span>:</span><span>
</span><span>  </span><span>def</span><span> </span><span>__init__</span><span>(</span><span>self</span><span>):</span><span>
</span>  self.spark = raydp.init_spark(
<span>    app_name=</span><span>'RayDP example'</span><span>,
</span><span>    num_executors=</span><span>2</span><span>,
</span><span>    executor_cores=</span><span>2</span><span>,
</span><span>    executor_memory=</span><span>'4GB'</span><span>)
</span>
<span>  </span><span>def</span><span> </span><span>foo</span><span>(</span><span>self</span><span>):</span><span>
</span><span>    </span><span>return</span><span> self.spark.range(</span><span>1000</span><span>).repartition(</span><span>10</span><span>).count()
</span>
<!-- -->driver = PySparkDriver.remote()
<!-- -->print(ray.get(driver.foo.remote()))
</code></pre></div><p>Under the hood, <code>raydp.init_spark</code> creates num_executors Ray Java <i>actors</i> that each launch a Spark executor. The actors communicate between each other using Spark’s internal IO layer. In the above example, we use the PySparkDriver actor class to wrap the Spark session so that it is callable from other parts of a Ray application. Note that this integration doesn’t use Ray’s object store, unlike the other integrations we’ll cover below.</p><p>If you like to learn more about RayDP, please check out the <a href="https://github.com/oap-project/raydp">documentation</a>.</p><h3>Dask on&nbsp;Ray</h3><p>We recently released a <a href="https://docs.ray.io/en/master/dask-on-ray.html">lightweight plugin</a> for <a href="https://dask.org/">Dask</a> that lets you use Ray as a backend for executing Dask tasks. This includes Ray-specific <a href="https://github.com/ray-project/ray/issues/13959">optimizations</a> for large scale shuffle performance. Here’s how you can try it out:</p><p><b>Installation:</b></p><div><pre><code><span>$ pip install ray </span><span>'dask[dataframe]'</span><span> pandas numpy</span></code></pre></div><p>Note that you do not need to install dask.distributed even if you are using a cluster because Ray will handle the distribution.</p><p><b>Example:</b></p><div><pre><code><span>import</span><span> ray
</span>
<span></span><span>import</span><span> dask
</span>
<span></span><span>import</span><span> dask.dataframe </span><span>as</span><span> dd 
</span><span></span><span>import</span><span> pandas </span><span>as</span><span> pd
</span><span></span><span>import</span><span> numpy </span><span>as</span><span> np
</span><span></span><span>from</span><span> ray.util.dask </span><span>import</span><span> ray_dask_get
</span>
<span>dask.config.set(scheduler=ray_dask_get) </span><span># Sets Ray as the default backend.</span><span>
</span>
<!-- -->ray.init()
<!-- -->
<span>df = pd.DataFrame(np.random.randint(</span><span>0</span><span>, </span><span>100</span><span>, size=(</span><span>2</span><span>**</span><span>10</span><span>, </span><span>2</span><span>**</span><span>8</span><span>)))
</span><span>df = dd.from_pandas(df, npartitions=</span><span>10</span><span>)
</span><span>print(df.head(</span><span>10</span><span>))</span></code></pre></div><p>Under the hood, Dask dispatches tasks to Ray for scheduling and execution. Task inputs and outputs get stored in Ray’s distributed, shared-memory object store. This means that you can seamlessly mix Dask and other Ray library workloads.</p><p>If you like to learn more about Dask on Ray, please check out the <a href="https://docs.ray.io/en/master/dask-on-ray.html">documentation</a>.</p><h3>Modin DataFrames</h3><p><a href="https://modin.readthedocs.io/en/latest/supported_apis/index.html">Modin DataFrames</a> enables transparent scaling of Pandas on Ray. Try it out:</p><p><b>Installation:</b></p><div><pre><code><span>$ pip install </span><span>'modin[ray]'</span><span> pandas numpy</span></code></pre></div><p><b>Example:</b></p><div><pre><code><span>import</span><span> ray
</span><span>ray.init() </span><span># Modin defaults to backing Ray's object store with disk. Start Ray before importing modin to use shared memory instead.</span><span>
</span>
<span></span><span>import</span><span> modin.pandas </span><span>as</span><span> pd
</span><span></span><span>import</span><span> numpy </span><span>as</span><span> np
</span>
<span>frame_data = np.random.randint(</span><span>0</span><span>, </span><span>100</span><span>, size=(</span><span>2</span><span>**</span><span>10</span><span>, </span><span>2</span><span>**</span><span>8</span><span>))
</span>df = pd.DataFrame(frame_data)
<!-- -->
<span>print(df.head(</span><span>10</span><span>))</span></code></pre></div><p>If you like to learn more about Modin, please check out the <a href="https://modin.readthedocs.io/en/latest/index.html">documentation</a>.</p><h3>Mars on&nbsp;Ray</h3><p><a href="https://modin.readthedocs.io/en/latest/supported_apis/index.html"></a><a href="https://docs.pymars.org/en/latest/">Mars</a> is a tensor-based framework that can scale numpy, Pandas, and scikit-learn applications. It recently added <a href="https://docs.ray.io/en/master/mars-on-ray.html">Ray as a backend</a> for distributed execution.</p><p>Here’s how you can try it out:</p><p><b>Installation:</b></p><div><pre><code><span>$ pip install -U pymars ray==</span><span>1.0</span></code></pre></div><p>Note that you do not need to install pymars[distributed] even if you are using a cluster because Ray will handle the distribution.</p><p><b>Example</b></p><div><pre><code><span>from</span><span> mars.session </span><span>import</span><span> new_session
</span><span>ray_session = new_session(backend=</span><span>'ray'</span><span>).as_default() </span><span># Set Ray as the default backend.</span><span>
</span>
<span></span><span>import</span><span> mars.dataframe </span><span>as</span><span> md
</span><span></span><span>import</span><span> mars.tensor </span><span>as</span><span> mt
</span>
<span>t = mt.random.randint(</span><span>100</span><span>, size=(</span><span>2</span><span>**</span><span>10</span><span>, </span><span>2</span><span>**</span><span>8</span><span>))
</span>df = md.DataFrame(t)
<span>print(df.head(</span><span>10</span><span>).execute())</span></code></pre></div><p>The Mars-on-Ray integration is experimental and under active development, but you can learn more from the <a href="https://docs.ray.io/en/master/mars-on-ray.html">documentation</a>.</p><h3>Conclusion</h3><p>This is just the beginning to provide support in Ray for 3rd party data processing libraries and frameworks. We’re actively developing features like object spilling and memory management to improve stability and performance. Keep an eye out for our next blog post on a large-scale distributed shuffle to better support these data processing frameworks.</p><p>In the meantime, if you’re interested in learning more, check out the <a href="https://docs.ray.io/en/master/whitepaper.html">whitepaper</a> or join us on the <a href="http://discuss.ray.io/">Ray Discourse</a>.</p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.anyscale.com/blog/data-processing-support-in-ray</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26382968</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 07:03:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Citizen Planning in Unincorporated Communities]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26382962">thread link</a>) | @DoreenMichele
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | http://www.eclogiselle.com/2021/03/citizen-planning-in-unincorporated.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.eclogiselle.com/2021/03/citizen-planning-in-unincorporated.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<div id="post-body-5008435277301249627"><p>
An unincorporated community may have a lower cost of living and less regulatory burden than an incorporated city. For some people, this can be the ideal setting for starting something they couldn't start elsewhere and turning it into a viable business or otherwise creating a lifestyle for themselves they couldn't have elsewhere.

</p><p>
If you are doing community development work in an unincorporated community, it may be helpful to put together some basic, useful information about living there. One way to do this would be to put together a small website talking about things like:

</p><ul><li>How utilities are accessed by locals -- wells? septic tanks? solar power? is it entirely off-grid or only partially?</li>
  
  <li>Unusual structures that exist due to a lack of zoning that you couldn't build in an incorporated city with zoning and other restrictions.</li>
   
   <li>Profiling local artists, entrepreneurs and other creatives either with their permission or from publicly available sources of information.</li></ul><p>

For example, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/CoastalWA/comments/jwr428/silverdale_washington_census_designated_place_in/">Silverdale, Washington is a Census-Designated Place in Kitsap County</a>. It is the birthplace of Tarn Adams, creator of <i>Dwarf Fortress</i> and he was still living there when he and his brother created <i>Dwarf Fortress</i> and turned it into a means to support themselves.
</p><p>
Silverdale had about 19,000 residents in 2010 and has made several attempts to incorporate but never succeeded. It's got a larger population than some incorporated communities in western Washington state and if Tarn Adams still lives there, it has a notable resident running an unusual business who is somewhat internet famous.
</p><p>
It's in Kitsap County, which is not far from Seattle via ferry. Kitsap has a fairly large population yet is relatively low cost and rural for the greater Seattle area.

</p><p>

Here's a video about an unusual space in San Francisco that exists in part because the physical structures were built before zoning was a factor:
</p><p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XhP6sFcpf4w" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe><br>San Francisco brick boiler room turned industrial tiny house</p><p>

If you are in an unincorporated community, you have a bit of latitude to build physical spaces for people that couldn't be built in a more regulated environment and you have more of an opportunity to build social elements, like local businesses, that also wouldn't work or would have poorer odds of success in a more regulated environment.

</p><p>

If you position it right, there is the opportunity to attract creative people -- artists, entrepreneurs, retirees who have a few bucks and some time on their hands and independence -- and do something cool.


</p><p>
There will be challenges in trying to do development work in an unincorporated community. You may not qualify for certain kinds of federal or state programs and this can be a barrier to getting financial and technical resources needed to develop local infrastructure.

</p><p>
But even without a city government, you will likely have some structure from county, state and federal governments and you can still do development work via local non-profits, co-ops, businesses and volunteer work. Rather than focus overly much on the things you can't do, just focus as much as you can on the things you still can do.
</p><p>
Make sure to genuinely count the things going well in the community explicitly due to the lack of incorporation. Make an effort to quantify unusual business activities and community events that you likely wouldn't see in an incorporated community. 
</p><p>
Sometimes trying too hard to fit a particular mold, such as incorporation for the community, can be the thing that kills the goose that's laying the golden eggs. Other times, people overlook tremendous opportunity because they are too focused on the thing they lack rather than focusing on the things they actually have.
</p><p>
Privately profile your community and try to make some kind of reasonable assessment about the pros and cons as they exist currently. Some of the pros will exist <i>because it is unincorporated</i>, not <i>in spite of</i> the lack of incorporation.
</p><p>

Start where you are and work with what you've got. Don't waste a lot of time on "if only-ing" about the lack of incorporation.
</p><p>
If you are really hung up about the lack of incorporation, consider playing devil's advocate and arguing against your ideas about why that is bad. Read up on the phenomonon of <i>emergence</i> and try to understand the factors that are actually essential to good economic development.
</p><p>

For many things, incorporated status for the community isn't essential. It may not even be pertinent at all in some cases.
</p><p>

If you do a bunch of analysis and conclude that, no, really, we should incorporate as the solution to our local problems, welp, now you have a potential new project to take on and it's a doozy. You can either decide to take it on or double down on focusing on lower hanging fruit.
</p><p>
Either way, try to avoid just whining about "If only we were incorporated..." That's generally not going to be a good use of your time and emotional energy.








</p></div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.eclogiselle.com/2021/03/citizen-planning-in-unincorporated.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26382962</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 07:02:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Programming Paradigms, Turing Completeness and Computational Thinking]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 17 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26382818">thread link</a>) | @mpweiher
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://programming-journal.org/2020/4/4/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://programming-journal.org/2020/4/4/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          
          
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
                
          
            
          <section>
            


            
            
            <p>Greg Michaelson<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup></p>

<p>The Art, Science, and Engineering of Programming, 2020, Vol. 4, Issue 3, Article 4</p>

<p>Submission date: 2019-01-28<br>
Publication date: 2020-02-17<br>
DOI: <a href="https://doi.org/10.22152/programming-journal.org/2020/4/4">https://doi.org/10.22152/programming-journal.org/2020/4/4</a><br>
Full text: <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2002.06178v1">PDF</a></p>

<h3 id="abstract">Abstract</h3>
<p>The notion of programming paradigms, with associated programming languages and methodologies, is a well established tenet of Computer Science pedagogy, enshrined in international curricula. However,this notion sits ill with Kuhn’s classic conceptualisation of a scientific paradigm as a dominant world view, which supersedes its predecessors through superior explanatory power.</p>

<p>Furthermore, it is not at all clear how programming paradigms are to be characterised and differentiated. Indeed, on closer inspection, apparently disparate programming paradigms are very strongly connected. Rather, they should be viewed as different traditions of a unitary Computer Science paradigm of Turing complete computation complemented by Computational Thinking.</p>



          </section>
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://programming-journal.org/2020/4/4/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26382818</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 06:35:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Hybrid Incremental Compilers F. Cross-Module Extensibility+Internal Build System]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 3 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26382816">thread link</a>) | @mpweiher
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://programming-journal.org/2020/4/16/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://programming-journal.org/2020/4/16/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          
          
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
            
              
                
          
            
          <section>
            


            
            
            <p>Jeff Smits<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup>, Gabriël D.P. Konat<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2">2</a></sup>, and Eelco Visser<sup id="fnref:3" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:3">3</a></sup></p>

<p>The Art, Science, and Engineering of Programming, 2020, Vol. 4, Issue 3, Article 16</p>

<p>Submission date: 2019-10-02<br>
Publication date: 2020-02-17<br>
DOI: <a href="https://doi.org/10.22152/programming-journal.org/2020/4/16">https://doi.org/10.22152/programming-journal.org/2020/4/16</a><br>
Full text: <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2002.06183v1">PDF</a></p>

<h3 id="abstract">Abstract</h3>
<p>Context: Compilation time is an important factor in the adaptability of a software project. Fast recompilation enables cheap experimentation with changes to a project, as those changes can be tested quickly. Separate and incremental compilation has been a topic of interest for a long time to facilitate fast recompilation.</p>

<p>Inquiry: Despite the benefits of an incremental compiler, such compilers are usually not the default. This is because incrementalization requires cross-cutting, complicated, and error-prone techniques such as dependency tracking, caching, cache invalidation, and change detection. Especially in compilers for languages with cross-module definitions and integration, correctly and efficiently implementing an incremental compiler can be a challenge. Retrofitting incrementality into a compiler is even harder. We address this problem by developing a compiler design approach that reuses parts of an existing non-incremental compiler to lower the cost of building an incremental compiler. It also gives an intuition into compiling difficult-to-incrementalize language features through staging.</p>

<p>Approach: We use the compiler design approach presented in this paper to develop an incremental com- piler for the Stratego term-rewriting language. This language has a set of features that at first glance look incompatible with incremental compilation. Therefore, we treat Stratego as our critical case to demonstrate the approach on. We show how this approach decomposes the original compiler and has a solution to com- pile Stratego incrementally. The key idea on which we build our incremental compiler is to internally use an incremental build system to wire together the components we extract from the original compiler.</p>

<p>Knowledge: The resulting compiler is already in use as a replacement of the original whole-program compiler. We find that the incremental build system inside the compiler is a crucial component of our approach. This allows a compiler writer to think in multiple steps of compilation, and combine that into a incremental compiler almost effortlessly. Normally, separate compilation à la C is facilitated by an external build system, where the programmer is responsible for managing dependencies between files. We reuse an existing sound and optimal incremental build system, and integrate its dependency tracking into the compiler.</p>

<p>Grounding: The incremental compiler for Stratego is available as an artefact along with this article. We evaluate it on a large Stratego project to test its performance. The benchmark replays edits to the Stratego project from version control. These benchmarks are part of the artefact, packaged as a virtual machine image for easy reproducibility.</p>

<p>Importance: Although we demonstrate our design approach on the Stratego programming language, we also describe it generally throughout this paper. Many currently used programming languages have a compiler that is much slower than necessary. Our design provides an approach to change this, by reusing an existing compiler and making it incremental within a reasonable amount of time.</p>



          </section>
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://programming-journal.org/2020/4/16/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26382816</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 06:35:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Finding Evil Go Packages]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26382593">thread link</a>) | @pabs3
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://michenriksen.com/blog/finding-evil-go-packages/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://michenriksen.com/blog/finding-evil-go-packages/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
            
            <div class="page">
                
                    

                    



<nav>
    <ul>
        
            <li>
                <a href="https://michenriksen.com/">Home</a>
            </li>
        

        
            
                <li>
                    <a href="https://michenriksen.com/blog">Blog</a>
                </li>
            
        

        
            
                <li>
                    <a href="https://michenriksen.com/projects">Projects</a>
                </li>
            
        

        

        
    </ul>
</nav>







<p><span>
    <time datetime="28-02-2021">Sunday, February 28, 2021</time>
     - <span title="Estimated read time">
    

    
        8 mins
    
</span>

</span></p><p><a href="https://michenriksen.com/assets/images/pkgtwist/gopher.png"><img src="https://michenriksen.com/assets/images/pkgtwist/gopher.png" alt=""></a>
</p>

<p>Because of the big <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2020_United_States_federal_government_data_breach">SolarWinds hack</a> and the recent blog post describing a new <a href="https://medium.com/@alex.birsan/dependency-confusion-4a5d60fec610">Dependency Confusion attack</a>, there has been a lot of talk lately about supply chain attacks, the sneaky technique of compromising less secure elements in a supply chain to compromise more secure targets.</p>

<p>A popular target for supply chain attacks has always been the many package management systems for popular programming languages such as NPM for JavaScript, Rubygems for Ruby, and PyPI for Python. These systems have been plagued for years by malicious actors uploading malicious packages and waiting for victims to install them.</p>

<p>I haven’t heard much talk about how the situation looks for the Go ecosystem, and since Go is my new language of choice, I decided to do some investigation.</p>

<p>The novel <a href="https://medium.com/@alex.birsan/dependency-confusion-4a5d60fec610">Dependency Confusion attack</a> vector is luckily not something a Go developer has to worry about since the source is always explicitly specified when importing a package, so when Go fetches the external dependency, it can’t be confused about where to fetch it:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>import</span> <span>"github.com/stretchr/testify"</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>There is however still a possible attack vector via simple <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Typosquatting">typosquatting</a> where the attacker exploits the fact that people often hit the wrong keys when typing on their keyboard. This could both be done on the host domain where the attacker registers a common typo of github.com, but even easier would be to simply register a new user on GitHub, or any other open package host, with a common typo of the package owner’s username.</p>

<p>With this in mind, I set out to build a tool that would help me uncover potential typosquat packages in the wild:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Take a large list of Go package import paths (e.g. <code>github.com/stretchr/testify</code>)</li>
  <li>Permutate the username of every unique package owner to get a list of potential typosquats</li>
  <li>Check if any of the typosquat users exists on the platform</li>
  <li>If a potential typosquat user is found, retrieve all of their repositories</li>
  <li>Log any of the repositories that have a name equal to the original packages being checked</li>
</ol>

<p>This resulted in a new tool I call <code>pkgtwist</code> which is <a href="https://gitlab.com/michenriksen/pkgtwist">available on GitLab</a> (the name is inspired by the awesome <a href="https://github.com/elceef/dnstwist">dnstwist</a> tool)  if you are interested in doing your own evil Go package hunting.</p>

<h2 id="permutations">Permutations</h2>

<p>Probably the most important part of <code>pkgtwist</code> was the generation of good username permutations in order to have the best chance of detecting typosquats. A bit of research led me to <a href="https://github.com/zntrio/typogenerator">zntrio/typogenerater</a> which looked like the perfect package for generating potential username typos. The package implements a pretty long list of permutation strategies that I picked a few from so that pkgtwist only spends time on checking what I feel are the most likely typosquats:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Omission:</strong> removal of a single character (missing a keypress, <code>stretchr</code> =&gt; <code>strechr</code>)</li>
  <li><strong>Repetition:</strong> repetition of characters (pressing a key twice, <code>gobuffalo</code> =&gt; <code>gobuffallo</code>)</li>
  <li><strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bitsquatting">Bitsquatting</a>:</strong> possible bit-flip errors (<code>stretchr</code> =&gt; <code>strftchr</code>)</li>
  <li><strong>Transposition:</strong> swapping of adjacent characters (pressing keys in the wrong order, <code>stretchr</code> =&gt; <code>strethcr</code>)</li>
</ul>

<p>This means that if pkgtwist is given the package <code>github.com/stretchr/testify</code> as input, it will check if any of the of following users exist on GitHub, and if they do, check if they have also have a repository called <code>testify</code>:</p>

<p><code>tretchr</code> <code>sretchr</code> <code>stetchr</code> <code>strtchr</code> <code>strechr</code> <code>strethr</code> <code>stretcr</code> <code>stretch</code> <code>sstretchr</code> <code>sttretchr</code> <code>strretchr</code> <code>streetchr</code> <code>strettchr</code> <code>stretcchr</code> <code>stretchhr</code> <code>stretchrr</code> <code>rtretchr</code> <code>qtretchr</code> <code>ptretchr</code> <code>wtretchr</code> <code>vtretchr</code> <code>utretchr</code> <code>ttretchr</code> <code>suretchr</code> <code>svretchr</code> <code>swretchr</code> <code>spretchr</code> <code>sqretchr</code> <code>srretchr</code> <code>ssretchr</code> <code>stsetchr</code> <code>stpetchr</code> <code>stqetchr</code> <code>stvetchr</code> <code>stwetchr</code> <code>sttetchr</code> <code>stuetchr</code> <code>strdtchr</code> <code>strgtchr</code> <code>strftchr</code> <code>stratchr</code> <code>strctchr</code> <code>strbtchr</code> <code>streuchr</code> <code>strevchr</code> <code>strewchr</code> <code>strepchr</code> <code>streqchr</code> <code>strerchr</code> <code>streschr</code> <code>stretbhr</code> <code>stretahr</code> <code>stretghr</code> <code>stretfhr</code> <code>stretehr</code> <code>stretdhr</code> <code>stretcir</code> <code>stretcjr</code> <code>stretckr</code> <code>stretclr</code> <code>stretcmr</code> <code>stretcnr</code> <code>stretcor</code> <code>stretchs</code> <code>stretchp</code> <code>stretchq</code> <code>stretchv</code> <code>stretchw</code> <code>stretcht</code> <code>stretchu</code> <code>tsretchr</code> <code>srtetchr</code> <code>stertchr</code> <code>strtechr</code> <code>strecthr</code> <code>strethcr</code> <code>stretcrh</code></p>

<h2 id="subjects">Subjects</h2>

<p>Next up was to find a list of packages to check. Initially, I thought about finding some sort of “Top X Go packages” list, but I couldn’t really find a good resource for that, so I ended up running pkgtwist against every github.com and gitlab.com hosted packages from the <a href="https://index.golang.org/index">Go Module Index</a> (731 packages in all).</p>

<h2 id="results">Results</h2>

<div>
  <p><a href="https://michenriksen.com/assets/images/pkgtwist/pkgtwist_1.png"><img src="https://michenriksen.com/assets/images/pkgtwist/pkgtwist_1.png" alt=""></a></p><figcaption>pkgtwist running in verbose mode.</figcaption>
</div>

<p>After several hours of crunching through the 731 packages, pkgtwist finished with a list of 7 potential typosquat packages to investigate further. I honestly expected the list to be bigger, but I was of course happy to see that the Go ecosystem isn’t completely infested (yet) with malicious typosquat packages.</p>

<p>There were however a couple of typosquat packages that jumped out at me…</p>

<h3 id="githubcomsiruspenlogrus-️">github.com/siruspen/logrus ⚠️</h3>

<p>The <a href="https://github.com/sirupsen/logrus/">logrus</a> package by <a href="https://github.com/sirupsen">sirupsen</a> is a very popular logging package (17.3k stars on GitHub) that many Go projects use, which obviously makes it a target for a typosquat supply chain attack. So when I saw that the user <code>siruspen</code> (notice the letter swapping) had a similarly named repository, I quickly checked out what it was doing.</p>

<p>It turns out that the project is a fork of the original <code>logrus</code> repository, so doing a comparison to find the differences was pretty easy. At the time of writing, the only thing that is added to the potential typosquat repository, <a href="https://github.com/sirupsen/logrus/compare/master...siruspen:master#diff-ff87b7c4777a35588053a509583d66c9f404ccbea9e1c71d2a5f224d7ad1323eR13-R16">is a small init function</a> with a single <code>Println</code> call:</p>

<div>
  <p><a href="https://michenriksen.com/assets/images/pkgtwist/siruspen_logrus.png"><img src="https://michenriksen.com/assets/images/pkgtwist/siruspen_logrus.png" alt=""></a></p><figcaption>Comparing siruspen/logrus with the original repository.</figcaption>
</div>

<p>While this is not malicious in any way it could very quickly be changed by the owner in the future, so I will definitely keep an eye on this repository. I would also recommend double-checking your projects if you use <code>logrus</code> to make sure you’re not using this package instead of the real one!</p>

<h3 id="githubcomutfavecli-️">github.com/utfave/cli ⚠️</h3>

<p><a href="https://github.com/urfave/cli">urfave/cli</a> is another popular Go package (15.4k stars on GitHub) for building CLI projects. So when I saw the user <code>utfave</code> also had a repository called <code>cli</code>, my alarm bells went off and I investigated further.</p>

<p>It turns out that the <a href="https://github.com/utfave/cli/commit/4af15496c49f613503d37d43b99df767f831bae1#diff-8d9ca23280f24fe6444d03ae46e7a15dd152170f32f57f978dfbdfd3cfe8ff55L26-R36">second-last commit</a> introduces a highly suspicious <code>init</code> function:</p>

<div>
  <p><a href="https://michenriksen.com/assets/images/pkgtwist/utfave_cli.png"><img src="https://michenriksen.com/assets/images/pkgtwist/utfave_cli.png" alt=""></a></p><figcaption>Ohai there, 122.51.124.140...</figcaption>
</div>

<p>It looks like the author <code>utfave</code> wants to know the hostname, operating system, and architecture of all the machines using their version of <code>urfave/cli</code>. The function extracts the system information and then calls out to the IP address <code>122.51.124.140</code> belonging to the Chinese company Shenzhen Tencent Computer Systems via HTTP with the system information added as URL parameters.</p>

<p>While this code won’t give them any access to systems, it’s highly suspicious that they collect this information and the actor can quickly change this code to call back with a reverse shell if they identify a system to be valuable or interesting.</p>

<p>I reported this repository to GitHub and hope to see it taken down in the near future. Until then, I recommend double-checking your projects if you use the <code>urfave/cli</code> to make sure you’re not using the typosquatted version.</p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>While my little research project didn’t cover every single Go package out there, I feel it covered enough to give a rough picture of what the supply chain attack situation looks like for the Go ecosystem. The two repositories <code>siruspen/logrus</code> and <code>utfave/cli</code>, were the only ones out of the 7 flagged repos that really worried me, but I will keep a close eye on the rest as they could in theory become malicious at any time.</p>

<p>I think Go is in a better situation than other programming languages because the source of packages is always explicitly written every time they are used, but code editor automation could make typosquat attacks more likely to happen as the developer doesn’t write the import paths manually as often. As an example, if the popular <a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=golang.Go">Go extension</a> for <a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/">VS Code</a> is installed, a developer will typically only type a package import on the first usage, and then the editor will automatically add the import in any other files as soon as the package name is used. If the developer mistypes the import path the first time, a malicious package could be introduced and live for a long time in a Go project before it’s discovered.</p>







<section>
    <p><img src="https://michenriksen.com/assets/images/profile.png" alt="Michael Henriksen">
    </p>

    <div>
        <h4>Michael Henriksen</h4>
        <p>Security engineer &amp; builder of tools</p>

        
    </div>
</section>








                </div>
            </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://michenriksen.com/blog/finding-evil-go-packages/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26382593</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 05:38:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Strength grows when you think you can’t go on, but you keep going anyway]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26382512">thread link</a>) | @ecoafriq
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://www.getrevue.co/profile/ecoafriq/issues/ecoafriq-eshop-5-strength-grows-when-you-think-you-can-t-go-on-but-you-keep-going-anyway-331232 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.getrevue.co/profile/ecoafriq/issues/ecoafriq-eshop-5-strength-grows-when-you-think-you-can-t-go-on-but-you-keep-going-anyway-331232">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="issue-holder">
<section>
</section>

<section id="issue">
<section id="issue-display">
<header>
<span></span>
<time datetime="2021-03-07T19:12:02-10:00">Mar  7, 2021</time>

</header>
<div id="issue-frame">


  <title></title>
  <!--[if !mso]><!-- -->
  <meta http-equiv="X-UA-Compatible" content="IE=edge">
  <!--<![endif]-->
<meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html; charset=UTF-8">

<!--[if !mso]><!-->

<!--<![endif]-->
<!--[if mso]>
<style type="text/css">
  .revue-p,
  .revue-h2,
  .revue-ul,
  .revue-ol,
  .revue-blockquote {margin-bottom: 14px !important;}
</style>
<xml>
  <o:OfficeDocumentSettings>
    <o:AllowPNG/>
    <o:PixelsPerInch>96</o:PixelsPerInch>
  </o:OfficeDocumentSettings>
</xml>
<![endif]-->
<!--[if lte mso 11]>
<style type="text/css">
  .outlook-group-fix {
    width:100% !important;
  }
</style>
<![endif]-->



  <div>
    

    

    

    <!--[if mso | IE]>
<table role="presentation" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" width="600" align="center" style="width:600px;">
  <tr>
    <td style="line-height:0px;font-size:0px;mso-line-height-rule:exactly;">
<![endif]--><div><div><!--[if mso | IE]>
<table role="presentation" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0"><tr><td style="vertical-align:top;width:600px;">
<![endif]--><div aria-labelledby="mj-column-per-100"><table role="presentation"><tbody><tr><td><p>
      Ecoafriq eshop - #5 Strength grows when you think you can’t go on, but you keep going anyway.
    </p></td></tr><tr><td></td></tr><tr><td><div><p><strong>Strength grows when you think you can’t go on, but you keep going anyway.</strong></p><p>Our resilience is often tested when life circumstances change unexpectedly and for the worse. We all have issues, demands upon us, illnesses, losses, pain and vulnerabilities. The rise of Coronavirus left us all with many emotions that go beyond sadness, including anger, guilt and frustrations. We are exhausted, fear and isolation are triggering mental health conditions.&nbsp;</p><p>Our world and personal circumstances defines us. Growing the ability to create you’re inner strength requires the ability to examine your ego’s desires, emotions and you’re own blind spots. Conscious choices about what environments we choose to blend with, influence who we are. Practising self acceptance and being kind to yourself when things don’t go as planned it’s a very important part of building inner strengths. We have to acknowledge and embrace our imperfections, cultivate a sense of purpose, try different learning tactics and view challenges as opportunities.</p><p><strong>Change is hard, NOT impossible. Strength is a concept open for interpretation. </strong></p><p>One of the major reasons we struggle with change is because of uncertainty. When we greet uncertainty and the unknown with self care and support, we have a much better chance of maintaining our mental health during major life changes. Inner strength means the possession of self discipline, resilience, perseverance and the ability to control unnecessary and harmful impulses and habits. When you are clear on what matters most to you, your inner strength and power can draw from those values to get through rough times quicker. You must recognise the core values that resonate with you and not hold onto the values that you think you should resonate with.</p><p><strong>Ideas to practise to help build you’re strengths:</strong></p><ol>
<li>
<strong> Self care. </strong>Get a good night sleep, maintain a healthy diet (plenty of water throughout the day, reduce your sugar intake) and exercise. Physical fitness and a balanced diet can help boost you’re mood and you’re body in countless ways.</li>
<li>
<strong>Be open minded. </strong>Allow yourself to learn new skills and show yourself what you are capable of by regularly stepping outside your comfort zone.</li>
<li>
<strong>Learn to say NO.</strong> It’s OK to say no<strong> </strong>without apologising, justifying or explaining your choice.</li>
<li>
<strong>Set new goals. </strong>Stop<strong> </strong>postponing that one task that scares you the most and create a plan of action to accomplish your goals.</li>
<li>
<strong>It’s OK to ask for help. </strong>Part of being strong and independent also means knowing when to reach out for support. It’s okay to be vulnerable and seek help from friends, family and professionals.</li>
</ol>

    </div></td></tr>
      <tr><td><!--[if mso | IE]><table role="presentation" align="center" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" style="font-size:1px;margin:0px auto;border-top:2px solid #E7E9EB;width:30px;" width="30"><tr><td style="height:0;line-height:0;"> </td></tr></table><![endif]--></td></tr>
  </tbody></table></div><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td></tr></table>
<![endif]--></div></div><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td></tr></table>
<![endif]-->

      <!--[if mso | IE]>
<table role="presentation" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" width="600" align="center" style="width:600px;">
  <tr>
    <td style="line-height:0px;font-size:0px;mso-line-height-rule:exactly;">
<![endif]--><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td></tr></table>
<![endif]-->


      <!--[if mso | IE]>
<table role="presentation" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" width="600" align="center" style="width:600px;">
  <tr>
    <td style="line-height:0px;font-size:0px;mso-line-height-rule:exactly;">
<![endif]--><div><div><!--[if mso | IE]>
<table role="presentation" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0"><tr><td style="vertical-align:top;width:600px;">
<![endif]--><div aria-labelledby="mj-column-per-100"><div><div>
      <p>Life is too short to hold on to past hurt. None of us know when our time is up and there is so much beauty in the world that will be missed if you keep living in the past. The world is a noisy place.&nbsp;It’s important to set aside time to completely unplug from everything, connect with nature and just sit with your thoughts.</p><p>City life can be challenging, adds pressure to many aspects of a person’s mental state, but living in a more ‘green area’ can boost your mental health. A garden, a little bit of green space or even houseplants can convey positive spaces, minimise the stresses of everyday life and the long term costs in mental health.</p><p>Being outdoors and enjoying nature is just as important. Nature offers gentle, more relaxing stimuli. Several scientific studies have proven that looking at images of nature or going for a nature walk, can improve and build you’re memory.&nbsp;Spending excessive time indoors and not taking regular excursions into nature can have a negative effect on your health and wellbeing.</p><p>When you’re immersed in nature, you boost the power needed  to build resilience and inner peace. This experience often causes your perspective to shift, as you realise how small your individual life can seem in light of millions of years of evolution, the infinite variety of landscapes and countless numbers of species. It’s impossible not to be awestruck by the beauty, size and power of the natural world. </p><p>You feel humbled by so much vitality and intelligence, yet empowered and discovering yourself in nature.</p>

    </div></div></div><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td></tr></table>
<![endif]--></div></div><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td></tr></table>
<![endif]-->


      <!--[if mso | IE]>
<table role="presentation" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" width="600" align="center" style="width:600px;">
  <tr>
    <td style="line-height:0px;font-size:0px;mso-line-height-rule:exactly;">
<![endif]--><div><div><!--[if mso | IE]>
<table role="presentation" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0"><tr><td style="vertical-align:top;width:600px;">
<![endif]--><div aria-labelledby="mj-column-per-100"><table role="presentation"><tbody><tr><td><p>
    <img alt="Parque Nacional do Quicama, Angola" title="Parque Nacional do Quicama, Angola" height="auto" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/revue/items/images/008/077/755/mail/EC5D0FA7-B7A3-438D-9A21-2EA76C79C293.jpeg?1615158836" width="600">
</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Parque Nacional do Quicama, Angola</p></td></tr></tbody></table></div><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td></tr></table>
<![endif]--></div></div><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td></tr></table>
<![endif]-->


      <!--[if mso | IE]>
<table role="presentation" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" width="600" align="center" style="width:600px;">
  <tr>
    <td style="line-height:0px;font-size:0px;mso-line-height-rule:exactly;">
<![endif]--><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td></tr></table>
<![endif]-->



      <!--[if mso | IE]>
<table role="presentation" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" width="600" align="center" style="width:600px;">
  <tr>
    <td style="line-height:0px;font-size:0px;mso-line-height-rule:exactly;">
<![endif]--><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td></tr></table>
<![endif]-->

        <!--[if mso | IE]>
<table role="presentation" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" width="600" align="center" style="width:600px;">
  <tr>
    <td style="line-height:0px;font-size:0px;mso-line-height-rule:exactly;">
<![endif]--><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td></tr></table>
<![endif]-->


    <!--[if mso | IE]>
<table role="presentation" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" width="600" align="center" style="width:600px;">
  <tr>
    <td style="line-height:0px;font-size:0px;mso-line-height-rule:exactly;">
<![endif]--><div><div><!--[if mso | IE]>
<table role="presentation" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0"><tr><td style="vertical-align:top;width:270px;">
<![endif]--><div aria-labelledby="mj-column-per-50"><!--[if mso | IE]>
<table  role="presentation" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0"><tr><td style="vertical-align:middle;width:162px;">
<![endif]--><div aria-labelledby="mj-column-per-60"><div><p>
        Did you enjoy this issue?
      </p></div></div><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td><td style="vertical-align:middle;width:54px;">
<![endif]--><div aria-labelledby="mj-column-per-20"><div><p><img alt="" title="" height="36" width="41" src="https://d3jbm9h03wxzi9.cloudfront.net/assets/email/thumbs_up-1ae5a7bdfcd3220e2b376aa0c1607bc5edaba758e5dd83b482d03965219a220b.png"></p></div></div><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td><td style="vertical-align:middle;width:54px;">
<![endif]--><div aria-labelledby="mj-column-per-20"><div><p><img alt="" title="" height="36" width="40" src="https://d3jbm9h03wxzi9.cloudfront.net/assets/email/thumbs_down-e13779fa29e2935b47488fb8f82977fedcf689a0cc0cc3c19fa3c6bb14d1493b.png"></p></div></div><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td></tr></table>
<![endif]--></div><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td></tr></table>
<![endif]--></div></div><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td></tr></table>
<![endif]-->

      
<!--[if mso | IE]>
<table role="presentation" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" width="600" align="center" style="width:600px;">
  <tr>
    <td style="line-height:0px;font-size:0px;mso-line-height-rule:exactly;">
<![endif]--><div><div><!--[if mso | IE]>
<table role="presentation" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0">
  <tr>
    <td style="vertical-align:top;width:600px;">
<![endif]--><div><table role="presentation"><tbody><tr><td><p>Become a member for $5 per month</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Don’t miss out on the other issues by Ecoafriq</p></td></tr></tbody></table></div><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td></tr></table>
<![endif]--></div></div><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td></tr></table>
<![endif]-->
<!--[if mso | IE]>
<table role="presentation" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" width="600" align="center" style="width:600px;">
  <tr>
    <td style="line-height:0px;font-size:0px;mso-line-height-rule:exactly;">
<![endif]--><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td></tr></table>
<![endif]-->

    <!--[if mso | IE]>
<table role="presentation" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" width="600" align="center" style="width:600px;">
  <tr>
    <td style="line-height:0px;font-size:0px;mso-line-height-rule:exactly;">
<![endif]--><div><div><div><!--[if mso | IE]>
<table role="presentation" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0"><tr><td style="vertical-align:top;width:600px;">
<![endif]--><div aria-labelledby="mj-column-per-100"><table role="presentation"><tbody><tr><td><p>
    <a target="_blank" href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/ecoafriq?utm_campaign=Issue&amp;utm_content=profileimage&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_source=Ecoafriq+eshop">
      <img alt="Ecoafriq" title="Ecoafriq" height="84px" width="84" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/revue/profiles/images/000/078/848/small/lFK7Sv4W.png?1612228354">
</a>  </p></td></tr><tr><td></td></tr><tr><td><p>Slow Fashion and EcoFashion-Made with Organic and Recycled Materials... “Pour la santé de notre planète!” 🇳🇦🇦🇴🇸🇳🇫🇷🇬🇧</p></td></tr>
          <tr><td></td></tr>

        </tbody></table></div><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td></tr></table>
<![endif]--></div></div></div><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td></tr></table>
<![endif]-->

    <!--[if mso | IE]>
<table role="presentation" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" width="600" align="center" style="width:600px;">
  <tr>
    <td style="line-height:0px;font-size:0px;mso-line-height-rule:exactly;">
<![endif]--><div><div><!--[if mso | IE]>
<table role="presentation" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0"><tr><td style="vertical-align:top;width:600px;">
<![endif]--><div aria-labelledby="mj-column-per-100"><table role="presentation"><tbody>
    <tr><td><p>
      You can manage your subscription <a href="#">here</a>
    </p></td></tr>
    <tr><td><p>
      If you were forwarded this newsletter and you like it, you can subscribe <a target="_blank" href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/ecoafriq?utm_campaign=Issue&amp;utm_content=forwarded&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_source=Ecoafriq+eshop">here</a>.
    </p></td></tr>
    <tr><td></td></tr></tbody></table></div><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td></tr></table>
<![endif]--></div></div><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td></tr></table>
<![endif]-->

<!--[if mso | IE]>
<table role="presentation" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" width="600" align="center" style="width:600px;">
  <tr>
    <td style="line-height:0px;font-size:0px;mso-line-height-rule:exactly;">
<![endif]--><div><div><!--[if mso | IE]>
<table role="presentation" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0"><tr><td style="vertical-align:top;width:600px;">
<![endif]--><div aria-labelledby="mj-column-per-100"><div><p>
      Côte d'Azur, Namibia, London
    </p></div></div><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td></tr></table>
<![endif]--></div></div><!--[if mso | IE]>
</td></tr></table>
<![endif]--></div>

  </div>


</section>

</section>
<section>
</section>

</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.getrevue.co/profile/ecoafriq/issues/ecoafriq-eshop-5-strength-grows-when-you-think-you-can-t-go-on-but-you-keep-going-anyway-331232</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26382512</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 05:21:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Future of Python]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 3 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26382447">thread link</a>) | @worldstreamseo
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://usemynotes.com/future-of-python/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://usemynotes.com/future-of-python/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

<p>Welcome back guys, in this module, we are going to discuss the Future of Python, i.e., how python is booming todayâ€™s industry, and how the same or more industries can be impacted by python. So, letâ€™s dive into the depth of this amazing module.</p>
<h2>Future of Python</h2>
<p>Since Python has become the most used modern programming language in todayâ€™s arena. It has been dominated in all other programming languages like <a href="https://usemynotes.com/c-programming/">C</a>, C++, <a href="https://usemynotes.com/java-programming/">Java</a>, and many more. Since, the day it comes into role i.e., the early nineties, from that very day till now, it has made its growth continuously. So, what is making python more popular, is it going to be in the same trend in the future also.</p>
<p><img src="https://usemynotes.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/future-of-python-1024x529.jpg" alt="Future of Python" width="1024" height="529" srcset="https://usemynotes.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/future-of-python-1024x529.jpg 1024w, https://usemynotes.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/future-of-python-300x155.jpg 300w, https://usemynotes.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/future-of-python-768x397.jpg 768w, https://usemynotes.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/future-of-python-150x78.jpg 150w, https://usemynotes.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/future-of-python-696x360.jpg 696w, https://usemynotes.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/future-of-python-1068x552.jpg 1068w, https://usemynotes.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/future-of-python-813x420.jpg 813w, https://usemynotes.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/future-of-python.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" wp-image-632="" of="" 1024w,="" 300w,="" 768w,="" 150w,="" 696w,="" 1068w,="" 813w,="" 1200w&quot;="" 1024px)="" 1024px&quot;="" title="Future of Python 1" data-old-src="data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%201024%20529'%3E%3C/svg%3E" data-lazy-srcset="https://usemynotes.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/future-of-python-1024x529.jpg 1024w, https://usemynotes.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/future-of-python-300x155.jpg 300w, https://usemynotes.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/future-of-python-768x397.jpg 768w, https://usemynotes.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/future-of-python-150x78.jpg 150w, https://usemynotes.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/future-of-python-696x360.jpg 696w, https://usemynotes.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/future-of-python-1068x552.jpg 1068w, https://usemynotes.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/future-of-python-813x420.jpg 813w, https://usemynotes.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/future-of-python.jpg 1200w" data-lazy-src="https://usemynotes.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/future-of-python-1024x529.jpg"></p>

<p>Letâ€™s focus on some of the key points about the popularity of python.</p>
<h3>Beginners Friendly</h3>
<p>Python is a very easy language; it can easily be chosen as the first language by each and every person who wants to land in the programming world.</p>
<h3>Open Source</h3>
<p>The most important part of python is that it is open-source, i.e., freely available on the internet and anyone from anywhere in the world can use that code and make changes or modify that accordingly as per the requirement.</p>
<h3>Versatility</h3>
<p>Python is a very versatile language, i.e., in almost everything we can work with python, developers, and making or developing many packages for everything, like it is mostly used in data science, web development, and many more. Some of the frequently used libraries are NumPy for working with numerical i.e., numbers, pandas for working with data sets, scikit-learn for working with various machine learning algorithms.</p>
<h3>Cross-Platform language</h3>
<p>The best part of python is that it can be easily used with any type of operating system whether it be Windows, Linux or Mac, etc. This means that you donâ€™t have to use different code for working with the different operating system, the code written in windows can be used in the Linux platforms also. In simple words, python doesnâ€™t need the support of our system.</p>
<h3>Speed and Productivity</h3>
<p>The ability of python, the way it controls the process, the integration of various processes, its various framework, these all things or we can say all these capabilities of python lead to increase its speed and productivity. Multi-protocol network applications, most applications can be built by using python.</p>
<h3>Pseudocode</h3>

<p>It is a very simple language, which comes with very advanced features that can easily overcome all the common programming tasks.</p>
<h3>Strong and rich community</h3>
<p>There are many programmers who are working in python only and coming up with various solutions for a variety of problems and this creates a strong community of smart developers.</p>
<h2>What are the benefits of Python?</h2>
<p>Since, we know why <a href="https://usemynotes.com/python/">python</a> is popular, so in the same way because of its popularity and features it is giving an advantage to a lot of companies using python, Letâ€™s see some of the benefits of using python.</p>
<h3>Dynamic Website Building</h3>
<p>Python can be used for creating websites as per your requirement very easily.</p>
<h3>Mobile App Development</h3>
<p>Many Apps are being created with the help of python only nowadays and are deployed in the play store.</p>
<h3>GUI-based Application</h3>
<p>Many responsive GUI applications are created with the help of python by using the <strong>Tkinter library.</strong></p>
<h3>Data Science</h3>
<p>The most important field in which python is booming the developers and creating a lot of competition in the market. Python is widely used for data analysis, data visualization, data exploration. As we know, there is a huge amount of data is generated every single day by almost all the companies, and so to handle that data, python is used.</p>
<h3>Machine Learning</h3>
<p>Python is used to build a Machine Learning model, which is used for making predictions. Healthcare, e-commerce, tech companies, almost all sectors are using the machine learning technique.</p>
<p>So, these are some of the benefits of python that why python is widely used, this is what python is in the current scenario, and also because of its amazing features and characteristics, it will continue to boom in the future also.</p>
<p>There are many programming languages, and python is on top of all that, it is usually the favorite language of all the programmers among all other available languages. Python is developing at a huge rate and is able to develop many of the applications which have been used in real-time, and the most important thing is <strong>Machine learning</strong> and <strong>Data Science</strong> and taking up the IT sector and working with these, python is used. So, we can easily assume that Python is even coming in the future decade, The only thing it can do, it can expand, i.e., maybe get involved with AI development.</p>
<p>I hope this module was very exciting, and you all must think to start learning or building your career in python. So, you are all in the right place, stay connected with us, for such more modules. Until then, Stay healthy, keep learning!</p>


</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://usemynotes.com/future-of-python/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26382447</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 05:07:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Is BTC a store of value or not?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26381929">thread link</a>) | @terminate
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://wasteofserver.com/is-bitcoin-a-store-of-value/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://wasteofserver.com/is-bitcoin-a-store-of-value/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">
<div>
<article>

<section>
<div>
<p>Michael Saylor, from <em>MicroStrategy Incorporated,</em> kicked of the conversation late November:</p><blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Bitcoin?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Bitcoin</a> is the world’s best treasury reserve asset &amp; the emerging dominant monetary network. It is the solution to the store of value problem faced by every individual, corporation, &amp; government on earth. As this news gets out, the world is going to change for the better. <a href="https://t.co/ADPBvhpHTk">https://t.co/ADPBvhpHTk</a></p>— Michael Saylor (@michael_saylor) <a href="https://twitter.com/michael_saylor/status/1333468351662796801?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 30, 2020</a></blockquote> <p>One month later the discussion picked up again with the following exchange between Musk and Saylor:</p><figure><img src="https://wasteofserver.com/content/images/2021/03/saylor_musk_conversation.png" alt=""></figure><p>As it's public knowledge from <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1318605/000156459021004599/tsla-10k_20201231.htm">TESLA's February filling</a>, the EV manufacturer pumped another 1.5 billion USD into Bitcoin. Assuming the above interactions are truthful, Tesla started buying only after Dec 20.</p><p>We also know that a lot of companies, like Square, followed. And that Grayscale and similar ETF-like companies have massive amounts of BTC in storage.</p><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>company</th>
<th>Market Cap in % of BTC</th>
<th>USD cost</th>
<th>todays value</th>
<th>num BTC</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>MicroStrategies</td>
<td>78 %</td>
<td>2.2 B</td>
<td>4.6 B</td>
<td>91064</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Tesla</td>
<td>0.3%</td>
<td>1.5 B</td>
<td>2.5 B</td>
<td>48000</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Grayscale</td>
<td>108%</td>
<td>32.8 B</td>
<td>32.8 B</td>
<td>649130</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><a href="https://bitcointreasuries.org/">Above data was taken from BitcoinTreasuries.org</a></p>
<p>Before dwelling on what store of value effectively means, lets take a look into BTC price during this last year, place the above orders and momentum into the book, and try to see if there may be any correlation. </p><figure><img src="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vSN_oBCremCq8KVyfVzXoKbqsG9366tUhmUe4tfXY0d5mQcuEG5guaHRacfviNPgzXdBtOjcqX2sax2/pubchart?oid=2093974450&amp;format=image" alt=""></figure><p>This chart should probably ring a few bells. From Saylors investment in Nov/Dec, to Musk in Dec/Jan, price doubled! And then you get that extra 33% increase following the release of the news.</p><p>Why is it a bit offsetting? Because nothing, other than pure speculation, increases in value like this. If you look at <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=NASDAQ%3A+MSTR">NASDAQ:MSTR</a> you'll see that the stock price went from 390$ on the 1st Jan to 1200$ on the 9th of Feb. It's a 1:1 in correlation with BTC's value. <strong>What's the intrinsic value of MicroStrategy then? </strong>Are we valuing the company for what it produces or for having bitcoins in its wallet?</p><h2 id="what-is-then-a-store-of-value">What is then a Store of Value?</h2><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Store_of_value">Wikipedia defines</a> it as "<em>something that can be saved, retrieved and exchanged at a later time".</em></p><p><a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/s/storeofvalue.asp">Investopedia</a> as something that <em>"maintains its value, rather than depreciating".</em></p><p><a href="https://goldsilver.com/blog/the-ultimate-store-of-value-money-is-gold-and-nothing-else/">GoldSilver, argues for gold</a>, which isn't surprising, but they are probably on point with what is the de facto for store of value.</p><h5 id="astoreofvaluemaintainsvalueovertime">A store of value maintains value over time.</h5>
<p>Given the right circumstance, any physical asset may be considered a store of value; not just gold. Which holds especially true for printed fiat money that has no innate value except for being legal tender. But <strong>legal tender goes a long way</strong>.</p><p>When countries started decoupling money from gold, Nixon did it in 1971, notes became just a piece of paper. The wording <em>fiat, </em>latin for "<em>let it be done</em>", is used precisely to describe the decree that governs such assets. While the inherent value of a 100 dollar bill is close to nothing, it is currently legal tender in the US and, as such, courts of law recognize it as satisfactory payment for debt.</p><h2 id="where-does-bitcoin-stand">Where does Bitcoin stand?</h2><p><strong># Legal Tender</strong><br>Some companies say that they are going to accept BTC. But that is entirely discretionary. They can accept it, but they don't have to. That makes BTC, as a standalone currency, very weak. If you want to use it as a form of payment, you will probably have to convert it first. If you are a company like Tesla or MicroStrategy and to support your business you must go into your cash positions (debt collateral, investment, etc) you'll have to sell it. The same hype that hypervaluated bitcoin may work in exactly the same way but precisely in opposite directions if Tesla starts dropping it</p><p><strong># 100% Virtual</strong><br><a href="https://wasteofserver.com/how-does-bitcoin-work/">We recently drilled down on what exactly is the blockchain</a>. If you read it, you may recall it's a database. An amazing piece of software, but a database nonetheless. Bitcoins exist only on that DB. The term wallet is a nice parallelism with the physical world, but bitcoins don't leave the blockchain. Ever. You merely transfer them between addresses inside that DB. The database can be copied and forked. It has happened multiple times in the past and will happen again in the future. On that scenario, it does really carry the value people want to give it. It has no inherent physical value. If you don't agree with the governance of the BTC database, you can just fork it:</p><ul><li><strong>BCH</strong><br>Bitcoin Cash, is a hard-fork of BTC. In 2017 a lot of people felt that BTC was not going in the right direction and that by implementing BIP91 (Bitcoin Improvement Proposal) BTC would become less of a coin and more of a digital investment. They took matters into their own hands and forked. Forking means that everyone that had BTC now had BTC and BCH. BHC has a 2B $ daily volume and is the 8th most traded cryptocurrency by volume.</li><li><strong>BTG</strong><br>Bitcoin Gold is another hard-fork of BTC. Again people were distrust with BTC, this time because they thought the algorithm used for proof of work (sha256) was too ASIC prone and, therefore, BTC mining would become centralized by hardware manufacturers (it has). So a new algorithm was created (Zhash) which was more ASIC resistant and BTG was born.</li></ul><p>Bitcoin Classic, Bitcoin Cash ABC, Bitcoin Diamond, Bitcoin <a href="https://forkdrop.io/how-many-bitcoin-forks-are-there">has been forked more than 100 times and will continue to be so</a>.</p><p><strong># Volatility</strong><br>If we agree that Gold is the definition of a Store of Value, we may have to take volatility out of the equation as Gold has had its share of price swings. We have seen it swing +120% in 1979 and have seen it drop -32% in 1981. We can still argue that those numbers fall short when compared to BTC (and they do), BTC has had a 95% increase in 2021 (so far), and a 629% increase in 2020. Both fall short of the BTC mania of 2017 when it saw a 2530% increase!</p><p><strong># Scarcity</strong><br>If you remember the big whales table above, Grayscale has ~650k Bitcoins. Bitcoin has a total max supply of 21 million units which means that Grayscale currently owns more than 3.1% of the total theoretical maximum supply of the asset. For something that has one of its strengths in decentralization, Grayscale sure has a say in the matter. It's a pretty straightforward comparison to gold where the FED has 8k tonnes of the total 187k tonnes mined (4.3%). The only difference being that we're comparing the whole of the US population (FED), vs a privatly held company.</p><h5 id="is-btc-a-store-of-value-or-not">Is BTC a Store of Value or not?</h5><p>I would have to make the case that it probably isn't, not yet, at least. The asset is just too new to be classified as such. When saying something is a Store of Value you must be making the informed bet that said asset will retain value over time. If you carried a gold block from the Roman Empire to today, you would still be able to use it. It's very likely that you'll be able to use gold 50 years from now. That cannot as easily be said about Bitcoin.</p><p><strong>Things change fast:</strong><br>- Altavista was the search engine, until it wasn't.<br>- Kodak was the de-facto, and disappeared in a couple of years.<br>- Nokia is but a fragment of its former self.<br></p><p>I have no idea how Bitcoin will behave and evolve over time. Rarely has the first project in an area became the standard - CocaCola being the notable exception - so there's also that. </p><p>Nonetheless, I've mined BTC in the past (when such was doable by an individual) and I'm very interested in the area. Technologically, what's happening, is fascinating! But, in all honesty, I see Bitcoin more of a speculative instrument than a store of value.</p>
</div>
</section>

</article>
</div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://wasteofserver.com/is-bitcoin-a-store-of-value/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26381929</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 03:00:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Set up self-hosted CI/CD Git pipelines with Platypush]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26381521">thread link</a>) | @blacklight
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://blog.platypush.tech/article/Set-up-self-hosted-CI-CD-git-pipelines-with-Platypush | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.platypush.tech/article/Set-up-self-hosted-CI-CD-git-pipelines-with-Platypush">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
                <h3>How to use Platypush to set up self-hosted build and test pipelines for your Gitlab and Github projects.</h3>
            </p><div>
            <p>Git automation, either in the form of <a href="https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/ci/pipelines/">Gitlab pipelines</a> or
<a href="https://github.com/features/actions">Github actions</a>, is amazing. It enables you to automate a lot
of software maintenance tasks (testing, monitoring, mirroring repositories, generating documentation, building and
distributing packages etc.) that until a couple of years ago used to take a lot of development time. These forms of
automation have democratized CI/CD, bringing to the open-source world benefits that until recently either belonged
mostly to the enterprise world (such as TeamCity) or had a steep curve in terms of configuration (such as Jenkins).</p>
<p>I have been using Github actions myself for a long time on the Platypush codebase, with a Travis-CI integration to
run integration tests online and a ReadTheDocs integration to automatically generate online documentation.</p>
<h2>You and whose code?</h2>
<p>However, a few things have changed lately, and I don't feel like I should rely much on the tools mentioned above for my
CI/CD pipelines.</p>
<p>Github has
<a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/software/github-threatens-to-ban-users-who-bypass-youtube-dl-takedown/">too often taken the wrong side</a>
in DMCA disputes since it's been acquired by Microsoft. The
<a href="https://devrant.com/rants/3366288/seems-like-even-githubs-ceo-has-now-chimed-in-on-the-youtube-dl-takedown-https-t">CEO of Github has in the meantime tried to redeem himself</a>,
but the damage in the eyes of many developers, myself included, was done, all in spite of the friendly olive branch
to the community handed over IRC. Most of all, that doesn't change the fact that Github has
<a href="https://github.com/github/dmca/tree/master/2020">taken down more than 2000 other repos</a> in 2020 alone,
often without any appeal or legal support - the CEO bowed down in the case of <code>youtube-dl</code> only because of the massive
publicity that the takedown attracted. Moreover, Github has yet to overcome its biggest contradiction:
it advertises itself like the home for open-source software, but its own source code is not open-source, so you can't
spin up your own instance on your own server. There's also increasing evidence in support of my initial suspicion that
the Github acquisition was nothing but another
old-school <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Embrace,_extend,_and_extinguish">Microsoft triple-E operation</a>. When you want
to clone a Github repo you won't be prompted anymore with the HTTPS/SSH link by default, you'll be prompted with the
Github CLI command, which extends the standard <code>git</code> command, but it introduces a couple of naming inconsistencies here
and there. They could have contributed to improve the <code>git</code> tool for everyone's benefit instead of providing their new
tool as the new default, but they have opted not to do so. I'm old enough to have seen quite a few of these examples in
the past, and it never ended well for the <em>extended</em> party. As a consequence of these actions, I
have <a href="https://git.platypush.tech/platypush">moved the Platypush repos to a self-hosted Gitlab instance</a> - which comes
with much more freedom, but also no more Github actions.</p>
<p>And, after the announcement of the
<a href="https://devclass.com/2020/11/25/travis-ci-open-source-engagement/">planned migration from travis-ci.org to travis-ci.com</a>,
with greater focus on enterprise, a limited credit system for open-source projects and a migration process that is
largely manual, I have also realized that Travis-CI is another service that can't be relied upon anymore when it comes
to open-source software. And, again, Travis-CI is plagued by the same contradiction as Github - it claims to be
open-source friendly, but it's not open-source itself, and you can't install it on your own machine.</p>
<p>ReadTheDocs, luckily, seems to be still coherent with its mission of supporting open-source developers, but I'm also
keeping an eye on them just in case :)</p>
<h2>Building a self-hosted CI/CD pipeline</h2>
<p>Even though abandoning closed-source and unreliable cloud development tools is probably the right thing to do, that
leaves a hole behind: how do we bring the simplicity of the automation provided by those tools to our new home -
and, preferably, in such a format that it can be hosted and moved anywhere?</p>
<p>Github and Travis-CI provide a very easy way of setting up CI/CD pipelines. You read the documentation, upload a YAML
file to your repo, and all the magic happens. I wanted to build something that was that easy to configure, but that
could run anywhere, not only in someone else's cloud.</p>
<p>Building a self-hosted pipeline, however, also brings its advantages. Besides liberating yourself of the concern of
handing your hard-worked code to someone else who can either change their mind about their mission, or take it down
overnight, you have the freedom of setting up the environment for build and test however you please and customize it
however you please. And you can easily set up integrations such as automated notifications over whichever channel you
like, without the headache of installing and configuring all the dependencies to run on someone else's cloud.</p>
<p>In this article we'll how to use Platypush to set up a pipeline that:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Reacts to push and tag events on a Gitlab or Github repository and runs custom Platypush actions in YAML format or
  Python code.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Automatically mirrors the new commits and tags to another repo - in my case, from Gitlab to Github.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Runs a suite of tests.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If the tests succeed, then it proceeds with packaging the new version of the codebase - in my case, I run the
  automation to automatically create the new <a href="https://aur.archlinux.org/packages/platypush-git"><code>platypush-git</code></a> package
  for Arch Linux on new pushes, and the new <a href="https://aur.archlinux.org/packages/platypush"><code>platypush</code></a> Arch package and
  the <a href="https://pypi.org/project/platypush/"><code>pip</code> package</a> on new tags.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If the tests fail, it sends a notification (over
  <a href="https://docs.platypush.tech/en/latest/platypush/plugins/mail.smtp.html">email</a>,
  <a href="https://docs.platypush.tech/en/latest/platypush/plugins/chat.telegram.html">Telegram</a>,
  <a href="https://docs.platypush.tech/en/latest/platypush/plugins/pushbullet.html">Pushbullet</a> or
  <a href="https://docs.platypush.tech/en/latest/">whichever plugin supported by Platypush</a>). Also send a notification if the
  latest run of tests has succeeded and the previous one was failing.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Note: since I have moved my projects to a self-hosted Gitlab server, I could have also relied on the native Gitlab CI/CD
pipelines, but I have eventually opted not to do so for two reasons:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Setting up the whole Docker+Kubernetes automation required for the CI/CD pipeline proved to be a quite cumbersome
  process. Additionally, it may require some properly beefed machine in order to run smoothly, while ideally I wanted
  something that could run even on a RaspberryPi, provided that the building and testing processes aren't too
  resource-heavy themselves.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The alternative provided by Gitlab to setting up your Kubernetes instance and configuring the Gitlab integration is to
  get a bucket on the cloud to spin a container that runs all you have to run. But if I have gone so far to set up my
  own self-hosted infrastructure for hosting my code, I certainly don't want to give up on the last mile in exchange of
  a small discount on the Google Cloud services :)</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>However, if either you have enough hardware resources and time to set up your own Kubernetes infrastructure to integrate
with Gitlab, or you don't mind running your CI/CD logic on the Google cloud, Gitlab CI/CD pipelines are something that
you may consider - if you don't have the constraints above then they are very powerful, flexible and easy to set up.</p>
<h2>Installing Platypush</h2>
<p>Let's start by installing Platypush with the required integrations.</p>
<p>If you want to set up an automation that reacts on Gitlab events then you'll only need the <code>http</code> integration, since
we'll use <a href="https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/integrations/webhooks.html">Gitlab webhooks</a> to trigger the
automation:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code>$ <span>[</span>sudo<span>]</span> pip install <span>'platypush[http]'</span>
</code></pre></div>

<p>If you want to set up the automation on a Github repo you'll only have one or two additional dependencies, installed
through the <code>github</code> integration:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code>$ <span>[</span>sudo<span>]</span> pip install <span>'platypush[http,github]'</span>
</code></pre></div>

<p>If you want to be notified of the status of your builds then you may want to install the integration required by the
communication mean that you want to use. We'll use <a href="https://pushbullet.com/">Pushbullet</a> in this example because it's
easy to set up and it natively supports notifications both on mobile and desktop:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code>$ <span>[</span>sudo<span>]</span> pip install <span>'platypush[pushbullet]'</span>
</code></pre></div>

<p>Feel free however to pick anything else - for instance, you can refer to
<a href="https://blog.platypush.tech/article/Build-a-bot-to-communicate-with-your-smart-home-over-Telegram">this article</a> for a
Telegram set up or
<a href="https://blog.platypush.tech/article/Deliver-customized-newsletters-from-RSS-feeds-with-Platypush">this article</a> for a
mail set up, or take a look at the
<a href="https://docs.platypush.tech/en/latest/platypush/plugins/twilio.html">Twilio integration</a> if you want automated
notifications over SMS or Whatsapp.</p>
<p>Once installed, create a <code>~/.config/platypush/config.yaml</code> file that contains the service configuration - for now we'll
just enable the web server:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span># The backend listens on port 8008 by default</span>
<span>backend.http</span><span>:</span>
  <span>enabled</span><span>:</span> <span>True</span>
</code></pre></div>

<h2>Setting up a Gitlab hook</h2>
<p>Gitlab webhooks are a very simple and powerful way of triggering things when something happens on a Gitlab repo. All
you have to do is setting up a URL that should be called upon a repository event (push, tag, new issue, merge request
etc.), and set up an automation on the endpoint that reacts to the event.</p>
<p>The only requirement for this mechanism to work is that the endpoint must be reachable from the Gitlab host - it means
that the host running the Platypush web service must either be publicly accessible, on the same network or VPN as the
Gitlab host, or the Platypush web port must be tunneled/proxied to the Gitlab host.</p>
<p>Platypush offers a very easy way to expose custom endpoints through the
<a href="https://docs.platypush.tech/en/latest/platypush/events/http.hook.html"><code>WebhookEvent</code></a>. All you have to do is set up
an event hook that reacts to a <code>WebhookEvent</code> at a specific endpoint. For example, create a new event hook under
<code>~/.config/platypush/scripts/gitlab.py</code>:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>from</span> <span>platypush.event.hook</span> <span>import</span> <span>hook</span>
<span>from</span> <span>platypush.message.event.http.hook</span> <span>import</span> <span>WebhookEvent</span>

<span># Token to be used to authenticate the calls from Gitlab</span>
<span>gitlab_token</span> <span>=</span> <span>'YOUR_TOKEN_HERE'</span>


<span>@hook</span><span>(</span><span>WebhookEvent</span><span>,</span> <span>hook</span><span>=</span><span>'repo-push'</span><span>)</span>
<span>def</span> <span>on_repo_push</span><span>(</span><span>event</span><span>,</span> <span>**</span><span>context</span><span>):</span>
    <span># Check that the token provided over the</span>
    <span># X-Gitlab-Token header is valid</span>
    <span>assert</span> <span>event</span><span>.</span><span>headers</span><span>.</span><span>get</span><span>(</span><span>'X-Gitlab-Token'</span><span>)</span> <span>==</span> <span>gitlab_token</span><span>,</span> \
      <span>'Invalid Gitlab token'</span>

    <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>'Add your logic here'</span><span>)</span>
</code></pre></div>

<p>This hook will react when an HTTP request is received on <code>http://your-host:8008/hook/repo-push</code>. Note that, unlike
most of the other Platypush endpoints, custom hooks are <em>not</em> authenticated - that's because they may be called from
any context, and you don't necessarily want to share your Platypush instance credentials or token with 3rd-parties.
Instead, it's up to you to implement whichever authentication policy you like over the requests.</p>
<p>Aft…</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.platypush.tech/article/Set-up-self-hosted-CI-CD-git-pipelines-with-Platypush">https://blog.platypush.tech/article/Set-up-self-hosted-CI-CD-git-pipelines-with-Platypush</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.platypush.tech/article/Set-up-self-hosted-CI-CD-git-pipelines-with-Platypush</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26381521</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 01:37:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Flamegraph for a Book]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26381464">thread link</a>) | @baby
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://www.cryptologie.net/article/516/a-flamegraph-of-real-world-cryptography/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cryptologie.net/article/516/a-flamegraph-of-real-world-cryptography/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>

<p>I've now spent 2 years writing my introduction on applied cryptography: <strong>Real-World Cryptography</strong>, which you can already <a href="https://www.manning.com/books/real-world-cryptography?a_aid=Realworldcrypto&amp;a_bid=ad500e09">read online here</a>.
(If you're wondering why I'm writing another book on cryptography <a href="https://www.cryptologie.net/article/504/why-im-writing-a-book-on-cryptography/">check this post</a>.)</p>
<p>I've written all the chapters, but there's still a lot of work to be done to make sure that it's good (collecting feedback), that it's consistent (unification of diagrams, of style, etc.), and that it's well structured.</p>
<p>For the latter point, I thought I would leverage the fact that I'm an engineer and use a tool that's commonly used to measure performance: a <a href="http://www.brendangregg.com/flamegraphs.html">flamegraph</a>!</p>
<p>It looks like this, and you can click around to zoom on different chapters and sections:</p>
<a href="https://www.cryptologie.net/upload/flamegraph.svg"><img src="https://www.cryptologie.net/upload/flamegraph.svg" title="real-world crypto flamegraph"></a>
<h2>How does this work?</h2>
<p>The bottom layer shows all the chapter in order, and the width of the boxes show how lengthy they are.
The more you go up, the more you "nest" yourself into a section.
For example, clicking on the chapter 9: Secure transport, you can see that it is composed of several sections with the longest being "How does TLS work", which itself is composed of several subsections with the longest being "The TLS handshake".</p>
<p><img alt="secure transport" src="https://www.cryptologie.net/upload/Screen_Shot_2021-03-07_at_3.20_.15_PM_.png"></p>
<h2>What is it good for?</h2>
<p>Using this flamegraph, I can now analyze how consistent the book is.</p>
<h3>Distribution</h3>
<p>The good news is that the chapters all seem pretty evenly distributed, for the exception of shorter chapters 3 (MACs), 6 (asymmetric encryption), and 16 (final remarks).
This is also expected are these chapters are much more straightforward than the rest of the book.</p>
<h3>Too length</h3>
<p>Looks like the bigger chapters are in order: post-quantum crypto, authenticated encryption, hardware cryptography, user authentication, secure transport.
This is not great, as post-quantum crypto is supposed to be a chapter for the curious people who get to the end of the book, not a chapter to make the book bigger...
The other chapters are also unnecessary long.
My goal is going to be to reduce these chapters' length in the coming weeks.</p>
<h3>Too nested</h3>
<p>This flamegraph is also useful to quickly see if there are sections that are way too nested. For example, Chapter 9 on secure transport has a lot of mini sections on TLS.
Also, look at some of the section in chapter 5: Key exchanges &gt; Key exchange standards &gt; ECDH &gt; ECDH standard. That's too much.</p>
<h3>Not nested enough</h3>
<p>Some chapters have almost no nested sections at all. For example, chapter 8 (randomness) and 16 (conclusion) are just successions of depth-1 sections. Is this a bad thing? I'm not sure. I think heavy nesting is much more of a problem.</p>
<h3>Errors</h3>
<p>I also managed to spot some errors in nested sections by doing this! So that was pretty cool as well :)</p>
<p>EDIT: If you're interested in doing something like this with your own project, I published the script <a href="https://gist.github.com/mimoo/bae1065d92efe9e18b75bb4a86834f6a">here</a>.</p>
</article><p>Well done! You've reached the end of my post. Now you can <a href="">leave a comment</a> or read something else.</p></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cryptologie.net/article/516/a-flamegraph-of-real-world-cryptography/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26381464</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 01:25:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Random City Video]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26381432">thread link</a>) | @xk3
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://unli.xyz/random/city/video/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://unli.xyz/random/city/video/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://unli.xyz/random/city/video/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26381432</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 01:19:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Modern action films fetishize the body even as they desexualize it]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 493 | Comments 405 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26381377">thread link</a>) | @Avshalom
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://bloodknife.com/everyone-beautiful-no-one-horny/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bloodknife.com/everyone-beautiful-no-one-horny/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                    
<h3 itemprop="name">
            Everyone Is Beautiful and No One Is Horny    </h3>                    
<h4><strong>Modern action and superhero films fetishize the body, even as they desexualize it.</strong></h4>



<p><strong>by RS Benedict</strong></p>



<p>When Paul Verhoeven adapted <em>Starship Troopers</em> in the late 1990s, did he know he was predicting the future? The endless desert war, the ubiquity of military propaganda, a cheerful face shouting victory as more and more bodies pile up?</p>



<p>But the scene that left perhaps the greatest impact on the minds of Nineties kids—and the scene that anticipated our current cinematic age the best—does not feature bugs or guns. It is, of course, the shower scene, in which our heroic servicemen and -women enjoy a communal grooming ritual.</p>



<p>On the surface, it is idyllic: racial harmony, gender equality, unity behind a common goal—and firm, perky asses and tits.</p>



<p>And then the characters speak. The topic of conversation? Military service, of course. One joined for the sake of her political career. Another joined in the hopes of receiving her breeding license. Another talks about how badly he wants to kill the enemy. No one looks at each other. No one flirts.</p>



<p>A room full of beautiful, bare bodies, and everyone is only horny for war.</p>



<p>*  *  *  *  *</p>



<p>In the early 2000s, there was a brief period where actresses pretended that their thinness was natural, almost accidental. Skinny celebrities confessed their love of burgers and fries in magazines; models undergoing profile interviews engaged in public consumption of pasta; leading ladies joked about how little they exercised and how much they hated it. It was all bullshit: no one looks like that without calorie restriction. We knew it then, and we know it now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We don’t pretend anymore. The promotional cycles for blockbuster movies now include detailed descriptions of the performers’ fitness regimens. We watch actors doing burpees or shaking ropes with expensive personal trainers. There is some talk of diets, though not terribly detailed—and no mention of steroids or other hormonal supplements, even though male actors’ suddenly ultra-swole selfies on Instagram suggest physiques crafted with chemical assistance.</p>



<p>Actors are more physically perfect than ever: impossibly lean, shockingly muscular, with magnificently coiffed hair, high cheekbones, impeccable surgical enhancements, and flawless skin, all displayed in form-fitting superhero costumes with the obligatory shirtless scene thrown in to show off shredded abs and rippling pecs.</p>



<figure><blockquote><p><span><strong>Even background extras are good-looking, or at least inoffensively bland. No one is ugly. No one is really fat. Everyone is beautiful.&nbsp;</strong></span></p></blockquote></figure>



<p>And this isn’t just the lead and the love interest: supporting characters look this way too, and even villains (frequently clad in monstrous makeup) are still played by conventionally attractive performers. Even background extras are good-looking, or at least inoffensively bland. No one is ugly. No one is really fat. Everyone is beautiful.</p>



<p>And yet, <a href="https://www.cheatsheet.com/entertainment/marvel-movies-this-esteemed-director-says-theyre-not-sexy-enough.html/"><strong>no one is horny</strong></a>. Even when they have sex, no one is horny. No one is attracted to anyone else. No one is hungry for anyone else.</p>



<p>When revisiting a beloved Eighties or Nineties film, Millennial and Gen X viewers are often startled to encounter long-forgotten sexual content content: John Connor’s conception in <em>Terminator</em>, Jamie Lee Curtis’s toplessness in <em>Trading Places</em>, the spectral blowjob in <em>Ghostbusters</em>. These scenes didn’t shock us when we first saw them. Of <em>course </em>there’s sex in a movie. Isn’t there always?</p>



<p>The answer, of course, is not anymore—at least not when it comes to modern blockbusters</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/qicstnq7qznw0tipo9fa-1024x640.jpg" alt="" width="511" height="319" srcset="https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/qicstnq7qznw0tipo9fa-1024x640.jpg 1024w, https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/qicstnq7qznw0tipo9fa-300x188.jpg 300w, https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/qicstnq7qznw0tipo9fa-768x480.jpg 768w, https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/qicstnq7qznw0tipo9fa-1536x960.jpg 1536w, https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/qicstnq7qznw0tipo9fa.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 511px) 100vw, 511px"></figure></div>



<p>We’re told that Tony Stark and Pepper Potts are an item, but no actual romantic or sexual chemistry between them is shown in the films. Wonder Woman and Steve Trevor utterly lack the sexual chemistry to convince us that either of them would be thirsty enough to commandeer a coma victim’s body (as they do in <em>Wonder Woman 1984</em>) so they can enjoy a posthumous hookup. In defiance of Norse mythology, Chris Hemsworth’s Thor<em> </em>smiles at Natalie Portman like a dumb golden retriever puppy without ever venturing to rend her asunder with his mighty hammer, so to speak. Not that the competition is any better. Despite accusations of being an incel icon, it is Heath Ledger’s Joker, not Christian Bale’s chaste and sexless Batman, who exudes the most sexual energy in the Dark Knight trilogy.</p>



<p>And speaking of Christopher Nolan’s inexplicably sexless oeuvre—did anyone else think it odd how <em>Inception </em>enters the deepest level of a rich man’s subconscious and finds <em>not </em>a psychosexual Oedipal nightmare of staggering depravity, but… a ski patrol?</p>



<p>*  *  *  *  *</p>



<p>Let’s not pretend that Old Hollywood was a progressive haven of body positivity. Since the departure of voluptuous vamp Theda Bara from the silver screen, actors have always gone to extremes to maintain a certain look. Rita Hayworth underwent an ethnic makeover to appear more Caucasian so she could get leading roles. Stars of the 1920s limited their fluid consumption to two glasses a day to avoid water weight. Jane Fonda suffered from severe bulimia at the height of her sex symbol status; so did Marlon Brando.</p>



<figure><blockquote><p><span><strong>Snake Plissken didn’t fuck on screen, but the character radiates overwhelming sex-haver energy.&nbsp;</strong></span></p></blockquote></figure>



<p>But old films still featured recognizable human bodies and human faces—bodies that could theoretically be achieved by a single person without the aid of a team of personal trainers, dieticians, private chefs, and chemists.&nbsp;</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/actors-featured-2-1024x512.jpg" alt="" width="503" height="252" srcset="https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/actors-featured-2-1024x512.jpg 1024w, https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/actors-featured-2-300x150.jpg 300w, https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/actors-featured-2-768x384.jpg 768w, https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/actors-featured-2-1300x650.jpg 1300w, https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/actors-featured-2.jpg 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 503px) 100vw, 503px"></figure></div>



<p>In the films of the Eighties and Nineties, leading actors were good looking, yes, but still human. Kurt Russel’s Snake Plissken was a hunk, but in shirtless scenes his abs have no definition. Bruce Willis was handsome, but he’s more muscular now than he was in the Nineties, when he was routinely branded a bona fide sex symbol. And when Isabella Rosselini strips in <em>Blue Velvet</em>, her skin is pale and her body is soft. She looks vulnerable and real.</p>



<p>And yet, these characters fucked. <em>Blue Velvet’s </em>Dorothy Vallens and Jeffrey Beaumant fucked. Michael Keaton’s Batman and Michelle Pfeiffer’s domme Catwoman fucked. Kyle Reese and Sarah Connor fucked. Snake Plissken didn’t fuck on screen, but the character radiates overwhelming sex-haver energy. And I defy you to find a mainstream film with a moment as horny and gay as the <a href="https://io9.gizmodo.com/the-true-story-of-the-lost-boys-sax-man-1842774832"><strong>Sexy Saxophone Solo</strong></a> from <em>The Lost Boys</em>.</p>



<p>*  *  *  *  *</p>



<p>Seen today, one of the most striking scenes in 1982’s Poltergeist is not the evil clown doll or the monster tree, but a moment of relaxed affection between the parents. The father—a bald, beer-bellied Craig T. Nelson—cracks jokes and prances for his wife, who wears a frumpy nightgown and smokes a joint and yammers weed thoughts and laughs at her husband’s silly display. Finally, the husband playfully dives onto the bed. Neither character is glamorous in this scene, but their relationship feels frisky and lived-in and charismatic and <em>real</em>.</p>



<p>The house looks real, too. There are toys and magazines scattered around the floor. There are cardboard boxes waiting to be unpacked since the recent move. Framed pictures rest against the wall; the parents haven’t gotten around to mounting them yet. The kitchen counters are cluttered and mealtimes are rambunctious and sloppy, as one expects in a house with three children. They’re building a pool in the backyard, but not for appearances: it’s a place for the kids to swim, for the parents to throw parties, and for the father to reacquaint himself with his love of diving.</p>



<p>At the time, this house represented an aspirational ideal of American affluence.</p>



<p>Compare this to homes in films now: massive, sterile cavernous spaces with minimalist furniture. Kitchens are industrial-sized and spotless, and they contain no food. There is no excess. There is no mess.</p>



<figure><blockquote><p><span><strong>A body is no longer a holistic system. It is not the vehicle through which we experience joy and pleasure. It is not a home to live in and be happy.&nbsp;</strong></span></p></blockquote></figure>



<p>In her blog McMansion Hell, Kate Wagner examines precisely why these widely-hated 5000-square foot housing bubble behemoths are so awful. Over and over again, she reiterates the point that McMansions are not built to be homes; they’re built to be short-term investments.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://mcmansionhell.com/post/150597521816/mcmansions-101-revisited-aesthetics-aside-why"><strong>Kate writes</strong></a>, “The inside of McMansions are designed in order to cram the most ‘features’ inside for the lowest costs.” These features exist to increase the house’s resale value, not to make it a good place to live. No thought is given to the labor needed to clean and maintain these spaces. The master bathroom includes intricate stone surfaces that can only be scrubbed with a toothbrush; the cathedral ceilings in the living room raise the heating and cooling costs to an exorbitant sum; the chandelier in the grand entryway dangles so high that no one can replace the bulbs in it, even with a stepladder.</p>



<p>The same fate has befallen our bodies. A body is no longer a holistic system. It is not the vehicle through which we experience joy and pleasure during our brief time in the land of the living. It is not a home to live in and be happy. It, too, is a collection of features: six pack, thigh gap, cum gutters. And these features exist not to make our lives more comfortable, but to increase the value of our assets. Our bodies are investments, which must always be optimized to bring us… what, exactly? Some vague sense of better living? Is a life without bread objectively better than a life with it? When we were children, did we dream of counting every calorie and logging every step?</p>



<p>A generation or two ago, it was normal for adults to engage in sports not purely as self-improvement but as an act of leisure. People danced for fun; couples socialized over tennis; kids played stickball for lack of anything else to do. Solitary exercise at the gym also had a social, rather than moral, purpose. People worked out to look hot so they could attract other hot people and fuck them. Whatever the ethos …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://bloodknife.com/everyone-beautiful-no-one-horny/">https://bloodknife.com/everyone-beautiful-no-one-horny/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bloodknife.com/everyone-beautiful-no-one-horny/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26381377</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 01:10:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Wireless Electricity]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26381190">thread link</a>) | @marshmallow_12
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://emrod.energy/wireless-power/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://emrod.energy/wireless-power/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://emrod.energy/wireless-power/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26381190</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:38:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Invisible Companion Technique]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26381082">thread link</a>) | @cookingoils
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://elliott.computer/pages/invisible-companion.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://elliott.computer/pages/invisible-companion.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <ol>
            <li>Purchase a small folding table.</li>
            <li>Place the table to the right or left of your current home office desk. It should be a little behind you so that it’s only visible in your periphery when you are sitting at your main desk.</li>
            <li>Open a secondary laptop on the folding table. If you don't have another computer, a few open books will suffice. <i>Bonus: light a candle or place a lamp on the desk.</i></li>
            <li>Go about your work at your home office desk and feel your companion’s productive energy.</li>
        </ol>

        <br>

        <h3><i>Advanced: Invisible Office Technique</i></h3>

        <ol>
            <li>Buy several folding desks and old laptops from Craigslist or Ebay.</li>
            <li>Follow the same steps as the <i>Invisible Companion Technique</i> to configure each desk.</li>
            <li>Experiment with placing desks behind you in the room like a classroom or audience observing you as you work.</li>
        </ol>

        <br>

        <figure>
            <img src="https://elliott.computer/pages/images/invisible-companion.jpg" alt="Invisible companion">
            <figcaption>
                An illustration of the <i>Invisible Companion Technique.</i>
            </figcaption>
        </figure>

        <p>
            • • •<br>
            Thanks to Lydia M. and <a href="http://laurelschwulst.com/">Laurel S.</a> for the technique names.
        </p>

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://elliott.computer/pages/invisible-companion.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26381082</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:18:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Israeli 5-minute battery charge aims to fire up electric cars]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26381007">thread link</a>) | @mishkovski
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://www.ctvnews.ca/autos/israeli-5-minute-battery-charge-aims-to-fire-up-electric-cars-1.5337215 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.ctvnews.ca/autos/israeli-5-minute-battery-charge-aims-to-fire-up-electric-cars-1.5337215">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <p>HERZLIYA, ISRAEL -- 
	From flat battery to full charge in just five minutes -- an Israeli start-up has developed technology it says could eliminate the "range anxiety" associated with electric cars.</p>
<p>
	Ultra-fast recharge specialists StoreDot have developed a first-generation lithium-ion battery that can rival the filling time of a standard car at the pump.</p>
<p>
	"We are changing the entire experience of the driver, the problem of 'range anxiety'... that you might get stuck on the highway without energy," StoreDot founder Doron Myersdorf said.</p>
<p>
	The innovation could eliminate the hours required to recharge an electric car, he said.</p>
<p>
	Hundreds of prototypes are being tested by manufacturers.</p>
<p>
	His company,&nbsp;based in Herzliya, near Tel Aviv, is backed by four key investors: German automobile manufacturer Daimler, the UK's British Petroleum and the electronic giants Samsung and TDK.</p>
<p>
	Myersdorf, who set up the company in 2012, has tested the battery on phones, drones and scooters, before tackling the big prize of electric vehicles.</p>
<h2>
	- 'Revolution' -</h2>
<p>
	But Eric Esperance, an analyst at Roland Berger consulting firm, cautioned that while ultra-fast charging would be a "revolution", many stages remain.</p>
<p>
	"We are still far off from the industrial automotive market," he told AFP.</p>
<p>
	In 2019, the Nobel Chemistry Prize was awarded to John Goodenough of the US, Britain's Stanley Whittingham and Japan's Akira Yoshino for the invention of lithium-ion batteries.</p>
<p>
	"This lightweight, rechargeable and powerful battery is now used in everything from mobile phones to laptops and electric vehicles," the Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences said on awarding the prize.</p>
<p>
	Myersdorf said charging "speed was not part" of the original design that won the Nobel, so he worked on what was "considered impossible": a lithium-ion battery good to go in minutes.</p>
<p>
	"We wanted to demonstrate that you can take a lithium-ion battery, replace some of its materials and then charge it in five minutes," he said.</p>
<p>
	The engineer switched the original graphite in the battery's negative anode with silicon.</p>
<p>
	"We are taking that amazing innovation of the lithium-ion battery and upgrading it to extreme fast charging capability," he said.</p>
<p>
	Batteries are assembled in a laboratory equipped with large glass boxes, sealed to keep oxygen out.</p>
<p>
	StoreDot chemists clad in goggles and white coats build 100 batteries a week, sent to companies for possible use in their products.</p>
<h2>
	- 'Fossil fuel-free society' -</h2>
<p>
	The team is already working on a second generation of batteries to cut costs.</p>
<p>
	While the design cycle of a vehicle is "typically&nbsp;four to five years", they are looking to speed up the process.</p>
<p>
	"We are working on taking this solution to the market&nbsp;in parallel, by designing the manufacturing facilities that would be able to mass produce this battery," Myersdorf said.</p>
<p>
	The Nobel jury praised the lithium-ion battery for being able to "store significant amounts of energy from solar and wind power, making possible a fossil fuel-free society".</p>
<p>
	As public opinion shifts towards prioritising the climate change crisis, manufacturers are gearing production towards less polluting vehicles.</p>
<p>
	But the road is long.</p>
<p>
	On the ground, charging stations would have to be adapted for the new generation batteries, costing between $1,500 and $10,000 depending on capacity.</p>
<p>
	Electric cars are also still expensive, and in 2019 they represented only 2.6 percent of global sales, according to the International Energy Agency.</p>
<p>
	For Myersdorf, the sooner the world switches to electric vehicles the better, pointing to the "huge impact on the planet".</p>
<p>
	But recycling lithium-ion batteries remains a problem, with Esperance noting that each has a lifespan of between 3,000 and 3,500 charges.</p>
<p>
	"We must set up a recycling system, as there is for lead-acid batteries," he said. "Today, this network is just being set up."</p>
<p>
	Both the extraction and recycling of lithium pose ecological, political and economic challenges for technology to overcome.</p>
                                              </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.ctvnews.ca/autos/israeli-5-minute-battery-charge-aims-to-fire-up-electric-cars-1.5337215</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26381007</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:03:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
