<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 12:24:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 12:24:24 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Intel, ARM, IBM, AMD Processors Vulnerable to New Side-Channel Attacks]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 117 | Comments 22 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24089281">thread link</a>) | @beefhash
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://modernnetsec.io/intel-arm-ibm-amd-processors-vulnerable-to-new-side-channel-attacks/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://modernnetsec.io/intel-arm-ibm-amd-processors-vulnerable-to-new-side-channel-attacks/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<div><a href="https://modernnetsec.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/intel-arm-ibm-amd-processors-vulnerable-to-new-side-channel-attacks-1.jpg"><amp-img alt="Side-Channel Attacks" data-original-height="380" data-original-width="728" src="https://modernnetsec.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/intel-arm-ibm-amd-processors-vulnerable-to-new-side-channel-attacks-1.jpg" title="Side-Channel Attacks" width="728" height="380" layout="intrinsic" i-amphtml-layout="intrinsic"><img alt="Side-Channel Attacks" src="https://modernnetsec.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/intel-arm-ibm-amd-processors-vulnerable-to-new-side-channel-attacks-1.jpg" title="Side-Channel Attacks" width="728" height="380" data-old-src="data:image/svg+xml;base64,PHN2ZyBoZWlnaHQ9JzM4MCcgd2lkdGg9JzcyOCcgeG1sbnM9J2h0dHA6Ly93d3cudzMub3JnLzIwMDAvc3ZnJyB2ZXJzaW9uPScxLjEnLz4="></amp-img></a></div>
<p>It turns out that the root cause behind several previously disclosed speculative execution attacks against modern processors, such as <a href="https://thehackernews.com/2018/01/meltdown-spectre-vulnerability.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Meltdown</a> and <a href="https://thehackernews.com/2018/08/foreshadow-intel-processor-vulnerability.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Foreshadow</a>, was misattributed to ‘prefetching effect,’ resulting in hardware vendors releasing incomplete mitigations and countermeasures.</p>
<p>Sharing its findings with The Hacker News, a group of academics from the Graz University of Technology and CISPA Helmholtz Center for Information Security finally revealed the exact reason behind why the kernel addresses are cached in the first place, as well as presented several new attacks that exploit the previously unidentified underlying issue, allowing attackers to sniff out sensitive data.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2008.02307.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">new research explains</a> microarchitectural attacks were actually caused by speculative dereferencing of user-space registers in the kernel, which not just impacts the most recent Intel CPUs with the latest hardware mitigations, but also several modern processors from ARM, IBM, and AMD — previously believed to be unaffected.</p>
<div>
<a href="https://go.thn.li/contrast" rel="nofollow noopener sponsored noreferrer" target="_blank" title="cybersecurity"><amp-img alt="cybersecurity" src="https://modernnetsec.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/intel-arm-ibm-amd-processors-vulnerable-to-new-side-channel-attacks-2.jpg" width="728" height="90" layout="intrinsic" i-amphtml-layout="intrinsic"><img alt="cybersecurity" src="https://modernnetsec.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/intel-arm-ibm-amd-processors-vulnerable-to-new-side-channel-attacks-2.jpg" width="728" height="90" data-old-src="data:image/svg+xml;base64,PHN2ZyBoZWlnaHQ9JzkwJyB3aWR0aD0nNzI4JyB4bWxucz0naHR0cDovL3d3dy53My5vcmcvMjAwMC9zdmcnIHZlcnNpb249JzEuMScvPg=="></amp-img></a>
</div>
<p>“We discovered that effects reported in several academic papers over the past 4 years were not correctly understood, leading to incorrect assumptions on countermeasures,” the researchers told The Hacker News.</p>
<p>“This <a href="https://gruss.cc/files/prefetch.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">prefetching effect</a> is actually unrelated to software prefetch instructions or hardware prefetching effects due to memory accesses and instead is caused by speculative dereferencing of user-space registers in the kernel.”</p>
<p>Besides analyzing the actual root cause of the prefetching effect, some other key findings from the research are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Discovery of several new attacks exploiting the underlying root cause, including an address-translation attack in more restricted contexts, direct leakage of register values in specific scenarios, and an end-to-end Foreshadow exploit targeting non-L1 data.</li>
<li>A novel cross-core covert channel attack that, in some instances, could let attackers observe caching of the address (or value) stored in a register without relying on shared memory.</li>
<li>Spectre ‘prefetch’ gadgets can directly leak actual data, which not only makes <a href="https://thehackernews.com/2019/11/zombieload-cpu-vulnerability.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ZombieLoad attack</a> efficient on Intel CPUs to leak sensitive data from internal buffers or memory but also impact non-Intel CPUs.</li>
<li>The speculative dereferencing issue — in certain attacks like <a href="https://thehackernews.com/2020/03/rowhammer-vulnerability-ddr4-dram.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rowhammer</a>, cache attacks, and DRAMA — could let attackers recover the physical addresses of JavaScript variables and exfiltrate information via <a href="https://gruss.cc/files/rowhammerjs.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">transient execution</a> remotely via a web browser.</li>
</ul>
<p>Additionally, researchers also demonstrated that the Foreshadow vulnerability on Intel CPUs could be exploited even when the recommended mitigations are enabled. This is made possible due to the fact the attack can be mounted on data not residing in L1 cache on kernel versions containing ‘prefetch’ gadgets.</p>
<h2>From Address Translation Attack to Foreshadow</h2>
<p>The idea behind this is straight-forward. System software relies on the CPU’s address translation mechanism to implement isolation among different processes. Each process has its own virtual memory space and cannot access arbitrary physical memory addresses outside of it.</p>
<p>[embedded content]</p>
<p>Address translation, thus, acts as an intermediate layer that maps the virtual address space, which is used by a program, to the physical address to a physical address.</p>
<p>The virtual address space also includes a kernel address space to house Linux kernel threads, thus making it easy for the underlying hardware to handle privileged instructions from user threads in kernel mode.</p>
<p>While operating system kernels can be secured against prefetch side-channel attacks via a technique called kernel page-table isolation (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kernel_page-table_isolation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">KPTI</a> or <a href="https://gruss.cc/files/kaiser.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">KAISER</a>) — which enforces a strict kernel and userspace isolation such that the hardware does not hold any information about kernel addresses while running in user mode — the researchers found that it does not guarantee full protection from address-translation attacks, where an attacker tries to check if two different virtual addresses map to the same physical address.</p>
<p>Put differently, the “address-translation attack allows unprivileged applications to fetch arbitrary kernel addresses into the cache and thus resolve virtual to physical addresses on 64-bit Linux systems.”</p>
<p>While the original line of thought was that such attacks were related to prefetch instructions, the new finding proves otherwise, thereby validating that KAISER isn’t an adequate countermeasure against microarchitectural side-channel attacks on kernel isolation.</p>
<p>Instead, it exploits a Spectre-BTB-SA-IP (Branch Target Buffer, same address, in-place) gadget to cause information leakage, causing speculative execution, and further carry out Meltdown and Foreshadow (L1 Terminal Fault) attacks by bypassing current L1TF mitigations.</p>
<p><a href="https://thehackernews.com/2018/11/meltdown-spectre-vulnerabilities.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Spectre-BTB-SA-IP</a> is a variant of <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1811.05441.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Spectre vulnerability</a> that exploits the Branch Target Buffer — a cache-like component in CPUs that’s used for branch prediction — to perform attacks within the same address space and the same branch location.</p>
<p>“The same prefetching effect can be used to perform Foreshadow,” the researchers said. “If a secret is present in the L3 cache and the direct-physical map address is derefenced in the hypervisor kernel, data can be fetched into the L1. This reenables Foreshadow even with Foreshadow mitigations enabled if the unrelated Spectre-BTB mitigations are disabled.”</p>
<p>“The consequence is that we are able to mount a Foreshadow attack on older kernels patched against Foreshadow with all mitigations enabled and on a fully patched kernel if only Spectre-v2 mitigations are disabled.”</p>
<h2>Enable Spectre-BTB mitigations such as Retpoline</h2>
<p>To highlight the impact of the side-channel attacks, the researchers established a cache-based covert channel that exfiltrated data from a process running on an Intel Core i7-6500U CPU to another stealthy process, achieving a transmission rate of 10 bit/s to relay a total of 128 bytes from the sender to the receiver process.<br>Furthermore, the researchers disclosed that it’s possible to leak register contents from an SGX enclave of Intel CPUs using a register that’s speculatively dereferenced (called “Dereference Trap”), using it to recover a 32-bit value stored in a 64-bit register within 15 minutes.</p>
<p>Lastly, ‘certain attacks’ can now be mounted remotely using JavaScript in a web browser, and “fill 64-bit registers with an attacker-controlled value in JavaScript by using WebAssembly.”</p>
<p>To mitigate these attacks, it’s recommended that current CPUs enable Spectre-BTB mitigations, including <a href="https://support.google.com/faqs/answer/7625886" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">retpoline</a> (short for “return trampoline”), which aims to <a href="https://software.intel.com/security-software-guidance/insights/deep-dive-retpoline-branch-target-injection-mitigation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">prevent branch-target-injection</a> by isolating <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Branch_predictor#Indirect_branch_predictor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">indirect branches</a> from speculative execution.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://modernnetsec.io/intel-arm-ibm-amd-processors-vulnerable-to-new-side-channel-attacks/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24089281</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 05:24:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Alcohol as a social technology to check the trustworthiness of others (2014)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 248 | Comments 255 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24088202">thread link</a>) | @searchableguy
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://hndex.org/7798063 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://hndex.org/7798063">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
<header>

<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=7798063" target="_blank">comments</a> <a href="https://plus.google.com/+KajSotala/posts/hofuxyXz78j" target="_blank">original article</a></header>
<p>Ohhh, never thought of this hypothesis: that the act of getting
drunk together might be a social technology that helps us verify
the trustworthiness of others by inhibiting their higher cognitive
functions and thus making it harder to consciously fake things.
That would make sense.</p>
<p>&gt; To enhance our natural thin-slicing abilities, humans have
therefore also developed various cultural practices that make these
instant assessments more reliable. These techniques take advantage
of the fact that deception is fundamentally a cold-cognition act
and relies on cognitive control centers. This means that if we can
impair the cognitive control abilities of people we're trying to
judge, we’ll do a better job of sussing them out: they will
be less able to confuse our cheater-detection systems.</p>
<p>&gt; In one study that has proven enormously useful to law
enforcement agencies, researchers found that police officers could
significantly improve their ability to detect false statements if
suspects were asked to give their alibis in reverse order, starting
with the most recent event and working their way back. This is not
the way we normally tell stories, so being forced to do it
increases cognitive load. Dishonest suspects, it turns out, are
less effective liars if you handicap their conscious minds in this
way.</p>
<p>&gt; This reverse-order alibi technique is a great tool for law
enforcement but not terribly practical when evaluating a potential
business partner or deciding if the people you’re about to
make a peace treaty with are being sincere. There are other ways to
achieve the same effect, though. The police study aimed to reduce
subjects’ cognitive control ability by increasing the
load-adding more weight, as it were. Alternately, you can keep the
load constant but decrease cognitive control ability-weaken the
mental muscles-by suppressing cognitive control centers. One way to
do this is transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS), which involves
applying a powerful magnetic force to the appropriate region of the
skull. TMS, however, is a very recent technology and not exactly
widely available. Also, in most cultures it’s considered bad
form to shock the heads of new acquaintances with huge magnets.</p>
<p>&gt; A much more low-tech and socially acceptable way to produce
the same effect is to get someone completely wasted. As we
discussed in chapter 6, one of the primary effects of alcohol and
other intoxicants is to "downregulate," or temporarily paralyze,
areas of the prefrontal cortex associated with cognitive control. A
couple shots of tequila is the liquid equivalent of a nice jolt of
TMS. It’s therefore no accident that intoxicants of various
sorts are frequently employed by human beings as social lubricants.
Alcohol, kava, cannabis, magic mushrooms, you name it: any
intoxicant that people can get their hands on quickly comes to play
a central role in social occasions, both formal and informal. In
ancient China, no major treaty was signed without first bringing
everyone together in an extended, alcohol-soaked banquet. In fact,
this is one feature of Chinese culture that has not changed a bit
in over four thousand years. Any modern businessperson hoping to
ink a deal with Chinese partners had better get his or her liver in
shape first.</p>
<p>&gt; On a less formal level, this is no doubt why intoxicants
are a universal feature of all sorts of human social gatherings,
from casual cocktail parties to fraternity mixers. Not only is
getting drunk pleasant, it also typically causes people to get
along more freely and easily (at least to a certain point, after
which the drunken fights break out). Intoxication enhances
cooperation in at least two ways. First of all, it reduces social
faking by inhibiting cognitive control centers. Second, if we all
get drunk together, we create a situation of mutual vulnerability
that makes trust easier to establish. Getting drunk is essentially
an act of mental disarmament. In the same way that shaking right
hands with someone assures them that you’re not holding a
weapon, downing a few tequila shots is like checking your
prefrontal cortex at the door. See? No cognitive control. You can
trust me.</p>
<p>Excerpt From: Slingerland, Edward. "Trying Not to Try." Crown
Publishing Group, 2014-03-04. ﻿</p>
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://hndex.org/7798063</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24088202</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 01:32:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Swedish doctor's perspective on Covid]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 126 | Comments 244 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24087287">thread link</a>) | @gofiggy
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://sebastianrushworth.com/2020/08/04/how-bad-is-covid-really-a-swedish-doctors-perspective/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://sebastianrushworth.com/2020/08/04/how-bad-is-covid-really-a-swedish-doctors-perspective/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Ok, I want to preface this article by stating that it is entirely anecdotal and based on my experience working as a doctor in the emergency room of one of the big hospitals in Stockholm, Sweden, and of living as a citizen in Sweden. As many people know, Sweden is perhaps the country that has taken the most relaxed attitude of any towards the covid pandemic. Unlike other countries, Sweden never went in to complete lockdown. Non-essential businesses have remained open, people have continued to go to cafés and restaurants, children have remained in school, and very few people have bothered with face masks in public.</p>



<p>Covid hit Stockholm like a storm in mid-March. One day I was seeing people with appendicitis and kidney stones, the usual things you see in the emergency room. The next day all those patients were gone and the only thing coming in to the hospital was covid. Practically everyone who was tested had covid, regardless of what the presenting symtom was. People came in with a nose bleed and they had covid. They came in with stomach pain and they had covid.</p>



<p>Then, after a few months, all the covid patients disappeared. It is now four months since the start of the pandemic, and I haven’t seen a single covid patient in over a month. When I do test someone because they have a cough or a fever, the test invariably comes back negative. At the peak three months back, a hundred people were dying a day of covid in Sweden, a country with a population of ten million. We are now down to around five people dying per day in the whole country, and that number continues to drop. Since people generally die around three weeks after infection, that means virtually no-one is getting infected any more. If we assume around 0.5 percent of those infected die (which I think is very generous, more on that later), then that means that three weeks back 1,000 people were getting infected per day in the whole country, which works out to a daily risk per person of getting infected of 1 in 10,000, which is miniscule. And remember, the risk of dying is at the very most 1 in 200 if you actually do get infected. And that was three weeks ago. Basically, covid is in all practical senses over and done with in Sweden. After four months.</p>



<p>In total covid has killed under 6,000 people in a country of ten million. A country with an annual death rate of around 100,000 people. Considering that 70% of those who have died of covid are over 80 years old, quite a few of those 6,000 would have died this year anyway. That makes covid a mere blip in terms of its effect on mortality.</p>



<p>That is why it is nonsensical to compare covid to other major pandemics, like the 1918 pandemic that killed tens of millions of people. Covid will never even come close to those numbers. And yet many countries have shut down their entire economies, stopped children going to school, and made large portions of their population unemployed in order to deal with this disease.</p>



<p>The media have been proclaiming that only a small percentage of the population have antibodies, and therefore it is impossible that herd immunity has developed. Well, if herd immunity hasn’t developed, where are all the sick people? Why has the rate of infection dropped so precipitously? Considering that most people in Sweden are leading their lives normally now, not socially distancing, not wearing masks, there should still be high rates of infection.</p>



<p>The reason we test for antibodies is because it is easy and cheap. Antibodies are in fact not the body’s main defence against virus infections. T-cells are. But T-cells are harder to measure than antibodies, so we don’t really do it clinically. It is quite possible to have T-cells that are specific for covid and thereby make you immune to the disease, without having any antibodies. Personally, I think this is what has happened. Everybody who works in the emergency room where I work has had the antibody test. Very few actually have antibodies. This is in spite of being exposed to huge numbers of infected people, including at the beginning of the pandemic, before we realized how widespread covid was, when no-one was wearing protective equipment.</p>



<p>I am not denying that covid is awful for the people who do get really sick or for the families of the people who die, just as it is awful for the families of people who die of cancer, or influenza, or an opioid overdose. But the size of the response in most of the world (not including Sweden) has been totally disproportionate to the size of the threat.</p>



<p>Sweden ripped the metaphorical band-aid off quickly and got the epidemic over and done with in a short amount of time, while the rest of the world has chosen to try to peel the band-aid off slowly. At present that means Sweden has one of the highest total death rates in the world. But covid is over in Sweden. People have gone back to their normal lives and barely anyone is getting infected any more. I am willing to bet that the countries that have shut down completely will see rates spike when they open up. If that is the case, then there won’t have been any point in shutting down in the first place, because all those countries are going to end up with the same number of dead at the end of the day anyway. Shutting down completely in order to decrease the total number of deaths only makes sense if you are willing to stay shut down until a vaccine is available. That could take years. No country is willing to wait that long.</p>



<p>Covid has at present killed less than 6000 in Sweden. It is very unlikely that the number of dead will go above 7,000. An average influenza year in Sweden, 700 people die of influenza. Does that mean covid is ten times worse than influenza? No, because influenza has been around for centuries while covid is completely new. In an average influenza year most people already have some level of immunity because they’ve been infected with a similar strain previously, or because they’re vaccinated. So it is quite possible, in fact likely, that the case fatality rate for covid is the same as for influenza, or only slightly higher, and the entire difference we have seen is due to the complete lack of any immunity in the population at the start of this pandemic. </p>



<p>This conclusion makes sense of the Swedish fatality numbers – if we’ve reached a point where there is hardly any active infection going on any more in Sweden in spite of the fact that there is barely any social distancing happening then that means at least 50% of the population has been infected already and have developed immunity, which is five million people. This number is perfectly reasonable if we assume a reproductive number for the virus of two: If each person infects two new, with a five day period between being infected and infecting others, and you start out with just one infected person in the country, then you will reach a point where several million are infected in just four months. If only 6000 are dead out of five million infected, that works out to a case fatality rate of 0.12 percent, roughly the same as regular old influenza, which no-one is the least bit frightened of, and which we don’t shut down our societies for.</p>



<p>If you thought this article was interesting, then you might be interested in my follow-up article, about <a href="https://sebastianrushworth.com/2020/08/08/what-is-the-best-way-to-measure-rates-of-covid-immunity/">the best way to measure rates of covid infection in a population</a></p>



<p>Additionally, If you liked this article, then please click the link at the bottom of this page to subscribe and receive future articles straight to your inbox.</p>

<div>
	<p><img alt="" src="https://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f80948fe1de6fa8784ebcbce1a6c153c?s=42&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" height="42" width="42">	</p><!-- .author-avatar -->

	<div>
		

		<p>
			I am a practicing physician in Stockholm, Sweden. Every day I get asked questions by my patients about health, diet, exercise, supplements, and medications. There is a lot of misinformation on the internet and it is easy to get the wrong advice, and hard to tell what is right and what is wrong if you don’t have advanced scientific training. The purpose of this blog is to share what the science actually says.			<a href="https://sebastianrushworth.com/author/doctorsebastian/" rel="author">
				View all posts by Sebastian Rushworth, M.D.			</a>
		</p><!-- .author-bio -->
	</div><!-- .author-description -->
</div><!-- .author-info -->
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://sebastianrushworth.com/2020/08/04/how-bad-is-covid-really-a-swedish-doctors-perspective/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24087287</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 23:00:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Microsoft Fast Design]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 552 | Comments 181 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24083260">thread link</a>) | @no_wizard
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://www.fast.design/docs/introduction | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.fast.design/docs/introduction">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Welcome to the FAST documentation! We're glad you're here. We can't wait to show you around.</p><h2>What is FAST?</h2><p>FAST is a collection of JavaScript packages centered around web standards, designed to help you efficiently tackle some of the most common challenges in website and application design and development.</p><p>Have you ever needed a reusable set of UI components that you could drop into your app and have an amazing experience? <em><strong>That's FAST.</strong></em></p><p>Have you ever needed to create your own components, and share them across your company, including across groups that use different, incompatible front-end frameworks? <em><strong>That's FAST.</strong></em></p><p>Have you ever needed to implement a branded experience or a design language like Microsoft's Fluent UI or Google's Material Design? <em><strong>That's FAST.</strong></em></p><p>Have you ever wanted to improve your app's startup time, render speed, or memory consumption? <em><strong>That's FAST.</strong></em></p><p>Have you ever wanted to adopt more web standards and build your site or app on a native web foundation that's immune to the shifting sands of the modern JavaScript front-end landscape? <em><strong>That's FAST.</strong></em></p><p>Let's take a look at what each of FAST's core packages gives us today.</p><h3>fast-element</h3><p><a href="https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://img.shields.io/badge/License-MIT-yellow.svg" alt="License: MIT"></a>
<a href="https://badge.fury.io/js/%40microsoft%2Ffast-element" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://badge.fury.io/js/%40microsoft%2Ffast-element.svg" alt="npm version"></a></p><p>The <code>fast-element</code> library is a lightweight means to easily building performant, memory-efficient, standards-compliant Web Components. FAST Elements work in every major browser and can be used in combination with any front-end framework or even without a framework. To get up and running with <code>fast-element</code> see <a href="https://www.fast.design/docs/fast-element/getting-started">the Getting Started guide</a>.</p><h3>fast-foundation</h3><p><a href="https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://img.shields.io/badge/License-MIT-yellow.svg" alt="License: MIT"></a>
<a href="https://badge.fury.io/js/%40microsoft%2Ffast-foundation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://badge.fury.io/js/%40microsoft%2Ffast-foundation.svg" alt="npm version"></a></p><p>The <code>fast-foundation</code> package is a library of Web Component classes, templates, and other utilities intended to be composed into registered Web Components by design systems (e.g. Fluent Design, Material Design, etc.). The exports of this package can generally be thought of as un-styled base components that implement semantic and accessible markup and behavior.</p><p>This package does not export Web Components registered as <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Web_Components/Using_custom_elements" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">custom elements</a> - it exports parts and pieces intended to be <em>composed</em> into Web Components, allowing you to implement your own design language by simply applying CSS styles and behaviors without having to write all the JavaScript that's involved in building production-quality component implementations.</p><h3>fast-components</h3><p><a href="https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://img.shields.io/badge/License-MIT-yellow.svg" alt="License: MIT"></a>
<a href="https://badge.fury.io/js/%40microsoft%2Ffast-components" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://badge.fury.io/js/%40microsoft%2Ffast-components.svg" alt="npm version"></a></p><p><code>fast-components</code> is a library of Web Components that <em>composes</em> the exports of <code>fast-foundation</code> with stylesheets aligning to the FAST design language. This composition step registers a custom element. See the <a href="https://www.fast.design/docs/components/getting-started">quick start</a> to get started using the components.</p><h3>fast-components-msft</h3><p><a href="https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://img.shields.io/badge/License-MIT-yellow.svg" alt="License: MIT"></a>
<a href="https://badge.fury.io/js/%40microsoft%2Ffast-components-msft" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://badge.fury.io/js/%40microsoft%2Ffast-components-msft.svg" alt="npm version"></a></p><p><code>fast-components-msft</code> is a library of Web Components that <em>composes</em> <code>fast-foundation</code>. <code>fast-components-msft</code> uses the same custom element names as <code>fast-components</code>, but makes use of different stylesheets that support Microsoft's Fluent design language.</p><h3>Component Explorer</h3><p>Launch our <a href="https://explore.fast.design/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Component Explorer</a> to experience our <a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/@microsoft/fast-components" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">FAST Components</a> and development tools.</p><h2>Getting started</h2><p>If you're looking to get started using our components right away, take a look at <a href="https://www.fast.design/docs/components/getting-started">the components quick start</a>. You'll also want to check out <a href="https://www.fast.design/docs/integrations/introduction">our integrations</a> if you're looking to add the components into a Webpack build or incorporate them with another front-end framework. For those interested in implementing their own design system or customizing the styles of the components, after you <a href="https://www.fast.design/docs/components/getting-started">have a look at the components</a>, you'll want to read through <a href="https://www.fast.design/docs/design/introduction">our styling docs</a>. Finally, if your goal is to build your own components or apps with <code>fast-element</code>, you can learn all about that in our <a href="https://www.fast.design/docs/fast-element/getting-started">guide to building web components with FASTElement</a>.</p><h2>Joining the community</h2><p>Looking to get answers to questions or engage with us in realtime? Our community is most active <a href="https://discord.gg/FcSNfg4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">on Discord</a>. Submit requests and issues on <a href="https://github.com/Microsoft/fast/issues/new/choose" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub</a>, or join us by contributing on <a href="https://github.com/Microsoft/fast/labels/community:good-first-issue" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">some good first issues via GitHub</a>.</p><p>We look forward to building an amazing open source community with you!</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.fast.design/docs/introduction</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24083260</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 15:55:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A T Cell Army against SARS-CoV-2]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 68 | Comments 28 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24082327">thread link</a>) | @karmel
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://www.hellovirology.com/2020/08/a-t-cell-army-against-sars-cov-2.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.hellovirology.com/2020/08/a-t-cell-army-against-sars-cov-2.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<div id="post-body-3178459137750369132">



<p>
We have talked a fair <a href="https://www.hellovirology.com/2020/07/what-is-mrna-vaccine.html">amount</a> <a href="https://www.hellovirology.com/2020/07/antibody-hope-in-sars-cov-2.html">about</a> antibodies, and much of the SARS-CoV-2 discussion is focused on antibodies as indicators, treatments, or vaccines. However, antibodies produced by B-cells are only one part of the larger immune picture, albeit one of the most accessible parts. To develop a comprehensive treatment strategy for SARS-CoV-2, we will likely need to understand how the broader network of immune cells responds to the virus. Today, we’ll take a closer look at the T cell response to SARS-CoV-2 infection, and what it says about long-term immunity.
</p>
<h3>A robust T cell response</h3>


<p>
A brief refresher: T cells, <a href="https://www.hellovirology.com/2020/06/adaptive-immune-cells.html">you may remember</a>, are adaptive immune cells. Each T cell has a unique T cell receptor that recognizes a different set of foreign peptides, and if a T cell’s receptor is activated, that T cell clones itself and produces an army of similar T cells capable of fighting off the invader that was recognized. T cells come in several varieties, the two most prominent of which are CD4+ T cells and CD8+ T cells. CD4+ T cells are responsible for surveying peptides (that is, short protein fragments) presented by antigen-presenting cells like B cells and macrophages and starting a signaling cascade that activates the rest of the immune system, and are thus referred to as “helper” T cells. CD8+ T cells survey peptides presented by normal tissue cells throughout the body, and, if they recognize one of the presented peptides as foreign, they kill the cell under the assumption that it has been infected. CD8+ T cells are thus called “killer” T cells.</p><p><img height="441" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/VHihcE0ie5EooWOw2mc8MzfuYgaOlru5R7lLNl22U_DTENRS9eBrKdPNZd1a0q609Hhyl7WZLuQpw8lVU3fO2ZsWAYwdT_anu_JpkUAMOyP1IkBQ_TGsvrYS4geTdOtRC1TVjQLU=w499-h441" width="499"></p><p>Given these critical roles in immune system activation, scientists are studying the extent to which CD4+ and CD8+ T cells recognize peptides from SARS-CoV-2. In <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-020-2550-z">one recent paper</a>, Grifoni et al. created pools of peptides that tile the entire set of proteins that make up SARS-CoV-2. In one pool, they created a peptide for every set of 15 amino acids from the Spike protein, tiled such that each length-15 chain overlapped by ten amino acids with the next peptide in the pool. In another pool, they computationally predicted which peptides would be efficiently held by antigen presenting cells like macrophages, and made peptides that covered the rest of the SARS-CoV-2 proteins. A similar pool was made for the peptides predicted to be efficiently held in the MHC class I molecules that CD8+ T cells recognize.</p> <p><img height="250" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/zUoM8PrduU9w1Tw6QW9QYVvR_PE7ctTnUvJyqoBkLcEO6jqFuuZwkc97g5hStxr7hNOl4ceN3bcB4PBHx0GrHLioF1cOAWLW9-eK3K7Xk6U_rw-ZTmx9oj5FiyisoABi1VRZ7fYv" width="241"></p><p>
Scientists regularly create overlapping peptides that tile proteins of interest when studying which pieces of a protein immune cells recognize. This is a generic example showing overlap strategies from Mimotopes.com, a company that creates and sells custom peptides.
</p>
<p>
To test out the effects of these peptide pools, the researchers collected blood from patients who tested positive for COVID-19 but were not hospitalized, 20 - 35 days after symptom onset. The researchers extracted the Peripheral Mononuclear Blood Cells (PBMCs) from the blood, as these include circulating T cells and other immune cells, and then ran a series of experiments to see how the T cells responded to the peptide pools. The number of patients was small (20 patients exposed to SARS-CoV-2, and 20 unexposed controls), but even so, the results were consistent: all recovered COVID-19 patients showed evidence of a robust T cell response to SARS-CoV-2 peptides. 100% of patients had CD4+ T cells that recognized and became activated in response to peptides from the Spike pool as well as peptides from the non-Spike peptide pool. These activated cells were able to produce inflammatory cytokines (immune signaling molecules) and to quickly clone themselves. The response of the patients’ CD8+ T cells was less universal, but still robust: 70% of patients had CD8+ T cells that were activated in response to the SARS-CoV-2 peptide pools. 
</p>
<h3>Memories of infections past</h3>


<p>
What does this T cell response mean? For starters, it indicates that recovered COVID-19 patients have a stronghold of “memory” T cells— T cells that have seen SARS-CoV-2 and learned its patterns so that they are ready to respond more quickly in the future. It’s unclear whether these T cells are able to confer long-term immunity for the patients, but there is some evidence that they might: another paper published by <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-020-2550-z">Le Bert et al.</a> ran a similar set of peptide/T cell experiments, but they were able to include a set of long-recovered SARS-CoV-1 patients. They found that even after 17 years, these patients had T cells that were able to quickly respond to both SARS-CoV-1 and SARS-CoV-2 peptides, which gives us hope that T cell memory of SARS-CoV-2 will be similarly long-lived.
</p>
<p>
These cross-reactive T cells were not limited to SARS-CoV-1 patients, either. Both Grifoni et al. and Le Bert et al. used PBMCs drawn from donors without any exposure to COVID as controls, but these unexposed controls proved more interesting than the “zero baseline” we might have expected, as up to 50% of the unexposed controls showed some degree of reactivity to peptides from SARS-CoV-2, though these reactions were skewed toward the non-spike peptide pools. The researchers reason this is likely due to previous exposure to coronaviruses that cause common colds, and indeed, all unexposed controls had antibodies for two common coronaviruses, HCoV-OC43 and HCoV-NL63. If true, this cross-reactivity between common cold coronaviruses and SARS-CoV-2 could explain some of the variability in severity of COVID-19 across different people; some immune systems may already be primed to react to SARS-CoV-2 by prior infections. Further, given that the cross-reactive responses were more pronounced for non-spike proteins, this finding lends support to the idea that we should have a multi-target approach to vaccination and treatment, rather than a Spike-only approach.
</p>
<p>
(We should pause for a moment here to address a nagging question: wait, if even the unexposed controls showed responses to SARS-CoV-2 peptides, how do we know any of these responses are real? Isn’t the whole idea of a control to give a baseline to compare to? There are several reasons to believe these results are legitimate: peptide assays are fairly robust in immunological studies; the amplitude and targets of the control response are distinct from the COVID-19-exposed response; and multiple studies from multiple labs found the same results with the same peculiarities. That said, the sample size is very small, and the lack of a non-reactive control should always be concerning, so more studies in this area should be conducted before we draw any strong conclusions here.)
</p>

<p>
COVID-19-exposed cells (top row) showed a robust response to a number of SARS-CoV-2 targets, but the unexposed controls also showed some responsiveness, especially among lesser-known viral peptides.
</p>
<h3>Reading the T leaves</h3>


<p>
Taken all together, these T cell experiments demonstrate that, well, T cells matter, too. A robust immune response requires many cells, and the evidence of consistent T cell activation in recovered patients indicates that T cells play an important role in the natural clearance of the virus. It stands to reason, then, that an effective vaccination strategy will likely have to consider how and when to activate T cells. These studies identify a number of distinct peptides that activate T cells across patients, and could therefore be used along with antibodies as part of a vaccination strategy.
</p>
<h3 id="sources">Sources</h3>


<ul>

<li>Image 1: <a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Figure_42_02_04.png">https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Figure_42_02_04.png</a>

</li><li>Image 2: Product image from <a href="http://www.mimotopes.com/peptideLibraryScreening.asp?id=90">http://www.mimotopes.com/peptideLibraryScreening.asp?id=90</a> , which sells peptide services

</li><li>Image 3: Figure 6B and 6C from Grifoni et al.

</li><li><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7289747/">Vaccination strategies to combat novel corona virus SARS-CoV-2</a>

</li><li>Grifoni et al: <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0092867420306103">Targets of T Cell Responses to SARS-CoV-2 Coronavirus in Humans with COVID-19 Disease and Unexposed Individuals</a> 

</li><li>Le Bert et al: <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-020-2550-z">SARS-CoV-2-specific T cell immunity in cases of COVID-19 and SARS, and uninfected controls</a> </li></ul>
</div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.hellovirology.com/2020/08/a-t-cell-army-against-sars-cov-2.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24082327</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 14:38:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[JuliaCon2020: Julia Is Production Ready]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 185 | Comments 97 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24082281">thread link</a>) | @ViralBShah
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://bkamins.github.io/julialang/2020/08/07/production-ready.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bkamins.github.io/julialang/2020/08/07/production-ready.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    

<p>Last time I have <a href="https://bkamins.github.io/julialang/2020/08/02/post_juliacon_1.html">posted</a> about the take-aways for DataFrames.jl from
<a href="https://juliacon.org/2020/">JuliaCon 2020</a>. This time I wanted to share my general conclusions
from attending different talks at this extremely successful event.</p>

<p>I have spent 20 years now deploying data science related projects in corporate
environments (back then it was not called data science, but we were already
training neural networks to make predictions) and have many colleagues who are
deeply into enterprise software development. Quoting a discussion with
Tomasz Olczak I had some time ago, who is a genuine one-man army in
delivering complex enterprise projects:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Julia is fast, and has a very nice syntax, but its ecosystem is not mature
enough for use in serious production projects.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>For many years I would agree with it, but after <a href="https://juliacon.org/2020/">JuliaCon 2020</a>
I believe we can confidently announce that</p>

<p>
  <b><i>Julia is production ready!</i></b>
</p>

<p>Let me now give a list of key (in my opinion) presentations given during
<a href="https://juliacon.org/2020/">JuliaCon 2020</a> that make me draw this conclusion.</p>

<p>I will not comment here on functionalities related to number crunching, as it
is clear that Julia shines here, but rather I want to focus on the things that
make Julia a great tool for deployment in production (still I skip many
interesting talks in this area — check out the detailed <a href="https://live.juliacon.org/agenda/">agenda</a> to
learn more).</p>



<p>In <a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/Y3H7FG">this talk</a> <a href="https://github.com/quinnj">Jacob Quinn</a> gives an end to end tutorial how
to build and deploy in an enterprise setting a microservice using Julia.
He gives ready recipes how to solve typical tasks that need to be handled in
such contexts: logging, context management, middleware setup, authentication,
caching, connection pooling, dockerization, and many other, that
are bread and butter of enterprise projects.</p>

<p>As an addition be sure to check out:</p>

<ul>
  <li>the <a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/Z8TE39">shippable apps</a> talk, where <a href="https://github.com/KristofferC">Kristoffer Carlsson</a> guides you
through creating executables which can be run on machines that do not have Julia
installed.</li>
  <li>the <a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/N39HSX">Julia for scripting</a> presentation, during which
<a href="https://github.com/fredrikekre">Fredrik Ekre</a> discusses the best practices for using Julia in contexts
where you need to execute short code snippets many times.</li>
  <li>the <a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/DTLBM9">Genie.jl</a> talk, in which <a href="https://github.com/essenciary">Adrian Salceanu</a> shows that it is currently
a mature, stable, performant, and feature-rich Julia web development framework.</li>
</ul>



<p>The two talks <a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/PLFURQ">Pkg.update()</a> and <a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/RXAN8F">What’s new in Pkg</a> show that
currently Julia has best in class functionalities for enterprise grade dependency
management for your projects. The list of provided functionalities is so long
that it is hard to list them all here.</p>

<p>Let me just mention one particular tool in this ecosystem, that is presented in
<a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/9WMAVU">BinaryBuilder.jl</a> talk that explains how to take software written in compiled
languages such as C, C++, Fortran, Go or Rust, and build precompiled artifacts
that can be used from Julia packages with ease (which means that no compilation
has to take place on client side when you install packages having such dependencies).</p>



<p>A natural topic related to dependency management is how to integrate Julia with
external tools. This area of functionality is really mature. Here is a list of
talks that cover this topic:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/7MALUA">Make your Julia code faster and compatible with non-Julia code</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/NNVQQF">Wrapping a C++ library using CxxWrap.jl</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/XGHSWW">Julia and C++: a technical overview of CxxWrap.jl</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/Y7ERM9">Introducing the @ccall macro</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/PHGCKB">Integrating Julia in R with the JuliaConnectoR</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/Q88P8U">Integrate Julia and Javascript using Node.js extensions</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Here it is worth to add Julia has had a great integration with Python for many
years now, see <a href="https://github.com/JuliaPy">JuliaPy</a>.</p>

<p>A good end to end example of doing some real work in Julia that requires integration
is <a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/KK9S9V">Creating a multichannel wireless speaker setup with Julia</a>
talk that show how to easily stitch things together (and in particular featuring
ZMQ.jl, Opus.jl, PortAudio.jl, and DSP.jl).</p>

<p>Another interesting talk showcasing integration capabilities is
<a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/GFE3DB">JSServe: Websites &amp; Dashboards in Julia</a>
that shows a high performance framework to easily combine interactive plots,
markdown, widgets and plain HTML/Javascript in Jupyter / Atom / Nextjournal and
on websites.</p>



<p>The two great talks <a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/DWCJUK">Juno 1.0</a> and <a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/HBTFT7">Using VS Code</a> that current IDE
support for Julia in VS Code is first class. You have all tools that normally you
would expect to get: code analysis (static and dynamic), debugger, workspaces,
integration with Jupyter Notebooks, and remote capabilities.</p>



<p>I do not want to cover many different ML algorithms that are available in Julia
natively, as there are just too many of them (and if something is missing you
can easily integrate it — see the integration capabilities section above).</p>

<p>However, on top of particular models you need frameworks that let you manage
ML workflows. In this area there are two interesting talks, one about
<a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/DMHZCC">MLJ: a machine learning toolbox for Julia</a> and the other showing
<a href="https://live.juliacon.org/talk/AD7TQW">AutoMLPipeline: A ToolBox for Building ML Pipelines</a>. From my experience
such tools are crucial when you want to move with your ML models from data scientist’s
sandbox to a real production usage.</p>



<p>Obviously, I have omitted many interesting things that were shown during
<a href="https://juliacon.org/2020/">JuliaCon 2020</a>. However, I hope that the aspects I have covered here,
that is:</p>

<ul>
  <li>enterprise grade patterns to create microservices and applications in Julia,</li>
  <li>robust dependency management tools,</li>
  <li>very flexible and powerful capabilities to integrate Julia with existing code
bases that were not written in Julia,</li>
  <li>excellent developer tooling in VSCode,</li>
  <li>mature packages that help you to create production-grade code for ML solutions
deployment,</li>
</ul>

<p>show that already now Julia can (and should) be considered as a serious option
for your next project in enterprise environment.</p>

<p>What I believe is crucially important is that not only we have required tools
ready but also we have great practical showcases how they can be used to build
robust production code with.</p>


  </div>
</article>

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bkamins.github.io/julialang/2020/08/07/production-ready.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24082281</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 14:32:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Self-Contained Development Environments (2018) [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 63 | Comments 24 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24082194">thread link</a>) | @tosh
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://charig.github.io/assets/papers/SCDE-DLS.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://charig.github.io/assets/papers/SCDE-DLS.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://charig.github.io/assets/papers/SCDE-DLS.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24082194</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 14:25:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[On the Performance of User-Mode Threads and Coroutines]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 142 | Comments 52 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24081713">thread link</a>) | @carimura
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://inside.java/2020/08/07/loomperformance/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://inside.java/2020/08/07/loomperformance/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://inside.java/2020/08/07/loomperformance/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24081713</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 13:46:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I made a mechanical keyboard with 3D-printed switches]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 177 | Comments 30 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24081046">thread link</a>) | @jstanley
<br/>
August 7, 2020 | https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/stories/jesboard.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/stories/jesboard.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

<h3>I made a mechanical keyboard with 3d-printed switches</h3>
<p><i>Fri  7 August 2020</i></p>
<p><i>Tagged: <a href="https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/tags/3dprinting.html">3dprinting</a>, <a href="https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/tags/keyboard.html">keyboard</a></i></p>
<p>The keyboard is done! This is basically the result of what I've been working on for the past 2 months, which has
involved 3 iterations of testing machines, over 100 printed switches, and now finally a keyboard that I can type on.
Unfortunately it is not a very good keyboard, but you can't win them all.</p>
<p>Here's some pictures of the keyboard:</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2843"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2843"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2844"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2844"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2845"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2845"></a></p>
<p>And here's a video of me typing on it:</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/iEBbCk1WJUk" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>(In the video it is a bit wobbly because the back is propped up to take the pressure off the exposed wiring. I have subsequently printed a couple of small legs to raise up
the back of the keyboard and now it is a lot <i>less</i> wobbly, but it could still do with some soft feet).</p>
<p>I am very happy with how the keyboard looks, and also happy that I have managed to produce a working keyboard using 3d-printed switches in the first place. I believe
this may be a world first.</p>
<p>That said, I started using the jesboard to write this blog post, and it was too annoying to type on so I went back to the Filco. Spending some time typing
on my homemade switches has given me a newfound appreciation for just how good Cherry MX switches are. I'm not sure what it is that makes the
jesboard so unpleasant to type on, there's just a general vagueness to it that makes typing frustrating. Pressing a single key up and down feels basically fine, which is why I hadn't
noticed this problem while developing the switches. But trying to use it as an actual keyboard, and type at a sensible speed, just feels <i>really</i> bad. It
is genuinely the worst keyboard I have ever used. So that's disappointing.</p>
<p>I think to improve upon this you'd probably want to reduce the activation force (that's easy, just make the spring thinner) and add some tactile feedback so it is easier to tell
when the switch has actually been pressed. Beyond that, I'm not sure.</p>
<h2>Switches</h2>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2841"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2841"></a></p>
<p>If you want to learn more about the switches, I would recommend looking at some of my other <a href="https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/tags/keyboard.html">posts tagged "keyboard"</a>, but in short:
pressing on the stem at the top compresses the spiral spring (I copied the spring design from <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCSsm4h2ccJMdR6bsAFyIu6A">Riskable 3D Printing</a>, he
is also developing 3d-printable keyboard switches, but using magnet sensors instead of making mechanical switches himself). Once
the stem is pressed down far enough, a contact wire bridges the 2 contacts at the bottom, activating the switch. As the switch is pressed further, the leaf spring compresses, allowing
the stem to move further down while allowing the contact wire to remain in place. Eventually the spiral spring bottoms out against its casing and then stem movement stops. When the key is released,
the spiral spring pushes everything back up to the top.</p>
<p>The leaf spring has a section in its bend that is narrow in the "other" axis, to allow it easily tilt side-to-side to ensure good contact with both of the contact wires.</p>
<p>I don't have a good photo of the latest switch design, but I have this of an earlier version:</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2757"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2757"></a></p>
<p>The working principle is the same but the new version is a bit shorter.</p>
<p>The switches are printed in PETG. If you want to see them in action, you might enjoy my <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hRBQBf6jzFM">video of operating the switch tester</a>.
The final incarnation of the switch design lasted over 350k presses in all cases, and some instances still hadn't failed at 500k presses. This is a lot lower than the "tens of millions" that might be
expected of a commercial switch, but it's a big improvement over <a href="https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/stories/keyswitch-failure.html">13907</a> which is where the first iteration failed, and that was on an extremely
gentle machine.</p>
<p>I said I was going to experiment with moving the activation point down to 75% of the plunger travel so as to reduce the strain on
the leaf spring. I did test this on the <a href="https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/stories/another-new-tester.html">new machine</a>, with 5 of the old design and 5 of the new design side-by-side, and the new design lasted almost
twice as long, so that was a good improvement.</p>
<p>The gold-plated "jewellery wire" that I bought off eBay ended up working well and soldering well (so I conclude it was not varnished),
and 4 metres (costing £4) was <i>just</i> enough to do the entire keyboard.</p>
<p>If you want, you can <a href="https://incoherency.co.uk/interest/3dpswitch.tar.gz">download the switch CAD</a>, including STL and FreeCAD files.</p>
<h2>Case</h2>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2805"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2805"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2804"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2804"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2832"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2832"></a></p>
<p>The case is split into 2 halves that are then glued together, so that it fits on the bed of the 3D printer. There is a large rectangular hole at the top and bottom in each half, and a long bit of plastic
inside joining them, to add a bit more strength to the joint. There's not a lot to the case design really, it is just a shape to fit the switches into,
with a bulge at the top to house the microcontroller, an exit hole for the cable, stabiliser mounts, and a cool-looking logo. I made the general shape of the case halves in FreeCAD, and then imported the resulting STL
into OpenSCAD to cut out the holes for the switches, because I found it easier to get the layout correct with code.</p>
<p>I printed the logo in a different colour by having the printer stop and wait for me to change the filament at the layer height where the colour changes, using the
<a href="https://marlinfw.org/docs/gcode/M600.html">M600</a> G-code command. PrusaSlicer has a nice GUI for setting this up, so I didn't even need to manually edit the G-code.</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2846"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2846"></a></p>
<p>If I were to make another keyboard, I would give myself more space to work with underneath by reducing the thickness of the "solid" middle part that the switches are mounted in.
I found that there was not really enough room to run the diodes and wires. I would also add provision for a few screws to attach a bottom cover to protect the wiring inside.</p>
<p>The case and keycaps are printed in Prusament Galaxy Black PLA, which I think gives a really nice finish.</p>
<h2>Keycaps</h2>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2848"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2848"></a></p>
<p>The keycaps were designed using <a href="https://github.com/rsheldiii/KeyV2">KeyV2</a>, a free parametric keycap library for OpenSCAD. If you want to design
some keycaps, you should check out KeyV2. Its creator, <a href="https://github.com/rsheldiii">Bob</a>, is friendly and gave me helpful advice and assistance.</p>
<p>There are several different ways to make an ISO (UK-style) enter key in KeyV2, but I couldn't find any combination of settings that would let me have rounded corners, sloping top,
and dished top, so I ended up making the enter key by hand in FreeCAD.</p>
<p>I was originally going to use "outset" legends on the keycaps, like I used on the <a href="https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/stories/3pct-keyboard.html">macro keypad</a>. But I read this comment in the KeyV2 source
which changed my mind, so I used inset legends instead:</p>
<pre><code>// make legends outset instead of inset.
// broken off from artisan support since who wants outset legends?
$outset_legends = false;</code></pre>
<p>But having printed all the keycaps, I'm not sure whether I think inset legends actually <i>are</i> better. They range from "perfectly fine" to "almost invisible" depending on the lighting. I'd
say the outset legends were easier to read.</p>
<h2>Wiring</h2>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2836"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2836"></a></p>
<p>The switches are hand-wired in a 15x5 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keyboard_matrix_circuit">keyboard matrix</a>, with diodes allowing current to pass only in one direction. 14x5 would be enough
if you thought about it a bit more than I did, but 15x5 is fine.</p>
<p>Originally I was planning to use an Arduino for the microcontroller, which has only 16 IO pins. This would allow for an 8x8 matrix, but when I went to layout the wiring, I came up with this, where
red is columns and green is rows:</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2824"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2824"></a></p>
<p>Obviously this is too complicated to wire up in real life, particularly in the small amount of space provided in the bottom of my case. You may also notice it was too complicated for me to
lay out in GIMP, as I have failed to connect the full-stop and apostophe keys to any row. For these reasons I decided to use a <a href="https://www.pjrc.com/teensy/">Teensy</a> 2.0 instead, which allowed me to use a more sensible matrix layout:</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2835"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2835"></a></p>
<p>(I laid this out on <a href="https://kbfirmware.com/">kbfirmware.com</a>).</p>
<p>The other part of the wiring is that the USB cable has to reach the microcontroller. I left a 4mm hole in the side of the case for the cable to run through, but this is too small for the connector
on the end. I was originally planning to cut the connector off and solder the wires directly to the USB pads on the micocontroller board, but they were too small and annoying to access, so instead
I just soldered the MiniUSB end back on and plugged it in. It's a tight fit but it does the job.</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2847"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2847"></a></p>
<p>In hindsight, I am not sure whether I regret hand-wiring the keyboard. I toyed with the idea of getting a PCB made up that I could directly solder my switches to. It would certainly have
made it easier to put the keyboard together, but I thought outsourcing the manufacturing of a PCB kind of takes the edge off making your own switches...</p>
<h2>Stabilisers</h2>
<p>Here's a clip showing how the stabilisers work:</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ZTvDP3Qutwk" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The idea is that when you press down on one side you cause the bar to rotate, which then pulls down on the other side of the switch, forcing the key to move down parallel (instead of rocking)
and activate the switch properly. The bar is made of 1.75mm stainless steel wire bent into a suitable shape. Thick stainless wire is quite hard to cut, but doable with a big-ish pair of nippers.</p>
<p>While trying to fit the stabilisers for the spacebar, I managed to break off the mounts attached to the case. This is bad news because the case halves are about a 10-hour print each, and aside from
that I had already soldered up all of the switches. To reprint the case halves would involve undoing all of my soldering work, and then 20 hours of printing, and then redoing all of the soldering.</p>
<p>I wasn't interested in redoing all of that work, so as a last resort I drilled a hole into the case in the position of each stabiliser mount, and printed 2 new stabiliser mounts, long enough to fit
in the holes. I printed the mounts in PETG so that they'd be less likely to break.</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2842"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2842"></a></p>
<p>This worked really well, disaster averted! The mounts were a tight fit in the drilled holes so I didn't even need to use any glue.</p>
<h2>QMK</h2>
<p>I used <a href="https://qmk.fm/">QMK</a> for the keyboard firmware, running on a Teensy 2.0. I found it quite hard to get started with my custom keyboard, because almost all of the documentation
is geared towards the case where you are using an off-the-shelf keyboard which is already defined in QMK. The key point I needed to know was that you can use the script "<tt>./util/new_keyboard.s…</tt></p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/stories/jesboard.html">https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/stories/jesboard.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/stories/jesboard.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24081046</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 12:17:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pocket P.C. Open Sourced]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 81 | Comments 33 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24078853">thread link</a>) | @nullagent
<br/>
August 6, 2020 | https://blog.popcorncomputer.com/2020/08/05/pocket-p-c-open-sourced/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.popcorncomputer.com/2020/08/05/pocket-p-c-open-sourced/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-content" role="main">

	
<article id="post-194">

	
<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>

		<div>

			
<div><figure><img src="https://opensource.popcorncomputer.com/community/bottom-2lyr-pcb-twitter-resolution-scaled.jpg" alt=""></figure></div>



<p>If you would like to follow along with the latest design or would like to dive deep into the internals of <a href="https://pocket.popcorncomputer.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pocket P.C.</a> we have created a repository on <a href="https://github.com/PopcornComputer/PocketPC-Hardware" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GitHub</a> for the latest hardware files. The work is licensed under a <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/us/">Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 United States License</a>.</p>



<p>&nbsp; Click the GitHub image below to check out the latest files.</p>



<figure><a href="https://github.com/PopcornComputer/PocketPC-Hardware" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://opensource.popcorncomputer.com/blog/GitHub_PocketPC.png" alt="GitHub Repository Badge"></a></figure>



<h3><strong>We are one step closer to shipping Pocket P.C. with the latest developments.</strong></h3>



<p>The latest D.V.T PCB design is out for production. We expect the PCBs to arrive within 10-12 days.&nbsp; After that, we will be assembling 25 units.</p>



<p>The D.V.T. design brings with it a newly added SPI Flash which will allow <a href="https://pocket.popcorncomputer.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pocket P.C. </a>to more easily boot multiple operating systems on the same <a href="https://pocket.popcorncomputer.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pocket P.C.</a> We also changed the design to a 10-layer PCB stackup vs. 8-layers which will ensure better signal integrity for high-speed signals.</p>



<p>The keyboard layout has been tweaked incorporating feedback from community suggestions and from hands-on the 3D printed prototypes. Thank you to everyone who submitted feedback about our initial layout. The space bar has been extended to allow for it to be pressed from a comfortable hand position and a few other minor changes. You can view the latest layout in our community keyboard thread here: <a href="https://community.popcorncomputer.com/t/pocket-p-c-keyboard-layout-part-2/541" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pocket P.C. Keyboard Layout (Part 2)</a></p>



<p>We learned a lot from the last production run of Original Popcorn. We did not receive the level of support that we were promised from the USB-C IC manufacturer that we chose to handle the USB Power Delivery system. As such, we changed the <a href="https://pocket.popcorncomputer.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pocket P.C.</a> design to incorporate a robust Texas Instruments single-chip solution. With this new solution, we added to the design dedicated port protector ICs with ESD protection and surge protection ICs also from Texas Instruments on every ports. This will make the design more robust to faulty power conditions.</p>



<p>Finally, to ensure that <a href="https://pocket.popcorncomputer.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pocket P.C. </a>has great software support out of the box, we have requested embedded development help from the community. Our goal is to ensure that we get all aspects of our products mainlined so that custom kernels will not be required. In order to accomplish this, a community effort is required to review and test new solutions before submitting them to the Linux Kernel mailing list. If you are interested in following with our development efforts you can join the discussion here: <a href="https://community.popcorncomputer.com/t/embedded-linux-development-help-requested/559/15" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Embedded Linux Development Help Requested</a></p>



<figure><img src="https://opensource.popcorncomputer.com/community/top-2lyr-pcb-twitter-resolution-scaled.jpg" alt=""></figure>



<h3>Visit the shop to pre-order your Pocket P.C. today!</h3>



<h4><a href="https://shop.popcorncomputer.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Pre-order Now</strong></a></h4>



<h3>Keep up to date on the latest developments in our community.</h3>



<p>In an effort to be more transparent with the latest on-goings with development and production, we have created a community thread where we will post updates as they happen.</p>



<h4><a href="https://community.popcorncomputer.com/t/pocket-p-c-development-updates/552" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Community Website</strong></a></h4>





		</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	</div><!-- .post-inner -->

	<!-- .section-inner -->

	
	<!-- .pagination-single -->

	
		<!-- .comments-wrapper -->

		
</article><!-- .post -->

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.popcorncomputer.com/2020/08/05/pocket-p-c-open-sourced/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24078853</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 06:04:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
