<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 08:23:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 08:23:53 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why I Link to WayBackMachine Instead of Original Web Content]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 137 | Comments 82 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24406193">thread link</a>) | @puggo
<br/>
September 8, 2020 | https://hawaiigentech.com/post/commentary/why-i-link-to-waybackmachine-instead/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://hawaiigentech.com/post/commentary/why-i-link-to-waybackmachine-instead/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main">
      <div>
        <div id="content">
          <article>
    
    

    
    <div>
      <p><img src="https://hawaiigentech.com/post/commentary/why-i-link-to-waybackmachine-instead/wayback.jpg" alt="WayBackMachine"></p>
<hr>
<p>When linking to a page for the <strong>purpose of reference</strong>, it seems better to me to <em><strong>link to the <a href="https://archive.org/">archive</a> of a given page</strong></em>, rather than to the original site itself.</p>
<p>This ensures that after some years have gone by, <strong>my article is guaranteed to be consistent</strong>. Due the  changing nature of the web, there is a chance that after some years, the link could lead to a:</p>
<ul>
<li>404 /  Not Found (most common)</li>
<li>Changed or edited content, or entirely replaced content</li>
<li>Content that, due to a rise in popularity, is now shielded, demanding the user to make an account to read the entire article.</li>
</ul>
<hr>

<p>Take defensive measures. To future-proof your content, rather than reference the general web, its far more reliable to link to an archive.</p>
<h2 id="example">Example:</h2>
<p>The Epoch Times wrote an article on Smartphones data-mining their users. This is the archived article here:</p>
<p><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20190214015500/https://www.theepochtimes.com/smartphone-app-users-are-data-mined-even-when-not-using-the-apps_2787202.html">The Archive Version (fully readable)</a></p>
<h3 id="article-content-before">Article Content Before</h3>
<p>You can see its perfectly “normal” readable useful  content.</p>
<p><img src="https://hawaiigentech.com/post/commentary/why-i-link-to-waybackmachine-instead/link-content-before.png" alt="Article Link Content Before"></p>
<h3 id="article-content-after">Article Content After</h3>
<p>Now it’s spam from a site suffering financial need.</p>
<p><img src="https://hawaiigentech.com/post/commentary/why-i-link-to-waybackmachine-instead/link-content-after.png" alt="Article Link Content Before"></p>
<p>So in Feb 14 2019 your users would have seen the content you intended. However in Sep 07 2020, your users are being asked to support independent Journalism instead.</p>
<h2 id="if-an-archive-record-doesnt-exist-make-one">If an Archive Record Doesn't Exist, Make One</h2>
<p>Its worth the extra moment, in referencing a site, to make an archive of the page you wish to reference, if one does not exist. After that, immediately use the link from the archive.org entry, rather than the blog, news, info, or forum site you wish to refer to.</p>
<h2 id="in-unstable-times-take-measures-for-stability">In Unstable Times, Take Measures for Stability</h2>
<p>The web is a fast changing place. Even more during the Covid pandemic and suffering financial markets. Since times are financially harder, websites are disappearing, heaping up advertising, demanding user response, and things like this.</p>
<p>To avoid your content losing quality due to these things, linking to a solid, unchanging static copy of the page is far more reliable.</p>

    </div>

    <div>
  <p>
    <span>Author</span>
    <span>Leo Blanchette</span>
  </p>
  <p>
    <span>LastMod</span>
    <span>
        2020-09-07
        
    </span>
  </p>
  
  
</div>

  </article>
        </div>
        

  

  

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://hawaiigentech.com/post/commentary/why-i-link-to-waybackmachine-instead/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24406193</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 08:03:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[URL query parameters and how laxness creates de facto requirements on the web]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 60 | Comments 46 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24404814">thread link</a>) | @oftenwrong
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/web/DeFactoQueryParameters | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/web/DeFactoQueryParameters">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2>URL query parameters and how laxness creates de facto requirements on the web</h2>

	<p><small>September  7, 2020</small></p>
</div><div><p>One of the ways that <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/dwiki/DWiki">DWiki</a> (the code behind <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/">Wandering Thoughts</a>) is unusual is that it strictly validates the query parameters
it receives on URLs, including on HTTP <code>GET</code> requests for ordinary
pages. If a HTTP request has unexpected and unsupported query
parameters, such a <code>GET</code> request will normally fail. When I made
this decision it seemed the cautious and conservative approach, but
<a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/web/CautionIsAMistakeToday">this caution has turned out to be a mistake on the modern web</a>. In practice, all sorts of sites will
generate versions of your URLs with all sorts of extra query
parameters tacked on, give them to people, and expect them to work.
If your website refuses to play along, (some) people won't get to
see your content. <strong>On today's web, you need to accept (and then
ignore) arbitrary query parameters on your URLs</strong>.</p>

<p>(Today's new query parameter is 's=NN', for various values of NN
like '04' and '09'. I'm not sure what's generating these URLs, but
it may be Slack.)</p>

<p>You might wonder how we got here, and that is a story of lax behavior
(or, if you prefer, being liberal in what you accept). In the
beginning, both Apache (for static web pages) and early web
applications often ignored extra query parameters on URLs, at least
on <code>GET</code> requests. I suspect that other early web servers also
imitated Apache here, but I have less exposure to their behavior
than Apache's. My guess is that this behavior wasn't deliberate,
it was just the simplest way to implement both Apache and early
web applications; you paid attention to what you cared about and
didn't bother to explicitly check that nothing else was supplied.</p>

<p>When people noticed that this behavior was commonplace and widespread,
they began using it. I believe that one of the early uses was for
embedding 'where this link was shared' information for your own web
analytics (<a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/web/AnalyticsVsSecurity">cf</a>), either based on your logs
or using JavaScript embedded in the page. In the way of things,
once this was common enough other people began helpfully tagging
the links that were shared through them for you, which is why I
began to see various 'utm_*' query parameters on inbound
requests to <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/">Wandering Thoughts</a> even though I never
published such URLs.
Web developers don't leave attractive nuisances alone for long, so
soon enough people were sticking on extra query parameters to your
URLs that were mostly for them and not so much for you. Facebook
may have been one of the early pioneers here with their 'fbclid'
parameter, but other websites have hopped on this particular train
since then (as I saw recently with these 's=NN' parameters).</p>

<p>At this point, the practice of other websites and services adding
random query parameters to your URLs that pass through them is so
wide spread and common that accepting random query parameters is
pretty much a practical requirement for any web content serving
software that wants to see wide use and not be irritating to the
people operating it. If, like <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/dwiki/DWiki">DWiki</a>, you stick to your guns and
refuse to accept some or all of them, you will drop some amount of
your incoming requests from real people, disappointing would be
readers.</p>

<p>This practical requirement for URL handling is not documented in
any specification, and it's probably not in most 'best practices'
documentation. People writing new web serving systems that are
tempted to be strict and safe and cautious get to learn about it
the hard way.</p>

<p>In general, any laxness in actual implementations of a system can
create a similar spiral of de facto requirements. Something that
is permitted and is useful to people will be used, and then supporting
that becomes a requirement. This is especially the case in a
distributed system like the web, where any attempt to tighten the
rules would only be initially supported by a minority of websites.
These websites would be 'outvoted' by the vast majority of websites
that allow the lax behavior and support it, because that's what
happens when the vast majority work and the minority don't.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/web/DeFactoQueryParameters</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24404814</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 02:50:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Optimize Onboarding]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 126 | Comments 43 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24402419">thread link</a>) | @tekdude
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | https://staysaasy.com/management/2020/08/28/Optimize-Onboarding.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://staysaasy.com/management/2020/08/28/Optimize-Onboarding.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p>It takes roughly 2 weeks to form a habit; it takes roughly two weeks to get comfortable in a new environment. A common mistake is to treat a new report’s first couple weeks like college orientation - social, light hearted, get-to-know-you stuff. If your report spends the first two weeks reading C# documentation and having lunch out on the town with the team, guess what, they’ve just normalized that behavior as what the role is.</p>

<p>The answer: start your report doing real work as soon as possible. If they’re a software engineer, they should be committing code week one (ideally day 2 or 3); If they’re a product manager, they should be attending meetings and picking up supporting activities on a similar time frame. Then the tone has been set - working here means getting things done.</p>

<p>This means as manager you need to give your report tractable work in the first week. Managers not being ready for a report to start is the number one reason people end up normalizing underperformance, because they had nothing meaningful to do. If a manager describes a report as not having initiative in the first couple weeks it’s a red flag - it’s the manager’s job to provide new hires with clear paths to contribute immediately.</p>

<p>Another main reason people fall into onboarding traps is because your organization has painfully slow onboarding. Endless HR videos, slow security processes, a mountain of fragile technology setup - these all make for a shitty and counterproductive start at a company. Optimize your onboarding to get people doing what you hired them to do. Look to formalize performance indicators of your onboarding. For example, for engineers this could be time-to-first-commit and time-to-joining-sprints.</p>

<p>This approach holds for managers and executives as well. In that cohort it’s also common and a common red flag for people to spend the first couple weeks putzing around under the guise of “getting to know what’s going on”. Managers and executives should be involved in the decisions of the team from day 1 and developing artifacts - plans, TODO lists, strategy documents - in the first couple weeks. With good managers and executives you see them day 1 adding perspective and insight into conversations, and everyone collectively appreciates that the right person has been hired.</p>

<p>Onboarding is one of the most critical periods in a person’s time at a company. It’s one of the highest ROI periods when managing someone. Take that opportunity to set expectations properly and measure success quantiatively.</p>


    




  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://staysaasy.com/management/2020/08/28/Optimize-Onboarding.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24402419</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 20:18:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Doom Eternal – Graphics Study]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 127 | Comments 32 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24401805">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | https://www.simoncoenen.com/blog/programming/graphics/DoomEternalStudy.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.simoncoenen.com/blog/programming/graphics/DoomEternalStudy.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="markdown-content">
            


<p>30 Aug 2020 - Simon Coenen - Reading time: <span title="Estimated read time">
  
  
    23 mins
  
</span><span></span> - <a href="#comment-section">Comments</a>
</p>
<p><img src="https://www.simoncoenen.com/images/blog/010_doom_eternal_study/image1.jpeg" alt=""></p>

<h2 id="background">Background</h2>

<p>Doom Eternal is the successor of Doom 2016. It’s developed using the 7th iteration of id Tech, id Software’s in-house game engine. Doom 2016 has inspired me greatly on a technologic level due to its simplicity and elegance while still having a high visual quality. For Doom Eternal, this is no different. Doom Eternal has improved in many areas of which a few are worth investigating which I will try to cover in this frame breakdown.</p>

<!--more-->

<p>This frame breakdown is inspired by <a href="http://www.adriancourreges.com/blog/2016/09/09/doom-2016-graphics-study/">Adrian Courreges’s study on Doom 2016</a>. I believe these graphics studies give a lot of insight into how certain rendering problems are solved in a AAA game and are greatly educational. In this breakdown I aim to stay at a high level and not go too in-depth of each rendering technique/pass. Some passes might not be covered here because they are very similar to Doom 2016 and are well covered in Adrian Courreges’s study.</p>

<p>I do want to stress here that these studies are absolutely nothing more than <strong>educational</strong>. I do not in any way support the reverse engineering for malicious purposes and stealing intellectual property. If you haven’t played the game yet, don’t worry about spoilers! The section I used for this study is in the beginning of the game which doesn’t give away any of the details.</p>

<p>Now, let’s get down to business.</p>

<p>With Id Tech 7, the engine has moved away from OpenGL and is entirely built with a <strong>Vulkan</strong> backend allowing them to make better use of current generation GPU features, bindless resources in particular.</p>

<hr>



<p><img src="https://www.simoncoenen.com/images/blog/010_doom_eternal_study/image2.png" alt=""></p>

<p>We’re looking at a section in the game close to the start. It’s an interior with a few enemies and a large portion of volumetric lighting. Just like its predecessor, Doom Eternal is using a <strong>forward rendering</strong> pipeline. Doom 2016 was mostly forward rendered with a thin G-Buffer for screen space reflections. However this time, everything is fully forward rendered omitting the G-Buffer.</p>

<hr>

<h2 id="step-away-from-mega-texture">Step away from Mega-Texture</h2>

<p>With id Tech 5 used in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rage_(video_game)">Rage</a>, there was a texture streaming concept introduced called ‘Mega-Texture’ which was also used in the previous Doom installment. This system works by rendering a so called ‘feedback texture’ each frame that contains the information of what texture data was visible, that texture is analysed next frame to determine which textures get streamed in from disk. This has an obvious flaw because once a texture is on screen, it’s basically already too late to load it and this causes blurry textures the first few frames it is on screen. In id Tech 7, id Software has stepped away from this approach.</p>

<hr>

<h2 id="gpu-skinning">GPU Skinning</h2>

<p>The first thing that happens even before anything gets drawn to a texture, is evaluating skinning. This is commonly done in a vertex shader before shading. An alternative approach used here, is to do skinning beforehand in a compute shader which writes out skinned vertices to a buffer. This has a couple of advantages mainly not having to do skinning in the vertex shader for every geometry pass. This results in having less shader permutations because the vertex shader doesn’t have to know about skinning.</p>

<p>Skinning in a compute shader is not much different from in a vertex shader except that the output gets written to an intermediate buffer which can then be consumed in a vertex shader that can treat it as a regular static mesh. Just like in a vertex shader, for each vertex, a compute shader thread retrieves the transform of each bone affecting the vertex, transforms its position with each bone transform and adds up these positions based on the skin weights stored on the vertex.</p>

<p>János Turánszki wrote a wonderful write-up of how it can be implemented using a compute shader:
<a href="https://wickedengine.net/2017/09/09/skinning-in-compute-shader/">https://wickedengine.net/2017/09/09/skinning-in-compute-shader/</a>.</p>

<p>Another thing that is worth noting here is the use of <strong>Alembic Caches</strong> in Doom Eternal. These caches contain baked animation which get streamed and decompressed at runtime. As <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UsmqWSZpgJY">Digital Foundry described in their tech breakdown</a>, this is used for a wide range of animations going from large cinematic pieces to small tentacles on the floor. This is especially useful for animations that are hard to achieve using skinned animation like organics and cloth simulation. You can compare an Alembic Cache with a video that can be played back and is highly compressed by looking ahead. I suggest watching <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zlz-7V_XiUA">Axel Gneiting’s talk at Siggraph 2014</a> if you’re interested in learning more.</p>

<hr>

<h2 id="shadow-mapping">Shadow Mapping</h2>

<p>Next up is shadow rendering. There doesn’t seem to be any large changes in how shadow maps are approached in id Tech 7 compared to its predecessor.</p>

<p>As seen below, shadows get rendered in a large 4096x8196px 24-bit depth texture which may vary across quality levels. The texture is persistent across frames and as described in “Devil is in the Details” at Siggraph 2016, the static geometry in the shadow map is cached to save having to redraw the shadow maps each frame. The technique is fairly simple: as long as nothing in the view of the light moves, there is no need to update the shadows. If a dynamic object in the frustum moves, a ‘cached’ shadow map is copied into the actual shadow map and the dynamic geometry is re-drawn on top. This cached shadow map is the same shadow map but only with static geometry because you can make the assumption that these will never change. This saves having to draw the entire scene in the frustum every time it needs to update. Of course, when the light moves, the entire scene has to be redrawn from scratch.</p>

<p>When sampling the shadow map during lighting, a 3x3 PCF sampling approach is used to smoothen the shadow edges. For the sun light, <strong>cascaded shadow maps</strong> are used to distribute the quality better as it covers such a large portion of the environment.</p>

<p>Here is a closer look at the shadow atlas. A light with higher importance, larger screen area or that is closer to the camera, will get a larger portion of the atlas assigned for better resolution. These heuristics are evaluated dynamically.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.simoncoenen.com/images/blog/010_doom_eternal_study/image3.jpeg" alt=""></p>

<hr>

<h2 id="depth-pre-pass-and-velocity">Depth Pre-pass and Velocity</h2>

<p>Opaque geometry gets rendered to a depth-only target starting with the player’s gun, then static geometry, and finally dynamic geometry. A depth pre-pass is common to avoid unnecessary pixel shader calculations later down the pipeline where geometry overlaps. A depth pre-pass is especially important in a forward renderer where redundant pixel calculations are extremely wasteful due to pixel overdraw. With a depth pre-pass, the actual forward lighting pixel shader can reject pixels by comparing with the depth buffer before execution, saving a lot of performance.</p>

<div id="prepassCarousel" data-ride="carousel">
  <ol>
    <li data-target="#prepassCarousel" data-slide-to="0"></li>
    <li data-target="#prepassCarousel" data-slide-to="1"></li>
    <li data-target="#prepassCarousel" data-slide-to="2"></li>
  </ol>
  <div>
    <div>
      <p><img src="https://www.simoncoenen.com/images/blog/010_doom_eternal_study/Prepass0.png"></p><p>First person gun</p>
    </div>
    <div>
      <p><img src="https://www.simoncoenen.com/images/blog/010_doom_eternal_study/Prepass1.png"></p><p>Static objects</p>
    </div>
    <div>
      <p><img src="https://www.simoncoenen.com/images/blog/010_doom_eternal_study/Prepass2.png"></p><p>Dynamic objects</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  <p><a href="#prepassCarousel" role="button" data-slide="prev">
    
    <span>Previous</span>
  </a>
  <a href="#prepassCarousel" role="button" data-slide="next">
    
    <span>Next</span>
  </a>
</p></div>

<p>Besides rendering depth, the pre-pass also renders to another color target. For dynamic geometry, the velocity is rendered using motion vectors which is the position of the current position subtracted from the position of the pixel in the previous frame. We only need the motion on the X and Y axis so the motion is stored in the red and green channel of a 16-bit floating point render target. This information is later used in post processing for applying motion blur and reprojection for temporal anti-aliasing. The image below is exaggerated because this snapshot doesn’t have a lot of motion. Static geometry does not need motion vectors as their motion can be derived from the camera motion because they have only “moved” relative to the camera.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.simoncoenen.com/images/blog/010_doom_eternal_study/image6.jpeg" alt=""></p>

<hr>

<h2 id="hierarchical-z-depth">Hierarchical-Z Depth</h2>

<p>Next up, a hierarchical mip chain of the depth buffer is generated which is similar to a mip map but instead of averaging 4 neighboring pixels, the maximum is taken. This is commonly done in graphics for various purposes like accelerating screen space reflections and occlusion culling. In this case, this mip chain is used to accelerate the light and decal culling which is covered later. More recently, mip generation is done in a single pass by writing into multiple mips at once. In Doom Eternal, it still traditionally does a dispatch for every mip separately.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.simoncoenen.com/images/blog/010_doom_eternal_study/image7.gif" alt=""></p>

<hr>

<h2 id="mesh-decals">Mesh Decals</h2>

<p>Up until what I’ve covered so far, there haven’t been many noticeable changes compared to Doom 2016. However, “mesh decals” is an addition to the mesh rendering pipeline introduced in Doom Eternal. Unlike the common decal workflow - which are placed freely in the environment - a mesh decal is placed during the mesh authoring pipeline by artists and so belong to the mesh. Before, Doom heavily relied on decals and stepped it up with the addition of so called “mesh decals” in this game for even better detailing and flexibility. “Mesh decals” are small decals like bolts, grills, bumps, stickers, … Just like a traditional decal, it can modify any property of the underlying surface like the normal, roughness, base color, …</p>

<p>To achieve this, the following geometry pass renders each of the decals’s ID into an 8-bit render target. Later during shading, this texture is sampled to retrieve the ID which is used to retrieve a projection matrix bound with each draw call. The matrix projects the pixel’s position from world space into texture space. These coordinates are then used to sample the decal and blend with the underlying material. This is extremely fast and allows artists to go crazy with massive amounts of decals. Because the IDs are rendered to an 8-bit texture, the maximum amount of decals per mesh would theoretically be 255.</p>

<p>One requirement for this, is that all decals are bound to the pipeline when drawing meshes. Doom Eternal uses a fully bindless render pipeline which allows them to bind all decal textures at once and dynamically index them in the shader. More on this bindless pipeline later as this is important to pull off other tricks they’ve done in this game.</p>

<p>Below, the mesh decal texture. The different IDs are coloured to visualize it better.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.simoncoenen.com/images/blog/010_doom_eternal_study/image8.jpeg" alt=""></p>

<hr>

<h2 id="light-and-decal-culling">Light and …</h2></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.simoncoenen.com/blog/programming/graphics/DoomEternalStudy.html">https://www.simoncoenen.com/blog/programming/graphics/DoomEternalStudy.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.simoncoenen.com/blog/programming/graphics/DoomEternalStudy.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24401805</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 19:10:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Named Parameters in C++20]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 83 | Comments 75 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24398756">thread link</a>) | @ibobev
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | https://pdimov.github.io/blog/2020/09/07/named-parameters-in-c20/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://pdimov.github.io/blog/2020/09/07/named-parameters-in-c20/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <div>
  
  <p><span>07 Sep 2020</span></p><p>A programming language supports <em>named parameters</em> when one
can call a function supplying the parameters by name, as in
the following hypothetical example (using C++ syntax):</p>

<div><div><pre><code>void f( int x, int y );

int main()
{
    f( x = 1, y = 2 );
}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>C++ is obviously not such a language and there have been
numerous proposals to rectify this omission, unfortunately none
of them successful. The latest attempt is Axel Naumann’s paper
<a href="http://www.open-std.org/jtc1/sc22/wg21/docs/papers/2018/p0671r2.html">Self-explanatory Function Arguments</a>,
which tries to attack the problem from another angle by just
allowing normal function calls to be tagged with the parameter
name, as in</p>



<p>enabling compilers to issue helpful warnings when a name doesn’t
match, but not allowing one to omit, or reorder, arguments.</p>

<p>Even in this limited form, named parameters would still be immensely
useful, but this is not what this post is about. What this post is
about is that we can already achieve something very close to named
parameters in C++20, by using a C99 feature called <em>designated
initializers</em>.</p>

<p>Designated initializers allow one to initialize structures by
member name, as in the following example:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>struct A
{
    int x;
    int y;
};

A a1 = { .x = 1, .y = 2 };
A a2 = { .x = 3 }; // a2.y == 0
A a3 = { .y = 4 }; // a3.x == 0
A a4 = { .y = 5, .x = 6 }; // valid C, invalid C++ (reorder)
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>C++ introduces a restriction C doesn’t have: the initializers
must follow the declaration order, similarly to how class member
initalizers are executed in member declaration order. But in
exchange, it allows us to supply default values:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>struct A
{
    int x = 0;
    int y = 0;
};

A a3 = { .y = 4 }; // a3.x == 0, no warning
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>You can already see where this is going. Instead of</p>



<p>we declare</p>



<p>and then call it like this:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>int main()
{
    f({ .x = 1, .y = 2 });
}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This works under <a href="https://godbolt.org/z/YfWj3W">GCC</a> and
<a href="https://godbolt.org/z/vbnz4T">Clang</a> even without <code>-std=c++20</code> because
they support designated initializers in earlier language modes as
an extension, and it works under <a href="https://godbolt.org/z/bKozaW">MSVC</a>
with <code>-std:c++latest</code>.</p>

<p>For a more realistic example, consider this snippet, taken from real
code, that sets a 10 second
<a href="https://www.boost.org/doc/libs/1_74_0/libs/beast/doc/html/beast/using_websocket/timeouts.html">timeout</a>
on a <a href="https://boost.org/libs/beast">Boost.Beast</a> websocket:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>#include &lt;boost/beast/websocket/stream.hpp&gt;
#include &lt;boost/beast/core/tcp_stream.hpp&gt;
#include &lt;chrono&gt;

void f1(boost::beast::websocket::stream&lt;boost::beast::tcp_stream&gt;&amp; ws)
{
    auto opt = boost::beast::websocket::stream_base::timeout();

    opt.keep_alive_pings = true;
    opt.idle_timeout = std::chrono::seconds(10);

    ws.set_option(opt);
}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Here’s how we can reformulate it by using the above idiom and <code>&lt;chrono&gt;</code>
literals:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>#include &lt;boost/beast/websocket/stream.hpp&gt;
#include &lt;boost/beast/core/tcp_stream.hpp&gt;
#include &lt;chrono&gt;

using namespace std::chrono_literals;

void f2(boost::beast::websocket::stream&lt;boost::beast::tcp_stream&gt;&amp; ws)
{
    ws.set_option({ .idle_timeout = 10s, .keep_alive_pings = true });
}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Apart from the slightly awkward <code>({ ... })</code> syntax and the need to observe
the right parameter order, that’s not that far from the ideal; and it’s
considerably better than <code>f1</code>.</p>

<p>This also works for constructors. Consider this hypothetical <code>vector</code> class
that is like <code>std::vector</code>, except with its various constructor overloads
replaced with one taking named parameters:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>template&lt;class T, class A = std::allocator&lt;T&gt;&gt; class vector
{
private:

    struct params
    {
        std::size_t size = 0;
        T element{};
        std::size_t capacity = 0;
        A allocator{};
    };

public:

    explicit vector( params p );
};
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This is <a href="https://godbolt.org/z/x17fdY">how it’s used</a>:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>auto f()
{
    vector&lt;int&gt; v{{ .size = 4, .element = 11, .capacity = 64 }};
    return v;
}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Again, apart from the odd <code>{{ ... }}</code> syntax, not that bad.</p>


</div>

<!--

<div class="related">
  <h2>Related posts</h2>
  <ul class="related-posts">
    
    
      <li>
        <h3>
          <a href="/blog/2020/09/06/why-use-the-boost-license/">
            Why You Should Use the Boost Software License
            <small>06 Sep 2020</small>
          </a>
        </h3>
      </li>
    
    
    
      <li>
        <h3>
          <a href="/blog/2020/09/05/from-simd-to-ast-extraction/">
            From SIMD to AST Extraction
            <small>05 Sep 2020</small>
          </a>
        </h3>
      </li>
    
    
    
      <li>
        <h3>
          <a href="/blog/2020/07/24/compilers-do-static-analysis/">
            Compilers Do Static Analysis, They Just Don't Tell You
            <small>24 Jul 2020</small>
          </a>
        </h3>
      </li>
    
    
  </ul>
</div>

-->

      </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://pdimov.github.io/blog/2020/09/07/named-parameters-in-c20/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24398756</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 11:51:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Raspberry Pi 3B+ Hackable Linux Handheld]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 133 | Comments 90 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24398485">thread link</a>) | @mmerlin
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | http://yarh.io/yarh-io-mki.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://yarh.io/yarh-io-mki.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
    <section id="top-section">
        <div id="top-section-top">
            <nav>
                
            </nav>
            <p id="heading">
                
                <h2>Raspberry Pi 3B+ Hackable Linux Handheld<br></h2>
            </p>
        </div>
    </section>
    <section id="yarh-io-mki">
        <div>
            <div>
                <div>
                    <p><a href="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-white-hand-large-t-001.png" target="_blank" data-lightbox="yarh-io-mki"><img src="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-white-hand-large-t-001.png"></a></p>
                    <div>
                        <p>YARH.IO is a fully hackable and custamizable Raspberry Pi based handheld, running Raspberry Pi OS and supporting all other Operating Systems available for Raspberry Pi.</p>
                        <p>The dream of a hackable&nbsp;Linux powered handheld has been around for many years, and many attempts have been made to create a working device. While some of the devices have reached the market, none of them withstood the test
                            of real world user experience.<br></p>
                        <p>YARH.IO project has taken on the challenge of building a fully functioning device by combining the best of Raspberry Pi design and 3D printing technology.&nbsp;<br></p>
                        <p>This project takes hackability to the next level by ensuring that every single component needed to build YARH.IO can be easily sourced, with no custom PCBs and just a bit of wire soldering required.&nbsp;</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <div>
                        <p>YARH.IO handheld and its unique modular design with exposed interfaces offers unprecedented connectivity with unlimited platforms and devices.<br></p>
                        <p>This model is powered by&nbsp;Raspberry Pi 3B+ and&nbsp;has the best ratio of functionality and computing power requirements for a mobile device. When it comes to the battery powered devices, the overall power consumption and longer
                            battery are more important then the extra processing power or memory.</p>
                        <p>For this model, the width of the main module is based on the keyboard dimensions for improved handling. The 5" Resistive Touch Screen 800x480 HDMI TFT LCD Display&nbsp;is a good option for YARH.IO as it&nbsp;will allow you to perform
                            all of the usual tasks with ease.&nbsp;<br></p>
                    </div>
                    <p><a href="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-red-right-large-t-001.png" target="_blank" data-lightbox="yarh-io-mki"><img src="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-red-right-large-t-001.png"></a></p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <p><a href="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-white-left-large-t-001.png" target="_blank" data-lightbox="yarh-io-mki"><img src="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-white-left-large-t-001.png"></a></p>
                    <div>
                        <p>Fosmon Portable Lightweight Mini Wireless Bluetooth Keyboard Controller has been selected as the best option for YARH.IO's multifunctional design. If you are using Vim, tmux, and Emacs everyday, the available modifier keys will
                            help you get the most out of the device.</p>
                        <p>In addition to the keyboard, YARH.IO's pointing device will allow you to effortlessly browse the internet and engage with other applications with graphical interface.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br></p>
                        <p>A single removable rechargeable battery will allow you to quickly replace an empty battery with a fully charged one. A high capacity Fenix ARB-L21-5000 5000mAh Li-ion Rechargeable Battery was chosen as the best option as it fits
                            the main module perfectly. For the charger/5v power supply the internals of a Fenix ARE-D1 Smart Charger were used.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <div>
                        <p>The RTC is a must have for a handheld device that is not continuously connected to the internet. YARH.IO includes a DS3231 High Precision RTC Clock Module.</p>
                        <p>Raspberry Pi GPIO connectors have been made available on the bottom sides of the main module and extension module for connecting all of your Raspberry Pi add-on boards.</p>
                        
                    </div>
                    <p><a href="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-black-top-large-t-001.png" target="_blank" data-lightbox="yarh-io-mki"><img src="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-black-top-large-t-001.png"></a></p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <p><a href="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-black-back-open-large-t-001.png" target="_blank" data-lightbox="yarh-io-mki"><img src="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-black-back-open-large-t-001.png"></a></p>
                    <div>
                        <p>YARH.IO features modular design, where the main module includes Raspberry Pi board, screen, power supply, battery, and RTC and GPIO connector with cables.&nbsp;</p>
                        <p>The main module can be used as a fully functioning handheld computer&nbsp;with the touch screen and onscreen keyboard available for the performance of your basic tasks.</p>
                        <p>One shared USB connector is available on the bottom of the main module, allows connecting USB devices like&nbsp;hard drives or Cellular/WiFi adaptors and mounted inside the extension module.</p>
                        <p>Raspberry Pi GPIO connector is also available on the bottom of the main module, allowing for different add-on modules,&nbsp;<br>including Lora radios, RFID readers/writers, and IR transivers, to&nbsp;be mounted inside the extension
                            module. This configuration works extremely well with Pi-DAC+, creating a great handheld audio player.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <p><a href="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-black-keyboard-large-t-001.png" target="_blank" data-lightbox="yarh-io-mki"><img src="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-black-keyboard-large-t-001.png"></a></p>
                    <div>
                        <p>No 'click' assembly here. This is a fully hackable device with stainless steel socket cap screw used&nbsp;throughout to allow for multiple assembly and disassembly cycles.&nbsp;The Military/Industrial aesthetic can be felt throughout
                            the YARH.IO project design.&nbsp;<br></p>
                        <p>The sturdy housing parts are 3D printed using PLA, ABS, and ASA plastic.&nbsp;<br></p>
                        
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <p><a href="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-black-back-keyboard-open-large-t-001.png" target="_blank" data-lightbox="yarh-io-mki"><img src="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-black-back-keyboard-open-large-t-001.png"></a></p>
                    <p>The list of parts used for the YARH.IO project can be purchased from Amazon and other online stores.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    
                    <p><a href="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-black-large-t-001.png" target="_blank" data-lightbox="yarh-io-mki"><img src="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-black-large-t-001.png"></a></p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <p><a href="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-white-front-large-t-001.png" target="_blank" data-lightbox="yarh-io-mki"><img src="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-white-front-large-t-001.png"></a></p>
                    <div>
                        <p>YARH.IO MKI Project at a Glance.&nbsp;</p>
                        <p>The outcome of this YARH.IO model is a successful handheld device with the potential to connect an unlimited range of extension devices and modules. It is a ruggedly designed and fully hackable device that can be 3D printed and
                            assembled in the field.<br></p>
                        <p>As an experimental model YARH.IO's future development will continue to increase usability and functionality of the device. One of the areas of improvement is the adaptation of IPS type screen for wider viewing angles.&nbsp;<br></p>
                        <p>Other future development will focus on adding new compartment modules to accommodate additional I/O, storage and communication devices.&nbsp;<br></p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </section>
    <section id="yarh-io-mki-gallery">
        
    </section>
    <section id="yarh-io-mki-downloads">
        
    </section>
    <section id="footer">
        <div>
            <div>
                <div>
                    <div>
                        <p>© 2019-2020 YARH.IO | info@yarh.io</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </section>
    
    
    
    


</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://yarh.io/yarh-io-mki.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24398485</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 10:56:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Many Ways to Start an Xserver]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 72 | Comments 14 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24398154">thread link</a>) | @gbrown_
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | https://nixers.net/Thread-How-Many-Ways-To-Start-An-Xserver | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nixers.net/Thread-How-Many-Ways-To-Start-An-Xserver">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nixers.net/Thread-How-Many-Ways-To-Start-An-Xserver</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24398154</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 09:49:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Threat modelling case study: bicycles]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 68 | Comments 98 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24397852">thread link</a>) | @calpaterson
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | http://calpaterson.com/bicycle-threat-model.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://calpaterson.com/bicycle-threat-model.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
        
        <p>August 2020</p>
        <p id="article-description">How to avoid buying your bike again every 6-12
        months and tips for how to apply the same reasoning to other things, like
        computers</p>
        <hr>
        <figure>
            <img src="http://calpaterson.com/assets/solitary-wheel.jpeg" alt="a solitary wheel left behind after the rest of the bike was nicked">
            <figcaption>
                Rucksack Rupert strikes again
            </figcaption>
        </figure>
        <p>Some very commonly repeated advice on preventing someone from nicking your
        bike:</p>
        <blockquote>
            <p>Buy a good [~10% of bicycle value] lock, ideally one with a high
            "SoldSecure" rating and lock your bicycle somewhere inside the rear
            triangle and the rear wheel.</p>
        </blockquote>
        <p>I've seen this advice repeated in cycling magazines, in quality newspapers,
        sometimes even by the police and of course on internet forums.</p>
        <p>The above would imply that if you own a £400 bicycle (<a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/395884/bicycle-average-prices-in-the-european-union-eu-by-country/">a
        typical price in the UK</a>) you'd buy a £40 lock and put it in the right
        place.</p>
        <p>However, it is a cold fact that a cordless angle grinder can defeat any
        bicycle lock, no matter how expensive (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pywN558dJaU&amp;t=198">see this video for a
        demonstration</a>). You can buy a used cordless angle grinder on eBay for less
        than £100. Even U-locks - traditionally thought to be the strongest type of
        lock - are opened in seconds with a sub-£100 angle grinder.</p>
        <p>There is other advice floating around of doubtful value, for example:</p>
        <blockquote>
            <p>Add your bicycle to a national register</p>
        </blockquote>
        <p>But cases where BikeRadar manage to reunite bicycles with their owners seem
        to be the exception rather than the rule. Probably this is because, as with
        cars, the first thing you do with a stolen bicycle is take it across a border
        to somewhere different.</p>
        <blockquote>
            <p>Lock your bicycle inside a secure building or place, away from sight</p>
        </blockquote>
        <p>This prevents opportunistic theft but if this space is shared with others
        (apartment blocks and offices) it in fact serves to increase the economies of
        scale for prepared thieves who break into your storage area late at night with
        a van. It's not uncommon for office bicycle stores (with many fancy, expensive
        bikes inside) to be emptied out completely overnight by professional
        thieves.</p>
        <h2>A threat model, by user persona</h2>
        <p>I think the advice above is poor because it doesn't come from a systematic
        consideration of the problem <em>from the point of view of thieves</em>.</p>
        <p>To come up with better advice requires a threat model, which is a piece of
        jargon for taking a holistic view of the danger posed by attackers. I think one
        of the simplest and most straightforward ways to do threat modelling is by
        <em>user persona</em>, whereby you consider each kind of attacker in turn,
        making some reasonable assumptions about their level of motivation and
        methods.</p>
        <p>As far as bicycle theft is concerned there are three basic types of
        thief.</p>
        <h3>"No-tools Nigel", the rank opportunist</h3>
        <p>Nigel has just his two hands and is simply looking for a ride home or maybe
        something he can sell to a friend for some quick cash.</p>
        <p>Nigel will steal any unlocked bicycle.</p>
        <p>Nigel is also able to take any bicycle parts that can be removed without
        tools. That means any quick-release wheels or thumbscrew saddles. In an urban
        area your parked bicycle may be passed by a Nigel as often as a few times an
        hour so anything that is not bolted down won't last very long.</p>
        <h3>"Rucksack Rupert", the thief with a few hand tools</h3>
        <p>Rupert has a small pair of shears; 4, 5 and 6mm Allen keys and a 15mm
        spanner for wheel nuts.</p>
        <p>Rupert will make his way through cable locks with his shears. If there is a
        valuable part that can be removed with hand tools he will take it. He is
        particularly keen on premium saddles and name brand wheels.</p>
        <h3>"Powertool Percy", the professional with a complete set of tools</h3>
        <p>Percy has a small collection of electric and air tools including an angle
        grinder as well as bolt-cutters and an air-jack. He has access to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fence_(criminal)">criminal fences</a> which he
        can use to sell stolen bicycles quickly. Percy often arrives in his van and
        this allows him to steal multiple bikes at once.</p>
        <p>No bicycle is safe from Percy. No lock can hold against his angle grinder.
        Often he finds if he's wearing a hi-vis jacket he can even get away with using
        his power tools in broad daylight. He's willing to chance that if the bicycle
        seems valuable enough.</p>
        <h2>Coming up with better advice based on Nigel, Rupert and Percy</h2>
        <p>In order to keep your bicycle safe you need to take steps against all three
        levels of imaginary thieves.</p>
        <p>"No-tools Nigel" will be warded off simply by:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>Locking your bicycle whenever you leave it - even if just for a
            minute</li>
            <li>Ensuring you leave nothing on your bicycle that can be removed without
            tools
                <ul>
                    <li>replace quick-release wheel skewers with bolts</li>
                    <li>take your lights with you when you park in public</li>
                    <li>make sure your saddle is not on a thumbscrew</li>
                </ul>
            </li>
        </ul>
        <p>"Rucksack Rupert" will be deterred by:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>Not using a cable lock!</li>
            <li>Making sure that nothing good can be removed from your bicycle with
            hand tools
                <ul>
                    <li>Lock both wheels <em>and the frame</em> to the bike stand -
                    don't rely on bolts</li>
                </ul>
            </li>
        </ul>
        <p>"Powertool Percy" will be kept at bay by:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>Nothing, save ensuring that your bicycle doesn't look valuable enough
            to be worth his time
                <ul>
                    <li>this probably means keeping its value down below a few hundred
                    pounds</li>
                </ul>
            </li>
        </ul>
        <h2>The virtue of the "bicycle shaped object"</h2>
        <p>Valuable bicycles (&gt;£1000) have an extremely short half-life in urban
        areas. The sad truth is that the Percys of the world are common enough and
        resourceful enough that a bicycle worth over a thousand pounds isn't really
        safe anywhere in a large town. <strong>This includes most e-bikes.</strong> You
        might notice that cycle couriers who have e-bikes tend to eat lunch while
        looking directly at their locked e-bike, so that it never goes out of their
        sight. Few people in other lines of work can do the same.</p>
        <p>If the tyres are inflated, my own commuter bicycle is probably worth £30 to
        the right buyer. My bicycle is so low-end that cycling snobs refer to it as a
        mere "bicycle shaped object". Rather selfishly I am glad that such snobs exist
        as having a lot of more valuable bicycles around provides me with good ambient
        security. No thief is going to bother cutting my locks when there is a
        Campagnolo on the next rack.</p>
        <p>One father I know had his primary-school-age daughter "decorate" his
        commuting bicycle with girly stickers and pink glitter. If anyone examines his
        bicycle closely he looks like a complete loon but I think his motivation is
        right: it's going to be much less appealing to steal when it's covered in Miffy
        stickers.</p>
        <h3>Insurance - not usually worth it</h3>
        <p>What about bicycle insurance? It's fairly expensive here in the UK, usually
        10-15% of the bicycle's value annually and insurers typically only pay out when
        the whole bicycle is taken (so if if your front wheel is nicked, you're on your
        own) and when you can demonstrate that it was locked to their standards. Often
        these standards require that it is locked up indoors which means you're
        chancing it whenever you park away from your home or office.</p>
        <h2>Lists of "best practices" vs having your own threat model</h2>
        <p>The same thing goes for securing your bicycle as for securing other things:
        pat, concrete pieces of security advice are something to treat with a bit of
        doubt.</p>
        <p>In bicycles the common mantra is "spend 10% on a lock" but in computing the
        mantras are slogans such as "use a strong password", "back up your important
        data" or "use encryption" but these can all be just as vapid.</p>
        <p>"Strong passwords!" as a slogan fails to address the fact that the average
        internet user has hundreds of logins for various sites (my own password manager
        has over 700 sites recorded). The majority of internet users decide on a single
        "strong password" and then use it everywhere. They are only a single bad
        sysadmin or javascript injection away from losing access to every account on
        every website they have.</p>
        <p>Backing up your important data is only an aid to your security if the backup
        is stored as securely as the original. Much user data is stolen or exposed
        through poorly secured backups on shared fileservers. A huge number of people
        have passport and utility bill scans in their Dropbox - again, behind the same
        email and password they use everywhere. Companies can be surprisingly sloppy
        with backups too: often dumped into cloud storage somewhere once before the Big
        Migration and never removed.</p>
        <p>Encryption is troublesome as it can give undue confidence that can backfire
        spectacularly: a quarter of a million American diplomatic cables were
        inadvertantly published in unredacted form when a Guardian journalist <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WikiLeaks:_Inside_Julian_Assange%27s_War_on_Secrecy">
        included the password for an widely-distributed encrypted file in his book</a>.
        Apparently he thought the file's password was somehow temporary. It wasn't.</p>
        <p>Instead of following such "best practices" it's much more intellectually
        robust to <strong>come up with your own threat model</strong> - then you can
        decide your own concrete steps instead of just following the security steps of
        others which might be inapplicable or even wrong.</p>
        <h2>Some hints on coming up with your own …</h2></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://calpaterson.com/bicycle-threat-model.html">http://calpaterson.com/bicycle-threat-model.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://calpaterson.com/bicycle-threat-model.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24397852</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 08:58:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Things I Learned to Become a Senior Software Engineer]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 134 | Comments 116 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24397269">thread link</a>) | @janvdberg
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | https://neilkakkar.com/things-I-learned-to-become-a-senior-software-engineer.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://neilkakkar.com/things-I-learned-to-become-a-senior-software-engineer.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>In 2018, I started working at Bloomberg. Things have changed a lot since. I’m not the most junior member in the company anymore and I’ve mentored quite a few new engineers, which has been amazing. It helped me observe how others differ from me, absorb their best practices, and figure out things I’ve unconsciously been doing pretty well.</p>

<p>Yearly work reviews are a good way to condense these lessons I’ve learned.  They’re valuable for pattern matching, too. Only when I zoom out do certain patterns become visible. I can then <a href="https://neilkakkar.com/the-human-log.html">start tracking these patterns consciously</a>.</p>

<p>The broad theme for this year is zooming out and challenging the boundaries. It’s also about zooming in, and adding nuance to the sections from last year. It’s more fun if you’ve <a href="https://neilkakkar.com/year-in-review-2019.html">read last year’s review first</a>: You can then diff my growth.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2">1</a></sup></p>

<p>It all began with a question: How do I grow further?</p>





<nav>

  <h4>Table of Contents</h4>

<ul id="markdown-toc">
  <li><a href="#growing-using-different-ladders-of-abstraction" id="markdown-toc-growing-using-different-ladders-of-abstraction">Growing using different ladders of abstraction</a></li>
  <li><a href="#learning-what-people-around-me-are-doing" id="markdown-toc-learning-what-people-around-me-are-doing">Learning what people around me are doing</a></li>
  <li>
<a href="#learning-good-habits-of-mind" id="markdown-toc-learning-good-habits-of-mind">Learning good habits of mind</a>    <ul>
      <li><a href="#thinking-well" id="markdown-toc-thinking-well">Thinking Well</a></li>
      <li><a href="#strategies-for-making-day-to-day-more-effective" id="markdown-toc-strategies-for-making-day-to-day-more-effective">Strategies for making day-to-day more effective</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#acquiring-new-tools-for-thought--mental-models" id="markdown-toc-acquiring-new-tools-for-thought--mental-models">Acquiring new tools for thought &amp; mental models</a></li>
  <li><a href="#protect-your-slack" id="markdown-toc-protect-your-slack">Protect your slack</a></li>
  <li><a href="#ask-questions" id="markdown-toc-ask-questions">Ask Questions</a></li>
  <li><a href="#noticing-confusion" id="markdown-toc-noticing-confusion">Noticing Confusion</a></li>
  <li><a href="#force-multipliers" id="markdown-toc-force-multipliers">Force multipliers</a></li>
  <li><a href="#on-ownership" id="markdown-toc-on-ownership">On Ownership</a></li>
  <li><a href="#embrace-fear" id="markdown-toc-embrace-fear">Embrace fear</a></li>
  <li>
<a href="#adding-nuance" id="markdown-toc-adding-nuance">Adding nuance</a>    <ul>
      <li><a href="#writing-code" id="markdown-toc-writing-code">Writing Code</a></li>
      <li><a href="#testing" id="markdown-toc-testing">Testing</a></li>
      <li>
<a href="#design" id="markdown-toc-design">Design</a>        <ul>
          <li><a href="#gathering-requirements" id="markdown-toc-gathering-requirements">Gathering Requirements</a></li>
        </ul>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#some-hacks-that-have-worked-very-well-for-me" id="markdown-toc-some-hacks-that-have-worked-very-well-for-me">Some hacks that have worked very well for me</a></li>
  <li><a href="#super-powers" id="markdown-toc-super-powers">Super powers</a></li>
  <li>
<a href="#some-gotchas-with-growing" id="markdown-toc-some-gotchas-with-growing">Some gotchas with growing</a>    <ul>
      <li><a href="#sometimes-i-feel-i-need-to-know-the-answer-to-everything" id="markdown-toc-sometimes-i-feel-i-need-to-know-the-answer-to-everything">Sometimes, I feel I need to know the answer to everything</a></li>
      <li><a href="#sometimes-i-lose-my-cool" id="markdown-toc-sometimes-i-lose-my-cool">Sometimes, I lose my cool</a></li>
      <li><a href="#neophilia" id="markdown-toc-neophilia">Neophilia</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#questions" id="markdown-toc-questions">Questions</a></li>
</ul>

</nav>

<!-- works only once jQuery is loaded -->


<h2 id="growing-using-different-ladders-of-abstraction">Growing using different ladders of abstraction</h2>

<p>Entering my second year, I had all the basics in place. I had picked all the low hanging fruit, and my rate of growth slowed down. Not good. The big question in my mind was “How do I grow further?”</p>

<p>There was only so much I could do to improve my coding skills. Most blogs epousing techniques to write cleaner code, repeating yourself, not repeating yourself, etc. are micro-optimisations. Almost none of them would make me instantly impactful.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3">2</a></sup></p>

<p>However, I did figure out something insightful. I’m working inside the software development lifecycle, but this lifecycle is part of a bigger lifecycle: the product and infrastructure development lifecycle. I decided to go broader instead of deeper. Surprisingly, the breadth provided more depth to what I knew.</p>

<p>I zoomed out in 3 broad directions: learning what people around me are doing, learning good habits of mind, and acquiring new tools for thought.</p>

<h2 id="learning-what-people-around-me-are-doing">Learning what people around me are doing</h2>

<p>Since we’re not in a closed system, it makes sense to better understand the job of the product managers, the sales people, and the analysts. In the end it’s a business making money through products. The goal isn’t to write code, it’s to be a profitable business.<sup id="fnref:15"><a href="#fn:15">3</a></sup></p>

<p>Most big companies aren’t doing just one thing, which means there are different paths to making money in the same company. Everyone is on at least one path - if they weren’t, they wouldn’t be here.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1">4</a></sup> Tracking these paths, and the path I’m on was pretty valuable. It helped me see how I matter, and what levers I can pull to become more effective. Sometimes, it’s about making the sales jobs easier, so they can make more sales. Other times, it’s about building a new feature for clients. And some other times, it’s about improving a feature that keeps breaking.</p>

<p>Product managers are the best source for this. They know how the business makes money, who are the clients, and what do clients need.</p>

<p>Over the year, I setup quite a few meetings with everyone on my path. A second benefit this gave me was the context of other’s jobs. It helped me communicate better. Framing things in the right way is powerful.</p>

<p>For example, one conversation helped me appreciate why Sarah in Sales wants a bulk update tool. Some companies have lots of employees, and  updating them one by one is a pain. The code I write would literally ease Sarah’s pain.</p>

<!-- More recently, I got a chance to sit in on a few product scoping meetings between teams. This gave me a lot more appreciation for the job my PM and TLs do. Communication is surprisingly hard, and aligning different teams takes skill. -->

<!-- Force multiplier in team vs force multiplier in the entire chain. -->

<h2 id="learning-good-habits-of-mind">Learning good habits of mind</h2>

<p>Software engineering entails thinking well and making the right decisions. Programming is implementing those decisions.</p>

<p>A habit of mind is something your brain does regularly. This could be thinking of X whenever you see Y happen, or applying thinking tool X to problem Y. In short, habits of mind facilitate better thinking.</p>

<p>I suspected if I learn the general skill, I should be able to apply it better to software engineering.</p>

<h3 id="thinking-well">Thinking Well</h3>

<p>Software engineering is an excellent field to practice thinking well in. The feedback loops are shorter, and gauging correctness doesn’t take too long.</p>

<p>I dived into cognitive science studies. It’s a permanent skill that’s worth exploring - a force multiplier for whatever I end up doing, and pays dividends throughout my life. One output was <a href="https://neilkakkar.com/Bayes-Theorem-Framework-for-Critical-Thinking.html">a framework for critical thinking</a>. It’s compounding, <a href="https://neilkakkar.com/year-in-review-2019.html#compounding-is-powerful-building-intuition-for-compounding-even-more-so">and compounding is powerful</a>.</p>

<p>There’s lots of good things that came out of this, which I’ll talk about in a bit. They deserve their own section.</p>

<h3 id="strategies-for-making-day-to-day-more-effective">Strategies for making day-to-day more effective</h3>

<p>The other side of the coin is habits that allow you to think well. It starts with noticing little irritations during the day, inefficiencies in meetings, and then figuring out strategies to avoid them. These strategic improvements are underrated.</p>

<p>You decide what to do, and then let it run on automatic, freeing up the brain to think of more fun stuff. Of course, that’s what a habit is, too.</p>

<p>Some good habits I’ve noticed:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Never leave a meeting without making the decision / having a next action</li>
  <li>Decide who is going to get it done. Things without an owner rarely get done.</li>
  <li>Document design decisions made during a project</li>
</ul>

<p>This pattern became visible during the review, so I’m keen to pay attention and collect more strategies next year. Having an excellent scrum master who holds me accountable has helped me get better at following these strategies.</p>



<p>New tools for thought are related to thinking well, but more specific to software engineering. Tools for thought help me think better about specific engineering problems.</p>

<p>I’ve adopted a just-in-time approach to this. I look for new tools only when I get stuck on something, or when I find out my abstractions and design decisions aren’t working well.</p>

<p>For example, I was recently struggling with a domain with lots of complex business logic. Edge cases were the norm, and we wanted to design a system that handles this cleanly. That’s when I read about <a href="https://amzn.to/2FdCYUQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Domain Driven Design</a><sup id="fnref:25"><a href="#fn:25">5</a></sup>. I could instantly put it to practice and make a big difference. Subsequently, I grasped these concepts better. I acquired a new mental model of how to create enterprise software.</p>

<p>The second way I keep learning and acquiring new mental models is via reading what surfaces on Hacker News. They are interesting ideas, some of which I’ve put to practice, but this is a lot less effective than the technique above. The only reason I still do this is to <a href="https://neilkakkar.com/rationality.html#map-and-the-territory">map the territory</a> - it keeps me aware of techniques that exist, so when I face a problem, I know there’s a method that might help.</p>

<p>The final way I acquire better mental models is by learning new diverse languages. The diversity bit is important. Learning yet another dialect of lisp has a lot less benefit than say, learning C++03, a functional programming language, a dynamic typed language, and a lisp. Today, <a href="https://www.hillelwayne.com/post/j-notation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">J seems interesting</a>, and one I might consider learning. It’s a thinking model I haven’t used before.</p>

<p>I’ve gotten lots of value from doing this. Each language has its own vocabulary and grammar, and <a href="https://neilkakkar.com/vocabulary-mental-model.html">vocabulary is a meta-mental model</a>. It’s a new lens to look at how to do things.</p>

<p>When memory management is in your control, you understand how pointers and allocators work. When Python then abstracts this away, you appreciate the complexity reduction. When maps and filters in a functional language show up, you appreciate how Python’s for loops can be improved. Indeed, that’s what list comprehensions are. And then you notice how some things are easier with object oriented programming. There’s no one magic tool that fits everything well. And then you understand that despite this, you don’t have to switch tools. You can adapt best practices from one into another to solve your problems: like writing functional javascript. It’s the principles that matter more than their expression.</p>

<figure>
    
    <img src="https://neilkakkar.com/assets/images/divider.jpg" alt="">
    
    
    
</figure>

<p>Broadly, that’s all I did this year. What follow are insights that sprang forth thanks to zooming out.</p>

<h2 id="protect-your-slack">Protect your slack</h2>

<p>When I say slack, I don’t mean the company, but the adjective.</p>

<p>One thing that gives me high output and productivity gains is to “slow down”. Want to get more done? Slow down.</p>

<p>Caveats apply, but here’s what I mean:</p>

<p>I’ve noticed people rush to solve problems. It can be something they’ve done before, or something we have a template for. It feels pretty good to smash through things. I’ve done that before, too! However, there’s very specific cases where this makes sense.<sup id="fnref:11"><a href="#fn:11">6</a></sup></p>

<p>Whenever I’m working on something new, I take the time to learn things about the system I’m working on, and things closely related to it. If it’s too massive, I optimise for learning as much as I can. Every time I revisit the system, I aim to learn more.</p>

<p>When <a href="https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/yLLkWMDbC9ZNKbjDG/slack" target="_blank" rel="noopener">there is slack</a>, you get a chance to experiment, learn, and think things through. This means you get enough time to get things done.</p>

<p>When there is no slack, deadlines are tight, and all your focus goes into getting shit done.</p>

<p>Protecting your slack means not letting deadlines wrap tight around you. Usually, this is as simple (or hard) as communicating.<sup id="fnref:16"><a href="#fn:16">7</a></sup></p>

<p>Slack might have a negative connotation with “slackers”, but protecting slack is a super power. It’s a long term investment into building yourself up at the cost of short term efficiency.</p>

<p>When I’m quickly dishing out stories, I also have a much harder time fixing bugs. I don’t take the time to create proper mental models of the system, which means my assumptions don’t match the code, and this mismatch is where most bugs lie.</p>

<p>I protect my slack, so I can take the time out to prioritise …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://neilkakkar.com/things-I-learned-to-become-a-senior-software-engineer.html">https://neilkakkar.com/things-I-learned-to-become-a-senior-software-engineer.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://neilkakkar.com/things-I-learned-to-become-a-senior-software-engineer.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24397269</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 07:11:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[PostgreSQL B-Tree index deduplication]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 183 | Comments 25 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24395825">thread link</a>) | @petergeoghegan
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2020/09/postgres-beta3-btree-dedup | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2020/09/postgres-beta3-btree-dedup">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                    <p>By Ryan Lambert -- Published September 06, 2020</p><p>PostgreSQL 13 development is coming along nicely, Postgres 13 Beta3 was
<a href="https://www.postgresql.org/about/news/2060/">released on 8/13/2020</a>.
The Postgres Beta 1 and 2 releases were released in May and June 2020.
One of the features that has my interest in Postgres 13 is the B-Tree deduplication effort.  B-Tree indexes are the default indexing method
in Postgres, and are likely the most-used indexes in production 
environments.
Any improvements to this part of the database are likely to have wide-reaching benefits.
Removing duplication from indexes keeps their physical size smaller,
reduces I/O overhead, and should help keep <code>SELECT</code> queries fast!</p>
<!--endteaser-->

<blockquote>
<p>This post is part of the series <a href="https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2018/06/pg-series-toc"><em>PostgreSQL:  From Idea to Database</em></a>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>There is a good summary of the what and how of this improvement
in <a href="https://www.cybertec-postgresql.com/en/b-tree-index-deduplication/">Laurenz Albe's post</a> from early in June 2020, presumably using
Pg13 Beta1.  <a href="https://www.highgo.ca/2020/07/06/features-in-pg13-deduplication-in-b-tree-indexes/">Hamid Akhtar's post in July</a>
covered this feature using Pg13 Beta2 and a different approach including
a look at the performance using <code>EXPLAIN</code>.
This post takes yet another look at this improvement using Pg13 Beta3.
I intend to see how well this improvement pans out on a data set I use in production.  For that task my go-to is
<a href="https://www.openstreetmap.org/">OpenStreetMap</a> data loaded to Postgres/PostGIS <a href="https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2020/01/postgis-osm-load-2020">using osm2pgsql</a>.</p>
<h2>Install Postgres 13 Beta 3</h2>
<p>The first step is to install the two versions of Postgres (12 and 13beta3) 
on a single Ubuntu 18 host.  In the past when I have tested pre-production
releases I have built Postgres from source instead of using <code>apt</code>.
This time around I decided to use <code>apt install</code>, so am including the
basic process for that.</p>
<p>The advised way to install PostgreSQL is from the pgdg (PostgreSQL Global Development Group) repositories,
see <a href="https://wiki.postgresql.org/wiki/Apt">the Postgres wiki</a> for more.
To enable the beta versions, the line needed in <code>/etc/apt/sources.list.d/pgdg.list</code> is:</p>
<pre><code>deb http://apt.postgresql.org/pub/repos/apt/bionic-pgdg main 13
</code></pre>
<p>With that in place, update the sources and install Postgres and PostGIS.</p>
<pre><code>sudo apt update
# Postgres 12
sudo apt install postgresql-12 postgresql-12-postgis-3
# Postgres 13 (Currently Beta)
sudo apt install postgresql-13 postgresql-13-postgis-3
</code></pre>
<p>On Ubuntu, installing multiple versions will create multiple instances running on different ports. The test server I'm using to write this post
currently has three versions of Postgres installed, only two are currently running. Postgres 12 was installed first so "won" the default port of 5432.  Postgres 11 was installed second and was assigned 5433, and Pg13 beta 3 was installed last and was assigned port 5434.  The <code>pg_lsclusters</code> is avaiable on Debian/Ubuntu hosts as part of the wrapper around <code>pg_ctl</code>.</p>
<pre><code>sudo -u postgres pg_lsclusters
Ver Cluster Port Status Owner    Data directory              Log file
11  main    5433 down   postgres /var/lib/postgresql/11/main /var/log/postgresql/postgresql-11-main.log
12  main    5432 online postgres /var/lib/postgresql/12/main /var/log/postgresql/postgresql-12-main.log
13  main    5434 online postgres /var/lib/postgresql/13/main /var/log/postgresql/postgresql-13-main.log
</code></pre>
<blockquote>
<p>This post does not use Postgres 11 beyond this example.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When working with multiple versions installed it is helpful to verify
versions match what you expect them to be.
First, the port 5432 for Postgres 12 version.</p>
<pre><code>psql -d pgosm -p 5432 -c "select version();"
â”Œâ”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”�
â”‚                                   version                                    â”‚
â•žâ•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•¡
â”‚ PostgreSQL 12.4 (Ubuntu 12.4-1.pgdg18.04+1) on x86_64-pc-linux-gnu, compiledâ€¦â”‚
â”‚â€¦ by gcc (Ubuntu 7.5.0-3ubuntu1~18.04) 7.5.0, 64-bit                          â”‚
â””â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”˜
</code></pre>
<p>Now, port 5434 for Postgres 13 version.</p>
<pre><code>psql -d pgosm -p 5434 -c "select version();"
â”Œâ”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”�
â”‚                                   version                                    â”‚
â•žâ•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•¡
â”‚ PostgreSQL 13beta3 (Ubuntu 13~beta3-1.pgdg18.04+1) on x86_64-pc-linux-gnu, câ€¦â”‚
â”‚â€¦ompiled by gcc (Ubuntu 7.5.0-3ubuntu1~18.04) 7.5.0, 64-bit                   â”‚
â””â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”˜
</code></pre>
<h2>Create Indexes</h2>
<p>Both versions of Postgres were loaded with the same Colorado OpenStreetMap
data loaded <a href="https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2020/01/postgis-osm-load-2020">using osm2pgsql</a>.
The osm2pgsql does not create any B-Tree indexes on its own, only the GIST
indexes on geometries.
For this post, we examine B-Tree index sizes created on four columns:
<code>osm_id</code>, <code>highway</code>, <code>waterway</code>, and <code>natural</code>.
Looking at the stats on the <code>public.planet_osm_line</code> table I can make 
a couple guesses where we will and will not see gains based on <code>n_distinct</code>.
I can guess we will not see major gains in the
<code>osm_id</code>, there is only a small amount of duplication in those values.
The other three columns (<code>highway</code>, <code>natural</code> and <code>waterway</code>) have a small number of distinct values
and varying amounts of <code>NULL</code> values.  These three columns would all
be candidates for partial indexes to avoid indexing the <code>NULL</code> values,
thus reducing the size of the created index.
I have hopes to see the benefits in Postgres 13 on these columns, possibly
making the use of partial indexes less frequent.</p>
<pre><code> SELECT attname, n_distinct, null_frac
    FROM pg_catalog.pg_stats
    WHERE tablename = 'planet_osm_line'
        AND attname IN ('osm_id', 'highway', 'waterway', 'natural')
;

â”Œâ”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”¬â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”¬â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”�
â”‚ attname  â”‚ n_distinct â”‚ null_frac  â”‚
â•žâ•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•ªâ•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•ªâ•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•¡
â”‚ osm_id   â”‚  -0.833553 â”‚          0 â”‚
â”‚ highway  â”‚         26 â”‚ 0.41616666 â”‚
â”‚ natural  â”‚          4 â”‚      0.994 â”‚
â”‚ waterway â”‚          9 â”‚     0.6663 â”‚
â””â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”´â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”´â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”˜
</code></pre>
<h3>Index on <code>osm_id</code></h3>
<p>First up is the <code>osm_id</code> column, a nearly unique set of positive and 
negative values.  The index to create in both versions:</p>
<pre><code>CREATE INDEX ix_osm_line_osm_id ON public.planet_osm_line (osm_id);
</code></pre>
<p>The following query is used throughout to report out index sizes.
The query itself will not be repeated, as only the filter would change.</p>
<pre><code>SELECT ai.schemaname AS s_name, ai.relname AS t_name,
        ai.indexrelname AS index_name,
        pg_size_pretty(pg_relation_size(quote_ident(ai.schemaname)::text || '.' || quote_ident(ai.indexrelname)::text)) AS index_size,
        pg_relation_size(quote_ident(ai.schemaname)::text || '.' || quote_ident(ai.indexrelname)::text) AS index_size_bytes
    FROM pg_catalog.pg_stat_all_indexes ai
    WHERE ai.indexrelname LIKE 'ix_osm_line%'
    ORDER BY index_name
;
</code></pre>
<p>Due to the low number of duplicates, it is no surprise that the
show only a tiny reduction in the size.  The reduction
would not be detectable from only the <code>index_size</code> column (in MB), the
<code>index_size_bytes</code> shows the slight reduction in size (29,515,776 bytes vs. 29,384,704 bytes).</p>
<p>Pg 12.</p>
<pre><code>â”Œâ”€[ RECORD 1 ]â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”¬â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”�
â”‚ s_name           â”‚ public             â”‚
â”‚ t_name           â”‚ planet_osm_line    â”‚
â”‚ index_name       â”‚ ix_osm_line_osm_id â”‚
â”‚ index_size       â”‚ 28 MB              â”‚
â”‚ index_size_bytes â”‚ 29515776           â”‚
â””â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”´â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”˜
</code></pre>
<p>Pg 13.</p>
<pre><code>â”Œâ”€[ RECORD 1 ]â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”¬â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”�
â”‚ s_name           â”‚ public             â”‚
â”‚ t_name           â”‚ planet_osm_line    â”‚
â”‚ index_name       â”‚ ix_osm_line_osm_id â”‚
â”‚ index_size       â”‚ 28 MB              â”‚
â”‚ index_size_bytes â”‚ 29384704           â”‚
â””â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”´â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”˜
</code></pre>
<h3>Index on <code>highway</code></h3>
<p>The <code>highway</code> data in the <code>planet_osm_line</code> data is a good example of when
a
<a href="https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/indexes-partial.html">partial index</a>
might typically be a good idea to minimize index size.  My hunch (and hope)
is that the de-duplication will make a partial index here a moot point by reducing the size required to index a large number of <code>NULL</code> values.</p>
<p>Create two indexes, one partial covering the non-<code>NULL</code> values and one full
index on the entire table.</p>
<pre><code>CREATE INDEX ix_osm_line_highway_partial 
    ON public.planet_osm_line (highway)
    WHERE highway IS NOT NULL;
CREATE INDEX ix_osm_line_highway_full
    ON public.planet_osm_line (highway);
</code></pre>
<p>The two indexes in Postgres 12, notice the partial index cuts out about 1/3 of the size from the full index.</p>
<pre><code>â”Œâ”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”¬â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”¬â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”…</code></pre></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2020/09/postgres-beta3-btree-dedup">https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2020/09/postgres-beta3-btree-dedup</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2020/09/postgres-beta3-btree-dedup</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24395825</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:39:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Introduction to Computational Thinking]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 315 | Comments 32 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24395700">thread link</a>) | @guiambros
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | https://mitmath.github.io/18S191/Fall20/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://mitmath.github.io/18S191/Fall20/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

<!-- Content appended here -->
<div>
<p>Welcome to the new course <strong>MIT 18.S191</strong>, the debut edition, <strong>Fall 2020</strong>!</p>
<p> This is an introductory course on Computational Thinking. We use the <a href="http://www.julialang.org/">Julia programming language</a> to approach real-world problems in varied areas applying data analysis and computational and mathematical modeling.  In this class you will learn computer science, software, algorithms, applications, and mathematics as an integrated whole.</p>
<p>Topics include:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>Image analysis</p>
</li>
<li><p>Particle dynamics and ray tracing</p>
</li>
<li><p>Epidemic propagation</p>
</li>
<li><p>Climate modeling</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="professors"><a href="#professors">Professors</a></h2>
<p><a href="http://math.mit.edu/~edelman">Alan Edelman</a>, <a href="http://sistemas.fciencias.unam.mx/~dsanders/">David P. Sanders</a>, <a href="https://www.3blue1brown.com/about">Grant Sanderson</a>, &amp; <a href="https://eapsweb.mit.edu/people/jars">James Schloss</a></p>
<h2 id="introduction_video"><a href="#introduction_video">Introduction video</a></h2>
<iframe id="course-intro" width="800" height="474" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vxjRWtWoD_w" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<h2 id="logistics"><a href="#logistics">Logistics</a></h2>
<p>Course materials will be published on the accompanying website: <a href="https://mitmath.github.io/18S191/Fall20/">https://mitmath.github.io/18S191/Fall20/</a></p>
<p>TR 2:30–3:30pm EST, online (Go to the lecture page on this site to stream it.)</p>
<ul>
<li><p>Tuesdays: Prerecorded videos, released on YouTube and played live on this site.</p>
</li>
<li><p>Thursdays: Live sessions (same YouTube link 2:30–3) and MIT-only discussion (3-3:30); link to follow</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Start date: September 1, 2020</p>
<p>Office hours TBD.</p>
<h3 id="discussion_forum_and_homework_submission"><a href="#discussion_forum_and_homework_submission">Discussion forum and homework submission</a></h3>
<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://discord.gg/Z5qnVf8">Discord</a>: discussion (we encourage you to hang out here during class!)</p>
</li>
<li><p><a href="https://piazza.com/class/kd33x1xnfyq3b1">Piazza</a>: (MIT only) allows for anonymity to other students, discussion</p>
</li>
<li><p><a href="https://canvas.mit.edu/courses/5637">Canvas</a>: (MIT only) homework submission. If you're a non-MIT student, please find a partner to cross-grade homeworks via Discord.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="evaluation"><a href="#evaluation">Evaluation</a></h3>
<ul>
<li><p>12 weekly problem sets with equal weight; your lowest score will be dropped. </p>
</li>
<li><p>Released on Thursdays and due before the following Thursday's class. (No problem set during Thanskgiving week.)</p>
</li>
<li><p>No exams</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Problem sets consist of code. MIT students enrolled in the course must submit homeworks via Canvas. If you are not a student then we encourage you to join the Discord and find a cross-grading partner.</p>
<div>
  <p>
    Last modified: September 09, 2020. Website built with <a href="https://github.com/tlienart/Franklin.jl">Franklin.jl</a>.
  </p>
</div>
</div><!-- CONTENT ENDS HERE -->

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://mitmath.github.io/18S191/Fall20/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24395700</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:08:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Elixir Is Erlang, not Ruby]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 401 | Comments 282 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24395695">thread link</a>) | @stanislavb
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | https://preslav.me/2020/09/06/elixir-is-not-ruby-elixir-is-erlang/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://preslav.me/2020/09/06/elixir-is-not-ruby-elixir-is-erlang/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Try to remember the first time you heard about this fascinating language called <a href="https://elixir-lang.org/">Elixir</a>. Chances are, you had by the time been developing software using Ruby. If that's the case, Elixir seems to have appeared out of nowhere until suddenly, it became the solution for all your previous problems. It is fast, clean, scales extremely well. It was <strong>almost</strong> like the Ruby you've always wanted to have, but never got.</p><p>I say <strong>almost</strong>, because as much as you want it to be, <strong>Elixir is not Ruby</strong>. The familiar syntax has definitely helped the language win the hearts of the broader developer community. Yet, under the hood, <strong>Elixir is all about Erlang.</strong> The <a href="https://elixir-lang.org/">Erlang</a> that everyone tells stories about, as if it were some mythical creature, but no one dares to touch.</p><figure><img src="https://preslav.me/content/images/2020/09/book-cover.png" alt="" width="500" height="700"><figcaption>Elixir for Non-Ruby Programmers</figcaption></figure><p>Why am I saying all of this? First, because I would love to see greater adoption of Elixir outside Ruby/Rails community. It was among that group of people where the idea first sparked, and I fully respect the fact. Nevertheless, I would love to see it growing out. As someone who discovered Elixir after years of doing Java, &nbsp;.NET and more recently, Go, I can say that there is enough goodness in it for everyone. Moreover, bringing people with different backgrounds (both technical and non-technical) will lead to an explosion of new ideas. Having more diverse minds will help us better understand and make use of the elephant in the room-Erlang.</p><p>This brings me to my second point. Erlang is not obscure at all, once you give it enough attention. It is actually oddly satisfying, once you start reading code written in it. I have had my few a-ha moments, when I figured the original inspiration for most constructs in Elixir. The point is, we shouldn't fear Erlang, but try to understand it. This applies both to when things go well, as well as when they go south.</p><p>My biggest hope of all is that by understanding Erlang well enough, the Elixir community will start looking for new uses for it. Uses that go beyond being a scalable replacement for Rails apps. More daring and more ambitious uses, where Erlang's resilience model can prove to be critical for the success of the mission. I'd love to see it used in transportation, space, as well as the domain that started it all- telecommunications.</p><blockquote>“Shoot for the moon. Even if you miss it you will land among the stars.”<br><strong>Les Brown</strong></blockquote>
                <section>
                  
                  <ul>
                      <li>
                        <a href="https://preslav.me/tag/elixir/" title="Elixir">Elixir</a>
                      </li>
                      <li>
                        <a href="https://preslav.me/tag/programming/" title="Programming">Programming</a>
                      </li>
                      <li>
                        <a href="https://preslav.me/tag/ruby/" title="Ruby">Ruby</a>
                      </li>
                      <li>
                        <a href="https://preslav.me/tag/erlang/" title="Erlang">Erlang</a>
                      </li>
                      <li>
                        <a href="https://preslav.me/tag/2-cents/" title="2 Cents">2 Cents</a>
                      </li>
                  </ul>
                </section>
            </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://preslav.me/2020/09/06/elixir-is-not-ruby-elixir-is-erlang/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24395695</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:07:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
