<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 01:11:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 01:11:08 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Modern action films fetishize the body even as they desexualize it]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 493 | Comments 405 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26381377">thread link</a>) | @Avshalom
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://bloodknife.com/everyone-beautiful-no-one-horny/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bloodknife.com/everyone-beautiful-no-one-horny/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                    
<h3 itemprop="name">
            Everyone Is Beautiful and No One Is Horny    </h3>                    
<h4><strong>Modern action and superhero films fetishize the body, even as they desexualize it.</strong></h4>



<p><strong>by RS Benedict</strong></p>



<p>When Paul Verhoeven adapted <em>Starship Troopers</em> in the late 1990s, did he know he was predicting the future? The endless desert war, the ubiquity of military propaganda, a cheerful face shouting victory as more and more bodies pile up?</p>



<p>But the scene that left perhaps the greatest impact on the minds of Nineties kids—and the scene that anticipated our current cinematic age the best—does not feature bugs or guns. It is, of course, the shower scene, in which our heroic servicemen and -women enjoy a communal grooming ritual.</p>



<p>On the surface, it is idyllic: racial harmony, gender equality, unity behind a common goal—and firm, perky asses and tits.</p>



<p>And then the characters speak. The topic of conversation? Military service, of course. One joined for the sake of her political career. Another joined in the hopes of receiving her breeding license. Another talks about how badly he wants to kill the enemy. No one looks at each other. No one flirts.</p>



<p>A room full of beautiful, bare bodies, and everyone is only horny for war.</p>



<p>*  *  *  *  *</p>



<p>In the early 2000s, there was a brief period where actresses pretended that their thinness was natural, almost accidental. Skinny celebrities confessed their love of burgers and fries in magazines; models undergoing profile interviews engaged in public consumption of pasta; leading ladies joked about how little they exercised and how much they hated it. It was all bullshit: no one looks like that without calorie restriction. We knew it then, and we know it now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We don’t pretend anymore. The promotional cycles for blockbuster movies now include detailed descriptions of the performers’ fitness regimens. We watch actors doing burpees or shaking ropes with expensive personal trainers. There is some talk of diets, though not terribly detailed—and no mention of steroids or other hormonal supplements, even though male actors’ suddenly ultra-swole selfies on Instagram suggest physiques crafted with chemical assistance.</p>



<p>Actors are more physically perfect than ever: impossibly lean, shockingly muscular, with magnificently coiffed hair, high cheekbones, impeccable surgical enhancements, and flawless skin, all displayed in form-fitting superhero costumes with the obligatory shirtless scene thrown in to show off shredded abs and rippling pecs.</p>



<figure><blockquote><p><span><strong>Even background extras are good-looking, or at least inoffensively bland. No one is ugly. No one is really fat. Everyone is beautiful.&nbsp;</strong></span></p></blockquote></figure>



<p>And this isn’t just the lead and the love interest: supporting characters look this way too, and even villains (frequently clad in monstrous makeup) are still played by conventionally attractive performers. Even background extras are good-looking, or at least inoffensively bland. No one is ugly. No one is really fat. Everyone is beautiful.</p>



<p>And yet, <a href="https://www.cheatsheet.com/entertainment/marvel-movies-this-esteemed-director-says-theyre-not-sexy-enough.html/"><strong>no one is horny</strong></a>. Even when they have sex, no one is horny. No one is attracted to anyone else. No one is hungry for anyone else.</p>



<p>When revisiting a beloved Eighties or Nineties film, Millennial and Gen X viewers are often startled to encounter long-forgotten sexual content content: John Connor’s conception in <em>Terminator</em>, Jamie Lee Curtis’s toplessness in <em>Trading Places</em>, the spectral blowjob in <em>Ghostbusters</em>. These scenes didn’t shock us when we first saw them. Of <em>course </em>there’s sex in a movie. Isn’t there always?</p>



<p>The answer, of course, is not anymore—at least not when it comes to modern blockbusters</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/qicstnq7qznw0tipo9fa-1024x640.jpg" alt="" width="511" height="319" srcset="https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/qicstnq7qznw0tipo9fa-1024x640.jpg 1024w, https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/qicstnq7qznw0tipo9fa-300x188.jpg 300w, https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/qicstnq7qznw0tipo9fa-768x480.jpg 768w, https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/qicstnq7qznw0tipo9fa-1536x960.jpg 1536w, https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/qicstnq7qznw0tipo9fa.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 511px) 100vw, 511px"></figure></div>



<p>We’re told that Tony Stark and Pepper Potts are an item, but no actual romantic or sexual chemistry between them is shown in the films. Wonder Woman and Steve Trevor utterly lack the sexual chemistry to convince us that either of them would be thirsty enough to commandeer a coma victim’s body (as they do in <em>Wonder Woman 1984</em>) so they can enjoy a posthumous hookup. In defiance of Norse mythology, Chris Hemsworth’s Thor<em> </em>smiles at Natalie Portman like a dumb golden retriever puppy without ever venturing to rend her asunder with his mighty hammer, so to speak. Not that the competition is any better. Despite accusations of being an incel icon, it is Heath Ledger’s Joker, not Christian Bale’s chaste and sexless Batman, who exudes the most sexual energy in the Dark Knight trilogy.</p>



<p>And speaking of Christopher Nolan’s inexplicably sexless oeuvre—did anyone else think it odd how <em>Inception </em>enters the deepest level of a rich man’s subconscious and finds <em>not </em>a psychosexual Oedipal nightmare of staggering depravity, but… a ski patrol?</p>



<p>*  *  *  *  *</p>



<p>Let’s not pretend that Old Hollywood was a progressive haven of body positivity. Since the departure of voluptuous vamp Theda Bara from the silver screen, actors have always gone to extremes to maintain a certain look. Rita Hayworth underwent an ethnic makeover to appear more Caucasian so she could get leading roles. Stars of the 1920s limited their fluid consumption to two glasses a day to avoid water weight. Jane Fonda suffered from severe bulimia at the height of her sex symbol status; so did Marlon Brando.</p>



<figure><blockquote><p><span><strong>Snake Plissken didn’t fuck on screen, but the character radiates overwhelming sex-haver energy.&nbsp;</strong></span></p></blockquote></figure>



<p>But old films still featured recognizable human bodies and human faces—bodies that could theoretically be achieved by a single person without the aid of a team of personal trainers, dieticians, private chefs, and chemists.&nbsp;</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/actors-featured-2-1024x512.jpg" alt="" width="503" height="252" srcset="https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/actors-featured-2-1024x512.jpg 1024w, https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/actors-featured-2-300x150.jpg 300w, https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/actors-featured-2-768x384.jpg 768w, https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/actors-featured-2-1300x650.jpg 1300w, https://bloodknife.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/actors-featured-2.jpg 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 503px) 100vw, 503px"></figure></div>



<p>In the films of the Eighties and Nineties, leading actors were good looking, yes, but still human. Kurt Russel’s Snake Plissken was a hunk, but in shirtless scenes his abs have no definition. Bruce Willis was handsome, but he’s more muscular now than he was in the Nineties, when he was routinely branded a bona fide sex symbol. And when Isabella Rosselini strips in <em>Blue Velvet</em>, her skin is pale and her body is soft. She looks vulnerable and real.</p>



<p>And yet, these characters fucked. <em>Blue Velvet’s </em>Dorothy Vallens and Jeffrey Beaumant fucked. Michael Keaton’s Batman and Michelle Pfeiffer’s domme Catwoman fucked. Kyle Reese and Sarah Connor fucked. Snake Plissken didn’t fuck on screen, but the character radiates overwhelming sex-haver energy. And I defy you to find a mainstream film with a moment as horny and gay as the <a href="https://io9.gizmodo.com/the-true-story-of-the-lost-boys-sax-man-1842774832"><strong>Sexy Saxophone Solo</strong></a> from <em>The Lost Boys</em>.</p>



<p>*  *  *  *  *</p>



<p>Seen today, one of the most striking scenes in 1982’s Poltergeist is not the evil clown doll or the monster tree, but a moment of relaxed affection between the parents. The father—a bald, beer-bellied Craig T. Nelson—cracks jokes and prances for his wife, who wears a frumpy nightgown and smokes a joint and yammers weed thoughts and laughs at her husband’s silly display. Finally, the husband playfully dives onto the bed. Neither character is glamorous in this scene, but their relationship feels frisky and lived-in and charismatic and <em>real</em>.</p>



<p>The house looks real, too. There are toys and magazines scattered around the floor. There are cardboard boxes waiting to be unpacked since the recent move. Framed pictures rest against the wall; the parents haven’t gotten around to mounting them yet. The kitchen counters are cluttered and mealtimes are rambunctious and sloppy, as one expects in a house with three children. They’re building a pool in the backyard, but not for appearances: it’s a place for the kids to swim, for the parents to throw parties, and for the father to reacquaint himself with his love of diving.</p>



<p>At the time, this house represented an aspirational ideal of American affluence.</p>



<p>Compare this to homes in films now: massive, sterile cavernous spaces with minimalist furniture. Kitchens are industrial-sized and spotless, and they contain no food. There is no excess. There is no mess.</p>



<figure><blockquote><p><span><strong>A body is no longer a holistic system. It is not the vehicle through which we experience joy and pleasure. It is not a home to live in and be happy.&nbsp;</strong></span></p></blockquote></figure>



<p>In her blog McMansion Hell, Kate Wagner examines precisely why these widely-hated 5000-square foot housing bubble behemoths are so awful. Over and over again, she reiterates the point that McMansions are not built to be homes; they’re built to be short-term investments.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://mcmansionhell.com/post/150597521816/mcmansions-101-revisited-aesthetics-aside-why"><strong>Kate writes</strong></a>, “The inside of McMansions are designed in order to cram the most ‘features’ inside for the lowest costs.” These features exist to increase the house’s resale value, not to make it a good place to live. No thought is given to the labor needed to clean and maintain these spaces. The master bathroom includes intricate stone surfaces that can only be scrubbed with a toothbrush; the cathedral ceilings in the living room raise the heating and cooling costs to an exorbitant sum; the chandelier in the grand entryway dangles so high that no one can replace the bulbs in it, even with a stepladder.</p>



<p>The same fate has befallen our bodies. A body is no longer a holistic system. It is not the vehicle through which we experience joy and pleasure during our brief time in the land of the living. It is not a home to live in and be happy. It, too, is a collection of features: six pack, thigh gap, cum gutters. And these features exist not to make our lives more comfortable, but to increase the value of our assets. Our bodies are investments, which must always be optimized to bring us… what, exactly? Some vague sense of better living? Is a life without bread objectively better than a life with it? When we were children, did we dream of counting every calorie and logging every step?</p>



<p>A generation or two ago, it was normal for adults to engage in sports not purely as self-improvement but as an act of leisure. People danced for fun; couples socialized over tennis; kids played stickball for lack of anything else to do. Solitary exercise at the gym also had a social, rather than moral, purpose. People worked out to look hot so they could attract other hot people and fuck them. Whatever the ethos …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://bloodknife.com/everyone-beautiful-no-one-horny/">https://bloodknife.com/everyone-beautiful-no-one-horny/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bloodknife.com/everyone-beautiful-no-one-horny/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26381377</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 01:10:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What Happens Inside a 100-Hop IPv6 Wireless Mesh Network?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 99 | Comments 10 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26380520">thread link</a>) | @tdrnd
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/100-hops-ipv6-mesh/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/100-hops-ipv6-mesh/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          <section><p>A <a href="https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/iot-sub-ghz-mesh">wireless mesh network</a> is a network where the nodes in the network help other nodes achieve coverage and connectivity by forwarding messages on behalf of&nbsp;others.</p>
<p>Street lighting systems is an example of where a wireless mesh network is needed. A single-hop network would not provide enough coverage, so the lights help each other to reach&nbsp;out.</p>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div data-controls="#filterControls" data-animation="quicksand" data-x-gap="15" data-y-gap="15" data-media-queries="[
{&quot;width&quot;: 1500, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 1100, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 800, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 480, &quot;cols&quot;: 1},
{&quot;width&quot;: 300, &quot;cols&quot;: 1}
]">


<div>
<div>
<article>
<a href="https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/100-hops-ipv6-mesh/streetlight-mesh.png">
<img src="https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/100-hops-ipv6-mesh/streetlight-mesh.png" alt="A wireless IPv6 mesh IoT network in the wild">
<span>
<span>
<span></span>
</span>
</span>
</a>

</article>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>



<p>The picture above shows an installation of a <a href="https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/why-iot-platform/" target="_blank">Thingsquare IoT platform</a> IPv6 mesh in the wild. (Although our system is known to be able to run on really, tiny devices operated by a <a href="https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/sensortag-power/" target="_blank">single coin-cell battery</a>, this particular installation does not use those low-power mechanisms as street lights have access to&nbsp;power.)</p>
<p>The big challenge with such a large wireless network is to understand what is going on – and how to develop the software that makes them&nbsp;tick.</p>
<p>In this article we look into how we develop such large-scale systems at Thingsquare and the tools we use. We push the envelope with a 100-hop network, which is larger than what we typically would see in real-world&nbsp;installations.</p>


<h2 id="a-100-node-wireless-testbed">A 100-Node Wireless&nbsp;Testbed</h2>
<p>To see what happens in a 100-hop network, we have built a testbed in our office. The testbed consists of  100 wireless nodes placed in a bookshelf. The nodes all use the <a href="http://www.ti.com/product/CC2538" target="_blank"><span>TI</span> CC2538 wireless System-on-a-Chip</a>, running the Thingsquare wireless mesh over a <span>IEEE</span> 802.15.4e low-power radio layer. The nodes are powered by USB, but otherwise have only a wireless connection. Each node also has an LED, which we use to develop and test our wireless lighting system. By default, the nodes form one large wireless&nbsp;network.</p>
<div>
<div>
<p><img src="https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/100-hops-ipv6-mesh/testbed.jpg" alt="IPv6 IoT mesh network wireless testbed">
</p>
<p><img src="https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/100-hops-ipv6-mesh/testbed-singlehop.gif" alt="IPv6 IoT mesh network wireless visualization view">
</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>
A 100-node testbed and the wireless mesh network created by the nodes in the&nbsp;testbed.
</p>
</div>
</div>

<p>Because every node in the testbed is close to each other, they can easily form a single-hop network. That is, every node can reach every other node without&nbsp;meshing.</p>
<p>To setup a 100-hop network, we manually configure their routes. This way, we can force the system to become a 100-hop&nbsp;network.</p>
<h3 id="setting-up-100-hops">Setting up 100&nbsp;Hops</h3>
<p>After configuring the system to have a 100-hop structure, the mesh looks like&nbsp;this:</p>
<div>
<div>
<p><img src="https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/100-hops-ipv6-mesh/100-dralite.gif" alt="IPv6 6lowpan IoT wireless mesh network with 100 hops">
</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>
The 100-node testbed in a 100-hop wireless mesh&nbsp;configuration.
</p>
</div>
</div>

<p>We now have a way to test the system with 100 hops, something that is beyond anything we are likely to see in the&nbsp;wild.</p>
<h3 id="100-hops-in-action">100 Hops in&nbsp;Action</h3>
<p>To see the 100 hops in action, we set up one node to act as a sniffer and run Wireshark to capture the packets from the network. We then ask the node that is 100 hops away to make a secure <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transport_Layer_Security" target="_blank"><span>TLS</span> connection</a> with the backend. In the Wireshark logs, we see the <span>TLS</span> traffic as well as the ICMPv6 control traffic that is used by the RPL routing protocol to set up and maintain its routing&nbsp;graph.</p>
<p>(For more in-depth information about the <span>RPL</span> IPv6 routing protocol, see <a href="https://www.thingsquare.com/docs/mesh/" target="_blank">this article</a> from our&nbsp;docs.)</p>
<div>
<div>
<p><img src="https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/100-hops-ipv6-mesh/wireshark.png" alt="IoT network security inspection of TLS traffic">
</p>
<p><img src="https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/100-hops-ipv6-mesh/wireshark2.png" alt="IoT network security inspection of TLS traffic">
</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>
Wireshark logs from the sniffer showing ICMPv6 and <span>TLS</span>&nbsp;traffic.
</p>
</div>
</div>

<p>If we look at the traffic inside the network, we can see how the packets move from node to node, in a snake-like&nbsp;manner:</p>
<div>
<div>
<p><img src="https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/100-hops-ipv6-mesh/100-packetdump-5.gif" alt="IoT network packets">
</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>
Packets move through every node in the network, 100 hops in&nbsp;total.
</p>
</div>
</div>

<h2 id="in-the-simulator">In the&nbsp;Simulator</h2>
<p>A wireless mesh system is extremely complex and while a testbed is essential to testing the system, it is not enough for developing&nbsp;it.</p>
<p>To develop our wireless mesh system, we use our wireless network simulator. The simulator lets us set up the same environment as we see in the real world, but on a single computer. There, we can inspect almost every aspect of the system to see what is going&nbsp;on.</p>
<div>
<div>
<p><img src="https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/100-hops-ipv6-mesh/cooja.png" alt="IoT IPv6 network wireless simulator">
</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>
The Cooja wireless network&nbsp;simulator.
</p>
</div>
</div>

<p>To see a similar behavior as we did our testbed, we set up a simulation with a regular grid of nodes and configure them in a similar fashion as we did in the testbed: they choose parents in the routing graph to make the network as long as&nbsp;possible.</p>
<p>The simulator also lets us see the packets in a timeline window, where we can see exactly what each node does at any given&nbsp;time.</p>
<div>
<div>
<p><img src="https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/100-hops-ipv6-mesh/cooja3-tls-network.gif" alt="IoT IPv6 network wireless simulator with TLS secure protocol traffic">
</p>
<p><img src="https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/100-hops-ipv6-mesh/cooja3-tls-timeline.gif" alt="IoT IPv6 network wireless simulator with TLS secure protocol traffic">
</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>
A <span>TLS</span> connection in the network and timeline views. We see the packet exchange across multiple&nbsp;hops.
</p>
</div>
</div>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Wireless mesh networking allow us to build extremely large-scale networks. But such networks are complex and to build the software that make them tick, we need both hardware testbeds and software&nbsp;simulators.</p>
</section>
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.thingsquare.com/blog/articles/100-hops-ipv6-mesh/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26380520</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 22:44:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Review: The Book of Why]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 120 | Comments 27 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26379695">thread link</a>) | @pizzicato
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://tachy.org/posts/book-of-why/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://tachy.org/posts/book-of-why/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <div id="main-container">
        



<p><a href="http://bayes.cs.ucla.edu/WHY/"><em>The Book of Why: The New Science of Cause and Effect</em></a> is a collaborative effort aimed at a general audience by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Judea_Pearl">Judea Pearl</a>, a professor of computer science at UCLA, and <a href="http://danamackenzie.com/">Dana Mackenzie</a>, a science writer. As a medical student with a laughably poor formal education in statistics, I believe I qualify as a card-carrying member of the general audience. Here's my review in three parts: i) an overview of topics covered by the book, ii) my thoughts, and iii) links to other reviews and further reading.</p>
<p>The book grounds Pearl's theoretical work on causal inference in a multitude of realistic and real examples, drawn from a range of disciplines including economics, biology, and law. Pearl himself is a pretty <a href="https://amturing.acm.org/award_winners/pearl_2658896.cfm">Big Deal</a> in computer science. Throughout the book, he demonstrates how his causal methods can be applied to many diverse fields of research, but it's clear that what excites him the most is its potential in artificial intelligence.</p>
<p>What is causal inference? When we perform scientific studies, we're often interested in the relationship between variables (treatments, risk factors, diseases, outcomes). Scientific studies that investigate these relationships can be divided into two types: observational and interventional. Observational studies can identify associations, but they cannot tell you anything about the direction of that association. There may be other variables that distort your results by concealing a true relationship, or worse, by generating false ones. That's why researchers turn to interventional studies as a more reliable source of evidence—specifically, randomised controlled trials (RCTs). The problem is, RCTs are not always ethical or feasible, and they require more resources to set up and run. Enter the exciting field of causal inference, which aims to answer questions about cause and effect from observational data.</p>
<p>A brief word on what causal inference is <em>not</em>—this is something that took me a while to wrap my head around. Causal inference doesn't tell us from scratch what the causes of an event are. Nor is it able to "prove" that one variable caused another. Those questions belong to the realm of causal <em>discovery</em>. Instead, causal inference aims to draw richer interpretations beyond mere associations from observational data. We can answer questions such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Which of these variables actually affect the outcome?</li>
<li>What is the magnitude of effect of each individual treatment variable on the outcome?</li>
<li>What are the mechanisms underlying a complex problem such as cancer?</li>
</ul>
<p>The catch is that, whether explicitly or implicitly, you must make
assumptions in the first place about the directions of causality among the variables. In many cases, the data can <em>support</em> your assumptions, but any
relationships you observe in the data without considering these prior
assumptions are purely correlation. And you know the drill,
<em>correlation is not causation</em>...</p>
<p>There are many approaches to causal inference, of which Pearl's is
characterised by two techniques: graphs (DAGs) and <em>do</em>-calculus. More
on that in a minute.</p>
<h2>Ladder of causation</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Rung 1: Associations, observational data (seeing)</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Rung 2: Intervention (doing)</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Rung 3: Counterfactuals (imagining)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Pearl proposes this framework which we can use to categorise the various techniques of causal inference. At the bottom lies passive observation of a system,
allowing us to find direction-free associations. The next rung up is
intervention: by explicitly setting the values of treatment variables,
we abolish the effects of confounders. This is even more effective
with randomisation, which is why RCTs are hailed as the gold standard
of scientific studies.</p>
<p>Going beyond intervention is the idea of the counterfactual, or
<em>what-if</em> thinking. If this person had never smoked, would he
still have gotten lung cancer? Counterfactuals are subtly but
crucially different from interventions. These hypothetical questions
pertain to what might have been, and cannot actually happen in the real
world. We can intervene by stopping that person with lung cancer from
smoking now, but we can't erase that lung cancer patient's 50-year history of smoking, which is the counterfactual question we're asking in this
case. Think of counterfactuals as parallel universes. Counterfactuals strengthen the case for a causal relationship:
if <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mi>A</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">A</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> causes <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mi>B</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">B</annotation></semantics></math></span></span>, then <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mi>B</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">B</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> shouldn't happen in the abscence of <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mi>A</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">A</annotation></semantics></math></span></span>. Of
course, things are rarely this simple in real life, and the authors also discuss <em>necessary</em> and <em>sufficienct</em> causes.</p>
<h2>DAGs</h2>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Directed_acyclic_graph">DAG</a> stands for "directed acyclic graph". A DAG is simply a diagram
containing nodes that are connected by edges (lines) with directions,
and tracing these edges according to their directions should not result in a closed loop. In causal analysis, DAGs are used to represent
the relationships between variables in a system, with the directed
edges indicating the (assumed) direction of causation.</p>
<p>Pearl is a vocal proponent of graphical models in causal
inference. DAGs, he argues, are much more intuitive than algrebraic
expressions in illustrating complex problems. Importantly, DAGs can
clearly tell us which variables should be controlled for and which
ones should be left as they are. Confounders (common causes) are commonly defined as variables that are associated with both the treatment variable and the outcome variable, and everyone knows we need to control for confounders. However, there are in fact other types of variables that are associated with both the treatment and the outcome that should <em>not</em> be controlled for. A common example is collider variables (common effects); controlling for a collider will create a spurious association between treatment and outcome, where there was previously none. DAGs are
invaluable in highlighting these potential pitfalls as our models get
more complex.</p>
<p>See <a href="https://cjasn.asnjournals.org/content/clinjasn/12/3/546/F3.large.jpg">here</a> for graphical representations of confounders, mediators, and colliders.</p>
<h2><em>do</em>-calculus</h2>
<p><em>do</em>-calculus is the other pillar of Pearl's approach to causal
inference, refined over the years by his students. I have to admit
that this entire topic has flown right over my head, and the authors don't
make it easy to follow in the book. Reading about how <em>do</em>-calculus
was derived and how it may be used felt a lot like "<a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/how-to-draw-an-owl">How to Draw An
Owl"</a> material.</p>
<p>At a high level, <em>do</em>-calculus is basically a formalised, mathematical
way of expressing interventions in contrast to observations. Conditional probabilities contain no information about causality. <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mi>P</mi><mo>(</mo><mi>A</mi><mo>∣</mo><mi>B</mi><mo>)</mo></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">P(A \mid B)</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> represents the probability of <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mi>A</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">A</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> given that <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mi>B</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">B</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> is <em>observed</em>, a concept that lies at the bottom rung of Pearl's Ladder of Causation. To show the probability of <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mi>A</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">A</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> when you cause <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mi>B</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">B</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> to happen in an experiment, you would write <span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mi>P</mi><mo>[</mo><mi>A</mi><mo>∣</mo><mi>d</mi><mi>o</mi><mo>(</mo><mi>B</mi><mo>)</mo><mo>]</mo></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">P[A \mid do(B)]</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> instead. When you're able to manipulate a treatment variable statistically, you can also delete arrows pointing towards it in a DAG, which may reveal new confounders, colliders, and mediators. Using <a href="https://stats.stackexchange.com/questions/350267/a-layman-understanding-of-the-difference-between-back-door-and-front-door-adjust">front-door adjustment</a>, we can also control for <em>unobserved</em> confounders, which is pretty darn nifty.</p>
<h2>Topics</h2>
<p>As its subtitle suggests, <em>The Book of Why</em> is ambitious in scope and
touches upon a dizzying array of seminal ideas from the 19th and 20th
century. These are the main topics covered in each chapter (paraphrased by me to be more informative; not actual titles).</p>
<ul>
<li>Chapter 1: Pearl's Ladder of Causation</li>
<li>Chapter 2: Sewall Wright and path analysis, a major
influence on Pearl</li>
<li>Chapter 3: Bayes' theorem and Pearl's work on Bayesian
networks</li>
<li>Chapter 4: Confounders, mediators, colliders, and back-door adjustment</li>
<li>Chapter 5: How causal inference could have resolved the
smoking-and-cancer debate</li>
<li>Chapter 6: Causal inference applied to statistical paradoxes
(Monty Hall problem, Simpson's paradox, Berkson's paradox, Lord's
paradox)</li>
<li>Chapter 7: <em>do</em>-calculus, front-door adjustment, and instrumental variables</li>
<li>Chapter 8: Counterfactuals, potential outcomes, and structural
equation modelling</li>
<li>Chapter 9: Mediation analysis</li>
<li>Chapter 10: The role of causal inference in Big Data and AI</li>
</ul>
<h2>My thoughts on <em>The Book of Why</em></h2>
<p>Let's start with the obvious. This book dwells on the history of statistics a lot, and statisticians, as the authors would have you believe, are zealots who have conspired to keep causal thinking out of their field right from the start. That is, until Pearl instigated the "Causal Revolution", as he dubs it, the latest and greatest gift to modern science. I have no dog in this fight, but Pearl (whom I assume is the source of most of these opinions put to paper by Mackenzie) often comes across as wildly biased and grandiose. For what it's worth, I doubt that statisticians as a whole are anywhere as malicious or ignorant as they're portrayed in this book.</p>
<p>I'm confused about the intended audience. This book is
simultaneously too simplistic for experts and too technical for
lay people (i.e. me). I suspect the ideal reader lies somewhere in between: someone with a solid grasp of basic statistics and maths who is interested in causal analysis. The authors' contempt and mischaracterisations of the entire field of statistics are unlikely to sit well with said reader, though.</p>
<p>There are many minor errors in the edition I have, including some
inexplicably basic ones that conflate odds and probability, but <a href="http://bayes.cs.ucla.edu/WHY/errata-pages-PearlMackenzie_BookofWhy_Final.pdf">this
PDF</a> contains the errata.</p>
<p>Overall, I'm pretty satisfied with what I got out of this book, I
think. While
Pearl's opinion of statistics and of his own work are on extreme ends of a
spectrum, and similarly irksome, there is much to celebrate in
this strange tome. I really appreciate the breadth of topics and historical anecdotes that feature here, sprinkled with a healthy dash of philosophy. I'm also very intrigued about the applications of causal inference in biomedical research, and this book has led me to the opening of many tantalising rabbit holes. However, I strongly recommend reading Pearl's technical overview instead (link below), which is very similar to <em>The Book of Why</em>, but more concise and palatable.</p>
<h2>Other reviews and associated discussion</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://doi.org/10.1090/noti1912">Lisa Goldberg for the American …</a></li></ul></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://tachy.org/posts/book-of-why/">https://tachy.org/posts/book-of-why/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://tachy.org/posts/book-of-why/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26379695</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 20:57:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Switzerland votes against electronic ID system provided by private companies]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 586 | Comments 337 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26377906">thread link</a>) | @bontoJR
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://www.swissinfo.ch/eng/digital-identity-scheme-faces-scepticism-around-data-privacy/46399636 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.swissinfo.ch/eng/digital-identity-scheme-faces-scepticism-around-data-privacy/46399636">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<section>
<div>
<div>
<figure>
<picture>
<source srcset="https://www.swissinfo.ch/resource/image/46427574/landscape_ratio3x2/880/587/364d58ef489c19d62b4514b5cc7357ea/E1340BD670F774490106371C395F66E0/438881215_highres.jpg" media="(min-width: 900px)">
<source srcset="https://www.swissinfo.ch/resource/image/46427574/landscape_ratio3x2/580/387/364d58ef489c19d62b4514b5cc7357ea/DF204523D16B6612A3C3D944D1829178/438881215_highres.jpg" media="(min-width: 321px)">

</picture>
<figcaption>
The government has called for joint efforts to push ahead with digitalisation despite voters' rejection of the eID on Sunday. <span>© Keystone/Christian Beutler</span>
</figcaption> </figure>
</div>
</div><p>Voters in Switzerland have thrown out a law governing a proposed&nbsp;electronic identity system. The result is&nbsp; a blow for plans by parliament and the government amid fears about data protection.</p>
<span>This content was published on March 7, 2021 - 18:16</span>
<time datetime="2021-03-07T18:16:00+01:00">

</time><address data-uk-scrollspy="hidden: false; repeat: true; offset-top: -50">

</address><p>Final results show 64.4% of voters coming out against the planned law on Sunday.&nbsp;The rejection rate among the cantons ranged between 70.7% and 55.8%.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>At stake was the creation of the legal basis for a digital identity verification system, to be licenced and controlled by the state but provided mainly by private companies.</p><p>The single access point is aimed at simplifying the use of online services offered by commercial businesses as well as contact with public institutions via e-government channels.</p>
<p>“Mistrust in private companies was&nbsp;dominant and helped to tip the vote,”&nbsp;said political scientist Urs Bieri of the GfS Bern research institute on SRF public radio.</p><p>Justice Minister Karin Keller-Sutter acknowledged “a certain unease”&nbsp;among voters. She called on parliament and critics of the failed plan to now cooperate to avoid a standstill.</p><p>“We have no choice and must work towards a new solution, even if it takes several attempts,”&nbsp;she told a news conference. “It is key for Switzerland to catch up with other countries when it comes digitalisation.”</p><p>Daniel Graf of the referendum committee said voters had not come out against a digital identity scheme but only against the proposed solution. Green Party parliamentarian Sibel Arslan, who also opposed the law, said voters made it clear that they want an eID provided only by the&nbsp;government and under democratic control.</p><p>People's Party parliamentarian&nbsp;Franz Grüter, a supporter of the failed electronic identity scheme, said he was disappointed but is confident that a solution&nbsp;can be found for a new proposal.</p>
<h2>Civil society group</h2><p>The law at stake was approved by parliament in 2019 but then <a href="https://www.swissinfo.ch/eng/data-security-issue-causes-concern-over-swiss-digital-id/46300224" target="_blank" rel="noopener">challenged to a referendum</a>&nbsp;by an alliance of civil society groups, backed by trade unions as well as left-wing and some centrist parties.</p><p>The opponents argued the state should not be limited to acting as a licensing and oversight authority but that it should take full responsibility. The risk of data abuse by commercial providers would undermine the effort to make digitalisation more democratic, they say.</p><p>That said, the need for some form of an eID for the business community was not contested by opponents. Switzerland is lagging behind many European countries following unsuccessful attempts over the past decades to set up a single login system for users of online services.</p>
<h2>No capacity</h2><p>The government, which launched the bill three years ago, had said the proposed law sets the basis for a secure online login system.</p><p>During the campaign, Keller-Sutter praised the law as&nbsp;a compromise, sharing out the tasks between the state and the private sector.</p><p>Supporters of the law also pointed out that almost no government has the IT capacity and resources to single-handedly develop an eID quickly and to the appropriate standards.</p><p>A previous attempt to set up a public-private e-identity solution, known as&nbsp;<a href="https://www.swissinfo.ch/eng/orell-fuessli_swiss-passport-printer-meets-digital-id-challenge-head-on/45697922" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SuisseID</a>, failed more than ten years ago.</p><h2>Complex and Covid</h2><p>The relative complexity of the issue at stake made it challenging for citizens to form their opinion, said Lukas Golder, co-director of the GfS Bern research institute.</p><p>Doubts over the practical use of the eID and concerns about potential data abuse have been overwhelming, he said.</p>
<p>Several political scientists also pointed out that opposition to the law was a protest vote against the government and its anti-Covid policy.</p><p>Keller-Sutter said&nbsp;the current restrictions on public gatherings due to the pandemic had made campaigning and face-to-face meeting with voters more difficult.&nbsp;</p><p>Public attention also appeared to focus more on the other issues up for vote on Sunday: a proposal to <a href="https://www.swissinfo.ch/eng/swiss--burka-ban--vote-too-close-to-call/46420534" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ban facial coverings, including the burka</a>, and to a lesser extent, a <a href="https://www.swissinfo.ch/eng/swiss-direct-democracy-could-undo-a-free-trade-deal-with-indonesia/46422650" target="_blank" rel="noopener">controversial free trade deal</a> between Switzerland and Indonesia, the world’s top producer of palm oil.</p><div role="region" aria-label="Infobox"><h2>Votes March 7, 2021</h2><p>Ban on facial covering/Burka:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 51.2% yes&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 48.8% no</p><p>Digital identification/eID:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 35.6% yes&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 64.4% no</p><p>Free trade accord with Indonesia:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 51.6.% yes&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 48.4% no</p><p>Turnout: 51.4%</p><p>About 5.5 million Swiss citizens, including registered expat Swiss, were eligible to take part in the votes.</p><p>There were also numerous ballots at cantonal and local levels on March 7.</p><p><span>End of insertion</span></p></div> </section>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.swissinfo.ch/eng/digital-identity-scheme-faces-scepticism-around-data-privacy/46399636</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26377906</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 17:45:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Mito – Write Python/Pandas faster by editing a spreadsheet, in Jupyter]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 91 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26377559">thread link</a>) | @aarondia
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://trymito.io/launch | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://trymito.io/launch">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://trymito.io/launch</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26377559</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 17:10:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I Bought a Business for $0]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 261 | Comments 99 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26377535">thread link</a>) | @catchmeifyoucan
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://every.to/superorganizers/how-i-bought-a-business-for-0 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://every.to/superorganizers/how-i-bought-a-business-for-0">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <p><em>Hiâ€”Dan here. We're continuing Justin Mares's column on side businesses today! You can read previous editions </em><a href="https://every.to/@jwmares" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>here</em></a><em>.</em></p><p>Before starting <a href="http://kettleandfire.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Kettle &amp; Fire</a>, I had a previous life in the SaaS world. I ran growth for a team (Exceptional Cloud Services)&nbsp; that bought small SaaS apps and grew them. We later sold the bundle of businesses to Rackspace for 8 figures, in early 2013.&nbsp;</p><p>When I left Rackspace after the acquisition and went out on my own, I wanted to replicate the model weâ€™d seen so much success with at Exceptional. I wanted to buy and grow my own SaaS business.&nbsp;</p><p>My partner Ryan and I were on the lookout for a business that fulfilled one of the <a href="https://every.to/superorganizers/the-four-kinds-of-side-hustles-2083436" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">side hustle criteria</a> Iâ€™ve written about before. A strong potential acquisition had to:</p><ul><li>Solve a problem someone is already aware of,</li><li>In a niche where customers are already paying,</li><li>Where the product <em>does not</em> require a lot of maintenance or hand-holding,</li><li>And is profitable or has a no-brainer path to profitability</li></ul><p>In early 2016, we stumbled across Notify: a simple Shopify plugin that would pop up at the bottom of a website, displaying a purchase another customer had recently made.</p><p><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/snCfaj5_C-1syTXy4LkPpzKMFBlQ52St0OM2P3E_zqzUVp9_Wt58QG4D2o6G3nuXYiamO1LNNi1b_cicP1781j0-BxSHMr0-XxKpoP7qY0ADq-Vq_xrId6tVHnM6keJxQ87B5CSD"></p><p>Once I saw it in action, I immediately installed it on <a href="https://www.kettleandfire.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Kettle &amp; Fire</a> and saw a 40% lift in conversionâ€¦ and $1,400 in extra sales (this was 2016â€¦ K&amp;F was a lot smaller then ðŸ™ƒ).</p><p><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/XaXoTmu3NxGZOEawmBfaPUhytLba2rid3i3Wf6PfomzNiAukmhLSZl-Mu3RFSjQtwZRFE8hle4yE2Ty1y5jHEkCJPv7VfoPxsaQ0cNbkiTu84Vw5JCHa4rF-JYCLi9f5haDumRSe"></p><p>Woah.&nbsp;</p><p>If it helped my site this much, how many others see a similar sales lift? We had a strong hunch that we could buy Notify, add a few features, put some marketing behind it and grow it quite a bit.&nbsp;</p><p>On February 1, we fired off this email:</p><p><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/HEMvbe7q_x7pz90iv_OjztnMmZgiPL4Pw_QjIlFmh84HsiEX8XA6Q7UuNKALqkx_mmBMZNaufWI_SjIj2JI1Qa8B09dw63vBWYFTiek2YFbd5uZM8-ACoIlpDIq7awjpG6jOm3p4"></p><p>Buying an app, no matter how small, is a lot of work. Iâ€™d tried to purchase other software businesses in the past and understood how hard it was to come to an agreement. The process involves a good bit of legal spend and can fall apart at the drop of a hat: lessons learned after spending $10k on legal for a failed acquisition 12 months prior ðŸ¤¦.&nbsp;</p><p>We first wanted to see how serious Notifyâ€™s owner, Scott, was about selling. We emailed him and grabbed dinner just one week after our first email exchange.</p><p>During dinner, Ryan and I expressed our admiration for what Scott had accomplishedâ€”which was truly impressive. We covered our backgrounds, and shared the many ideas we had for the product that could take it to the next level.&nbsp;</p><p>Dinner went swimmingly and we learned a LOT about the product. Within a day or two, we followed up with super early diligence questions:</p><p><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/oQNRoVWMgHJ3bEzzDTXffQnVO1ipHtGFyUQkSqBy-M56RTL8wJ1ZL_xE-Aq9caFXoz5FtlQ4Aoa_ON-04u3Su5s4y1A2zT5vIFCznVUFurYclJy1whYDgqmHXXvSyJ2AzJexRqbS"></p><p>After taking four days to review the numbers he sent over, we responded with a Letter of Intent: a legal but non-binding letter showing we were serious about buying the business. An LOI also serves to ensure that both parties are aligned on high-level terms: what weâ€™d pay, when those payments would hit, etc.&nbsp;</p><h2>Actually buying the business</h2><p>Letâ€™s pause here for a second to address some common misconceptions.&nbsp;</p><p>First, it may feel like youâ€™re listening to Uncle Warren Buffett espousing the benefits and strong returns that come from buying a railroad. <em>Thanks Warren, but how the hell does this apply to me?&nbsp;</em></p><p>The truth is, you donâ€™t need a lot (or any) money to buy many of these small businesses. Many small businesses you can actually buy for $0 up front, if you negotiate it properly and find a motivated seller. Where revenue is less than $20K per month, many of the businesses youâ€™re looking at arenâ€™t businesses at all: theyâ€™re jobs. And if you find an owner (like we did) who wants to quit his job, you can make a deal happen. Youâ€™ll get what you want (a revenue-generating business), the seller gets what he wants (his time back and money for his efforts), and everybody wins.&nbsp;</p><p>While negotiating this acquisition, I kept in mind something one of my mentors shared when buying assets. Assuming youâ€™re not in crazy hot competition for something, it often pays to approach deals in a certain way: â€œ<strong>my price, your terms OR your price, my terms.</strong>â€�&nbsp;</p><p>Letâ€™s say we wanted to buy an app for $1M, and wanted to pay for it over 1-2 years with monthly cash payments. Our lovely seller wants to sell for $1.5M.&nbsp;</p><p>In a scenario like this, weâ€™d put in an offer of $1M cash, up-front (his terms, our price) and see if that gets it done. Alternatively, if the seller was firm on price but didnâ€™t care as much about cash right now, weâ€™d offer $1.5M paid out over 1-2 years in monthly cash payments. His price, our terms.&nbsp;</p><p>In this case, we ended up going with the other option for the Notify deal: the price the owner wanted for the company, on our terms.</p><p>Scott, Notifyâ€™s owner, wanted a high (but fair) price, and wanted to have a piece of the upside going forward. We landed on a structure that would reach his goals <em>and</em> allow us to buy the business for literally $0.&nbsp;</p><p>Hereâ€™s how (<em>note: numbers are not actuals</em>):</p><ol><li>We agreed on an overall value of the business: call it $500K.&nbsp;</li><li>We then discussed how much ownership Scott wanted to maintain in the entity going forward. Letâ€™s say we landed at 20%: we then subtracted that ownership from the total purchase price, and had to figure out how to come up with $400K to buy 80% of the business.&nbsp;</li><li>As I said earlier: he chose the price, we chose the terms. Our terms were that weâ€™d buy the business via a series of monthly payments over the next 20 months. So, in our example $400K required purchase amount, weâ€™d pay $20K/mo to buy the business.&nbsp;</li><li>Hereâ€™s the kicker: we structured the deal so that payments would begin 60 days after close. Because the business was already doing more than our monthly payments to the seller, as long as the business didnâ€™t implode (it didnâ€™t ðŸ˜…), <strong>weâ€™d be able to buy the business with its own revenue</strong>. $0 out of our own pockets.&nbsp;</li></ol><p>Once the price and terms were baked into the LOI (and the seller signed), we moved into deeper diligence. Just 23 days after our first email to Scott ðŸ�Žï¸�!&nbsp;</p><p>We asked him to complete a questionnaire about Notifyâ€™s growth, revenue, tools used, etc., as well as give us all the logins related to the business. Over the next two weeks, as we dug into the info he sent us, we worked with a lawyer to pull together an Asset Purchase Agreement (APA)â€”the document that would make the sale official.</p><p>Fast forward to closing day: March 10, 2016. We received a signed APA, and became owners of a business that was generating cash!</p><p>Several years later, Notify has become <a href="http://fomo.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Fomo</a>: a software business that does $1M+ each year.&nbsp;</p><p>Though buying a small SaaS business is more competitive now, there are still a ton of opportunities to buy small assets and scale them on the side. If I were to run this strategy again, Iâ€™d focus on a few areas:</p><ol><li>Buying land and putting it on Hipcamp and other camping rental sites (as I discussed in <a href="https://justinmares.substack.com/p/the-next-brand-episode-13" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">my last newsletter</a>, please God someone reach out to me and help me do this).&nbsp;</li><li>Buying up small apps in the Google Chrome or Mac app store.</li><li>Buying assets on rapidly growing platforms. Could you buy out a Fortnite skins developer? A creator on Roblox? A top theme developer on Webflow or Shopify? A tool on Figma?&nbsp;</li><li>Buying small software businesses in industries tech doesnâ€™t traditionally touch. In my world of CPG (consumer packaged goods) and food, there are a <em>ton</em><strong> </strong>of small software opportunities where a strong operator could buy an asset, tune it up, and do quite well.&nbsp;</li></ol><p>Happy hunting!&nbsp;</p><p><em>Note â€“ this post originally appeared on Justin's newsletter&nbsp;</em><a href="https://justinmares.substack.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>The Next Brand</em></a><em>.</em></p>
      </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://every.to/superorganizers/how-i-bought-a-business-for-0</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26377535</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 17:07:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Get Better at Recursion]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 58 | Comments 59 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26377312">thread link</a>) | @eatonphil
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://notes.eatonphil.com/practicing-recursion.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://notes.eatonphil.com/practicing-recursion.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <div>
        <p>tldr; reimplement standard library functions in your favorite
language <em>without loops</em>.</p>
<h3 id="background">Background</h3><p>For a few years after college I spent a lot of free time doing
projects in Standard ML and Scheme. As a result I got really
comfortable doing recursion. The two big reasons for this are 1)
neither Standard ML or Scheme have loops and 2) they both have very
small standard libraries. (Ok, they have loops. They're just so
limited as to be useless.)</p>
<p>I ended up building <a href="https://github.com/eatonphil/ponyo">a standard
library</a> for Standard ML including
string functions (contains, indexOf, count, replace, etc.), an HTTP
server and client, a hash table, a binary search tree, parts of a
Standard ML parser, and <a href="https://ponyo.org/reference">so on</a>.</p>
<p>All of this without loops.</p>
<h3 id="strategy">Strategy</h3><p>The good news (if you don't want to learn a new language) is that you
don't have to take up Standard ML or Scheme to get better at
recursion. But you do need to dedicate some time to <em>practicing
recursion</em> to get better at it.</p>
<p>My recommendation would be to pick 10-20 string or array functions out
of your favorite language's standard library and reimplement them
without loops. (Obviously, start simple and just pick one. But
don't stop there.)</p>
<h3 id="some-examples">Some examples</h3><p>Here's an example reimplementation of <code>indexOf</code> in
JavaScript:</p>
<pre><code>function indexOf(input, toMatch) {
  function helper(index, offset, test) {
    if (index === input.length) {
      return -1;
    }

    if (toMatch === test) {
      return index;
    }

    if (input[index+offset] !== toMatch[offset] || test.length &gt; toMatch.length) {
      return helper(index+1, 0, "");
    }

    return helper(index, offset+1, test+input[index+offset]);
  }

  return helper(0, 0, "");
}
</code></pre>
<p>Or here's an example immutable reimplementation of <code>insert</code>
in Python:</p>
<pre><code>def insert(arr, index, item):
  def helper(currentIndex, accum):
    if currentIndex == len(arr):
      return accum
    if currentIndex &lt; index:
      return helper(currentIndex+1, accum + [arr[currentIndex]])
    if currentIndex == index:
      return helper(currentIndex+1, accum + [item, arr[currentIndex]])
    return helper(currentIndex+1, accum + [arr[currentIndex]])
  return helper(0, [])
</code></pre>
<p>
  You're going to find an edge case and that's all right. The
  important part at the moment is practicing recursion.
</p><p>For bonus points, avoid all mutation in your implementations and use
only tail recursion.</p>
<p>Happy recursion!</p>
<h4 id="feedback">Feedback</h4><p>As always, I'd love to <a href="mailto:me@eatonphil.com">hear from you</a> with
questions or ideas.</p>
<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Reimplementing standard library functions without for loops is a great way to get better at recursion and you don't need to use a functional programming language to do so<a href="https://t.co/JiPnXMQW3l">https://t.co/JiPnXMQW3l</a> <a href="https://t.co/MHwX5t70HT">pic.twitter.com/MHwX5t70HT</a></p>— Phil Eaton (@phil_eaton) <a href="https://twitter.com/phil_eaton/status/1368602496168497154?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 7, 2021</a></blockquote> 

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://notes.eatonphil.com/practicing-recursion.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26377312</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 16:41:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why winter exercise can be especially hard on the lungs]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 188 | Comments 106 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26376423">thread link</a>) | @curmudgeon22
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/winter-exercise-lungs-1.5936703 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/winter-exercise-lungs-1.5936703">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Chronic cough is a common symptom among cross-country skiers. One Edmonton researcher is trying to understand why and to encourage athletes to protect their lungs from harsh winter air.</p><div><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5938617.1614970532!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/jogger.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>A woman jogs in a quiet park in Ottawa, Ont., in January 2021. Vigorous outdoor exercise during cold winter months can constrict and irritate lungs and cause a chronic cough. <!-- --> <!-- -->(CBC)</figcaption></figure><p><span><p>Canadian Olympic hopeful Katherine Stewart-Jones can't remember when she first started experiencing a cough she and other cross-country skiers call "race hack," but she said it was probably when she started competing in her early teen years.</p>  <p>"Sometimes, it goes like all the way into your back ... it's just this burning sensation," she said.&nbsp;"I'll lean over and just don't want to get up for a while because it hurts.</p>  <p>"Generally, I'll get a race hack pretty much every race I do, but for sure, if it's cold out, it's affected me a bit more."</p>  <p>The 25-year-old skier from Chelsea, Que., says she slows down on cold days when she's training but on race days, she pushes herself hard, sometimes so hard it can take weeks for the post-race coughing to subside.</p>  <p>"It would be interesting to do some more research on it ... Like, are we ruining our lungs for the rest of our lives?"</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5938558.1614969423!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/katherine-stewart-jones.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5938558.1614969423!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/katherine-stewart-jones.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5938558.1614969423!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/katherine-stewart-jones.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5938558.1614969423!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/katherine-stewart-jones.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5938558.1614969423!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/katherine-stewart-jones.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5938558.1614969423!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/katherine-stewart-jones.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Katherine Stewart-Jones, a 25-year-old elite cross-country skier, skis along a winter trail. The Olympic hopeful says she first began experiencing symptoms of what she and her fellow skiiers call 'race hack' in her early teens.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Nordic Focus)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>Michael Kennedy, an associate professor in kinesiology at the University of Alberta in Edmonton, has been interested in the effects of cold weather on lungs for more than a decade.</p>  <p>His curiosity comes from working as a wax technician for Canadian elite cross-country skiers in the early- to mid-2000s while he was still getting his PhD. He travelled with teams for months and noticed how breathing issues would worsen as the ski season wore on.</p>  <p>"By the time you got to national or the spring season races in March, they were hacking all the time, so they basically had chronic cough," he said. "It's not healthy to have chronic cough."</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5938575.1614969828!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/katherine-stewart-jones.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5938575.1614969828!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/katherine-stewart-jones.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5938575.1614969828!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/katherine-stewart-jones.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5938575.1614969828!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/katherine-stewart-jones.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5938575.1614969828!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/katherine-stewart-jones.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5938575.1614969828!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/katherine-stewart-jones.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>A graphic representation of Stewart-Jones shows the airways in her lungs and how they appear like tree branches. <!-- --> <!-- -->(Sködt McNalty/CBC Graphics )</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>The condition for some can lead to problems such as interrupted sleep&nbsp;or speech, and yet, a chronic cough is sometimes&nbsp;normalized in Canadian cross-country ski culture, he said.&nbsp;</p>  <p>Kennedy's <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31369875/">last study </a>on&nbsp;cold-weather exercise, published in 2019 in the journal <em>Respiratory Physiology &amp; Neurobiology,</em> looked at the effects of running a five-kilometre race outdoors in –15 C weather on 16 physically fit men and women&nbsp;compared to a lab-controlled test. All the participants exercised regularly in the cold, whether it was running outside, cross-country skiing or ski mountaineering.</p>  <p>All participants reported having some type of respiratory symptom&nbsp;after running in the cold (most said they had a cough), and breathing tests revealed that nine out of the 16 showed symptoms of bronchoconstriction, or narrowing of the airways, consistent with levels that would be considered exercise-induced asthma.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5938610.1614976337!/fileImage/httpImage/lungs2.gif"></p></div><figcaption>As the winter athlete begins to heavily inhale cold, dry air, the bronchioles can begin to constrict as if they are under threat. <!-- --> <!-- -->(Sködt McNalty/CBC Graphics)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <h2>What happens to lungs in the cold</h2>  <p>A main issue with exercising in the cold, especially in temperatures –15 C and colder, is the lack of moisture in the air.&nbsp;</p>  <p>When dry air hits the lungs, especially when someone is breathing heavily, it can provoke the lungs to react as if they were under threat.&nbsp;The airways essentially constrict to protect themselves.</p>  <p>Kennedy has compared the effects of&nbsp;room temperature dry air against cold dry air, and his findings suggest that dry air that's also cold can provoke even more of a reaction,&nbsp;which may explain why chronic cough is so common among winter athletes, he said.&nbsp;</p>  <p>Some research from around the world is beginning to suggest&nbsp;people who spend years exercising in cold, dry conditions might become more sensitive to lung irritants over time, according to Kennedy, although he cautions more data in this area is still needed.&nbsp;</p>  <p>"Over time, if you repeat that irritation or that provocation, the lung just becomes less capable of healing itself,"&nbsp;said Kennedy.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5938593.1614976349!/fileImage/httpImage/lungs.gif"></p></div><figcaption>A cross section of a bronchiole shows how muscles constrict to make the airway more narrow. It is the same process that takes place in people experiencing asthma symptoms. <!-- --> <!-- -->(Sködt McNalty/CBC Graphics)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <h2>Ways to protect your lungs</h2>  <p>Gordon Giesbrecht, the director of the Laboratory for Exercise and Environmental Medicine at the University of Manitoba in Winnipeg, agrees the cold, dry air can be an issue for anyone who engages in heavy cardiovascular activity on a regular basis in the winter. He likens the experience of lung constriction to trying to take a deep breath through an ever-narrowing straw.</p>  <p>"You can't freeze your lungs," he said. "You're not going to cause any damage although it is possible that continuous long-term training in the cold actually does make you more susceptible to this (bronchoconstriction)."</p>  <p>Both Giesbrecht and Kennedy say a simple face covering, such as a fabric mask, neck warmer or scarf, can go a long way to protecting the lungs from being irritated.</p>  <p>"If you cover your mouth, you're essentially warming the air and humidifying the air in a very productive manner," said Kennedy. "So essentially, your lung has to deal with less cold, dry air."</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5938600.1614970180!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/rideau-canal-skating.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5938600.1614970180!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/rideau-canal-skating.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5938600.1614970180!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/rideau-canal-skating.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5938600.1614970180!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/rideau-canal-skating.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5938600.1614970180!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/rideau-canal-skating.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5938600.1614970180!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/rideau-canal-skating.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>A simple face covering, such as a mask, scarf or neck warmer, can help humidify and warm air before it hits the lungs. <!-- --> <!-- -->(Brian Morris/CBC)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>He also suggests that athletes take time to warm up before they exercise and take it easy on very cold days by slowing down their pace.&nbsp;</p>  <p>He hopes his work helps to change the culture of winter sport in Canada so that athletes&nbsp;take steps to prevent&nbsp;symptoms such as chronic cough, lung pain and wheezing.</p>  <p>"One of the things I want to do in the next 10 years is try to prevent some of this acute dysfunction from happening by improving the behaviours of younger skiers or winter sports athletes," Kennedy said.</p>  <p>Later this month, he plans to begin his next study — a survey of cross-country skiers and biathlon athletes&nbsp;asking them to elaborate on any respiratory&nbsp;symptoms they have so researchers have a better sense of the scope of the issue. He plans to expand the study to winter runners and other recreational athletes as well.</p>  <p>For now, Stewart-Jones&nbsp;brushes off the concerns about cold-weather exercise on her breathing. No serious athlete, including herself,&nbsp;would turn down a race because it's –18C, she said. As far as face coverings go, she wears them if her skin is at risk of freezing but she avoids them otherwise — neck warmers, like masks, can make it slightly more difficult to breathe.&nbsp;</p>  <p>"I guess it's so normal and common for people to have irritated lungs that it's not something I think about," she said between a couple, short bursts of coughing after competing in Oberstdorf, Germany, at the World Championships in late February.</p>  <p>"For sure it feels like it's probably not great for my lungs long term."</p></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/winter-exercise-lungs-1.5936703</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26376423</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 15:14:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[We may soon have city-spanning 900 MHz mesh networks]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 257 | Comments 162 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26376388">thread link</a>) | @RiderOfGiraffes
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/900mhz-mesh.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/900mhz-mesh.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/900mhz-mesh.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26376388</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 15:10:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Please support Web Monetization if you want less ads on the web]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 160 | Comments 204 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26375857">thread link</a>) | @sofixa
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://atodorov.me/2021/03/07/please-support-web-monetization-if-you-want-less-ads-on-the-web/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://atodorov.me/2021/03/07/please-support-web-monetization-if-you-want-less-ads-on-the-web/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      
        
        <h2>Table of Contents</h2>
        
         
      
      <p><em>Note: Since it came up last time, I’m not in any way affiliated with any of the entities discussed in this article</em></p>
<h2 id="what-is-web-monetization">What is Web Monetization</h2>
<p><a href="https://webmonetization.org/">Web Monetization</a> is a browser API that allows content creators to monetize content, and content consumers to pay for it, anonymously, without ads or any friction, like paywalls and subscriptions.</p>
<p>The basic concept is that a content creator signals they’re accepting payments, and the content consumer, via a browser extension, natively in the browser or by account linking, streams micropayments via the <a href="https://interledger.org/">Interledger</a>, which supports a wide variety of providers and currencies ( real and crypto). The point is, as a consumer you pay for what you consume directly ( instead of indirectly via tracking and ads ) and proportionally.</p>
<p>It’s based on an open <a href="https://webmonetization.org/specification.html">specification</a> which is still a work in progress, but fully functional.</p>
<h2 id="why-you-should-participate-in-it">Why you should participate in it</h2>
<p>A lot of people don’t like ads - be it because they find them wasteful, too obnoxious, too insistent, too intrusive, too dumb, etc. Even more people dislike tracking ( the art of following user actions across the internet to serve them more “relevant” ads based on their interests ), because that centralises a lot of power and knowledge in a few big companies ( Google, Facebook, etc. ), and allows precise targeting, which has been used for some nasty things. If I may quote the EFF directly:</p>
<p><em>Over the years, the machinery of targeted advertising has frequently been used for <a href="https://www.americanbanker.com/news/payday-lenders-are-finding-ways-around-googles-ad-ban">exploitation</a>, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-facebook-advertisers/u-s-charges-facebook-with-racial-discrimination-in-targeted-housing-ads-idUSKCN1R91E8">discrimination</a>, and <a href="https://stoponlinevaw.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Black-ID-Target-by-Russia-Report-SOVAW.pdf">harm</a>. The ability to target people based on ethnicity, religion, gender, age, or ability allows discriminatory ads for jobs, housing, and credit. Targeting based on credit history - or characteristics systematically associated with it - enables predatory ads for high-interest loans. Targeting based on demographics, location, and political affiliation helps purveyors of politically motivated disinformation and voter suppression.</em></p>
<p>A big part of the aforementioned people, and plenty of others, use ad blockers ( either as browser plugins like AdBlock Plus or Ublock (Origin), or DNS-level like PiHole and AdGuard Home ), which block ads, trackers and various analytics software, which aren’t necessarily the same as trackers - their main purpose is to analyse and aggregate users of the website, by country, language, browser, device type (mobile, PC), how they came upon the website, how much time they spent on what page, etc. compared to trackers' main purpose, which is to analyse per-user (anonymised, but still) interests and behaviour and recommend related ads.</p>
<p>There are proposals by Google to supposedly improve upon the experience of tracking ( in part due to major browsers like Firefox blocking some of the technology enabling such tracking ), but there are <a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2021/03/googles-floc-terrible-idea">major issues with them</a>.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, for a lot of web content creators, ads remain the main way to make money of the content they produce, which could be just to compensate costs, as a reward for the time spent, or even potentially to allow transferring to full time content producing. And for a lot of content consumers, blocking ads removes the only way to “pay”, baring some direct donations scheme.</p>
<p>Ideally, there should be an easy way to directly pay for the content you consume. In some cases you can subscribe and pay a monthly fee, but that could never cover it all - nobody will pay for every small blog, recipe/repair tutorial/gardening tips website/YouTube channel. How much value do they bring to you ? How much would you pay for them? How would you know they’re worth it without using them first, and why would they allow you to use them for free, when most users would be one-shot coming from a search engine? And then there’s non-profit open/crowdsourced institutions like <a href="https://www.wikipedia.org/">Wikipedia</a> and the <a href="https://archive.org/">Internet Archive</a> ( which is Web Monetized) whose principles make them incompatible with ads and paywalls/subscriptions and force them to rely on donations.</p>
<p>Enter Web Monetization - with almost no friction, content consumers pay-per-use ( time spent ), automatically, and more or less anonymously. If content creators desire, there can be exclusive features only for “paying” ( participating in Web Monetization ) users, or no ads for them.</p>
<p>Funnily enough, the concept is nothing new - the French Minitel ( more info on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minitel">Wikipedia</a> and a fascinating read by the <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/tech-history/cyberspace/minitel-the-online-world-france-built-before-the-web">IEEE</a>) system, in a sense a predecessor of the Internet, which among other things, contained specifically paying per time spent on pages.</p>
<h2 id="how-it-works">How it works</h2>
<p>At the time of writing, there is only one Web Monetization provider - <a href="https://coil.com/">Coil.com</a>, but the API is open so in theory anyone can join in and compete with them.</p>
<p>For content consumers, they provide browser extensions ( which are FOSS under the Apache 2.0 licence and available on <a href="https://github.com/coilhq/web-monetization-projects">GitHub</a>) and subscriptions ($5 USD/month), which are spent at the rate of $0.36 USD an hour, providing for roughly 13 hours of content consumption. After $4.50 is spent, the rate is lowered to last until the end of the month. Said subscription also includes some perks, such as ad-free experiences on <a href="https://help.coil.com/docs/membership/perks/imgur-emerald">Imgur</a> with Emerald and <a href="https://help.coil.com/docs/membership/perks/cinnamon">Cinnamon</a> ( a subscription-based video content platform).</p>
<p>For content creators, you need an account with a virtual wallet providers that supports ILP ( the Interledger protocol used to make the magic happen, like <a href="https://www.uphold.com/">Uphold</a> and <a href="https://gatehub.net/">Gatehub</a> ) and an HTML meta tag with the address of your wallet ( like so <code>&lt;meta name="monetization" content="$ilp.uphold.com/8Q6r7F3XjXEi"&gt;</code> ) in the code of your website. The latter can be added manually or via any of the existing plugins (there are ones for <a href="https://github.com/sabinebertram/hugo-webmonetization-component">Hugo</a>, <a href="https://github.com/mrmuhammadali/gatsby-plugin-monetization">Gatsby</a>, <a href="https://github.com/sorxrob/svelte-monetization">Svelte</a>, <a href="https://wordpress.org/plugins/coil-web-monetization/">Wordpress</a>). For some cases where that’s impossible, Coil allow you to connect with YouTube and Twitch directly.</p>
<p>Anonymity and privacy are provided by the way things work - that wallets are randomly generated IDs, Coil transfer the money, the wallet provider knows who the recipient is, the content creators knows how much they’ve received, but nobody knows everything. <a href="https://coil.com/p/sharafian/Doubling-Down-on-Privacy/cD_ZiwT2J">Here’s a post</a> by Coil’s co-founder and CTO Ben Sharafian discussing wallet-side and sender-site (based on <a href="https://privacypass.github.io/">PrivacyPass</a>) privacy techniques they and the wallet providers use to ensure everyone’s privacy is respected.</p>
<h2 id="limitations">Limitations</h2>
<p>Of course, that could never replace premium subscription services like the Financial Times, or even direct ones like Substack due to the limited amounts involved, and it isn’t trying to - the point is to help monetise smaller sized websites ( and Youtube/Twitch channels ) <em>or</em> open/crowdsourced/non-profit institutions by providing a decent alternatives to obnoxious ads (which millions of people block anyway ) and paywalls. For instance the <a href="https://archive.org/">Internet Archive</a> and <a href="https://hackernoon.com/">Hacker Noon</a> are web monetized; and so is this and some other small-scale personal blogs. It’s more similar to <a href="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/">Buy me a coffee</a>, <a href="https://www.patreon.com/">Patreon</a> and <a href="https://github.com/sponsors">GitHub Sponsors</a>, only more automated, ubiquitous and with less effort.</p>
<p>However, it’s relatively recent and not very popular yet - according to the <a href="https://twitter.com/WebMotized">WebMotized</a> Twitter bot there’s only 1482 web monetized websites so far. Some more participation is needed, on both sides ( content creators and consumers) to make it a viable alternative to ads and some paywalls. I already did my part</p>
<h2 id="conclusion--summary">Conclusion &amp; Summary</h2>
<p>Are you a content consumer or provider, or both? Don’t like ads and privacy invading tracking? Participate in Web Monetization!</p>
<p>If I’ve convinced you, feel free to sign up for <a href="https://help.coil.com/docs/membership/get-membership">Coil’s membership</a> to contribute and/or <a href="https://help.coil.com/docs/account/monetize-content">set up</a> web monetization on your website. If not, check out the <a href="#discuss">Discuss</a> section below, I’d really like to hear why not and what did I miss.</p>
<h2 id="discuss">Discuss</h2>
<p>Hacker News: <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26375857">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26375857</a></p>
<p>Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/sofixa/status/1368561842835099649">https://twitter.com/sofixa/status/1368561842835099649</a></p>

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://atodorov.me/2021/03/07/please-support-web-monetization-if-you-want-less-ads-on-the-web/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26375857</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 13:58:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Apple M1 Microarchitecture Research]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 198 | Comments 25 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26375139">thread link</a>) | @my123
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://dougallj.github.io/applecpu/firestorm.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dougallj.github.io/applecpu/firestorm.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><pre><strong>Apple M1 Microarchitecture Research</strong> by <a href="https://twitter.com/dougallj">Dougall Johnson</a>

Firestorm: <a href="https://dougallj.github.io/applecpu/firestorm.html">Overview</a> | <a href="https://dougallj.github.io/applecpu/firestorm-int.html">Base Instructions</a> | <a href="https://dougallj.github.io/applecpu/firestorm-simd.html">SIMD and FP Instructions</a>
Icestorm:  <a href="https://dougallj.github.io/applecpu/icestorm.html">Overview</a> | <a href="https://dougallj.github.io/applecpu/icestorm-int.html">Base Instructions</a> | <a href="https://dougallj.github.io/applecpu/icestorm-simd.html">SIMD and FP Instructions</a>

</pre><p>This is an early attempt at microarchitecture documentation for the CPU in the Apple M1, inspired by and building on the amazing work of <a href="https://uops.info/">Andreas Abel</a>,
<a href="https://www.anandtech.com/show/16226/apple-silicon-m1-a14-deep-dive/2">Andrei Frumusanu</a>, <a href="https://github.com/Veedrac/microarchitecturometer">@Veedrac</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/travisdowns/robsize">Travis Downs</a>, <a href="http://blog.stuffedcow.net/2013/05/measuring-rob-capacity/">Henry Wong</a>
and <a href="https://agner.org/optimize/">Agner Fog</a>. This documentation is my best effort, but it is based on black-box reverse engineering, and there are definitely mistakes. No warranty of any kind (and not just as a legal technicality). To make it easier to verify the information and/or identify such errors, entries in the instruction tables link to the experiments and results (~35k tables of counter values).</p>


<p>Firestorm is the high-performance microarchitecture used by the four P-cores in the M1.</p>

<h2>Firestorm Units (ports)</h2>

<p>These are refered to as "units", to try to avoid confusion if Apple releases official documentation, as they
probably refer to them as "ports" or "pipes", and order them differently. (If this just causes more confusion,
I apologise.)</p>

<pre>Integer units:

  1:  alu + flags + branch + adr + msr/mrs nzcv + mrs
  2:  alu + flags + branch + adr + msr/mrs nzcv + ptrauth
  3:  alu + flags + mov-from-simd/fp?
  4:  alu + mov-from-simd/fp?
  5:  alu + mul + div
  6:  alu + mul + madd + crc + bfm/extr

Load and store units (up to 128-bit loads and stores, including address generation with shifts up to LSL #3):

  7:  store + amx
  8:  load/store + amx
  9:  load
  10: load

FP/SIMD units:

  11: fp/simd
  12: fp/simd
  13: fp/simd + fcsel + to-gpr
  14: fp/simd + fcsel + to-gpr + fcmp/e + fdiv + frecpe + frsqrte + fjcvtzs + ursqrte + urecpe + sha
</pre>


<h2>Instruction Fusion</h2>

<p>Certain instructions are able to issue as one uop if they appear consecutively in the instruction stream.</p>

<ul>
<li>adds/subs/ands/cmp/tst + b.cc (complete fusion when fused instructions read no more than 4 registers per 6 instructions)</li>
<li>aese + aesmc (always fused if operands match pattern "A, B ; A, A")</li>
<li>aesd + aesimc (always fused if operands match pattern "A, B ; A, A")</li>
<li>pmull + eor (usually fused if operands match pattern "A, B, C ; A, A, D" or "A, B, C ; A, D, A")</li>
<li>amx + amx (excluding loads and stores - probably fuses to something like a STP)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Elimination</h2>

<p>Certain instructions do not need to issue:</p>

<ul>
<li>mov x0, 0 (handled by renaming)</li>
<li>mov x0, x1 (usually handled by renaming)</li>
<li>movi v0.16b, #0 (handled by renaming)</li>
<li>mov v0.16b, v1.16b (usually handled by renaming)</li>
<li>mov imm/movz/movn (handled by renamer at a max of 2 per 8 instructions, includes all tested "mov")</li>
<li>nop (never issues)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Complex Latencies</h2>

<p>Several instructions have latencies that aren't adequately described in the instruction tables:</p>

<ul>
<li>MADD's output can be passed to its third operand (the addend) with 1c latency, but if it's chained with other instructions it has 3c latency.</li>
<li>Loads may be passed to the base address of other loads with 3c latency (which is nice for linked lists), but chaining with ALU operations gives a latency of 4c. (Although the second destination register in an LDP always has 4c latency.)</li>
<li>Integer to SIMD/FP roundtrip latency can be as low as 7c (e.g. when chaining flags operations).</li>
<li>Not yet in the table: pointer authentication uops have seven cycle latency, one cycle throughput. They are one uop (except for memory operations).</li>
</ul>


<h2>Other limits</h2>

<p>Firestorm can retire eight instructions per cycle, but can issue more uops (using implicit shifts or extends on ALU operations, as thus far other uops retire separately).</p>

<ul>
<li>Retires per cycle: 8</li>
<li>ROB (in-flight renames): ~623</li>
<li>Integer physical register file size: ~380</li>
<li>FP/SIMD physical register file size: ~434</li>
<li>Fetch window tracking slots (in-flight I-cache lines or branches): ~144</li>
<li>Load buffers: ~129</li>
<li>Store buffers: ~108</li>
</ul>

<p>These numbers mostly come from my <a href="https://gist.github.com/dougallj/5bafb113492047c865c0c8cfbc930155">M1 buffer size measuring tool</a>.
The M1 seems to use something other than an entirely conventional reorder buffer, which
complicates measurements a bit. So these may or may not be accurate.
(This paragraph previously said "it seems to use something along the lines of a validation buffer".
I think the VB hypothesis has since been disproven. Various attempts to measure ROB size
have yielded values 623, 853, and 2295 (see the previous link). My uninformed hypothesis
is that this may imply a kind of distributed reorder buffer, where only structures that
need to know about a given operation track them, and/or some kind of out-of-order retirement.)
</p>


<h2>Terminology</h2>

<p>
As instructions are executed, they are mapped to operations inside the processor.
This work describes two kinds, "operations that retire" (which I call "retires",
but should maybe be called "retirement slots"), and "operations that issue" (uops).
Operations that issue are limited by how many ports are available that can execute
that operation in a given cycle. Retirement slots are limited to eight per cycle,
which I have called the "retires per cycle" limit, but likely corresponds to a
frontend "decode width", rather than a limit related to retirement itself
(which I suspect could be either out-of-order, or much wider). All instructions
have at least one retire, but some instructions have more uops than retires
(e.g. ADD (shift)), and others have fewer (e.g. NOP, LDP).
</p>


<p>
These two types of operations can be measured, using the retire counter (counter 01,
undocumented, shown in the <strong>Retire</strong> column in the tables), and the
issue counter (counter 52, documented). The following three undocumented counters
(53, 54, and 55) count the same kind of uops as the issue counter, but at a different
point in the pipeline. These correspond to the <strong>Int</strong>, <strong>Mem</strong>
and <strong>FP</strong> columns in the tables, and count uops that issues to units of
the given type.
</p>

<p>
Finally, the <strong>Units</strong> column is based on finding conflicts when measuring
throughput - if two uops block each other, we can tell they both use the same unit.
(Unfortunately these experiments are not yet automated nor included in the documentation,
so there may be some mistakes.)
</p>

</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dougallj.github.io/applecpu/firestorm.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26375139</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 11:49:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Let's Encrypt's performance is currently degraded due to a DDoS attack]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 254 | Comments 104 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26374430">thread link</a>) | @sorcix
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://letsencrypt.status.io/pages/incident/55957a99e800baa4470002da/6044830be2838505358d3108 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://letsencrypt.status.io/pages/incident/55957a99e800baa4470002da/6044830be2838505358d3108">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p>Components  </p><p>acme-staging-v02.api.letsencrypt.org (Staging), acme-staging.api.letsencrypt.org (Staging), acme-v01.api.letsencrypt.org (Production), acme-v02.api.letsencrypt.org (Production), ocsp.root-x1.letsencrypt.org, ocsp.staging-x1.letsencrypt.org (Staging), {e1,e2,r3,r4}.o.lencr.org &amp; ocsp.int-x{3..4}.letsencrypt.org</p></div><div><p>Locations  </p><p>High Assurance Datacenter 1, High Assurance Datacenter 2</p></div><br><div><p><strong>March 7, 2021 12:14 UTC</strong></p><p><strong>[Resolved] </strong><span id="statusio_incident_message_6044c3b5e919ab0536928260">We have successfully mitigated the Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) attack. Our services are now operating normally.</span></p></div><br><div><p><strong>March 7, 2021 07:38 UTC</strong></p><p><strong>[Identified] </strong><span id="statusio_incident_message_6044830be2838505358d3114">Our services' performance is currently degraded due to a Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) attack, which we are working to mitigate.</span></p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://letsencrypt.status.io/pages/incident/55957a99e800baa4470002da/6044830be2838505358d3108</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26374430</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 09:20:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why I rewrote my Rust keyboard firmware in Zig: consistency, mastery, and fun]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 671 | Comments 332 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26374268">thread link</a>) | @iansinnott
<br/>
March 7, 2021 | https://kevinlynagh.com/rust-zig/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://kevinlynagh.com/rust-zig/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a href="https://kevinlynagh.com/">← Back to Kevin's homepage</a><span>Published: 2021 March 7</span></p><p>I’ve spent the last year <a href="https://kevinlynagh.com/keyboards/">building keyboards</a>, which has included writing firmware for a variety custom circuit boards.</p>

<p>I initially wrote this firmware in Rust, but despite years of experience with that language I still struggled quite a bit.
I eventually got my keyboards working, but it took an embarrassingly long time and wasn’t <em>fun</em>.</p>

<p>After repeated suggestions from my much more Rust-and-computing-experienced friend <a href="https://scattered-thoughts.net/">Jamie Brandon</a>, I rewrote the firmware in <a href="https://ziglang.org/">Zig</a>, which turned out swimmingly.</p>

<p>I found this quite surprising, given that I’d never seen Zig before and it’s a pre-1.0 language written by a <a href="https://twitter.com/andy_kelley">fellow PDX hipster</a> with basically just a <a href="https://ziglang.org/documentation/0.7.1/">single page of documentation</a>.</p>

<p>The experience went so well, in fact, that I now feel just as likely to turn to Zig (a language I’ve used for a dozen hours) as to Rust (which I’ve used for at least a thousand hours).</p>

<p>This, of course, reflects as much about me and my interests as it does about either of these languages.
So I’ll have to explain what I want from a systems programming language in the first place.</p>

<p>Also, to explain why I struggled with Rust I’ll have to show a lot of complex code that I’m obviously unhappy about.
My intent here is not to gripe about Rust, but to establish my (lack of) credibility: It’s so you can judge for yourself whether I’m using Rust’s features in a reasonable way or if I’ve totally lost the plot.</p>

<p>Finally, while it risks falling into the dreadfully boring “language X is better than Y” blog trope, I feel that it’d be more helpful to some readers if I explicitly compare Rust and Zig, rather than write a wholly positive “Zig’s great!” article.
(After all, I’d steadily ignored six months of Jamie gushing about Zig because, “that’s great buddy, but I already know Rust and I just want to get my keyboard done, okay?”)</p>

<h2>What I want from a systems language</h2>

<p>I was educated as a physicist and learned programming so I could make data visualizations.
My first languages were PostScript and Ruby (dynamic, interpreted languages) and I later moved to JavaScript so I could draw on the web.
That led me to Clojure (using ClojureScript to draw on the web), where I’ve spent much of my career.</p>

<p>In 2017 I decided to learn a systems language.
Partly this was intellectual curiosity — I wanted to become more familiar with concepts like the stack, heap, pointers, and static types which had remained mucky to me as a web developer.
But mostly it was because I wanted the capabilities that systems languages promised:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>To write code that was <em>fast</em>; that could take advantage of how computers actually worked and run as fast as the hardware allowed.</p></li>
<li><p>To write applications that could run in minimal environments like microcontrollers or web assembly where it just isn’t feasible (in time or space) to carry along a garbage collector, language runtime, etc.</p></li>
</ol>

<p>My interest was not (and still isn’t) in operating systems, programming language design, or safety (with respect to memory, formal verfiability, modeling as types, etc.).</p>

<p>I just wanted to blink the litle squares on the screen on and off very quickly.</p>

<p>Based on its growing popularity in the open source community and tons of beginners-to-systems-programming documentation, I picked up Rust around version 1.18.</p>

<p>Since then, Rust has undoubtedly helped me achieve those capabilities I was after: I was able to compile it to WASM for a <a href="https://github.com/lynaghk/subform-layout">layout engine</a>, build and sell a <a href="https://keminglabs.com/finda">fast desktop search app</a> (Rust <a href="https://keminglabs.com/blog/building-a-fast-electron-app-with-rust/">shoved into Electron</a>), and compile Rust to an stm32g4 microcontroller to drive a <a href="https://kevinlynagh.com/newsletter/2020_02_robot_update/">track saw robot</a> (I even <a href="https://github.com/stm32-rs/stm32-rs/pull/335">found a typo</a> in the register definitions; the full “hard-mode” embedded debugging experience!).</p>

<p>Despite all this, I still don’t feel <em>comfortable</em> with Rust.
It feels fractally complex — seemingly every time I use Rust on a new project, I run into some issue that forces me to confront a new corner of the language/ecosystem.
Developing my keyboard firmware was no exception: I ran into two problems, and each required learning a completely new language feature.</p>

<p>These problems aren’t really specific to embedded, but they’re representative of the sorts of challenges I’ve run into using Rust over the past three years.</p>

<p>If you want the gory embedded details or understand why I’m writing my own firmware using newfangled languages at all, see my notes on <a href="https://kevinlynagh.com/keyboards/">building keyboards</a>.</p>

<h2>Conditional compilation</h2>

<p>The first challenge I ran into with Rust was getting my firmware to run on hardware varying from 4-button dev-kit PCBs to the left/right halves of a wireless split to a single <a href="https://atreus.technomancy.us/">Atreus</a>:</p>

<p><img src="https://kevinlynagh.com/rust-zig/typical_keyboards.jpg" alt="Various keyboard hardware"></p>

<p>Varying the features of firmware at compile-time is known as “conditional compilation”.
(It needs to be done at compile-time rather than run-time because microcontrollers have limited program space, roughly 10–100kB in my case.)</p>

<p>Rust’s solution to this problem is “features”, which are defined in <code>Cargo.toml</code>:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>[dependencies]</span>
<span>cortex-m</span> <span>=</span> <span>"0.6"</span>
<span>nrf52840-hal</span> <span>=</span> <span>{</span> <span>version</span> <span>=</span> <span>"0.11"</span><span>,</span> <span>optional</span> <span>=</span> <span>true</span><span>,</span> <span>default-features</span> <span>=</span> <span>false</span> <span>}</span>
<span>nrf52833-hal</span> <span>=</span> <span>{</span> <span>version</span> <span>=</span> <span>"0.11"</span><span>,</span> <span>optional</span> <span>=</span> <span>true</span><span>,</span> <span>default-features</span> <span>=</span> <span>false</span> <span>}</span>
<span>arraydeque</span> <span>=</span> <span>{</span> <span>version</span> <span>=</span> <span>"0.4"</span><span>,</span> <span>default-features</span> <span>=</span> <span>false</span> <span>}</span>
<span>heapless</span> <span>=</span> <span>"0.5"</span>

<span>[features]</span>
<span>keytron</span> <span>=</span> <span>["nrf52833"]</span>
<span>keytron-dk</span> <span>=</span> <span>["nrf52833"]</span>
<span>splitapple</span> <span>=</span> <span>["nrf52840"]</span>
<span>splitapple-left</span> <span>=</span> <span>["splitapple"]</span>
<span>splitapple-right</span> <span>=</span> <span>["splitapple"]</span>

<span># specify a default here so that rust-analyzer can build the project; when building use --no-default-features to turn this off</span>
<span>default</span> <span>=</span> <span>["keytron"]</span>

<span>nrf52840</span> <span>=</span> <span>["nrf52840-hal"]</span>
<span>nrf52833</span> <span>=</span> <span>["nrf52833-hal"]</span>
</pre></div>
<p>For example, the <code>keytron</code> feature is enabled for a specific keyboard hardware design.
That hardware depends on the <code>nrf52833</code> feature (representing a kind of a microcontroller), which depends on the <code>nrf52833-hal</code> crate (actual code which maps that microcontroller’s peripheral memory addresses to Rust types).</p>

<p>My Rust code can then use attribute annotations to conditionally enable stuff.
E.g., a namespace can import the microcontroller-specific crate:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>#[cfg(feature = </span><span>"nrf52833"</span><span>)]</span><span></span>
<span>pub</span><span> </span><span>use</span><span> </span><span>nrf52833_hal</span>::<span>pac</span><span> </span><span>as</span><span> </span><span>hw</span><span>;</span><span></span>

<span>#[cfg(feature = </span><span>"nrf52840"</span><span>)]</span><span></span>
<span>pub</span><span> </span><span>use</span><span> </span><span>nrf52840_hal</span>::<span>pac</span><span> </span><span>as</span><span> </span><span>hw</span><span>;</span><span></span>
</pre></div>
<p>or call the appropriate key scanning routine:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>fn</span> <span>read_keys</span><span>()</span><span> </span>-&gt; <span>Packet</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span>
<span>    </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>device</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>unsafe</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span> </span><span>hw</span>::<span>Peripherals</span>::<span>steal</span><span>()</span><span> </span><span>};</span><span></span>

<span>    </span><span>#[cfg(any(feature = </span><span>"keytron"</span><span>, feature = </span><span>"keytron-dk"</span><span>))]</span><span></span>
<span>    </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>u</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span>
<span>        </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>p0</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>device</span><span>.</span><span>P0</span><span>.</span><span>in_</span><span>.</span><span>read</span><span>().</span><span>bits</span><span>();</span><span></span>
<span>        </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>p1</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>device</span><span>.</span><span>P1</span><span>.</span><span>in_</span><span>.</span><span>read</span><span>().</span><span>bits</span><span>();</span><span></span>

<span>        </span><span>//invert because keys are active low</span>
<span>        </span><span>gpio</span>::<span>P0</span>::<span>pack</span><span>(</span><span>!</span><span>p0</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>|</span><span> </span><span>gpio</span>::<span>P1</span>::<span>pack</span><span>(</span><span>!</span><span>p1</span><span>)</span><span></span>
<span>    </span><span>};</span><span></span>

<span>    </span><span>#[cfg(feature = </span><span>"splitapple"</span><span>)]</span><span></span>
<span>    </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>u</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>gpio</span>::<span>splitapple</span>::<span>read_keys</span><span>();</span><span></span>

<span>    </span><span>Packet</span><span>(</span><span>u</span><span>)</span><span></span>
<span>}</span><span></span>
</pre></div>
<p>Getting this conditional compilation working required learning a lot of stuff:</p>

<ul>
<li>the attribute annotation conditional mini-language (the <code>any</code> in <code>#[cfg(any(feature = "keytron", feature = "keytron-dk"))]</code>)</li>
<li>the <code>optional = true</code> that must be added to the device crates in <code>Cargo.toml</code> (even though the source is already conditionally requiring them!)</li>
<li>how to enable features when building a static binary (<code>cargo build --release --no-default-features --features "keytron"</code>)</li>
</ul>

<p>I still have many unresolved questions, too!</p>

<p>At some point I gave up trying to pass device peripherals as function arguments because I couldn’t figure out how to add conditional attributes to types — the “obvious” thing doesn’t work:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>fn</span> <span>read_keys</span><span>(</span><span>port</span>: <span>#[cfg(feature = </span><span>"splitapple"</span><span>)]</span><span></span>
<span>                   </span><span>nrf52840_hal</span>::<span>pac</span>::<span>P1</span><span></span>
<span>                   </span><span>#[cfg(feature = </span><span>"keytron"</span><span>)]</span><span></span>
<span>                   </span><span>nrf52833_hal</span>::<span>pac</span>::<span>P0</span><span>)</span><span> </span>-&gt; <span>Packet</span><span> </span><span>{}</span><span></span>
</pre></div>
<p>There’s a neat embedded framework, <a href="https://rtic.rs/0.4/book/en/preface.html">RTIC</a>, whose main entry point is an <code>app</code> annotation that takes the device crate as an, uh, argument:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>#[app(device = nrf52833)]</span><span></span>
<span>const</span><span> </span><span>APP</span>: <span>()</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span>
<span>  </span><span>//your code here...</span>
<span>};</span><span></span>
</pre></div>
<p>How does one conditionally vary this argument at compile-time?
I have no idea.</p>

<h2>Types and macros</h2>

<p>Rust also proved challenging even within a single hardware configuration.</p>

<p>Consider scanning a keyboard matrix: If we don’t have enough microcontroller pins to connect each keyboard switch directly to a pin, we can arrange the switches with diodes (one-way valves) into a matrix:</p>

<p><img src="https://kevinlynagh.com/rust-zig/key_matrix.png" alt="circuit schematic of key matrix"></p>

<p>We then set a single column high and read out the the rows to find state of the switches on that column.</p>

<p>In this example, if we set pin 1.10 high (col0) and then read pin 0.13 (row1) as high, we know that switch K8 is pressed.</p>

<p>Pretty simple in theory, but complex in Rust because:</p>

<ol>
<li>Device crates expose hardware peripherals as distinct types</li>
<li>One does not simply compute with distinct types in Rust</li>
</ol>

<p>Say I need to initialize all the columns as output pins.</p>

<p>Doing this for a single pin, say peripheral port P0’s pin 10, is simple enough:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>P0</span><span>.</span><span>pin_cnf</span><span>[</span><span>10</span><span>].</span><span>write</span><span>(</span><span>|</span><span>w</span><span>|</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span>
<span>    </span><span>w</span><span>.</span><span>input</span><span>().</span><span>disconnect</span><span>();</span><span></span>
<span>    </span><span>w</span><span>.</span><span>dir</span><span>().</span><span>output</span><span>();</span><span></span>
<span>    </span><span>w</span><span></span>
<span>});</span><span></span>
</pre></div>
<p>But my column pins are spread across two ports, so what I <em>want</em> to write:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>for</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>port</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>pin</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>in</span><span> </span><span>&amp;</span><span>[(</span><span>P0</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>10</span><span>),</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>P1</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>7</span><span>),</span><span> </span><span>..</span><span>.]</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span>
<span>    </span><span>port</span><span>.</span><span>pin_cnf</span><span>[</span><span>pin</span><span>].</span><span>write</span><span>(</span><span>|</span><span>w</span><span>|</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span>
<span>        </span><span>w</span><span>.</span><span>input</span><span>().</span><span>disconnect</span><span>();</span><span></span>
<span>        </span><span>w</span><span>.</span><span>dir</span><span>().</span><span>output</span><span>();</span><span></span>
<span>        </span><span>w</span><span></span>
<span>    </span><span>});</span><span></span>
<span>}</span><span></span>
</pre></div>
<p>isn’t going to fly because now the tuples have different types — <code>(P0, usize)</code> and <code>(P1, usize)</code> — and so they can’t hang together in the same collection.</p>

<p>Here’s the solution I came up with:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>type</span> <span>PinIdx</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>u8</span><span>;</span><span></span>
<span>type</span> <span>Port</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>u8</span><span>;</span><span></span>

<span>const</span><span> </span><span>COL_PINS</span>: <span>[(</span><span>Port</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>PinIdx</span><span>);</span><span> </span><span>7</span><span>]</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span></span>
<span>    </span><span>[(</span><span>1</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>10</span><span>),</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>1</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>13</span><span>),</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>1</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>15</span><span>),</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>0</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>2</span><span>),</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>0</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>29</span><span>),</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>1</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>0</span><span>),</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>0</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>17</span><span>)];</span><span></span>

<span>pub</span><span> </span><span>fn</span> <span>init_gpio</span><span>()</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span>
<span>    </span><span>for</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>port</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>pin_idx</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>in</span><span> </span><span>&amp;</span><span>COL_PINS</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span>
<span>        </span><span>match</span><span> </span><span>port</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span>
<span>            </span><span>0</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span>
<span>                </span><span>device</span><span>.</span><span>P0</span><span>.</span><span>pin_cnf</span><span>[</span><span>*</span><span>pin_idx</span><span> </span><span>as</span><span> </span><span>usize</span><span>].</span><span>write</span><span>(</span><span>|</span><span>w</span><span>|</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span>
<span>                    </span><span>w</span><span>.</span><span>input</span><span>().</span><span>disconnect</span><span>();</span><span></span>
<span>                    </span><span>w</span><span>.</span><span>dir</span><span>().</span><span>output</span><span>();</span><span></span>
<span>                    </span><span>w</span><span></span>
<span>                </span><span>});</span><span></span>
<span>            </span><span>}</span><span></span>
<span>            </span><span>1</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span>
<span>                </span><span>device</span><span>.</span><span>P1</span><span>.</span><span>pin_cnf</span><span>[</span><span>*</span><span>pin_idx</span><span> </span><span>as</span><span> </span><span>usize</span><span>].</span><span>write</span><span>(</span><span>|</span><span>w</span><span>|</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span>
<span>                    </span><span>w</span><span>.</span><span>input</span><span>().</span><span>disconnect</span><span>();</span><span></span>
<span>                    </span><span>w</span><span>.</span><span>dir</span><span>().</span><span>output</span><span>();</span><span></span>
<span>                    </span><span>w</span><span></span>
<span>                </span><span>});</span><span></span>
<span>            </span><span>}</span><span></span>
<span>            </span><span>_</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span> </span><span>{}</span><span></span>
<span>        </span><span>}</span><span></span>
<span>    </span><span>}</span><span></span>
<span>}</span><span></span>
</pre></div>
<p>Yup, good ol’ copy-paste to the rescue.</p>

<p>But wait, I hear you asking, what about <em>macros</em>?
Oh yes, my friend, I shaved the macro yak in the actual scanning routine:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><span>pub</span><span> </span><span>fn</span> <span>read_keys</span><span>()</span><span> </span>-&gt; …</pre></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://kevinlynagh.com/rust-zig/">https://kevinlynagh.com/rust-zig/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://kevinlynagh.com/rust-zig/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26374268</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 08:42:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Don’t use 7-segment displays (2011) [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 109 | Comments 78 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26373405">thread link</a>) | @parsecs
<br/>
March 6, 2021 | http://www.harold.thimbleby.net/cv/files/seven-segment.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.harold.thimbleby.net/cv/files/seven-segment.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div g="">Éê-Ø¦¶ÐêÀ[4õkéy¥Xð=A,(Ý¯RÑ‘a€ÆÝˆâ€“�†ýÈª„=~6A<yŽwrÏ¶Ön·{¹fÈ$Â˜î èóiu£žñz1ð¸w_="" ¦�ƒ�Øo{'”g="" ç0âc="kŒÅä%F.=óÈe&quot;@ƒ×‰�Ž¿vŒ‘Ûô:ñŒ1–®¼BðÞýJ÷jê¼ÒLìžum/EËÍØ3r˜hŠ3âz_vŒîñpQCAí¤©{¡u" éíå§r^(•w²ë\íÑù?Ái(wb~ì="" )¯.k(rÄ‹Œ{‹ŒÏ="">/ñuÂÂ ®ƒøæ
úÆseóå&gt;Ç„˜0ÑwÎø°t²‚×zÈÎPŒ)/XcÁ½ÁNã*0ÂoÝCMËe¦\”ø
ZR-¬&amp;˜¥žQ¶SËò&nbsp;ùa'-k&gt;FŸ,åù‰âÆ¯Rïè´®I/ˆw°zÀá‰U´[ˆ§Ÿ€5J¼¥C–i’ð‰Eîf’êÚˆ21„u6qÞQèv‡;æ÷±Blr•T÷0Pî…|
ô½X@IjF{àD¸1¿ÔsF0‚à1PØ”G&lt;]Ì¶{¼É”å—2ep‹ƒáh§§D™¾'ÛŸSè'SÌŒle²¸·C=¿Z&amp;b�÷Y‡Å]À�É+ÁR!Šƒ8&lt;.Líƒ®ý›­]þj~3-&amp;˜1ûß’°É~{šcA‚E„™I¯ñ\›H52jÀDæ°µˆ€ú‡ÄôlMÇÂ:€aÎHö\“Ý îþãü	ÅÁöÞ½{ÇcéT	òvóùmµ˜³Ž«!�L^’HË¥}
zÿágû+’·?~¸ûîã‹oA©Œyê÷(ŒÃßøø1 &amp;˜±SÖD™/žŽ&nbsp;ƒÅFÓšÚð<gÿ~ù(z½á›‘À ="" Ðm��ˆ^ˆ°kÂ�="" ¥<é�<9z#´ÇÑœnôfö®Ê|Üô¥xÒÓgëg;nu¶�ô`‹àiÖwh{fnî="" ·—¢a="" ÒŽÃ]¢<%Óÿëm="" ¢ÎÍ="" ¦,Õãlööb1hr="" j—øžŠ¬rË3œ%'l{‹ôjùì¸þysx¾¼‰„öx®¦À¾ÿïÌj="" endstream="" endobj="" 14="" 0="" obj="" <<="" type="" page="" contents="" 15="" r="" resources="" 13="" mediabox="" [0="" 595.276="" 841.89]="" parent="" 19="">&gt; endobj
3 0 obj &lt;&lt;
/Type /XObject
/Subtype /Image
/Width 1500
/Height 126
/BitsPerComponent 8
/ColorSpace /DeviceRGB
/Length 33027
/Filter/FlateDecode
/DecodeParms&lt;&gt;
&gt;&gt;
stream
xì½wÔo7q†BrC˜PC$¡šŽéÍôÞ{‡Ð;$tLï½Cè½ƒ)¦šbŠ��ÈÅ4‡îÐIå&gt;Akié¾{kï–´Ïù€9œ¥O[3½�F£ò;Þ¯ýë?ˆ�@ �@ �@ �@ {�?Ü»ÕEm�@ �@ �@ �@ ÿ‡@eB�@ �@ �@ �@ ØDPf€U�@ �@ �@ �@ A™Ð�@ �@ �@ �@ ö”Ù&nbsp;G•�@ �@ �@ �@ DP&amp;t �@ �@ �@ �}€@eöèQe �@ �@ �@ ”	�@ �@ �@ �@` A™}zT�@ �@ �@ �@eB�@ �@ �@ �@ ØDPf€U�@ �@ �@ �@ A™Ð�@ �@ �@ �@ ö”Ù&nbsp;G•�@ �@ �@ �@ DP&amp;t �@ �@ �@ �}€@eöèQe �@ �@ �@ ”	�@ �@ �@ �@` A™}zT�@ �@ �@ �@eB�@ �@ �@ �@ ØDPf€U�@ �@ �@ �@ A™Ð�@ �@ �@ �@ ö”Ù&nbsp;G•�@ �@ �@ �@ DP&amp;t �@ �@ �@ �}€@eöèQe �@ �@ �@ ”	�@ �@ �@ �@` A™}zT�@ �@ �@ �@eB�@ �@ �@ �@ ØDPf€U�@ �@ �@ �@ A™Ð�@ �@ �@ �@ ö´ê¬Wùßÿýß¿úÕ¯êß­/':Ñ‰Žw¼ãYE½Bÿñÿñ_ÿõ_^ÙùRø‡xÂžpþ[kî/ùËÿùŸÿi¥þ?º?ú£?:Á	NÐÃAhýë_ÿâ¿àÉ_õçÿó›«H–ƒX-—ÙñëŸþéŸÿøÇß±˜_�B¯üò³%OTýÃþðOúÓYÌÌÓ�îtó7cvŠa©ÞûÞ÷þïÿþ¯S¸V‘¬öµ!ˆªc©°W
µ×H¾úÕ¯~á_¨}uòz—»ÜåÆZu&amp;:Ñ©½V©0µ¯mùøÀ0¡m´‰êŒg&lt;ã_ýÕ_õpÚÿüÏÿ&lt;âˆ#:­ú¹Ï}îSŸúÔÂ¹çÏïÿûŸüä'{8@{‰K\bì¼üÿþæ_�TÌ~—¹Ìez8Li?õ©O}ï{ß›æû9§8Å)&gt;ø`¿¼S¥êœÿâ7ÿœºÌ2ø	ïÿûÍÂµbç;ßùNyÊSÖ¾6ä‡Wìƒ^±‰n•Y¸Vì‚¼àÉNv²Ú×†üo~ó›ÿôOÿÔ@˜IppÆúê»sxä‘Gþä'?É
oHtÐAû·Û@X#ÁIøùÏ^ûjæÿÉŸüÉÿñ›…�bÿþïÿþÑ�~Ô)¹Pæ¢½èŸýÙŸ-øieð’“��&nbsp;9ÉINrà�ŽÂ½ÿÎw¾Óé’"Ì©Nuªý÷ßˆTóƒüàG?úQ'7ìkÂQë
¨{öìùÙÏ~Ö)¡¢ÓŸþôüßÉ'‘û@©XWtr%°µ,dÝõío»_ÕOzÒ“ôÿ~üã£ê�@AÎêk”ýB©îq�{&lt;å)Oé”ŠèvyÔP×½îußýîwwJu–³œåŸø�ØÉ'‘£ä¨zgøV`uÚÓžv”ªººöµ¯
b�m|ÐƒôÐ‡&gt;´“I&amp;?î¸ã:—©‰@�øÄ'Îl{tÜïxÇç?ÿù=L&nbsp;e–9ê¨£ÎzÖ³vòIä?üá¯q�kô»ïý×ý±�}lVÿò/ÿrå+_ùk_ûZgÅ¯~õ«;™dò·¾õ­7¸Á
ú½ÒÇ=îq÷º×½2ÛÎÄ£ýè&lt;à�Óñá‡~éK_ºS˜DÎ"çV·ºÕË_þòNnÌ}ØO¼…N&gt;‰œ¹ïªW½j¤�èÕ‡&gt;ô¡QÛ]£¼bfä�QÑðŠM•Û�^ñ±Ç‹ýì€À!‡Âü&gt;j	�‡võ«_�h»‰m­Ø]îr—~�13ß�^ñ½ï}ï'&gt;ñ‰YÈ¶ùÈGÎu®sµ‘Ë€ýÓê„IV;æ˜c®t¥+}éK_i×þy…+\ámo{Û(©–k?þCò�å{ç+�Ûo}ë[�;ÏIT¦üQ{˜Ä&gt;†øî†²2úíá=ô/rVÄPöÛo¿~UK±�þ)HEáƒÑ¿,„ÓOç~x
&amp;�!‹
úã5DÕñØÐ¨~ÿ/…ùú§Ã„ªÎÂ¾?¬†r^ëZ×zéK_šØöü�~¾ó�ï¼Ñ�n„`=|&nbsp;e)Èâäãÿx'È‰«²‰}ÃÞ°ÿd
a&gt;T½?Ì‡T`…&gt;ô«ç&gt;÷¹´nˆY`�sö³Ÿýç8G'ì4
“N¬¡“O"GE±	ýªÎfÎÕ®vµ×¿þõýRaÞóž÷ÜøÆ7î7¸2—ºÔ¥&gt;ûÙÏöKæDR®ýë÷[õw½ë]xHßýîwû¥B$æ¾‹_üâý¬žô¤'Ýò–·ì�þ#	GHXØs
¤S*òmns›Ç?þñ�| g¶"ä„5îßÇ§:ôÐCßþö·÷KÅDÃÁ–›Üä&amp;/êäöùÏUï&lt;Ð—d`»å+_ù
XuŠùX¯˜YfÈÆ3¼b§sq™”‡L½bÂŽ¨:‹U§	Ëe¾þõ¯c‡¯r•«,s¾¾ò•¯¼æ5¯Ùyô#UÄžg@Îsžó8õ.”îYbôØKxñ‹_¼ ¹ùi&nbsp;W+TßÃ¬z¡Ø@Ug3‰c§¶P�ùéË_þ2ÎÞå/y³|O±}”AééK¼¢´ÐÓ¡Å²¨`ß¸áp
–Á˜Àp”G-S“x4©sxÇ?ñö	�#8Är¥†ûÄ|G1¤^û@&amp;zßy¹äLp†�Æ¶E‹þíßþíä'?9TÖÏCbI6´”¤‚ŠFA˜ÎÈ”�íL#,Û ±!¨980j™ššCcq(Qªw™îÃõ§÷ov³›½ñ�oìÄ'“Ã%½ÈE.ÒL’ªƒó….t¡/~ñ‹™mg‚«=,À¸rÒ }—ì'hã¥±Ü)O"OªÞ¦TYÕÙZg&gt;p}ôÑ7½éM‰d1×6&nbsp;Ð(þ¡çhûZò…ò€�^%æÅf?eûÉa"b
³e2i#½jP*ªKR1ãÀ¡ÿ4J–ŸqMøƒ³E
R¡E¬"0üá_xÈ:'	FT”`
fªA*L
NQ¹×¾öµ·¾õ­G
@ø#`ì`Bb£¨zšÍïÿû?ãÏÈøw&amp;°	x¥Ü¸¤½
XeUgß²ÿàUnî'X9Ù L’T¬sXÂ1f¶�‰ý×%ð\É;ZÅ
{Â&nbsp;ãø$Õ�åD®�ä9ü°b.@-Ñ+t~TD&amp;	†�A£ó,ª™ØÎ+Fö&gt;Y&gt;`ØMar1¤JãßØm^1sª&gt;ÐÙûÜç&gt;Gü&nbsp;”
pØ‰‡–C”Œt,cØ™Àªßâ·`ù†Â¯eE¿3ÝàcÛ‰ ¯%_(Ÿ€hP*îÅ&amp;¯˜Ùêu¯{ÝB-«&gt;1œ™û0¡‰ù*Z
'ûÉ`AÕQûµäµòØ(ðÇ6ØO„+üì9ÌÀÅ2þ'[ŒÌÈ
ª^kélþÈ·f+¨e2™røG°§×=©q&amp;ÄÀ2•˜ñàµƒ
3�z±×A×2ž‡l,$9a…†±vJÌkÂÏæ3»£&nbsp;)B„¶
Ô‰ÔF˜¯
99&gt;ÇÆõ«^õ*Ò/Ñ$nØ/Ö«x¥³€Ô2±7¿ùÍÏ{ÞóâÔ‚7ák%×æãŽ}g2«µ-žT�'XŽr®­½V{Ê™d&amp;¶†{Ì¦¸À8&lt;ÂÄèÃÖjY›�ÙÂo;ÿùÏÏ&amp;ãhùÞðžŸHU;ì0´}ùBá{ÞóžÜ„¢û&lt;’‡?üá¨:{Å(ÕÓžö´Q�îcÇƒ(ªÎ_~ú‰^cÖÁž&nbsp;óœÔ­cåŒµIÌ§U/ä0l±Ÿh#âa�ÙûZ(¼êÓ9ÏyÎW¼â¬êYÔÙ\EËž¶àlAÅjØW‘/f9ÁØÉÌJN?½ìe/£QOxÂøÄ�•�f�«^·½ímQªµá'Fëýîw?®½ï}ï%�7¸�Ó–’ÃôÇE!R­í&gt;†Çˆ§¢Zg&gt;ó™ïsŸûÌVÑ�‰žðƒLJËÿ«8`I!k]ô|à–óyÏ{Ì9Ì¿v®[KÇˆî{ßûžéLgZÕ¨…ÂÌ×»Þõx0…ÛÅf?qb¥â¾â60	Î[›‰r&gt;æ1�A*”ŠÕÅ*ræâ;ßùÎ@Î&lt;2a¥a¸ŠC­06�Yì/x÷XÖŠÍæ³äVcÅŒ&lt;Ð+fŽ@Ûq&gt;“Ë=[{-“)‡›�}ÀL�õŠq³Ë]`6ŸPR¥®uÿqÅ\^ñ§?ýi‚Œ&nbsp;œi&amp;Ø3@ÓR�'L*§@áIfæI*ƒec%Ospù˜þ¸ÏèÓ.—D?Ùza=�ÍYk©Xqpâ˜ †„ß¾\—ÿ•«»læá'\ö²—e@ù„”dá€Wœ6“Pƒ�^1F'
�mX¾éMoÂ+fZGÂG&lt;â×5w»ÛÝ0SüÃÅ]…ùÈG2¡¿ùÍoÆ�]òüHZ]®=PÉ\Ì
b&amp;P¢E¬Œ^sN°¢ôàÀðÓ,æûæ¤­bn`ã»ƒ#†žy£3+¥ŸÉ„[Î,}æ3Ÿa@rågÂ\DaåÓâ+ÆœÍäŠTÄÒ`¶$
Ä~1a›™Ï–œfâX§å@oblÓÆ!ñ?ôd’Çº/Ü´AtÓîp‡G=êQLÒïxÇ;p#Ò+08•U±�Óœæ4hBZNàŽÓæt‹qÇ¿å-oA»¸«Â~Œ ¢®�-¦;
³Hj ÿÓ¡ˆ:-9Í¡vT‘†«:š@²2‡9zEEœ 0Q;¶&amp;hÛ×2{�3Jµ6†2m/zÎùXN´Òœ(b£Ób³9�}ìcYL2@¸«‚¹g†ye)Þ9ÑŸg=ëYpNÚ…ž›ª8l¹°:î”òè½ß®W†^ –Ÿü”
ƒcª:¨b©hRñ²Ÿ¨ÿf�õ31@€Â $æ¸&amp;¦Ra&nbsp;�*Ù7$A¹¸N“…ñe˜–„¾ÇI8(�1Di¯s�ë˜RaÀÓÅXD‚=¥êô ¦˜ˆ~&amp;ææj`qð‡¶ÜÉGÉQ*Ö‡¸ù4m¾ŸƒV¿ä%/Á/I|”
	éS‡Š!�ÚÐT´‰`åúŸ&gt;eqÂxáöYš¶�
Ý0'e4ŠÙœ³Pñ
2G¥p£
¯ËiÔBV)¸Y€ƒÞæqd*[»HÅRÕâ°BEY	4|EB›¥ QžÜ¤ù„f¤LíOÉãÇjÑqLÉõÏ~³@”œÓ(¸Rô�\pWMŒ2]âùµ!�nàqPVMý›½Œ5ÆMÂW�fê²öZ›ÂÌ,@k°‹]ìbèÿ{�ìÜ&nbsp;\{Ík^ƒ•†9›«æÉ&gt;.=1W2{2L�ÃŽÆ¢Öbæ³ëÉÄr¢tDr¹MU€¢9ü£-ØÏÝàcx¶´…I“®çß(¯½"Fgz�°&amp;–ÙÁa˜7q{(Ì0Al/
¹v»eZ=Å¤Œ&amp;dæt�é*àHcšXÕ£Eøêa^7gF^.œJ2ÄîY?ÓØÔdß+Æ3¼ä%/É£6ˆ‡$H…�pCÓ¦­Ê�íSŸúTÝ?ÿó?cX’6}uðÁ+fêä®
jÏD3ÊUÀ+fà`œ}tªg³]n¡bÃñŠyÂŸg1¡ìèÀÊä0[ýá%ÿ³”C$6'8iþDÂæãÆ.
I^1v�	=iÂluf&amp;=Åär§;Ý‰½ÏÄœm3Åèc)Ê,ƒ•ãÁG¶„	ùá1ö¿�,¸
t"Z�Tüï«ºÙð²Øñ¨£ü{/¤Q&amp;�*UŠn ‚›–�&nbsp;.‹´¤O¬žóœç°Û‘-&amp;˜XYìÏÿüÏ±ªè+ÿÊüµé4ùác•„D1œ;ÿ,ØÊ%
¬xÅEí€«d¸6ÍB·Ò25ÑÂœ{ìIÚen·»ÝíÒ®W*Æ¢‚kœ¤ÓBn™vù+s‘‚rr%°Z¦J_	÷²�K2°Ÿþô§£ÞH•3Û,uè¾ÒµE]�Ø0N;¥ª3‡±Ê¢ê`órüÆXìØFV8L]¥þpÜ»3DÕY®â)›ÌÚyÏI–,<sk ´‘ÉµÎ¹€ŸÀ¦Óyi™š¨aŽhffç¶s®Üpø“fÒ¹9¿!‘6±k�="" 7Žs¤+Ü÷Ò( �`ŽsÈÊ ê,2Ë¦%æ$éòˆ6âgÒ‰ÀÞyÛ@±yb¯²œzÂ�ËÖÀË²¹ü="" ì="" ÆrÙÆ²€™f…à="" Ì9ÇáøÊ{ØÃüàçŠhîb¾jÓ—ø="" Ì¦©="" r9xßâ`å’ÄÙãoÞ,‡s.à'k¨gÙ}Ä="" sïÈÅ,œÀi…Ù�c…�óÇyâÉ—°÷È2µ4ƒì·;'Îˆ1×”c="" £7n="" wºü•i™Ù�“žÌï¹$a1ÖqùÏz‚ur="" Åp`ˆhv£rò™s˜="" °„¹0jÅ4�¨9§–àx§ÀòwÂ1)šf÷uzðèztn="" Ä×¸šëzh€'‹�\€5azä ê9³-q¶³��="" zÜayÿ¢½hgnŒüpÍ%Ù="" àpÒwdÄi.w®«–ØÔ+Æ°‹ËmzÅ8¢Òx˜q^1amüÛ="" þ'Õ9qmõò\3éÎpø="" ñŠ1éˆqjezÅmãÔo&¼ýíoÏ3lÎlk°m†h¥wÌªÕ9dh‰)©ÄŠce,òË8{mÂd*æ÷ýo™ÿø�ÿÈú<¨%û„ŒËé€s3œïâã¥k¼="" kå(¦»Þõ®yæ$bÕy="" -eèò§µ="" &;‚på‹òØsºÀy�‚'3×nì—ðçu‡yùú="">�6®r]‰¿üË¿d­‘°À./3)'3rf[‚°,–yêr·qÛ‘jÌoÜìXMY˜ÄÉKŽ,Ë’²dCTÎÓppœ?ŠM—îøîäóJ4“I¦ãÇñÝ§R’|,~fÞœ(}w˜ÀÜ�”L#0×›&amp;†•3›Ò&amp;øLeD†Ú‰Ýò?-êW*,u9÷ÀÖì¾MU�g‘ñ¥"(SÎ=¦ü�¦[;��ÔþÁ¼ÝàÏâ¼V¸Ì/½dò¡JÚÈ¼XkK³á\šÝ‰H•”Š|Ž6”ÛÒlÈ”„¦TS/!búUæ­0 îû¬6-â_ÙÌ†4“t¹¤‡C¶9ËÜÄ˜P8a…?ä¸DËÌËˆ6%QWLè2Iú*J•ÛbnÉ.W!ÑS©àÉF\É9«:ÖÊü†4Š!Ñ
S*¨$Ð�°Â7åhCƒ$%	ÆYÌ&nbsp;©êì@”x&amp;©ˆˆñ¯¬¢!ýÂ¾ÁJÂÜeæ4-mL®ëUþMË¯Êyæ3ŸY–'âDd ©¹
S*¶¥	—„¦RaâdEšº¸ú•
ÅHTY0³û{•Èá¯3XNÊ07U½f?‡¸
â¨#•Ùƒ¢êc½bÑX&amp;/s¦©r[†xÅ5æYÍfj%x�TÙúUãYntùÝ‡£^Fd LªÎvB¿T”��
snêËRËÇJ\öo’U'"6Ûã«2åvº‘\î™ˆTá!ª.03_–ŠsseD†ÂIÕY)÷+UÍå^©ùëÿ­ð÷ò?ñ9¨}Hˆ!µ‚è¦4‡CY’3û§H…êg«:[~U¦0g1™á@&nbsp;�¿�9n�Êæ›—$µ4®&nbsp;üjÎˆÍý^ÖUKP3;¢™°&amp;I™ßÌ\°bËÅ9_SV½�æl‰˜5…pÔÏW'Q+³ûˆ¥Êšp&nbsp;ªû�5¡)•´…š„½–?53o&amp;ÌU/$D7°Ÿæ9[‘
cbºÂäOÍÌ¥9»AÕÙ²_v&nbsp;ªcÒ%`gj¬ò¥’îƒyÛ\@²Vt&amp;¤É„YÓ‘ºÙJs@x&nbsp;ª‹Tf/ÐéÄJÉMÂ’¤–†¹ì”˜JÅQ!8i¯Xu³É‚0­6	kø”ù¢|2U]ñŠÍhNY{--Ìw‰W,aöB³6ÖÀ)ó§^±©ê&lt;Ãk6§¬½––î£˜)• á@©š™!±‚Dµ¶¯Í¬D)¶²#‘j PTÝÆœýo9õ3P*ÓåÕ„4™K[|Â»€Ò}ä˜ªî0Ÿ–Ù÷A\‡�†^ú†ýÎ?O›=ÍÜÇ‚ÞÆ{*„æT:mÝ4C/®‰ÙdÎµ¹S¦9Ò^
˜RI¿Chæ©Óœf©„Ðw;¦2Ls„9a&gt;øO‹Ms«�@QWsŽ²s¾ºu&nbsp;T¨«œþ0•jzu&nbsp;TÒ}´Ý”ª™°„·–ž27mŽúnGM’2_”Š�çî'D*á²ê…ts|Ù`¨T„?dKÜl² L«J%@Á¼M*ìGÓzdÕ§QR!’¹Åâˆ'ÁŽ¨é¾KsL„‘(Ã¤_–4uƒÍ¹£d–uÕÒx/²à4›,Ã&nbsp;TÍÌe®aÏÙ¼uXÃ§ÌÝð]n!4.«^H·1ß4ü�ý”ÇªLÝ�¶Ðê�X53oÖÆ…^ËŸFIÅ�Q€d¶�	i2G¹§ãðB³ßÎ”¬LÝàœÚvûßœ¢’Ëƒf“(Zg:X‰ô™o*•tR™=è4yZfßehÞnØÒÜ‚Þ&lt;‹HÐd¬*43ß�Ú/RqôÃÆM‡Ä4GtÃ?E%„•
!¥MæPÉ1¿�û„Ì"r%Ç´×¿‡[:¢þè–~÷ƒqSÅžæˆT&gt;s!4µq*ÀlŽŒnS©šƒq³2H&amp;ÌùWfšM–¶ÀÁlNYW--½@1Sª©34äÚ`’³Y*ÁŠGRÌ`\
Ÿ2_¤"øhú!"ÕÀîC¼6æÍÁ¸�Zš[Bm§¨¤-ðˆ•˜A˜›ª.Raâx¦ÖöµùÂ‘Ì»cBèã	EÕ‘ÊTuÙDØ©yÇ±ùØ�#ÏŸÁ¿,ij¬ ‡�XI/øÌE©¸uh&gt;ºT"PKK“ýST"•‰pMÉocÞŒ“Úgÿœî›]„Âe‹e&nbsp;¯PÔ6;bê*˜„³àH¦t_MæBÈÛFý·æ³l¢ê¾Wœ9¬JìŠ&nbsp;Ì*‰—ËKQf�njè›™‹*Ðð�†¾™¹h?^2¾òr§ø_E*KG¤2ûÝL¤2{¡9çH5õiL©šÝG*oË,bv„tu™„ŽTÒ}�˜X‰TgM÷T�Jw,#Rù§¨„ÐlËŽò¤mÌétñeJÅÛIòx„©Ò8Pªfæ¢THe6ÇéÁQRÑ6
i�Ê?E%X

±+S76½ÒÈ)*y¨Èl²´…Ö™ÍqºOzS*!d6òB’yÚds©#Rñ&lt;¤IØ€·,ñàM„Î”¬LÝÀ¤Ëln:RíN¯Xtƒ†˜!C8P©„y³WLœÝÆ9=(R™º�ãÚ¶FsDb›ä_øBYÒì¾é•F“°¬«–Sƒÿ@©šU]ñÌŸ§¨áSæsÿ•
ñ¤MU/Ûµ*½·ƒ2Ü#ØÎÐóÆaùD9@˜}#öÂ�¸73Ÿngèi²É\´7Ë¼5ãè¥4™^0g‘í}sø£Ùíp€3ÑÜ}šcÄ‘ª9ˆ.„<cc¾¤àh%xí’-�©ª;m™fúÌaÛÆÜ4ƒ‚0u™„ŽtÍ§¨6•jºÏo²Øoösœßqs€¢Œ4ÙßÒ©Ú¤¬lÝàæ¿2v6|à>!î{Û•F
ñbÕÌ\ú©L�Kxkéf©„“Î^}­–µù¢T˜Aóž—H5°ûhBs"qmÁ8´æØŠ L]çš)sSc§„¥’îóOQÉ¤-¦ãêô&nbsp;4™öšÌ¥9cU}Úd§-˜ôí®4ò0¼&lt;Án6Y€¢!&amp;¡Ódé&gt;HLU©Æ^iæXæôca;¶HEÕÂÜœñ™Íåñ2“pÇÆR&nbsp;yè0Ÿ-³·ƒ2Í
:+½dJ�òÕÔ±/šÃF˜ýsÚdsB¨L·cVÉ”&amp;û³ˆ€l",µ×þ”&amp;›½@0Nžs(UslEÚB“Í~¯�SæO™›XI÷!Òv¯Tú§¨D*"}¦ÛQbRKV&amp;PØbyIa¬¡ŸÀšüe&gt;TVæ˜Í)IjiŠb&amp;ó)á@UÝ@*st‹T~0®†O™?eÞ¶%&gt;P©O¤2»¥’+�&amp;Â% µtó)*FŸ¨ú@©(„7±jÖÆ&gt;e~3siÛ$wJD*ÿax!Ø}€&amp;M6»�{Xm/)”ÝTKó+{öì)¿šM&nbsp;à`–uÕÒÅL¬š	k’”ùÍÌ…Ð?vWÖ^KKGø§¨D*áš’ßÆœß(�_}¨TÍ‘&gt;A˜–”jÊÜœ^…�©Üü%é©Ù?¥ûðlMïH¤âñ²í¬ºŠjÓýoq¹MÝàÍ„¶`ÜlI¦8ê|;º¥:þÜ÷ASA§¢OsD‰)`^Œ—a3ÖÐ73Â±ªÐÆœÇ±¿ó�ï”È›Ã¦$©¥›OQMû}&nbsp;TÂ›ÑLXÃ§ÌŸ27Ç‘œIá:=Ú^rîIKGø³Èv†žæV&amp;P\™á-´��J50ÒgjcÙ�ZZ€¢˜É\}·£&amp;I™/JåŸ¢©Ì¶”U/¤Û˜¡hs;$ÉŸaˆaªú¦WE$¤5;BúÂ�PºÏ—JìçØ+�ÒdŽP™§¨¤9&amp;ÂYs–"•ÙxÉmï‹-“¾N#}¦ªK[àf6Ç‘ª™y3¡#Uó¥ò�Ý9R	sßåÂÝ&nbsp;êÍÇî&nbsp;ðŠá_–4›¼©RI/ ^ÛÄU0×h%µ´4™†[B?W“¤Ì¬ÊÜq©Z*Äks¹›/£”€ÔÒÍ§¨(øÄJºæ¦ª×š¹cþ&gt;Ê0lÌ
Æ[Bq˜¸ê¶ÿþû;„‚ûXÐ…¹iRq;ÚÎW;í�Î"f“aêÚTûM¬¦cr&nbsp;¡åÓøn‡Óƒ¢TtŸyŠJ°Ø}ˆÝÆ|Ïž=ûÊV”jwnéH÷ÑvSÕ§„æÈ-á­¥§ªn2©&nbsp;2ÝŽš$e¾(•¿¥3•ªdÛ“&amp;ü!ÌÍîc™ÊcØeÕU�î“£%¦T‚0â™ŒeCjiŠb¦T2×ðãÐ_©U÷OQ	V»dÚ˜Oƒq&amp;Âµ.+óªí÷hšº¬½–nV*Aþ{°™¹r¥‘‡*km_›/XáróÏa"„•ŠÚÛ˜Oƒq¥âkÎÓJ[à`Î›e]µô”¹ÙdQ*øTõQRaÒ^i”&amp;óØ%W~jÀ–ùB8(j¬Ìîã'Û~ºlW-ý­o}«í•ÿ�X53BfóÝð+�5ðwÌßÇASAwlF* }cª†^\´�R5Ï"2’ià@©š™ÂHe‚ìôàT*sn©:è 60��2"•[Â�Ý‡ØmÌ¹äõÍo~³lõÀî›Î"¦O#Ý‡x&amp;aÙ�ZZ€¢˜Ù²&amp;»¥3•ÊTu!„ÊÆÕð)ó…9@™±•)aÉ¶3-êajls0Î‘¶ù&nbsp;“´…ºÌæ8RI/@bªºH…‰c«Ð©Ñ)#R¡QðwE*‚qÛ©º9úlwÐ	WA.Æ›ºÑŒsz�ST²9dJ%ÝG]&amp;¡#•($mª¾ß~ûqË©Ñ)#MöOQ	áÀé±+¨M#}»Ó+–^:ScaM�¥jf.?;Í³©N�N‘Ê?E% ›;"Q¦�ù¦WÙÿæ_)¿©Ò}pˆ•å3o&amp;,¨¥…9®‚ù0¼úÁ¸š$e¾¨:®‚é—LV¥÷jPfSC�£,[:æÜ&amp;à3‡�´ô¨Ï|Jh:Ž›J%ÚÀxà�N�Ni2û9æ)*‘j&nbsp;ñBl‘ÊÔ�f·Ã
æâ(›R	PÔ5«fæSÂ��¤ûhrVøîxðNï8eDªÝé3
Nóùj¨={öðRCYÒÔXAf¿—uÕÒÍÌEÕ‰2˜nGM’2*•Ùƒ"ÕØ+�"•ïÓ´�¯.YH‹T¦nL¯4š&gt;Æ‚$ùÓ1Çó‹_ü"ÿIÂd.m�ÐlNYW--ºA1s
!"™?]“¤Ì—&amp;7GúhË@[šlv³ùv‘¾f—[ü�JÕìro*•tŸ¯ê"VÝŒ;—*]Kóßj¯˜+�¼Å[¶Ô4&amp;%I-=}Þd.
üMÂš$e¾tŸÚ&amp;å±R5«ºŽý•FaîŸ¢Â�ÝìÒƒÍ`©'ez¯e¶ÞÒ!.S¶Íìqof.„¾ÛQ"PKsÙ…Ú?
Æ™ý^§ÌÇaÂ4©BÏÝ&nbsp;TÒ}H5«fæBH˜�óÛe/ô¤EÕwÉ–ŽHeêFs0Î�ýœ¶Hß¦ª.ºák¬ ¡	²ƒUs“¥9ü
·rœ�2Òd,•y´D6åÚÄ©Ì^àå2NÞ•­(SC©dnJ%Ý‡�RI/øÌaÍIªD&nbsp;––&amp;û§¨¤9þûb5IÊ|i2ÝgÆVd6°û´1ŸãJ…¥B°:SÕ›M\YW--Ý…</cc¾¤àh%xí’-�©ª;m™fúìaûæü4ƒ‚0u™„žtí§¨6•jºïo²øoösœßqs€¢œ4ùßò©ú¤¬lýàæ¿2v6|à></sk></gÿ~ù(z½á›‘à></yžwrï¶ön·{¹fè$â˜î></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://www.harold.thimbleby.net/cv/files/seven-segment.pdf">http://www.harold.thimbleby.net/cv/files/seven-segment.pdf</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.harold.thimbleby.net/cv/files/seven-segment.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26373405</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 05:27:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Functioning iPhone returned to owner after six months at bottom of lake]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 125 | Comments 94 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26372407">thread link</a>) | @Tiktaalik
<br/>
March 6, 2021 | https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/cell-phone-recovered-from-harrison-lake-1.5937753?cmp=rss | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/cell-phone-recovered-from-harrison-lake-1.5937753?cmp=rss">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>A Vancouver woman who lost her phone in Harrison Lake in September is shocked and surprised that not only has it been recovered from the lake bottom, but that it still works.</p><div><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939069.1614985130!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/cell-phone.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Clayton Helkenberg puts a cellphone in a net along with other items he and his wife Heather found in a lake-bottom search at Harrison Lake. The cellphone would later power up and Helkenberg tracked down the owner — six months after it was lost in the water.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Clayton Helkenberg)</figcaption></figure><p><span><p>Fatemeh Ghodsi was skeptical at first when she got a text from someone saying they found her phone nearly six months after she lost it in Harrison Lake.</p>  <p>Ghodsi, who lives in Vancouver, was confused&nbsp;and thought one of her friends might&nbsp;be playing a prank on her. But she was soon convinced and made the trip to Chilliwack to collect the phone, which amazingly still works.</p>  <p>Clayton Helkenberg&nbsp;and his wife Heather found the lost iPhone 11 during a sweep of the lake bottom under the water park at Harrison Lake — part&nbsp;of a hobby that includes the odd treasure find, but mostly just lots of&nbsp;garbage clean up.</p>  <p>Ghodsi dropped the phone in the water in early September, during a ride on the bumper boats — photos recovered from the phone show her still smiling moments before the mishap.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939063.1614985154!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/fatemeh-ghodsi.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939063.1614985154!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/fatemeh-ghodsi.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939063.1614985154!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/fatemeh-ghodsi.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939063.1614985154!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/fatemeh-ghodsi.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939063.1614985154!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/fatemeh-ghodsi.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939063.1614985154!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/fatemeh-ghodsi.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Fatemeh Ghodsi gives the peace sign as she and her friend are seen riding bumper boats at Harrison Lake in early September. Moments later, Ghodsi's phone was lost at the bottom of the lake.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Fatemeh Ghodsi)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>"I was in a situation where I kind of lost balance and dropped it in the water," she said, adding that the water park staff convinced her it would be impossible to find the phone in the deep water.</p>  <p>"Distressed and in tears, we went back to Vancouver just kind of hopeless," said Ghodsi.</p>    <p>She soon bought a new phone, and came to terms with the lost photos, contacts, and other personal information that hadn't been backed up.</p>  <h2>YouTubing&nbsp;diver</h2>  <p>Helkenberg&nbsp;has been snorkeling, swimming&nbsp;and diving for years, but at the start of 2020 — with extra time on his hands after being laid off — he started putting more effort into searching for lost items in the water, as well as doing trash cleanup missions.</p>  <p>Sometime he goes on his diving missions with friends and his wife.&nbsp;He even started a YouTube channel to document his finds.</p>  <p><span><span><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ifzizYAf-hs" frameborder="no" title="YouTube content" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></span></span></p>  <p>Last year, he found more than a hundred pairs of sunglasses, 26 cellphones and two GoPro cameras. This year, he's already counted 35 pairs of sunglasses, five phones and one GoPro.</p>  <p>His underwater work has even attracted some <a href="https://www.theprogress.com/news/chilliwack-diver-retrieves-items-dropped-in-cultus-lake/" target="_blank">media attention</a>, including a report&nbsp;of&nbsp;<a href="https://www.vancouverisawesome.com/bc-news/divers-haul-792-pounds-of-trash-out-of-cultus-lake-3364548" target="_blank">359 kilograms of trash he and friends pulled from Cultus Lake</a> earlier this year.</p>  <p>This week, he was at Harrison Lake — the water is much shallower now than it was in the summer, and according to&nbsp;Helkenberg, it's quite clear. He found a severely damaged&nbsp;flip phone, but Heather Helkenberg&nbsp;noticed Ghodsi's iPhone.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939076.1614993376!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/cell-phone.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939076.1614993376!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/cell-phone.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939076.1614993376!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/cell-phone.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939076.1614993376!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/cell-phone.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939076.1614993376!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/cell-phone.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939076.1614993376!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/cell-phone.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Heather Helkenberg finds an iPhone 11 in the sediment at the bottom of Harrison Lake. She said it was the first cellphone she has found. <!-- --> <!-- -->(Clayton Helkenberg)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <h2>'It just turned right on'</h2>  <p>Clayton Helkenberg&nbsp;said he usually puts phones in a container of silica to dry them out, but he's had good luck with iPhone 11s.</p>  <p>"I took it home, cleaned the dirt off of it and it just turned right on, so it was pretty amazing," he said.</p>  <p>He pulled out the SIM card, put it in another phone to figure out the phone number and got in touch with Ghodsi.</p>  <p>"I was in complete shock, initially to start with. It was kind of like a zombie phone coming back to me, because I'd totally made peace with it being gone," she said.</p>    <p>Ghodsi said the microphone is broken and the speaker sounds weird, but everything else is in perfect shape; the battery health is still at 96 per&nbsp;cent.</p>  <p>She's thankful for the phone's recovery and inspired that Helkenberg makes the effort to reunite people with lost valuables, asking nothing in return. But the experience has left Ghodsi even more impressed by his trash cleanup work, saying it's a reminder to keep our water clean.</p>  <p>"It gives me so much hope for the good that's out there," she said.</p>  <p>As for the next time she takes a ride on the bumper boats?&nbsp;Ghodsi said she'll either leave her phone and valuables on the shore&nbsp;or keep them securely stowed in a pocket.</p>  <hr>  <p><em>Do you have more to add to this story? Email <a href="mailto:rafferty.baker@cbc.ca?subject=diving%20for%20trash%20and%20valuables">rafferty.baker@cbc.ca</a></em></p>  <p><em>Follow Rafferty Baker on Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/raffertybaker" target="_blank">@raffertybaker</a></em></p></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/cell-phone-recovered-from-harrison-lake-1.5937753?cmp=rss</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26372407</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 01:54:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: PrograMaker – Visual Programming Platform]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 81 | Comments 16 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26369893">thread link</a>) | @kenkeiras
<br/>
March 6, 2021 | https://programaker.com/about | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://programaker.com/about">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://programaker.com/about</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26369893</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 19:38:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Tech posers of the Bauhaus]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 81 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26366513">thread link</a>) | @amicoleo
<br/>
March 6, 2021 | https://www.orgonomyproductions.info/notes/notes/2021/02/27/TechPosersBauhaus.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.orgonomyproductions.info/notes/notes/2021/02/27/TechPosersBauhaus.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        




<article itemscope="" itemtype="https://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  


  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>The Bauhaus greatest achievement was to make artists interested in the creative use of technology, to design things that are useful and nice to use. And they did that without knowing a lot about tech.</p>

<hr>

<p>Product, experience, interaction, industrial designers, creative technologists. If somehow you are a creative interested in making things that are useful and nice to use, you owe that to the Bauhaus. It’s also because of that school and their influence on art education that we can enjoy things designed by people with an artistic sensibility. Rather than only having things designed by engineers.</p>

<p>At the time, few artists were willing to collaborate with the industry to create mass-manufactured objects. Architect Walter Gropius, founder and director of the school, was especially passionate about social architecture and in general in creating things for the common people. Mass-manufacturing technology could allow that at scale. So some years after the creation of the school, he adjusted the focus in the Bauhaus curriculum. And since 1925, when the Bauhaus moved to Dessau, the school new motto became ‘Art and technology: a new unity’.</p>

<hr>

<p>But despite the ambition of the Bauhaus to teach students how to design for the industry, few of the tutors at the time had experience in industrial production. The school method was still based on a combination of applied arts and academic education, and the students’ practical lessons were given by craftsmen whose experience was in making things by hand and not in designing for production.</p>

<p>For instance, in the metal workshop under Moholy-Nagy, students would handmade prototypes with a style they thought would be easy to reproduce industrially. For instance using spheres, cylinders and other basic shapes. Except that due to their ignorance of industrial processes, those objects were hard to make in a mass-production facility.</p>

<p>But the strongest critique of the Bauhaus lack of technological knowledge was Buckminster Fuller. Fuller was familiar with the work of the Bauhaus due to the Black Mountain College in the US, where he and other former Bauhaus tutors were teaching. According to him, the ‘International Style’ brought to the US by the Bauhaus, simple replaced the previous decorative style with a new simplified one made of basic shapes and colours. A new exterior, but that was leaving unchanged the structural and functional elements of the building.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>In short they only looked at problems of modifications of the surface of end-product, which end-products were inherently sub-functions of a technically obsolete world</p>
</blockquote>

<p>(Obviously, Bucky did all the things he was criticising Gropius and the Bauhaus about. But that’s a story I’ll save for some other time).</p>

<hr>

<p>The excitement of the Bauhauslers for new technologies is still present among designers now. And so is that limit in understanding fully a new innovation that can be used in a new product or service. I feel that every time I’m working with machine learning. But what the Bauhaus achieved was to get artists interested in bringing their sensibility in the creative use of technology. And whatever Bucky thinks, that remains.</p>

<p><strong>References</strong></p>

<p>Bauhaus - Madgalena Droste</p>

<p>Theory and Design in the First Machine Age - Reyner Banham</p>


  </div>

  
</article>



      </div>


    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.orgonomyproductions.info/notes/notes/2021/02/27/TechPosersBauhaus.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26366513</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 10:29:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Tell HN: I am doing online reading sessions on analytic number theory]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 100 | Comments 27 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26366464">thread link</a>) | @susam
<br/>
March 6, 2021 | https://spxy.github.io/bc/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://spxy.github.io/bc/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>


<p>
Welcome to the first edition of our online reading session. This is a
tiny book club. In the first edition, we will be diving into the
beautiful world of <em>number theory</em>.
</p>



<p>
  <small>
  †
  The Matrix room and Freenode channel are bridged together, so if you
  join one of them, you will automatically receive the updates and
  messages from the other one too. If you are not an active Freenode
  user, prefer joining the Matrix room because it is more convenient,
  e.g., you can close your browser or client and your chat session will
  still stay alive. You can connect back the next day and catch up with
  the messages. Doing that with Freenode IRC requires slightly more work
  (setting up IRC bouncers etc.).
  </small>
</p>


<h2 id="reference">Reference Material<a href="#reference"></a></h2>

<p>
The primary reference book for these meetings is going to be:
<em>Introduction to Analytic Number Theory</em> written by Tom M.
Apostol. Admittedly, the book is quite expensive but you may find a
relatively cheap paperback (softcover) copy on some websites. A DRM-free
PDF eBook is available for purchase at <a href="https://www.springer.com/gp/book/9780387901633">springer.com/gp/book/9780387901633</a>.
</p>

<p>
If you are unable to buy the reference book, you can still participate
in this book club activity by downloading freely available notes from
  the University of Illinois: <a href="https://faculty.math.illinois.edu/~hildebr/ant/main.pdf">main.pdf</a>.
</p>

<p>
For solutions to exercise problems, refer to this excellent PDF created
by Greg Hurst: <a href="https://greghurst.files.wordpress.com/2014/02/apostol_intro_to_ant.pdf">apostol_intro_to_ant.pdf</a>.
</p>


<h2 id="schedule">Schedule<a href="#schedule"></a></h2>

<p>
Here is the schedule for the upcoming planned meetings:
</p>

<ul>
  <li>
     04 Mar 2021 18:00-18:40 UTC: Introduction. Kick-starting chapter 1.
    (Pilot)
  </li>
  <li>
    05 Mar 2021 18:00-18:40 UTC: Chapter 1
  </li>
  <li>
    06 Mar 2021 10:00-10:40 UTC: Chapter 1
  </li>
  <li>
    07 Mar 2021 10:00-10:40 UTC: Chapter 1
  </li>
  <li>
    08 Mar 2021 18:00-18:40 UTC: Chapter 1
  </li>
  <li>
    09 Mar 2021 18:00-18:40 UTC: Chapter 1
  </li>
  <li>
    10 Mar 2021 18:00-18:40 UTC: Chapter 1
  </li>
  <li>
    More sessions coming up later ...
  </li>
</ul>

<p>
Roughly speaking, the plan is to cover a chapter every one or two weeks.
</p>

<p>
If you have any questions, join our <a href="https://app.element.io/#/room/#susam:matrix.org">Matrix room</a>
(or the corresponding Freenode channel) and discuss.
</p>

<p>
Also, <a href="https://twitter.com/intent/follow?screen_name=susam">follow me on
Twitter</a> where I will post upcoming reading session details.
</p>

<h2 id="faq">FAQ<a href="#faq"></a></h2>
<ol>
  <li id="faq-who">
    <h3>
      Who are you?
      <a href="#faq-who"></a>
    </h3>
    <p>
      Hi! I am <a href="https://susam.in/">Susam</a>. I am just someone
      who enjoys mathematics, Lisp, and Emacs and wants to spread the
      joy of spending time with these beautiful things. I have been
      working as an information security professional for about 15
      years. Of these 15 years, close to 7 years were spent working with
      probability theory, calculus, and combinatorics, and another 3
      years in implementation of cryptographic utilities.
    </p>
    <p>
      I do a lot of teaching as hobby. This is my way of giving
      something back to the technology community. I have taught Common
      Lisp, Emacs, Python, C, Vim, and various areas of mathematics. In
      each one of my previous workplaces, I have created communities
      around mathematics, algorithms, and/or, cryptography. In the
      online world, I created the <a href="https://webchat.freenode.net/##algorithms">##algorithms</a>
      channel on Freenode IRC (my nick there is <code>spal</code>). What
      started as a tiny hobby club around algorithms 13 years ago is now
      a thriving community with over 200 members. (Disclosure: I don't
      participate in it anymore but a highly talented group of
      moderators helps maintain the channel).
    </p>
    <p>
      These hobbies of teaching and forming local and online communities
      have also led me to write some open source projects. Some are
      mildly popular and some not so popular but have managed to find
      its own niche community of users. For example, <a href="https://github.com/susam/texme">TeXMe</a> and <a href="http://mathb.in/">MathB.in</a> were born out of the need to
      share mathematics problems and solutions within these communities.
      <a href="https://github.com/susam/uncap">Uncap</a> was born when I
      used to teach Vim and I wanted Windows users to have a good
      ergonomic experience. Similarly, <a href="https://github.com/susam/emacs4cl">Emacs4CL</a> was born
      while teaching Common Lisp with Emacs and SLIME.
    </p>
    <p>
      To summarize, I work in information security by profession and I
      am an open source software developer by hobby. I want to use some
      part of my leisure time in hosting book club meetings where we
      pick up good books and work through them together.
    </p>
  </li>
  <li id="faq-why">
    <h3>
      Why are you doing this?
      <a href="#faq-why"></a>
    </h3>
    <p>
      During the course of my career and hobbies, I have found
      Mathematics, Lisp, and Emacs to be extraordinarily elegant and
      beautiful and it is my goal to introduce as many people to these
      things as possible.
    </p>
    <p>
      Software development these days focus a lot around stitching
      together many libraries to accomplish complex tasks. I understand
      that this is more economical and productive. This approach has
      certainly made it possible to develop huge and complex
      software-based infrastructure that has changed the way we live.
      However, I think, in this fast-paced software development world,
      the simpler joys of devising or implementing algorithms from
      scratch and appreciating the underlying beauty of mathematics is
      taking a backseat. I intend to introduce more and more people to
      some of these simpler joys, especially, the joy of unravelling the
      mysteries of prime numbers, appreciating the simplicity and
      elegance of Lisp, experiencing the remarkable extensibility of
      Emacs, and so on.
    </p>
    <p>
      Also, the more I help others work though a formidable book like
      <em>Introduction to Analytic Number Theory</em>, the more it helps
      me too to appreciate some finer and deeper points that I may not
      have paid due attention to when I read the book for the first
      time. So I benefit from these reading sessions too. Similarly, the
      more I help someone with Common Lisp programming, the more I have
      to dive into the Common Lisp HyperSpec which often teaches me a
      few new things too, so I gain from the experience too.
    </p>
  </li>
  <li id="faq-book">
    <h3>
      Have you read the entire book?
      <a href="#faq-book"></a>
    </h3>
    <p>
      No, I have read approximately half of the book (Introduction to
      Analytic Number Theory) and I am enjoying it so far. This means
      that I am a good number of chapters ahead of someone who has just
      begun reading this book, so I can maintain a steady pace in the
      reading sessions and also be able to tell if some topics or areas
      of confusion in an earlier chapter will be clarified in a later
      chapter.
    </p>
  </li>
  <li id="faq-lisp">
    <h3>
      You mentioned Lisp. Can you do a book club for it?
      <a href="#faq-lisp"></a>
    </h3>
    <p>
      Yes, Lisp and Emacs are two other areas at the top of my mind.
      Once there has been sufficient progress in the number theory book
      club, I plan to start a Lisp one next. Join the <a href="https://app.element.io/#/room/#susam:matrix.org">Matrix
      room</a> or <a href="https://app.element.io/#/room/#susam:matrix.org">follow me
      on Twitter</a> to receive further updates about this.
    </p>
  </li>
  <li id="faq-but">
    <h3>
      But I want to do group reading sessions for another book!
      <a href="#faq-but"></a>
    </h3>
    <p>
      Start your own book club around it! This is mine. I have chosen
      number theory as the topic of discussion for now. After a few
      months, I will move on to topics around Lisp and Emacs. If you
      have a different topic or book in mind, start your own book club
      for it. You can reuse my channels (see top of this page) for it or
      you can do it your own way. If you let me know about it and if I
      can find the time, I will join your book club too! I think, we
      need more book clubs, not less!
    </p>
  </li>
  <li id="faq-recording">
    <h3>
      Will these sessions be recorded?
      <a href="#faq-recording"></a>
    </h3>
    <p>
      Not at this time because we often refer to a few pages of the book
      via screen sharing during the reading session. I don't know the
      copyright implications of recording such sessions as videos and
      sharing them with everyone online. If you have expertise in this
      area, I would like to know if my concern is genuine and if there
      is a way to resolve it.
    </p>
  </li>


</ol></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://spxy.github.io/bc/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26366464</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 10:14:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
