<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 20]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 20. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 08:23:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-20.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 08:23:09 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Untimely Demise of Workstations]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 27 | Comments 14 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24977652">thread link</a>) | @ingve
<br/>
November 3, 2020 | https://deprogrammaticaipsum.com/the-untimely-demise-of-workstations/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://deprogrammaticaipsum.com/the-untimely-demise-of-workstations/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

		<p>Last month’s news that <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/10/ibm-to-split-into-two-companies-by-the-end-of-2021/">IBM would do a Hewlett-Packard</a> and divide into two—an IT consultancy and a buzzword compliance unit—marks the end of “business as usual” for yet another of the great workstation companies.</p>
<p>A quick aside on computing history. You can imagine personal computing being driven by two distinct schools of thought. The “top down” school, represented by research-led organisations including Xerox PARC, Bell Labs,academia and the military, asked “what would the world be like if everyone had their own minicomputer”? They took large, time-sharing systems like UNIX and installed them first under, then on, employees’ desks for their own personal use.</p>
<p>The “bottom up” school was made up of hobbyists who asked “can we make an interesting computer out of inexpensive components”? Thus companies like Apple and MITS in the US, Acorn and Sinclair Radionics in the UK, and others took chips that were usually used as peripherals controllers in “real” computers and built interactive programming systems around them. The microcomputer revolution came from the bottom-up school, as they made home computing affordable. The workstation revolution came from the top-down school, as they made powerful on-demand computing feasible.</p>
<p>The two schools came into very close proximity in the 1980s, when the Motorola 68000 family of CPUs (along with the 68881/68882 FPU and 68851 MMU) were the processors of choice in everything from entry-level PCs like the Atari 520ST, through games consoles like the Sega Mega Drive (Genesis in the US), to the most expensive UNIX workstations from NeXT Computer, Sun Microsystems, and Apollo Computer.</p>
<p>But then the workstation makers invested heavily in their own CPU architectures based on RISC design principles and again the two diverged. The workstation market became highly differentiated: RS/6000 from IBM (later PowerPC), Alpha from Digital Equipment Corp, MIPS from, well, MIPS, SPARC from Sun, PA-RISC from HP. The software on these workstations, while superficially very similar, was also differentiated and surprisingly incompatible. Take a program from HP-UX and you’ll have difficulty running it on NeXTSTEP, unless the authors shared the source code and used the nascent GNU autotools to support portable building. As Yoda said: begun, the <a href="https://www.livinginternet.com/i/iw_unix_war.htm">UNIX wars</a> have.</p>
<p>Of course we know that the (desktop) computing world today is mostly Intel and that workstations are mostly fancy PCs, rather than bespoke designs by vertically-integrated companies, Apple being the two trillion dollar outlier. How we got here was that the commodity parts got good enough that there was no evident advantage to workstation-grade hardware. A high-end PC could easily run a workstation OS like System V UNIX (Solaris was an early example), BSD (386BSD which later became FreeBSD, or NeXTSTEP) or Windows NT.</p>
<p>Along the way, the workstation companies consolidated (Apollo and eventually DEC got absorbed into HP; MIPS into SGI) or disappeared altogether (Sun became Oracle Hardware; SGI went bankrupt and sold its assets to sgi; Symbolics did similar—incidentally Symbolics was the first company with a .com domain). IBM long ago stopped even making its own brand PCs, and the news of its split means that there are now very few workstation companies trading in the same form they had “back in the day”. The only ones I can think of that have not had major changes to their corporate structures are Xerox and Sony, whose management may not even have known that they sold workstations.</p>
<p>What’s got lost alongside the death of the workstation is the business model where you sell expensive computers as part of an integrated solution into a particular vertical market, where that expensive solution will cost a lot less than cobbling something together out of cheap PCs. Why? I think people have a lower expectation and higher pain threshold when using computers now; they expect an amount of friction based on their own experience and translate that expectation into realms where it doesn’t belong. As I described way back in issue 2, <a href="https://deprogrammaticaipsum.com/the-various-meanings-of-quality/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">computing is a lemon market</a>.</p>
<p>Organisations would go to the workstation vendors because they solved particular problems very well. If you’re in AI, you need Symbolics. Computer graphics, SGI. Telecoms, that’d be Sun. If you want to write software in Ada for the military-industrial complex, you’ll be buying a Rational workstation. Yes, the first IDE was a completely integrated package of hardware and software. And, of course, Apple for Desktop Publishing, the Mac being a workstation of sorts itself. People would buy computers <em>because</em> applications like AutoCAD, Quark or Mathematica ran well on them. They wouldn’t buy the computer then browse the App Store to see whether it could do anything useful.</p>
<p>And the strange thing is that catering to those vertical markets with integrated solutions is easier than ever now. The wide availability of free software means that the basic job of “being a desktop computer” is taken care of at zero cost, so business can focus on contributing valuable bespoke behaviour. And hardware costs are lower than ever: the availability of high-capability SoCs and single-board computers like the Raspberry Pi and Rock64 should make it a no-brainer to sell the computers as accessories for the applications, not the other way around.</p>
<p>In high-tech domains, an engineer could readily have a toolchest of suitable computers in the same way that a mechanic has different tools for their tasks. This one has an FPGA connected by both PCI-E and JTAG to allow for quick hardware prototyping. This one is connected to a high-throughput GPU for visualisations; that one to a high-capacity GPU for scientific simulations.</p>
<p>The general purpose hardware vendors want us to believe that an okay-at-anything computer is the best for everything: you don’t need a truck, so here’s a car. But when you’re hauling a ton of goods, you’ll find it cheaper and more satisfying to shell out more for a truck. Okay-at-anything is good for nothing.</p>
<p>Cover photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@serejahh">Serhii Butenko</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/zx2Vc1zPDIs">Unsplash</a>.</p>
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://deprogrammaticaipsum.com/the-untimely-demise-of-workstations/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24977652</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 08:34:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Nassim Taleb vs. Nate Silver: who is right about election forecasting?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 70 | Comments 101 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24976175">thread link</a>) | @probe
<br/>
November 2, 2020 | http://quant.am/statistics/2020/10/11/taleb-silver-feud/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://quant.am/statistics/2020/10/11/taleb-silver-feud/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			
<p>Perhaps lost in the whirlwind of presidential name-calling, a lesser-known multi-year old feud has resurfaced on Twitter this election season. Nate Silver is the founder of <a href="https://fivethirtyeight.com/">FiveThirtyEight</a> and is a popular statistician frequently called upon by media members to give commentary and expertise on election forecasting. Nassim Taleb is a statistician/quant turned philosopher, perhaps most well known for authoring the book “The Black Swan”. He is second most well known for calling people names on Twitter. In this 2018 instance he seemed to take issue with FiveThirtyEight’s election forecasts, saying that <a href="https://twitter.com/nntaleb/status/1059202026184282113">“klueless Nate Silver” “doesn’t know how math works”</a>, among a host of other insults. Silver responded that Taleb was an <a href="https://twitter.com/NateSilver538/status/1062782704159256576">“intellectual-yet-idiot”</a>, an phrase coined by Taleb himself. Ouch. A litany of statisticans, mathematicians, and data scientists came out of the woodwork to take sides. Taleb himself <a href="https://twitter.com/nntaleb/status/1314902682570764288">doubled down</a> on Oct. 10, 2020, again calling Silver “totally clueless”.</p>

<p>In this article I take a look behind the mathematical premises of Taleb’s arguments, and give intuitive explanations of why or why not they hold up. In short, while Taleb’s math is sound, he still manages to miss the mark by ignoring the nuance of Silver’s forecasts.</p>

<p>Taleb’s main gripe is that forecasters change their opinion too much over time. Take a look at FiveThirtyEight’s forecast from the 2016 presidential election, where the probability of Clinton winning peaked at 90%, and hit a low of 50%. 
<img src="http://quant.am/assets/2016election.png" alt="2016 election"></p>

<p>Taleb insists that Clinton never should’ve received a probability of winning of 90%. Even if polls were heavily in favor of Clinton at the time, he says Silver should’ve taken into account the uncertainty that polls would change over the next few months leading up to the election, or the possibility of major news breaking. If Silver had factored in the “unknown unknowns” his forecast should’ve been closer to 50%. In essence, this single number should reflect all <em>current and future uncertainty</em>. Taleb constructs this argument by way of quantitative finance, which perhaps led to him and traditional statisticians talking past each other. In the following sections I step through his argument in intuitive terms.</p>


<p>A well known truth to economists, quants, and traders: if I tell you a number, I must be willing to transact at that number. If I tell you the fair value of this house is $500,000, I must be willing to buy AND sell at that price. Otherwise, the number I gave you is meaningless. Likewise, if I tell you the probability of Biden winning this election is 73%, I must be willing to pay $0.73 to make the following wager: if Biden wins I receive $1, if he loses I receive $0.</p>

<p>This is important because it turns the predicted probabilities into a tradeable financial instrument known as a binary option. If the prediction is 50%, I can buy the option at $0.50. If the prediction moves to 65%, I can now sell the option at $0.65, turning a $0.15 profit.</p>

<p>This brings us to another important principle known as the <em>no-arbitrage condition</em>. If the election predictions are accurate, there should be no way for a trader to make guaranteed money by trading this option. To give an illustrative example, let’s say that we live in an unchanging world where the probability of Candidate A winning is static at 50%. If a pollster does not report a static forecast day after day, he will create an arbitrage opportunity. We will sell when the prediction is above 50%, and buy below. 
<img src="http://quant.am/assets/arbitrage-pollster.jpeg" alt="Arbitrage condition"></p>

<p>OK, so now we’ve established that if an arbitrage condition exists, then the pollster is wrong and should not have made that prediction in the first place. Still, it’s not obvious that there’s an arbitrage condition within Silver’s predictions yet (remember, the trader doesn’t have access to an oracle, and only has the same information available to him as the pollster). There’s two more building blocks that we need in order to establish an arbitrage condition.</p>


<p>To paraphrase Taleb, if I tell you an event has a 0% chance of occurring, I cannot change my mind and tell you tomorrow it now has a 50% chance of occurring. Otherwise I shouldn’t have told you it has a 0% chance in the first place. Probability and confidence are inextricably linked, and the number a pollster predicts should encapsulate both. To go to the other extreme, if the uncertainty is extremely high (and therefore confidence low), <em>it does not matter what the polls today are saying</em>. I should give both candidates a 50% chance of winning, because I am admitting the extremely likely possibility that an external event will happen that will invalidate today’s polls. To put it in technical terms, maximum uncertainty implies maximum entropy, and the maximum entropy distribution on the [0, 1] interval is the uniform distribution, which has a mean at .5. The following figure (from <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1703.06351.pdf">this paper</a>) shows the relationship between probability (x-axis) and volatility (y-axis) under a specific option pricing formulation.
<img src="http://quant.am/assets/confidence-probability.png" alt="Confidence vs volatility"></p>

<p>At this point we are suspecting something doesn’t look right with FiveThirtyEight’s predictions, as they seem to have both high volatility and high probability, which contradict each other. Where is the threshold though? How can we prove that the volatility is too high?</p>


<p>Now we’re going to go a little bit technical and show that a no-arbitrage condition was likely violated. The basic construction is as follows:</p>

<ol>
  <li>In order to satisfy the no-arbitrage condition, all information must be “priced in” into the pollster’s current prediction.</li>
  <li>Therefore, the time series of predictions must be a martingale.</li>
  <li>Martingales cannot show trending or mean-reverting behavior, therefore Silver’s predictions violated the martingale property, and therefore the no-arbitrage condition.</li>
</ol>

<p>The definition of a martingale is a stochastic process \(X_1, X_2, ... X_t\) that satisfies</p><p>

\[E[X_{t+1} | X_1, ... ,X_t] = X_t\]

</p><p>To quote <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Christopher_Wlezien/publication/344419648_Information_incentives_and_goals_in_election_forecasts/links/5f73c994a6fdcc0086484861/Information-incentives-and-goals-in-election-forecasts.pdf">Andrew Gelman</a>,</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>In non-technical terms, the martingale property says that knowledge of the past will be of no use in predicting the future…One implication of this is
that it should be unlikely for forecast probabilities to change too much during the campaign (Taleb, 2017). Big events can still lead to big changes in the forecast: for example, a series of polls with Biden or Trump doing much better than before will translate into an inference that public opinion has shifted in that candidate’s favor. The point of the martingale property is not that this cannot happen, but that the possibility of such shifts should be anticipated in the model, to an amount corresponding to their prior probability. If large opinion shifts are allowed with high probability, then there should be a correspondingly wide uncertainty in the vote share forecast a few months before the election, which in turn will lead to win probabilities closer to 50%.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>In other words, all information is already priced into the current market. If it were not so, a trader could make money by taking advantage of the information that is not priced in already. So last thing we need to check: is it likely that Silver’s predictions have the martingale property? It is not in dispute that the answer is no…it shows clear mean-reversion behavior and can be validated by a statistical test of the martingale hypothesis (for example, a <a href="http://www.planchet.net/EXT/ISFA/1226.nsf/9c8e3fd4d8874d60c1257052003eced6/35822efeb009804cc1257afe006b0063/$FILE/11park.pdf">Kolmogorov-Smirnov test</a>). It seems that Taleb’s math is sound here. So where did he go wrong?</p>


<p>I believe Nate Silver is answering a subtly different question with his election forecasts. Each data point that Silver produces is answering the question: <em>if the election were to happen today</em>, what is the probability of each candidate winning? I argue that this is a valid and useful formulation. To put it slightly differently: if the question is “Who will win the election on Nov. 3?”, which of the following answers is more satisfying?</p>

<ul>
  <li>“If nothing else changes between now and the election, Joe Biden has a 85% chance of winning.” (Silver’s argument)</li>
  <li>“I dunno, anything could happen between now and the election, I give neither candidate chances much more than 50%.” (Taleb’s argument)</li>
</ul>

<p>It is a valid criticism that perhaps Silver is not very clear on explaining what his numbers represent, and therefore the media misreports his predictions. Still, I wager that most people would find the first answer more useful. In this interpretation, the “financial instrument” is a binary option that expires every day. Thefore the time series of Silver’s predictions is not interpretable as a martingale, as it strings together the price of a completely different instrument every day.</p>

<p>It is also a valid criticism that Silver’s predictions prior to Nov. 3 mean absolutely nothing, whereas in the Taleb formulation it has a natural interpretation as the betting odds for each candidate. Silver has explicitly stated that he only judges his models based on his finalized prediction. To that end, his models are extremely well calibrated, i.e., when he says something has a 50% chance of happening it actually does happen 50% of the time.
<img src="http://quant.am/assets/538-calibration.png" alt="538 calibration"></p>

<p>In conclusion, Taleb and Silver should be having a philosophical debate on what pollsters’ numbers actually mean, and stay away from the useless distraction of calling each other names on Twitter.</p>

<h3 id="update-10122020">Update (10/12/2020)</h3>
<p>Andrew Gelman, Aubrey Clayton, Dhruv Madeka and many other statisticians respond and give their thoughts: <a href="https://statmodeling.stat.columbia.edu/2020/10/12/more-on-martingale-property-of-probabilistic-forecasts-and-some-other-issues-with-our-election-model/">https://statmodeling.stat.columbia.edu/2020/10/12/more-on-martingale-property-of-probabilistic-forecasts-and-some-other-issues-with-our-election-model/</a></p>

<h3 id="update-2-1132020">Update 2 (11/3/2020)</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Nassim Taleb responds to this post on <a href="https://twitter.com/nntaleb/status/1323594733797679104">Twitter</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24976175">Hacker News discussion</a></li>
</ul>

		</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://quant.am/statistics/2020/10/11/taleb-silver-feud/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24976175</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 04:04:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[EME, CDM, AES, CENC, and Keys – Building Blocks of DRM]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 78 | Comments 19 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24975487">thread link</a>) | @jayjohn436
<br/>
November 2, 2020 | https://ottverse.com/eme-cenc-cdm-aes-keys-drm-digital-rights-management/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ottverse.com/eme-cenc-cdm-aes-keys-drm-digital-rights-management/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<figure>
<img src="https://i0.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/eme-cdm-cenc-featured-image.png?resize=678%2C381&amp;ssl=1" alt="eme cdm cenc keys" title="eme-cdm-cenc-featured-image" data-src="https://i0.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/eme-cdm-cenc-featured-image.png?resize=678%2C381&amp;ssl=1" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==">
</figure>


<p><strong>Anyone trying to understand DRM (Digital Rights Management) will be confronted with acronyms such as AES, CDM, CENC, EME, etc. This can get very confusing for a newcomer, but understanding them is important to get a good understanding of DRM. In this article, let’s take a gentle tour of the building blocks of DRM:- EME, CDM, AES, CENC, and the use of Keys &amp; Key Servers.</strong></p>








<h2 id="simplified-architecture-of-a-drm-system"><span id="Simplified_Architecture_of_a_DRM_System"></span>Simplified Architecture of a DRM System<span></span></h2>



<p>As we saw&nbsp;<a href="https://ottverse.com/what-is-drm-digital-rights-management/">in the previous article</a>,&nbsp;<strong>DRM is a combination of encryption and business rules to control access and consumption of digital content.</strong></p>



<p>Simply put, DRM is a system that,</p>



<ul><li>provides the tools and infrastructure to enable a content provider to encrypt their content, and</li><li>build an ecosystem around the encrypted content so that the content provider can control who/what can decrypt and consume their content.</li></ul>



<p><a href="https://ottverse.com/what-is-drm-digital-rights-management/">In the previous article of the series</a>, we saw Ram and Shyam sending coded messages to each other. At the same time, Hari maintained the codebooks and decided who got to read/write the notes – remember?</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="156" data-permalink="https://ottverse.com/with-drm/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/with-drm.png?fit=1316%2C878&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1316,878" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="with-drm" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/with-drm.png?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/with-drm.png?fit=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="683" src="https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/with-drm.png?resize=1024%2C683&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" alt="aes-cenc-cdm-eme-keys" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/with-drm.png?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/with-drm.png?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/with-drm.png?resize=768%2C512&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/with-drm.png?resize=1200%2C801&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/with-drm.png?w=1316&amp;ssl=1 1316w" data-lazy-sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-lazy-src="https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/with-drm.png?resize=1024%2C683&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure>



<p>Now, let’s take this simple system and replace it with the technology needed to secure and distribute video. What do we get?</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="138" data-permalink="https://ottverse.com/step-0/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/step-0.png?fit=1396%2C818&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1396,818" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="step-0" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/step-0.png?fit=300%2C176&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/step-0.png?fit=1024%2C600&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="600" src="https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/step-0.png?resize=1024%2C600&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" alt="aes-cenc-cdm-eme-keys" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/step-0.png?resize=1024%2C600&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/step-0.png?resize=300%2C176&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/step-0.png?resize=768%2C450&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/step-0.png?resize=1200%2C703&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/step-0.png?w=1396&amp;ssl=1 1396w" data-lazy-sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-lazy-src="https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/step-0.png?resize=1024%2C600&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure>



<p>Let’s describe what we have here. There is a movie that we want to send to an authenticated user securely.</p>



<p>So,</p>



<ol><li>we ask a DRM company’s server for a codebook to encrypt our video,</li><li>then, we encrypt the video using that codebook</li><li>we send the movie to the user.</li><li>the user then asks the DRM company’s server for the codebook to unlock the video (decrypt it)</li><li>and then he watches the movie!</li></ol>



<p>Fantastic!</p>



<p>Is this all there is to know about DRM for video?</p>



<p>Nope! What we have here is a simple, toy-example of how to transfer movies securely using DRM. It captures the essence of DRM perfectly but wouldn’t work well in the real world.</p>



<p>In the rest of this article, let’s take each piece of this simple system, re-think it, re-design it, and see how it fits within the world of video delivery and DRM, shall we?</p>



<h2 id="step-0-lets-move-to-adaptive-bitrate-streaming"><span id="Step_0_Let%E2%80%99s_Move_to_Adaptive_Bitrate_Streaming"></span>Step 0: Let’s Move to Adaptive Bitrate Streaming<span></span></h2>



<p>Before we talk about the order, let’s modify our example to suit the ABR (<strong>A</strong>daptive&nbsp;<strong>B</strong>it<strong>R</strong>ate) model of video delivery.</p>



<p><strong>ABR Refresher:</strong>&nbsp;in ABR, a movie is encoded into different bitrate-resolution combinations&nbsp;<em>(a.k.a ladder)</em>&nbsp;and then split into&nbsp;<strong>chunks or segments</strong>. Each chunk represents a few seconds of video and it is independently decodable.</p>



<p><strong>“Packaging”</strong>&nbsp;refers to chunking or breaking up a movie into small pieces and describing it in a manifest or playlist document. When the user wants to play the movie, he needs to refer to this manifest.</p>



<p>Depending on the available bandwidth, the player requests a chunk/segment of a particular bitrate&nbsp;<em>(rendition, or rung of the ladder)</em>&nbsp;and a CDN (Content Delivery Network) responds with the requested chunk.</p>



<p>Popular methods of video delivery using ABR are MPEG DASH and HLS. For a deeper understanding, please refer to our articles on&nbsp;<a href="https://ottverse.com/what-is-ott-video-streaming/">OTT</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://ottverse.com/what-is-abr-video-streaming/">ABR</a>&nbsp;video streaming.</p>



<p>Let’s change our block digram to reflect ABR video delivery.</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="139" data-permalink="https://ottverse.com/step-0-with-abr/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/step-0-with-abr.png?fit=1476%2C868&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1476,868" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="step-0-with-abr" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/step-0-with-abr.png?fit=300%2C176&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/step-0-with-abr.png?fit=1024%2C602&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="602" src="https://i0.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/step-0-with-abr.png?resize=1024%2C602&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" alt="aes-cenc-cdm-eme-keys" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i0.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/step-0-with-abr.png?resize=1024%2C602&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/step-0-with-abr.png?resize=300%2C176&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/step-0-with-abr.png?resize=768%2C452&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/step-0-with-abr.png?resize=1200%2C706&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/step-0-with-abr.png?w=1476&amp;ssl=1 1476w" data-lazy-sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-lazy-src="https://i0.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/step-0-with-abr.png?resize=1024%2C602&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure>



<p>The only changes here are the packaging and CDN-based delivery steps. That’s all.</p>



<p>Okay, let’s move on and start with the encryption process.</p>



<h2 id="step-1-video-encryption"><span id="Step_1_Video_Encryption"></span>Step 1: Video Encryption<span></span></h2>



<p>The whole idea of encryption is to ensure that when someone intercepts our data, they should not read it or watch it in the case of video.</p>



<p><strong>Encryption refresher:</strong>&nbsp;–&nbsp;<em>encryption is a technique used to keep data confidential and prevent unauthorized people from reading it. Encryption uses a “key” to convert input data (plaintext) into an alternate form called ciphertext. It is almost impossible to convert the ciphertext back to plaintext without the key.</em></p>



<p><em>However, practically speaking, decryption without the key is possible, and encryption algorithms are designed make reverse-engineering extremely expensive – in terms of time, money, and computing resources needed.</em></p>



<p>One of the most popular encryption techniques is the “Advanced Encryption Standard” or “AES” for short. It is also called Rijndael (after its inventor) and was established by the U.S. National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) in 2001 to encrypt electronic data.</p>



<p>Some important points to remember about AES:-</p>



<ul><li>It’s a&nbsp;<strong>symmetric-key algorithm</strong>: encryption and decryption are performed using the same key.</li><li>It has three variants based on the key-length: 128, 192, and 256 bits. The longer the key, the harder it is to crack.</li><li>Cracking the AES-128 without the key would require a “billion times a billion years” and a super-computer (<a href="https://www.eetimes.com/how-secure-is-aes-against-brute-force-attacks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">source</a>).</li></ul>



<p>If you are interested in going deep into the AES standard, look at the&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Advanced_Encryption_Standard" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AES’s Wikipedia page</a>.&nbsp;<em>I am not an expert in cryptography and won’t be able to do justice to the AES.</em></p>



<p><strong>Note:</strong>&nbsp;Please remember that&nbsp;<strong>encryption is not encoding, and decryption is not decoding in the video space</strong>. For videos, encoding and decoding are words used to refer to compression and decompression, respectively. To learn more about encoding, decoding, and video codecs, please read our articles on&nbsp;<a href="https://ottverse.com/need-for-video-compression/">the need for compression</a>&nbsp;and a&nbsp;<a href="https://ottverse.com/what-is-a-video-codec/">simple introduction to video codecs</a>.</p>



<h3 id="is-aes-128-the-only-encryption-technique"><span id="Is_AES128_The_Only_Encryption_Technique"></span>Is AES-128 The Only Encryption Technique?<span></span></h3>



<p>No, it isn’t, and let’s think about the implication of this for a minute.</p>



<p>If a content provider decides to engage with three different DRM companies, and all three use different encryption techniques, then it means that the content provider needs to encrypt their videos three times, resulting in a waste of storage space and other resources.</p>



<p>That is why the CENC specification came into being – to reduce this encryption-driven fragmentation of the market and to reduce storage requirements.</p>



<p>Let’s learn about this next.</p>



<h3 id="cenc-or-common-encryption"><span id="CENC_or_Common_Encryption"></span>CENC or Common Encryption<span></span></h3>



<p><strong>Actually, before we dive into CENC, let’s step back and take a look at the state of OTT streaming protocols and CMAF in particular.</strong></p>



<p>There are primarily two protocols in use today – MPEG-DASH and HLS.&nbsp;<em>There are others such as MSS (Microsoft Smooth Streaming) and HDS, but, we’ll leave them aside for this discussion.</em></p>



<p>MPEG-DASH uses the&nbsp;<code>mp4</code>&nbsp;container format for its videos and HLS uses the MPEG-TS (<code>ts</code>) container for its files. If a content provider uses both MPEG-DASH and HLS, then they need to store a copy of their videos in both&nbsp;<code>mp4</code>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<code>ts</code>&nbsp;file formats.</p>



<p>Now, let’s add the DRM encryption problem to it. If our three hypothetical DRM providers use three different encryption standards, then a content providers needs to store&nbsp;<code>2 * 3</code>&nbsp;… six copies of each video! What a waste of storage space!!</p>



<p><strong>To combat the first problem posed by video streaming protocols, the&nbsp;<a href="https://mpeg.chiariglione.org/standards/mpeg-a/common-media-application-format" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CMAF</a>&nbsp;specification was created</strong> which said that videos can be stored in the&nbsp;<strong>fragmented mp4</strong>&nbsp;container format (<code>fmp4</code>). With support from both MPEG-DASH and HLS, you can now create only one set of videos, store it in&nbsp;<code>fmp4</code>&nbsp;format, and use a common set of files for both protocols. </p>



<p><strong>Just make sure you create two manifests (sigh!).</strong></p>



<h3><span id="How_About_Unifying_the_Encryption"></span><strong>How About Unifying the Encryption?</strong><span></span></h3>



<p>We still need to store multiple copies of each file if different DRM technologies use different encryption standards, right?</p>



<p>For this purpose, the MPEG developed the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.iso.org/standard/68042.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CENC or Common Encryption specification</a>, specifying that videos can be encrypted using either&nbsp;<code>cenc</code>&nbsp;(AES-128 CTR) or&nbsp;<code>cbcs</code>&nbsp;(AES-128 CBC).&nbsp;<em>CTR stands for Counter; and CBC stands for Cipher Block Chaining.</em></p>



<p>The implication of CENC is that a content provider needs to encrypt his videos only once and any decryption module can decrypt it.&nbsp;<em>Note: Exposing the encryption algorithm is not a problem as long as the keys are strongly protected.</em></p>



<p><strong>Well, CENC might sound like a magic wand for DRM-unification, but it is not.</strong></p>



<p>There are three primary DRM technologies in the market – Apple FairPlay, Google Widevine, and Microsoft PlayReady.</p>



<ul><li>Apple FairPlay supports only AES-CBC&nbsp;<code>cbcs</code>&nbsp;mode.</li><li>HLS supports only AES-CBC&nbsp;<code>cbcs</code>&nbsp;mode (irrespective of CMAF)</li><li>Widevine and PlayReady support both AES-128 CTR&nbsp;<code>cenc</code>&nbsp;or AES-128 CBC&nbsp;<code>cbcs</code>&nbsp;modes.</li><li>MPEG-DASH with CMAF supports both AES-128 CTR&nbsp;<code>cenc</code>&nbsp;or AES-128 CBC&nbsp;<code>cbcs</code>&nbsp;modes.</li><li>MPEG-DASH without CMAF supports only AES-128 CTR&nbsp;<code>cenc</code>&nbsp;mode.</li></ul>



<p>As you can see, the CMAF and CENC specs have lead to confusion and fragmentation in the streaming space. </p>



<p><strong>A possible convergence point is the universal use of CMAF and AES-CBC&nbsp;cbcs&nbsp;mode, but, how will these impact legacy devices that support only CTR or only MPEG-TS?</strong></p>



<p>That’s a discussion for another time.</p>



<h2 id="step-2-key-keyid-and-the-license-server"><span id="Step_2_Key,_KeyID,_and_the_License_Server"></span>Step 2: Key, KeyID, and the License Server<span></span></h2>



<p>By now, we have established that we will be encrypting or videos using AES-128 bit encryption. At this stage, a few questions that come up are –</p>



<ol><li>Where do we get the AES-128 Encryption Keys?</li><li>How do we associate an Encryption Key with a movie?</li><li>Where do we store the Encryption Keys?</li></ol>



<p>Let’s answer them one at a time.</p>



<h3 id="where-do-we-get-the-aes-128-bit-encryption-keys"><span id="Where_do_we_get_the_AES128_bit_encryption_keys"></span>Where do we get the AES-128 bit encryption keys?<span></span></h3>



<p>Any content provider can generate the encryption keys manually using specialized software. Alternatively, several DRM vendors provide the necessary tools and software to generate these keys.</p>



<h3 id="how-do-we-associate-an-encryption-key-with-a-movie"><span id="How_do_we_associate_an_encryption_key_with_a_movie"></span>How do we associate an encryption key with a movie?<span></span></h3>



<p>Let’s understand the “why” first. When you go to a hotel, you ask the receptionist for the keys to a particular room by mentioning the room number – right? You’re providing the association here between a key and a room by telling her the room number.</p>



<p>Similarly, when we encrypt a movie with a particular key, we need to create that association and provide that to the DRM license server&nbsp;<em>(our receptionist, if you will)</em>.</p>



<p>In DRM, a “<strong>KeyID</strong>” provides the association between an encryption key and a movie. It is a&nbsp;<strong>unique</strong>&nbsp;string of characters generated at the time of creating an encryption key for a particular movie.</p>



<p><em>And finally,</em></p>



<h3 id="where-do-we-store-the-encryption-key--its-keyid"><span id="Where_do_we_store_the_Encryption_Key_its_KeyID"></span>Where do we store the Encryption Key &amp; its KeyID?<span></span></h3>



<p><strong>The Encryption Key and the KeyID are stored in a secure server (Key Store) that works alongside a DRM license server</strong>.</p>



<p>When a client needs to play an encrypted movie, it requests the DRM license server for the decryption key by providing that …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://ottverse.com/eme-cenc-cdm-aes-keys-drm-digital-rights-management/">https://ottverse.com/eme-cenc-cdm-aes-keys-drm-digital-rights-management/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ottverse.com/eme-cenc-cdm-aes-keys-drm-digital-rights-management/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24975487</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 01:38:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Leaving OCaml]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 191 | Comments 117 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24974907">thread link</a>) | @rbanffy
<br/>
November 2, 2020 | https://blog.darklang.com/leaving-ocaml/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.darklang.com/leaving-ocaml/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">
    <div>

        <article>

            

            <figure>
                <img srcset="https://blog.darklang.com/content/images/size/w300/2020/11/skeleton-camel.jpg 300w,
                            https://blog.darklang.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/11/skeleton-camel.jpg 600w,
                            https://blog.darklang.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/11/skeleton-camel.jpg 1000w,
                            https://blog.darklang.com/content/images/size/w2000/2020/11/skeleton-camel.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 400px,
                        (max-width: 1170px) 1170px,
                            2000px" src="https://blog.darklang.com/content/images/size/w2000/2020/11/skeleton-camel.jpg" alt="Leaving OCaml">
            </figure>

            <section>
                <div>
                    <p><em>Part of a 3 part series. Followups on <a href="https://blog.darklang.com/new-backend-fsharp/">F#</a>, <a href="https://blog.darklang.com/why-dark-didnt-choose-rust/">Rust</a></em></p><p>I built the first demo of Dark in Python, in about two weeks. A few months later when I started productizing it, I rebuilt it in OCaml. Back in 2017, when I was considering the language and platform to use for Dark, OCaml was extremely compelling:</p><ul><li>it's a high-level language with static types, so easy to make large scale changes as we figure out what the language/product was</li><li>you mostly model data with sum types, which in my mind are the best way to model data</li><li>it's very similar to the language I wanted to build (in particular, we could reuse built-in immutable data structures for Dark's values)</li><li>it had a reputation for being high-performance, which meant that we could write an interpreter for Dark and not have it be terribly slow (vs writing an interpreter in python, which might be too slow)</li></ul><p>Unfortunately, as we've built Dark we've run into significant problems that have made it challenging to build in OCaml.</p><h2 id="lack-of-libraries">Lack of libraries</h2><p>When you bet on an off-mainstream language, one of the things you accept is that many libraries are not going to be available. When there is a small community, often there aren't enough people working in the language to make important libraries. This is especially true if few people are building business applications.</p><p>In OCaml there are many high quality libraries, especially for data structures and data manipulation. The annual<a href="https://opensource.janestreet.com/core/"> Jane Street code dump</a> has been quite useful and very high quality. However, we really felt the lack of several libraries. The most obvious of these is that we had to build a <a href="https://github.com/darklang/dark/blob/main/backend/libexecution/unicode_string.mli">Unicode string library</a> ourselves (built on top of the <a href="https://erratique.ch/software/uuseg">very impressive OCaml Unicode libraries</a> built by <a href="https://erratique.ch/contact.en">Daniel Bünzli</a>), but we needed many more libraries than that.</p><p>The lack of an SDK for Google Cloud has affected us greatly. When you're searching for product-market fit, you do the simplest, easiest thing. If you lack a good SDK for your cloud provider, the simplest, easiest thing is often a terrible architectural choice. We've built our own queue on top of our database rather than using the production-quality cloud queues available on GCP. Similarly, we barely use the Cloud Storage (GCP's version of S3), because we initially put things in the database <a href="https://blog.darklang.com/evolving-darks-tracing-system/">because it was easier</a>. We've built 3 services, 2 <a href="https://github.com/darklang/dark/tree/main/containers/stroller">in</a> <a href="https://github.com/darklang/dark/tree/main/containers/queue-scheduler">Rust</a>, and 1 in <a href="https://github.com/darklang/dark/tree/main/containers/postgres-honeytail">Go</a>, to workaround the challenges we've faced.</p><p>The biggest challenge here is our use of Postgres. Postgres is a great database and we're big fans, but Cloud SQL is not a great hosted database. GCP's position is that Cloud SQL is there to tick a box and we should be using Cloud Spanner. I would love to switch to Cloud Spanner, but we have no driver for it in OCaml. Given the Postgres driver in OCaml is not particularly mature, it's hard to expect that a Cloud Spanner driver would exist, and indeed it doesn't. We've had to contribute to the <a href="https://github.com/mmottl/postgresql-ocaml/commit/81a4ae5240decd8f483a90568257cfbc1558c7ed">OCaml Postgres driver</a>, and some parts of our codebase have been <a href="https://github.com/darklang/dark/blob/main/backend/libbackend/serialize.ml#L226">well and truly mangled</a> when working around features not supported in that driver.</p><p>We've also suffered from a lack of a high-level, production web stack (there are <a href="https://github.com/anmonteiro/ocaml-h2">low-level stacks with good reputations</a> that I've struggled to use, and a <a href="https://github.com/oxidizing/sihl">few</a> <a href="https://github.com/reason-native-web/morph">new</a> ones out there that look good), in particular lacking a user authentication module. We've been using <a href="https://auth0.com/">Auth0</a> to work around this for now, which has more moving pieces than I'd like, and a shockingly high cost (our 7000 users, most of whom never log in, costs us over $500/mo).</p><p>We've worked around other missing vendor SDKs by calling their HTTP endpoints directly and that's been mostly fine. However, for libraries like encryption we don't have that option - we <a href="https://github.com/darklang/dark/pull/1455/files">hacked around a missing encryption library</a>, but decided not to ship it to production until we audited it for security (which was never actually worth the cost).</p><p>At CircleCI, we bet on Clojure. That was also a non-mainstream language, but its ability to call Java SDKs meant we had a mature cloud library, which was essential for building CircleCI. Of course, in OCaml we could call C libraries (and <a href="https://github.com/darklang/dark/pull/1841">even Rust libraries</a>, perhaps), but it doesn't match having native libraries we can call directly.</p><h2 id="learnability">Learnability</h2><p>I'm mostly in the camp that anyone can learn any language, but I saw a team struggle with OCaml, and for good reason. Language tutorials are extremely poor in OCaml compared to other languages; they're mostly lecture notes from academic courses.</p><p>The compiler isn't particularly helpful, certainly compared to Rust or Elm (both of which have been in our stack at one point). Often it gives no information about an error. Syntax errors typically say "Syntax error"; though it will try to give a good error for a mismatched brace, often incorrectly. Type errors can be a real burden to read, even after 3 years of experience with it.</p><p>The docs in OCaml are often challenging to find. The <a href="https://ocaml.janestreet.com/ocaml-core/latest/doc/base/index.html">Jane Street docs</a> have improved significantly in the last few years, but it can be a challenge to even figure out what functions are available in a particular module for most libraries. Compare to the excellent <a href="https://docs.rs/">docs.rs</a> in Rust, which has comprehensive API docs for every package in Rust.</p><p>One of the ways I personally struggled in OCaml is around <code>Lwt</code>. Lwt is (one of!) OCaml's async implementations. I couldn't figure it out several years ago and so just built a single-threaded server. The amount of workarounds and downtime we've suffered from that single decision is immense. A tutorial around building high-performance (or even medium performance!) web servers would be very valuable. </p><p>Tooling is something I read would be good in OCaml. I remember reading there was a debugger that could go back in time! I don't know where that's gone but I've never heard of anyone using it.</p><p>We have struggled to make editor tooling work for us. This is partially because we also use ReasonML and this seems to break things. Unfortunately, this is common in programming, but even more so in small communities: you might be the first person to ever try to use a particular configuration.</p><p>Finally, the disconnect between the various tools is immense. You need to understand Opam, Dune, and Esy, to be able to get something working (you could also do it without Esy and just rely on Opam, but that's much worse). I talked about a bunch of these challenges <a href="https://blog.darklang.com/first-thoughts-on-rust-vs-ocaml/">here</a>.</p><h2 id="language-problems">Language problems</h2><p>Multicore is coming Any Day Now™️, and while this wasn't a huge deal for us, it was annoying. </p><h2 id="minor-annoyances">Minor annoyances</h2><p>One of my biggest annoyances was how often OCaml folks talk about Fancy Type System problems, instead of how to actually build products and applications. In other communities for similar languages (ReasonML, Elm, F#), people talk about building apps and solving their problems. In OCaml, it feels like people spend an awful lot of time discussing Functors. It's not quite at the level that I perceived in the Haskell world, but it pointed out that the people building the core of the ecosystem do not have the same problems that I do (which is building web-y stuff).</p><p>I honestly think OCaml was a great choice at the start. Being able to quickly and safely make large-scale changes to your app is something that staticly-typed functional languages excel at. I'm happy that we made the choice, and in retrospect, it still seems like the best choice of those we had at the time.</p><p>I'm working on building the next version of the backend. We have about 20k lines to be replaced, and they'll be rewritten in a new language while keeping the semantics the same. I plan to leave keep the frontend in ReasonML: it doesn't suffer from the same library problems as it can interface nicely to JS, and it's nearly 50k lines of code so it would be a much bigger undertaking.</p><p>Read <a href="https://blog.darklang.com/new-backend-fsharp/">the followup</a> to see what we picked!</p><hr><p><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em>You can sign up for Dark </em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em><a href="https://darklang.com/signup" rel="noopener nofollow"><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em>here</em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></a><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em>. For more info on Dark, follow our </em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em><a href="https://blog.darklang.com/rss" rel="noopener nofollow"><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em>RSS</em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></a><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em>, follow </em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em><a href="https://twitter.com/darklang" rel="noopener nofollow"><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em>us</em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></a><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em> (or </em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em><a href="https://twitter.com/paulbiggar" rel="noopener nofollow"><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em>me</em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></a><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em>) on Twitter, join our </em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em><a href="https://darklang.com/slack-invite" rel="noopener nofollow"><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em>Slack Community</em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></a><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em>, watch our </em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em><a href="https://github.com/darklang/dark" rel="noopener nofollow"><em><em><em><em><em><em><em><em>GitHub repo</em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></a><em>, or join our <a href="http://darklang.com/mailing-list">mailing list</a><em><em><em><em><em><em><em>.</em></em></em></em></em></em></em></em></p>
                </div>
            </section>



        </article>

    </div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.darklang.com/leaving-ocaml/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24974907</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:03:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[DKIM: Show Your Privates]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 90 | Comments 42 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24972609">thread link</a>) | @ryan-c
<br/>
November 2, 2020 | https://rya.nc/dkim-privates.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rya.nc/dkim-privates.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody"> <p>If you’re like most people, there’s a good chance that it’s been years since you’ve sent an email that wasn’t cryptographically signed. You don’t use PGP, you say? Well, even if <em>you</em> are not signing your email, your provider is almost certainly doing it for you. Plausible deniability has been tossed aside in the name of stopping spam, but it doesn’t have to be.</p> <p><span data-title="DomainKeys Identified Mail"><abbr title="DomainKeys Identified Mail">DKIM</abbr></span>, originally standardized in 2007 by <a href="http://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc4871.html">RFC 4871</a>, now has near universal<a href="#id4" id="id1">[1]</a> adoption. To quote the RFC, the goal behind the protocol is to “permit a signing domain to assert responsibility for a message, thus protecting message signer identity and the integrity of the messages they convey”. It’s one of several technologies used prevent the sender identity information in email from being spoofed<a href="#id5" id="id2">[2]</a>. Anti-spam systems use it to help determine whether to consider the reputation of a domain name when making a processing decision.</p> <p>While <abbr title="DomainKeys Identified Mail">DKIM</abbr> was designed to be useful for spam prevention, the cryptographic signatures it uses have quietly made a property called “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Non-repudiation">non-repudiation</a>” the new normal for email. The term is used in in contract law — for example if someone claims “that’s not my signature”, they could be said to be “repudiating” the authenticity of the document. In the case of email, the impact is that if you have a copy of an email in its original format including full headers (for example, an email spool dump) you can check the signature. The extent to which this is a reliable means of verification varies depending on the circumstances — keys short enough to be cracked used to be common, and in some cases straight-up theft of the private keys is plausible.</p> <p>Meanwhile, secure messaging tools like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Off-the-Record_Messaging">OTR</a> and its successors have taken the approach of explicitly providing “deniable encryption”. The <a href="https://signal.org/blog/simplifying-otr-deniability/#potential-simplifications-and-improvements">state of the art</a> allows a sender, given a recipient’s public key, to craft a fake transcript apparently between the two of them that will pass cryptographic checks. This is generally fine for users of these apps because they know what they said. To the best of my knowledge, there is nowhere this creates a legal “get out of jail free” card. All it really does is ensure the users of these tools aren’t <em>reducing</em> their deniability by using the tool. This is an issue where <abbr title="DomainKeys Identified Mail">DKIM</abbr> really fails its users, and I’m apparently not the only one that feels this way.</p> <blockquote> <p>Apropos of nothing, I really wish Gmail would start publishing its expired DKIM secret keys.</p> <p>—<a href="https://twitter.com/matthew_d_green/status/1323011619069321216">Matthew Green</a></p> </blockquote> <p>A little over three years ago, I started doing exactly that for my domain. Since then, I’ve had a <a href="https://gist.github.com/ryancdotorg/a8f565b9e4f0902eb7b5cd4cdefeea0f">key rotation script</a> running every day, generating a new key and adding the appropriate record (called a “selector”).</p> <div><pre><span></span><code>20170829-<wbr>b29b2444f764c222c3faf5c.<wbr>_domainkey.<wbr>ryanc.<wbr>org.<wbr> 5 <wbr>IN <wbr>TXT <wbr>"<wbr>v=<wbr>DKIM1;<wbr>t=<wbr>s;<wbr>h=<wbr>sha256;<wbr>p=<wbr>MIGfMA0GCSqGSIb3DQEBAQUAA4GNADCBiQKBgQDkOSIRW7R8a3e0J0lZqbBJSpHJYPk043/<wbr>OB3lcT2apKtnu7MLjIRqUAgRyYSVAGC10ID2Qlxmy1Ji3EBRB1qI2IsNKgC2C4qzGxx54ShpVR/<wbr>8yY9Qy1eyNtTF5Y/<wbr>XSoLWoRVO1oly+<wbr>WL+<wbr>4O2TRuyujEwoZcFUwXzuuuqJtzbI17wIDAQAB"<wbr>
</code></pre></div> <p>Each selector remains live for seven days, then is “revoked” by publishing an update blanking the public key portion of the record.</p> <div><pre><span></span><code>20170829-<wbr>b29b2444f764c222c3faf5c.<wbr>_domainkey.<wbr>ryanc.<wbr>org.<wbr> 5 <wbr>IN <wbr>TXT <wbr>"<wbr>v=<wbr>DKIM1;<wbr>t=<wbr>s;<wbr>p=<wbr>"<wbr>
</code></pre></div> <p>Once another three days pass, the minimal set of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSA_(cryptosystem)">RSA</a> parameters needed to recreate the public and private keys are published in the selector’s “notes” field.</p> <div><pre><span></span><code>20170829-<wbr>b29b2444f764c222c3faf5c.<wbr>_domainkey.<wbr>ryanc.<wbr>org.<wbr> 5 <wbr>IN <wbr>TXT <wbr>"<wbr>v=<wbr>DKIM1;<wbr>t=<wbr>s;<wbr>p=<wbr>;<wbr>n=<wbr>e:<wbr>AQAB,<wbr>p:<wbr>6o/<wbr>8upWykC5USot9Q2o5M89EO1qA7J/<wbr>ao/<wbr>FPc2TUJKat+<wbr>z4JXde2HWW/<wbr>8D3LJR4hGwSpgwLMq9drTzdjbzFTkQ=<wbr>=<wbr>,<wbr>q:<wbr>+<wbr>RTTux+<wbr>yMx0LPyXDkAQiEBcOt8xYrr60s1sXO/<wbr>5nQSQSZBlLtRJKHQpz65MnIxlOCB+<wbr>1umqLW8q78hHC3Asxfw=<wbr>=<wbr>"<wbr>
</code></pre></div> <p>The format here is non-standard, as a full RSA private key with all of the redundant data it includes would exceed the 255 character limit for strings stored in DNS<a href="#id6" id="id3">[3]</a>. A small Python script is enough to reconstitute everything, though.</p> <table><thead><tr><th colspan="2"><a href="https://rya.nc/dkim-privates_/attach/dkim-private.py" download="">dkim-private.py</a></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td unselectable="on">1</td><td> <code><span>import</span> <span>gmpy2</span><span>,</span> <span>sys</span><span>,</span> <span>dns.resolver</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">2</td><td> <code><span>from</span> <span>Cryptodome.PublicKey</span> <span>import</span> <span>RSA</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">3</td><td> <code><span>from</span> <span>base64</span> <span>import</span> <span>b64decode</span> <span>as</span> <span>b64d</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">4</td><td> <code></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">5</td><td> <code><span>def</span> <span>decode_dkim_private</span><span>(</span><span>txt</span><span>):</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">6</td><td> <code>    <span>params</span> <span>=</span> <span>dict</span><span>()</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">7</td><td> <code>    <span># Parse the DKIM selector record.</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">8</td><td> <code>    <span>for</span> <span>key</span><span>,</span> <span>_</span><span>,</span> <span>val</span> <span>in</span> <span>map</span><span>(</span><span>lambda</span> <span>x</span><span>:</span> <span>x</span><span>.</span><span>partition</span><span>(</span><span>'='</span><span>),</span> <span>txt</span><span>.</span><span>split</span><span>(</span><span>';'</span><span>)):</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">9</td><td> <code>        <span>if</span> <span>key</span> <span>==</span> <span>'n'</span><span>:</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">10</td><td> <code>            <span>for</span> <span>k</span><span>,</span> <span>v</span> <span>in</span> <span>map</span><span>(</span><span>lambda</span> <span>x</span><span>:</span> <span>x</span><span>.</span><span>split</span><span>(</span><span>':'</span><span>),</span> <span>val</span><span>.</span><span>split</span><span>(</span><span>','</span><span>)):</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">11</td><td> <code>                <span>params</span><span>[</span><span>k</span><span>]</span> <span>=</span> <span>int</span><span>.</span><span>from_bytes</span><span>(</span><span>b64d</span><span>(</span><span>v</span><span>),</span> <span>'big'</span><span>)</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">12</td><td> <code>    <span># Compute rest of RSA keypair parameters (if possible).</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">13</td><td> <code>    <span>if</span> <span>all</span> <span>(</span><span>k</span> <span>in</span> <span>params</span> <span>for</span> <span>k</span> <span>in</span> <span>(</span><span>'e'</span><span>,</span> <span>'p'</span><span>,</span> <span>'q'</span><span>)):</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">14</td><td> <code>        <span>params</span><span>[</span><span>'n'</span><span>]</span> <span>=</span> <span>params</span><span>[</span><span>'p'</span><span>]</span> <span>*</span> <span>params</span><span>[</span><span>'q'</span><span>]</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">15</td><td> <code>        <span>phi</span> <span>=</span> <span>(</span><span>params</span><span>[</span><span>'p'</span><span>]</span> <span>-</span> <span>1</span><span>)</span> <span>*</span> <span>(</span><span>params</span><span>[</span><span>'q'</span><span>]</span> <span>-</span> <span>1</span><span>)</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">16</td><td> <code>        <span>params</span><span>[</span><span>'d'</span><span>]</span> <span>=</span> <span>int</span><span>(</span><span>gmpy2</span><span>.</span><span>invert</span><span>(</span><span>params</span><span>[</span><span>'e'</span><span>],</span> <span>phi</span><span>))</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">17</td><td> <code>        <span>rsa</span> <span>=</span> <span>map</span><span>(</span><span>lambda</span> <span>x</span><span>:</span> <span>params</span><span>[</span><span>x</span><span>],</span> <span>'nedpq'</span><span>)</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">18</td><td> <code>        <span>return</span> <span>RSA</span><span>.</span><span>construct</span><span>(</span><span>tuple</span><span>(</span><span>rsa</span><span>))</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">19</td><td> <code>    <span>else</span><span>:</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">20</td><td> <code>        <span>return</span> <span>None</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">21</td><td> <code></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">22</td><td> <code><span>if</span> <span>__name__</span> <span>==</span> <span>'__main__'</span> <span>and</span> <span>len</span><span>(</span><span>sys</span><span>.</span><span>argv</span><span>)</span> <span>==</span> <span>3</span><span>:</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">23</td><td> <code>    <span>domain</span> <span>=</span> <span>sys</span><span>.</span><span>argv</span><span>[</span><span>1</span><span>]</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">24</td><td> <code>    <span>selector</span> <span>=</span> <span>sys</span><span>.</span><span>argv</span><span>[</span><span>2</span><span>]</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">25</td><td> <code>    <span>for</span> <span>answer</span> <span>in</span> <span>dns</span><span>.</span><span>resolver</span><span>.</span><span>query</span><span>(</span><span>selector</span> <span>+</span> <span>'._domainkey.'</span> <span>+</span> <span>domain</span><span>,</span> <span>'TXT'</span><span>):</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">26</td><td> <code>        <span>txt</span> <span>=</span> <span>str</span><span>(</span><span>answer</span><span>)</span><span>.</span><span>strip</span><span>(</span><span>'"'</span><span>)</span></code> </td></tr><tr><td unselectable="on">27</td><td> <code>        <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>decode_dkim_private</span><span>(</span><span>txt</span><span>)</span><span>.</span><span>exportKey</span><span>()</span><span>.</span><span>decode</span><span>())</span></code> </td></tr></tbody></table><p>An example run:</p> <div><pre><span></span><code><span>$</span> ./dkim-private.py <span>'ryanc.org'</span> <span>'20170829-b29b2444f764c222c3faf5c'</span>
<span>-----BEGIN RSA PRIVATE KEY-----</span>
<span>MIICXQIBAAKBgQDkOSIRW7R8a3e0J0lZqbBJSpHJYPk043/OB3lcT2apKtnu7MLj</span>
<span>IRqUAgRyYSVAGC10ID2Qlxmy1Ji3EBRB1qI2IsNKgC2C4qzGxx54ShpVR/8yY9Qy</span>
<span>1eyNtTF5Y/XSoLWoRVO1oly+WL+4O2TRuyujEwoZcFUwXzuuuqJtzbI17wIDAQAB</span>
<span>AoGBAKClArD7PzExKGJcIQqHIjqEzdfVdbVfyc+JfUiX72h2bE78wzXDUIUMYnrs</span>
<span>nJ7gJeaO5ycG5ST29sQtAkVRwn1KTLaU9fYmGpbkKyOWWfmztppZIvwi9l4tU5h2</span>
<span>GJVw+HbhcWO6tYbTqR9Bc8IelXyVibwmJwImr0AoD8sBLryhAkEA6o/8upWykC5U</span>
<span>Sot9Q2o5M89EO1qA7J/ao/FPc2TUJKat+z4JXde2HWW/8D3LJR4hGwSpgwLMq9dr</span>
<span>TzdjbzFTkQJBAPkU07sfsjMdCz8lw5AEIhAXDrfMWK6+tLNbFzv+Z0EkEmQZS7US</span>
<span>Sh0Kc+uTJyMZTggftbpqi1vKu/IRwtwLMX8CQFT/ABGMlTvxzdGFYkq/fyLrBEqN</span>
<span>rRIRiuTFWIj0DHuLepgEDtjWhcN5T2f6vFYi6NQliFdU+F18ngICjCGKukECQHse</span>
<span>ClIyJpkRQB/kgLfM8zFU1FeRUDx/0z3cRq3G4C7Yr6Z+wmcsNSoJoqbMw8mblnB5</span>
<span>jBAq3dtvaFsM4G53se0CQQC9ocR9eQdXvq5ibwZAmgYcMLEaq7NeX//l6zdxLd52</span>
<span>NcVcuaAUzf5KdTRwA9gJ4Qdzwntc+UB2ElpI2AOj7AFV</span>
<span>-----END RSA PRIVATE KEY-----</span>
</code></pre></div> <p>When I originally set this up, I was a bit concerned that I’d run into issues with filtering systems trying to validate my sent emails significantly after delivery. Per the RFC:</p> <blockquote> A signer should not sign with a private key when the selector containing the corresponding public key is expected to be revoked or removed before the verifier has an opportunity to validate the signature. The signer should anticipate that verifiers may choose to defer validation, perhaps until the message is actually read by the final recipient. In particular, when rotating to a new key pair, signing should immediately commence with the new private key and the old public key should be retained for a reasonable validation interval before being removed from the key server.</blockquote> <p>In the process of writing this up, I went through the 24 months of query logs I have. With very few exceptions (most of which were probably my own testing) there were no lookups against selectors other than on the day they were being used, so this doesn’t seem to be a problem in practice.</p> <p>I alluded to it earlier, but I want to be clear — publishing <abbr title="DomainKeys Identified Mail">DKIM</abbr> private keys like this mainly addresses leaks as a threat model. In a legal dispute, mail server logs and/or stored mail can be subpoenaed if the authenticity of messages is in question. Even in my case, where I have my own mail server on dedicated hardware with full disk encryption at an undisclosed location, most mail I send will be delivered to a server operated by a third party with no incentive to alter logs at the behest of the recipient.</p> <p>It would make for a fascinating experiment for one of the privacy focused email providers to try deploying a key management strategy similar to the one I’ve described in this post.</p> <table id="id4"> <colgroup><col><col></colgroup> <tbody> <tr><td><a href="#id1">[1]</a></td><td>I can’t find any recent public data on this, but Google reported that 87.6% of non-spam emails received by Gmail users had valid DKIM signatures as of Febuary 2016. <a href="https://security.googleblog.com/2013/12/internet-wide-efforts-to-fight-email.html">https://security.googleblog.com/2013/12/internet-wide-efforts-to-fight-email.html</a></td></tr> </tbody> </table> <table id="id5"> <colgroup><col><col></colgroup> <tbody> <tr><td><a href="#id2">[2]</a></td><td>The core protocol behind email, <span data-title="Simple Mail Transfer Protocol"><abbr title="Simple Mail Transfer Protocol">SMTP</abbr></span> was designed in the early eighties, and one of the terms it uses is “envelope sender”. This is apt because it originally was not much harder to fake than the return address on a physical envelope.</td></tr> </tbody> </table> <table id="id6"> <colgroup><col><col></colgroup> <tbody> <tr><td><a href="#id3">[3]</a></td><td>The DNS standards provide for storing values longer than 255 characters in a TXT record by simply storing multiple strings in the record, but such records can be annoying to work with in some software.</td></tr> </tbody> </table> </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rya.nc/dkim-privates.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24972609</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 20:10:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[My Thoughts on Monorepo]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 37 | Comments 17 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24971288">thread link</a>) | @shekhargulati
<br/>
November 2, 2020 | https://shekhargulati.com/2020/11/02/my-thoughts-on-monorepo/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://shekhargulati.com/2020/11/02/my-thoughts-on-monorepo/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-6395">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	
	
	<div>
		
<p>Before we start let me give some context on my background so that you can better understand my thoughts on Monorepo.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I head technology at an IT services organization. Most of the products that I build are using Microservices architecture, have multiple frontends(web and mobile). The biggest product that I recently built had close to 30 microservices, 1 web client written in React,&nbsp; and native mobile app built using React Native. These numbers are nowhere near the numbers big product companies have shared.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote><p>I prefer Macroservices over Microservices. I think most products don’t need more than 10 microservices.&nbsp;</p></blockquote>



<p>The reason I am clearly specifying I belong to the IT services world is because most of the stuff we consume on software development is written by engineers and senior tech people at the product companies. The stuff they write and share is based on the real problems and challenges they face at work. There are times when those problems resonate with problems other software engineers face at their work but there are times they are solutions to the problems we don’t have. So, we have to look at these solutions from the lens of our problems.</p>



<blockquote><p>The post is based on my experience building software, leading and managing software delivery teams, and learning from the great articles written by engineers using Monorepos. Please refer to the references section for good resources on monorepos.</p></blockquote>



<p>Let’s get back to the topic at hand.</p>



<h2>So, what is a Monorepo?</h2>



<p>A monorepo is a software development strategy where a single version control repository has source code for multiple projects, libraries, and applications irrespective of their programming language. Also, the organizations using Monorepo strategy often use a common build tool (like Bazel, Pants, Buck) to manage all the source code. Some of the popular examples of organizations that employ monorepo strategy are Google, Facebook, Twitter, Microsoft, and Uber.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The alternative to monorepo is polyrepo/multirepo. In multirepo, you have a separate version control repository for each component. This is the common strategy used by most organizations to structure their code. This in my view has been largely driven by Microservices architecture style and small modules movement.</p>



<p>As mentioned in the paper[1] (Advantages and Disadvantages of a Monolithic Repository – A case study at Google), Monorepos have following properties:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Centralization</strong>: The codebase is contained in a single repo encompassing multiple projects.</li><li><strong>Visibility</strong>: Code is viewable and searchable by all engineers in the organization.</li><li><strong>Synchronization</strong>: The development process is trunk-based; engineers commit to the head of the repo.</li><li><strong>Completeness</strong>: Any project in the repo can be built only from dependencies also checked into the repo. Dependencies are unversioned; projects must use whatever version of their dependency is at the repo head.</li><li><strong>Standardization</strong>: A shared set of tooling governs how engineers interact with the code, including building, testing, browsing, and reviewing code.</li></ul>



<p>My understanding is that to successfully use monorepo you will have to satisfy all the properties. Otherwise, you will not get benefits intended from monorepo.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>Advantages of Monorepos</h2>



<p>There are valid reasons why many big product organizations prefer Monorepo. Following are the main reasons:</p>



<h3>Reason 1: Simplified dependency management</h3>



<p>Monorepos make dependency management simple by:</p>



<ol><li>You can easily depend on other projects/modules in a monorepo without the need for artifact management tools like Nexus, Artifactory etc.</li><li>You avoid diamond dependency problem. Diamond dependences occur when a project has two dependencies which depend on the same underlying library. When a developer upgrades a dependency, they run the risk of breaking a diamond in the dependency graph.</li><li>It is easier to keep all dependencies on the same version by using a centralized way to manage version numbers.</li></ol>



<p>This is simplified further by using a single build tool. I have not used Bazel, Bucks, or Pants. I was watching a talk on Twitter monorepo journey where they talked about Gradle being too slow for their use case. For the size of applications I have built Gradle has worked just fine.</p>



<h3>Reason 2: Code sharing and reusability</h3>



<p>The second big benefit of Monorepo is that developers can share code across projects. It is easier to enforce best practices across the code base by using monorepo. Another related point is that with monorepo we don’t end up creating silos. This is important in an enterprise setup because it leads to passing the buck and bugs falling through the cracks of the boundaries. In my experience with multirepo setup people only care about their Microservice running fine. They miss the point that value is achieved by integrating the software and collaboration. In IT service organizations where there is more bureaucracy and uneven distribution of skilled developers the problem scales very quickly with multirepo setup. Yes, I know it is a culture problem but most IT service organizations can’t burn investor dollars to build the culture.</p>



<h3>Reason 3: Atomic changes</h3>



<p>This I didn’t realize before I read literature on Monorepo. There is a lot of benefit in seeing related changes in a single commit. If you are working on a story that requires changes in multiple components then in a multirepo scenario you will have to see changes in multiple repositories and merge the PRs in some sequence so that you are in a healthy state. WIth monorepo you save the pain of trying to coordinate commits across multiple repositories. Also, this leads to better code reviews as all the changes are in one place.</p>



<h3>Reason 4: Large-scale code refactoring</h3>



<p>This is related to reason 3. With a monorepo, you can refactor the API and all of its callers in one commit. You see all the usages of an API at a single place and it is much easier to do than with multirepo where you might not even have all the code checked out. In my experience with multirepo setup most developers don’t keep all the repos updated with the upstream changes. Monorepos enables continuous improvement on global level that multirepo you do at local level.</p>



<h3>Reason 5: Less bureaucracy</h3>



<p>With some organizations I have worked at, you have to create ServiceNow tickets to create a repository. It can take a couple of days before you get your empty repository. With monorepo you don’t have to go through this pain.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>Disadvantages of Monorepo</h2>



<p>Nothing comes for free. There are always trade offs involved. Your job as a software engineer is to figure out if advantages weigh more than trade offs or not.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In my view following are the downsides of monorepo:</p>



<ol><li>Monorepos could slow down developers because of slow build times, poor tooling, and merge conflicts.&nbsp;<ol><li>Most developers still in 2020 struggle to cleanly merge code.&nbsp;</li><li>Git is slow for projects with large numbers of files and history.</li></ol></li><li>There is cognitive overhead involved as developers have to get comfortable with a much larger code base than they would have with multirepo setup.</li><li>To do monorepo well require investment in tooling that most organization non-tech leadership will fail to understand</li></ol>



<h2>So, what’s my view on monorepos?</h2>



<p>Before I talk about my views on Monorepo let’s understand three main constraints of IT services organization.&nbsp;</p>



<ol><li>We work with multiple customers so we can’t keep code of all customers in the same repository even when we host their code in our version control for obvious reasons. Also, we can’t give access to all our repositories to all our developers because of security and IP related issues. So, we will keep our discussion focused on how to manage repos for a single customer.</li><li>IT services organizations have a high ratio of junior(&lt; 5 years) to senior engineers(&gt; 10 years) somewhere in the range of 10:1 to 100:1 or may be higher in bigger IT service organizations. The reason I am bringing this point is that monorepos requires discipline and it is tough to achieve without senior engineers driving it using a well-defined process.</li><li>People come and go at a faster rate.</li></ol>



<p>Given the above two constraints and the disadvantages of monorepos it might seem that monorepos will not work for us. But, I see real problems faced by software delivery teams that can be solved by monorepos.</p>



<p>We build products for different customers. These products usually follow Microservice architecture, have multiple frontends – web and mobile, functional tests, scripts for deployment automation. In the multirepo strategy, you will create at minimum 5 repositories – 1 for backend with all microservices, 1 for SPA frontend, 1 or 2 repo for mobile depending on whether you are building pure native or using some native framework like React Native or Flutter, 1 for functional tests, 1 for deployment automation scripts.&nbsp; More often than not your team will use one repo per Microservice then only god knows how many repos you end up creating.</p>



<blockquote><p>Let me tell you a real story. I was once working with a client that had more than 1000 repositories in their version control system. They were using the Gitlab version control platform. They had 5 products and each product was made up of multiple Microservices. The first question I asked them was to help us understand which all services and their respective code repositories were part of product A. Their chief architect had to spent a day figuring out all the repositories that made the product A. After spend a day still she was not sure if she has covered all the services.</p></blockquote>



<p>Let’s discuss problems that I face with software delivery teams using the multirepo strategy. Just to reiterate these problems are in the context of a single customer.</p>



<ol><li>Lack of accountability: Humans are good at creating boundaries and silos. They don’t care what happens outside those boundaries. They don’t care about the bigger picture.</li><li>Version drift. 10 different versions of Spring Boot, three different JDK versions, …</li></ol></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://shekhargulati.com/2020/11/02/my-thoughts-on-monorepo/">https://shekhargulati.com/2020/11/02/my-thoughts-on-monorepo/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://shekhargulati.com/2020/11/02/my-thoughts-on-monorepo/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24971288</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 18:24:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Cellular immunity to SARS-CoV2 found at 6 months in non-hospitalised individuals]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 177 | Comments 132 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24968034">thread link</a>) | @ageitgey
<br/>
November 2, 2020 | https://www.uk-cic.org/news/cellular-immunity-sars-cov-2-found-six-months-non-hospitalised-individuals | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.uk-cic.org/news/cellular-immunity-sars-cov-2-found-six-months-non-hospitalised-individuals">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><img alt="UK-CIC logo" data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="8a702f0f-0ed4-43c4-b10a-d98dba34a018" src="https://www.uk-cic.org/sites/default/files/inline-images/UK-CIC%20logo%20square%20300pix.jpg">Cellular (T cell) immunity against SARS-CoV-2 is likely to be present within most adults six months after primary infection, a new pre-print on bioRxiv suggests. The research from the UK Coronavirus Immunology Consortium (UK-CIC), Public Health England and Manchester University NHS Foundation Trust&nbsp;demonstrates robust T cell responses to SARS-CoV-2 virus peptides at this timepoint in all participants following asymptomatic or mild/moderate COVID-19 infection.</p>

<p>A key question is whether previous infection with SARS-CoV-2 results in immunity to reinfection, and if so for how long. The immune system is extremely complex and there are many different potential routes whereby it can generate immunity to a disease post-infection. This study examines the role of T cells in contributing to immunity against SARS-CoV-2 at six months post infection.</p>

<p>As part of UK-CIC, researchers from the University of Birmingham, Public Health England, Manchester University NHS Foundation Trust (MFT) and&nbsp;NIHR Manchester Clinical Research Facility collected serum and blood samples from a cohort of more than 2,000 clinical and non-clinical healthcare workers including 100 individuals who tested sero-positive for SARS-CoV-2 in March/April 2020 (average age 41 (range 22–65); 23 men, 77 women). All 100 individuals experienced either mild/moderate symptoms or were asymptomatic (56 versus 44 people) and none were hospitalised for COVID-19. Serum samples were collected monthly to measure antibody levels, and blood samples were taken after six months to assess the cellular (T cell) response. A range of analyses were carried out to assess different aspects of the T cell response including the magnitude of response and the response to different proteins from SARS-CoV-2. Carrying out these cellular analyses is much more complex than antibody studies – but this study of 100 individuals is one of the largest in the world to date in this field.</p>

<p>T cell responses were present in all individuals at six months after SARS-CoV-2 infection. The cellular immune response was directed against a range of proteins from the virus, including the Spike protein that is being used in most vaccine studies. However, comparable immunity was present against additional proteins, such as nucleoprotein, which suggests that these may be of value for incorporation in future vaccine protocols. This indicates that a robust cellular memory against the virus persists for at least six months.</p>

<p>The size of T cell response differed between individuals, being considerably (50%) higher in people who had experienced symptomatic disease at the time of infection six months previously. Further research will be needed to determine the significance of this finding. It is possible that heightened cellular immunity might provide increased protection against re-infection in people with initial symptomatic infection, or that asymptomatic individuals are simply able to fight off the virus without the need to generate a large immune response.</p>

<p>Antibodies are also a crucial component of immune defence and cellular immunity was strongly correlated with the peak level of the antibody response. Furthermore, larger cellular responses appeared to protect against antibody ‘waning’ over time, again suggesting the need to ensure that cellular immune responses are elicited in vaccine regimens.</p>

<p>Overall, these findings indicate a robust cellular (T cell) immune response against SARS-CoV-2 at six months post-infection. These findings will feed not only into our understanding of how immunity to SARS-CoV-2 works but also help inform future vaccine strategies. Further research is now needed to assess whether this immune response is maintained over the longer term and to better understand how strength of cellular immune response corresponds to likelihood of reinfection.</p>



<p><b>Professor Paul Moss, UK Coronavirus Immunology Consortium lead from University of Birmingham, said:</b></p>

<blockquote>
<p>“Understanding what constitutes effective immunity to SARS-CoV-2 is extremely important, both to allow us to understand how susceptible individuals are to reinfection and to help us develop more effective COVID-19 vaccines.</p>

<p>“To our knowledge, our study is the first in the world to show robust cellular immunity remains at six months after infection in individuals who experienced either mild/moderate or asymptomatic COVID-19. Interestingly, we found that cellular immunity is stronger at this time point in those people who had symptomatic infection compared with asymptomatic cases. We now need more research to find out if symptomatic individuals are better protected against reinfection in the future.</p>

<p>“Our knowledge of SARS-CoV-2 infection is increasing all the time. While our findings cause us to be cautiously optimistic about the strength and length of immunity generated after SARS-CoV-2 infection, this is just one piece of the puzzle. There is still a lot for us learn before we have a full understanding of how immunity to COVID-19 works. While we increase our understanding, whether we think we have previously had COVID-19 or not, we all should still follow Government guidelines on social distancing to ensure we play our part in minimising the spread of COVID-19 within our communities.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p><b>Dr Shamez Ladhani, Consultant epidemiologist at Public Health England and the study’s author, said:</b></p>

<blockquote>
<p>“Cellular immunity is a complex but potentially very significant piece of the COVID-19 puzzle, and it’s important that more research be done in this area. However, early results show that T-cell responses may outlast the initial antibody response, which could have a significant impact on COVID vaccine development and immunity research.</p>

<p>“Our thanks go to the more than 2,000 staff who have volunteered to provide monthly blood samples since the beginning of the pandemic. Recruiting donors so early in 2020 allowed us significantly longer follow-up than many similar studies have achieved so far.”</p>


</blockquote>

<p><b>Professor Fiona Watt, Executive Chair of the Medical Research Council, part of UKRI, said: </b></p>

<blockquote>
<p>“This study shows the benefit of funding world-leading immunologists through the UK Coronavirus Immunology Consortium. Researchers investigated whether previous infection with SARS-CoV-2 results in immunity to reinfection. They found that a robust cellular memory against the virus persists for at least six months. This is promising news – if natural infection with the virus can elicit a robust T cell response then this may mean that a vaccine could do the same.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p><strong>Dr Shazaad Ahmad, Consultant Virologist at Manchester University NHS Foundation Trust (MFT) and Principal Investigator for the study at MFT, said:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<blockquote>
<p>“As one of the leading NHS trusts for research and innovation, known for our strong track record of recruiting to studies, we were selected to rapidly enlist a cohort of healthcare workers to take part in this important research – and 1,200 MFT staff swiftly answered the call.</p>

<p>“The study was delivered at the NIHR Manchester Clinical Research Facilities at Manchester Royal Infirmary and Wythenshawe Hospital (both part of MFT), which provide dedicated research space and highly-trained staff. I would like to say how grateful I am to my colleagues for continuing to deliver and participate in this study, as without them we would not be able to report the findings, which could have a huge global impact."<br>
&nbsp;</p>


</blockquote>

<p>Please note, this paper is a pre-print reporting preliminary data that has not yet been peer-reviewed.</p>

<p>----------Ends----------</p>

<p><u><strong>Notes for editors</strong></u><br>
This press release reports on findings in the following pre-print which is <a href="http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2020.11.01.362319">available to read on bioRxiv</a>:<br>
Zuo <em>et al. </em>2020 Robust SARS-CoV-2-specific T-cell immunity is maintained at 6 months following primary infection<br>
Journalists - please contact the press team for a copy of the preprint, or use the link above to find it directly.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The UK Coronavirus Immunology Consortium brings together UK 19 immunology centres of excellence to research how the immune system interacts with SARS-CoV-2 to help us improve patient care and develop better diagnostics, treatments and vaccines against COVID-19. It is jointly funded by UK Research and Innovation (UKRI) and National Institute for Health Research (NIHR) and supported by the British Society for Immunology.<br>
Website: <a href="https://www.uk-cic.org/news/www.uk-cic.org">www.uk-cic.org</a>&nbsp;<br>
Twitter: <a href="https://www.uk-cic.org/news/www.twitter.com/UKCICstudy">@UKCICstudy</a><br>
Email: <a href="mailto:uk-cic@immunology.org">uk-cic@immunology.org</a></p>

<p><strong>Press contacts</strong><br>
Gabriela De Sousa<br>
Email: <a href="mailto:g.desousa@immunology.org%C2%A0">g.desousa@immunology.org&nbsp;</a><br>
Jennie Evans<br>
Tel: 07703 807 444<br>
Email: <a href="mailto:j.evans@immunology.org">j.evans@immunology.org</a></p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.uk-cic.org/news/cellular-immunity-sars-cov-2-found-six-months-non-hospitalised-individuals</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24968034</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 13:45:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Is a billion dollars worth of server lying on the ground?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 315 | Comments 307 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24966028">thread link</a>) | @george3d6
<br/>
November 2, 2020 | https://cerebralab.com/Is_a_billion-dollar_worth_of_server_lying_on_the_ground | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://cerebralab.com/Is_a_billion-dollar_worth_of_server_lying_on_the_ground">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">
        <p>Published on: 2020-11-02</p>
        
<p><em>Note: Some details of the stories in this article are slightly altered to protect the privacy of the companies I worked for</em></p>
<p>It's somewhat anecdotal, but in my work, I often encounter projects that seem to use highly inefficient infrastructure providers, from a cost perspective.</p>
<p>I usually point out that, based on a fairly unbiased hardware comparison, that they could save over half their budget by migrating, and am usually met with a series of almost canned answer about migrations being too difficult due to x,y,z.</p>
<h2>I - A representative comparison</h2>
<p>I will pick one of the "expensive" and one of the "cheap" server providers, chosen simply based on the fact that I've worked with them a lot, and compare two of their high~ish end servers.</p>
<p>I'm going to take 1 example from a cheap server provider OVH and a somewhat worst machine from AWS.</p>
<p>OVH offers <a href="https://us.ovh.com/us/order/dedicated/#/dedicated/configure-hg?product=~(dc~(gra~1)~planCode~%271901bhg~option~(~(planCode~%27cpu-2x6132-dual-2018v1~family~%27cpu~quantity~1)~(planCode~%27ram-768g-2666-dual-2018v1~family~%27ram~quantity~1)~(planCode~%27disk-960ssd-sata-2019~family~%27disk~quantity~8)))">this machine</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li>2x Intel Xeon Scalable Gold 6132 - 28c/56t - 2.6/3.7 GHz</li>
<li>768GB RAM DDR4 ECC 2666MHz</li>
<li>960GB SATA SSD</li>
<li>3 Gb/s internal and 1 Gb/s external free bandwidth</li>
</ul>
<p>For $15,800/year (though it can be paid monthly)</p>
<p>For a close comparison, AWS offers their <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/pricing/on-demand/">4.16xlarge</a>. I'll try to figure out the exact hardware specs on <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/memory-optimized-instances.html">this description</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>R4 instances feature up to 64 vCPUs and are powered by two AWS-customized Intel XEON processors based on E5-2686v4 that feature high-memory bandwidth and larger L3 caches to boost the performance of in-memory applications.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So basically let's call it 2x E5-2686v4, though the "real" E5-2686v4 seems to have more cores (both real and virtual) than the AWS version, I'll give AWS the benefit of the doubt and say that their version is more or less the same. I'll also assume AWS's RAM is the same 2666MHz DDR4 EEC2 (basically the best you can get right now) though they don't specify this, but I'll be generous here.</p>
<p>So we have:</p>
<ul>
<li>2x Intel Xeon E5-2686v4 - 36c/72t - 2.3/3.0 GHz</li>
<li>488GB RAM DDR4 ECC 2666MHz</li>
<li>Storage paid for separately</li>
<li>Bandwith paid for separately</li>
</ul>
<p>For $37,282/year (paid hourly) or $25,771/year (paid upfront)</p>
<p>The OVH server has more memory, it comes with 1TB of very fast storage, and adding more storage is much cheaper than AWS EBS prices (+ you get the option for NVME SSDs connected via PCIe on all servers).</p>
<p>I chose two processors which are <em>fairly</em> similar but running a comparison is still hard. Unlike e.g. RAM, processors are much more synergistic, you can't just look at parameters like nr cores, cache size, and frequency to figure out how well they perform.</p>
<p>Still, these two seem to be pretty close on those parameters and when looking at <a href="https://www.cpubenchmark.net/compare/Intel-Xeon-E5-2686-v4-vs-Intel-Xeon-Gold-6132/2870vs3227">the benchmarks</a>. It seems that the Gold 6132 is marginally better than the E5-2684-v4. Granted, benchmarking server CPUs is hard, but still, I think it's fair to say that the former has at least a tiny advantage, even if somehow the E5-2684 performs worst of benchmarks than on "real tasks".</p>
<p>So we have 2 servers:</p>
<ul>
<li>Both are in Paris</li>
<li>One has 768GB of RAM the other 488GB (58% of the first one) with the same specs</li>
<li>One has an extremely to slightly better CPU (let's say 10% better, a bit bellow the ~17% claimed by the benchmarks)</li>
<li>One has free bandwidth, the other one charges you for every single Kb of communication with the outside world (though at a fairly small sum)</li>
<li>One comes with 1TB of very fast NVME storage, for the other one you have to pay extra</li>
<li>One is paid monthly, the other one yearly or hourly.</li>
</ul>
<p>If the first server, the one that is better in literally every way, costs ~16k/year... how much should the other one cost? Well, maybe 10, maybe 12, maybe 14?</p>
<p>I don't know, but the answer certainly shouldn't be "Almost twice as much at 26k/year", that's the kind of answer that indicates something is broken.</p>
<p>In a worst-case scenario, AWS is ~1.6x times as expensive, but again, that's paid yearly. If we compare paid monthly to paid hourly (not exactly fair) we get 37k vs 16k, if we do some <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/ebs/pricing/">napkin math calculations</a> for equivalent storage cost (with equivalent speed via guaranteed iops) we easily get to ~3k/year extra. We have a 40k vs 16k difference, the AWS machine with the worst specs is 250% more expensive.</p>
<p>But whether the worst AWS machine is 160% or 250% as expensive as the OVH one is not the relevant question here, the question is why are we seeing those astronomical differences in terms of cost to being with.</p>
<p>We should consider there are hosting providers cheaper than OVH (e.g. scaleway, potentially online.net, and other such providers you never heard of). On the flip side of the coin, there are server providers such as digital oceans, GC, and Azure that can be more expensive than AWS.</p>
<p>Why?</p>
<h2>II - Vendor lock-in hypothesis</h2>
<p>The easiest thing to do here is to cry vendor lock-in.</p>
<p>The story goes that you end up using firebase for authentication, then you hire a sysadmin / DevOps guy that knows GC to create your infrastructure there. Then you make use of some fancy google ML service that integrates seamlessly with the GC storage... so on and so forth, until it would cost you a lot more manpower to move away from GC than to pay them a bit extra for whatever compute or storage you could get for less elsewhere.</p>
<hr>
<p>This is compounded by the fact that most of the time startups are oblivious to the cost of these services.</p>
<p>I switched my personal "infrastructure" from AWS since it ended up costing me over $100/month to maintain. Nowadays I pay $23/month and get a lot more leeway out of my current setup. But I haven't done that with some startups I've worked with or advised, even though the cost savings could have one or two additional zeros added to them. Why?</p>
<p>I can often call the shots regarding hardware at the startups I've worked with, yet I usually can't argue against using AWS or GC... because often enough, the first hit is free. AWS, GC, and Azure are throwing out 10k$ worth of credits like candy, and topping that off with 50-200k$ worth of credit for startups that they think have potential. The catch here is that the credits expire in 1 year, and once that year is done many are probably locked into the vendor.</p>
<p>The startup model is one of exponential growth, most fail and the winners have dozens or hundreds of millions from investments. So what is one or two hundred thousand a year on an IaaS bill?</p>
<p>Well, the answer is almost nothing. I believe the standard AWS offering for free credits is something like 100k$/year. So assuming a startup that uses that for a year gets 10mil in investment, it costs them 1% of their budget a year to maintain that.</p>
<p>The problem is that investment reflects future potential worth, a startup receiving a 10 mil investment is probably operating at a small fraction of the capacity those investors hope it will reach. For the shares to be worth 5x time that original investment, the company might have to scale its operations 20x or 50x, or 100x.</p>
<p>This becomes a problem since you can't run on investment forever, and scaling up 20x suddenly turns that 100k into 2 million a year spent on servers.</p>
<p>Of course, this is just a hypothetical, the numbers here are stand-ins to make a point, not a case-study. From my own experience, that the lock-in funnel looks something like:</p>
<ol>
<li>Free credits, let's use {expensive infrastructure provider}.</li>
<li>Loads of investment money, let's not waste time switching away from {expensive infrastructure provider}, it's &lt; 1% of our yearly budget.</li>
<li>Turns out that once the company grew, {expensive infrastructure provider} now consists of a double-digit percentage of our yearly expenditure, but it's too late to switch now.</li>
</ol>
<hr>
<p>This situation is exacerbated by consolidation (big fish buys little fish). I vividly remember a situation where I found an optimal hardware+software combination for a data processing platform, I think a conservative estimate would be that it was ~5 times cheaper than the vendor lock-in alternative being used at the time.</p>
<p>This happened to make it worth the switch since the startup lacked a generous credit offer for Google cloud. But, as soon as it was "consolidated", I was forced to switch the whole system back to Google cloud, granted a much better GC setup, but one that still involved costs ~2-3x times greater than the original solution.</p>
<p>Why? Well, boils down to the parent company using Google cloud, all their employees knowing how to work with GC, all their contracts having weird security-related clauses composed by many lawyers based on "official security audits" ran on their GC infrastructure, and so on.</p>
<p>However, this leads nicely into my second hypothesis.</p>
<h2>III - Employee lock-in hypothesis</h2>
<p>Employees end up deciding most of what a company is using internally, including infrastructure providers.</p>
<p>People aggregate <a href="https://slatestarcodex.com/2014/09/30/i-can-tolerate-anything-except-the-outgroup/">along weird lines</a>, to the extent that it wouldn't surprise me if a CTO hired initial engineers that favored his preferred infrastructure provider, even if he didn't actively seek that trait out.</p>
<p>Once the first few employees are fans of a given infrastructure provider, it starts making it into the job specs, because onboarding someone familiar with AWS when you use Azure is a huge pain in the ass. All other things being equal you'd rather have someone familiar with the technology you are already using.</p>
<p>This is compounded by the kind of employees that permeate a given field. If you are developing mobile apps or web apps, for example, it's likely that many engineers you will find will be familiar with Heroku and Digital Oceans. If you are developing whatever the heck people use C# for, I'd bet you'll find people that know how to use Azure. If you are doing machine learning, most people will know a thing or two about google cloud's offers regarding TPUs.</p>
<p>More broadly, this leaves no room for people that want to have a "multi-cloud" infrastructure or use a very little known platform. Either you get engineers that are very versed in the subject, but that will cost extra. Or you consign to having a few experts on the subject handle everything, with the rest of the team having no idea how to boot up a new VM without calling someone up.</p>
<p>Of …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://cerebralab.com/Is_a_billion-dollar_worth_of_server_lying_on_the_ground">https://cerebralab.com/Is_a_billion-dollar_worth_of_server_lying_on_the_ground</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://cerebralab.com/Is_a_billion-dollar_worth_of_server_lying_on_the_ground</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24966028</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 09:09:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Build a Collaborative Chatbot with Google Sheets and TensorFlow]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 93 | Comments 14 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24966013">thread link</a>) | @jonathanbgn
<br/>
November 2, 2020 | https://jonathanbgn.com/nlp/2020/09/29/chatbot-universal-sentence-encoder.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jonathanbgn.com/nlp/2020/09/29/chatbot-universal-sentence-encoder.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p><img src="https://jonathanbgn.com/assets/images/taipei.jpg" alt="Taipei"></p>

<p>Currently living in Taiwan, I recently joined the <a href="https://github.com/taiwangoldcard/taiwan-bot">Taiwan Bot 🤖</a> project along with <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/shawn-lim-0a307550">Shawn</a> and <a href="https://erickhun.com/about/">Eric</a>. The idea is to build a go-to assistant to help foreigners answer their questions about moving to, working, and living in Taiwan (pro-tip: ask the bot where to find cheese or chocolate).</p>

<p>Building a functional and useful chatbot is a non-trivial project. Fortunately, there has been impressive progress in the fields of machine learning and <strong>natural language processing (NLP)</strong> in the past few years. Moreover, the democratization and open-source sharing of cutting-edge deep learning models from research work at large tech companies like Google or Facebook is making it possible for anyone to implement the latest state-of-the-art solutions.</p>

<p>The <a href="https://ai.googleblog.com/2018/05/advances-in-semantic-textual-similarity.html">Universal Sentence Encoder</a>, recently released by Google AI, is one of these new models available via <a href="https://tfhub.dev/google/universal-sentence-encoder/4">Tensorflow Hub</a>. Trained in a <strong>multi-tasking</strong> fashion, the model can encode sentences into meaningful continuous representations that work well on a range of different tasks. It is thus ideal for <strong>transfer learning</strong> and performs competitively with more complex models like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BERT_(language_model)">BERT</a>. Moreover, it can run much faster than BERT or other similar <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transformer_(machine_learning_model)">Transformer</a> models and is thus more applicable to real-world problems. There is even a <a href="https://tfhub.dev/google/universal-sentence-encoder-lite/2">Lite version</a> of the model, small enough to run in Javascript on the client-side.</p>

<h2 id="the-project">The project</h2>

<p>Despite being an amazing place to live, <strong>Taiwan is still misunderstood by most foreigners</strong>. We think that a fun and approachable chatbot could help people understand a lot more about all the great things this place has to offer, as well as answer most of the questions they might have about living here.</p>

<p>We decided to start with a limited scope first and to focus on answering practical questions about moving to and living in Taiwan. Specifically, we chose to focus on visa issues and the recently created <a href="https://taiwangoldcard.com/">Gold Card program</a>. We plan to expand the bot capabilities in future versions.</p>

<p>When it comes to chatbots, there are a lot of ways to go, and many tools and libraries out there to help you make your plan a reality. However, being just a small team of 3 doing this in our spare time, we didn’t have enough resources and time to build something very sophisticated. We also didn’t want to spend a lot of time to compile a large training dataset. So we looked for the best way to build a system that would be:</p>

<ul>
  <li>🧩 Easy and quick to build</li>
  <li>⚡️ Lightweight and runnable on a small server</li>
  <li>🔧 Iterable and easy to improve</li>
  <li>🧠 Focused on finding relevant answers</li>
</ul>

<p>We chose to build our bot with Microsoft’s <a href="https://github.com/microsoft/botframework-sdk">Bot Framework SDK</a> for easy development, user management and to be able to easily publish it to multiple platforms like Messenger or Line, the most popular messaging platform in Taiwan. <strong>The only thing remaining was to build the brain behind the messages.</strong></p>

<h2 id="understanding-the-meaning-behind-a-question">Understanding the meaning behind a question</h2>

<p>The main challenge when building a bot is <strong>relevancy</strong>, and this starts by having a clear understanding of what the user’s intention is. There are many approaches possible to make sense of what the user wants. At the most simple, one could simply look for some keywords such as <code>hello</code>, <code>restaurant</code>, or <code>visa</code>. However, this doesn’t take at all into account all the nuances of the language.</p>

<p>We didn’t have the resources to build a full-scale bot that could recognize the user intention among thousands of possibilities, yet we wanted to create something that could be relevant enough so that people would find it useful. So we needed to find an ideal middle ground between complexity and performance.</p>

<p>One of the most important concepts in NLP is one of <strong>distributed representations</strong>, inspired by the linguistic field of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Distributional_semantics">distributional semantics</a>. The core idea is to encode linguistic items (words, sentences) into <strong>embeddings</strong> (vectors in a large dimensional space) such that items with similar properties should be closer in the resulting space.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>You shall know a word by the company it keeps.</p>

  <p><em>- John Rupert Firth (1957)</em></p>
</blockquote>

<p>For example, similar words will cluster together in the vector space:</p>

<p><img src="https://jonathanbgn.com/assets/images/word-embeddings.png" alt="Word Embeddings"></p>

<p><em>Image from <a href="https://blog.tensorflow.org/2020/08/introducing-semantic-reactor-explore-nlp-sheets.html">TensorFlow Blog</a></em></p>

<p>You could do the same as the above but with sentences, effectively encoding them into large vectors which can be compared between themselves using <strong>similarity functions</strong>. Hence sentences with similar vector representations are sentences with similar meaning, topic, syntax…</p>

<h2 id="encoding-questions-with-the-universal-sentence-encoder">Encoding questions with the Universal Sentence Encoder</h2>

<p>The <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1803.11175">Universal Sentence Encoder</a> is a powerful Transformer model (in its large version) allowing to extract <a href="https://developers.google.com/machine-learning/crash-course/embeddings/video-lecture">embeddings</a> directly from sentences instead of from individual words. It already powers some impressive Google projects such as <a href="https://books.google.com/talktobooks/">Talk to Books</a> or <a href="https://google.github.io/mysteryofthreebots/">Mystery of the Three Bots</a>.</p>

<p>For our chatbot project, we are first using the model to encode all the questions that we think users would want to ask to the bot. This can be done in a few lines of code thanks to the convenient TensorFlow Hub library:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>import</span> <span>tensorflow</span> <span>as</span> <span>tf</span>
<span>import</span> <span>tensorflow_hub</span> <span>as</span> <span>tfhub</span>

<span>model</span> <span>=</span> <span>tfhub</span><span>.</span><span>load</span><span>(</span><span>"https://tfhub.dev/google/universal-sentence-encoder/4"</span><span>)</span>

<span>questions</span> <span>=</span> <span>[</span> <span>...</span> <span>]</span>  <span># questions most likely to be asked to the bot
</span><span>answers</span> <span>=</span> <span>[</span> <span>....</span> <span>]</span>  <span># all answers to the questions above
</span>
<span>batch_size</span> <span>=</span> <span>10</span>
<span>embeddings</span> <span>=</span> <span>[]</span>
<span>for</span> <span>i</span> <span>in</span> <span>range</span><span>(</span><span>0</span><span>,</span> <span>len</span><span>(</span><span>questions</span><span>),</span> <span>batch_size</span><span>):</span>
    <span>embeddings</span><span>.</span><span>append</span><span>(</span><span>model</span><span>(</span><span>questions</span><span>[</span><span>i</span><span>:</span><span>i</span><span>+</span><span>batch_size</span><span>]))</span>
<span>questions_embeddings</span> <span>=</span> <span>tf</span><span>.</span><span>concat</span><span>(</span><span>embeddings</span><span>,</span> <span>axis</span><span>=</span><span>0</span><span>)</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Then whenever a user asks a question, we can just extract its embedding and find the most similar question in our database of embeddings. In our case we use a simple vector dot product as a similary function:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>def</span> <span>find_best_answer</span><span>(</span><span>question</span><span>:</span> <span>str</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>str</span><span>:</span>
    <span>embedding</span> <span>=</span> <span>model</span><span>([</span><span>question</span><span>,])</span>
    <span># compute dot product with each question:
</span>    <span>scores</span> <span>=</span> <span>questions_embeddings</span> <span>@</span> <span>tf</span><span>.</span><span>transpose</span><span>(</span><span>embedding</span><span>)</span>

    <span>return</span> <span>answers</span><span>[</span><span>np</span><span>.</span><span>argmax</span><span>(</span><span>tf</span><span>.</span><span>squeeze</span><span>(</span><span>scores</span><span>).</span><span>numpy</span><span>())]</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="google-sheets-as-a-collaborative-database">Google Sheets as a collaborative database</h2>

<p>We built our dataset using a simple Google spreadsheet with 2 columns: questions and answers. Whenever a user asks a question, we just find the most relevant question and return the appropriate answer.</p>

<p><img src="https://jonathanbgn.com/assets/images/taiwan-bot-database.png" alt="Questions Answers Dataset"></p>

<p>This approach, while relatively simple, is a flexible enough for efficiently working together. Querying the data is done once during startup with a few lines of code:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>client</span> <span>=</span> <span>gspread</span><span>.</span><span>authorize</span><span>(</span>
    <span>ServiceAccountCredentials</span><span>.</span><span>from_json_keyfile_dict</span><span>(</span><span>SERVICE_ACCOUNT_INFO_DICT</span><span>,</span>
        <span>[</span><span>'https://spreadsheets.google.com/feeds'</span><span>,</span><span>'https://www.googleapis.com/auth/drive'</span><span>])</span>
<span>)</span>
<span>sheet</span> <span>=</span> <span>client</span><span>.</span><span>open</span><span>(</span><span>SPREADSHEET_FAQ_FILE</span><span>).</span><span>worksheet</span><span>(</span><span>SPREADSHEET_SHEET_NAME</span><span>)</span>
<span>questions</span> <span>=</span> <span>list</span><span>(</span><span>map</span><span>(</span><span>str</span><span>.</span><span>strip</span><span>,</span> <span>sheet</span><span>.</span><span>col_values</span><span>(</span><span>1</span><span>)[</span><span>1</span><span>:]))</span>
<span>answers</span> <span>=</span> <span>list</span><span>(</span><span>map</span><span>(</span><span>str</span><span>.</span><span>strip</span><span>,</span> <span>sheet</span><span>.</span><span>col_values</span><span>(</span><span>2</span><span>)[</span><span>1</span><span>:]))</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Here is an example of a conversation with the bot:</p>

<p><img src="https://jonathanbgn.com/assets/images/taiwan-bot-conversation.jpg" alt="Conversation with the bot"></p>

<h2 id="continuous-improvement">Continuous improvement</h2>

<p>We did our best to think about what would be the most commonly asked questions but, of course, we cannot predict everything people will ask. This is why if you ask a question that is not present in our database, the bot can answer with something completely unrelated. To prevent this, we built a small logging system to be able to track the questions asked to the bot and which question it thought was the most similar (along with the similarity score).</p>

<p>For example, here is what happened behind the scenes during the small conversation above. The first column is the user message. The second column is the most similar question (as based on the embeddings similarity). The third column is the best answer and the last column the computed similarity score. If the similarity score is not good enough, the bot will answer with a generic reply <em>” Sorry, I cannot help with that yet “</em>.</p>

<p><img src="https://jonathanbgn.com/assets/images/taiwan-bot-logs.png" alt="Conversation Logs"></p>

<p>This logging system will also help us improve our answers as more people use the bot and new edge cases are found. Still, no chatbot is perfect, and we think the bot will be most useful in a context where humans can take over when the bot fails. For example, on Slack, we added the bot to a general FAQ channel where people can get assistance from both the bot and humans for more specific information.</p>

<p><img src="https://jonathanbgn.com/assets/images/taiwan-bot-slack.png" alt="Chatbot on Slack"></p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>Building an effective chatbot doesn’t have to be a complex project. As long as the scope is relatively narrow, it is possible to use a general encoder model like the Universal Sentence Encoder to build something useful. The hard part is collecting enough questions/answers for the bot to be able to answer most questions. It is also important to regularly monitor what users are asking and complement new data whenever the bot can’t find a relevant answer.</p>

<p>If you are also living or considering to move to Taiwan, you can <a href="https://m.me/thetaiwanbot">chat with Taiwan bot on Messenger here</a>!</p>

<h3 id="read-next">Read next</h3>

<p><a href="https://jonathanbgn.com/nlp/2020/08/30/gpt2-gpt3-creativity.html">Unleash GPT-2 (and GPT-3) Creativity through Decoding Strategies</a></p>

<p><a href="https://jonathanbgn.com/speech/2020/10/31/emotion-recognition-transfer-learning-wav2vec.html">Detecting Emotions from Voice with Very Few Training Data</a></p>

  </div>
  
  
</article>

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jonathanbgn.com/nlp/2020/09/29/chatbot-universal-sentence-encoder.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24966013</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 09:05:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[You might not need to store plaintext email addresses]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 242 | Comments 155 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24965671">thread link</a>) | @danielskogly
<br/>
November 2, 2020 | https://blog.klungo.no/2020/11/01/you-might-not-need-to-store-plaintext-emails/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.klungo.no/2020/11/01/you-might-not-need-to-store-plaintext-emails/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Earlier this year, when I went from having only Facebook-login on <a href="https://wishy.gift/">Wishy.gift</a> to allow registrations with email address and password, one of my concerns was how to implement this is a way that protects the data and privacy of my users. I don’t have any ads or analytics on the site, the users can select whatever display name they want, and I never stored the email addresses I got from Facebook when a user registered or logged in - only a hashed<sup><a href="#fn1" id="fnref1">[1]</a></sup> version of the ID. Email addresses and passwords, on the other hand, are a whole other beast, and the consequences of a database breach much worse.</p>
<p>Considering that the only kind of emails I ever need to send out are transactional - no newsletters or other kinds of notifications - the only thing I need to store them for are as identifiers, and can safely be hashed.</p>
<p>For every transactional email I need to send out - registration, account recovery, and email change verification - the user always initiates this by submitting their email address, and it will at that time be available to the backend to perform the needed action.</p>
<p>In conclusion, if you only use email addresses for transactional emails, you might be able to only store hashed versions of them. For <a href="https://wishy.gift/">Wishy.gift</a> I use SHA512 with a fixed salt, and this has been working perfectly since implementation in June.</p>
<p>Thank you for reading this! I would love to hear your thoughts and ideas too. Join the discussion on <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24959734">Hacker News</a>, or feel free to email me at <code>daniel</code> at the domain this blog is on.</p>
<hr>
<section>
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>I discovered that, even though the ID was unique to my FB-app, it was still possible to go to <a href="http://facebook.com/%7Bid%7D">facebook.com/{id}</a> and be redirected to the user’s FB-profile. <a href="#fnref1">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.klungo.no/2020/11/01/you-might-not-need-to-store-plaintext-emails/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24965671</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 08:11:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[As an older guy I've finally figured out weight-loss]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 47 | Comments 112 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24965631">thread link</a>) | @RikNieu
<br/>
November 2, 2020 | https://www.riknieu.com/the-best-way-to-lose-weight/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.riknieu.com/the-best-way-to-lose-weight/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
				<p>This post isn't really product or development related, but I think it applies to lots of us desk-job types. Hopefully it'll help someone else who's struggling just as much as I was.</p><h2 id="first-my-results-and-progress-so-far">First my results and progress so far</h2><p>I started getting serious about my diet at the end of September 2020. I weighed about 80kg/176lbs. </p><p>Today, on 1 Nov 2020, I weighed about 74kg/163lbs. </p><figure><img src="https://www.riknieu.com/content/images/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-01-at-17.09.12.png"><figcaption>My weight-loss chart 20 Sept - 1 Nov</figcaption></figure><p>That's a loss of 6kg/13lbs in a bit over a month! Insane! I would never have dreamt it possible for a middle-aged guy like me, who doesn't exercise too much and sits behind a computer all day to pull something like that off.</p><p>My journey is far from complete, but the progress I've had up to now is exciting enough to share. This would likely(hopefully) be the first in a series of posts detailing my weight-loss journey.</p><h2 id="the-backstory">The backstory</h2><p>I've never had a flat stomach in my entire life. Not when I was a kid, not when I was a young adult, and certainly not now, in my almost middle-age.</p><p>And I'm not even talking about having that shredded, six-pack look like the guys on the MensHealth covers, I'm just talking about a regular, flat tummy that doesn't bulge out in vague convex shape. I've always hovered between almost obese to dad-bod at best.</p><p>I've been self-conscious about my weight since forever. Being the fat kid in the 80s, when most kids weren't overweight yet left it's mark on my psyche and self-esteem. I got noticed and bullied for it, often. It also didn't help that my skin was pale enough to trip the sun when I took my shirt off on the beach.</p><p>All jokes aside, being able to swim in public without a shirt on has just never been in the realms of conceivability for me. The shame is too great.</p><p>Society, my community and my peers have made it very clear, since a young age, that nobody wants to see that shit. In fact, I don't think I've been in any form of public water without a shirt on since the age of 10. Maybe even earlier.</p><h2 id="when-the-dough-starts-to-rise">When the dough starts to rise</h2><p>I've learned to live with it, of course. The pale skin, the belly - it's not that bad. I mean, I've still managed to convince a poor, unsuspecting soul to be my wife. I still had fun outdoors. And getting older means nobody really cares about my appearance anymore, at least not to my face. Being doughy is not ideal but it's not that big a deal either.</p><p>I always assumed it's just the genetic cards I've been dealt, my unique biology or some sort of weird hormonal thing. This made sense to me because most of my extended family are overweight, and dangerously so. Maybe we're just built to look like this.</p><p>This idea might have a sliver of truth to it - I personally know people who look fit and fabulous without any seeming effort and who can eat whatever they like. </p><p>I, however, seem to gain weight by just looking at delicious food. But if I'm honest, declaring it impossible to slim down due to my genes might have just been a convenient excuse. </p><p>On my 38th birthday this year, I reflected on this, and the fact that my 40s were rapidly coming into view. I can see it emerging just over the horizon, arms and legs pumping as it's sprinting towards me. Soon.</p><p>I wasn't concerned with becoming unattractive with age(I've never been considered attractive anyway) but using my family history as a rough model for extrapolation suggested that the physical shape I was in then was past the point of good-as-it-would-ever-be. Other thoughts circled around, about getting older, about my losing my health, mobility and vitality. </p><p>And the signs were certainly there. My weight and pant size had already started creeping up over the last couple of years. </p><p>I wasn't obviously overweight, don't get me wrong. Most people would have considered my weight quite normal, perhaps even slim when compared to most of society. </p><p>But the trend in measurements suggested that my future would involve an ever-increasing waistline, with the eventual addition of tent-like shirts, feebly trying to conceal the obvious. </p><p>Yep, the coming years would see me getting rounder, wrinklier and unhealthier. Not paler though, that wouldn't be possible. This bun could never be baked, my genes won't allow for it.</p><h2 id="middle-age-is-looming-let-s-set-a-crazy-goal-">Middle-age is looming - let's set a crazy goal!</h2><p>To my credit though, I did realise that being middle-aged didn't mean it's game over yet. Perhaps I could still steer this ship around, if I just put my mind to it.</p><p>I won't ever become that tasty, handsome dish that turns heads, but perhaps I could aim for a relatively healthy, strong, utilitarian body? Like Sean Connery(RIP) in those first James Bond films. Old-school fit.</p><p>And with that musing, on the eve of my biological new year, I made the resolution to give it one last, genuine shot. </p><p>I would do my best to attempt a solid, last-ditch effort in getting my stomach flat. My goal is cultivating an appearance that I won't necessarily want to show off, but that I'd at least not feel the need to cover up and hide.</p><p>The idea is too sport, by the end of this year or early the next, a completely flat stomach without having to suck it in. And I would endeavour to keep it that way, perpetually, for the foreseeable future.</p><p>This will be hard, and I know it. I've been down this road before. Though I was comfortable plump my whole life, I am no stranger to diets and exercise. I know them well.</p><h2 id="the-revolving-door-of-fad-diets">The revolving door of fad diets </h2><p>In fact, I've tried almost every diet you can think of - keto, vegetarian, calorie counting, Fit-For-Life, caveman, paleo diet, slow carb... you name it, I probably tried it. And I've had various levels of success, but none left me with consistent, long-lasting results. Never mind washboard abs.</p><p>At best I'd maybe lose a couple of kilos, hit the inevitable plateau, and then give up out of frustration and resentment. Or I'd start feeling feeble and sick, suffer from weak concentration, or just feel generally miserable.</p><p>There was also the issue of inevitable birthdays and celebrations interfering, where I didn't want to be a party-pooper, or deny myself life's simple pleasures either, but which then would usually result in me falling off the bus. </p><p>And the cheat days too. Not often, maybe once or twice on weekends. Those, I told myself, would be needed to keep myself sane and motivated, to keep the cravings at bay. But they were a trap. Cheat day's may not add more weight, but they certainly stop any progress dead in its tracks.</p><p>Then there's exercise. Although my foray into the myriad of options available were not as extensive as with diets(due to some personal health limitations), my results - or lack thereof - were similar.</p><p>I tried to do some form of exercise at least 3 times a week. These included rollerblading with the wife, bodyweight routines, weight lifting, martial arts, walks and even the infernal torture that is running. </p><p>Exercise seemed to have <em>some</em> effect on sharpening my curves, but had no measurable effect on the scale.</p><p>Safe to say, it was pretty daunting to decide to commit to yet another version of this whole rigmarole again. When you feel you've tried everything before, you're skeptical this time would be different. Which diet would I be following this time, which training schedule?</p><p>I could feel that "it's just genetics" excuse looming just behind my shoulder, smugly waiting to tell me, "I told you so. It's pointless."</p><p>But this is what I wanted to do, so I decided to break it down and approach it from first principles, or at the very least keep it dead simple.</p><h2 id="best-way-of-losing-weight-science-simplicity-patience-and-discipline">Best way of losing weight? Science, simplicity, patience and discipline</h2><p>First principles suggested I stop faffing around with diets that operate on clever narratives, assumptions and "magic" rules, and just look at what the science said. And the science was pretty consistent - calories matter above all else. </p><p>The majority of studies suggested that for most people, the amount of calories consumed determines your weight. Hormonal factors exist, but they're either negligible or applicable to a very, very, VERY small part of the population. You're likely not it.</p><p>Exercise does help, but in the modern world with its convenient packaged foods one can easily consume way more calories in a single day than you could realistically burn off in a week of exercising. And if you're not cognisant of the calories in your meals and snacks, you won't even know it when you're over-consuming.</p><p>Now, of course I've tried calorie counting before, and it worked alright, but still lead to the inevitable plateau and quit cycle. This was something I'd need to be mindful of. I'd need to be strict to the max.</p><p>I decided that this time I was going to be <em>extremely</em> disciplined and committed. The only bending of rules would be cheat meals(not days) on birthdays or other rare and special occasions. Not weekly, like I weaselled about with before. No other cheating would be tolerated at all.</p><p>And for exercise it would be just as simple. I would do weight training 3x a week, ala <a href="https://startingstrength.com/">Starting Strength</a>, because it's the only form of exercise I actually enjoy doing. That's it. Beyond that would just be whatever recreational activities we did with friends over weekends.</p><h3 id="calories-energy-in-energy-out">Calories - energy in, energy out</h3><p>I'm not going to give you a lecture on calories and the intricacies behind their workings in this post, you can look it up yourself. </p><p>The <em>only</em> thing you need to know to successfully lose weight is that you need to consume less calories than your body requires to maintain its current weight. That's it. And, of course, you need to muster the discipline or come up with hacks to stick to it.</p><p>"Not all calories are equal!", I hear some of you seethe, and yes, I've considered that too. I took it into account for this experiment as well. It will be addressed below.</p><h2 id="weight-loss-plan">Weight-loss plan</h2><h4 id="5-steps-calculate-adjust-simplify-measure-patience">5 Steps - calculate, adjust, simplify, measure, patience</h4><p><strong>Calculate</strong> - Google and find a free calorie calculator online, enter your particular details, and calculate the amount of daily calories you need to maintain your current weight. </p><p><strong>Adjust</strong> - To lose weight you need to reduce the amount of daily calories you consume. Take the …</p></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.riknieu.com/the-best-way-to-lose-weight/">https://www.riknieu.com/the-best-way-to-lose-weight/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.riknieu.com/the-best-way-to-lose-weight/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24965631</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 08:02:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Rendering photo-realistic glass in the browser]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 375 | Comments 105 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24965005">thread link</a>) | @anonytrary
<br/>
November 1, 2020 | https://domenicobrz.github.io/webgl/projects/SSRefractionDepthPeeling/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://domenicobrz.github.io/webgl/projects/SSRefractionDepthPeeling/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://domenicobrz.github.io/webgl/projects/SSRefractionDepthPeeling/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24965005</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 05:13:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why Leaders Need to Learn the Skill of Writing]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 118 | Comments 29 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24964730">thread link</a>) | @mooreds
<br/>
November 1, 2020 | https://fromthegreennotebook.com/2020/10/03/why-leaders-need-to-learn-the-skill-of-writing/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://fromthegreennotebook.com/2020/10/03/why-leaders-need-to-learn-the-skill-of-writing/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">

	<section id="primary">
		<main id="main" role="main">

		
			<article id="post-6068">
	
	
		

	<div>
		<p><img data-attachment-id="6071" data-permalink="https://fromthegreennotebook.com/2020/10/03/why-leaders-need-to-learn-the-skill-of-writing/shutterstock_55915930-e1415052560114-2/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/fromthegreennotebook.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/shutterstock_55915930-e1415052560114-2.jpg?fit=3862%2C1974&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="3862,1974" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="shutterstock_55915930-e1415052560114-2" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/fromthegreennotebook.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/shutterstock_55915930-e1415052560114-2.jpg?fit=300%2C153&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/fromthegreennotebook.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/shutterstock_55915930-e1415052560114-2.jpg?fit=723%2C369&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/fromthegreennotebook.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/shutterstock_55915930-e1415052560114-2.jpg?resize=715%2C365&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="715" height="365" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/fromthegreennotebook.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/shutterstock_55915930-e1415052560114-2.jpg?w=3862&amp;ssl=1 3862w, https://i0.wp.com/fromthegreennotebook.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/shutterstock_55915930-e1415052560114-2.jpg?resize=300%2C153&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/fromthegreennotebook.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/shutterstock_55915930-e1415052560114-2.jpg?resize=1024%2C523&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/fromthegreennotebook.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/shutterstock_55915930-e1415052560114-2.jpg?resize=768%2C393&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/fromthegreennotebook.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/shutterstock_55915930-e1415052560114-2.jpg?resize=1536%2C785&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/fromthegreennotebook.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/shutterstock_55915930-e1415052560114-2.jpg?resize=2048%2C1047&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/fromthegreennotebook.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/shutterstock_55915930-e1415052560114-2.jpg?w=1446&amp;ssl=1 1446w, https://i0.wp.com/fromthegreennotebook.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/shutterstock_55915930-e1415052560114-2.jpg?w=2169&amp;ssl=1 2169w" sizes="(max-width: 715px) 100vw, 715px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p>By Joe Byerly<span data-ez-name="fromthegreennotebook_com-box-3"></span></p>
<p>Anyone who has worked directly for a battalion commander or above probably has experience writing “ghost notes.” These are emails a subordinate writes and addresses for their boss to send to other people. Ghost notes can be weekly or monthly sitreps, updates on an ongoing situation or emails asking for additional resources. No matter the type, they are the “easy button” for the commander because all they have to do is hit “send.”</p>
<p>Recently, I worked for a senior Army leader who encouraged his subordinate commanders to own their communications—meaning, write their own emails. As I reflected on his guidance, I realized there are benefits to communications ownership. I witnessed many of these benefits firsthand as I watched him communicate with senior military leaders, senior civilian leaders and his own commanders.<span data-ez-name="fromthegreennotebook_com-medrectangle-3"></span></p>

<p><strong>Greatness and Writing</strong></p>
<p>One of the best ways to work through a problem is to write it down. Throughout history, leaders who found themselves in tough situations sat alone with their thoughts and worked through them using pen and paper.<span data-ez-name="fromthegreennotebook_com-medrectangle-4"></span></p>
<p>Marcus Aurelius, who served as Roman emperor for almost two decades, wrote his <em>Meditations</em> to work through daily leadership challenges, wars and a pandemic. In the week leading up to the D-Day landings, Gen. Dwight Eisenhower wrote himself letters to help work through risks, opportunities and necessities of operations.</p>
<p>Both Marcus and Eisenhower used writing to achieve clarity of thought. This point is underscored by author Stephen King, who has said writing is “refined thinking.” In our minds, our thoughts are clear, but real clarity doesn’t come until those thoughts are solidified in writing. The process of framing an email, capturing important points and discarding nonessential elements helps us gain more clarity.</p>
<p><strong>Sound Authentic</strong></p>
<p>Over the years, I have worked under multiple commanders while in staff positions, and the best ones never let me draft their intent for operations orders. They wanted to own those. At the time, I didn’t understand it—thinking it was one more staff drill I could handle for them. But as I gained experience, I realized they wanted that section of the operations order to reflect their voice.<span data-ez-name="fromthegreennotebook_com-box-4"></span></p>
<p>We all have a voice when we write. This voice is our certificate of authenticity. When commanders write their own correspondence, their voice comes through. When someone else drafts an email, using words and phrases the commander wouldn’t normally use, others can tell someone else wrote it.</p>
<p>Authenticity in communications is important for two reasons. First, subordinates will know if the intent, the guidance, the policy, etc., is the commander’s, or if it is another product produced by staff. They are more likely to follow it and adhere to it when they know it comes directly from the commander’s mind and is not a draft by a random staff officer.</p>
<p>Also, commanders who write their own communications tend to reinforce the message by repeating what they wrote. The senior Army leader I worked for occasionally wrote guidance that he sent out in an email. He then repeated key words and phrases from the document in meetings, during battlefield circulation and in one-on-one discussions. Everyone knew he wrote the email because he owned it and talked about it; his guidance didn’t become memorandums left on a bulletin board in a headquarters.</p>
<p>The second reason authenticity in communications is important is that it signals leader involvement in an issue. I have learned that many senior leaders can tell when a subordinate commander’s email is authentic or a staff-produced ghost note.</p>
<p>Every time there was a change or inflection point in the strategic situation, my boss would provide a one- or two-page update to his commanders. He always wrote these himself, for the reasons mentioned above. I found out from those commanders’ staff members that their bosses read these emails because they knew it was from him, and that if he took the time to write it, they should take the time to read it.</p>
<p>Communication can be frustrating. Sometimes it is like tapping out a song you have in your head and expecting another person to immediately know the tune. It is hard to convey an idea in your head to someone who may not have the same background or experiences as you, or who wasn’t in the same room when you had a conversation.</p>
<p>Communication is a skill that takes practice. We need repetition. Leaders who write their own emails gain needed communication experience when it matters. I have also learned that speed comes with practice. I can write in hours what used to take days.</p>
<p><strong>Honing the Skill</strong></p>
<p>I recognize that commanders have a lot on their plates, and it isn’t feasible for them to spend hours writing and responding to emails. There are many ghost notes best produced by staff in the interest of time. However, when it comes to communicating up or down the chain of command on key issues, or writing guidance on important topics, it is best for commanders to own those.</p>
<p>Great leaders are also great communicators, but the ability to communicate effectively and efficiently takes time to develop. By owning communications, commanders refine and hone this skill. They also have an opportunity to work through problems and refine their thinking through the process of writing. Finally, they gain authenticity in their communications—an important factor in ensuring that “message sent” is “message received.”</p>
<p>This article was first published in <a href="https://www.ausa.org/articles/leaders-subject-write-your-own-emails">ARMY Magazine</a> and reprinted with their permission.</p>



	





		
		
					</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->

</article><!-- #post-## -->

			
<!-- #comments -->

		
		</main><!-- #main -->
	</section><!-- #primary -->

	<!-- #secondary --></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://fromthegreennotebook.com/2020/10/03/why-leaders-need-to-learn-the-skill-of-writing/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24964730</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 04:03:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Names are not type safety]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 256 | Comments 121 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24963821">thread link</a>) | @azhenley
<br/>
November 1, 2020 | http://lexi-lambda.github.io/blog/2020/11/01/names-are-not-type-safety/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://lexi-lambda.github.io/blog/2020/11/01/names-are-not-type-safety/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section role="main">
        <!-- Main column -->
        <div>



          <article>
  <header>
    
    
  </header>

<p>Haskell programmers spend a lot of time talking about <em>type safety</em>. The Haskell school of program construction advocates “capturing invariants in the type system” and “making illegal states unrepresentable,” both of which sound like compelling goals, but are rather vague on the techniques used to achieve them. Almost exactly one year ago, I published <a href="http://lexi-lambda.github.io/blog/2019/11/05/parse-don-t-validate/">Parse, Don’t Validate</a> as an initial stab towards bridging that gap.</p>

<p>The ensuing discussions were largely productive and right-minded, but one particular source of confusion quickly became clear: Haskell’s <code>newtype</code> construct. The idea is simple enough—the <code>newtype</code> keyword declares a wrapper type, nominally distinct from but representationally equivalent to the type it wraps—and on the surface this <em>sounds</em> like a simple and straightforward path to type safety. For example, one might consider using a <code>newtype</code> declaration to define a type for an email address:</p>

<div>
 <div>
  <pre><span></span><span>newtype</span> <span>EmailAddress</span> <span>=</span> <span>EmailAddress</span> <span>Text</span>
</pre></div>

</div>

<p>This technique can provide <em>some</em> value, and when coupled with a smart constructor and an encapsulation boundary, it can even provide some safety. But it is a meaningfully distinct <em>kind</em> of type safety from the one I highlighted a year ago, one that is far weaker. On its own, a newtype is just a name.</p>

<p>And names are not type safety.</p>
<!-- more-->



<p>To illustrate the difference between constructive data modeling (discussed at length in my <a href="http://lexi-lambda.github.io/blog/2020/08/13/types-as-axioms-or-playing-god-with-static-types/">previous blog post</a>) and newtype wrappers, let’s consider an example. Suppose we want a type for “an integer between 1 and 5, inclusive.” The natural constructive modeling would be an enumeration with five cases:</p>

<div>
 <div>
  <pre><span></span><span>data</span> <span>OneToFive</span>
  <span>=</span> <span>One</span>
  <span>|</span> <span>Two</span>
  <span>|</span> <span>Three</span>
  <span>|</span> <span>Four</span>
  <span>|</span> <span>Five</span>
</pre></div>

</div>

<p>We could then write some functions to convert between <code>Int</code> and our <code>OneToFive</code> type:</p>

<div>
 <div>
  <pre><span></span><span>toOneToFive</span> <span>::</span> <span>Int</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Maybe</span> <span>OneToFive</span>
<span>toOneToFive</span> <span>1</span> <span>=</span> <span>Just</span> <span>One</span>
<span>toOneToFive</span> <span>2</span> <span>=</span> <span>Just</span> <span>Two</span>
<span>toOneToFive</span> <span>3</span> <span>=</span> <span>Just</span> <span>Three</span>
<span>toOneToFive</span> <span>4</span> <span>=</span> <span>Just</span> <span>Four</span>
<span>toOneToFive</span> <span>5</span> <span>=</span> <span>Just</span> <span>Five</span>
<span>toOneToFive</span> <span>_</span> <span>=</span> <span>Nothing</span>

<span>fromOneToFive</span> <span>::</span> <span>OneToFive</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Int</span>
<span>fromOneToFive</span> <span>One</span>   <span>=</span> <span>1</span>
<span>fromOneToFive</span> <span>Two</span>   <span>=</span> <span>2</span>
<span>fromOneToFive</span> <span>Three</span> <span>=</span> <span>3</span>
<span>fromOneToFive</span> <span>Four</span>  <span>=</span> <span>4</span>
<span>fromOneToFive</span> <span>Five</span>  <span>=</span> <span>5</span>
</pre></div>

</div>

<p>This would be perfectly sufficient for achieving our stated goal, but you’d be forgiven for finding it odd: it would be rather awkward to work with in practice. Because we’ve invented an entirely new type, we can’t reuse any of the usual numeric functions Haskell provides. Consequently, many programmers would gravitate towards a newtype wrapper, instead:</p>

<div>
 <div>
  <pre><span></span><span>newtype</span> <span>OneToFive</span> <span>=</span> <span>OneToFive</span> <span>Int</span>
</pre></div>

</div>

<p>Just as before, we can provide <code>toOneToFive</code> and <code>fromOneToFive</code> functions, with identical types:</p>

<div>
 <div>
  <pre><span></span><span>toOneToFive</span> <span>::</span> <span>Int</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Maybe</span> <span>OneToFive</span>
<span>toOneToFive</span> <span>n</span>
  <span>|</span> <span>n</span> <span>&gt;=</span> <span>1</span> <span>&amp;&amp;</span> <span>n</span> <span>&lt;=</span> <span>5</span> <span>=</span> <span>Just</span> <span>$</span> <span>OneToFive</span> <span>n</span>
  <span>|</span> <span>otherwise</span>        <span>=</span> <span>Nothing</span>

<span>fromOneToFive</span> <span>::</span> <span>OneToFive</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Int</span>
<span>fromOneToFive</span> <span>(</span><span>OneToFive</span> <span>n</span><span>)</span> <span>=</span> <span>n</span>
</pre></div>

</div>

<p>If we put these declarations in their own module and choose not to export the <code>OneToFive</code> constructor, these APIs might appear entirely interchangeable. Naïvely, it seems that the newtype version is both simpler and equally type-safe. However—perhaps surprisingly—this is not actually true.</p>

<p>To see why, suppose we write a function that consumes a <code>OneToFive</code> value as an argument. Under the constructive modeling, such a function need only pattern-match against each of the five constructors, and GHC will accept the definition as exhaustive:</p>

<div>
 <div>
  <pre><span></span><span>ordinal</span> <span>::</span> <span>OneToFive</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Text</span>
<span>ordinal</span> <span>One</span>   <span>=</span> <span>"first"</span>
<span>ordinal</span> <span>Two</span>   <span>=</span> <span>"second"</span>
<span>ordinal</span> <span>Three</span> <span>=</span> <span>"third"</span>
<span>ordinal</span> <span>Four</span>  <span>=</span> <span>"fourth"</span>
<span>ordinal</span> <span>Five</span>  <span>=</span> <span>"fifth"</span>
</pre></div>

</div>

<p>The same is not true given the newtype encoding. The newtype is opaque, so the only way to observe it is to convert it back to an <code>Int</code>—after all, it <em>is</em> an <code>Int</code>. An <code>Int</code> can of course contain many other values besides <code>1</code> through <code>5</code>, so we are forced to add an error case to satisfy the exhaustiveness checker:</p>

<div>
 <div>
  <pre><span></span><span>ordinal</span> <span>::</span> <span>OneToFive</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Text</span>
<span>ordinal</span> <span>n</span> <span>=</span> <span>case</span> <span>fromOneToFive</span> <span>n</span> <span>of</span>
  <span>1</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>"first"</span>
  <span>2</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>"second"</span>
  <span>3</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>"third"</span>
  <span>4</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>"fourth"</span>
  <span>5</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>"fifth"</span>
  <span>_</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>error</span> <span>"impossible: bad OneToFive value"</span>
</pre></div>

</div>

<p>In this highly contrived example, this may not seem like much of a problem to you. But it nonetheless illustrates a key difference in the guarantees afforded by the two approaches:</p>

<ul>
 <li>
  <p>The constructive datatype captures its invariants in such a way that they are <em>accessible</em> to downstream consumers. This frees our <code>ordinal</code> function from worrying about handling illegal values, as they have been made unutterable.</p></li>
 <li>
  <p>The newtype wrapper provides a smart constructor that <em>validates</em> the value, but the boolean result of that check is used only for control flow; it is not preserved in the function’s result. Accordingly, downstream consumers cannot take advantage of the restricted domain; they are functionally accepting <code>Int</code>s.</p></li></ul>

<p>Losing exhaustiveness checking might seem like small potatoes, but it absolutely is not: our use of <code>error</code> has punched a hole right through our type system. If we were to add another constructor to our <code>OneToFive</code> datatype,<sup><a href="#2020-11-01-names-are-not-type-safety-footnote-1-definition" name="2020-11-01-names-are-not-type-safety-footnote-1-return">1</a></sup> the version of <code>ordinal</code> that consumes a constructive datatype would be immediately detected non-exhaustive at compile-time, while the version that consumes a newtype wrapper would continue to compile yet fail at runtime, dropping through to the “impossible” case.</p>

<p>All of this is a consequence of the fact that the constructive modeling is <em>intrinsically</em> type-safe; that is, the safety properties are enforced by the type declaration itself. Illegal values truly are unrepresentable: there is simply no way to represent <code>6</code> using any of the five constructors. The same is not true of the newtype declaration, which has no intrinsic semantic distinction from that of an <code>Int</code>; its meaning is specified extrinsically via the <code>toOneToFive</code> smart constructor. Any semantic distinction intended by a newtype is thoroughly invisible to the type system; it exists only in the programmer’s mind.</p>

<h2 id="revisiting-non-empty-lists">Revisiting non-empty lists</h2>

<p>Our <code>OneToFive</code> datatype is rather artificial, but identical reasoning applies to other datatypes that are significantly more practical. Consider the <code>NonEmpty</code> datatype I’ve repeatedly highlighted in recent blog posts:</p>

<div>
 <div>
  <pre><span></span><span>data</span> <span>NonEmpty</span> <span>a</span> <span>=</span> <span>a</span> <span>:|</span> <span>[</span><span>a</span><span>]</span>
</pre></div>

</div>

<p>It may be illustrative to imagine a version of <code>NonEmpty</code> represented as a newtype over ordinary lists. We can use the usual smart constructor strategy to enforce the desired non-emptiness property:</p>

<div>
 <div>
  <pre><span></span><span>newtype</span> <span>NonEmpty</span> <span>a</span> <span>=</span> <span>NonEmpty</span> <span>[</span><span>a</span><span>]</span>

<span>nonEmpty</span> <span>::</span> <span>[</span><span>a</span><span>]</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Maybe</span> <span>(</span><span>NonEmpty</span> <span>a</span><span>)</span>
<span>nonEmpty</span> <span>[]</span> <span>=</span> <span>Nothing</span>
<span>nonEmpty</span> <span>xs</span> <span>=</span> <span>Just</span> <span>$</span> <span>NonEmpty</span> <span>xs</span>

<span>instance</span> <span>Foldable</span> <span>NonEmpty</span> <span>where</span>
  <span>toList</span> <span>(</span><span>NonEmpty</span> <span>xs</span><span>)</span> <span>=</span> <span>xs</span>
</pre></div>

</div>

<p>Just as with <code>OneToFive</code>, we quickly discover the consequences of failing to preserve this information in the type system. Our motivating use case for <code>NonEmpty</code> was the ability to write a safe version of <code>head</code>, but the newtype version requires another assertion:</p>

<div>
 <div>
  <pre><span></span><span>head</span> <span>::</span> <span>NonEmpty</span> <span>a</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>a</span>
<span>head</span> <span>xs</span> <span>=</span> <span>case</span> <span>toList</span> <span>xs</span> <span>of</span>
  <span>x</span><span>:</span><span>_</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>x</span>
  <span>[]</span>  <span>-&gt;</span> <span>error</span> <span>"impossible: empty NonEmpty value"</span>
</pre></div>

</div>

<p>This might not seem like a big deal, since it seems unlikely such a case would ever happen. But that reasoning hinges entirely on trusting the correctness of the module that defines <code>NonEmpty</code>, while the constructive definition only requires trusting the GHC typechecker. As we generally trust that the typechecker works correctly, the latter is a much more compelling proof.</p>



<p>If you are fond of newtypes, this whole argument may seem a bit troubling. It may seem like I’m implying newtypes are scarcely better than comments, albeit comments that happen to be meaningful to the typechecker. Fortunately, the situation is not quite that grim—newtypes <em>can</em> provide a sort of safety, just a weaker one.</p>

<p>The primary safety benefit of newtypes is derived from abstraction boundaries. If a newtype’s constructor is not exported, it becomes opaque to other modules. The module that defines the newtype—its “home module”—can take advantage of this to create a <em>trust boundary</em> where internal invariants are enforced by restricting clients to a safe API.</p>

<p>We can use the <code>NonEmpty</code> example from above to illustrate how this works. We refrain from exporting the <code>NonEmpty</code> constructor, and we provide <code>head</code> and <code>tail</code> operations that we trust to never actually fail:</p>

<div>
 <div>
  <pre><span></span><span>module</span> <span>Data.List.NonEmpty.Newtype</span>
  <span>(</span> <span>NonEmpty</span>
  <span>,</span> <span>cons</span>
  <span>,</span> <span>nonEmpty</span>
  <span>,</span> <span>head</span>
  <span>,</span> <span>tail</span>
  <span>)</span> <span>where</span>

<span>newtype</span> <span>NonEmpty</span> <span>a</span> <span>=</span> <span>NonEmpty</span> <span>[</span><span>a</span><span>]</span>

<span>cons</span> <span>::</span> <span>a</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>[</span><span>a</span><span>]</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>NonEmpty</span> <span>a</span>
<span>cons</span> <span>x</span> <span>xs</span> <span>=</span> <span>NonEmpty</span> <span>(</span><span>x</span><span>:</span><span>xs</span><span>)</span>

<span>nonEmpty</span> <span>::</span> <span>[</span><span>a</span><span>]</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Maybe</span> <span>(</span><span>NonEmpty</span> <span>a</span><span>)</span>
<span>nonEmpty</span> <span>[]</span> <span>=</span> <span>Nothing</span>
<span>nonEmpty</span> <span>xs</span> <span>=</span> <span>Just</span> <span>$</span> <span>NonEmpty</span> <span>xs</span>

<span>head</span> <span>::</span> <span>NonEmpty</span> <span>a</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>a</span>
<span>head</span> <span>(</span><span>NonEmpty</span> <span>(</span><span>x</span><span>:</span><span>_</span><span>))</span> <span>=</span> <span>x</span>
<span>head</span> <span>(</span><span>NonEmpty</span> <span>[]</span><span>)</span>    <span>=</span> <span>error</span> <span>"impossible: empty NonEmpty value"</span>

<span>tail</span> <span>::</span> <span>NonEmpty</span> <span>a</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>[</span><span>a</span><span>]</span>
<span>tail</span> <span>(</span><span>NonEmpty</span> <span>(</span><span>_</span><span>:</span><span>xs</span><span>))</span> <span>=</span> <span>xs</span>
<span>tail</span> <span>(</span><span>NonEmpty</span> <span>[]</span><span>)</span>     <span>=</span> <span>error</span> <span>"impossible: empty NonEmpty value"</span>
</pre></div>

</div>

<p>Since the only way to construct or consume <code>NonEmpty</code> values is to use the functions in <code>Data.List.NonEmpty.Newtype</code>’s exported API, the above implementation makes it impossible for clients to violate the non-emptiness invariant. In a sense, values of opaque newtypes are like <em>tokens</em>: the implementing module issues tokens via its constructor functions, and those tokens have no intrinsic value. The only way to do anything useful with them is to “redeem” them to the issuing module’s accessor functions, in this case <code>head</code> and <code>tail</code>, to obtain the values contained within.</p>

<p>This approach is significantly weaker than using a constructive datatype, since it is theoretically possible to screw up and accidentally provide a means to construct an invalid <code>NonEmpty []</code> value. For this reason, the newtype approach to type safety does not on its own constitute a <em>proof</em> that a desired invariant holds. However, it restricts the “surface area” where an invariant violation can occur to the defining module, so reasonable confidence the invariant really does hold can be achieved by thoroughly testing the module’s API using fuzzing or property-based testing techniques.<sup><a href="#2020-11-01-names-are-not-type-safety-footnote-2-definition" name="2020-11-01-names-are-not-type-safety-footnote-2-return">2</a></sup></p>

<p>This tradeoff may not seem all that bad, and indeed, it is often a very good one! Guaranteeing invariants using …</p></article></div></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://lexi-lambda.github.io/blog/2020/11/01/names-are-not-type-safety/">http://lexi-lambda.github.io/blog/2020/11/01/names-are-not-type-safety/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://lexi-lambda.github.io/blog/2020/11/01/names-are-not-type-safety/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24963821</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:27:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Microservices – architecture nihilism in minimalism's clothes]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 226 | Comments 151 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24963742">thread link</a>) | @zdw
<br/>
November 1, 2020 | https://vlfig.me/posts/microservices | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://vlfig.me/posts/microservices">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Some recent <a href="https://twitter.com/gergelyorosz/status/1247132806041546754" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">backtracking</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/copyconstruct/status/1247130488667394049" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">from</a> what we have been calling “Microservices” has sparked anew the debate around that software architecture pattern. It turns out that for increasingly more software people, having a backend with (<a href="https://www.infoq.com/presentations/monzo-microservices/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">sometimes several</a>) hundreds of services wasn’t that great an idea after all. The debate has <a href="https://riak.com/posts/technical/microservices-please-dont/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">been going on for a while</a> and much has already been said, but there are still a couple of things I’d like to say.</p>
<p><strong>TL;DR</strong> “Microservices” was a good idea taken too far and applied too bluntly. The fix isn’t just to dial back the granularity knob but instead to 1) focus on the split-join criteria as opposed to size; and 2) differentiate between the project model and the deployment model when applying them.</p>
<p>I explain. Allow me to rant a bit first.</p>


<p>There were three main reasons for the initial success of <em>microservices</em> as an architectural pattern for software: 1) forced modularisation, 2) weakened dependencies, and 3) an excuse for having no architecture. In order:</p>
<ol>
<li>In the monoliths of old, you could in theory enforce module boundaries. You could say that your <code>acme-helpers</code> or <code>acme-data-tools</code> could not depend on <code>acme-domain</code>, say, and you even had some tooling to enforce that, but it was fallible. Especially in big companies where these monoliths spanned more than a team’s cognitive horizon, violations of those boundaries were often a simple <code>import</code> away, and of course rife. Angry architects saw in microservices the promise of making those a thing of the past: now the developer is forced to only deal with the API. Codebases parted ways and calls were made to go down the network stack and back.</li>
<li>
<p>So then, one wouldn’t depend on a fellow service at build time, only at runtime. Great. Method calls became http calls. “Now we don’t need to care about dependencies” — actual people said this, as if the dependency wasn’t fundamental and instead just an accidental artifact of the build setup. Everybody brushed up on their HTTP and different server and client implementations, read all about REST and Soap (and RPC, RMI and CORBA while at it) and merrily created a layer of indirection between modules — now <em>services</em> — that was <em>very</em> loose. Typed APIs, granular network policies and contract testing came much later.</p>
<p>It felt liberating until the complexities of API versioning, delivery semantics, error propagation, distributed transaction management and the sprawl of client code in all callers of a service began to show up. This was a gigantic <strong>shift right</strong>, but hey, the build process was simpler.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>More insidious perhaps was the validation that “doing microservices” brought to organisations that lacked a thesis about how their architecture should be. There was now a sanctioned answer to most architectural dilemmas: another microservice. Another entry in the service catalog for any and all interested parties to call. This ecology of interacting parties, each acting in their own interest for the common good spoke to an underlying, tacit belief that the emergent mesh of services would approximate the latent natural architecture of the domain.</p>
<p>So soft and convenient was the lure of not having to draw hard architectural lines that we got lazy where we weren’t and accepted our lazyness where we already were. If you didn’t subscribe to that belief, the problem was you and your lack of understanding of complex systems, you objectivist cretin.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Yes, there was real pain in managing monoliths and sure, many systems were too monolithic (i.e. had deployables too large) but the zealotry of a newfound purity swung the pendulum too far, as they always do. Not only do we not need to run so many services so small, we also don’t benefit from isolating their codebases so much. To summarise:</p>
<ol>
<li>having a big flat permissive build is no good reason to split deployables;</li>
<li>weakening dependencies between different parts of our systems is a “shift-right” loan with high interest; and</li>
<li>having a ready answer when the thinking gets tough is a soothing lie that just moves complexity about. There is no substitute to the effortful application of cognitive power to a problem.</li>
</ol>

<p>Two things: focus on the right criteria for splitting a service instead of on its size, and apply those criteria more thoughtfully.</p>
<h2 id="size-is-not-the-answer"><a href="#size-is-not-the-answer" aria-label="size is not the answer permalink"></a>Size is not the answer</h2>
<p>The <em>micro</em> in microservices ought to be at best a prediction, never a goal. We may predict services <em>will be</em> micro but they don’t <em>have to be</em>. <a href="https://kalele.io/microservices-and-microservices/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Vaugh Vernon is right</a> when he speaks about “cohesion for a reason”.</p>
<p>There should be no prescribed <em>a priori</em> granularity of services. There <em>is</em> no prescribed size of a service. There are instead <strong>good and bad reasons to split</strong> parts of a software system.</p>
<p>So the heuristic is:</p>
<div data-language="text"><pre><code>                      Start one, split with a reason.</code></pre></div>
<p>Conversely, if a reason ceases to exist, consider joining them.</p>
<h2 id="the-missing-hinge"><a href="#the-missing-hinge" aria-label="the missing hinge permalink"></a>The missing hinge</h2>
<p>There are however different realms in which “software systems” exist: they exist both as artifacts we interact with and as artifacts computers interact with. Code and binary. We organise them in different ways: the <strong>project model</strong> (repositories, projects, modules and their dependencies) and the <strong>deployment model</strong> (what production environments look like and how deployables run in them).</p>
<figure>
    <span>
      <a href="https://vlfig.me/static/8123a14a0e4efcacfddc6f26f7ad3e78/6246a/monolith.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="A monolithic setup where one big repo builds one single big deployable." title="A monolithic setup where one big repo builds one single big deployable." src="https://vlfig.me/static/8123a14a0e4efcacfddc6f26f7ad3e78/6a068/monolith.jpg" srcset="https://vlfig.me/static/8123a14a0e4efcacfddc6f26f7ad3e78/09b79/monolith.jpg 240w,
https://vlfig.me/static/8123a14a0e4efcacfddc6f26f7ad3e78/7cc5e/monolith.jpg 480w,
https://vlfig.me/static/8123a14a0e4efcacfddc6f26f7ad3e78/6a068/monolith.jpg 960w,
https://vlfig.me/static/8123a14a0e4efcacfddc6f26f7ad3e78/644c5/monolith.jpg 1440w,
https://vlfig.me/static/8123a14a0e4efcacfddc6f26f7ad3e78/6246a/monolith.jpg 1463w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span>
    <figcaption><p>A monolithic setup where one big repo builds one single big deployable.</p></figcaption>
  </figure>
<p>In the process of going from coarse to granular (i.e. from monolith to microservices) however, little attention was paid to the difference — and possible indirection — between those two models. The hammer hit both fairly indiscriminately and made us split codebases because of runtime concerns and split deployables due to project concerns.</p>
<figure>
    <span>
      <a href="https://vlfig.me/static/fd7e19a50516d91d0b3a84dd16e262ca/6c0a0/stiff-1-1.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="A set of repositories each building their own self-contained independent service." title="Excessive mirroring between the project and deployment models." src="https://vlfig.me/static/fd7e19a50516d91d0b3a84dd16e262ca/6a068/stiff-1-1.jpg" srcset="https://vlfig.me/static/fd7e19a50516d91d0b3a84dd16e262ca/09b79/stiff-1-1.jpg 240w,
https://vlfig.me/static/fd7e19a50516d91d0b3a84dd16e262ca/7cc5e/stiff-1-1.jpg 480w,
https://vlfig.me/static/fd7e19a50516d91d0b3a84dd16e262ca/6a068/stiff-1-1.jpg 960w,
https://vlfig.me/static/fd7e19a50516d91d0b3a84dd16e262ca/6c0a0/stiff-1-1.jpg 1062w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span>
    <figcaption><p>Excessive mirroring between the project and deployment models.</p></figcaption>
  </figure>
<p>Much like stiffness in a part of the human spine can result in pain in another, <strong>stiffness in our build DAGs is causing excessive mirroring between our project and deployment models</strong>; between our repositories and our services; between the way we organise our code and the way our services run. That mirroring is on the one hand preventing us from shifting left concerns about the relationships between modules that have often been made weak and fragile runtime dependencies, while on the other hand encouraging us to have more services than what the runtime reality would call for. That brings pain.</p>
<figure>
    <span>
      <a href="https://vlfig.me/static/1f3476e5c0b1320f4dd42084cfc102b9/dc6ba/hinge.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="The build DAG as a hinge between the project model and the deployment model." title="A build DAG mediates the project and the deployment models, absorbing the impedance mismatch between what is human friendly and what is machine-friendly." src="https://vlfig.me/static/1f3476e5c0b1320f4dd42084cfc102b9/6a068/hinge.jpg" srcset="https://vlfig.me/static/1f3476e5c0b1320f4dd42084cfc102b9/09b79/hinge.jpg 240w,
https://vlfig.me/static/1f3476e5c0b1320f4dd42084cfc102b9/7cc5e/hinge.jpg 480w,
https://vlfig.me/static/1f3476e5c0b1320f4dd42084cfc102b9/6a068/hinge.jpg 960w,
https://vlfig.me/static/1f3476e5c0b1320f4dd42084cfc102b9/dc6ba/hinge.jpg 1335w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span>
    <figcaption><p>A build DAG mediates the project and the deployment models, absorbing the impedance mismatch between what is human friendly and what is machine-friendly.</p></figcaption>
  </figure>
<p>Central to resolving this stiffness is the realisation that the build flow, at least conceptually, is a DAG – Directed Acyclic Graph – where the nodes are <em>jobs</em> and <em>versioned artifacts</em> and the edges connect either a job to a versioned artifact (“produces”) or a versioned artifact to a jobs (“dependency_of”). Deployables are by definition the versioned artifacts that are consumed by the deployment jobs.</p>
<figure>
    <span>
      <a href="https://vlfig.me/static/e029adab126c3c2556e80d1647accb16/50066/dag.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="A graph of two types of nodes, jobs and versioned artifacts, connected by edges 'dependency_of' and 'produces'. Versioned artifacts can be further specialised." title="A graph of two types of nodes, jobs and versioned artifacts, connected by edges 'dependency_of' and 'produces'. Versioned artifacts can be further specialised." src="https://vlfig.me/static/e029adab126c3c2556e80d1647accb16/6a068/dag.jpg" srcset="https://vlfig.me/static/e029adab126c3c2556e80d1647accb16/09b79/dag.jpg 240w,
https://vlfig.me/static/e029adab126c3c2556e80d1647accb16/7cc5e/dag.jpg 480w,
https://vlfig.me/static/e029adab126c3c2556e80d1647accb16/6a068/dag.jpg 960w,
https://vlfig.me/static/e029adab126c3c2556e80d1647accb16/50066/dag.jpg 1384w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span>
    <figcaption><p>A graph of two types of nodes, jobs and versioned artifacts, connected by edges ‘dependency_of’ and ‘produces’. Versioned artifacts can be further specialised.</p></figcaption>
  </figure>
<p>For too long we overlooked how much a flexible and frictionless build DAG allows us to improve our architecture on both sides. With moderately rich build patterns we can have our code where its intent is clearer and more constraints can be validated at build time and still have it deployed into its simplest viable form, running where its execution is cheaper, faster and safer.</p>
<figure>
    <span>
      <a href="https://vlfig.me/static/08e9b2a03b92afa1c2b43018fb141eb0/a18e1/wedding-altar.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="Cheesy cisgender, neurotypical westernised image of a wedding altar with the build dag marrying developer effectiveness with mechanical sympathy." title="Sorry. I had to." src="https://vlfig.me/static/08e9b2a03b92afa1c2b43018fb141eb0/a18e1/wedding-altar.jpg" srcset="https://vlfig.me/static/08e9b2a03b92afa1c2b43018fb141eb0/09b79/wedding-altar.jpg 240w,
https://vlfig.me/static/08e9b2a03b92afa1c2b43018fb141eb0/7cc5e/wedding-altar.jpg 480w,
https://vlfig.me/static/08e9b2a03b92afa1c2b43018fb141eb0/a18e1/wedding-altar.jpg 612w" sizes="(max-width: 612px) 100vw, 612px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span>
    <figcaption><p>Sorry. I had to.</p></figcaption>
  </figure><p>.</p>
<h3 id="why-so-stiff-bro"><a href="#why-so-stiff-bro" aria-label="why so stiff bro permalink"></a>Why so stiff, bro?</h3>
<p>I’m not sure what the historically accurate account is that would explain the excessive simplicity of build patterns across the industry. I do know from experience that too many practices make do with very simple and linear flows where one repository builds independently one and only one service. Regardless of the legitimate argument about code duplication and its tradeoffs, there seems to be an aversion to build-time internal dependencies, even when these bring in clearly desirable data or logic such as message format definitions.</p>
<p>I suspect it might have something to do with how very few CI tools support composition natively (i.e. the outputs of jobs being able to be the inputs of others), how fallible semantic versioning in practice is and the difficulty of automating deterministic version propagation.</p>
<p>By that I mean keeping local copies in sync with CI, builds repeatable, and new upstream versions automatically used by their downstream dependents. It isn’t trivial and requires some versioning and build-fu that, to my knowledge, most practices end up shortcutting to either sacrifice repeatability by using <code>latest</code> or stifling the flow by requiring repeated manual work. Hence the pressure to have a simple build setup.</p>
<p>The exact cause is unimportant though. What is important is that overcoming this is crucial.</p>

<p>Many criteria for splitting or joining software systems, ranging from the social (teams, bounded contexts) to the mechanical (cpu or io boundedness) have been put forth, and they all make some form of sense. However, most of them are either a good reason to split projects or modules, or a good reason to split deployables, rarely both. Keeping that in mind will help us apply them more effectively.</p>
<p>Below are a few possible criteria and some comments about their application. I’m not trying to be exhaustive, just illustrating the kind of reasoning makes sense to me.</p>
<h2 id="runtime-deployment-side-criteria"><a href="#runtime-deployment-side-criteria" aria-label="runtime deployment side criteria permalink"></a>Runtime, deployment side criteria</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Different Runtime</strong> – If a part of the codebase compiles to a different runtime it becomes a different deployable and we call it a different service.</li>
<li><strong>Elasticity Profile</strong> – Some parts of the system may have a spikier load profile. It might pay off to have them scale in and out separately from the rest.</li>
<li><strong>Load Type</strong> – Some parts of a generally latency-oriented io-bound system may generate occasional peaks of cpu-bound load which can hurt response times. It might be better to put them in a …</li></ul></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://vlfig.me/posts/microservices">https://vlfig.me/posts/microservices</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://vlfig.me/posts/microservices</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24963742</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:16:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
