<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 08:31:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 08:31:41 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Chaos Ink]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 312 | Comments 66 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24813921">thread link</a>) | @parisianka
<br/>
October 17, 2020 | https://dev.scottdarby.com/chaos-ink/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dev.scottdarby.com/chaos-ink/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dev.scottdarby.com/chaos-ink/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24813921</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 22:27:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[We deleted the production database by accident]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 272 | Comments 279 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24813795">thread link</a>) | @caspii
<br/>
October 17, 2020 | https://keepthescore.co/blog/posts/deleting_the_production_database/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://keepthescore.co/blog/posts/deleting_the_production_database/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <div>
        <div>

          


<article>
  <header>
    <h2 dir="auto"><a href="https://keepthescore.co/blog/posts/deleting_the_production_database/">We deleted the production database by accident 💥</a></h2>
    <p><time datetime="2020-10-17T00:00:00+02:00">Sat Oct 17, 2020</time> by Caspar</p>
  </header>
  

<p>Today at around 10:45pm CET, after a couple of glasses of red wine, we deleted the production database by accident 😨. Over 300.00 scoreboards and their associated data were vaporised in an instant.</p>

<p>Thankfully our database is a managed database from DigitalOcean, which means that DigitalOcean automatically do backups once a day. After 5 minutes of hand-wringing and panic, we took the website into maintenance mode and worked on restoring a backup. At around 11:15pm CET, 30 minutes after the disaster, we went back online, however 7 hours of scoreboard data was gone forever 😵.</p>

<p>To be precise, any scoreboards created or scores added on the 17th October 2020 between 15:47 CET and 23:21 CET have been lost. We are extremely sorry about this.</p>

<p><img src="https://keepthescore.co/blog/disaster.jpg" alt="Blue green tennis"></p>

<h2 id="what-happened">What happened?</h2>

<p>It’s tempting to blame the disaster on the couple of glasses of red wine. However, the function that wiped the database was written whilst sober. It’s a function that deletes the local database and creates all the required tables from scratch. This evening, whilst doing some late evening coding, the function connected to the production database and wiped it. Why? This is something we’re still trying to figure out.</p>

<p>Here is the code that caused the disaster:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="python"><span>def</span> <span>database_model_create</span>():
    <span>"""Only works on localhost to prevent catastrophe"""</span>
    database <span>=</span> config<span>.</span>DevelopmentConfig<span>.</span>DB_DATABASE
    user <span>=</span> config<span>.</span>DevelopmentConfig<span>.</span>DB_USERNAME
    password <span>=</span> config<span>.</span>DevelopmentConfig<span>.</span>DB_PASSWORD
    port <span>=</span> config<span>.</span>DevelopmentConfig<span>.</span>DB_PORT
    local_db <span>=</span> PostgresqlDatabase(database<span>=</span>database, user<span>=</span>user, password<span>=</span>password, host<span>=</span><span>'localhost'</span>, port<span>=</span>port)
    local_db<span>.</span>drop_tables([Game, Player, Round, Score, Order])
    local_db<span>.</span>create_tables([Game, Player, Round, Score, Order])
    <span>print</span>(<span>'Initialized the local database.'</span>)</code></pre></div>
<p>Note that <code>host</code> is hardcoded to <code>localhost</code>. This means it should <strong>never connect to any machine other than the developer machine</strong>.  Also: <strong>of course</strong> we use different passwords and users for development and production. We’re too tired to figure it out right now.</p>

<h2 id="what-have-we-learned-why-won-t-this-happen-again">What have we learned? Why won’t this happen again?</h2>

<p>We’ve learned that having a function that deletes your database is too dangerous to have lying around. The problem is, you can never really test the safety mechanisms properly, because testing it would mean pointing a gun at the production database.</p>

<p>We’ve learned that having a backup which allows a quick recovery is absolutely essential. Thanks DigitalOcean, for making this part reliable and simple.</p>

<p>We’ve learned that even a disaster can have some up-sides. This blog post generated a lot of interest. When life gives you citrus fruits, and so on.</p>

<p>The truth is, we can never be 100% sure that something like this won’t happen again. Computers are just too complex and there are days when the complexity gremlins win. However, we will figure out what went wrong and ensure that this <em>particular</em> error doesn’t happen again.</p>

<h2 id="some-perspective">Some perspective</h2>

<p>Thankfully nobody’s job is at risk due to this disaster. The founder is not going to fire the developer – because they are one and the same person.</p>

<p>Also, this webapp is just a side-project. It’s not the software that’s running a power-plant. Nonetheless, we have many users, some of them paying customers, and we try our very best to make them happy. Today we let those users down and that hurts.</p>

<p>The wonderful irony is that not 4 days earlier we tweeted a <em>hilarious</em> meme about deleting your production database:
</p><blockquote><p lang="und" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/mOlFqWal08">pic.twitter.com/mOlFqWal08</a></p>— Keepthescore.co (@keep_the_score) <a href="https://twitter.com/keep_the_score/status/1315552102299598851?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 12, 2020</a></blockquote>



<p>Again, we are very sorry. Good night.</p>

<p>PS This generated some <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24813795">great discussion on Hackernews</a>.</p>

<p><span>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@darmfield?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Dawn Armfield</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/disaster?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Unsplash</a></span></p>


  

  
  <hr>
  
  

</article> 



        </div> <!-- /.blog-main -->

        


      </div> <!-- /.row -->
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://keepthescore.co/blog/posts/deleting_the_production_database/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24813795</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 22:09:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Themed days, Timeboxing and why you should use them]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 55 | Comments 36 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24813440">thread link</a>) | @jamalx31
<br/>
October 17, 2020 | https://www.jamalx31.com/post/themed-days-timeboxing-and-why-you-should-use-them | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.jamalx31.com/post/themed-days-timeboxing-and-why-you-should-use-them">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Have you ever wondered how Elon Musk is running two billion-dollar companies at once? Musk is an interesting example of someone who manages his time so well that he can work 100 hours a week and still manage to take time out for his hobbies, family, and even Twitter! So, how does he do it?<br></p><p>Musk is known for using timeboxing methods to manage his time effectively. He uses timeboxing from the moment he wakes up in the morning where he assigns each time block to a certain task that he needs to accomplish on a given day. This timeboxing method can be used for any tasks ranging from writing emails, scheduling meetings, meditating or anything that you would like to do on a particular day.<br></p><p>Before I began using timeboxing, I learned about another technique called <strong>Themed days</strong>. I decided to combine both to maximize productivity. Themed days are <strong>strategically planned days in your calendar, which are entirely dedicated to one single thing or tasks from the same category</strong>. While timeboxing is <strong>to allocate a certain amount of time to a task in advance and then complete it within that time frame</strong>. The idea behind these two techniques is to eliminate context switching or minimize it.<br></p><p>How to use them? Very simple.<br></p><p>Make a list of 4-5 things you want to focus on this week. For example:</p><ol role="list"><li>☎️ Talk to 5 customers</li><li>💻️ Implement features X,Y &amp; Z</li><li>🎨 Redesign landing page</li><li>✍️ Write a blog post about productivity<br></li></ol><p>These are going to be your “themes”. Now open your calendar and assign a day for each one. Let’s say you want to work Monday and Tuesday on coding the missing features. Use Wednesday to interview customers, etc, you got the idea. (Tip: give each theme a color or an emoji 😉️)<br></p><p>Themed days could be super useful if you already have a day job and are trying to make time for your side hustle. Instead of trying to work on it one hour each day after your day job when you already feel exhausted, you dedicate a whole day for your side project.</p><p>With the one hour a day approach, the chance you could skip the scheduled hour is higher; <strong>with themed days, maintaining self-discipline is much easier.</strong></p><h2>Timeboxing</h2><p>To spice things up a little bit, you should use time timeboxing. Once you finished assigning themes and each day has one:</p><ol role="list"><li>Zoom in on each day</li><li>Add sub-tasks for that day’s theme</li><li>Add a time estimate to each task, and frame it with a start and end time.<br>‍<br></li></ol><p>You want to avoid any tasks without a clear deadline, even if the deadline is not accurate. According to Parkinson’s Law, if you have more time to finish a task, the overall time that you will take to finish the task will also expand. This holds true for many people and timeboxing greatly helps in dealing with that as well.<br></p><p>It’s important that as much as possible in Step 3 above, you avoid the <strong>mental optimistic bias</strong> of underestimating how long the completion of a task would require. When we’re too optimistic about how long a given task is going to take, we fail to completely follow through on what we set out to do.This bias, can be avoided by simply using a <strong>feedback loop, </strong>where you're constantly thinking about what you've done and how you could be doing it better. At the end of each day or at least once a week, reflect on your progress and review the things you worked on that week and think to yourself how you could improve.&nbsp;<br></p><p>Timeboxing is amazing if you learn to do it effectively. In simple words, it is a process to merge your to-do list with your calendar. Another benefit of timeboxing is that it reduces the number of choices you’d have to make in any given moment — boosting your willpower for peak productivity.</p><h2>Productivity as an indie hacker</h2><p>To maximize your productivity, you must set your priorities straight. For me as a developer, I find myself investing the majority of my time coding, but as an indie hacker who wants to build a profitable business, I must focus on other stuff too; marketing, promoting, writing, and talking to customers. Themed days made me realize that <a href="https://www.jamalx31.com/post/is-coding-a-procrastination-trap">coding could be a procrastination trap</a>.<br></p><p>Applying theme days helped me break out of the dev-hamster-wheel (aka coding) and forced me to do more of what needed to be done. So I decided to structure my themed days to look like this:<br></p><p><strong>Monday</strong>: Coding <br>‍<strong>Tuesday</strong>: Coding<strong><br>Wednesday</strong>: Writing / Learning<strong><br>Thursday</strong>: Coding&nbsp;<strong><br>Friday</strong>: Housekeeping / Reflecting&nbsp;<strong><br>Saturday</strong>: Marketing / SEO&nbsp;<strong><br>Sunday</strong>: Writing&nbsp;</p><p>As you see, I only code three days a week, so I can focus on other equally or sometimes even more important things.</p><p>I also found themed days to be very effective when it comes to dealing with new or unexpected tasks. Depending on the task’s "theme", I know precisely on which day it should be scheduled. It takes me a fraction of the time to add it to my system.<br></p><h2>Themed Inbox</h2><p>I took themed days an extra step and applied it to my Gmail inbox. With a <a href="https://www.axllent.org/docs/gmail-snooze-script/">super cool trick using Google Apps Script</a>, I have control over when emails hit my inbox. Instead of checking my email everyday and having dozens of unrelated emails, now emails show up in my inbox on the right day. For example, all unimportant emails are scheduled for Friday (my Housekeeping day), while all marketing &amp; SEO related emails come in on Saturday, and so on. This way I make sure I read the right email at the right time when I’m ready to act on it. So cool, right?<br></p><figure id="w-node-01d3452ce5a9-4885bece"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5eed2ff36d85f3277043492b/5f8b5b8eb994e7219ad5c7a6_aacavebgfxMyaKY5fTJeYgq5iGSUGD-5kW-_E5b-80Oo0IdiLDzEmok9W3WkT5_U-_woBP59Bk2TJg2xCFos_w3fsecvjQiGpCcArpMwuSTAgkbBQkGZUL0fY1dDm_AIU3Vs5NiL.png" alt=""></p><figcaption>The script automatically label emails</figcaption></figure><h2>Building a system: find a tool that works for you.</h2><p>When it comes to productivity in general, it’s important to have an efficient and flexible system that can adapt as your needs change without investing countless hours rebuilding everything from scratch.<br></p><p>Notion has been the core part of my system for the last five months. I’ve been experimenting a lot with different productivity techniques and approaches and it would have been so hard to do that without a super flexible and elegant tool like Notion. It's my second brain and where I store everything, so I’m using it to implement themed days, with Notion build-in templates.<br></p><p>I have a database where I have designed a template for each day and theme. Every morning, after preparing my coffee, I create a new page for that day using the proper template. The new page gets populated with everything I need to be as productive as possible on that day.<br></p><p>For example, on Saturday, which is a marketing/SEO day, I have a page with all the resources and reminders related to that subject.<br></p><figure id="w-node-5a939054f819-4885bece"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5eed2ff36d85f3277043492b/5f8b5b8e51775d3896dd2ca8_IR7wRnLd7_xn6THm_98T9fff1sIPhOhPUMI39ZsvQZckACxBvIC6BGD4oOj2ke_tcSEynYyETcdgfdGl_6kFQibk_no8hh-5oawKs_-YBQTp8GeLS8dstn5kCNhbzySBkC7BNe7X.png" alt="my Notion templates"></p><figcaption>Notion template for each day of the week</figcaption></figure><figure id="w-node-fb4ef460147c-4885bece"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5eed2ff36d85f3277043492b/5f8b5b8e1cd4becfc1e46ca2_RaH23NZlbiaNZOdoL6Pg-aIbRYxrnuE3L3A2-ttTweWCPEe_vbzW6XUu0d-Ycspa372e7ZdciYXHQsFhw_3jadOX_Soqdvqd_ohmn1ikovesCXtAMPrdljxuWiv9Gt15cxeWtB9x.png" alt="Saturday template"></p><figcaption>Saturday's template, focus on marketing &amp;&nbsp;SEO</figcaption></figure><p>What I found really nice about this approach is that my templates are not static, and as I keep updating them, they keep evolving and improving.</p><h2>Next level: Themed weeks</h2><p>If you really want to level up your game and accelerate your progress even further, you can implement themed weeks.</p><p>One of my favourite indie makers, <a href="https://twitter.com/yongfook">Jon Yongfook</a>, has implemented themed weeks for his workflow. Jon works in a 2 weeks sprint, one week of coding, followed by one week of marking, and then wraps it up by writing a newsletter and changelog. When I asked him if he tried shorter sprints, he said that he did but found shorter sprints lead to too much context switching, and two weeks sprint works very well for him.<br></p><p>You can also use the same concept to devote the whole week to a single project, and really make huge advancements, or to a certain business function, and today, with all the rapid prototyping tools available, you could take a week to build an MVP/prototype and test your idea on the market.</p><h2>Give it a try and see for yourself.&nbsp;&nbsp;</h2><p>The best way to see what themed days can do for your productivity is merely trying it out. Here's your homework:</p><ul role="list"><li>Make a list of 3-4 categories/themes you want to focus on (e.g writing, coding, marketing)</li><li>Break them down to atomic tasks, ideally each sub-task should take one hour or less</li><li>Map each theme to a day of the week</li><li>If you can’t find time on working days, try to do it on a Saturday.</li><li>Open your calendar</li><li>Timebox the sub-tasks by scheduling them on their dedicated day</li><li>Get excited -message me to hold you accountable- and do it!&nbsp;<br></li></ul><p>I promise that afterwards, you will feel a sense of achievement and see the progress that can</p><p>be made with this approach. It’s time to make room in your calendar for what matters!</p><p>‍<br></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.jamalx31.com/post/themed-days-timeboxing-and-why-you-should-use-them</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24813440</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 21:15:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Banks help scammers with their bad UI]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 95 | Comments 75 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24810870">thread link</a>) | @ZainRiz
<br/>
October 17, 2020 | https://www.zainrizvi.io/blog/how-banks-help-scammers-with-their-bad-ui/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.zainrizvi.io/blog/how-banks-help-scammers-with-their-bad-ui/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
			<!-- .cover -->


				<div>
					<p>My sister Sana just wanted to earn some money before returning to college. She was looking for a covid-friendly job on craigslist, something to cut down on the student loans she'd have to take out for the year. After searching and scrounging, Sana found someone who needed logistical help taking care of their pets. She applied and was excited to get hired.</p><p>First, they needed help buying pet food. They had ordered $1,800 worth of pet food (they bought high quality stuff in bulk apparently) but the seller would only accept payments via Zelle. Her employer was a bit old fashioned and didn't know how to use that service, so they offered a different arrangement: “I’ll mail you a check for $2,000” they said, “please deposit it in your own bank account, and then use $1,800 of it to Zelle the payment to the sellers. The remaining $200 is your fee.”</p><p>Sana was a bit suspicious, but she deposited the check into her Chase bank account and it cleared a few days later. Chase’s site showed that the money had been deposited successfully and was available to use, no strings attached. </p><p>Seemed like it was legit. So she did the honest thing and Zelle'd the money &nbsp;to the seller.</p><p>Happy with the job well done, her "employer" sent her another $2,000 check to deposit and transfer. This person really liked their pets. The same process happened again, and her employer was happy with the job well done.</p><p>Two weeks later, Sana’s debit card stopped working. Confused, she checked her account to see what was wrong. </p><p>Her heart sank. </p><p>Chase showed it as overdrawn.</p><p>By more than three thousand dollars.</p><p>The checks had bounced, two weeks after Chase’s site had indicated they had “cleared”. Before this whole thing had started, Sana had $300 in her bank account. Now she had negative $3,300.</p><p>She had just been scammed out of $3,600.</p><h2 id="what-happened">What happened?</h2><p>Turns out checks can bounce weeks after they're deposited. It can take that long for the bank to verify they’re legitimate.</p><p>Why does it take so long? Here’s a peek behind the scenes:</p><ol><li>You deposit your check, and it shows up as pending in your account.</li><li>Your bank sends the check to the check-writer’s bank to request the funds.</li><li>Their bank verifies if the check is legitimate and the account actually contains the funds. At small or international banks this step is often manual and could take <em>weeks</em>.</li><li>Their bank lets your bank know it's legit. That's when the check has "cleared".</li></ol><figure><img src="https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/2020/10/Check-lifecycle-large.jpeg" alt="" srcset="https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/size/w600/2020/10/Check-lifecycle-large.jpeg 600w, https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/size/w1000/2020/10/Check-lifecycle-large.jpeg 1000w, https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/size/w1600/2020/10/Check-lifecycle-large.jpeg 1600w, https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/size/w2400/2020/10/Check-lifecycle-large.jpeg 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption>The life cycle of a check</figcaption></figure><p>I skipped one step though: </p><p>It take can than more than <strong>six months</strong> for a check to clear, but banks remove that “pending” status just a couple days after it's deposited and allow people to spend the money. This might sound a bit iffy, but it's actually a good thing. Most checks are legitimate and people might need the money quickly. But that assumption breaks down with fraudulent checks.</p><p>By removing the “pending” status before fully verifying the check’s legitimacy, Chase gave the illusion that the check had already cleared. <em>This is what the scammers count on.</em> &nbsp;</p><p>Today there is <em>no way</em> for a Chase customer to be sure that a check has fully cleared. But unless you have the inside scoop on how banks work, or a finely honed sense of when someone is trying to swindle you, you won’t catch it.</p><p>When Sana called up Chase, the bank heard her out. But instead of stopping the scammers, their only concern was making sure she pays up the remaining $3,000 that they claimed she owed them.</p><p><em>Edit: Chase customer support had one clarification to make. I'd originally said it might take weeks for the check to clear, but they explained it could actually take more than six months. And you'll have no idea when that magic moment occurs.</em></p><!--kg-card-begin: html--><p><img src="https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/2020/10/IMG_1399.jpg" alt="" srcset="https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/size/w600/2020/10/IMG_1399.jpg 600w, https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/2020/10/IMG_1399.jpg 828w" sizes="(min-width: 525px) 525px"></p><!--kg-card-end: html--><h2 id="and-she-s-not-the-only-one-who-s-been-hit-by-this-scam-">And she's not the only one who's been hit by this scam.</h2><p>My friend David Vargas was caught by <a href="https://davidvargas.me/blog/i-got-scammed-out-of-5k/">pretty much the exact same scam</a>. He was sent checks which included his fee and payment that was supposed to be made to someone else. And they only accepted Zelle.</p><p>In fact, similar<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/16/zelle-users-are-finding-out-the-hard-way-theres-no-fraud-protection/?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly9uZXdzLnljb21iaW5hdG9yLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAEVQ_LYXhqL8UBL2vmnP9kphsW_QtokZbglthvs6MgR-ZvqTSF7pcgQMl05VmPjal00O9pBtatU8paO6pmmAYyt91oRIxVEX7L32zEu7v3WKlKOYDV-RVDEHjYe3Co_ugzyWZPRq3oFD-D2giDL1H-Dvj7jmdSbg6NLoAjBnnyWt"> scams</a> <a href="https://news.cardnotpresent.com/news/zelle-scam-emerging">have</a> <a href="https://chicago.cbslocal.com/2019/11/19/how-to-avoid-zelle-scams-and-fraud/">been</a> <a href="https://medium.com/@eirurueta/i-was-scammed-by-using-zelle-for-ethereum-crypto-online-2fa3a38d1817">going on</a> <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/you-accidentally-venmoed-149-to-a-stranger-good-luck-getting-it-back-1531411133">for years</a>, yet most banks don’t seem to care as long as they're not the ones losing money.</p><h2 id="what-should-chase-have-done-here">What should Chase have done here?</h2><h3 id="-1-take-responsibility-their-system-is-broken">#1 Take responsibility: their system is broken</h3><p>Is Chase bank directly responsible for scamming people? Of course not. Did they create an environment where scammers could thrive? Absolutely.</p><p>The harm was unintentional, but they played a hand in it. </p><p>Involuntary manslaughter.</p><p>What have other companies done when someone abused their products to deliberately cause harm? They took responsibility for it and fixed the problem at a systematic level.</p><p><strong>The Tylenol murders: </strong>In 1982, someone started <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/health/tylenol-murders-1982">spiking bottles of Tylenol</a> with poison, killing seven people. This was clearly not Tylenol’s fault, but they still immediately paid to recalled all bottles in the stores, offered anyone who had already purchased the pills free replacements. They took it a step further and <strong>developed tamper-proof packaging </strong>to prevent anyone from contaminating the medicine again in the future.</p><p><strong>Credit Card fraud services</strong>: Online payments are inherently risky. Credit card companies know this, and they’ve committed to helping their customers when the inevitable fraud occurs. If you pay someone with your Discover card and the product turns out to be a scam, <em>Discover will accept responsibility and refund you the money</em>, taking a loss if necessary. This dynamic keeps Discover on their toes working to prevent scams before they even happen.</p><h3 id="-2-how-should-they-fix-it">#2 How should they fix it?</h3><p>Make the status of the deposited check abundantly clear. This is how Chase can tamper-proof their bottles.</p><p>If a check has been deposited but not fully cleared, if it hasn't had the actual funds transferred over to the bank, then Chase needs to make that fact clear to customers! This missing piece of UX is what scammers depend on. That’s the systemic flaw here.</p><p>If the bank actually made the status of the funds clear to its customers, then it would have a much stronger leg to stand on when claiming innocence.</p><p>But as things stand right now, the only way a person could know the check was still at risk is if they already knew about the long clearing time and how banks hide it. Before the results come back from the external bank, Chase itself doesn’t know if the check is valid. Yet they offer customers no hint of that uncertainty.</p><p>And instead of taking responsibility, what did Chase actually do?</p><h3 id="chase-took-option-3-shakedown-their-customers">Chase took option #3: Shakedown their customers</h3><figure><img src="https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/2020/09/Ya340FffaeszEwIQ0ZPdxC9WQbRbN4kGKmcgTWiXLUiifzyqYvwzQSr4nwR3-jR--TS_Z-WrSDyVCcx4G37knBt171ds1zqYgfJ9hB4m-rUHKsDrCMG_N_2u6uTVCOreTRlc32iw.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/Ya340FffaeszEwIQ0ZPdxC9WQbRbN4kGKmcgTWiXLUiifzyqYvwzQSr4nwR3-jR--TS_Z-WrSDyVCcx4G37knBt171ds1zqYgfJ9hB4m-rUHKsDrCMG_N_2u6uTVCOreTRlc32iw.png 600w, https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/size/w1000/2020/09/Ya340FffaeszEwIQ0ZPdxC9WQbRbN4kGKmcgTWiXLUiifzyqYvwzQSr4nwR3-jR--TS_Z-WrSDyVCcx4G37knBt171ds1zqYgfJ9hB4m-rUHKsDrCMG_N_2u6uTVCOreTRlc32iw.png 1000w, https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/2020/09/Ya340FffaeszEwIQ0ZPdxC9WQbRbN4kGKmcgTWiXLUiifzyqYvwzQSr4nwR3-jR--TS_Z-WrSDyVCcx4G37knBt171ds1zqYgfJ9hB4m-rUHKsDrCMG_N_2u6uTVCOreTRlc32iw.png 1192w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Chase acted like the mafia, shaking down whoever they could to get their money back.</p><p>My sister had created this bank account back when she was in high school. For minors, Chase requires a guarantor, someone who would make sure her debts are paid. My dad had listed himself, he was also a Chase customer.</p><p>And now Chase came after him for the remaining three grand.</p><p>He spent hours on the phone with Chase’s customer support trying to get the scam resolved. The reps may have been empathetic, they weren’t empowered to help.</p><p>From the bank's perspective, the money they had already pulled from Sana's account was theirs. Sorry, no negotiation possible. The computer won't let us. And Chase did their darned best to not have to take a hair cut on the rest of the amount they enabled scammers to steal.</p><p>The most those reps could share was to suggest my dad could try not paying the remaining three thousand and wait until the debt goes to collections. And then pray that the collections department has more leniency. It might hurt his credit rating though, they warned. How much? They didn’t know. &nbsp;The account was scheduled to go to collections at the end of September.</p><p>But a month before that date, my dad noticed his own account was now three thousand dollars lighter. Chase had just helped itself to those funds without warning.</p><p>And now that Chase is no longer losing money on this scam, customer support tells him “Sorry, there’s nothing we can do.”</p><p>With every step Chase made sure it got paid, one way or another. Vito Corleone would be proud.</p><figure><img src="https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/2020/09/image-3-1.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-3-1.png 600w, https://www.zainrizvi.io/content/images/2020/09/image-3-1.png 669w"></figure><p>And if the bank has no skin in the game, why worry about fixing some misleading UI? They seem to think people don’t bother switching banks, and that it can treat its customers as captive users.</p><h2 id="how-widespread-must-this-be">How widespread must this be?</h2><p>When a person gets scammed they’re usually hesitant to speak up about it. </p><p>They're ashamed of having been duped, afraid of being scorned for their foolishness, and so their story rarely gets told. </p><p>Yet I know two people who’ve admitted to being hurt by this scam. What does that imply about the scale of this problem?</p><p>And Chase allows it to continue happening, punishing their customers for not having intimate knowledge of how banking works.</p><h2 id="is-your-blood-boiling-yet">Is your blood boiling yet?</h2><p>I get furious every time I think about it. David Vargas tried to pass his situation off as his own fault, but I was outraged on his behalf.</p><p>I want everyone at Chase to see this story. I want every other bank that’s enabling scammers to see this. And I want them to fix their system to let people know when shady checks have not yet been deposited.</p><p>When I showed this article to a friend, he got restless, he wanted to take action. “How can I help?” he asked, “Tell me what to do!” At the time I wasn’t sure what could be done, but there is one thing:</p><p><strong>My ask to you:</strong> Can you help spread the word and make Chase notice this problem? Maybe the internet outrage machine can turn this into a priority and protect the thousands of other people who are being scammed by this.</p><p>You could share this article (<a href="https://twitter.com/ZainRzv/status/1311701855148236800">retweet the Tweet</a>, or post on FB, Reddit, HN, whatever your usual channels are). Get this shared widely. And maybe, just maybe, some executive at Chase will notice and take the lead in transforming the banking industry. My sincerest thank you to everyone who helps.</p><p>So far, Chase hasn’t been interested in accepting an ounce of responsibility for their part in this scheme. Why bother fixing the system when you can just pull money from your customer’s bank accounts? But maybe they can change. Who wants to be known as an unwitting accomplice to scammers?</p><p>And even if they don't change, remember Chase's missteps and …</p></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.zainrizvi.io/blog/how-banks-help-scammers-with-their-bad-ui/">https://www.zainrizvi.io/blog/how-banks-help-scammers-with-their-bad-ui/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.zainrizvi.io/blog/how-banks-help-scammers-with-their-bad-ui/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24810870</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 15:52:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Lisp from Nothing]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 140 | Comments 18 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24809293">thread link</a>) | @nils-m-holm
<br/>
October 17, 2020 | http://t3x.org/lfn/index.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://t3x.org/lfn/index.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Lulu Press, 2020 - 301 pages - 17 figures - 6"&nbsp;x&nbsp;9" format - <a href="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">CC0</a> code</p></div><p>
This text plays with the theme of minimal LISP by providing
several implementations from a simple metacircular evaluator to
a full compiler that emits a single, self-contained C program.
The discussion is embedded in reflections on what hacking looked
like in the early days of LISP.
</p></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://t3x.org/lfn/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24809293</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 11:48:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Building a 10BASE5 “Thick Ethernet” Network (2012)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 65 | Comments 23 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24807542">thread link</a>) | @RicardoLuis0
<br/>
October 16, 2020 | http://tech.mattmillman.com/projects/10base5/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://tech.mattmillman.com/projects/10base5/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>I can hardly claim to have worked professionally with 10BASE5 as when I first started building my own 10BASE2 networks in 1997, 10BASE5 was long obsolete. Back then, I knew about 10BASE5, but it wasn’t practical, affordable or interesting enough for me to attempt building one.</p>
<p>Fast forward to 2012, and 10BASE5 is now truly a vintage technology. Anyone studying something&nbsp;I.T. related likely will at some point have been told about this stuff, because it’s very important in the history of computing. This was the first standardised, commercially used form of Ethernet, and today, almost the entire Internet is Ethernet, but heck, who’s ever actually seen a working 10BASE5 setup? Not me, that’s for sure, nor or anyone I’ve ever met.</p>
<p>So… can I build a working setup in 2012? Read on…</p>

<p>I’ve written this page primarily for people like myself, who came into the computing scene just a bit too late to have ever seen this technology in use. A 1980s network engineer can safely skip this page.</p>

<p>In order to connect to a true 10BASE5 network, network adapters with AUI are required. AUI stands for Attachment Unit Interface. It is in effect, a media independent form of all of the physical 10Mbit ethernet variants, which I shall call 10BASE-X. AUI was to 10BASE-X what MII is to 100BASE-X, with the exception that MII is rarely found as an external connector.</p>
<p>Unfortunately for this project, networking equipment with external AUI connectors is becoming rather difficult to find.</p>
<p>As I see it, there’s 2 options:</p>
<ul>
<li>Build true 10BASE5 nodes using equipment natively supporting AUI</li>
<li>Bridge to something else i.e. 10BASE-T</li>
</ul>
<h2>Building true 10BASE5 nodes</h2>
<p>Not many options remain for connecting to modern PCs. Here’s a few:</p>
<h3>ISA Cards</h3>
<p>While this can be done, modern mainboards with ISA slots are niche and very expensive. I ruled out this option.</p>
<p><a href="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c509.jpg"><img src="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c509.jpg" alt="3c509" width="717" height="453" srcset="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c509.jpg 717w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c509-150x95.jpg 150w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c509-300x190.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 717px) 100vw, 717px"></a></p>

<h3>PCI Cards</h3>
<p>Fortunately, some modern PCs still have 32-Bit/5 volt parallel PCI slots, also, PCI and 10BASE5 had enough overlap that a small number of products were manufactured. A couple of examples are the 3Com 3C900B-COMBO, and 3C905B-COMBO. At the time of writing there were a fair few of these on eBay, but often for outrageous sums of money. Fortunately I managed to pick up a couple for a few quid. 64-Bit Windows drivers do not exist, making Windows 7 32-bit likely the last version of Windows able to make use of them, short of writing some new drivers. All versions of Linux will work OK with these.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1354" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1354"><a href="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c900-cmb.jpg"><img src="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c900-cmb.jpg" alt="3Com 3c900-COMBO NIC" width="2575" height="1615" srcset="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c900-cmb.jpg 2575w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c900-cmb-150x94.jpg 150w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c900-cmb-300x188.jpg 300w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c900-cmb-768x482.jpg 768w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/3c900-cmb-800x502.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 2575px) 100vw, 2575px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1354">3Com 3c900-COMBO NIC With AUI Connector</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_32" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-32"><a href="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/10BASE5Node.jpg"><img src="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/10BASE5Node-800x600.jpg" alt="10BASE5 Node" width="474" height="356" srcset="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/10BASE5Node-800x600.jpg 800w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/10BASE5Node-150x113.jpg 150w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/10BASE5Node-300x225.jpg 300w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/10BASE5Node.jpg 1113w" sizes="(max-width: 474px) 100vw, 474px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-32">A true 10BASE5 node. Using a 3Com 3c905B-COMBO NIC with AUI</figcaption></figure>
<h3>USB or other solutions</h3>
<p>As far as I can tell no USB product was ever made. With 10BASE5 MAU’s requiring 12 volts and some 5 or more watts of power, over and above what USB can provide, this would be a problematic proposition. Also, no single chip “USB with AUI” solutions exist. From my research, it seems theoretically possible to create a 2-chip adapter, with external power supply, but apparently there is no market for such as a thing.</p>
<figure id="attachment_71" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71"><a href="http://tech.mattmillman.com/projects/usbaui/"><img src="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/axaui_proto_tn-800x534.jpg" alt="USB AUI Ethernet adapter proof of concept, based on a D-Link DUB-E100, NQ8502 connected to MII" width="474" height="316" srcset="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/axaui_proto_tn-800x534.jpg 800w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/axaui_proto_tn-150x100.jpg 150w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/axaui_proto_tn-300x200.jpg 300w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/axaui_proto_tn.jpg 880w" sizes="(max-width: 474px) 100vw, 474px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-71">A D-Link DUB-E100 with its 100BASE-TX PHY removed, and an NQ8502 frankensteined in its place.<br> This image illustrates my key design objective: To give an AUI interface to a USB Ethernet MAC, instead of converting from 10BASE-T.</figcaption></figure>
<p>But that didn’t stop me from building one. Above is what is quite possibly one of the worlds only USB Ethernet Adapters with AUI interface. I have a seperate project page for this&nbsp;<a href="http://tech.mattmillman.com/usbaui/">here</a>.</p>
<h3>Routers</h3>
<p>A Cisco NM-1E2W module could be used if one has a large ISR kicking around.</p>
<h2>Bridging 10BASE5 to modern twisted pair networks</h2>
<h3>10BASE-T Hubs equipped with AUI</h3>
<p>Using a 10BASE-T hub with AUI to bridge to a twisted pair network is probably the easiest approach. There’s thousands of these for sale on eBay for peanuts, but in my case, having one of these on each node would make the setup rather clunky.</p>
<h3>10BASE-T to AUI Media converters</h3>
<p>What I was really looking for was a few of these little boxes. Easily mistaken for a 10BASE-T MAU, these (unlike the former which tend to be spilling out of every I.T. junk box in the land) are fairly uncommon.</p>
<figure id="attachment_17" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17"><a href="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/MC12T.jpg"><img src="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/MC12T-800x475.jpg" alt="Allied Telesis MC12T" width="474" height="281" srcset="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/MC12T-800x475.jpg 800w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/MC12T-150x89.jpg 150w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/MC12T-300x178.jpg 300w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/MC12T.jpg 872w" sizes="(max-width: 474px) 100vw, 474px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17">An Allied Telesis MC12T next to an ordinary 10BASE-T MAU. Spot the difference?</figcaption></figure>

<p>To keep the cost of this project to a minimum, I decided my network would only have 3-4 nodes as this was sufficient to demonstrate a proper shared media network as opposed to a 2 node effective “point to point” link. For this I sourced the following components:</p>
<ul>
<li>2x 3Com 3C900B-COMBO PCI NICs with AUI</li>
<li>3x MiLAN MIL-130A AUI-to-10BASE-T bridges</li>
<li>1x MiLAN MIL-10P 10BASE-T Transceiver (for testing AUI nodes)</li>
<li>1x Allied Telesis MC12T</li>
<li>6x Cabletron ST-500 MAU’s</li>
<li>3x AMP 228752-1 Vampire taps</li>
<li>2x AMP 221914-1 Intrusive N connector taps</li>
<li>5x AUI Drop cables</li>
<li>15M of Belden #9880 cable</li>
<li>2x 50ohm N terminators</li>
<li>2x N female to female couplers</li>
<li>10x UNC 4-40 x 1.1/2″ countersunk screws (to replace missing ones on my MAUs)</li>
</ul>

<p>A common belief persists that 10BASE5 used RG-8/U cable. This, for the most part, appears to be untrue. The cable used was purpose designed for 10BASE5 and manufactured by Belden under the part number 9880 (A few other compatible cables may exist). The reason #9880 cable was specified is that several variants of RG-8 exist with varying dimensions and manufacturing standards. Given that the main form of connection of MAU’s to 10BASE5 networks was by the precisely designed prongs in “Vampire taps”, cable dimensions and dielectric consistency had to be spot on.</p>
<p>A network designed using only intrusive N connector taps such as AMP 221914-1 could get away with using pretty much any 50 ohm coax, but then the sum total of insertion losses created by each node may prevent the full 500M segment length from being achieved. Also, this approach wouldn’t permit addition of new nodes without bringing down the network. After an evening of wrestling with RG-8/U cable (why oh why didn’t I just buy RG-58) while attempting to make a short test lead, I think I’ll stick with the Vampire Taps.</p>
<p>For someone like me who hadn’t encountered it before, no amount of looking at pictures could prepare for how big this stuff is. Short of high power transmission cables, it’s the largest coaxial cable I’ve ever seen. It is also very heavy, rigid and the bend radius is absurdly large.</p>
<p>Another interesting feature of this cable is the black bands which appear every 2.5M. In 10BASE5 networks, MAUs can only be attached at 2.5M intervals, this is to ensure that signal reflections generated by taps stay out of phase, which stops them compounding across the whole segment. In a small network such as mine, it’s probably not so important to respect this tap placement rule, but I’ll respect it anyway.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1325" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1325"><a href="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/BELDEN_9880.jpg"><img src="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/BELDEN_9880-800x423.jpg" alt="Belden 9880" width="474" height="251" srcset="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/BELDEN_9880-800x423.jpg 800w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/BELDEN_9880-150x79.jpg 150w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/BELDEN_9880-300x159.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 474px) 100vw, 474px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1325">Belden 9880 next to standard CAT5E cable. Either side of this frame is 10 kilos of steel, about the minimum required to hold this stuff down for the photo</figcaption></figure>

<p>Unlike the BNC connectors found on 10BASE2, the official connector used by 10BASE5 (where connectors are required) is the N connector. While still used extensively in lab/specialist environments, this large coaxial connector isn’t something the average ‘tech dude’ is likely to encounter these days. They perform exceptionally, have an intrinsic impedance of 50 ohms, are fairly common/inexpensive and easily handle the large sized #9880 cable.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1324" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1324"><a href="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/N.jpg"><img src="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/N-800x449.jpg" alt="10BASE5 N connectors" width="474" height="266" srcset="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/N-800x449.jpg 800w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/N-150x84.jpg 150w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/N-300x169.jpg 300w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/N.jpg 1789w" sizes="(max-width: 474px) 100vw, 474px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1324">N Connector and joiner with CAT5E patch cable for comparison</figcaption></figure>

<p>These cables sporting male and female 15-pin D-sub connectors, connect a node to the MAU. Since the MAU is bolted to a rigid behemoth piece of coax, it wasn’t exactly convenient to try and drag that lot down to the back of a PC, so these cables bridged that gap. With a maximum length of 50 metres, that gap can be very large indeed. Also, given that taps could only be placed at 2.5M intervals, a world without drop cables would lend its self to much humour around the office, at the expense of well-intended PC and desk placement considerations.</p>
<p>One notable feature is the slide locking mechanism used in place of the usual UNC 4-40 screws. It is my personal opinion that the design of this mechanism is a bit daft. In theory it’s a good idea but in practice I think it was implemented too flimsily. AUI drop cables are often very large and rigid (likely thanks to a half a dozen layers of shielding), so much so that a mild sideways nudge on a cable can easily rip a latched connector straight out of the socket, bending/breaking the mechanism. They also have a feature that the screws in the female end often work their way out over time, inevitably to be lost forever. Even during this small scale project, I have suffered some grief over these locking mechanisms. I can imagine they were a source of many support calls in the 80s and early 90s.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1322" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1322"><a href="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/AUI_DROP.jpg"><img src="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/AUI_DROP-800x447.jpg" alt="1M AUI drop cable" width="474" height="265" srcset="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/AUI_DROP-800x447.jpg 800w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/AUI_DROP-150x84.jpg 150w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/AUI_DROP-300x168.jpg 300w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/AUI_DROP.jpg 1605w" sizes="(max-width: 474px) 100vw, 474px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1322">AUI drop cable, with a one-up-from-useless slide locking mechanism</figcaption></figure>

<p>These metal boxes are one of the key defining pieces of kit in a 10BASE5 network. They function as the transceiver, converting the primitive signals from the AUI interface to what’s required on the physical media, as well as performing collision detection. They came in 4 flavours:</p>
<ul>
<li>With a tap for 10BASE5 networks, using a Vampire Tap</li>
<li>With a tap for 10BASE5 networks, using N connectors (Rare)</li>
<li>With a tap for 10BASE2 networks, using BNC connectors</li>
<li>Without a tap (Buy your own)</li>
</ul>
<p>I chose Cabletron ST-500’s, because they have blinky lights. The ST-500 (90 Series) would have been one of the last and most modern 10BASE5 MAUs manufactured. The internal component count (when compared with, say, a DEC h4000) is low.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1314" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1314"><a href="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/ST500-01.jpg"><img src="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/ST500-01-800x542.jpg" alt="Cabletron ST500-01" width="474" height="321" srcset="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/ST500-01-800x542.jpg 800w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/ST500-01-150x102.jpg 150w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/ST500-01-300x203.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 474px) 100vw, 474px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1314">Cabletron ST500-01</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_1315" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1315"><a href="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/ST500-02a.jpg"><img src="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/ST500-02a-800x659.jpg" alt="" width="474" height="390" srcset="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/ST500-02a-800x659.jpg 800w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/ST500-02a-150x124.jpg 150w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/ST500-02a-300x247.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 474px) 100vw, 474px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1315">Cabletron ST500-02</figcaption></figure>

<p>By far the most common means of connection to the coax segment. The bottom half is plastic, I assume to eliminate ground loops by ensuring the braid remains electrically isolated from the metal case of the MAU. The top half is extruded aluminium. Each contains three prongs (two to connect to the braid, and one to the centre conductor). To me, the idea of using this style of connection to coaxial cable is ambitious, but it has to be said that a few spikes in a coaxial cable will equate to significantly less reflection and insertion loss …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://tech.mattmillman.com/projects/10base5/">http://tech.mattmillman.com/projects/10base5/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://tech.mattmillman.com/projects/10base5/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24807542</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 04:47:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What they don’t tell you about demand paging in school]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 69 | Comments 22 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24806246">thread link</a>) | @luu
<br/>
October 16, 2020 | https://offlinemark.com/2020/10/14/demand-paging/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://offlinemark.com/2020/10/14/demand-paging/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			
<p>This post details my adventures with the Linux virtual memory subsystem, and my discovery of a creative way to taunt the OOM (out of memory) killer by accumulating memory in the kernel, rather than in userspace.</p>



<p>Keep reading and you’ll learn:</p>



<ul><li>Internal details of the Linux kernel’s demand paging implementation</li><li>How to exploit virtual memory to implement highly efficient sparse data structures</li><li>What page tables are and how to calculate the memory overhead incurred by them</li><li>A cute way to get killed by the OOM killer while appearing to consume very little memory (great for parties)</li></ul>



<h2>Part 1: Demand paging is nuanced</h2>



<p>As usual, the story begins with me asking questions about implementation details. This time, about the Linux kernel’s demand paging implementation.</p>



<p>In Operating Systems 101 we learn that operating systems are “lazy” when they allocate memory to processes. When you mmap() an anonymous page, the kernel slyly returns a pointer immediately. It then waits until you trigger a page fault by “touching” that memory before doing the real memory allocation work. This is called “demand paging”.</p>



<p>This is efficient — if the memory is never touched, no physical memory is ever allocated. This also means you can allocate virtual memory in vast excess of what is physically available (“overcommit”), which can be useful.<span id="easy-footnote-1-496"></span><span><a href="#easy-footnote-bottom-1-496" title="Some examples of applications that allocate immense virtual memory are Address Sanitizer and Webkit."><sup>1</sup></a></span>. You just can’t touch it all.</p>



<p>Let’s dive deeper. Barring execution, “touching” memory means reading or writing. Writes to a new mmap’d region require the kernel to perform a full memory allocation. You need memory, you need it <em>now</em>, and the kernel can’t push it off any longer.</p>



<p>Now, the question: <strong>What about reads?</strong></p>



<p>Unlike writes, reads to a new mmap’d region do <em>not</em> trigger a memory allocation. The kernel continues to push off the allocation by exploiting how new anonymous mappings must be zero initialized. Instead of allocating memory, the kernel services the page fault using the “zero page”: a pre-allocated page of physical memory, completely filled with zeros. In theory this is “free” — a single physical frame can back all zero-initialized pages.</p>



<p>The point? <strong>Demand paging is nuanced — not all ways of accessing a new mapping require the kernel to allocate memory</strong>.</p>



<p>Let’s see what this looks like in the <a href="https://elixir.bootlin.com/linux/v5.8.12/source/mm/memory.c#L4191">source</a>. The core page fault handler, <code>handle_mm_fault</code> is in <code>mm/memory.c</code>. A few calls deep via <code>__handle_mm_fault</code> and <code>handle_pte_fault</code>, we hit this block:</p>



<div><pre data-lang="C"><code>static vm_fault_t handle_pte_fault(struct vm_fault *vmf)
{
	// ...

	if (!vmf-&gt;pte) {
		if (vma_is_anonymous(vmf-&gt;vma))
			return do_anonymous_page(vmf);
		else
			// ...
	}

	// ...
}</code></pre></div>



<p>Which leads us to <code>do_anonymous_page</code> — the core page fault handler for anonymous pages. </p>



<div><pre data-lang="C"><code>static vm_fault_t do_anonymous_page(struct vm_fault *vmf)
{
	// ...
	
	if (pte_alloc(vma-&gt;vm_mm, vmf-&gt;pmd))
		return VM_FAULT_OOM;
	// ...

	/* Use the zero-page for reads */
	if (!(vmf-&gt;flags &amp; FAULT_FLAG_WRITE) &amp;&amp; // (1)
			!mm_forbids_zeropage(vma-&gt;vm_mm)) {
		entry = pte_mkspecial(pfn_pte(my_zero_pfn(vmf-&gt;address), // (2)
						vma-&gt;vm_page_prot));
		vmf-&gt;pte = pte_offset_map_lock(vma-&gt;vm_mm, vmf-&gt;pmd,
				vmf-&gt;address, &amp;vmf-&gt;ptl);
		// ...
		goto setpte;
	}
	// ...
setpte:
	set_pte_at(vma-&gt;vm_mm, vmf-&gt;address, vmf-&gt;pte, entry); // (3)
	// ...
	return ret;

	// ...
}</code></pre></div>



<p>Bingo. It checks whether a read caused the fault (1), then maps the virtual page to the zero page (2 and 3).</p>



<p>Note that this all happens in the page fault handler, which is an implementation choice. The mmap <a href="https://elixir.bootlin.com/linux/v5.8.12/source/mm/mmap.c#L1687">core logic</a> does not touch the page tables at all, and only records the presence of the new mapping. It leaves the mapping’s page table entry non-present (present bit = 0) which will trigger a page fault on access.</p>



<p>Alternatively, mmap could proactively allocate the page table entry, and initialize it to the zero page. This would avoid a page fault on the first read, but at the cost of initializing (potentially many) page table entries up front. Given that it’s most efficient to be maximally lazy, the current implementation is best.</p>



<h2>Part 2: Allocating infinite memory, and touching it too</h2>



<p>This led me to another question. Since reads from anonymous mappings are “free”, in addition to allocating excessive virtual memory, can’t you actually touch all of it? As long as that “touch” is a read?</p>



<p>Time for an experiment. Here’s some code that allocates 100 GB of linear memory, and tries to read from the first byte of each page. It allocates 512 MB at a time because I <a href="https://twitter.com/damageboy/status/1317676450393300994">incorrectly thought</a> you couldn’t mmap 100GB at once <s>you can’t directly ask mmap for 100 GB 🙂</s>.<span id="easy-footnote-2-496"></span><span><a href="#easy-footnote-bottom-2-496" title="Thanks to <a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/damageboy&quot;>@damageboy</a> for pointing this out."><sup>2</sup></a></span><span id="easy-footnote-3-496"></span><span><a href="#easy-footnote-bottom-3-496" title="This is lazy, dirty research code :) It is not sound or portable, and only just works because Linux happens to place the mmaps contiguously, growing down in memory."><sup>3</sup></a></span> My test system was a x64 Ubuntu 20.04 VPS.</p>



<div><pre data-lang="C++"><code>#include &lt;sys/mman.h&gt;
#include &lt;iostream&gt;

const size_t MB = 1024 * 1024;
const size_t GB = MB * 1024;

int main() {
  size_t alloc_size = 512 * MB;
  size_t total_alloc = 100 * GB;
  size_t num_allocs = total_alloc / alloc_size;

  // std::cout &lt;&lt; "alloc_size (MB)" &lt;&lt; alloc_size / (1024*1024)&lt;&lt; "\n";
  // std::cout &lt;&lt; "total_alloc " &lt;&lt; total_alloc &lt;&lt; "\n";
  // std::cout &lt;&lt; "num_allocs " &lt;&lt; num_allocs &lt;&lt; "\n";

  std::cout &lt;&lt; "Allocating mem...\n";

  char* base = nullptr;

  // Allocate a ton of memory
  for (size_t i = 0; i &lt; num_allocs; i++) {
    // Unsound alert - assuming allocations are contiguous and grow down.
    base = (char*)mmap(NULL, alloc_size, PROT_READ, MAP_PRIVATE | MAP_ANONYMOUS, -1, 0);
    if (base == MAP_FAILED) {
      perror(NULL);
      throw std::runtime_error("Fail");
    }
    std::cout &lt;&lt; (void*)base &lt;&lt; " " &lt;&lt; i &lt;&lt; "\n";
  }

  std::cout &lt;&lt; "Allocated Virtual Mem (GB): " &lt;&lt; total_alloc / GB &lt;&lt; "\n";
  std::cout &lt;&lt; "Base Addr: " &lt;&lt; (void*)base &lt;&lt; "\n";
  std::cout &lt;&lt; "Press enter to start reading.\n";
  getchar();
  std::cout &lt;&lt; "Reading each page...\n";

  // Read the first byte of each page
  for (size_t i = 0; i &lt; total_alloc; i += 0x1000) {
    auto x = base[i];
  }

  std::cout &lt;&lt; "Done!\n";
  getchar();
}</code></pre></div>



<p>When we run it, here’s what we see:</p>



<div><pre data-lang="Bash"><code>$ ./demo
Allocating mem...
0x7f3f6d300000 1
0x7f3f4d300000 2
0x7f3f2d300000 3
...
0x7f26cd300000 198
0x7f26ad300000 199
0x7f268d300000 200
Allocated Virtual Mem (GB): 100
Base Addr: 0x7f268d300000
Press enter to start reading.</code></pre></div>



<p>It successfully allocated 100 GB of linear virtual memory in 512 MB chunks. We can confirm this with <code>pmap</code>, which shows a 100GB region of anonymous virtual memory at the base address printed.</p>



<div><pre><code>$ pmap `pidof demo`
485209:   ./demo
00005600e1d0c000      4K r---- demo
00005600e1d0d000      4K r-x-- demo
00005600e1d0e000      4K r---- demo
00005600e1d0f000      4K r---- demo
00005600e1d10000      4K rw--- demo
00005600e2a47000    132K rw---   [ anon ]
00007f268d300000 104857600K r----   [ anon ] &lt;&lt;&lt;&lt; 100 GB region
00007f3f8d300000     16K rw---   [ anon ]
00007f3f8d304000     60K r---- libm-2.31.so
00007f3f8d313000    668K r-x-- libm-2.31.so
...</code></pre></div>



<p>What does htop say?</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="625" height="87" src="https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=625%2C87&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=1024%2C142&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=300%2C42&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=768%2C107&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=1536%2C213&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=624%2C87&amp;ssl=1 624w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?w=1916&amp;ssl=1 1916w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?w=1250&amp;ssl=1 1250w" sizes="(max-width: 625px) 100vw, 625px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=1024%2C142&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=300%2C42&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=768%2C107&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=1536%2C213&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=624%2C87&amp;ssl=1 624w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?w=1916&amp;ssl=1 1916w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?w=1250&amp;ssl=1 1250w" data-lazy-src="https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-9.png?resize=625%2C87&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure>



<p>htop confirms that 100 GB of virtual memory is allocated (VIRT column), but a much more reasonable 1540 KB of resident memory (RES) is actually occupying RAM. Note the MINFLT column — this is the number of “minor” page faults that have occurred. A minor page fault is one that does not require loading from disk. We will be triggering lots of these and should expect to see this number grow dramatically.</p>



<p>Here’s what happens after I press enter to trigger reading.</p>



<div><pre><code>0x7f26cd300000 198
0x7f26ad300000 199
0x7f268d300000 200
Allocated Virtual Mem (GB): 100
Base Addr: 0x7f268d300000
Press enter to start reading.

Reading each page...
Done!</code></pre></div>



<p>The process hits the “Done!” print. This means it successfully touched every page of the 100 GB allocation!</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="625" height="79" src="https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=625%2C79&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=1024%2C130&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=300%2C38&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=768%2C98&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=1536%2C195&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=624%2C79&amp;ssl=1 624w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?w=1888&amp;ssl=1 1888w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?w=1250&amp;ssl=1 1250w" sizes="(max-width: 625px) 100vw, 625px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=1024%2C130&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=300%2C38&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=768%2C98&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=1536%2C195&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=624%2C79&amp;ssl=1 624w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?w=1888&amp;ssl=1 1888w, https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?w=1250&amp;ssl=1 1250w" data-lazy-src="https://i0.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-10.png?resize=625%2C79&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure>



<p>htop confirms that many minor faults have occurred. We would expect it to cause exactly 26214400 faults (100 GB / 4 KB), and indeed, 26214552 – 26214400 = 152, the number we started with. Intriguingly, the resident memory appears to have also increased, which should not have happened. See the <a href="#rss-spike">Appendix A</a> for discussion of this.</p>



<p>Here’s a video to see it all in action:</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Allocating 100 GB and touching it all (Demand Paging Pt 1)" width="625" height="469" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HYNMt6FWsI4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p><strong>So the theory is confirmed! You can apparently “Allocate your memory, and touch it too” (as long as that touch is a read).</strong><span id="easy-footnote-4-496"></span><span><a href="#easy-footnote-bottom-4-496" title="Or if you prefer, the famous Henry Ford <a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/23494-any-customer-can-have-a-car-painted-any-colour-that&quot;>quote</a>:  &amp;#8220;You can touch as much memory as you want, as long as you are only reading&amp;#8221;."><sup>4</sup></a></span></p>



<p>If your application, for some reason, benefits from the ability to have a 100 GB array of zeros then this is perfect for you. What about the rest of us?</p>



<p>A closer-to-real-life application is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sparse_matrix">sparse array</a>. A sparse array is a (typically very large) array, whose elements are mostly zero. By exploiting demand paging, you can implement a memory efficient sparse array, where the majority of the array is backed by the zero page (or not even mapped). You get the fast indexing benefits of an array while avoiding the memory overhead.</p>



<h2>Part 3: Playing with a killer</h2>



<p>I have a confession. Remember when I said not all ways of accessing memory require the kernel to allocate memory? Yeah, that’s a lie.</p>



<p>Even though a read can be serviced by the shared zero page, that doesn’t mean no memory is allocated. Even the process of mapping a zero page requires allocating  memory. And here’s where we get into the nitty gritty.</p>



<h3>The hidden overhead of page tables</h3>



<p>The overhead comes from the virtual memory infrastructure itself — the page tables. Page tables are data structures that power the virtual memory subsystem. Like regular data structures, they occupy memory, only their overhead is easy to overlook, since it’s hidden from userspace.</p>



<p>This is what page tables on x86_64 look like:</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="625" height="463" src="https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?resize=625%2C463&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?resize=1024%2C758&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?resize=300%2C222&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?resize=768%2C568&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?resize=624%2C462&amp;ssl=1 624w, https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?w=1276&amp;ssl=1 1276w" sizes="(max-width: 625px) 100vw, 625px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?resize=1024%2C758&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?resize=300%2C222&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?resize=768%2C568&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?resize=624%2C462&amp;ssl=1 624w, https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?w=1276&amp;ssl=1 1276w" data-lazy-src="https://i1.wp.com/offlinemark.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/image-11.png?resize=625%2C463&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><figcaption>x86_64 Page Tables: Intel Manual Vol 3A Chapter 4.5</figcaption></figure>



<p>They’re a tree data structure that is 4 levels deep, with each node (table) being an array of 512 8-byte entries. Together these tables offer an efficient way to represent a mapping between every virtual page in the address space and a physical frame.</p>



<p>Here’s where the overhead comes from. Each page touched requires 1 Page Table Entry (PTE) to be allocated. However, PTEs aren’t allocated individually. They’re allocated in blocks of 512 called Page Tables. Each Page Table requires 1 Page Directory Entry to be allocated. But …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://offlinemark.com/2020/10/14/demand-paging/">https://offlinemark.com/2020/10/14/demand-paging/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://offlinemark.com/2020/10/14/demand-paging/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24806246</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 00:09:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
