<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 5]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 5. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 12:29:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-5.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 12:29:54 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why I Link to WayBackMachine Instead of Original Web Content]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 137 | Comments 82 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24406193">thread link</a>) | @puggo
<br/>
September 8, 2020 | https://hawaiigentech.com/post/commentary/why-i-link-to-waybackmachine-instead/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://hawaiigentech.com/post/commentary/why-i-link-to-waybackmachine-instead/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main">
      <div>
        <div id="content">
          <article>
    
    

    
    <div>
      <p><img src="https://hawaiigentech.com/post/commentary/why-i-link-to-waybackmachine-instead/wayback.jpg" alt="WayBackMachine"></p>
<hr>
<p>When linking to a page for the <strong>purpose of reference</strong>, it seems better to me to <em><strong>link to the <a href="https://archive.org/">archive</a> of a given page</strong></em>, rather than to the original site itself.</p>
<p>This ensures that after some years have gone by, <strong>my article is guaranteed to be consistent</strong>. Due the  changing nature of the web, there is a chance that after some years, the link could lead to a:</p>
<ul>
<li>404 /  Not Found (most common)</li>
<li>Changed or edited content, or entirely replaced content</li>
<li>Content that, due to a rise in popularity, is now shielded, demanding the user to make an account to read the entire article.</li>
</ul>
<hr>

<p>Take defensive measures. To future-proof your content, rather than reference the general web, its far more reliable to link to an archive.</p>
<h2 id="example">Example:</h2>
<p>The Epoch Times wrote an article on Smartphones data-mining their users. This is the archived article here:</p>
<p><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20190214015500/https://www.theepochtimes.com/smartphone-app-users-are-data-mined-even-when-not-using-the-apps_2787202.html">The Archive Version (fully readable)</a></p>
<h3 id="article-content-before">Article Content Before</h3>
<p>You can see its perfectly “normal” readable useful  content.</p>
<p><img src="https://hawaiigentech.com/post/commentary/why-i-link-to-waybackmachine-instead/link-content-before.png" alt="Article Link Content Before"></p>
<h3 id="article-content-after">Article Content After</h3>
<p>Now it’s spam from a site suffering financial need.</p>
<p><img src="https://hawaiigentech.com/post/commentary/why-i-link-to-waybackmachine-instead/link-content-after.png" alt="Article Link Content Before"></p>
<p>So in Feb 14 2019 your users would have seen the content you intended. However in Sep 07 2020, your users are being asked to support independent Journalism instead.</p>
<h2 id="if-an-archive-record-doesnt-exist-make-one">If an Archive Record Doesn't Exist, Make One</h2>
<p>Its worth the extra moment, in referencing a site, to make an archive of the page you wish to reference, if one does not exist. After that, immediately use the link from the archive.org entry, rather than the blog, news, info, or forum site you wish to refer to.</p>
<h2 id="in-unstable-times-take-measures-for-stability">In Unstable Times, Take Measures for Stability</h2>
<p>The web is a fast changing place. Even more during the Covid pandemic and suffering financial markets. Since times are financially harder, websites are disappearing, heaping up advertising, demanding user response, and things like this.</p>
<p>To avoid your content losing quality due to these things, linking to a solid, unchanging static copy of the page is far more reliable.</p>

    </div>

    <div>
  <p>
    <span>Author</span>
    <span>Leo Blanchette</span>
  </p>
  <p>
    <span>LastMod</span>
    <span>
        2020-09-07
        
    </span>
  </p>
  
  
</div>

  </article>
        </div>
        

  

  

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://hawaiigentech.com/post/commentary/why-i-link-to-waybackmachine-instead/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24406193</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 08:03:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why Past Attempts of Software Metrics Have Failed Us]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 9 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24406030">thread link</a>) | @abyx
<br/>
September 8, 2020 | https://www.usehaystack.io/blog/software-development-metrics-pros-cons-and-why-past-attempts-have-failed | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.usehaystack.io/blog/software-development-metrics-pros-cons-and-why-past-attempts-have-failed">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-w-id="0ea0c8ae-8333-a516-8908-f86a85ef9373"><p>TLDR; Software engineering is a black box. It's incredibly complex and nuanced. The industry makes attempts to stack rank and measure via simplified metrics. This is the wrong approach and hurts engineering culture. Software is complex, previous attempts don't take that into account. There is a better solution.</p><p>‍</p><p><strong>Software engineering is a black box because</strong></p><ol role="list"><li><a href="https://www.notion.so/usehaystack/Articles-f56dc18398104dca8534fc1e1ddd4ff2#990eff2e60e346b282c47abcb5687b96" target="_blank">Software engineering is complex and invisible</a></li><li><a href="https://www.notion.so/usehaystack/Articles-f56dc18398104dca8534fc1e1ddd4ff2#d32d356b92594f6cbb8a4993cdf1c2d0" target="_blank">The output of software development varies</a></li></ol><p>‍</p><p><strong>There have been several attempts at quantifying developer productivity. The limited content you'll find fits into a few categories.</strong></p><ol role="list"><li><a href="https://www.notion.so/usehaystack/Articles-f56dc18398104dca8534fc1e1ddd4ff2#128c578b6c9c489d8c53525166e0f932" target="_blank">KPIs used to measure software engineer performance</a></li><li><a href="https://www.notion.so/usehaystack/Articles-f56dc18398104dca8534fc1e1ddd4ff2#8d31dd02f20a42a6b1b586b955207ce4" target="_blank">Methods of measuring developer performance and their fall backs</a></li><li><a href="https://www.notion.so/usehaystack/Articles-f56dc18398104dca8534fc1e1ddd4ff2#dbf2216d7f134396bcfe69185e96c1a9" target="_blank">Opinion pieces on if measurement is even possible</a></li></ol><p>‍</p><p><strong>You'll notice a pattern prevalent in the space. The industry is obsessed with finding</strong></p><ol role="list"><li>Golden metrics to stack rank and compare teams and individuals.</li><li>KPIs to objectively determine an engineer's performance.</li></ol><p>‍</p><p><strong>The result?</strong></p><p>Attempts to measure software engineer and team productivity using the same, simplified metrics and KPIs.</p><p>‍</p><p><strong>But that's the wrong approach..</strong></p><ol role="list"><li><a href="https://www.notion.so/usehaystack/Articles-f56dc18398104dca8534fc1e1ddd4ff2#5f58624ed1f6432087fa3ef21378cf0b" target="_blank">Attempting to stack rank is fundamentally flawed</a></li><li><a href="https://www.notion.so/usehaystack/Articles-f56dc18398104dca8534fc1e1ddd4ff2#447680dd5e204f8a8bb526db55ebbe5c" target="_blank">'Successful outcomes' are situational</a></li><li><a href="https://www.notion.so/usehaystack/Articles-f56dc18398104dca8534fc1e1ddd4ff2#ea18251c7c0a4d50a1eb57e1e34f7ff8" target="_blank">Simplified metrics hurt engineering culture</a></li></ol><p>‍</p><p><strong>Focus on productivity, not yard sticks</strong></p><ol role="list"><li><a href="https://www.notion.so/usehaystack/Articles-f56dc18398104dca8534fc1e1ddd4ff2#c685ee9fc42c4c678d86b85f01006df8" target="_blank">Measure engineers and teams independently</a></li><li><a href="https://www.notion.so/usehaystack/Articles-f56dc18398104dca8534fc1e1ddd4ff2#dcd2a669df6a4e97afa9ec24e25fbc14" target="_blank">Compare relative to individual history</a></li><li><a href="https://www.notion.so/usehaystack/Articles-f56dc18398104dca8534fc1e1ddd4ff2#b0b75fb866ee44d29f9a5862be9e2579" target="_blank">Identify the main risks and bottlenecks of productivity</a></li></ol><p>‍</p><p><strong>Why is this better?</strong></p><ol role="list"><li><a href="https://www.notion.so/usehaystack/Footnotes-f56dc18398104dca8534fc1e1ddd4ff2#95433ef2f1cb46c5ac5b116b3221ac69" target="_blank">Accurately measures productivity</a></li><li><a href="https://www.notion.so/usehaystack/Articles-f56dc18398104dca8534fc1e1ddd4ff2#f20c40f07837457ea2dc431fbbeb4c6c" target="_blank">Handles situational outcomes</a></li><li><a href="https://www.notion.so/usehaystack/Articles-f56dc18398104dca8534fc1e1ddd4ff2#0f37d98374d64ea3a76d2b179cc16a74" target="_blank">Supports engineering culture</a></li><li><a href="https://www.notion.so/usehaystack/Footnotes-f56dc18398104dca8534fc1e1ddd4ff2#d09f4a9a554643139c1c3d9f0987e1a4" target="_blank">Enables early risk identification</a></li></ol><p>‍</p><p><strong>Main takeaway:</strong></p><p>From the nature of the work to the culture that supports it, engineering is incredibly complex and nuanced. Previous attempts at measuring engineering performance have done a poor job of taking this complexity into account. Making attempts to measure each engineer and team against the same yard stick not only hurts culture, but gives no true indication of productivity to begin with.</p><p>‍</p><p>To date, the industry has been attempting this 'holy grail' of software development metrics from the wrong perspective. By focusing on drivers and blockers of productivity rather than KPIs and stack ranking; we can start to measure engineers and teams in a healthy way. More importantly, this new perspective enables engineering leaders to introduce a software development metrics to help improve while maintaining the highest impact driver of productivity (culture).</p><p>‍</p><p>Check out Haystack's approach <a href="https://usehaystack.io/">here</a>!</p><figure><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5ed57622ee14fb96d022d544/5ef130052901e5cad8432b81_Haystack_Designed_Presentation.png" alt=""></p></figure><p><a href="https://usehaystack.io/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=3%20git%20signals%20to%20identify%20blockers&amp;utm_campaign=inside%20blog">Haystack</a> helps engineering leaders identify blockers and trends. Directly from Github. Instead of guessing if you're improving, or constantly bothering your team for progress updates, simply use Haystack to get alerts in your inbox every morning. Plus a dashboard to track improvements over time.</p><p><a href="https://usehaystack.io/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=3%20git%20signals%20to%20identify%20blockers&amp;utm_campaign=inside%20blog">Try it for free</a></p><p>‍</p><p>‍</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.usehaystack.io/blog/software-development-metrics-pros-cons-and-why-past-attempts-have-failed</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24406030</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 07:32:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Escape from creek fire]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 21 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24405981">thread link</a>) | @twohey
<br/>
September 8, 2020 | https://www.jmeshe.co/escape-from-creek-fire | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.jmeshe.co/escape-from-creek-fire">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<div>
<p><span>
By subscribing to the mailing list of
<strong>
Jaymie Shearer
</strong>
your email address is stored securely, opted into new post notifications and related communications. We respect your inbox and privacy, you may unsubscribe at any time.
</span></p><div>
<p><a href="https://www.exposure.co/privacy" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Link to Jaymie Shearer Privacy Policy">
Privacy Policy
</a>
<a href="https://www.exposure.co/terms" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Link to Jaymie Shearer Terms of Service">
Terms of Service
</a>
<a href="https://www.exposure.co/report" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Report a story or story">
Report
</a>
</p></div>

</div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.jmeshe.co/escape-from-creek-fire</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24405981</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 07:22:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[URL query parameters and how laxness creates de facto requirements on the web]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 60 | Comments 46 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24404814">thread link</a>) | @oftenwrong
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/web/DeFactoQueryParameters | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/web/DeFactoQueryParameters">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2>URL query parameters and how laxness creates de facto requirements on the web</h2>

	<p><small>September  7, 2020</small></p>
</div><div><p>One of the ways that <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/dwiki/DWiki">DWiki</a> (the code behind <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/">Wandering Thoughts</a>) is unusual is that it strictly validates the query parameters
it receives on URLs, including on HTTP <code>GET</code> requests for ordinary
pages. If a HTTP request has unexpected and unsupported query
parameters, such a <code>GET</code> request will normally fail. When I made
this decision it seemed the cautious and conservative approach, but
<a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/web/CautionIsAMistakeToday">this caution has turned out to be a mistake on the modern web</a>. In practice, all sorts of sites will
generate versions of your URLs with all sorts of extra query
parameters tacked on, give them to people, and expect them to work.
If your website refuses to play along, (some) people won't get to
see your content. <strong>On today's web, you need to accept (and then
ignore) arbitrary query parameters on your URLs</strong>.</p>

<p>(Today's new query parameter is 's=NN', for various values of NN
like '04' and '09'. I'm not sure what's generating these URLs, but
it may be Slack.)</p>

<p>You might wonder how we got here, and that is a story of lax behavior
(or, if you prefer, being liberal in what you accept). In the
beginning, both Apache (for static web pages) and early web
applications often ignored extra query parameters on URLs, at least
on <code>GET</code> requests. I suspect that other early web servers also
imitated Apache here, but I have less exposure to their behavior
than Apache's. My guess is that this behavior wasn't deliberate,
it was just the simplest way to implement both Apache and early
web applications; you paid attention to what you cared about and
didn't bother to explicitly check that nothing else was supplied.</p>

<p>When people noticed that this behavior was commonplace and widespread,
they began using it. I believe that one of the early uses was for
embedding 'where this link was shared' information for your own web
analytics (<a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/web/AnalyticsVsSecurity">cf</a>), either based on your logs
or using JavaScript embedded in the page. In the way of things,
once this was common enough other people began helpfully tagging
the links that were shared through them for you, which is why I
began to see various 'utm_*' query parameters on inbound
requests to <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/">Wandering Thoughts</a> even though I never
published such URLs.
Web developers don't leave attractive nuisances alone for long, so
soon enough people were sticking on extra query parameters to your
URLs that were mostly for them and not so much for you. Facebook
may have been one of the early pioneers here with their 'fbclid'
parameter, but other websites have hopped on this particular train
since then (as I saw recently with these 's=NN' parameters).</p>

<p>At this point, the practice of other websites and services adding
random query parameters to your URLs that pass through them is so
wide spread and common that accepting random query parameters is
pretty much a practical requirement for any web content serving
software that wants to see wide use and not be irritating to the
people operating it. If, like <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/dwiki/DWiki">DWiki</a>, you stick to your guns and
refuse to accept some or all of them, you will drop some amount of
your incoming requests from real people, disappointing would be
readers.</p>

<p>This practical requirement for URL handling is not documented in
any specification, and it's probably not in most 'best practices'
documentation. People writing new web serving systems that are
tempted to be strict and safe and cautious get to learn about it
the hard way.</p>

<p>In general, any laxness in actual implementations of a system can
create a similar spiral of de facto requirements. Something that
is permitted and is useful to people will be used, and then supporting
that becomes a requirement. This is especially the case in a
distributed system like the web, where any attempt to tighten the
rules would only be initially supported by a minority of websites.
These websites would be 'outvoted' by the vast majority of websites
that allow the lax behavior and support it, because that's what
happens when the vast majority work and the minority don't.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/web/DeFactoQueryParameters</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24404814</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 02:50:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[On writing and selling science fiction stories (2018)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 7 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24404555">thread link</a>) | @forrestbrazeal
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | https://forrestbrazeal.com/2018/11/08/on-writing-and-selling-science-fiction-stories/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://forrestbrazeal.com/2018/11/08/on-writing-and-selling-science-fiction-stories/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <section>
          <section>
              

              
              
              <article>
                  

<p>Each year, I try to set a few personal goals that stretch me in some way.</p>

<p>In 2017, for example, I <a href="https://forrestbrazeal.com/2017/12/03/how-to-read-100-books-in-a-year-and-still-have-a-life/">read one hundred books</a>, which turned out to be more a test of endurance than skill.</p>

<p>This year, I decided to see if I could write a fictional short story and get it published somewhere. Though I do a fair amount of technical writing in the course of my work, I’d never seriously attempted to write and sell a short story before, or even taken a creative writing class.</p>

<p>This meant I had no knowledge of the market, no connections, and generally no idea what I was doing.</p>

<p>So, a challenge!</p>

<h2 id="goals">Goals</h2>

<p>I decided to focus on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speculative_fiction">speculative fiction genre</a>, partly because it seemed more accessible and mostly because unlike literary journals, the best speculative fiction magazines still pay their authors.</p>

<p>My goals, in descending order of likelihood, were as follows:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Get something published somewhere, even if unpaid</p></li>

<li><p>Get something published and get paid something for it, even a token amount</p></li>

<li><p>Get something published at <a href="https://www.sfwa.org/about/join-us/sfwa-membership-requirements/#short">Science Fiction Writers of America (SFWA) professional rates</a> (currently 6 cents a word)</p></li>

<li><p>Get at least 1000 words published at SFWA-qualifying markets (the standard for <a href="https://www.sfwa.org/about/join-us/sfwa-membership-requirements/#associate">SFWA associate member status</a>)</p></li>

<li><p>Get at least three stories published, totaling more than 10,000 words, at SFWA-qualifying professional markets (<a href="https://www.sfwa.org/about/join-us/sfwa-membership-requirements/#active">SFWA Active Member status</a>, my self-imposed standard for a legit “professional” science fiction writer)</p></li>
</ol>

<h2 id="results-through-nov-8">Results (through Nov. 8)</h2>

<p>After many form rejections on several terrible stories, I sold my <a href="https://dailysciencefiction.com/science-fiction/biotech/forrest-brazeal/memory-foam">first story</a> on March 23rd, 2018, to Daily Science Fiction (an SWFA pro market). At 1010 words, this sale actually crossed the first four goals off my list at once.</p>

<p>However, I continued to write and improve over the spring and summer of 2018, selling several more stories along the way, eventually totaling more than 16,000 words of fiction. Some publications have long wait times, but by the time “Empathy Bee” <a href="http://www.diabolicalplots.com/the-diabolical-plots-year-five-fiction-lineup/">is published</a> in March 2019, I should have the wordcount needed for active SFWA membership status, my most insane stretch goal.</p>

<h3 id="by-the-numbers">By the numbers</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Stories Written: 22</p></li>

<li><p>Total Wordcount: ~60,000, the length of a medium-sized novel</p></li>

<li><p>Total Submissions: 70</p></li>

<li><p>Stories Sold: 8</p></li>

<li><p>SFWA-qualifying professional sales: 6</p></li>

<li><p>Rejections: 50 (15 personal)</p></li>

<li><p>Withdrawals: 2</p></li>

<li><p>Still Pending: 10</p></li>

<li><p>Other Results: <a href="https://www.writersofthefuture.com/writers-of-the-future-3rd-quarter-standings-for-year-35/">Honorable Mention, Writers of the Future</a></p></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="what-i-learned">What I Learned</h2>

<h3 id="have-no-ego">Have no ego</h3>

<p>It turns out writing short stories that sell is really, really hard. It’s hard to think of good ideas, it’s hard to write them down in a form that anyone would want to read, and it’s even harder when those readers are magazine editors who get literally hundreds of unsolicited submissions every month. Don’t attempt it if you have an easily bruised sense of self-worth, or you will be depressed a lot.</p>

<p>I’m grateful to have sold some stories this year, but my identity is not tied up in “being a writer”. It can’t be, because I have to…</p>

<h3 id="embrace-failure">Embrace failure</h3>

<p>I learned to view rejections as a badge of honor, which is a helpful mental trick to keep from going insane after a few dozen forms. As I told Jason Bougger in an <a href="http://www.themeofabsence.com/2018/11/author-interview-forrest-brazeal/">author interview</a> over at Theme of Absence, rejections are like the good soreness you feel after working out – it means you’re growing.</p>

<h3 id="keep-your-feedback-loop-short">Keep your feedback loop short</h3>

<p>Early on, when I was getting form rejections from big magazines with no accompanying feedback, I got really frustrated because I knew my work was obviously not up to par – I just didn’t know why. A submission to a smaller publication, Abyss and Apex (who I later ended up selling a different story to!) brought back a personalized rejection with a helpful piece of advice: try signing up for the <a href="https://sff.onlinewritingworkshop.com/">Online Writing Workshop</a>.</p>

<p>At the time I had never heard of writers’ workshops and didn’t really understand why they would be helpful. But I paid a few dollars and signed up. The other writers there provided generous feedback on how to improve my work, and I learned just as much from critiquing their pieces. The OWW membership more than paid for itself when several readers pointed out an obvious plot hole in my story “Empathy Bee”, which subsequently sold in revised form to Diabolical Plots.</p>

<p>Later, once I had professional credits, I was able to join the wonderful <a href="http://www.codexwriters.com/">Codex</a> writers’ community, which has hugely expanded my horizons and understanding of the industry. The more I write, the less I trust myself to be a good judge of my work’s quality, and the more I seek out and appreciate feedback from others.</p>

<h3 id="write-smart-not-just-hard">Write smart, not just hard</h3>

<p>Some writers recommend keeping insane writing regimens, cranking out thousands of words a day, saying it’s the only way to improve. And I wrote a fair amount this year. But stepping back and getting feedback on my work was just as important.</p>

<p>I had a music teacher who used to ask: “Did you practice ten hours, or just the same hour ten times?” When I took time to evaluate my work and deliberately build on it, I improved faster than just by vomiting words indiscriminately onto the page.</p>

<h3 id="keep-reading-good-prose">Keep reading good prose</h3>

<p>No, I didn’t read a hundred books again this year. But I did try to keep my ear filled with good prose. For example, this summer I got on a southern realist kick: Flannery O’Connor, Eudora Welty, Carson McCullers. Studying how those writers crafted characters and situations helped me nail down a couple of southern-set stories that ended up selling. My science fiction writing improved more from reading good writers, period, than from reading science fiction.</p>

<h3 id="just-because-you-wrote-something-good-enough-to-get-published-somewhere-that-doesn-t-mean-the-next-thing-you-write-won-t-be-terrible">Just because you wrote something good enough to get published somewhere, that doesn’t mean the next thing you write won’t be terrible</h3>

<p>This sounds stupid in hindsight, but for a long time I had it in my head that once I sold a story, I’d have figured out what it took to get published, and I wouldn’t have any trouble after that. Instead, I still get tons of rejections, and often my writing seems just as lifeless and terrible to me as it did before I sold my first story.</p>

<p>The good news is that with practice, the overall trend appears to be upward. At least, when I look back at my work from the beginning of the year, I can’t believe how bad it is. So I must be improving, right?</p>

<h2 id="what-s-next">What’s next?</h2>

<p>Like many people who start out in the short fiction game, I would love to publish a novel. So I think that might be a 2019 goal. But I’m sure I’ll continue to write short stories, too. There’s real satisfaction in creating something that you can hold in your head all at once, knowing how it will turn out and why it’s effective.</p>

<p><em>Some of the stories I sold this year are free to read online. You can check them out in my <a href="https://forrestbrazeal.com/bibliography/">bibliography</a></em></p>

              </article>
              <center>
              <p>
                      If you enjoy my articles, comics, and stories, why not sign up for the mailing list?
                  </p>
              
            </center>
              
          </section>
          <br>
          

      </section>

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://forrestbrazeal.com/2018/11/08/on-writing-and-selling-science-fiction-stories/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24404555</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 01:53:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Fast.ai and why Python is not the future of ML with Jeremy Howard]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 49 | Comments 50 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24404002">thread link</a>) | @tosh
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | https://www.wandb.com/podcast/jeremy-howard | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.wandb.com/podcast/jeremy-howard">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Jeremy Howard is a founding researcher at fast.ai, a research institute dedicated to making Deep Learning more accessible. Previously, he was the CEO and Founder at Enlitic, an advanced machine learning company in San Francisco, California. </p><p>Howard is a faculty member at Singularity University, where he teaches data science. He is also a Young Global Leader with the World Economic Forum, and spoke at the World Economic Forum Annual Meeting 2014 on "Jobs For The Machines." </p><p>Howard advised Khosla Ventures as their Data Strategist, identifying the biggest opportunities for investing in data-driven startups and mentoring their portfolio companies to build data-driven businesses. Howard was the founding CEO of two successful Australian startups, FastMail and Optimal Decisions Group. Before that, he spent eight years in management consulting, at McKinsey &amp; Company and AT Kearney.</p><p><strong>TOPICS COVERED:</strong></p><p>0:00 Introduction</p><p>0:52 Dad things</p><p>2:40 The story of Fast.ai</p><p>4:57 How the courses have evolved over time</p><p>9:24 Jeremy’s top down approach to teaching</p><p>13:02 From Fast.ai the course to Fast.ai the library</p><p>15:08 Designing V2 of the library from the ground up</p><p>21:44 The ingenious type dispatch system that powers Fast.ai</p><p>25:52 Were you able to realize the vision behind v2 of the library</p><p>28:05 Is it important to you that Fast.ai is used by everyone in the world, beyond the context of learning</p><p>29:37 Real world applications of Fast.ai, including animal husbandry</p><p>35:08 Staying ahead of the new developments in the field</p><p>38:50 A bias towards learning by doing</p><p>40:02 What’s next for Fast.ai</p><p>40.35 Python is not the future of Machine Learning</p><p>43:58 One underrated aspect of machine learning</p><p>45:25 Biggest challenge of machine learning in the real world</p><p>Follow Jeremy on Twitter:</p><p><a href="https://twitter.com/jeremyphoward" target="_blank">https://twitter.com/jeremyphoward</a><br></p><p>Links:</p><p>Deep learning R&amp;D &amp; education: <a target="_blank" href="https://t.co/ZvDGNlehRt?amp=1">http://fast.ai</a></p><p>Software: <a target="_blank" href="https://t.co/GMYkPDXNW3?amp=1">http://docs.fast.ai</a></p><p>Book: <a target="_blank" href="https://t.co/1YSqXvWW87?amp=1">http://up.fm/book</a></p><p>Course: <a target="_blank" href="https://t.co/Q2qMl59EfH?amp=1">http://course.fast.ai</a></p><p>Papers:</p><p><a target="_blank" href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/2487575.2491127"><strong>The business impact of deep learning</strong></a></p><p><a target="_blank" href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/2487575.2491127">https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/2487575.2491127</a></p><p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/redir/redirect?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww%2Ejmir%2Eorg%2F2012%2F1%2Fe33%2F&amp;amp;urlhash=gLU-&amp;trk=public_profile_publication-title"><strong>De-identification Methods for Open Health Data</strong></a></p><p><a href="https://www.jmir.org/2012/1/e33/">https://www.jmir.org/2012/1/e33/</a><br></p><p>Visit our podcasts homepage for transcripts and more episodes!</p><p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.wandb.com/podcast">www.wandb.com/podcast</a></p><p> Get our podcast on Soundcloud, Apple, and Spotify!</p><p>Soundcloud: <a target="_blank" href="https://bit.ly/2YnGjIq">https://bit.ly/2YnGjIq</a></p><p>Apple Podcasts: <a target="_blank" href="https://bit.ly/2WdrUvI">https://bit.ly/2WdrUvI</a></p><p>Spotify: <a target="_blank" href="https://bit.ly/2SqtadF">https://bit.ly/2SqtadF</a></p><p>We started Weights and Biases to build tools for Machine Learning practitioners because we care a lot about the impact that Machine Learning can have in the world and we love working in the trenches with the people building these models. One of the most fun things about these building tools has been the conversations with these ML practitioners and learning about the interesting things they’re working on. This process has been so fun that we wanted to open it up to the world in the form of our new podcast called Gradient Dissent. We hope you have as much fun listening to it as we had making it!</p><p>Weights and Biases:</p><p>We’re always free for academics and open source projects. Email carey@wandb.com with any questions or feature suggestions.</p><ul role="list"><li>Blog: <a target="_blank" href="https://www.wandb.com/articles">https://www.wandb.com/articles</a></li><li>Gallery: See what you can create with W&amp;B - <a target="_blank" href="https://app.wandb.ai/gallery">https://app.wandb.ai/gallery</a></li><li>Continue the conversation on our slack community - <a href="http://bit.ly/wandb-forum" target="_blank">http://bit.ly/wandb-forum</a><br></li></ul><p>Host: Lukas Biewald - <a href="https://twitter.com/l2k" target="_blank">https://twitter.com/l2k</a></p><p>Producer: Lavanya Shukla - <a href="https://twitter.com/lavanyaai" target="_blank">https://twitter.com/lavanyaai</a></p><p>TRANSCRIPT:</p><p><strong>Lukas: </strong>You're listening to Gradient Dissent, a show where we learn about making machine learning models work in the real world. I'm your host Lukas Biewald. Jeremy Howard created the Fast.ai course, which is maybe the most popular course to learn machine learning and there are a lot out there. He's also the author of the book Deep Learning for Coders with Fast.ai and PyTorch and in that process, he made the Fast.ai library which lots of people use independently to write deep learning. Before that, he was the CEO and co-founder of Enlitic, an exciting startup that applies deep learning to health care applications. And before that, he was the president of Kaggle, one of the most exciting earliest machine learning companies. I'm super excited to talk to him. So Jeremy, it's nice to talk to you. And in preparing the questions, I realized that every time I've talked to you there have been a few gems that I've remembered that I would never think to ask about. Like one time you told me about how you learned Chinese and another time you gave me Dad parenting advice, very specific advice and it's been actually super helpful. </p><p><strong>Jeremy: </strong>Oh great. Tell me what Dad parenting advice worked out?</p><p><strong>Lukas: </strong>Well, what you told me was when you change diapers, use a blow dryer to change a really frustrating experience to a really joyful experience and it's like such good advice. I don't know how you.. I guess I can imagine how you thought of it, but it's...</p><p><strong>Jeremy: </strong>Yeah, yeah, I know they love the whooshing sound, they love the warmth. I'm kind of obsessed about Dad things. So I'm always happy to talk about Dad things. That is this podcast.</p><p><strong>Lukas: </strong>Can we start with that? Now that my daughter is eight months old. Do you have any suggestions for her?</p><p><strong>Jeremy: </strong>Oh my goodness! Eight months old. You know, it's like the same with any kind of learning. It's all about consistency. So I think that the main thing we did right with Claire was just, you know, this delightful child now is we were just super consistent. Like if we said you can't have X unless you do Y, we would never give her X if she didn't do Y. If you want to take your scooter down to the bottom of the road, you have to carry it back up again. We read this great book that was saying if you're not consistent, it becomes like this thing, it's like a gambler. It's like sometimes you get the thing you want, so you just have to keep trying so that's my number one piece of advice. It's the same with teaching machine learning. We always tell people that tenacity is the most important thing for students. To stick with it, do it every day.</p><p><strong>Lukas: </strong>I guess just in the spirit of questions, I'm genuinely curious about, you know, you've built this amazing framework and teaching thing that I think is maybe the most popular and most appreciated framework. I was wondering if you could start by telling me the story of what inspired you to do that and what was the journey to making Fast.ai, the curriculum and Fast.ai, the ML framework.</p><p><strong>Jeremy: </strong>So it was something that my wife Rachel and I started together. Rachel has a math PhD, super technical background, early data scientist and engineer, Uber. I don't. I have just scraped by a philosophy undergrad and have no technical background. But from both of our different directions, we both had this frustration that neural networks in 2012 were super important, clearly going to change the world, but super inaccessible and so we would go to meetups and try to figure out like how do we... Like I knew the basic idea, I'd coded neural networks 20 years ago, but how do you make them really good? There wasn't any open source software at the time for running on GPUs. You know, Dan Seresen's thing was available, but you had to pay for it. There was no source code and we just thought, oh, we've got to change this, because the history of technology leaps has been that it generally increases inequality because the people with resources can access the new technology and then that leads to societal upheaval and a lot of unhappiness. So we thought, well, we should just do what we can. So we thought how are we going to fix this? Basically the goal was, and still is, to be able to use deep learning without requiring any code so that, you know, because the vast majority of the world can't code, we kind of thought, well, to get there, we should, first of all, see what exists right now? Learn how to use it as best as we can ourselves, teach people how to best use it as we can and then make it better, which requires doing research and then turning that into software and then changing the course to teach the hopefully slightly easier version and repeat that again and again for a few years. And so we're kind of in that process.</p><p><strong>Lukas: </strong>That's so interesting. Do you worry that the stuff you're teaching, you're sort of trying to make it obsolete, right? Because you're trying to build higher level abstractions? Like I think one of the things that people really appreciate your course is that it's really clear, in-depth explanations of how these things work. Do you think that that's eventually going to be not necessary or how do you think about that?</p><p><strong>Jeremy: </strong>Yeah, to some extent. I mean, so if you look at the new book and the new course, chapter one starts with really, really foundational stuff around what is a machine learning algorithm? What do we mean to learn an algorithm? What's the difference between traditional programming and machine learning to solve the same problem? And those kinds of basic foundations I think will always be useful, even at the point you're not using any code. I feel like even right now, if somebody is using like PlatformAI or some kind of code-free framework, you still need to understand these basics of an algorithm can only learn based on the data you provide. It's generally not going to be able to extrapolate to patterns it's not seen yet, stuff like that. Um, but yeah, I mean, we have so far released two new courses every year, you know, a part one and part two every year because every year, it's totally out of date. And we always say to our students at the start of part one, Look, you know, none of the details you're learning are going to be of any use in a year or two's time. There's a time when we're doing Piano and then TensorFlow and Keras, and then playing PyTorch. We always say, look, don't worry too much about the software we're using because none of it's still any good, you know, it's goal changing rapidly, you know, faster than JavaScript frameworks, but the concepts are important and yeah, you can pick up a new library and I don't know by weekend, I …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.wandb.com/podcast/jeremy-howard">https://www.wandb.com/podcast/jeremy-howard</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.wandb.com/podcast/jeremy-howard</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24404002</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:10:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Optimize Onboarding]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 126 | Comments 43 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24402419">thread link</a>) | @tekdude
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | https://staysaasy.com/management/2020/08/28/Optimize-Onboarding.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://staysaasy.com/management/2020/08/28/Optimize-Onboarding.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p>It takes roughly 2 weeks to form a habit; it takes roughly two weeks to get comfortable in a new environment. A common mistake is to treat a new report’s first couple weeks like college orientation - social, light hearted, get-to-know-you stuff. If your report spends the first two weeks reading C# documentation and having lunch out on the town with the team, guess what, they’ve just normalized that behavior as what the role is.</p>

<p>The answer: start your report doing real work as soon as possible. If they’re a software engineer, they should be committing code week one (ideally day 2 or 3); If they’re a product manager, they should be attending meetings and picking up supporting activities on a similar time frame. Then the tone has been set - working here means getting things done.</p>

<p>This means as manager you need to give your report tractable work in the first week. Managers not being ready for a report to start is the number one reason people end up normalizing underperformance, because they had nothing meaningful to do. If a manager describes a report as not having initiative in the first couple weeks it’s a red flag - it’s the manager’s job to provide new hires with clear paths to contribute immediately.</p>

<p>Another main reason people fall into onboarding traps is because your organization has painfully slow onboarding. Endless HR videos, slow security processes, a mountain of fragile technology setup - these all make for a shitty and counterproductive start at a company. Optimize your onboarding to get people doing what you hired them to do. Look to formalize performance indicators of your onboarding. For example, for engineers this could be time-to-first-commit and time-to-joining-sprints.</p>

<p>This approach holds for managers and executives as well. In that cohort it’s also common and a common red flag for people to spend the first couple weeks putzing around under the guise of “getting to know what’s going on”. Managers and executives should be involved in the decisions of the team from day 1 and developing artifacts - plans, TODO lists, strategy documents - in the first couple weeks. With good managers and executives you see them day 1 adding perspective and insight into conversations, and everyone collectively appreciates that the right person has been hired.</p>

<p>Onboarding is one of the most critical periods in a person’s time at a company. It’s one of the highest ROI periods when managing someone. Take that opportunity to set expectations properly and measure success quantiatively.</p>


    




  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://staysaasy.com/management/2020/08/28/Optimize-Onboarding.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24402419</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 20:18:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Doom Eternal – Graphics Study]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 127 | Comments 32 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24401805">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | https://www.simoncoenen.com/blog/programming/graphics/DoomEternalStudy.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.simoncoenen.com/blog/programming/graphics/DoomEternalStudy.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="markdown-content">
            


<p>30 Aug 2020 - Simon Coenen - Reading time: <span title="Estimated read time">
  
  
    23 mins
  
</span><span></span> - <a href="#comment-section">Comments</a>
</p>
<p><img src="https://www.simoncoenen.com/images/blog/010_doom_eternal_study/image1.jpeg" alt=""></p>

<h2 id="background">Background</h2>

<p>Doom Eternal is the successor of Doom 2016. It’s developed using the 7th iteration of id Tech, id Software’s in-house game engine. Doom 2016 has inspired me greatly on a technologic level due to its simplicity and elegance while still having a high visual quality. For Doom Eternal, this is no different. Doom Eternal has improved in many areas of which a few are worth investigating which I will try to cover in this frame breakdown.</p>

<!--more-->

<p>This frame breakdown is inspired by <a href="http://www.adriancourreges.com/blog/2016/09/09/doom-2016-graphics-study/">Adrian Courreges’s study on Doom 2016</a>. I believe these graphics studies give a lot of insight into how certain rendering problems are solved in a AAA game and are greatly educational. In this breakdown I aim to stay at a high level and not go too in-depth of each rendering technique/pass. Some passes might not be covered here because they are very similar to Doom 2016 and are well covered in Adrian Courreges’s study.</p>

<p>I do want to stress here that these studies are absolutely nothing more than <strong>educational</strong>. I do not in any way support the reverse engineering for malicious purposes and stealing intellectual property. If you haven’t played the game yet, don’t worry about spoilers! The section I used for this study is in the beginning of the game which doesn’t give away any of the details.</p>

<p>Now, let’s get down to business.</p>

<p>With Id Tech 7, the engine has moved away from OpenGL and is entirely built with a <strong>Vulkan</strong> backend allowing them to make better use of current generation GPU features, bindless resources in particular.</p>

<hr>



<p><img src="https://www.simoncoenen.com/images/blog/010_doom_eternal_study/image2.png" alt=""></p>

<p>We’re looking at a section in the game close to the start. It’s an interior with a few enemies and a large portion of volumetric lighting. Just like its predecessor, Doom Eternal is using a <strong>forward rendering</strong> pipeline. Doom 2016 was mostly forward rendered with a thin G-Buffer for screen space reflections. However this time, everything is fully forward rendered omitting the G-Buffer.</p>

<hr>

<h2 id="step-away-from-mega-texture">Step away from Mega-Texture</h2>

<p>With id Tech 5 used in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rage_(video_game)">Rage</a>, there was a texture streaming concept introduced called ‘Mega-Texture’ which was also used in the previous Doom installment. This system works by rendering a so called ‘feedback texture’ each frame that contains the information of what texture data was visible, that texture is analysed next frame to determine which textures get streamed in from disk. This has an obvious flaw because once a texture is on screen, it’s basically already too late to load it and this causes blurry textures the first few frames it is on screen. In id Tech 7, id Software has stepped away from this approach.</p>

<hr>

<h2 id="gpu-skinning">GPU Skinning</h2>

<p>The first thing that happens even before anything gets drawn to a texture, is evaluating skinning. This is commonly done in a vertex shader before shading. An alternative approach used here, is to do skinning beforehand in a compute shader which writes out skinned vertices to a buffer. This has a couple of advantages mainly not having to do skinning in the vertex shader for every geometry pass. This results in having less shader permutations because the vertex shader doesn’t have to know about skinning.</p>

<p>Skinning in a compute shader is not much different from in a vertex shader except that the output gets written to an intermediate buffer which can then be consumed in a vertex shader that can treat it as a regular static mesh. Just like in a vertex shader, for each vertex, a compute shader thread retrieves the transform of each bone affecting the vertex, transforms its position with each bone transform and adds up these positions based on the skin weights stored on the vertex.</p>

<p>János Turánszki wrote a wonderful write-up of how it can be implemented using a compute shader:
<a href="https://wickedengine.net/2017/09/09/skinning-in-compute-shader/">https://wickedengine.net/2017/09/09/skinning-in-compute-shader/</a>.</p>

<p>Another thing that is worth noting here is the use of <strong>Alembic Caches</strong> in Doom Eternal. These caches contain baked animation which get streamed and decompressed at runtime. As <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UsmqWSZpgJY">Digital Foundry described in their tech breakdown</a>, this is used for a wide range of animations going from large cinematic pieces to small tentacles on the floor. This is especially useful for animations that are hard to achieve using skinned animation like organics and cloth simulation. You can compare an Alembic Cache with a video that can be played back and is highly compressed by looking ahead. I suggest watching <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zlz-7V_XiUA">Axel Gneiting’s talk at Siggraph 2014</a> if you’re interested in learning more.</p>

<hr>

<h2 id="shadow-mapping">Shadow Mapping</h2>

<p>Next up is shadow rendering. There doesn’t seem to be any large changes in how shadow maps are approached in id Tech 7 compared to its predecessor.</p>

<p>As seen below, shadows get rendered in a large 4096x8196px 24-bit depth texture which may vary across quality levels. The texture is persistent across frames and as described in “Devil is in the Details” at Siggraph 2016, the static geometry in the shadow map is cached to save having to redraw the shadow maps each frame. The technique is fairly simple: as long as nothing in the view of the light moves, there is no need to update the shadows. If a dynamic object in the frustum moves, a ‘cached’ shadow map is copied into the actual shadow map and the dynamic geometry is re-drawn on top. This cached shadow map is the same shadow map but only with static geometry because you can make the assumption that these will never change. This saves having to draw the entire scene in the frustum every time it needs to update. Of course, when the light moves, the entire scene has to be redrawn from scratch.</p>

<p>When sampling the shadow map during lighting, a 3x3 PCF sampling approach is used to smoothen the shadow edges. For the sun light, <strong>cascaded shadow maps</strong> are used to distribute the quality better as it covers such a large portion of the environment.</p>

<p>Here is a closer look at the shadow atlas. A light with higher importance, larger screen area or that is closer to the camera, will get a larger portion of the atlas assigned for better resolution. These heuristics are evaluated dynamically.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.simoncoenen.com/images/blog/010_doom_eternal_study/image3.jpeg" alt=""></p>

<hr>

<h2 id="depth-pre-pass-and-velocity">Depth Pre-pass and Velocity</h2>

<p>Opaque geometry gets rendered to a depth-only target starting with the player’s gun, then static geometry, and finally dynamic geometry. A depth pre-pass is common to avoid unnecessary pixel shader calculations later down the pipeline where geometry overlaps. A depth pre-pass is especially important in a forward renderer where redundant pixel calculations are extremely wasteful due to pixel overdraw. With a depth pre-pass, the actual forward lighting pixel shader can reject pixels by comparing with the depth buffer before execution, saving a lot of performance.</p>

<div id="prepassCarousel" data-ride="carousel">
  <ol>
    <li data-target="#prepassCarousel" data-slide-to="0"></li>
    <li data-target="#prepassCarousel" data-slide-to="1"></li>
    <li data-target="#prepassCarousel" data-slide-to="2"></li>
  </ol>
  <div>
    <div>
      <p><img src="https://www.simoncoenen.com/images/blog/010_doom_eternal_study/Prepass0.png"></p><p>First person gun</p>
    </div>
    <div>
      <p><img src="https://www.simoncoenen.com/images/blog/010_doom_eternal_study/Prepass1.png"></p><p>Static objects</p>
    </div>
    <div>
      <p><img src="https://www.simoncoenen.com/images/blog/010_doom_eternal_study/Prepass2.png"></p><p>Dynamic objects</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  <p><a href="#prepassCarousel" role="button" data-slide="prev">
    
    <span>Previous</span>
  </a>
  <a href="#prepassCarousel" role="button" data-slide="next">
    
    <span>Next</span>
  </a>
</p></div>

<p>Besides rendering depth, the pre-pass also renders to another color target. For dynamic geometry, the velocity is rendered using motion vectors which is the position of the current position subtracted from the position of the pixel in the previous frame. We only need the motion on the X and Y axis so the motion is stored in the red and green channel of a 16-bit floating point render target. This information is later used in post processing for applying motion blur and reprojection for temporal anti-aliasing. The image below is exaggerated because this snapshot doesn’t have a lot of motion. Static geometry does not need motion vectors as their motion can be derived from the camera motion because they have only “moved” relative to the camera.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.simoncoenen.com/images/blog/010_doom_eternal_study/image6.jpeg" alt=""></p>

<hr>

<h2 id="hierarchical-z-depth">Hierarchical-Z Depth</h2>

<p>Next up, a hierarchical mip chain of the depth buffer is generated which is similar to a mip map but instead of averaging 4 neighboring pixels, the maximum is taken. This is commonly done in graphics for various purposes like accelerating screen space reflections and occlusion culling. In this case, this mip chain is used to accelerate the light and decal culling which is covered later. More recently, mip generation is done in a single pass by writing into multiple mips at once. In Doom Eternal, it still traditionally does a dispatch for every mip separately.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.simoncoenen.com/images/blog/010_doom_eternal_study/image7.gif" alt=""></p>

<hr>

<h2 id="mesh-decals">Mesh Decals</h2>

<p>Up until what I’ve covered so far, there haven’t been many noticeable changes compared to Doom 2016. However, “mesh decals” is an addition to the mesh rendering pipeline introduced in Doom Eternal. Unlike the common decal workflow - which are placed freely in the environment - a mesh decal is placed during the mesh authoring pipeline by artists and so belong to the mesh. Before, Doom heavily relied on decals and stepped it up with the addition of so called “mesh decals” in this game for even better detailing and flexibility. “Mesh decals” are small decals like bolts, grills, bumps, stickers, … Just like a traditional decal, it can modify any property of the underlying surface like the normal, roughness, base color, …</p>

<p>To achieve this, the following geometry pass renders each of the decals’s ID into an 8-bit render target. Later during shading, this texture is sampled to retrieve the ID which is used to retrieve a projection matrix bound with each draw call. The matrix projects the pixel’s position from world space into texture space. These coordinates are then used to sample the decal and blend with the underlying material. This is extremely fast and allows artists to go crazy with massive amounts of decals. Because the IDs are rendered to an 8-bit texture, the maximum amount of decals per mesh would theoretically be 255.</p>

<p>One requirement for this, is that all decals are bound to the pipeline when drawing meshes. Doom Eternal uses a fully bindless render pipeline which allows them to bind all decal textures at once and dynamically index them in the shader. More on this bindless pipeline later as this is important to pull off other tricks they’ve done in this game.</p>

<p>Below, the mesh decal texture. The different IDs are coloured to visualize it better.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.simoncoenen.com/images/blog/010_doom_eternal_study/image8.jpeg" alt=""></p>

<hr>

<h2 id="light-and-decal-culling">Light and …</h2></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.simoncoenen.com/blog/programming/graphics/DoomEternalStudy.html">https://www.simoncoenen.com/blog/programming/graphics/DoomEternalStudy.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.simoncoenen.com/blog/programming/graphics/DoomEternalStudy.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24401805</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 19:10:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Soft Skills for Managers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 11 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24400840">thread link</a>) | @hackitup7
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | https://staysaasy.com/product/2020/09/06/soft-skills-for-managers.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://staysaasy.com/product/2020/09/06/soft-skills-for-managers.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p>Many of the hard technical skills that make a great manager are testable. You can easily evaluate technical expertise – for example, an engineering manager should demonstrate their ability to produce or at least understand code. Similarly, in-depth discussions will quickly reveal whether someone can clearly and concisely communicate nuanced concepts.</p>

<p>The softer skills of management are more difficult to assess but just as important. Below are a few of the soft skills that I value most highly in managers, some ideas on how to assess them, and common traps.</p>

<h2 id="soft-skill-1-initiative">Soft Skill #1: Initiative</h2>

<p>Managers set the tempo for their teams – if they aren’t actively looking for ways to help the business, they will set an example that being proactive is optional. The sad truth is that once you’re a manager you can survive a long time by simply maintaining existing processes, reacting to personnel issues, or (worse) creating busywork and taking credit. Many managers collect fine paychecks drifting like an inert gas within a broader bureaucratic cloud. To scale a company effectively, managers need to be proactive rather than existing simply to push virtual papers across their desks.</p>

<p>Initiative tends to be pretty obvious when evaluating internal management candidates. For external candidates, I usually ask deep-dive questions about a meaty project from their past. The goal: learn about what they did, their role, and most importantly the “why” behind their decisions, diving into the details of what really went down. A sample prompt: “Tell me about a significant project that you led, and I’ll ask a bunch of questions to dive deeper.” This is usually fun to ask and I expect to learn something new from strong candidates – after all, they know much more than I do about the project they worked on, so if they can’t teach me something that’s a red flag.</p>

<p>Searching for the “why” behind their decisions is a good test for initiative – being able to explain why certain decisions were made indicates that a candidate can think critically about what a project actually needs, rather than just executing on someone else’s plan.</p>

<h2 id="soft-skill-2-emotional-control">Soft Skill #2: Emotional Control</h2>

<p>Management can be stressful, <a href="https://staysaasy.com/scaling/2020/05/07/startup-is-this-normal.html">especially at a high growth startup company</a>. You’re the first point of escalation for all manner of problems: inter- or intra-team conflict, critical last-minute blockers, HR issues, and other corporate delights. You don’t have a safety net to fall back on if a situation gets too heated – you are the safety net.</p>

<p>Managers can’t be emotionally reactive. They need to remain rational even in the face of severe stressors, allowing them to remain unflappable when shit goes down (more calm also comes with experience). Sometimes, the downsides of reacting are minor: if someone says something dumb during a presentation and you visibly scowl, you can cause them to get flustered. Others are much more important: for example, if someone comes into a 1:1 very upset over their compensation, you need to remain calm as it can be disastrous to make promises or comments that could be misconstrued.</p>

<p>This skill is challenging to assess when hiring managers. Unlike in, say, the Marine Corps, it’s frowned upon in the tech industry to throw someone into a stressful situation and assess their emotional control. References are imperfect but can help, and this skillset is one of the reasons that internal manager candidates can be such tempting known quantities.</p>

<p>The very best managers take this a step further and demonstrate durability – the ability to not only exercise control, but to do so repeatedly over months and emerge on the other side energized and positive. High growth companies are challenging, and more significantly, they’re challenging <a href="https://staysaasy.com/scaling/2020/07/29/the-rogue-wave-of-enterprise-saas.html">over a very long time</a> – typically years. People who are a consistent force for optimistic calm are the pillars around which you should build your team.</p>

<h2 id="soft-skill-3-dispassionate-empathy">Soft Skill #3: Dispassionate Empathy</h2>

<p>Managers need dispassionate empathy: the ability to logically breakdown how their teams will react to new situations by viewing things from multiple perspectives – without allowing viewpoints that they’re sympathetic to cloud their judgment. If someone on your team is passed over for a promotion that goes to their teammate, how will they react? If someone gets really tough feedback, how will they handle it? Managers need to be able to assess factors such as incentives and egos as they chart a course for their entire team.</p>

<p>Promotions provide a common example: when you promote someone you’re affirming the behaviors that you will reward (as well as other behaviors that you tolerate…), and everyone else on the team will observe, calculate, and react differently according to their own interpretation. If you promote Alice, will her peer Bob freak out that it was unfair, become apathetic, or work harder? What message will it send to their more junior team member Charlie?</p>

<p>Empathizing with others’ viewpoints dispassionately is surprisingly difficult as there’s little in day-to-day life that prepares you for it. When a friend or family member is in a difficult situation, they’re typically looking for empathy without reservations, and we’re trained as primates to deliver it. Mirroring the emotions of people we’re close to is often a feature, not a bug. Many managers need to fight the urge to over-empathize.</p>

<p>I assess this trait in interviews by asking about challenging situations that occurred on a prior team. Examples include:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Tell me about a time that someone asked for something (eg a raise or promotion), and you didn’t give it to them.</li>
  <li>Tell me about a time when a member of your team was in conflict with a member of another team, and you needed to help out.</li>
  <li>Tell me about a time that someone on your team was underperforming.</li>
</ul>

<p>In asking about these scenarios, I’m first looking for the candidate’s ability to articulate the different motivations or incentives involved: do they understand the situation? Did they view it through others’ eyes rather than just their own? I also assess their ability to discuss the situation in a calm way: are they getting emotionally biased?</p>

<p>While emotional life isn’t as cut and dried as a Python script, I find that most great managers can break down situations like an algorithm: look at all of the different incentives and personalities on the team, add a new decision or situation, and guess at what will happen next.</p>

<h2 id="the-soft-skill-trap">The Soft Skill Trap</h2>

<p>Especially for internal candidates for management positions, beware the most common soft skill trap: mistaking a likeable personality for leadership or management aptitude.</p>

<p>It’s easy to misinterpret a gregarious, likeable personality for innate management skill. “Timmy is a ‘people person’ – of course he’ll be able to manage a team!” This is simply not how life works. Timmy might be great as a manager, or he might suck, but in my experience his likeability is unlikely to correlate strongly with the soft skills that matter.</p>

<p>I blame this phenomenon on Hollywood’s stereotypical portrayal of what it means to be a “leader.” Many great managers are gregarious, sociable, and charismatic, but many others are introverted, quiet in group settings, or somewhat socially awkward. I’ve met managers whom I actually somewhat disliked in a social capacity but who were extremely effective at their jobs. However, I have yet to meet a great manager who didn’t take initiative, couldn’t regulate their own emotions, and didn’t understand the incentives that would motivate their team.</p>

<p><img src="https://staysaasy.com/assets/soft_skills/gladiator.jpg" alt="Gladiator">
Good leader overall, but perhaps too much shouting for your average tech company</p>

<p>There’s also a potential element of bias here: does someone seem like they should be in a leadership position just because they’re really confident? Do they feel like they should be in charge because they’re often the loudest voice in the room? These sorts of subjective judgements are also minefields for bias. For a random example, some of the behaviors that say “leader” in American culture scream “jerk” in East Asian culture. I highly recommend assessing management potential according to the dimensions listed above and trying to remove likeability or sociability from your decision calculus.</p>

<h2 id="takeaways">Takeaways</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Great management requires both hard and soft skills. Soft skills are often harder to assess.</li>
  <li>When assessing a manager’s soft skills, look for the following traits: initiative, emotional control, and an ability to understand how others will perceive and react to situations.</li>
  <li>Promoting from within is a great way to remove manager hiring risk.</li>
  <li>Don’t mistake sociability for management skill.</li>
</ul>

    




  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://staysaasy.com/product/2020/09/06/soft-skills-for-managers.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24400840</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 17:13:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Heroku terminates Ruqqus site and account without a warning or an explanation]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 35 | Comments 27 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24400102">thread link</a>) | @ecmascript
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | https://ruqqus.com/post/301l/you-cant-cancel-freedom-that-easily | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ruqqus.com/post/301l/you-cant-cancel-freedom-that-easily">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="post-body">
<p>At 16:09 EDT on 04 Sep 2020 (about 26 hours ago), SalesForce (the owner of web hosting company Heroku) notified us that they had suspended the Ruqqus live and test server environments, with account termination to follow twenty-four hours later.</p>
<p>At the time of this writing, we have not been given a reason as to why we were being kicked. I do not believe we violated Heroku ToS (though Heroku may think otherwise) and we did not exceed Heroku usage limits. Our account manager was friendly but was unfortunately unable to provide us with any information. It is my opinion that by not warning us first (ex. "please remove X which violates Heroku's acceptable use policy") that Heroku actually violated their own terms of service.</p>
<p>We immediately downloaded all of the Ruqqus data, and began working on setting up shop at another host.</p>
<p>I'd like to give a massive shoutout to <a href="https://ruqqus.com/@p2hang"><img src="https://ruqqus.com/@p2hang/pic/profile">@p2hang</a> for lending his considerable expertise in support of getting Ruqqus operational as quickly as possible. He is the third recipient of the super-rare Fire Extinguisher badge.</p>
<p>All (or at least, almost all) functionality is restored. There are a few things which aren't quite yet back to normal, which I hope to fix over the course of tonight and tomorrow.</p>
<p>Known issues:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><del>hCaptcha verification issues on attempted signups</del></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><del>Custom guild colors are currently disabled. This was an intentional decision by me, as there were issues loading the style files needed for custom coloring, so it was easier to just disable that for the sake of getting up and running.</del></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><del>Notification bell stuck on.</del></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><del>Lastly, and most importantly, we have no idea how well the current server will be able to handle user load. For that reason, I will be continuing to monitor and make adjustments as needed. Performance may be spotty and unreliable as load resumes.~~ ~~Doesn't seem to be an issue, but we'll have to see how it goes with everyone trying to get on.</del> There are some load/efficiency problems that I'm trying to sort out.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><del>hCaptcha on signup is malfunctioning.</del></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><del><a href="http://i.ruqqus.com/">i.ruqqus.com</a> image uploads don't save.</del></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The most recent 30k or so comments didn't make it into the new host. Also possibly some post votes. I <em>think</em> all the comment votes made it in. The missing data is something I'm still working on, but you will probably see rep fluctuating unpredictably as vanished stuff is no longer counted.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>If you'd like to contribute to the future of freedom, please consider donating via <a href="https://patreon.com/ruqqus" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Patreon</a> or <a href="https://paypal.me/ruqqus" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Paypal</a> to help cover current and future server costs. <a href="https://ruqqus.com/help/donate">Cryptocurrency is also accepted</a>.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ruqqus.com/post/301l/you-cant-cancel-freedom-that-easily</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24400102</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 15:35:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[URL query parameters and how laxness creates de facto requirements on the web]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 7 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24399774">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/web/DeFactoQueryParameters | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/web/DeFactoQueryParameters">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2>URL query parameters and how laxness creates de facto requirements on the web</h2>

	<p><small>September  7, 2020</small></p>
</div><div><p>One of the ways that <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/dwiki/DWiki">DWiki</a> (the code behind <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/">Wandering Thoughts</a>) is unusual is that it strictly validates the query parameters
it receives on URLs, including on HTTP <code>GET</code> requests for ordinary
pages. If a HTTP request has unexpected and unsupported query
parameters, such a <code>GET</code> request will normally fail. When I made
this decision it seemed the cautious and conservative approach, but
<a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/web/CautionIsAMistakeToday">this caution has turned out to be a mistake on the modern web</a>. In practice, all sorts of sites will
generate versions of your URLs with all sorts of extra query
parameters tacked on, give them to people, and expect them to work.
If your website refuses to play along, (some) people won't get to
see your content. <strong>On today's web, you need to accept (and then
ignore) arbitrary query parameters on your URLs</strong>.</p>

<p>(Today's new query parameter is 's=NN', for various values of NN
like '04' and '09'. I'm not sure what's generating these URLs, but
it may be Slack.)</p>

<p>You might wonder how we got here, and that is a story of lax behavior
(or, if you prefer, being liberal in what you accept). In the
beginning, both Apache (for static web pages) and early web
applications often ignored extra query parameters on URLs, at least
on <code>GET</code> requests. I suspect that other early web servers also
imitated Apache here, but I have less exposure to their behavior
than Apache's. My guess is that this behavior wasn't deliberate,
it was just the simplest way to implement both Apache and early
web applications; you paid attention to what you cared about and
didn't bother to explicitly check that nothing else was supplied.</p>

<p>When people noticed that this behavior was commonplace and widespread,
they began using it. I believe that one of the early uses was for
embedding 'where this link was shared' information for your own web
analytics (<a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/web/AnalyticsVsSecurity">cf</a>), either based on your logs
or using JavaScript embedded in the page. In the way of things,
once this was common enough other people began helpfully tagging
the links that were shared through them for you, which is why I
began to see various 'utm_*' query parameters on inbound
requests to <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/">Wandering Thoughts</a> even though I never
published such URLs.
Web developers don't leave attractive nuisances alone for long, so
soon enough people were sticking on extra query parameters to your
URLs that were mostly for them and not so much for you. Facebook
may have been one of the early pioneers here with their 'fbclid'
parameter, but other websites have hopped on this particular train
since then (as I saw recently with these 's=NN' parameters).</p>

<p>At this point, the practice of other websites and services adding
random query parameters to your URLs that pass through them is so
wide spread and common that accepting random query parameters is
pretty much a practical requirement for any web content serving
software that wants to see wide use and not be irritating to the
people operating it. If, like <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/dwiki/DWiki">DWiki</a>, you stick to your guns and
refuse to accept some or all of them, you will drop some amount of
your incoming requests from real people, disappointing would be
readers.</p>

<p>This practical requirement for URL handling is not documented in
any specification, and it's probably not in most 'best practices'
documentation. People writing new web serving systems that are
tempted to be strict and safe and cautious get to learn about it
the hard way.</p>

<p>In general, any laxness in actual implementations of a system can
create a similar spiral of de facto requirements. Something that
is permitted and is useful to people will be used, and then supporting
that becomes a requirement. This is especially the case in a
distributed system like the web, where any attempt to tighten the
rules would only be initially supported by a minority of websites.
These websites would be 'outvoted' by the vast majority of websites
that allow the lax behavior and support it, because that's what
happens when the vast majority work and the minority don't.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/web/DeFactoQueryParameters</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24399774</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 14:50:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Named Parameters in C++20]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 83 | Comments 75 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24398756">thread link</a>) | @ibobev
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | https://pdimov.github.io/blog/2020/09/07/named-parameters-in-c20/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://pdimov.github.io/blog/2020/09/07/named-parameters-in-c20/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <div>
  
  <p><span>07 Sep 2020</span></p><p>A programming language supports <em>named parameters</em> when one
can call a function supplying the parameters by name, as in
the following hypothetical example (using C++ syntax):</p>

<div><div><pre><code>void f( int x, int y );

int main()
{
    f( x = 1, y = 2 );
}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>C++ is obviously not such a language and there have been
numerous proposals to rectify this omission, unfortunately none
of them successful. The latest attempt is Axel Naumann’s paper
<a href="http://www.open-std.org/jtc1/sc22/wg21/docs/papers/2018/p0671r2.html">Self-explanatory Function Arguments</a>,
which tries to attack the problem from another angle by just
allowing normal function calls to be tagged with the parameter
name, as in</p>



<p>enabling compilers to issue helpful warnings when a name doesn’t
match, but not allowing one to omit, or reorder, arguments.</p>

<p>Even in this limited form, named parameters would still be immensely
useful, but this is not what this post is about. What this post is
about is that we can already achieve something very close to named
parameters in C++20, by using a C99 feature called <em>designated
initializers</em>.</p>

<p>Designated initializers allow one to initialize structures by
member name, as in the following example:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>struct A
{
    int x;
    int y;
};

A a1 = { .x = 1, .y = 2 };
A a2 = { .x = 3 }; // a2.y == 0
A a3 = { .y = 4 }; // a3.x == 0
A a4 = { .y = 5, .x = 6 }; // valid C, invalid C++ (reorder)
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>C++ introduces a restriction C doesn’t have: the initializers
must follow the declaration order, similarly to how class member
initalizers are executed in member declaration order. But in
exchange, it allows us to supply default values:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>struct A
{
    int x = 0;
    int y = 0;
};

A a3 = { .y = 4 }; // a3.x == 0, no warning
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>You can already see where this is going. Instead of</p>



<p>we declare</p>



<p>and then call it like this:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>int main()
{
    f({ .x = 1, .y = 2 });
}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This works under <a href="https://godbolt.org/z/YfWj3W">GCC</a> and
<a href="https://godbolt.org/z/vbnz4T">Clang</a> even without <code>-std=c++20</code> because
they support designated initializers in earlier language modes as
an extension, and it works under <a href="https://godbolt.org/z/bKozaW">MSVC</a>
with <code>-std:c++latest</code>.</p>

<p>For a more realistic example, consider this snippet, taken from real
code, that sets a 10 second
<a href="https://www.boost.org/doc/libs/1_74_0/libs/beast/doc/html/beast/using_websocket/timeouts.html">timeout</a>
on a <a href="https://boost.org/libs/beast">Boost.Beast</a> websocket:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>#include &lt;boost/beast/websocket/stream.hpp&gt;
#include &lt;boost/beast/core/tcp_stream.hpp&gt;
#include &lt;chrono&gt;

void f1(boost::beast::websocket::stream&lt;boost::beast::tcp_stream&gt;&amp; ws)
{
    auto opt = boost::beast::websocket::stream_base::timeout();

    opt.keep_alive_pings = true;
    opt.idle_timeout = std::chrono::seconds(10);

    ws.set_option(opt);
}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Here’s how we can reformulate it by using the above idiom and <code>&lt;chrono&gt;</code>
literals:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>#include &lt;boost/beast/websocket/stream.hpp&gt;
#include &lt;boost/beast/core/tcp_stream.hpp&gt;
#include &lt;chrono&gt;

using namespace std::chrono_literals;

void f2(boost::beast::websocket::stream&lt;boost::beast::tcp_stream&gt;&amp; ws)
{
    ws.set_option({ .idle_timeout = 10s, .keep_alive_pings = true });
}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Apart from the slightly awkward <code>({ ... })</code> syntax and the need to observe
the right parameter order, that’s not that far from the ideal; and it’s
considerably better than <code>f1</code>.</p>

<p>This also works for constructors. Consider this hypothetical <code>vector</code> class
that is like <code>std::vector</code>, except with its various constructor overloads
replaced with one taking named parameters:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>template&lt;class T, class A = std::allocator&lt;T&gt;&gt; class vector
{
private:

    struct params
    {
        std::size_t size = 0;
        T element{};
        std::size_t capacity = 0;
        A allocator{};
    };

public:

    explicit vector( params p );
};
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This is <a href="https://godbolt.org/z/x17fdY">how it’s used</a>:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>auto f()
{
    vector&lt;int&gt; v{{ .size = 4, .element = 11, .capacity = 64 }};
    return v;
}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Again, apart from the odd <code>{{ ... }}</code> syntax, not that bad.</p>


</div>

<!--

<div class="related">
  <h2>Related posts</h2>
  <ul class="related-posts">
    
    
      <li>
        <h3>
          <a href="/blog/2020/09/06/why-use-the-boost-license/">
            Why You Should Use the Boost Software License
            <small>06 Sep 2020</small>
          </a>
        </h3>
      </li>
    
    
    
      <li>
        <h3>
          <a href="/blog/2020/09/05/from-simd-to-ast-extraction/">
            From SIMD to AST Extraction
            <small>05 Sep 2020</small>
          </a>
        </h3>
      </li>
    
    
    
      <li>
        <h3>
          <a href="/blog/2020/07/24/compilers-do-static-analysis/">
            Compilers Do Static Analysis, They Just Don't Tell You
            <small>24 Jul 2020</small>
          </a>
        </h3>
      </li>
    
    
  </ul>
</div>

-->

      </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://pdimov.github.io/blog/2020/09/07/named-parameters-in-c20/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24398756</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 11:51:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Think Real Hard]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24398649">thread link</a>) | @codesuki
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | https://www.benkuhn.net/thinkrealhard/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.benkuhn.net/thinkrealhard/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article><p>Famous physicist Murray Gell-Mann is supposed to have <a href="http://wiki.c2.com/?FeynmanAlgorithm" target="_blank">suggested</a> that Richard Feynman solved problems with the following cutting edge technique:</p><blockquote><ol><li>Write down the problem.</li><li>Think real hard.</li><li>Write down the solution.</li></ol></blockquote><p>Usually when people quote this, it’s to make a joke about how smart Feynman was. (If I tried this, I wouldn’t come up with quantum electrodynamics! I must not be able to think hard enough.) That’s one reading, but I prefer a different one.</p><p>When I started programming professionally, I was really excited about figuring out how to become a better programmer. (I still am!) So I asked a lot of people, “how can I become a better programmer?” But nobody gave me very satisfactory answers. They would tell me to play around with obscure programming languages, or study algorithms, or read papers, or do a bunch of other stuff that felt tangential and didn’t really move the needle.</p><p>In retrospect, I wish those people had just told me “think real hard.” I was looking for an easy way out—One Weird Trick to Programming Better—but programming is too hard for that.</p><p>That’s my preferred reading of the Feynman Algorithm: there is no one weird trick.</p><p>On the other hand, I <em>have</em> gotten a ton better at programming in the last four years. Not through any specific piece of advice, or any weird trick. Rather, it’s come by constantly trying to learn small new things, make small tool improvements, make my models a little deeper, work a little faster, come up with slightly better ideas. By, literally, thinking real hard, for a long, long time. The Feynman Algorithm works!</p><p>(That’s not to say good advice is impossible. I’m sure if <a href="http://www.informatika.bg/jeffdean" target="_blank">Jeff Dean</a> watched me go through my programming day, he would have tons of great tactical tips that would help me a lot. But even that depends on Jeff Dean being able to know which of his 10,000 tactical tips would be most useful to me. And the real difference between us isn’t the tactical tips, it’s the underlying models that generate the tips in the first place. Those seem to be nearly impossible to communicate.)</p><p>A lot of the things people ask for advice on fall into this category. “How can I be happier?” “How can I be more productive?” “How can I have a bigger impact on the world?” Sure, there are basic life hacks like sleeping well or getting exercise. But 99% of the “secret”—the thing that separates me from Gell-Mann, or Jeff Dean—is tacit knowledge. It often can’t be articulated any better than “think real hard.” But, believe it or not, thinking real hard, for real long, <em>does</em> work.</p></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.benkuhn.net/thinkrealhard/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24398649</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 11:30:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Raspberry Pi 3B+ Hackable Linux Handheld]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 133 | Comments 90 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24398485">thread link</a>) | @mmerlin
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | http://yarh.io/yarh-io-mki.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://yarh.io/yarh-io-mki.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
    <section id="top-section">
        <div id="top-section-top">
            <nav>
                
            </nav>
            <p id="heading">
                
                <h2>Raspberry Pi 3B+ Hackable Linux Handheld<br></h2>
            </p>
        </div>
    </section>
    <section id="yarh-io-mki">
        <div>
            <div>
                <div>
                    <p><a href="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-white-hand-large-t-001.png" target="_blank" data-lightbox="yarh-io-mki"><img src="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-white-hand-large-t-001.png"></a></p>
                    <div>
                        <p>YARH.IO is a fully hackable and custamizable Raspberry Pi based handheld, running Raspberry Pi OS and supporting all other Operating Systems available for Raspberry Pi.</p>
                        <p>The dream of a hackable&nbsp;Linux powered handheld has been around for many years, and many attempts have been made to create a working device. While some of the devices have reached the market, none of them withstood the test
                            of real world user experience.<br></p>
                        <p>YARH.IO project has taken on the challenge of building a fully functioning device by combining the best of Raspberry Pi design and 3D printing technology.&nbsp;<br></p>
                        <p>This project takes hackability to the next level by ensuring that every single component needed to build YARH.IO can be easily sourced, with no custom PCBs and just a bit of wire soldering required.&nbsp;</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <div>
                        <p>YARH.IO handheld and its unique modular design with exposed interfaces offers unprecedented connectivity with unlimited platforms and devices.<br></p>
                        <p>This model is powered by&nbsp;Raspberry Pi 3B+ and&nbsp;has the best ratio of functionality and computing power requirements for a mobile device. When it comes to the battery powered devices, the overall power consumption and longer
                            battery are more important then the extra processing power or memory.</p>
                        <p>For this model, the width of the main module is based on the keyboard dimensions for improved handling. The 5" Resistive Touch Screen 800x480 HDMI TFT LCD Display&nbsp;is a good option for YARH.IO as it&nbsp;will allow you to perform
                            all of the usual tasks with ease.&nbsp;<br></p>
                    </div>
                    <p><a href="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-red-right-large-t-001.png" target="_blank" data-lightbox="yarh-io-mki"><img src="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-red-right-large-t-001.png"></a></p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <p><a href="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-white-left-large-t-001.png" target="_blank" data-lightbox="yarh-io-mki"><img src="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-white-left-large-t-001.png"></a></p>
                    <div>
                        <p>Fosmon Portable Lightweight Mini Wireless Bluetooth Keyboard Controller has been selected as the best option for YARH.IO's multifunctional design. If you are using Vim, tmux, and Emacs everyday, the available modifier keys will
                            help you get the most out of the device.</p>
                        <p>In addition to the keyboard, YARH.IO's pointing device will allow you to effortlessly browse the internet and engage with other applications with graphical interface.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br></p>
                        <p>A single removable rechargeable battery will allow you to quickly replace an empty battery with a fully charged one. A high capacity Fenix ARB-L21-5000 5000mAh Li-ion Rechargeable Battery was chosen as the best option as it fits
                            the main module perfectly. For the charger/5v power supply the internals of a Fenix ARE-D1 Smart Charger were used.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <div>
                        <p>The RTC is a must have for a handheld device that is not continuously connected to the internet. YARH.IO includes a DS3231 High Precision RTC Clock Module.</p>
                        <p>Raspberry Pi GPIO connectors have been made available on the bottom sides of the main module and extension module for connecting all of your Raspberry Pi add-on boards.</p>
                        
                    </div>
                    <p><a href="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-black-top-large-t-001.png" target="_blank" data-lightbox="yarh-io-mki"><img src="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-black-top-large-t-001.png"></a></p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <p><a href="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-black-back-open-large-t-001.png" target="_blank" data-lightbox="yarh-io-mki"><img src="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-black-back-open-large-t-001.png"></a></p>
                    <div>
                        <p>YARH.IO features modular design, where the main module includes Raspberry Pi board, screen, power supply, battery, and RTC and GPIO connector with cables.&nbsp;</p>
                        <p>The main module can be used as a fully functioning handheld computer&nbsp;with the touch screen and onscreen keyboard available for the performance of your basic tasks.</p>
                        <p>One shared USB connector is available on the bottom of the main module, allows connecting USB devices like&nbsp;hard drives or Cellular/WiFi adaptors and mounted inside the extension module.</p>
                        <p>Raspberry Pi GPIO connector is also available on the bottom of the main module, allowing for different add-on modules,&nbsp;<br>including Lora radios, RFID readers/writers, and IR transivers, to&nbsp;be mounted inside the extension
                            module. This configuration works extremely well with Pi-DAC+, creating a great handheld audio player.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <p><a href="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-black-keyboard-large-t-001.png" target="_blank" data-lightbox="yarh-io-mki"><img src="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-black-keyboard-large-t-001.png"></a></p>
                    <div>
                        <p>No 'click' assembly here. This is a fully hackable device with stainless steel socket cap screw used&nbsp;throughout to allow for multiple assembly and disassembly cycles.&nbsp;The Military/Industrial aesthetic can be felt throughout
                            the YARH.IO project design.&nbsp;<br></p>
                        <p>The sturdy housing parts are 3D printed using PLA, ABS, and ASA plastic.&nbsp;<br></p>
                        
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <p><a href="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-black-back-keyboard-open-large-t-001.png" target="_blank" data-lightbox="yarh-io-mki"><img src="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-black-back-keyboard-open-large-t-001.png"></a></p>
                    <p>The list of parts used for the YARH.IO project can be purchased from Amazon and other online stores.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    
                    <p><a href="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-black-large-t-001.png" target="_blank" data-lightbox="yarh-io-mki"><img src="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-black-large-t-001.png"></a></p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <p><a href="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-white-front-large-t-001.png" target="_blank" data-lightbox="yarh-io-mki"><img src="http://yarh.io/assets/img/yarh-white-front-large-t-001.png"></a></p>
                    <div>
                        <p>YARH.IO MKI Project at a Glance.&nbsp;</p>
                        <p>The outcome of this YARH.IO model is a successful handheld device with the potential to connect an unlimited range of extension devices and modules. It is a ruggedly designed and fully hackable device that can be 3D printed and
                            assembled in the field.<br></p>
                        <p>As an experimental model YARH.IO's future development will continue to increase usability and functionality of the device. One of the areas of improvement is the adaptation of IPS type screen for wider viewing angles.&nbsp;<br></p>
                        <p>Other future development will focus on adding new compartment modules to accommodate additional I/O, storage and communication devices.&nbsp;<br></p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </section>
    <section id="yarh-io-mki-gallery">
        
    </section>
    <section id="yarh-io-mki-downloads">
        
    </section>
    <section id="footer">
        <div>
            <div>
                <div>
                    <div>
                        <p>© 2019-2020 YARH.IO | info@yarh.io</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </section>
    
    
    
    


</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://yarh.io/yarh-io-mki.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24398485</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 10:56:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Many Ways to Start an Xserver]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 72 | Comments 14 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24398154">thread link</a>) | @gbrown_
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | https://nixers.net/Thread-How-Many-Ways-To-Start-An-Xserver | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nixers.net/Thread-How-Many-Ways-To-Start-An-Xserver">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nixers.net/Thread-How-Many-Ways-To-Start-An-Xserver</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24398154</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 09:49:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Open Transclude for Networked Writing]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 14 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24398014">thread link</a>) | @Frodo478
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | http://subpixel.space/entries/open-transclude/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://subpixel.space/entries/open-transclude/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>tl;dr: If you follow this blog you’ve seen me experiment with iframe-based citations; this post is about open-sourcing that tooling. <a href="#tutorial-start" target="_self">Skip</a> to demo, implementation tutorial, and GitHub link.</p>

<hr>

<p>Knowledge tooling is happily becoming a hot topic again. With this trend is coming revived interest in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Project_Xanadu">Xanadu</a>, bi-directional hyperlinking, knowledge databases, visualizing knowledge graphs, and so on. At this moment, I see most of the emphasis being put on tooling for the research side, with Notion, Workflowy, and the new and hyped Roam Research leading the way.</p>

<p><img src="http://subpixel.space/uploads/xanadu-shot.png" alt="Screenshot of the OpenXanadu prototpye"></p>

<p>Where I see less focus is the <em>writing</em> part of the knowledge production process, where older apps like Scrivener are still the thing to beat. And almost nobody at all is working on the reader’s experience. As a blogger who largely caters to a wide audience, I’m especially interested in these areas.</p>

<p>Written information is largely still presented as a single document, and writing tools are geared toward the production of long pages. But before I say what’s wrong with this, let me sing the praises of documents for a moment.</p>

<p>People often get carried away when they discover the original vision of hypertext, which involves a network of documents, portions of which are “transcluded” (included via hypertext) into one another. The implication is that readers could follow any reference and see the source material—and granted, this would be transformative. However, there’s a limit to the effectiveness of the knowledge network as a reading experience. “Hypertext books,” online books which are made up of an abundance of interlinked HTML pages, are mostly unpopular. The failure of this experiment is, in my opinion, very revealing.</p>

<p><img src="http://subpixel.space/uploads/sprawlingplaces-shot.jpg" alt="Screenshot of tinderbox map of hypertext book Sprawling Places by David Kolb">
<span>Tinderbox map of a portion of David Kolb’s hypertext book Sprawling Places</span></p>

<p>Knowledge is not an accumulation of facts, nor is it even a set of facts and their relations. Facts are only rendered meaningful within narratives, and the single-page document is a format very conducive to narrative structure. The hypertext books that have gained popularity (I’m thinking here of <a href="http://meaningness.com/">Meaningness.com</a>) have largely conformed to this in two ways: 1) there is an intended reading order, and 2) the longer essays within the project do most of the heavy lifting in terms of imparting the author’s perspective to readers.</p>

<p>On the other hand, the notion of the “document” that is intrinsic to web development today is overdetermined by the legacy of print media. The web document is a static, <em>finished</em> artifact that does not bring in dynamic data. This is strange because it lives on a medium that is alive, networked, and dynamic, a medium which we increasingly understand more as a <em>space</em> than a thing.</p>

<p>For example, consider how silly it is to include MLA-style citations at the bottom of a text when we have the vast capabilities of linked documents on the web. Why should the reader have to read every citation or trust that an author is not taking a citation out of context, when hyperlinks are available?</p>

<p>This all suggests that a compromise must be struck between the coherence of a text and the new opportunities for knowledge work afforded by the fundamental capabilities of the medium: the internet’s connectivity, the screen’s frame rate.</p>

<hr>

<p>My own blogging is one context in which I’ve seen this tension play out, and have been working to explore ways of making my texts richer. A lot of the ideas I talk about in various pieces of writing are connected to one another. When I publish an essay, I’m not done with it. The ideas live on and get renewed, reused, and recycled in later works. Some sentences contain definitions that are core to my mental models, and there are whole paragraphs that might be useful out of context. I’m building my knowledge network in mind maps and behind various SaaS APIs, but how can I publicly show my thinking to be part a cohesive worldview?</p>

<p>Normally people solve this by simply block quoting themselves, but this is a waste of an opportunity. The indented block quote is a print medium invention <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Block_quotation#Origins">almost as old as typesetting</a>. The block quote is <em>plaintext</em>, it is not actually linked to the original text or its context.</p>

<p>I’ve been experimenting with one idea for a solution, and if you’ve read the last couple blog posts you’ll have seen it there. My stab at an answer is an iframe which shows the quote within its original context and gives a hint at its surroundings. Effectively, it’s a transclusion within my own blog. I’m currently satisfied with what I have as a v1, and am interested to see if others find it useful, so I’m open sourcing it here and including a tutorial.</p>



<p>Open Transclude is a UX pattern, a spec for networked writing within your own blog. Here’s how it looks:</p>



<!-- <script src="/portal.js"></script> -->



<p>What you are looking at is an scroll-locked iframe that links to a quote I picked out of my blog post “Notes on Comparative Psychology.” You can use Open Transclude anywhere you can drop an <code>&lt;a&gt;</code> tag on your own site.</p>

<p>Open Transclude:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Works anywhere on your own domain</li>
  <li>Compatible with most static site generators / templating engines</li>
  <li>12 lines of HTML, 80 lines of SCSS, 22 lines of JS (4.5 kb total)</li>
  <li>Has 0 dependencies&nbsp;— this is native web technology</li>
</ul>

<p>Open Transclude is extremely simple, and the heaviest part of the code is the CSS, which you can simplify at your whim. That’s why I am referring to it as a UX pattern. This is not a protocol. The code is really a commodity. What’s interesting about it is the idea and the design, and this is just one viable implementation! Feel free to adapt it however you like.</p>

<p>The principal improvement over a block quotation is <em>sense of context</em>.</p>

<p>Over on GitHub you’ll find the <a href="https://github.com/tobyshorin/Open-Transclude/">reference implementation for Jekyll</a>. Below is a tutorial for implementing it yourself, by way of also explaining some of the technical design decisions.</p>

<hr>

<h2 id="implementation-recipe">Implementation Recipe</h2>

<p>Here’s what you need to do to get Open Transclude up and running.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Create an anchor tag in the blog post where you want to cite yourself.</li>
  <li>Create the HTML for the reusable transclusion component.</li>
  <li>Call the portal into any document and passing it Jekyll variables.</li>
  <li>A small piece of Javascript which populates your transclusion into the document.</li>
  <li>Create the SCSS file with the component’s styles.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="1-create-the-anchor-tag-where-you-want-to-cite-yourself">1. <strong>Create the anchor tag where you want to cite yourself</strong></h3>

<p>To quote yourself, you’ll need to create an <code>&lt;a&gt;</code> anchor tag in the markdown file for the post you want to quote. If you wish to highlight a specific piece of text, instead create a <code>&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</code> around the section you want to quote. Note that this can <em>only be on your own website</em>—it doesn’t work cross domain.</p>

<p>Here’s what it looks like for the example iframe above.</p>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="markdown">It will, for one thing, become newly conscious of itself, and, to the degree that it is, <span>**it will tend to undermine its own experiential integrity**</span>" (emphasis mine).

<span>&lt;span</span> <span>name=</span><span>"mainstream-magic"</span><span>&gt;</span>Ironically, psychology remains one of the closest things we have to a mainstream magic or a mystical art today. Not only is it plainly the direct descendent of medieval magic, as I learned when I read Ioan Coulianou's <span>*Eros and Magic in the Renaissance*</span> earlier this year. <span>**It is a theory of the self that is phenomenologically accurate, objectively wrong, and is based on magical thinking even as it deconstructs itself**</span>.<span>&lt;/span&gt;</span> Some magical thinking processes that happen in psychotherapy, such as <span>[</span><span>transference to the psychologist</span><span>](</span><span>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transference#Transference_and_countertransference_during_psychotherapy</span><span>)</span>, are even intended to stay unmentioned to the patient in order to be utilized most effectively by the therapist!</code></pre></figure>

<h3 id="2-create-your-iframe-component">2. Create your iframe component</h3>

<p>This is most useful as a standardized component which can be used across the site, so we are going to take advantage of Jekyll’s templating features. Jekyll and other static site generators like Kirby and Zola support HTML “partials” or “includes” so that you can create reusable components.</p>

<p>In your <code>/_scss</code> or <code>/_sass</code> folder make a new file, <code>portal.scss</code>. I called it “portal” because it’s shorter than “transclusion” and less prone to spelling errors.</p>

<p>Here’s our component:</p>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="html"><span>&lt;div</span> <span>class=</span><span>"portal-container"</span><span>&gt;</span>
    <span>&lt;div</span> <span>class=</span><span>"portal-head"</span><span>&gt;</span>
        <span>&lt;div</span> <span>class=</span><span>"portal-backlink"</span> <span>&gt;</span>
            <span>&lt;div</span> <span>class=</span><span>"portal-title"</span><span>&gt;</span>From <span>&lt;span</span> <span>class=</span><span>"portal-text-title"</span><span>&gt;</span>{{ include.title }}<span>&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</span>
            <span>&lt;a</span> <span>href=</span><span>"{{ include.link }}"</span> <span>class=</span><span>"portal-arrow"</span><span>&gt;</span>Go to text <span>&lt;span</span> <span>class=</span><span>"right-arrow"</span><span>&gt;</span>→<span>&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</span>
        <span>&lt;/div&gt;</span>
    <span>&lt;/div&gt;</span>
    <span>&lt;div</span> <span>id=</span><span>"portal-parent-{{include.anchor}}"</span> <span>class=</span><span>"portal-parent"</span><span>&gt;</span>
        <span>&lt;div</span> <span>class=</span><span>"portal-parent-fader-top"</span><span>&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</span>
        <span>&lt;div</span> <span>class=</span><span>"portal-parent-fader-bottom"</span><span>&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</span>        
        <span>&lt;!-- We'll use Javascript to populate the iframe right here --&gt;</span>
    <span>&lt;/div&gt;</span>    
<span>&lt;/div&gt;</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>You’ll notice immediately that the iframe isn’t there yet. Like I mentioned above, we’re going to be populating it with Javascript.</p>

<p>You’ll also see that in various places we’re using <code>{{ include.___}}</code>. A cool thing about Jekyll includes its that it’s possible to define variables and pass them to our include, so we can create reusable components across our site. Dave Rupert has a <a href="https://daverupert.com/2017/07/jekyll-includes-are-cool/">nice blog post about this</a> called if you want to see more advanced examples!</p>

<h3 id="3-calling-the-component">3. Calling the component</h3>

<p>Anytime you want to pull this component into a blog post, all you have to do is <code>include</code> it in the markdown of another blog post, like this:</p>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="html">  {% include portal.html title="Notes On Comparative Psychology" link="/entries/notes-on-comparative-psychology/#mainstream-magic" anchor="emotional-deficit" %} </code></pre></figure>

<p>When you include it, you’ll need to pass in those three variables - title, link, and anchor, that fill in the includes above. If you’re following along now and making a build in Jekyll, you’ll see an empty, unstyled component with the link. So good so far!</p>

<h3 id="4-populating-with-javascript">4. Populating with Javascript</h3>

<p>This is a good time to address why we need Javascript. Web developers reading this are probably asking why we don’t simply put the full <code>/link#with-anchor</code> into the iframe src and be done with it. …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://subpixel.space/entries/open-transclude/">http://subpixel.space/entries/open-transclude/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://subpixel.space/entries/open-transclude/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24398014</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 09:23:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Threat modelling case study: bicycles]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 68 | Comments 98 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24397852">thread link</a>) | @calpaterson
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | http://calpaterson.com/bicycle-threat-model.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://calpaterson.com/bicycle-threat-model.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
        
        <p>August 2020</p>
        <p id="article-description">How to avoid buying your bike again every 6-12
        months and tips for how to apply the same reasoning to other things, like
        computers</p>
        <hr>
        <figure>
            <img src="http://calpaterson.com/assets/solitary-wheel.jpeg" alt="a solitary wheel left behind after the rest of the bike was nicked">
            <figcaption>
                Rucksack Rupert strikes again
            </figcaption>
        </figure>
        <p>Some very commonly repeated advice on preventing someone from nicking your
        bike:</p>
        <blockquote>
            <p>Buy a good [~10% of bicycle value] lock, ideally one with a high
            "SoldSecure" rating and lock your bicycle somewhere inside the rear
            triangle and the rear wheel.</p>
        </blockquote>
        <p>I've seen this advice repeated in cycling magazines, in quality newspapers,
        sometimes even by the police and of course on internet forums.</p>
        <p>The above would imply that if you own a £400 bicycle (<a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/395884/bicycle-average-prices-in-the-european-union-eu-by-country/">a
        typical price in the UK</a>) you'd buy a £40 lock and put it in the right
        place.</p>
        <p>However, it is a cold fact that a cordless angle grinder can defeat any
        bicycle lock, no matter how expensive (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pywN558dJaU&amp;t=198">see this video for a
        demonstration</a>). You can buy a used cordless angle grinder on eBay for less
        than £100. Even U-locks - traditionally thought to be the strongest type of
        lock - are opened in seconds with a sub-£100 angle grinder.</p>
        <p>There is other advice floating around of doubtful value, for example:</p>
        <blockquote>
            <p>Add your bicycle to a national register</p>
        </blockquote>
        <p>But cases where BikeRadar manage to reunite bicycles with their owners seem
        to be the exception rather than the rule. Probably this is because, as with
        cars, the first thing you do with a stolen bicycle is take it across a border
        to somewhere different.</p>
        <blockquote>
            <p>Lock your bicycle inside a secure building or place, away from sight</p>
        </blockquote>
        <p>This prevents opportunistic theft but if this space is shared with others
        (apartment blocks and offices) it in fact serves to increase the economies of
        scale for prepared thieves who break into your storage area late at night with
        a van. It's not uncommon for office bicycle stores (with many fancy, expensive
        bikes inside) to be emptied out completely overnight by professional
        thieves.</p>
        <h2>A threat model, by user persona</h2>
        <p>I think the advice above is poor because it doesn't come from a systematic
        consideration of the problem <em>from the point of view of thieves</em>.</p>
        <p>To come up with better advice requires a threat model, which is a piece of
        jargon for taking a holistic view of the danger posed by attackers. I think one
        of the simplest and most straightforward ways to do threat modelling is by
        <em>user persona</em>, whereby you consider each kind of attacker in turn,
        making some reasonable assumptions about their level of motivation and
        methods.</p>
        <p>As far as bicycle theft is concerned there are three basic types of
        thief.</p>
        <h3>"No-tools Nigel", the rank opportunist</h3>
        <p>Nigel has just his two hands and is simply looking for a ride home or maybe
        something he can sell to a friend for some quick cash.</p>
        <p>Nigel will steal any unlocked bicycle.</p>
        <p>Nigel is also able to take any bicycle parts that can be removed without
        tools. That means any quick-release wheels or thumbscrew saddles. In an urban
        area your parked bicycle may be passed by a Nigel as often as a few times an
        hour so anything that is not bolted down won't last very long.</p>
        <h3>"Rucksack Rupert", the thief with a few hand tools</h3>
        <p>Rupert has a small pair of shears; 4, 5 and 6mm Allen keys and a 15mm
        spanner for wheel nuts.</p>
        <p>Rupert will make his way through cable locks with his shears. If there is a
        valuable part that can be removed with hand tools he will take it. He is
        particularly keen on premium saddles and name brand wheels.</p>
        <h3>"Powertool Percy", the professional with a complete set of tools</h3>
        <p>Percy has a small collection of electric and air tools including an angle
        grinder as well as bolt-cutters and an air-jack. He has access to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fence_(criminal)">criminal fences</a> which he
        can use to sell stolen bicycles quickly. Percy often arrives in his van and
        this allows him to steal multiple bikes at once.</p>
        <p>No bicycle is safe from Percy. No lock can hold against his angle grinder.
        Often he finds if he's wearing a hi-vis jacket he can even get away with using
        his power tools in broad daylight. He's willing to chance that if the bicycle
        seems valuable enough.</p>
        <h2>Coming up with better advice based on Nigel, Rupert and Percy</h2>
        <p>In order to keep your bicycle safe you need to take steps against all three
        levels of imaginary thieves.</p>
        <p>"No-tools Nigel" will be warded off simply by:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>Locking your bicycle whenever you leave it - even if just for a
            minute</li>
            <li>Ensuring you leave nothing on your bicycle that can be removed without
            tools
                <ul>
                    <li>replace quick-release wheel skewers with bolts</li>
                    <li>take your lights with you when you park in public</li>
                    <li>make sure your saddle is not on a thumbscrew</li>
                </ul>
            </li>
        </ul>
        <p>"Rucksack Rupert" will be deterred by:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>Not using a cable lock!</li>
            <li>Making sure that nothing good can be removed from your bicycle with
            hand tools
                <ul>
                    <li>Lock both wheels <em>and the frame</em> to the bike stand -
                    don't rely on bolts</li>
                </ul>
            </li>
        </ul>
        <p>"Powertool Percy" will be kept at bay by:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>Nothing, save ensuring that your bicycle doesn't look valuable enough
            to be worth his time
                <ul>
                    <li>this probably means keeping its value down below a few hundred
                    pounds</li>
                </ul>
            </li>
        </ul>
        <h2>The virtue of the "bicycle shaped object"</h2>
        <p>Valuable bicycles (&gt;£1000) have an extremely short half-life in urban
        areas. The sad truth is that the Percys of the world are common enough and
        resourceful enough that a bicycle worth over a thousand pounds isn't really
        safe anywhere in a large town. <strong>This includes most e-bikes.</strong> You
        might notice that cycle couriers who have e-bikes tend to eat lunch while
        looking directly at their locked e-bike, so that it never goes out of their
        sight. Few people in other lines of work can do the same.</p>
        <p>If the tyres are inflated, my own commuter bicycle is probably worth £30 to
        the right buyer. My bicycle is so low-end that cycling snobs refer to it as a
        mere "bicycle shaped object". Rather selfishly I am glad that such snobs exist
        as having a lot of more valuable bicycles around provides me with good ambient
        security. No thief is going to bother cutting my locks when there is a
        Campagnolo on the next rack.</p>
        <p>One father I know had his primary-school-age daughter "decorate" his
        commuting bicycle with girly stickers and pink glitter. If anyone examines his
        bicycle closely he looks like a complete loon but I think his motivation is
        right: it's going to be much less appealing to steal when it's covered in Miffy
        stickers.</p>
        <h3>Insurance - not usually worth it</h3>
        <p>What about bicycle insurance? It's fairly expensive here in the UK, usually
        10-15% of the bicycle's value annually and insurers typically only pay out when
        the whole bicycle is taken (so if if your front wheel is nicked, you're on your
        own) and when you can demonstrate that it was locked to their standards. Often
        these standards require that it is locked up indoors which means you're
        chancing it whenever you park away from your home or office.</p>
        <h2>Lists of "best practices" vs having your own threat model</h2>
        <p>The same thing goes for securing your bicycle as for securing other things:
        pat, concrete pieces of security advice are something to treat with a bit of
        doubt.</p>
        <p>In bicycles the common mantra is "spend 10% on a lock" but in computing the
        mantras are slogans such as "use a strong password", "back up your important
        data" or "use encryption" but these can all be just as vapid.</p>
        <p>"Strong passwords!" as a slogan fails to address the fact that the average
        internet user has hundreds of logins for various sites (my own password manager
        has over 700 sites recorded). The majority of internet users decide on a single
        "strong password" and then use it everywhere. They are only a single bad
        sysadmin or javascript injection away from losing access to every account on
        every website they have.</p>
        <p>Backing up your important data is only an aid to your security if the backup
        is stored as securely as the original. Much user data is stolen or exposed
        through poorly secured backups on shared fileservers. A huge number of people
        have passport and utility bill scans in their Dropbox - again, behind the same
        email and password they use everywhere. Companies can be surprisingly sloppy
        with backups too: often dumped into cloud storage somewhere once before the Big
        Migration and never removed.</p>
        <p>Encryption is troublesome as it can give undue confidence that can backfire
        spectacularly: a quarter of a million American diplomatic cables were
        inadvertantly published in unredacted form when a Guardian journalist <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WikiLeaks:_Inside_Julian_Assange%27s_War_on_Secrecy">
        included the password for an widely-distributed encrypted file in his book</a>.
        Apparently he thought the file's password was somehow temporary. It wasn't.</p>
        <p>Instead of following such "best practices" it's much more intellectually
        robust to <strong>come up with your own threat model</strong> - then you can
        decide your own concrete steps instead of just following the security steps of
        others which might be inapplicable or even wrong.</p>
        <h2>Some hints on coming up with your own …</h2></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://calpaterson.com/bicycle-threat-model.html">http://calpaterson.com/bicycle-threat-model.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://calpaterson.com/bicycle-threat-model.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24397852</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 08:58:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Things I Learned to Become a Senior Software Engineer]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 134 | Comments 116 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24397269">thread link</a>) | @janvdberg
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | https://neilkakkar.com/things-I-learned-to-become-a-senior-software-engineer.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://neilkakkar.com/things-I-learned-to-become-a-senior-software-engineer.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>In 2018, I started working at Bloomberg. Things have changed a lot since. I’m not the most junior member in the company anymore and I’ve mentored quite a few new engineers, which has been amazing. It helped me observe how others differ from me, absorb their best practices, and figure out things I’ve unconsciously been doing pretty well.</p>

<p>Yearly work reviews are a good way to condense these lessons I’ve learned.  They’re valuable for pattern matching, too. Only when I zoom out do certain patterns become visible. I can then <a href="https://neilkakkar.com/the-human-log.html">start tracking these patterns consciously</a>.</p>

<p>The broad theme for this year is zooming out and challenging the boundaries. It’s also about zooming in, and adding nuance to the sections from last year. It’s more fun if you’ve <a href="https://neilkakkar.com/year-in-review-2019.html">read last year’s review first</a>: You can then diff my growth.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2">1</a></sup></p>

<p>It all began with a question: How do I grow further?</p>





<nav>

  <h4>Table of Contents</h4>

<ul id="markdown-toc">
  <li><a href="#growing-using-different-ladders-of-abstraction" id="markdown-toc-growing-using-different-ladders-of-abstraction">Growing using different ladders of abstraction</a></li>
  <li><a href="#learning-what-people-around-me-are-doing" id="markdown-toc-learning-what-people-around-me-are-doing">Learning what people around me are doing</a></li>
  <li>
<a href="#learning-good-habits-of-mind" id="markdown-toc-learning-good-habits-of-mind">Learning good habits of mind</a>    <ul>
      <li><a href="#thinking-well" id="markdown-toc-thinking-well">Thinking Well</a></li>
      <li><a href="#strategies-for-making-day-to-day-more-effective" id="markdown-toc-strategies-for-making-day-to-day-more-effective">Strategies for making day-to-day more effective</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#acquiring-new-tools-for-thought--mental-models" id="markdown-toc-acquiring-new-tools-for-thought--mental-models">Acquiring new tools for thought &amp; mental models</a></li>
  <li><a href="#protect-your-slack" id="markdown-toc-protect-your-slack">Protect your slack</a></li>
  <li><a href="#ask-questions" id="markdown-toc-ask-questions">Ask Questions</a></li>
  <li><a href="#noticing-confusion" id="markdown-toc-noticing-confusion">Noticing Confusion</a></li>
  <li><a href="#force-multipliers" id="markdown-toc-force-multipliers">Force multipliers</a></li>
  <li><a href="#on-ownership" id="markdown-toc-on-ownership">On Ownership</a></li>
  <li><a href="#embrace-fear" id="markdown-toc-embrace-fear">Embrace fear</a></li>
  <li>
<a href="#adding-nuance" id="markdown-toc-adding-nuance">Adding nuance</a>    <ul>
      <li><a href="#writing-code" id="markdown-toc-writing-code">Writing Code</a></li>
      <li><a href="#testing" id="markdown-toc-testing">Testing</a></li>
      <li>
<a href="#design" id="markdown-toc-design">Design</a>        <ul>
          <li><a href="#gathering-requirements" id="markdown-toc-gathering-requirements">Gathering Requirements</a></li>
        </ul>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#some-hacks-that-have-worked-very-well-for-me" id="markdown-toc-some-hacks-that-have-worked-very-well-for-me">Some hacks that have worked very well for me</a></li>
  <li><a href="#super-powers" id="markdown-toc-super-powers">Super powers</a></li>
  <li>
<a href="#some-gotchas-with-growing" id="markdown-toc-some-gotchas-with-growing">Some gotchas with growing</a>    <ul>
      <li><a href="#sometimes-i-feel-i-need-to-know-the-answer-to-everything" id="markdown-toc-sometimes-i-feel-i-need-to-know-the-answer-to-everything">Sometimes, I feel I need to know the answer to everything</a></li>
      <li><a href="#sometimes-i-lose-my-cool" id="markdown-toc-sometimes-i-lose-my-cool">Sometimes, I lose my cool</a></li>
      <li><a href="#neophilia" id="markdown-toc-neophilia">Neophilia</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#questions" id="markdown-toc-questions">Questions</a></li>
</ul>

</nav>

<!-- works only once jQuery is loaded -->


<h2 id="growing-using-different-ladders-of-abstraction">Growing using different ladders of abstraction</h2>

<p>Entering my second year, I had all the basics in place. I had picked all the low hanging fruit, and my rate of growth slowed down. Not good. The big question in my mind was “How do I grow further?”</p>

<p>There was only so much I could do to improve my coding skills. Most blogs epousing techniques to write cleaner code, repeating yourself, not repeating yourself, etc. are micro-optimisations. Almost none of them would make me instantly impactful.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3">2</a></sup></p>

<p>However, I did figure out something insightful. I’m working inside the software development lifecycle, but this lifecycle is part of a bigger lifecycle: the product and infrastructure development lifecycle. I decided to go broader instead of deeper. Surprisingly, the breadth provided more depth to what I knew.</p>

<p>I zoomed out in 3 broad directions: learning what people around me are doing, learning good habits of mind, and acquiring new tools for thought.</p>

<h2 id="learning-what-people-around-me-are-doing">Learning what people around me are doing</h2>

<p>Since we’re not in a closed system, it makes sense to better understand the job of the product managers, the sales people, and the analysts. In the end it’s a business making money through products. The goal isn’t to write code, it’s to be a profitable business.<sup id="fnref:15"><a href="#fn:15">3</a></sup></p>

<p>Most big companies aren’t doing just one thing, which means there are different paths to making money in the same company. Everyone is on at least one path - if they weren’t, they wouldn’t be here.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1">4</a></sup> Tracking these paths, and the path I’m on was pretty valuable. It helped me see how I matter, and what levers I can pull to become more effective. Sometimes, it’s about making the sales jobs easier, so they can make more sales. Other times, it’s about building a new feature for clients. And some other times, it’s about improving a feature that keeps breaking.</p>

<p>Product managers are the best source for this. They know how the business makes money, who are the clients, and what do clients need.</p>

<p>Over the year, I setup quite a few meetings with everyone on my path. A second benefit this gave me was the context of other’s jobs. It helped me communicate better. Framing things in the right way is powerful.</p>

<p>For example, one conversation helped me appreciate why Sarah in Sales wants a bulk update tool. Some companies have lots of employees, and  updating them one by one is a pain. The code I write would literally ease Sarah’s pain.</p>

<!-- More recently, I got a chance to sit in on a few product scoping meetings between teams. This gave me a lot more appreciation for the job my PM and TLs do. Communication is surprisingly hard, and aligning different teams takes skill. -->

<!-- Force multiplier in team vs force multiplier in the entire chain. -->

<h2 id="learning-good-habits-of-mind">Learning good habits of mind</h2>

<p>Software engineering entails thinking well and making the right decisions. Programming is implementing those decisions.</p>

<p>A habit of mind is something your brain does regularly. This could be thinking of X whenever you see Y happen, or applying thinking tool X to problem Y. In short, habits of mind facilitate better thinking.</p>

<p>I suspected if I learn the general skill, I should be able to apply it better to software engineering.</p>

<h3 id="thinking-well">Thinking Well</h3>

<p>Software engineering is an excellent field to practice thinking well in. The feedback loops are shorter, and gauging correctness doesn’t take too long.</p>

<p>I dived into cognitive science studies. It’s a permanent skill that’s worth exploring - a force multiplier for whatever I end up doing, and pays dividends throughout my life. One output was <a href="https://neilkakkar.com/Bayes-Theorem-Framework-for-Critical-Thinking.html">a framework for critical thinking</a>. It’s compounding, <a href="https://neilkakkar.com/year-in-review-2019.html#compounding-is-powerful-building-intuition-for-compounding-even-more-so">and compounding is powerful</a>.</p>

<p>There’s lots of good things that came out of this, which I’ll talk about in a bit. They deserve their own section.</p>

<h3 id="strategies-for-making-day-to-day-more-effective">Strategies for making day-to-day more effective</h3>

<p>The other side of the coin is habits that allow you to think well. It starts with noticing little irritations during the day, inefficiencies in meetings, and then figuring out strategies to avoid them. These strategic improvements are underrated.</p>

<p>You decide what to do, and then let it run on automatic, freeing up the brain to think of more fun stuff. Of course, that’s what a habit is, too.</p>

<p>Some good habits I’ve noticed:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Never leave a meeting without making the decision / having a next action</li>
  <li>Decide who is going to get it done. Things without an owner rarely get done.</li>
  <li>Document design decisions made during a project</li>
</ul>

<p>This pattern became visible during the review, so I’m keen to pay attention and collect more strategies next year. Having an excellent scrum master who holds me accountable has helped me get better at following these strategies.</p>



<p>New tools for thought are related to thinking well, but more specific to software engineering. Tools for thought help me think better about specific engineering problems.</p>

<p>I’ve adopted a just-in-time approach to this. I look for new tools only when I get stuck on something, or when I find out my abstractions and design decisions aren’t working well.</p>

<p>For example, I was recently struggling with a domain with lots of complex business logic. Edge cases were the norm, and we wanted to design a system that handles this cleanly. That’s when I read about <a href="https://amzn.to/2FdCYUQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Domain Driven Design</a><sup id="fnref:25"><a href="#fn:25">5</a></sup>. I could instantly put it to practice and make a big difference. Subsequently, I grasped these concepts better. I acquired a new mental model of how to create enterprise software.</p>

<p>The second way I keep learning and acquiring new mental models is via reading what surfaces on Hacker News. They are interesting ideas, some of which I’ve put to practice, but this is a lot less effective than the technique above. The only reason I still do this is to <a href="https://neilkakkar.com/rationality.html#map-and-the-territory">map the territory</a> - it keeps me aware of techniques that exist, so when I face a problem, I know there’s a method that might help.</p>

<p>The final way I acquire better mental models is by learning new diverse languages. The diversity bit is important. Learning yet another dialect of lisp has a lot less benefit than say, learning C++03, a functional programming language, a dynamic typed language, and a lisp. Today, <a href="https://www.hillelwayne.com/post/j-notation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">J seems interesting</a>, and one I might consider learning. It’s a thinking model I haven’t used before.</p>

<p>I’ve gotten lots of value from doing this. Each language has its own vocabulary and grammar, and <a href="https://neilkakkar.com/vocabulary-mental-model.html">vocabulary is a meta-mental model</a>. It’s a new lens to look at how to do things.</p>

<p>When memory management is in your control, you understand how pointers and allocators work. When Python then abstracts this away, you appreciate the complexity reduction. When maps and filters in a functional language show up, you appreciate how Python’s for loops can be improved. Indeed, that’s what list comprehensions are. And then you notice how some things are easier with object oriented programming. There’s no one magic tool that fits everything well. And then you understand that despite this, you don’t have to switch tools. You can adapt best practices from one into another to solve your problems: like writing functional javascript. It’s the principles that matter more than their expression.</p>

<figure>
    
    <img src="https://neilkakkar.com/assets/images/divider.jpg" alt="">
    
    
    
</figure>

<p>Broadly, that’s all I did this year. What follow are insights that sprang forth thanks to zooming out.</p>

<h2 id="protect-your-slack">Protect your slack</h2>

<p>When I say slack, I don’t mean the company, but the adjective.</p>

<p>One thing that gives me high output and productivity gains is to “slow down”. Want to get more done? Slow down.</p>

<p>Caveats apply, but here’s what I mean:</p>

<p>I’ve noticed people rush to solve problems. It can be something they’ve done before, or something we have a template for. It feels pretty good to smash through things. I’ve done that before, too! However, there’s very specific cases where this makes sense.<sup id="fnref:11"><a href="#fn:11">6</a></sup></p>

<p>Whenever I’m working on something new, I take the time to learn things about the system I’m working on, and things closely related to it. If it’s too massive, I optimise for learning as much as I can. Every time I revisit the system, I aim to learn more.</p>

<p>When <a href="https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/yLLkWMDbC9ZNKbjDG/slack" target="_blank" rel="noopener">there is slack</a>, you get a chance to experiment, learn, and think things through. This means you get enough time to get things done.</p>

<p>When there is no slack, deadlines are tight, and all your focus goes into getting shit done.</p>

<p>Protecting your slack means not letting deadlines wrap tight around you. Usually, this is as simple (or hard) as communicating.<sup id="fnref:16"><a href="#fn:16">7</a></sup></p>

<p>Slack might have a negative connotation with “slackers”, but protecting slack is a super power. It’s a long term investment into building yourself up at the cost of short term efficiency.</p>

<p>When I’m quickly dishing out stories, I also have a much harder time fixing bugs. I don’t take the time to create proper mental models of the system, which means my assumptions don’t match the code, and this mismatch is where most bugs lie.</p>

<p>I protect my slack, so I can take the time out to prioritise …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://neilkakkar.com/things-I-learned-to-become-a-senior-software-engineer.html">https://neilkakkar.com/things-I-learned-to-become-a-senior-software-engineer.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://neilkakkar.com/things-I-learned-to-become-a-senior-software-engineer.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24397269</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 07:11:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Never Lose a Part Again, with the Ultimate Component Storage System]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 23 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24396611">thread link</a>) | @kevinqqsam
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | https://www.hackster.io/news/never-lose-a-part-again-with-the-ultimate-component-storage-system-00987cde6744 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.hackster.io/news/never-lose-a-part-again-with-the-ultimate-component-storage-system-00987cde6744">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section><div><p><span>The creator of </span><a href="https://www.instructables.com/id/The-Ultimate-Component-Storage-System/" rel="nofollow">this project</a><span>, APTechnologies, came up with the idea for the storage cabinet by observing that he would run into trouble when organizing his component library. Rather than having to go across the workshop to get each part, he wanted a way to consolidate everything into one place for easy finding. The system works by first having the user search for a part on an adjacent screen, and then the associated bin will light up if the component is found in the system.</span></p><h3 id="toc-designing-the-cabinet-0"><a href="#toc-designing-the-cabinet-0"><i></i></a><span>Designing the Cabinet</span></h3><p>The storage solution is comprised of a 35 x 12 grid of drawers, which gives ample space for parts. The drawers are laid out according to the spacing between the LEDs in the strip (30 LEDs/meter). They are meant to be printed individually and then slotted in, plus they come in several different sizes.</p><h3 id="toc-fabrication-1"><a href="#toc-fabrication-1"><i></i></a><span>Fabrication</span></h3><p>Each drawer was 3D-printed on a Prusa Mk2S with PLA filament at a .2mm layer height. In order to minimize filament consumption, wall thicknesses are kept very thin, but even with this savings, 5kg of filament was required to fabricate the parts. There is also a small articulating arm that juts out from the side for the HDMI display.</p><h3 id="toc-software-2"><a href="#toc-software-2"><i></i></a><span>Software</span></h3><p>The primary way to interact with the system is through the terminal, which runs a Python 3 script. It begins by checking the text file for data integrity, where it then gets parsed and loaded into an object. Data is stored in CSV-style fashion, with the ID being the first column, the associated LEDs in the second, and finally the quantity in the third column. All subsequent values are optional and simply loaded by the user when the parts is located. A regex is used to parse the user's request, including searching for a component, changing its quantity, adding a new part, and removing a component.</p><h3 id="toc-electronics-3"><a href="#toc-electronics-3"><i></i></a><span>Electronics</span></h3><p>According to the project's creator, the choice for hardware components was quite straightforward. He used a Raspberry Pi 4 Model B in conjunction with a generic HDMI monitor to show the command line interface. For power delivery, he opted for a simple 5V adapter to power both the Raspberry Pi 4 and NeoPixel strip. Since the Pi outputs 3.3v signals from its GPIO pins, a level-shifter is needed, in this case a 74AHCT125. There is an option to use an Arduino Uno via UART if the NeoPixel strip is too unreliable, since the Arduino Uno can supply stricter timings.</p><h3 id="toc-usage-4"><a href="#toc-usage-4"><i></i></a><span>Usage</span></h3><p><span>To add a new part, the command </span><code>PI&lt;ledn&gt;:PI&lt;ledn+k&gt;, &lt;quantity&gt;[, optional parameters]:add</code><span> is sent, which adds a new component to the library. Other commands such as ID&lt;id number&gt; (search for part by ID) and ID&lt;id number&gt;:rm (remove part with that ID) exist to manage added components in the library.</span></p><h3 id="toc-possible-additions-5"><a href="#toc-possible-additions-5"><i></i></a><span>Possible Additions</span></h3><p>Although the system works well for one place and a small collection of components, it tends to scale poorly when there's a large library or multiple users want to interact with it. One way to solve this issue is to replace the single text file with a relational database such as MySQL, where parts can be stored and indexed in a single table, and other data can be referenced. This gives a very powerful interface for the software to easily search, add, and modify parts without having to read and rewrite the text file constantly.</p></div></section><section></section><div><div><a href="https://www.hackster.io/gatoninja236"></a><div><p><span><a href="https://www.hackster.io/gatoninja236">Arduino “having11” Guy</a><span></span></span></p><p>18 year-old IoT and embedded systems enthusiast. Also an interned at Hackster.io and love working on projects and sharing knowledge.</p></div></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.hackster.io/news/never-lose-a-part-again-with-the-ultimate-component-storage-system-00987cde6744</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24396611</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 04:21:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[David Graeber on harmful jobs, odious debt, and fascists who mind global warming]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24396247">thread link</a>) | @kunfuu
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | https://www.disenz.net/en/david-graeber-on-harmful-jobs-odious-debt-and-fascists-who-believe-in-global-warming/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.disenz.net/en/david-graeber-on-harmful-jobs-odious-debt-and-fascists-who-believe-in-global-warming/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
					
<p>It was a warm spring evening in London and David Graeber, an anthropology professor at the LSE, was sitting on a rooftop. Our conversation was transmitted through the Internet because of the global travel ban due to the coronavirus pandemic. However, we did not only talk about the new virus and its consequences for society, politics, and the economy. We took the rare opportunity to discuss most of his published works – from the <em>Fragments of Anarchist Anthropology</em> and <em>Debt</em> to <em>Utopia of Rule</em>s, and his most recent book <em>The Bullshit Jobs</em>. All of which have become even more relevant during the corona-crisis.</p>



<p>Professor Graeber presents himself as an anthropologist and anarchist. However, he will not be happy if you refer to him as an “anarchist anthropologist” because there is no such discipline, which he explained during the conversation. The professor is also an activist. He joined many social movements and protests in the last few decades and is often credited as the author of the unofficial slogan from the Occupy Wall Street movement: We are the 99 percent. But he insists that the slogan – as well as everything else in the movement – was a collective effort.</p>



<p>How can democratic governments use this health crisis to enforce authoritarian measures on their citizens? Why don’t the health and care workers strike, during the pandemic, for higher wages? What would happen if we closed Wall Street for a few months? Why do we only see flying cars as special effects in science fiction movies? How can anarchistic principles bring order into chaos during the crisis? Why do we not want to depend on the Chinese and US armies to save our planet?</p>



<p>And finally – how can a drunken rant become a best-selling book?</p>



<figure><img src="https://www.disenz.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/DG-in-office-IMG_2027.JPG-1-2-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" width="561" height="748" srcset="https://www.disenz.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/DG-in-office-IMG_2027.JPG-1-2-768x1024.jpeg 768w, https://www.disenz.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/DG-in-office-IMG_2027.JPG-1-2-225x300.jpeg 225w, https://www.disenz.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/DG-in-office-IMG_2027.JPG-1-2-rotated.jpeg 864w" sizes="(max-width: 561px) 100vw, 561px"><figcaption>David Graeber in his office</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Everybody seems to be speaking the same language during the coronavirus pandemic – from progressive and conservative governments to ISIS and the anarchists: stay at home, wash your hands, avoid other people … And people have been listening to the officials without much protest. They stayed at home and accepted the new rules. We have not seen anything like this for a long while. What has happened?</strong></p>



<p>Well, there are just not all that many people who are quite crazy enough to ignore medical advice during a pandemic.</p>



<p>It brings to mind the 19<sup>th</sup> century French political thinker Henry Saint-Simon—who might have been the first person to come up with the notion of withering away of the state. He argued that if the state was refounded on scientific basis, eventually it would not need to rely on coercion, and therefore, it wouldn’t even be a state in the contemporary sense of having a monopoly of violence.</p>



<p><strong>Why?</strong></p>



<p>For the same reason, he said, that doctor doesn’t have to threaten to beat you up to convince you to the medicine they prescribe. You know the doctor knows something you don’t know, and you assume the doctor is acting in your best interest. Saint-Simon argued once the state was rationally founded on scientific principles, citizens would act in the same way, and coercive enforcement would become unnecessary. Maybe they’d be a few nutty people who refuse to take their medicine but not enough to make much difference.</p>



<p>Obviously this was all very optimistic and naive—that’s why Marx dismissed people like Saint Simon as “utopian socialists”. But there are certain branches of the government that still claim to operate on such basis. And one could make the argument that they’re not by their nature part of government at all.</p>



<p>During the student movement in the UK in 2010 we talked about this a lot, we were mostly anarchists, but we believed in a public health system, and a public university system. Was this hypocritical? None of us felt it was, but we talked a lot about why. Perhaps the problem is that states don’t allow the existence of public institutions – that is, ones which are both universal and non-profit-oriented – that they don’t control. That doesn’t mean those institutions are somehow of the same nature as the army, or prison system, which are entirely creatures of the state.</p>



<blockquote><p>The idea that knowledge is always a form of power is very flattering to academics, who have a great deal of one and very little of the other, so it’s hardly surprising they like it so much.</p></blockquote>



<p><strong>Yes and of course Foucault would say the authority that does not need a violent force to enforce itself is the scariest kind of all.</strong></p>



<p>He would. Though I think Foucault is often misinterpreted in this regard, to assume that any truth discourse is a form of power, and every form of power is violent and objectionable in itself. True, he sometimes sounds as if that’s what he’s saying. But if specifically challenged, he’d always say, no, no, obviously not.</p>



<p>The idea that knowledge is always a form of power is very flattering to academics, who have a great deal of one and very little of the other, so it’s hardly surprising they like it so much. Foucault himself had his own immediate concerns – he was diagnosed as a homosexual in his youth, and wanted to understand how it came about that his most intimate desires could be considered a disease.</p>



<p>He effectively dedicated his life to trying to understand that. But many on the academic left forget that, such diagnoses were not just abstractions, they ultimately relied on force of law, on the threat of physical violence, even if the doctor isn’t personally carrying a gun. A kind of vulgar Foucauldianismn has encouraged us to overlook how much the threat of force really does still lurk behind most of the institutions he describes.</p>



<p>The Panopticon was a prison after all. Normally if you think someone might be staring at you at any moment, you just go someplace else. Actually things have gotten rather worse in that respect since Foucault’s time. There didn’t used to be actual armed guards in schools and hospitals; now in many places there are.</p>



<p><strong>Many governments all over the world are using public health to enforce measures that could not have been imaginable in democratic societies only a few months ago. In Slovenia, for example, individuals are fined when they try to protest against the government actions. Not for protesting, of course. That would be undemocratic. But for violating the law on infectious diseases. So the only groups of people that are allowed move freely are the police, the army, and the politicians.</strong></p>



<p>That does not surprise me. You can learn a lot of things about your state by comparing how they treat a political assembly, and any other kind.</p>



<p><strong>In what way?</strong></p>



<p>In liberal democracies, the entire justification for a country’s legal structure is, typically, some kind of ideal of human freedom and liberty. The American bill of rights begins with the freedom of speech, freedom of press, and freedom of assembly. In practice, the assembly of people that gather in order to protest – which is the very essence of what is supposed to be American – is considered <em>less</em> legitimate than an assembly of people who want to sell you something.</p>



<p>You point this out to most middle-class Americans, they seem incredulous. Poor ones not so much, they don’t assume the rules are fair. Anyway: they’ll say “but of course you have the right to assemble, you just need a permit, what’s wrong with that?” So you have to say “all right, if you have to ask police permission to print something, that’s called not having freedom of the press. If you have to ask police permission to say something..” And they’ll say, “but that’s different! There are traffic issues. You can’t just gather. It gets in the way of people walking down the street” Which is funny, because I don’t remember anywhere in the constitution it says anything about the right to unimpeded traffic flow.</p>



<p>We learned that lesson during the Occupy movement. It was startling, after they evicted our camp, how many middle class Americans just shrugged their shoulders when they went on to rip up the Bill of Rights, the very thing they teach their children to be so proud of…</p>



<blockquote><p>The Anonymous movement has shown that you can have meaningful and impactful protests online. And people all across the world are inventing new ways to protest from their home.</p></blockquote>



<p><strong>You were trying to occupy a public space?</strong></p>



<p>Any space. After they evicted us from Zuccotti Park, we tried to reestablish a new camp because… well, it was crucial that everyone knew where we were. That was what was so effective about the original occupation: anyone in the city who felt they wanted to get involved knew where they could go and plug in instantly.</p>



<p>At first we thought we could relocate to a huge lot near Wall Street that belong to the Episcopalian Church, they agreed, but huge pressure was place on the Church hierarchy and eventually they reversed themselves. We had a march led by several bishops trying to occupy anyway; the cops beat us up, and the media refused to show any footage of the priests but only anyone in masks to make us look violent and scary.</p>



<p>Then we occupied a park that was open all night and they changed the rules of the park. We then got a legal ruling from a judge that we could sleep on the sidewalk as long as we do not take more than half of it. So the city just passed an order that Lower Manhattan was an emergency zone where legal decisions do not apply. So we decided to occupy the stairs of the building where the Bill of Rights was actually signed, which is right near Wall Street incidentally, but wasn’t under city jurisdiction. We were immediately were surrounded by SWAT teams and after two days they found a way to force us from there.</p>



<p>We tried everything to set up a legal alternative. But the state completely simply shredded the very legal principles that they teach children are what makes them proud to be Americans, and the media didn’t even cover it.</p>



<p><strong>But what can you occupy when you are not allowed to even leave your own apartment?</strong></p>



<p>There are always things you can do. The Anonymous movement has shown that you …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.disenz.net/en/david-graeber-on-harmful-jobs-odious-debt-and-fascists-who-believe-in-global-warming/">https://www.disenz.net/en/david-graeber-on-harmful-jobs-odious-debt-and-fascists-who-believe-in-global-warming/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.disenz.net/en/david-graeber-on-harmful-jobs-odious-debt-and-fascists-who-believe-in-global-warming/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24396247</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 02:52:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[My thoughts about editors in 2020]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 46 | Comments 59 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24395863">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | https://phaazon.net/blog/editors-in-2020 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://phaazon.net/blog/editors-in-2020">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><h2><em>editor, vim, neovim, atom, vs-code, emacs, intellij-idea</em></h2><h2>2020-09-07 00:03:00 UTC, by Dimitri Sabadie — <a href="https://phaazon.net/blog/feed">feed</a></h2><hr><div><p>I have been trying a lot of editors lately. When I say “trying”, I really meant I spent some time configuring and using those editors. The ones I spent time using are:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://neovim.io/">neovim</a>, my main, daily editor I use for pretty much almost all projects I work on.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/idea">IntelliJ IDEA</a>, that I currently use at work to hack on Java codebases.</li>
<li><a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/">VS Code</a>, that I have been trying mainly in Rust, TOML and Markdown.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs">emacs</a>, that I highly hacked around to play on my Haskell and Rust codebases (and YAML / Markdown / TOML too).</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/hlissner/doom-emacs">DOOM Emacs</a>, that I tried when I saw a colleague in a previous company I worked in (I was impressed by the “united” feeling of the UI and by how everything looked so slick). So I gave it a try.</li>
<li><a href="https://atom.io/">atom</a>, <a href="https://github.com/">GitHub</a>’s take on editors. Same thing, mostly Rust, Haskell, etc.</li>
<li>A bunch of others that I won’t talk about because I quickly stopped using.</li>
</ul>
<p>The goal of this article is to create a temporal “snapshot” of my views on editors and what I think about the current situation. I have been using vim and especially neovim for more than a decade. I need to explain about my current workflow and what I cherish in editing before talking about each editors. Expect a point of view from a neovimer which is looking around at lots of editors.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>This is only a personal workflow / point of view that works well <em>for me right now</em>. It doesn’t mean it will for you and it doesn’t mean a different workflow would be worse.</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- vim-markdown-toc GFM -->
<ul>
<li><a href="#what-i-think-powerful-editing-should-be">What I think powerful editing should be</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#keyboard-layout">Keyboard layout</a></li>
<li><a href="#modal-editors">Modal editors</a></li>
<li><a href="#how-i-like-to-move-around">How I like to move around</a></li>
<li><a href="#all-the-other-modal-candies">All the other modal candies</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="#the-editors">The editors</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#neovim">neovim</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#my-neovim-setup">My neovim setup</a></li>
<li><a href="#what-i-like-about-neovim">What I like about neovim</a></li>
<li><a href="#what-i-dislike-about-neovim">What I dislike about neovim</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="#intellij-idea">IntelliJ IDEA</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#what-i-like-about-intellij-idea">What I like about IntelliJ IDEA</a></li>
<li><a href="#what-i-dislike-about-intellij-idea">What I dislike about IntelliJ IDEA</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="#vs-code">VS Code</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#what-i-like-about-vs-code">What I like about VS Code</a></li>
<li><a href="#what-i-dislike-about-vs-code">What I dislike about VS Code</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="#emacs-and-doom-emacs">emacs and DOOM emacs</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#what-i-like-about-emacs--doom-emacs">What I like about emacs / DOOM emacs</a></li>
<li><a href="#what-i-dislike-about-emacs--doom-emacs">What I dislike about emacs / DOOM Emacs</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="#atom">atom</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#what-i-like-about-atom">What I like about atom</a></li>
<li><a href="#what-i-dislike-about-atom">What I dislike about atom</a></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="#wrap-it-up">Wrap it up</a></li>
</ul>
<!-- vim-markdown-toc -->

<h2 id="keyboard-layout">Keyboard layout</h2>
<p>I am French and I’m using a keyboard layout that is made to type very quickly in French and to code. With hindsight, since I type more often in English than in French, maybe I should have picked another keyboard layout, but the coding experience in my keyboard layout is really great, so I stick around.</p>
<p>The keyboard layout is <strong>bépo</strong>. I learned bépo the “recommended” way — i.e.&nbsp;you have to practice <em>typing</em> (« dactylographie » in French). It means that I use all my fingers to type on a keyboard, and that each key on the keyboard is assigned <em>a single finger</em> that will press it. That helps a lot with muscle memory and to reduce wrist pain (my wrists barely move when I type on a keyboard), among other things. The typing speed is a side-effect of being accurate and having good comfort (if you are curious, I’m pretty fast but there are faster people — I type at around 120 to 130 words per minute). Because I think the speed doesn’t matter when programming, I think the most important part to remember here is the comfort: the wrists don’t move and my fingers fly around the keyboard, whatever the speed.</p>
<h2 id="modal-editors">Modal editors</h2>
<p>I think a modal editor is superior, for various reasons. The first one is that I truly <strong>hate</strong> having to use a <em>mouse</em> for something that can be done without having to move around hundred of pixels with your cursor and clicking on buttons. For instance, running an application, on my current machines, is simply typing <code>alt d</code>, the name of the program (I typically use completion, so I never type fully the name of the program) and hit enter. All this without moving my hands from the keyboard. And I do that for programs like <code>firefox</code>, <code>kdenlive</code>, etc. but for terminal applications, I simply type and complete them in my terminal, which I open simply with <code>alt return</code>.</p>
<p>So, using a mouse to move around a cursor in an editor feels like completely suboptimal to me, especially because we write code (i.e.&nbsp;we type on a keyboard) most of the time, so moving around with the mouse implies several back and forth movements between the keyboard and the mouse. Maybe you don’t care and it’s cool to you, but to me, this is truly <em>horror land</em>. I feel <em>very</em> uncomfortable when doing this.</p>
<p>Also, <em>modern editors</em> that are not modal typically make people move by using the arrows keys, which are either far on your keyboard, or — like my keyboard, a 60% home made one — not in direct access and then require a function key to enable them.</p>
<p>So that’s the first reason why I like modal editors. They make a smarter use of your keyboard for simple yet recurrent features, like moving around — e.g.&nbsp;<code>h j k l</code>. The second reason why I like them is because of the facts they have a completely new mode for non-modal editor (i.e.&nbsp;the <em>normal</em> mode), you have a whole keyboard / lots of keys to bind actions to and do lots of things people usually do with the mouse. Being able to split an editor into several buffers, move around the buffers, go at the beginning of the paragraph, search and replace, register actions into macros and replay them, etc. All this without even moving the wrists. The learning curve is steep if you’re used to the mouse, but once you’ve passed the mental barrier, really, and this is a personal opinion, but I truly think that using the mouse again after that feels like handicap to me.</p>
<h2 id="how-i-like-to-move-around">How I like to move around</h2>
<p>When I look at people coding, I see several kind of programmers:</p>
<ul>
<li>The ones who move with the arrows or with <code>h j k l</code> in modal editors. You can spot them very easily at how the cursor moves in a document. It typically implies keeping a key pressed until the cursor reach a given row, then pressing another key until the cursor reach a given column and then adjust if they went passed the location they had in mind.</li>
<li>People using the mouse, by clicking at the place they want to put the cursor at.</li>
<li>People using <em>relative numbers</em>. That’s an enhancement of the first group: they typically use relative numbers to know which lines they want to jump to very quickly, so that they don’t have to press the up / down keys for ages until reaching the line they want to. Instead, they look at the number on the lines, press that number, and the direction, and bam, they are on the lines. They then use typical motions from vim like <code>$</code> (go to end of line), <code>f</code> (go to the first occurrence of the next character typed after <code>f</code>, like <code>f(</code> will make your cursor go to the next <code>(</code>), <code>%</code> (go to the matching delimiter) or <code>w</code> (go to the beginning of the next word) / <code>b</code> (go to the beginning of the previous word), etc. to move faster on the same line (it works across lines too).</li>
</ul>
<p>I think that represents 99,9% of what I see people do. Obviously, you will get that I don’t belong to the second set of people… but I don’t really belong to any, actually. How I move is, I guess, convoluted for most people and I know some people won’t understand how it can feel. I use <code>h j k l</code> and all the motions from vim described in the third group (and even more; I full lecture of four hours would be required to explain all of them :D), but it all depends on the <em>distance</em> I need to travel. If my cursor is on a word and I want to move to the beginning of a word located very closely to my cursor on the same line, I’ll simply type <code>www</code> if it’s three words apart (or <code>3w</code> if I’m feeling funny). If the distance is higher, I use a tool called [EasyMotion].</p>
<p>Easymotion really is a wonderful tool. The idea is that it has several modes, depending on the kind of move you want to perform:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>By lines</em>: this mode allows you to jump to any line in the current (or all open) buffers.</li>
<li><em>By words</em>: tihs mode allows you to jump to any “word” in the current (or all open) buffers.</li>
<li><em>By characters</em>: when the <em>word</em> mode doesn’t help with jumping to a special operator or character (because it’s not recognized as a word), this mode allows you to jump to any character in the current or (or all open) buffers.</li>
<li>It has other modes but I have never really found useful cases for them.</li>
</ul>
<p>The way I typically do it is by mapping the three modes to <code>&lt;leader&gt;l</code>, <code>&lt;leader&gt;w&gt;</code> and <code>&lt;leader&gt;c</code> (in my case, <code>&lt;leader&gt;</code> is the <em>space</em> key).</p>
<p>Typing <code>SPC l</code> in my current buffer results in this:</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://phaazon.net/media/uploads/easymotion_lines.png" alt=""><figcaption>EasyMotion lines</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Typing any highlighted character will make my cursor jump to it. The same applies for words, with <code>SPC w</code>:</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://phaazon.net/media/uploads/easymotion_words.png" alt=""><figcaption>EasyMotion words</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>For the <em>character</em> mode, after pressing <code>SPC c</code>, I have to press another character (the one I want to jump to). Let’s say we want to jump to a <code>#</code> (which is not part of words): <code>SPC c #</code>:</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://phaazon.net/media/uploads/easymotion_chars.png" alt=""><figcaption>EasyMotion characters</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>This way of moving is not intuitive at first, but once you get used to it… it’s a <em>must have</em>.</p>
<h2 id="all-the-other-modal-candies">All the other modal candies</h2>
<p>Among all the things that I like about modal editing, here is a non-exhaustive list of features I expect to have around my fingers:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>C-i</code> and <code>C-o</code>: those allows me to jump to something / a file / a place in a buffer and then go back to where I was right before with <code>C-o</code> (read it like <em>out</em>) or go back again with <code>C-i</code> (read it like <em>in</em>).</li>
<li>Macros and registers: those allow me to yank content into different registers (like clipboards) by assigning a single key to paste their content. For instance, I can put a few lines in my <code>t</code> register with <code>"tyi(</code> (“put in the <code>t</code> register the <code>y</code>ank <code>i</code>nside matching <code>(</code>), and paste that content later with <code>"tp</code>. Macros allow more powerful editing control by assigning a key to set of actions with the <code>q</code> keyword (<code>qa</code> will register all the next keystrokes and actions into the <code>a</code> macro). Then simply replay the macro with <code>@a</code>, for instance.</li>
<li>Obviously, all the basic vim motions, like <code>d</code> to delete, <code>y</code> to yank, <code>c</code> to change, <code>t</code> to go to the character right before the one you search, <code>%</code> to go to the other delimiter, etc. And more complex text manipulation, such as “Let’s change what’s inside this function parameter list, delimited by <code>(</code>”: <code>ci(</code>.</li>
</ul>
<p>It would take too much time to list everything, but the main idea is: I need the modal features when editing code.</p>

<p>So let’s talk about the list of editors I mentioned in the preface. The idea is to give <em>my own opinion</em> on those …</p></div></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://phaazon.net/blog/editors-in-2020">https://phaazon.net/blog/editors-in-2020</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://phaazon.net/blog/editors-in-2020</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24395863</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:50:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[PostgreSQL B-Tree index deduplication]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 183 | Comments 25 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24395825">thread link</a>) | @petergeoghegan
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2020/09/postgres-beta3-btree-dedup | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2020/09/postgres-beta3-btree-dedup">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                    <p>By Ryan Lambert -- Published September 06, 2020</p><p>PostgreSQL 13 development is coming along nicely, Postgres 13 Beta3 was
<a href="https://www.postgresql.org/about/news/2060/">released on 8/13/2020</a>.
The Postgres Beta 1 and 2 releases were released in May and June 2020.
One of the features that has my interest in Postgres 13 is the B-Tree deduplication effort.  B-Tree indexes are the default indexing method
in Postgres, and are likely the most-used indexes in production 
environments.
Any improvements to this part of the database are likely to have wide-reaching benefits.
Removing duplication from indexes keeps their physical size smaller,
reduces I/O overhead, and should help keep <code>SELECT</code> queries fast!</p>
<!--endteaser-->

<blockquote>
<p>This post is part of the series <a href="https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2018/06/pg-series-toc"><em>PostgreSQL:  From Idea to Database</em></a>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>There is a good summary of the what and how of this improvement
in <a href="https://www.cybertec-postgresql.com/en/b-tree-index-deduplication/">Laurenz Albe's post</a> from early in June 2020, presumably using
Pg13 Beta1.  <a href="https://www.highgo.ca/2020/07/06/features-in-pg13-deduplication-in-b-tree-indexes/">Hamid Akhtar's post in July</a>
covered this feature using Pg13 Beta2 and a different approach including
a look at the performance using <code>EXPLAIN</code>.
This post takes yet another look at this improvement using Pg13 Beta3.
I intend to see how well this improvement pans out on a data set I use in production.  For that task my go-to is
<a href="https://www.openstreetmap.org/">OpenStreetMap</a> data loaded to Postgres/PostGIS <a href="https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2020/01/postgis-osm-load-2020">using osm2pgsql</a>.</p>
<h2>Install Postgres 13 Beta 3</h2>
<p>The first step is to install the two versions of Postgres (12 and 13beta3) 
on a single Ubuntu 18 host.  In the past when I have tested pre-production
releases I have built Postgres from source instead of using <code>apt</code>.
This time around I decided to use <code>apt install</code>, so am including the
basic process for that.</p>
<p>The advised way to install PostgreSQL is from the pgdg (PostgreSQL Global Development Group) repositories,
see <a href="https://wiki.postgresql.org/wiki/Apt">the Postgres wiki</a> for more.
To enable the beta versions, the line needed in <code>/etc/apt/sources.list.d/pgdg.list</code> is:</p>
<pre><code>deb http://apt.postgresql.org/pub/repos/apt/bionic-pgdg main 13
</code></pre>
<p>With that in place, update the sources and install Postgres and PostGIS.</p>
<pre><code>sudo apt update
# Postgres 12
sudo apt install postgresql-12 postgresql-12-postgis-3
# Postgres 13 (Currently Beta)
sudo apt install postgresql-13 postgresql-13-postgis-3
</code></pre>
<p>On Ubuntu, installing multiple versions will create multiple instances running on different ports. The test server I'm using to write this post
currently has three versions of Postgres installed, only two are currently running. Postgres 12 was installed first so "won" the default port of 5432.  Postgres 11 was installed second and was assigned 5433, and Pg13 beta 3 was installed last and was assigned port 5434.  The <code>pg_lsclusters</code> is avaiable on Debian/Ubuntu hosts as part of the wrapper around <code>pg_ctl</code>.</p>
<pre><code>sudo -u postgres pg_lsclusters
Ver Cluster Port Status Owner    Data directory              Log file
11  main    5433 down   postgres /var/lib/postgresql/11/main /var/log/postgresql/postgresql-11-main.log
12  main    5432 online postgres /var/lib/postgresql/12/main /var/log/postgresql/postgresql-12-main.log
13  main    5434 online postgres /var/lib/postgresql/13/main /var/log/postgresql/postgresql-13-main.log
</code></pre>
<blockquote>
<p>This post does not use Postgres 11 beyond this example.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When working with multiple versions installed it is helpful to verify
versions match what you expect them to be.
First, the port 5432 for Postgres 12 version.</p>
<pre><code>psql -d pgosm -p 5432 -c "select version();"
â”Œâ”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”�
â”‚                                   version                                    â”‚
â•žâ•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•¡
â”‚ PostgreSQL 12.4 (Ubuntu 12.4-1.pgdg18.04+1) on x86_64-pc-linux-gnu, compiledâ€¦â”‚
â”‚â€¦ by gcc (Ubuntu 7.5.0-3ubuntu1~18.04) 7.5.0, 64-bit                          â”‚
â””â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”˜
</code></pre>
<p>Now, port 5434 for Postgres 13 version.</p>
<pre><code>psql -d pgosm -p 5434 -c "select version();"
â”Œâ”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”�
â”‚                                   version                                    â”‚
â•žâ•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•¡
â”‚ PostgreSQL 13beta3 (Ubuntu 13~beta3-1.pgdg18.04+1) on x86_64-pc-linux-gnu, câ€¦â”‚
â”‚â€¦ompiled by gcc (Ubuntu 7.5.0-3ubuntu1~18.04) 7.5.0, 64-bit                   â”‚
â””â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”˜
</code></pre>
<h2>Create Indexes</h2>
<p>Both versions of Postgres were loaded with the same Colorado OpenStreetMap
data loaded <a href="https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2020/01/postgis-osm-load-2020">using osm2pgsql</a>.
The osm2pgsql does not create any B-Tree indexes on its own, only the GIST
indexes on geometries.
For this post, we examine B-Tree index sizes created on four columns:
<code>osm_id</code>, <code>highway</code>, <code>waterway</code>, and <code>natural</code>.
Looking at the stats on the <code>public.planet_osm_line</code> table I can make 
a couple guesses where we will and will not see gains based on <code>n_distinct</code>.
I can guess we will not see major gains in the
<code>osm_id</code>, there is only a small amount of duplication in those values.
The other three columns (<code>highway</code>, <code>natural</code> and <code>waterway</code>) have a small number of distinct values
and varying amounts of <code>NULL</code> values.  These three columns would all
be candidates for partial indexes to avoid indexing the <code>NULL</code> values,
thus reducing the size of the created index.
I have hopes to see the benefits in Postgres 13 on these columns, possibly
making the use of partial indexes less frequent.</p>
<pre><code> SELECT attname, n_distinct, null_frac
    FROM pg_catalog.pg_stats
    WHERE tablename = 'planet_osm_line'
        AND attname IN ('osm_id', 'highway', 'waterway', 'natural')
;

â”Œâ”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”¬â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”¬â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”�
â”‚ attname  â”‚ n_distinct â”‚ null_frac  â”‚
â•žâ•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•ªâ•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•ªâ•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•¡
â”‚ osm_id   â”‚  -0.833553 â”‚          0 â”‚
â”‚ highway  â”‚         26 â”‚ 0.41616666 â”‚
â”‚ natural  â”‚          4 â”‚      0.994 â”‚
â”‚ waterway â”‚          9 â”‚     0.6663 â”‚
â””â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”´â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”´â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”˜
</code></pre>
<h3>Index on <code>osm_id</code></h3>
<p>First up is the <code>osm_id</code> column, a nearly unique set of positive and 
negative values.  The index to create in both versions:</p>
<pre><code>CREATE INDEX ix_osm_line_osm_id ON public.planet_osm_line (osm_id);
</code></pre>
<p>The following query is used throughout to report out index sizes.
The query itself will not be repeated, as only the filter would change.</p>
<pre><code>SELECT ai.schemaname AS s_name, ai.relname AS t_name,
        ai.indexrelname AS index_name,
        pg_size_pretty(pg_relation_size(quote_ident(ai.schemaname)::text || '.' || quote_ident(ai.indexrelname)::text)) AS index_size,
        pg_relation_size(quote_ident(ai.schemaname)::text || '.' || quote_ident(ai.indexrelname)::text) AS index_size_bytes
    FROM pg_catalog.pg_stat_all_indexes ai
    WHERE ai.indexrelname LIKE 'ix_osm_line%'
    ORDER BY index_name
;
</code></pre>
<p>Due to the low number of duplicates, it is no surprise that the
show only a tiny reduction in the size.  The reduction
would not be detectable from only the <code>index_size</code> column (in MB), the
<code>index_size_bytes</code> shows the slight reduction in size (29,515,776 bytes vs. 29,384,704 bytes).</p>
<p>Pg 12.</p>
<pre><code>â”Œâ”€[ RECORD 1 ]â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”¬â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”�
â”‚ s_name           â”‚ public             â”‚
â”‚ t_name           â”‚ planet_osm_line    â”‚
â”‚ index_name       â”‚ ix_osm_line_osm_id â”‚
â”‚ index_size       â”‚ 28 MB              â”‚
â”‚ index_size_bytes â”‚ 29515776           â”‚
â””â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”´â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”˜
</code></pre>
<p>Pg 13.</p>
<pre><code>â”Œâ”€[ RECORD 1 ]â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”¬â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”�
â”‚ s_name           â”‚ public             â”‚
â”‚ t_name           â”‚ planet_osm_line    â”‚
â”‚ index_name       â”‚ ix_osm_line_osm_id â”‚
â”‚ index_size       â”‚ 28 MB              â”‚
â”‚ index_size_bytes â”‚ 29384704           â”‚
â””â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”´â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”˜
</code></pre>
<h3>Index on <code>highway</code></h3>
<p>The <code>highway</code> data in the <code>planet_osm_line</code> data is a good example of when
a
<a href="https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/indexes-partial.html">partial index</a>
might typically be a good idea to minimize index size.  My hunch (and hope)
is that the de-duplication will make a partial index here a moot point by reducing the size required to index a large number of <code>NULL</code> values.</p>
<p>Create two indexes, one partial covering the non-<code>NULL</code> values and one full
index on the entire table.</p>
<pre><code>CREATE INDEX ix_osm_line_highway_partial 
    ON public.planet_osm_line (highway)
    WHERE highway IS NOT NULL;
CREATE INDEX ix_osm_line_highway_full
    ON public.planet_osm_line (highway);
</code></pre>
<p>The two indexes in Postgres 12, notice the partial index cuts out about 1/3 of the size from the full index.</p>
<pre><code>â”Œâ”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”¬â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”¬â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”…</code></pre></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2020/09/postgres-beta3-btree-dedup">https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2020/09/postgres-beta3-btree-dedup</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2020/09/postgres-beta3-btree-dedup</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24395825</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:39:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Introduction to Computational Thinking]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 315 | Comments 32 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24395700">thread link</a>) | @guiambros
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | https://mitmath.github.io/18S191/Fall20/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://mitmath.github.io/18S191/Fall20/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

<!-- Content appended here -->
<div>
<p>Welcome to the new course <strong>MIT 18.S191</strong>, the debut edition, <strong>Fall 2020</strong>!</p>
<p> This is an introductory course on Computational Thinking. We use the <a href="http://www.julialang.org/">Julia programming language</a> to approach real-world problems in varied areas applying data analysis and computational and mathematical modeling.  In this class you will learn computer science, software, algorithms, applications, and mathematics as an integrated whole.</p>
<p>Topics include:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>Image analysis</p>
</li>
<li><p>Particle dynamics and ray tracing</p>
</li>
<li><p>Epidemic propagation</p>
</li>
<li><p>Climate modeling</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="professors"><a href="#professors">Professors</a></h2>
<p><a href="http://math.mit.edu/~edelman">Alan Edelman</a>, <a href="http://sistemas.fciencias.unam.mx/~dsanders/">David P. Sanders</a>, <a href="https://www.3blue1brown.com/about">Grant Sanderson</a>, &amp; <a href="https://eapsweb.mit.edu/people/jars">James Schloss</a></p>
<h2 id="introduction_video"><a href="#introduction_video">Introduction video</a></h2>
<iframe id="course-intro" width="800" height="474" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vxjRWtWoD_w" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<h2 id="logistics"><a href="#logistics">Logistics</a></h2>
<p>Course materials will be published on the accompanying website: <a href="https://mitmath.github.io/18S191/Fall20/">https://mitmath.github.io/18S191/Fall20/</a></p>
<p>TR 2:30–3:30pm EST, online (Go to the lecture page on this site to stream it.)</p>
<ul>
<li><p>Tuesdays: Prerecorded videos, released on YouTube and played live on this site.</p>
</li>
<li><p>Thursdays: Live sessions (same YouTube link 2:30–3) and MIT-only discussion (3-3:30); link to follow</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Start date: September 1, 2020</p>
<p>Office hours TBD.</p>
<h3 id="discussion_forum_and_homework_submission"><a href="#discussion_forum_and_homework_submission">Discussion forum and homework submission</a></h3>
<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://discord.gg/Z5qnVf8">Discord</a>: discussion (we encourage you to hang out here during class!)</p>
</li>
<li><p><a href="https://piazza.com/class/kd33x1xnfyq3b1">Piazza</a>: (MIT only) allows for anonymity to other students, discussion</p>
</li>
<li><p><a href="https://canvas.mit.edu/courses/5637">Canvas</a>: (MIT only) homework submission. If you're a non-MIT student, please find a partner to cross-grade homeworks via Discord.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="evaluation"><a href="#evaluation">Evaluation</a></h3>
<ul>
<li><p>12 weekly problem sets with equal weight; your lowest score will be dropped. </p>
</li>
<li><p>Released on Thursdays and due before the following Thursday's class. (No problem set during Thanskgiving week.)</p>
</li>
<li><p>No exams</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Problem sets consist of code. MIT students enrolled in the course must submit homeworks via Canvas. If you are not a student then we encourage you to join the Discord and find a cross-grading partner.</p>
<div>
  <p>
    Last modified: September 10, 2020. Website built with <a href="https://github.com/tlienart/Franklin.jl">Franklin.jl</a>.
  </p>
</div>
</div><!-- CONTENT ENDS HERE -->

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://mitmath.github.io/18S191/Fall20/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24395700</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:08:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Elixir Is Erlang, not Ruby]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 401 | Comments 282 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24395695">thread link</a>) | @stanislavb
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | https://preslav.me/2020/09/06/elixir-is-not-ruby-elixir-is-erlang/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://preslav.me/2020/09/06/elixir-is-not-ruby-elixir-is-erlang/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Try to remember the first time you heard about this fascinating language called <a href="https://elixir-lang.org/">Elixir</a>. Chances are, you had by the time been developing software using Ruby. If that's the case, Elixir seems to have appeared out of nowhere until suddenly, it became the solution for all your previous problems. It is fast, clean, scales extremely well. It was <strong>almost</strong> like the Ruby you've always wanted to have, but never got.</p><p>I say <strong>almost</strong>, because as much as you want it to be, <strong>Elixir is not Ruby</strong>. The familiar syntax has definitely helped the language win the hearts of the broader developer community. Yet, under the hood, <strong>Elixir is all about Erlang.</strong> The <a href="https://elixir-lang.org/">Erlang</a> that everyone tells stories about, as if it were some mythical creature, but no one dares to touch.</p><figure><img src="https://preslav.me/content/images/2020/09/book-cover.png" alt="" width="500" height="700"><figcaption>Elixir for Non-Ruby Programmers</figcaption></figure><p>Why am I saying all of this? First, because I would love to see greater adoption of Elixir outside Ruby/Rails community. It was among that group of people where the idea first sparked, and I fully respect the fact. Nevertheless, I would love to see it growing out. As someone who discovered Elixir after years of doing Java, &nbsp;.NET and more recently, Go, I can say that there is enough goodness in it for everyone. Moreover, bringing people with different backgrounds (both technical and non-technical) will lead to an explosion of new ideas. Having more diverse minds will help us better understand and make use of the elephant in the room-Erlang.</p><p>This brings me to my second point. Erlang is not obscure at all, once you give it enough attention. It is actually oddly satisfying, once you start reading code written in it. I have had my few a-ha moments, when I figured the original inspiration for most constructs in Elixir. The point is, we shouldn't fear Erlang, but try to understand it. This applies both to when things go well, as well as when they go south.</p><p>My biggest hope of all is that by understanding Erlang well enough, the Elixir community will start looking for new uses for it. Uses that go beyond being a scalable replacement for Rails apps. More daring and more ambitious uses, where Erlang's resilience model can prove to be critical for the success of the mission. I'd love to see it used in transportation, space, as well as the domain that started it all- telecommunications.</p><blockquote>“Shoot for the moon. Even if you miss it you will land among the stars.”<br><strong>Les Brown</strong></blockquote>
                <section>
                  
                  <ul>
                      <li>
                        <a href="https://preslav.me/tag/elixir/" title="Elixir">Elixir</a>
                      </li>
                      <li>
                        <a href="https://preslav.me/tag/programming/" title="Programming">Programming</a>
                      </li>
                      <li>
                        <a href="https://preslav.me/tag/ruby/" title="Ruby">Ruby</a>
                      </li>
                      <li>
                        <a href="https://preslav.me/tag/erlang/" title="Erlang">Erlang</a>
                      </li>
                      <li>
                        <a href="https://preslav.me/tag/2-cents/" title="2 Cents">2 Cents</a>
                      </li>
                  </ul>
                </section>
            </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://preslav.me/2020/09/06/elixir-is-not-ruby-elixir-is-erlang/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24395695</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:07:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
