<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 13:12:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 13:12:20 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Full success of first-ever cubesat mission equipped with Hall-effect propulsion]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 51 | Comments 10 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25829683">thread link</a>) | @sohkamyung
<br/>
January 18, 2021 | https://exotrail.com/news/2021-01-12/100-exotrail-paves-the-way-for-new-space-mobility-with-first-of-its-kind-successful-in-orbit-demonstration-mission/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://exotrail.com/news/2021-01-12/100-exotrail-paves-the-way-for-new-space-mobility-with-first-of-its-kind-successful-in-orbit-demonstration-mission/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-v-1a8790d4=""><h4 data-v-1a8790d4="">More</h4> <p><span data-v-1a8790d4="">Images credits : ESA, NASA, CNRS, UVSQ, Ecole polytechnique,
            Clyde Space, Optimized System Engineering</span> <span data-v-1a8790d4=""><i data-v-1a8790d4=""></i> <i data-v-1a8790d4="">Mobility solutions for an agile space</i> <i data-v-1a8790d4=""></i></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://exotrail.com/news/2021-01-12/100-exotrail-paves-the-way-for-new-space-mobility-with-first-of-its-kind-successful-in-orbit-demonstration-mission/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25829683</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 03:30:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Everything you need to know to design your own CNC router]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 164 | Comments 84 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25829337">thread link</a>) | @mferraro89
<br/>
January 18, 2021 | https://mattferraro.dev/posts/cnc-router | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://mattferraro.dev/posts/cnc-router">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><img src="https://mattferraro.dev/images/my_router.jpg" alt="My Homemade CNC Router" title="My Homemade CNC Router"></p>
<p>This is the encyclopedic blog post I wish I could have read when I started designing my CNC router</p>
<p>I'll cover all the components and some of the design considerations you'll need to keep in mind when desiging your own CNC router.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="#overall-layout">Overall Layout</a></li>
<li><a href="#frame-construction">Frame Construction</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#wood">Wood</a></li>
<li><a href="#metal-tube-with-3d-printed-joints">Metal tube with 3D Printed Joints</a></li>
<li><a href="#extruded-aluminum-aka-8020">Extruded Aluminum aka 8020</a></li>
<li><a href="#steel-beams">Steel Beams</a></li>
<li><a href="#cast-iron">Cast Iron</a></li>
<li><a href="#epoxy-granite">Epoxy Granite</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#linear-guides">Linear Guides</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#box-ways-or-dovetail-ways">Box Ways or Dovetail Ways</a></li>
<li><a href="#supported-shafts">Supported Shafts</a></li>
<li><a href="#ground-rails">Ground Rails</a></li>
<li><a href="#unsupported-shafts">Unsupported Shafts</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#linear-actuation">Linear Actuation</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#belt-drives">Belt Drives</a></li>
<li><a href="#rack-and-pinion">Rack and Pinion</a></li>
<li><a href="#lead-screwsacme-screws">Lead Screws/Acme Screws</a></li>
<li><a href="#ball-screws">Ball Screws</a></li>
<li><a href="#threaded-rod">Threaded Rod</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#motors">Motors</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#stepper-motors">Stepper Motors</a></li>
<li><a href="#servo-motors">Servo Motors</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#gcode-interpreter-and-step-generator">GCode Interpreter and Step Generator</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#grbl">GRBL</a></li>
<li><a href="#tinyg">TinyG</a></li>
<li><a href="#g2core">G2Core</a></li>
<li><a href="#smoothieware">Smoothieware</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#gcode-sender">GCode sender</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#universal-gcode-sender">Universal GCode Sender</a></li>
<li><a href="#cncjs">CNCJS</a></li>
<li><a href="#bcnc">bCNC</a></li>
<li><a href="#carbide-motion">Carbide Motion</a></li>
<li><a href="#smoothieboard">Smoothieboard</a></li>
<li><a href="#others">Others</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#spindle">Spindle</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#palm-router">Palm Router</a></li>
<li><a href="#air-cooled-spindle">Air Cooled Spindle</a></li>
<li><a href="#water-cooled-spindle">Water Cooled Spindle</a></li>
<li><a href="#dc-spindle">DC Spindle</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#work-holding">Work Holding</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#fixing-directly-to-the-spoilboard">Fixing Directly to the Spoilboard</a></li>
<li><a href="#t-track-and-clamps">T Track and Clamps</a></li>
<li><a href="#machinist-vise">Machinist Vise</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#dust-collection">Dust Collection</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#vacuum-boot">Vacuum Boot</a></li>
<li><a href="#enclosure">Enclosure</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#axis-arrangement">Axis Arrangement</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#sliding-gantry">Sliding Gantry</a></li>
<li><a href="#fixed-gantry">Fixed Gantry</a></li>
<li><a href="#column-mill">Column Mill</a></li>
<li><a href="#knee-mill">Knee Mill</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#cutting-tools">Cutting Tools</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#flat-nose">Flat Nose</a></li>
<li><a href="#ball-nose">Ball Nose</a></li>
<li><a href="#spoilboard-surfacer">Spoilboard Surfacer</a></li>
<li><a href="#engraving">Engraving</a></li>
<li><a href="#others-1">Others</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#usability-improvements">Usability Improvements</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#z-axis-probe">Z Axis probe</a></li>
<li><a href="#automatic-tool-changing">Automatic Tool Changing</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#conclusion">Conclusion</a></li>
<li><a href="#contact-me">Contact me</a></li>
</ul>

<p>The foundation of a CNC router is some sort of rigid frame. On top of the frame you attach linear guides which allow your axes to move. You actuate that movement with belts or screws, whose rotation is powered by motors. Those motors are controlled by a pulse generator attached to a gcode intepreter, which gets its commands from a gcode sender. I'll cover all your major options below.</p>
<hr>

<p>The frame is the main body of your machine. You should use the most rigid material you are able to work with.</p>
<h2 id="wood">Wood</h2>
<p><img src="https://mattferraro.dev/images/wooden_frame.jpg" alt="Wooden Frame Router" title="Example Wooden Frame Router"></p>
<p>If you only have access to woodworking equipment, then <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jjdXpp77MdU">wood is your only choice</a>. The main advantages of wood are that it is cheap and easy to work with. The main disadvantage is that wood is not rigid enough to resist cutting forces, leading to chatter and low-quality surface finishes. A secondary concern is that wood is very dimensionally unstable, easily fluctuating with temperature and humidity changes.</p>
<p>If you never intend to cut any material harder than wood and you are comfortable never achieving tight tolerances or repeatable dimensions, a wooden frame can be a very economical choice. If you are primarily making art pieces rather than functional mechanical parts subject to tolerances, this might be a good choice for you.</p>

<p><img src="https://mattferraro.dev/images/mpcnc.jpg" alt="Mostly Printed CNC" title="The Mostly Printed CNC"></p>
<p>The Mostly Printed CNC and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Njs0FU6PfPg">others</a> like it make use of cheap extruded metal tube to serve as bones and 3D printed parts to serve as joints. Many of these designs don't require metalworking skills of any kind except to cut metal tubes to length. Given the ubiquity of 3D printers nowadays, these designs are extremely accessible, maybe moreso than wooden designs.</p>
<p>Their primary weakness is that 3D printed parts aren't very rigid, so the precision, repeatability, and surface finish of parts created on these machines is limited. Another common weakness in these designs is to use the extruded metal surface as the linear guide. Extruded metal is not a precision surface so any surface imperfections in the metal will translate to imperfections in the finished work. This limits the usefulness to hobby and art projects.</p>
<p>I should mention that "low-precision" for a CNC router might mean give or take 30 thousandths of an inch. If you are a woodworker used to table saws and pencil-drawn lines, tolerances that tight are fantastic and either a wooden frame or mostly printed frame will likely exceed your needs.</p>
<h2 id="extruded-aluminum-aka-8020">Extruded Aluminum aka 8020</h2>
<p><img src="https://mattferraro.dev/images/avidcnc.jpg" alt="Avid CNC" title="Avid CNC"></p>
<p>A very popular choice for router frames is aluminum 8020. The extruded profiles can be ordered in many dimensions and some providers like <a href="https://us.misumi-ec.com/vona2/mech/M1500000000/M1501000000/M1501010000/?searchFlow=results2category&amp;KWSearch=Aluminum%20extrusions">Misumi</a> will not only cut them to length for you, they will drill and countersink holes, they will tap ends, and perform many other operations for you right in their factory.</p>
<p>The ease of working with 8020 cannot be overstated. If you have a miter saw you can easily cut it to length yourself to produce whatever design you like. The main advantages are that you get the rigidity of metal-on-metal joints and the infinite reworkability of a lego set without the difficulty of more traditional metalworking.</p>
<p>Some providers can even mill precision surfaces onto your extrusion, allowing it to play double duty as a structural member and a linear guide.</p>
<p>The main disadvantages of 8020 are that it is more costly than extruded aluminum tube and that it isn't as rigid as steel. Still, it is a very popular choice because it is the cheapest, easiest way to produce a machine capable of hitting tolerances and producing great surface finishes.</p>
<h2 id="steel-beams">Steel Beams</h2>
<p><img src="https://mattferraro.dev/images/steel_frame_router.jpg" alt="Steel Frame Router" title="Steel Frame Router"></p>
<p>A Steel frame is a fantastic choice for its high mass and high rigidity. The biggest downsides are that metalworking requires tools that many hobbyists don't have access to, and that steel frames do not damp vibration well.</p>
<p>If you are comfortable cutting, welding, and powder coating steel then you should probably go ahead and build the frame out of steel. Some large surfaces will need to be milled flat to hold linear guides, so make sure you plan everything out before you start welding.</p>
<p>With a steel frame you can hit tight tolerances and cut almost any material. Your machine's primary limitation won't be its frame. See This Old Tony's excellent steel-framed CNC router build <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K9UA9ZRFwWU">here</a></p>
<h2 id="cast-iron">Cast Iron</h2>
<p><img src="https://mattferraro.dev/images/cast_iron.jpg" alt="Cast Iron Frame" title="A CNC machine with cast iron frame"></p>
<p>Mills and lathes very often have frames made of cast iron for its superior vibration damping, extreme rigidity, and reduced part count by combining many parts together into a single casting.</p>
<p>This technique requires a tremendous amount of pre-planning, experience, and access to a metal foundry. It is prohibitively expensive and difficult for most hobbyists, but it produces some of the finest CNC machines that can be produced.</p>
<p>Other disadvantages are that cast iron parts can easily rust in open air or corrode if attacked with solvents. Cast parts generally need to be sand blasted and painted to survive industrial environments.</p>
<p>The casting process does not leave you with precision surfaces, so surface machining will be required on any parts that must be within a specified tolerance.</p>
<p>There is significant upfront engineering cost to produce the required molds, but once you have molds the per-unit cost of casting can be cost competitive. If you are designing an extremely high quality CNC router specifically to be mass produced and sold to others, consider cast iron for your frame.</p>
<h2 id="epoxy-granite">Epoxy Granite</h2>
<p><img src="https://mattferraro.dev/images/epoxy_granite.webp" alt="Epoxy Granite Frame" title="A CNC machine with epoxy granite frame"></p>
<p>An exotic choice for frame building is epoxy granite--crushed up natural granite suspended in an epoxy binder that you cast into whatever shape you want, at room temperature.</p>
<p>The advantages of epoxy granite are that it is very dimensionally stable, it is resistent to chemical solvents, it does not require painting, and it can damp vibrations up to 30 times better than an equivalent steel frame, or 10 times better than cast iron. Epoxy granite can be cast into any shape you like using only at-home equipment and techniques. Pre-made threaded inserts and linear guides can be inserted at casting time, greatly reducing the need for machine finishing the final cast parts. For ultra high precision builds, epoxy granite is a fantastic choice.</p>
<p>The disdvantages are that epoxy granite has low tensile strength, and generally needs to be quite thick in all parts of the frame.</p>
<p>Epoxy granite is a rare choice among hobbyists, but I believe it is mostly because the design and build process are so foreign. Frames made from steel beams are easy to visualize and intuitive to link together. Frames made from cast material require a very different design approach that is just not well understood by most hobbyists.</p>
<p>If you are really looking to build an incredibly high performance machine, especially if you plan to make many machines, epoxy granite might be a good choice for you.</p>
<hr>

<p>The role of the linear guide is to constrain movement onto a single axis, preventing any unwanted rotation or deflection. These are often some of the most expensive parts on a CNC router.</p>
<h2 id="box-ways-or-dovetail-ways">Box Ways or Dovetail Ways</h2>
<p><img src="https://mattferraro.dev/images/dovetail_ways.jpg" alt="Dovetail Ways" title="Dovetail ways"></p>
<p>Mills and lathes generally use box ways or dovetail ways, which are precision machined surfaces floating over each other on a microscopically thin film of oil, kept tight with a small insert called a gibbs. When kept clean of damaging debris and maintained properly with oil, ways <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cwdoUjynpEk&amp;t=125">do not wear whatsoever</a> and will last longer than every other part of the machine.</p>
<p>Ways have the advantage of a huge contact area, allowing vibrations to couple very effectively across the linear guide and into the frame. This allows vibrational energy to spread out through the entire machine body where it can be dampened effectively.</p>
<p>They carry the secondary advantage of being extremely massive, which helps reduce the amplitude of vibrations. Ways are the most rigid linear guides available. In mills or lathes the ways can be ground directly into the body of the machine, reducing assembly complexity and part count.</p>
<p>Despite all these advantages they are almost never incorporated into CNC routers because they are too expensive per unit length, their large mass makes them unweildy, and their wear patterns are not a good match for computer controlled machining.</p>
<p>The issue with wear is that if a small problem does develop on the ways, it can quickly cascade into a serious issue that causes further damage. Repairing ways, especially in situ, is a tremendously tedious and therefore expensive process. A human machinist is likely to notice such problems developing on a manual mill, but the computer operating a CNC mill will not notice.</p>
<p>In contrast all following linear guides are cheap and easy to replace when worn.</p>
<h2 id="supported-shafts">Supported Shafts</h2>
<p><img src="https://mattferraro.dev/images/supported_shafts.jpg" alt="Supported Shaft linear guides" title="Supported Shafts"></p>
<p>Supported shafts are precision ground steel with aluminum support structure underneath that allows you to fix the shaft firmly to the frame of the CNC machine. The linear bearings that run on the shaft are free to rotate about 20 degrees back and forth on the long axis of the shaft, meaning they actually offer two distinct degrees of freedom, one of which must be further …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://mattferraro.dev/posts/cnc-router">https://mattferraro.dev/posts/cnc-router</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://mattferraro.dev/posts/cnc-router</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25829337</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 02:35:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Colorize]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 109 | Comments 59 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25828312">thread link</a>) | @didizaja
<br/>
January 18, 2021 | https://alexbeals.com/projects/colorize/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://alexbeals.com/projects/colorize/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			<h2>What is Colorize?</h2>
			<p>Colorize is a website that turns any word or phrase into a hex color.  It works by using a search engine to find image results for the word or phrase, and then finding the average color across the approximately 25 image results.  Because of this, there's usually a small delay when a word is searched for the first time.</p>

			<h2>What would I use it for?</h2>
			<p>If you've ever been drawing in Photoshop and thought 'What color is the sky', or have been designing a website and looking for that perfect 'purple' color, or just wanted to know what color sand is, Colorize is the tool for you.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://alexbeals.com/projects/colorize/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25828312</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 00:04:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Software engineering is a learning process, working code is a side effect]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 185 | Comments 61 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25827356">thread link</a>) | @io_nathan
<br/>
January 18, 2021 | https://www.lambdabytes.io/posts/selearning/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.lambdabytes.io/posts/selearning/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article role="article">
        <p>I have come to the conclusion that <em>Software Engineering is primarily a learning endeavour, the working code is rather a side effect</em>.</p>
<p>This quote is actually not mine but I am paraphrasing Alberto Brandolini who is making this very point in <a href="https://leanpub.com/introducing_eventstorming">Event Storming</a> (he was actually talking about Software Development, but I do not want to get into an academic discussion on the differences between Software <em>Engineering</em> and <em>Development</em> and I am treating them as being equal here).</p>
<p>I have actually always been thinking of Software Engineering (SE) as a learning process, but it was only until I read Brandolinins <em>Event Storming</em> where I found this view expressed in such clarity, which also made it clear to me that I, myself have been seeing SE in this very way. In short: for any non-trivial SE project, the main challenge is understanding the domain, which is primarily a learning process. This view is also very prominent in the Domain-Driven Design community and was expressed by Eric Evans himself: <em>The critical complexity of most software projects is in understanding the domain itself.</em></p>
<p>It is no surprise that agile processes have been proven to be so successful and useful: they emphasise <strong>collective learning</strong>. What is even better is that agile is a very scientific approach to SE: we fornulate hypotheses from discussions (among developers <strong>and</strong> customer) and then test them in experiments to arrive at new insights and deeper understanding. Plan-based processes on the other hand are a rather inductive aproach, based on many assumptions which are not tested and verified until the very end (just ask yourself: would you approach your Ph.D. in that way?)</p>
<p>When we finally acknowledge that SE is a learning process then we need to structure the methodologies, processes, tools and technologies around it to create an environment where quick, shared learning can happen through continuous experimentation and feedback:</p>
<ul>
<li>Lightweight requirements allowing for quick understanding of the domain and what and why to implement for whom: <em>Impact Maps (Godzic), Event Storming (Brandolini), User Stories, User Story Mapping (Patton)</em>.</li>
<li>A lightweight development and engineering process with emphasis on collective learning through continuous feedback: Agile / <em>Scrum</em> with <em>eXtreme Programming</em> (XP) practices.</li>
<li>A suitable design methodology which emphasises collective learning and experiments: <em>Domain-Driven Design</em></li>
<li>The most suitable architecture for the problem at hand, found by applying careful prototyping.</li>
<li>A programming language which makes it easier to map the domain into code: object-oriented, something along <em>Java, C#</em>,… (I am actually going to do research on using Haskell for that, but that is a topic for another post)</li>
<li>Technology which lets developers focus on the learning of the domain instead of dealing with low-level plumbing: <em>Spring, Thymeleaf, REST, React/Angular/Vue/…, Hibernate, Web, Mobile, IDEs</em>,…</li>
</ul>
<p>It is my firm belief that learning SE requires to apply it in the same way as learning a programming language requires us to apply it. Yes, when learning how to program we have books and slides and lecture notes describing the language and concepts but they always come with exercises. It is a mystery to me how we can write SE books which ignore that.</p>
<p>Unfortunately none of the SE textbooks I have read and studied (I had a fair share of them…) seems to embrace all of the above in any deeper way, and just throws a checklist of the usual topics at the reader in a rather very academic, dry and boring way. These books seem to treat SE simply as a collection of methodologies, processes, tools and technologies as a means to an end in itself which need to be applied <em>somehow</em>. A student who works through them has acquired lot of book knowledge about SE but has no clue how to <strong>really</strong> put it together and how the knowledge <strong>really</strong> relates to real-world SE. Even worse, the idea that SE is a learning process is not communicated in any of the SE textbooks I know. I think one of the main reason this is the case is that all these books have been written a long time ago and have only been extended with “newer” topics such as Agile / Web / Cloud / Whatever but have been sticking to the same end 90s/early 2000s SE mindset (just think about it: <em>Sommerville</em> is in its 10th edition now…),</p>
<p>Therefore, it is my aim to write a textbook book on applied, modern SE which is going to embrace all discussed issues above - I feel it is a very much needed textbook. It will be based on my teaching experience from my SE course at the FHV, paired with real-world experience from myself and industry partners. At the moment it is just a vision in my head but I want to get into it as soon as possible. Uunfortunately not before Spring 2022 as I will be occupied with a heavy load of teaching until then but this will give me enough time to earn more experience in teaching SE and reflecting my approach to the book which I will share in future posts.</p>

    </article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.lambdabytes.io/posts/selearning/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25827356</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 22:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I wasted $40k on a fantastic startup idea]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 661 | Comments 310 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25825917">thread link</a>) | @swyx
<br/>
January 18, 2021 | https://tjcx.me/p/i-wasted-40k-on-a-fantastic-startup-idea | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://tjcx.me/p/i-wasted-40k-on-a-fantastic-startup-idea">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p><span>Y</span>ou have a mind-shattering headache. You're standing in the aisle of your local CVS, massaging your temples while scanning the shelves for something—<em>anything</em>—to make make the pain stop.</p>

<p>What do you reach for? Tylenol? Advil? Aleve?</p>

<p>Most people, I imagine, grab whatever's cheapest, or closest, or whatever they <em>always</em> use. But if you're scrupulous enough to ask Google for the best painkiller, here's how your friendly neighborhood tech behemoth would answer:</p>

<p><img src="https://cringle.io/rails/active_storage/blobs/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaHBDQT09IiwiZXhwIjpudWxsLCJwdXIiOiJibG9iX2lkIn19--692ad5fb57e820714ca1dc70e3b05260aae65913/image-1601262407690.jpg" alt="Most effective painkillers"></p>

<p>Oh thanks Google that's just <em>all of them</em>.</p>

<p>If you're among the <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2013/02/01/majority-of-adults-look-online-for-health-information/">77% of Americans</a> that Google their health problems, insipid answers like this won't surprise you. But we should be surprised, because researchers carry out <a href="https://bmjopen.bmj.com/content/5/9/e008932">tens of thousands</a> of clinical trials every year. And hundreds of clinical trials have examined the effectiveness of painkillers. So why can't I Google those results?</p>

<p>And so in the year of our lord 2017 I had a <strong>Brilliant Startup Idea</strong>: use a structured database of clinical trials to provide simple, practical answers to common medical questions.</p>

<p>As a proof-of-concept I tried this by hand: I made a <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1xIx25J54JifJ8qliGnMBlKWn3PdB5sn852blOBfKfJk/">spreadsheet</a> with every OTC painkiller trial I could find and used <a href="https://www.r-project.org/">R</a> to run a <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5386629/">network meta-analysis</a>, the <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00406-016-0715-4">gold standard</a> of evidence-based medicine.</p>

<p>The results were pretty interesting, and <em>exactly</em> the kind of thing I was looking for back in the sad sterile aisles of CVS:</p>

<p><img src="https://cringle.io/rails/active_storage/blobs/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaHBEZz09IiwiZXhwIjpudWxsLCJwdXIiOiJibG9iX2lkIn19--b560c1e2bdbe33d8ddd1f10436432d3658d62c1b/image-1601347817059.jpg" alt="Most effective painkillers"></p>

<p>A wave of exhiliration washed over me. Here was a problem that</p>

<ol>
<li>Was interesting</li>
<li>Could help people</li>
<li>I knew how to solve</li>
</ol>

<p>A perfect bullseye. After a few hours searching domains I came up with a name for my project: <strong>GlacierMD</strong>.</p>

<p>Over the next nine months I would quit my job, write over 200,000 lines of code, hire five contractors, create a Delaware C-Corp, add four doctors to my advisory board, and demo GlacierMD for twelve Bay Area medical practices. I would spend $40K of my own savings buying clinical trials and paying contractors to enter said trials into the GlacierMD database.</p>

<p>On July 2, 2018, GlacierMD powered the world's largest depression meta-analysis, using data from 846 trials, beating <a href="https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(17)32802-7/fulltext">Cipriani's previous record</a> of 522.</p>

<p><img src="https://cringle.io/rails/active_storage/blobs/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaHBEdz09IiwiZXhwIjpudWxsLCJwdXIiOiJibG9iX2lkIn19--f65968deef4b6b7b836a90d2eee15119b5583f8c/image-1601347863747.jpg" alt="GlacierMD's evidence graph for depression treatments."></p>

<p>Choirs of angels sang in my ears. Here I was, living the Silicon Valley dream: making the world a better place through technology.</p>

<p>Two weeks later GlacierMD was dead.</p>

<hr>

<div><p><span>"T</span>hat's an awesome idea," said Carl. "It sounds like something worth working on."
</p><p>
Carl was my boss. We worked at a startup that leveraged autonomous blockchains to transfer money from naïve investors to slightly less naïve twenty-somethings. There are worse gigs.</p></div>

<p>And here was Carl telling me that my startup idea would bring such benefit to humanity that I simply <em>had</em> to quit, his roadmap be damned. I nodded knowingly, feeling the weight of this responsibility resting on my proud shoulders.</p>

<p>"Thanks Carl," I said. "I'll try to mention you when I accept my Nobel."</p>

<p>I quit two weeks later and started coding at a blistering pace. I drew all sorts of inscrutable diagrams with dry-erase pens on my parents' windows. I hired a motley crew of Egyptian contractors to start entering clinical trials into my database. I commissioned a logo, registered my domain, and started obsessing over color schemes.</p>

<p><img src="https://cringle.io/rails/active_storage/blobs/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaHBFQT09IiwiZXhwIjpudWxsLCJwdXIiOiJibG9iX2lkIn19--da9ab4b5da5f08cc26afe10e0531b89321ff5a24/image-1601347898563.jpg" alt="Data extraction portal for GlacierMD"></p>

<p>When I finally finished the MVP I showed it to the head of product at the company I'd just left. I watched him as he watched my demo, waiting for his eyes to melt with the glory of it all. Instead he just sorta shrugged.</p>

<p>"Lots of people make medical claims on the internet," he said. "Why should I trust yours?"</p>

<p>I started babbling about network meta-analyses, statistical power, and p-values, but he cut me off.</p>

<p>"Yeah okay that's great but nobody cares about this math crap. You need doctors."</p>

<p>Goddamnit he was right. If nobody could be bothered with the math, then I was no better than Gwyneth Paltrow hawking <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-45426332">vagina eggs</a>. To build trust I needed to get endorsements from trustworthy people.</p>

<p>So I called up some friends, some buddies, some friends-of-friends. "Would you like to be an advisor for my cutting-edge health-tech startup?" I'd ask, while eating Dominos in my parents' laundry room. I'd give them 1% of this extermely valuable, high-growth startup and in exchange I could plaster their faces all over my website.</p>

<p>Four of these doctors agreed. This is called <em>making deals</em> ladies and gentlemen and I was like the lovechild of Warren Buffet and Dr. Oz.</p>

<p>Things are going great. My friends and family all tell me they love the site. Even some strangers on the internet love it. "I know right," I tell them. "So how much would you pay for this?"</p>

<p>"Hahahahahahah," they say in unison. "Good one!"</p>

<p>I forgot that the the first law of consumer tech is <em>nobody pays for consumer tech</em>. But no problemo, I say to myself. This is why <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eric_Schmidt">Eric Schmidt</a> invented ads. I'll just plaster a few banners on GlacierMD and <em>bing bang boom</em> I'll be <a href="https://www.seasteading.org/">seasteading</a> with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_Thiel">Peter Thiel</a> before <a href="https://burningman.org/">Burning Man</a>.</p>

<p>But then I look at WebMD's <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1326583/000119312517247147/d391943d10q.htm">10-Qs</a> and start to spiral. Turns out the world's biggest health website makes about $0.50/year <em>per user</em>. That is...not enough money to bootstrap GlacierMD. I'm pouring money into my rent, into my Egyptian contractors, into AWS—I need some cash soon.</p>

<p>What I need are people willing to pay for this thing. What about doctors? Doctors have money, right? Maybe doctors, or practices, or whatever—someone in the medical industry—maybe they would shell out some cash for my on-demand meta-analyses.</p>

<p>So I listened to a few podcasts and became a sales expert. I started cold calling people using scripts from the internet and tried to convince them to sit through a GlacierMD demo.</p>

<p>In the meantime I receive some worrying messages from my Egyptian contractors.</p>

<p>"I think it's time to talk about a raise," one of them says.</p>

<p>"I feel that I have become exceptional at my job," says another. "Please consider a raise or I will stop working."</p>

<p>"Please increase my pay," says the third, including helpful screenshots demonstrating how to give said raise through the Upwork website.</p>

<p><em>Are my contractors unionizing?</em> I wonder. I glance obliquely at my shrinking bank account statement, grit my teeth, and approve the raises. At this rate I'll hit zero in a matter of weeks.</p>

<p>But my sales calls start paying off. Miraculously I find some doctors that are willing to talk to me. So I borrow my parents' car and drive out to the burbs to meet a doctor I'll call Susan.</p>

<p>Susan has a small practice in downtown Redwood City, a Silicon Valley town that looks 3-D printed from the Google Image results for <em><a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=main+street&amp;tbm=isch">main street</a></em>.</p>

<p>Susan is a bit chatty (she's a psychiatrist) but eventually I demo GlacierMD. I show her how you can filter studies based on the demographic data of the patient, how you can get treatment recommendations based on a preferred side effect profile, how you can generate a dose-response curve. She <em>oohs</em> and <em>aahs</em> at all the right points. By the end of the interview she's practically drooling.</p>

<p><img src="https://cringle.io/rails/active_storage/blobs/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaHBFUT09IiwiZXhwIjpudWxsLCJwdXIiOiJibG9iX2lkIn19--927e2748d8adb987b5d491746fcbb3691f186d1b/image-1601347948152.jpg" alt="Comparing the efficacy of two antidepressants over time"></p>

<p><em>Hook, line, and sinker</em> I think to myself. I'm already contemplating what color <a href="https://www.awaytravel.com/">Away bags</a> would look best in the back of my <a href="https://www.tesla.com/cybertruck">Cybertruck</a> when Susan interrupts my train of thought.</p>

<p>"What a fun project!" she says enthusiastically.</p>

<p>Something in her tone makes me pause. "Uh, yeah," I say. "So what would you imagine a product like this—one that could change the very <em>practice</em> of medicine—how much would you pay for such a service?"</p>

<p>"Oh, uh—hmmmm," she said. "I don't know if we can spare the budget here, to be honest. It's very fun...but I'm not sure if our practice can justify this cost."</p>

<p>If you read enough sales books most of them tell you that when people say your product is <em>too expensive</em> what they really mean is your product <em>isn't valuable enough</em>. Susan acted like I was offering her Nirvana as a Service so the conversation has taken quite a wild turn.</p>

<p>"So you don't think this product is useful?"</p>

<p>"Oh sure! I mean, I think in many cases I'll just prescribe what I normally do, since I'm comfortable with it. But you know it's possible that sometimes I'll prescribe something different, based on your metastudies."</p>

<p>"And that isn't worth something? Prescribing better treatments?"</p>

<p>"Hmmmm," she said, picking at her fingernails. "Not directly. Of course I always have the best interests of my patients in mind, but, you know, it's not like they'll pay more if I prescribe Lexapro instead of Zoloft. They won't come back more often or refer more friends. So I'd sorta just be, like, <em>donating</em> this money if I paid you for this thing, right?"</p>

<p>I had literally nothing to say to that. It had been a bit of a working assumption of mine over the past few weeks that if you could improve the health of the patients then, you know, the doctors or the hospitals or whatever would pay for that. There was this giant thing called <em>healthcare</em> right, and its main purpose is <em>improving health</em>—trillions of dollars are spent trying to do this. So if I built a thing that improves health someone should pay me, right?</p>

<p>I said goodbye to Susan and tried to cheer myself up. I had ten more meetings with doctors all over the Bay Area—surely not all of them were ruthless capitalists like Susan. Maybe they would see the the towering genius of GlacierMD and shell out some cash.</p>

<p>But in fact everyone gave me some version of Susan's answer. "We just can't justify the cost," a pediatrician told me. "I'm not sure it's in the budget," said a primary care physician. "It's awesome," said a hospitalist. "You should try to sell this!" <em>Ugh</em>.</p>

<hr>

<p><span>S</span>o in July 2018, nine months and $40K after starting GlacierMD, I shut it down. I fired my contractors, archived the database, and shut down the servers. GlacierMD was dead.</p>

<p><em>Make something people want</em>. It's Y-Combinator's motto and a maxim of aspiring internet entrepreneurs. The idea is that if you build something truly awesome, you'll figure out a way to make some money off of it.</p>

<p>So I built something people wanted. Consumers wanted it, doctors wanted it, <em>I</em> wanted it. Where did I go wrong?</p>

<p>Occassionally I like to disconnect from the IV drip of internet …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://tjcx.me/p/i-wasted-40k-on-a-fantastic-startup-idea">https://tjcx.me/p/i-wasted-40k-on-a-fantastic-startup-idea</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://tjcx.me/p/i-wasted-40k-on-a-fantastic-startup-idea</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25825917</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 20:01:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How I Build Web Apps As A Freelancer]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 145 | Comments 67 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25825444">thread link</a>) | @timdaub
<br/>
January 18, 2021 | https://timdaub.github.io/2021/01/16/web-principles/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://timdaub.github.io/2021/01/16/web-principles/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>It's now roughly seven or eight years that I'm building dynamic front ends for the web. From <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://www.ascribe.io/">digital art wallets</a> to games (<a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://ipfs.leapdao.org/blog/Planet-A-ccc-ethberlin-recap/">1</a>, <a href="https://timdaub.github.io/videogame">2</a>) and <a href="https://timdaub.github.io/wasm-synth">synthesizers</a>, I've seen it all. And since my process of creation has dramatically changed over the years, today, I'd like to share how I'm developing web apps in 2021.</p>
<h2 id="i-avoid-build-processes.">I avoid build processes.</h2>
<p>I still remember the debates with colleagues about using <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://babeljs.io/">babel</a> a few years ago. Within the front end development world, transpiling had just become a thing, so we ended up babelifying our builds to use ES6. Our argument back then was that one day, we would be able to push our application's directory structure on a web server and since all browsers would then support the augmented ES6 features, our app would just work! Without a build process. WOW! That must have been around 2015. When I look at the source code of these old applications now, our technical visions didn't end up becoming reality.</p>
<p>Now, I try to keep my build process to a minimum. When I need to write a demo app, I particularly like using <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://babeljs.io/docs/en/babel-standalone#script-tags"><code>&lt;script type="text/babel"&gt;</code></a>. I love <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://preactjs.com/guide/v10/getting-started/#no-build-tools-route">preact's "no build tools route."</a> too. When I have to set up an actual app, I avoid <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://webpack.js.org/">webpack</a> and <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://rollupjs.org/">rollup</a>. I mainly get frustrated about the myriad ways of configuring them. Some minor thing always ends up being broken, which leads to hours of debugging foreign code. And that's frustrating. Using preact's no build route, finally something like the above is possible:</p>
<figure><table><tbody><tr><td><pre><span>1</span><br><span>2</span><br><span>3</span><br><span>4</span><br><span>5</span><br><span>6</span><br></pre></td><td><pre><span>&lt;script type=<span>"module"</span>&gt;</span><br><span>  </span><br><span>  <span>import</span> { h, Component, render } <span>from</span> <span>'https://unpkg.com/preact?module'</span>;</span><br><span>  <span>const</span> app = h(<span>'h1'</span>, <span>null</span>, <span>'Hello World!'</span>);</span><br><span>  render(app, <span>document</span>.body);</span><br><span>&lt;/script&gt;</span><br></pre></td></tr></tbody></table></figure>
<p>When having to use a build tool, I gravitate towards <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://parceljs.org/">parcel</a> or <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://github.com/developit/microbundle">microbundle</a> as they come preconfigured. And in particular, parcel is excellent, as it's merely using an HTML file as its entry point. To me, that's promising as it assumes a proper directory structure and properly connected files such that maybe one day I can push my app to the web without that build step.</p>
<h2 id="i-avoid-transpiling.">I avoid transpiling.</h2>
<p>For the same reasons as pointed out above, I also try to avoid transpiling. It's not because I don't like ESNext features, but more because I want to minimize the risk of getting stuck with the transpiler. Hence, I try to avoid using babel. <a href="https://timdaub.github.io/2020/09/01/typescript/">I also don't use Typescript</a>. To me, JavaScript is productive enough. Additionally, for <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://reactjs.org/">react</a>-style projects, no transpilers mean I stopped using <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://reactjs.org/docs/introducing-jsx.html">JSX</a>. Instead, I found an excellent library called <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://github.com/developit/htm">htm</a> that uses JavaScript's template strings. It has a similar syntax to JSX, but it's not breaking ECMAScript standards and hence needs no transpliation.</p>
<h2 id="i-avoid-the-new-and-shiny.">I avoid the <em>new</em> and <em>shiny</em>.</h2>
<p>I even avoid changing the way I work if I don't feel comfortable or inclined. For example, I never switched to <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://reactjs.org/docs/hooks-intro.html">react hooks</a>. The <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://reactjs.org/docs/state-and-lifecycle.html">lifecycle methods</a> that I initially know from iOS Objective-C programming are - in my opinion - a beautiful metaphor for writing front end components. And neither did I have any issues with my sites' performance. I would make the switch if I started to have problems. But I don't. The same goes for up and coming frameworks. Angular V2? <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://svelte.dev/">Svelte</a>? Cool, but why relearn a framework when I'm already productive with the one I use?</p>
<h2 id="i-test-everything.">I test EvErYtHiNg.</h2>
<p>When I started front-end development, testing was complicated. Only a few front end developer colleagues tested their apps properly. I ended up doing a lot of testing by hand. It was frustrating and unproductive. But testing front ends has improved dramatically over the years. Not only have the tools been significantly enhanced.</p>
<p>We, as front-end developers, have now also figured out how to correctly write front end tests. Finally, we're able to distinguish between functional code and presentational code. For functional code, we now write unit tests. For presentational code, we use snapshot-based testing and integration tests. I'm pleased about tools like <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://www.cypress.io/">cypress</a> that is great for integration tests. I also like <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://github.com/avajs/ava/">ava</a> for unit tests.</p>
<h2 id="i-optimize-for-performance-and-quality.">I optimize for performance and quality.</h2>
<p>I used to be eager about building extensively functional software: the more features, the better. I'm not anymore. Instead, I try to develop software that works well for my users. I strive for quality. So I try to measure my build's size. I take proper care about delivering my application, meaning I turn on compression and <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Caching">caching</a>. I care about optimizing my static assets like pictures. And I like to check my apps by using tools like <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://developers.google.com/speed/pagespeed/insights/?hl=de">PageSpeed Insights</a> or <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://developers.google.com/web/tools/lighthouse">lighthouse</a>.</p>
<h2 id="i-use-my-own-work">I use my own work</h2>
<p>From experience, I learned that I hardly ever get stuck on a algorithmic problem. On the contrary, I get motivated to learn something new and excel in the process. However, I caught my self often spending many hours on debugging other people's code. Mainly when it's third-party libraries that I included via npm. Once, I thought that using npm packages was a JavaScript developer's superpower. Now, I know that it can also be their curse.</p>
<p>Instead of collecting heaps of third-party code, I now prefer following <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="http://hintjens.com/blog:96">Peter Hintjens' principles for writing good code</a>. I "use my own work." Meaning, I dare to write seemingly complex code myself. I still won't roll my own crypto or write a date library, but I dare to implement parts of a protocol or build an algorithm. It's not to say that I ditch every npm package and go npm-keto-diet. No, instead, I take a more mindful approach towards dependencies and only include them when I truly need them.</p>
<p>I try to do that by leaving my technical vision at the doorstep of my office, so that I can now focus on solving the problems at hand. I try to stop worrying about eventualities far in the future as I view that as speculation. In cases I have past experiences, I use it to form my decision. For unchartered teritory, I move carefully, step by step.</p>
<h2 id="i-use-open-source-to-my-advantage.">I use open source to my advantage.</h2>
<p>I'm building websites since I'm a teenager. And had I open-sourced and maintained a few pieces of code that I need frequently, I'd be more productive now. Unfortunately, I was short-sighted. Surprisingly, I didn't think about still using JavaScript at 29 years of age 😂</p>
<p>I stopped framing open source mainly around certain virtues like free speech, fairness or certain politics. They're still important virtues for me, but I learned that I could use open source also for building a personal toolset.</p>
<p>Extracting a library from a codebase allows me to think about it from a user's perspective. It means I'm able to think about a piece of code's interfaces emphatically. Additionally, there's positive peer pressure. I'm not going to release shit to the world. When my project is public, it's going to have a proper README and some docs. And it's going to be tested. Since everybody can see it, I might as well create something I can be proud of.</p>
<p>Hence, contributing to open source, for me, is about building high-quality software. Being anxious about not being able to monetize this particular piece of code has become less of a concern. <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://github.com/sindresorhus">sindresohrus</a> inspired me to treat open source packages like my personal toolbox.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>And that's my incomplete list of principles. I'm sure there's more than just these. Anyway, I still find some of these points quite controversial. I'm sure they won't work for everyone as all our contexts differ. But working solo as a freelancer, I've found that these principles contribute to me being content about what I'm doing. Hence, I was eager to share them.</p>
<p>I'm curious to hear other's thoughts and see if they've taken similar paths. Please reach out! Also, don't forget to subscribe to my newsletter!</p>

  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://timdaub.github.io/2021/01/16/web-principles/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25825444</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 19:22:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Nobody lives here: Nearly 5M Census Blocks with zero population (2014)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 150 | Comments 90 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25825390">thread link</a>) | @sndean
<br/>
January 18, 2021 | https://tumblr.mapsbynik.com/post/82791188950/nobody-lives-here-the-4-million-census-blocks | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://tumblr.mapsbynik.com/post/82791188950/nobody-lives-here-the-4-million-census-blocks">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      

      <p>10,674 notes</p>
<!-- AddThis Button BEGIN -->


<!-- AddThis Button END --> 

 
      
      <p>A <em><a href="https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=http%3A%2F%2Fblogs.census.gov%2F2011%2F07%2F20%2Fwhat-are-census-blocks%2F&amp;t=NjNlY2UyNTY4N2ZmYTRiMDRkZDRkOWVjN2I1MWU3YmQ1M2Q5MjA1ZCx4ZmVCRFVSUQ%3D%3D&amp;b=t%3A08IjTEwOylSib4KWGzwNdw&amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Ftumblr.mapsbynik.com%2Fpost%2F82791188950%2Fnobody-lives-here-the-4-million-census-blocks&amp;m=0&amp;ts=1611234754">Block</a></em> is the smallest area unit used by the U.S. Census Bureau for tabulating statistics. As of the 2010 census, the United States consists of 11,078,300 Census Blocks. Of them, 4,871,270 blocks totaling 4.61 million square kilometers were reported to have no population living inside them. Despite having a population of more than 310 million people, 47 percent of the USA remains unoccupied.</p><p>Green shading indicates unoccupied Census Blocks. A single inhabitant is enough to omit a block from shading.</p><p><strong>Update Jan 2015</strong>: <a href="http://tumblr.mapsbynik.com/post/107762841792/nobody-lives-here-map-prints-available">Prints and canvas of the Nobody Live Here map</a> are now available.</p><p><em>Update 2014.05.01</em>: I’ve received a couple questions about Canada.  Just to be clear, this map is of the United States only. It is based on 2010 data published by the U.S. Census Bureau, which for reasons I hope are apparent, does not include data on our friends in the Great White North. For a similar depiction of Canada, see <a href="https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=http%3A%2F%2Fi.imgur.com%2FSrefoUG.jpg&amp;t=ZDczYzhjNzQzZmRkZmM0ZmI4ZjBlNjI4M2M0ZWU2MGUzOTMwZmJkYix4ZmVCRFVSUQ%3D%3D&amp;b=t%3A08IjTEwOylSib4KWGzwNdw&amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Ftumblr.mapsbynik.com%2Fpost%2F82791188950%2Fnobody-lives-here-the-4-million-census-blocks&amp;m=0&amp;ts=1611234754">this map</a> whipped up by Michael Chung.</p><h2>Map observations</h2><p>The map tends to highlight two types of areas:</p><ul><li>places where human habitation is physically restrictive or impossible, and</li><li>places where human habitation is prohibited by social or legal convention.</li></ul><p>Water features such lakes, rivers, swamps and floodplains are revealed as places where it is hard for people to live. In addition, the mountains and deserts of the West, with their hostility to human survival, remain largely void of permanent population.</p><p>Of the places where settlement is prohibited, the most apparent are wilderness protection and recreational areas (such as national and state parks) and military bases. At the national and regional scales, these places appear as large green tracts surrounded by otherwise populated countryside.</p><p>At the local level, city and county parks emerge in contrast to their developed urban and suburban surroundings. At this scale, even major roads such as highways and interstates stretch like ribbons across the landscape.</p><p>Commercial and industrial areas are also likely to be green on this map. The local shopping mall, an office park, a warehouse district or a factory may have their own Census Blocks. But if people don’t live there, they will be considered “uninhabited”. So it should be noted that just because a block is unoccupied, that does not mean it is undeveloped.</p><p>Perhaps the two most notable anomalies on the map occur in Maine and the Dakotas. Northern Maine is conspicuously uninhabited. Despite being one of the earliest regions in North America to be settled by Europeans, the population there remains so low that large portions of the state’s interior have yet to be politically organized.</p><p>In the Dakotas, the border between North and South appears to be unexpectedly stark. Geographic phenomena typically do not respect artificial human boundaries. Throughout the rest of the map, state lines are often difficult to distinguish. But in the Dakotas, northern South Dakota is quite distinct from southern North Dakota. This is especially surprising considering that the county-level population density on both sides of the border is about the same at less than 10 people per square mile.</p><p><em>Update</em>: On a more detailed examination of those two states, I’m convinced the contrast here is due to differences in the sizes of the blocks. North Dakota’s blocks are more consistently small (StDev of 3.3) while South Dakota’s are more varied in area (StDev of 9.28). West of the Missouri River, South Dakota’s blocks are substantially larger than those in ND, so a single inhabitant can appear to take up more space. Between the states, this provides a good lesson in how changing the size and shape of a geographic unit can alter perceptions of the landscape.</p><p>Finally, the differences between the eastern and western halves of the contiguous 48 states are particularly stark to me. In the east, with its larger population, unpopulated places are more likely to stand out on the map. In the west, the opposite is true. There, population centers stand out against the wilderness.</p><h2>::</h2><p>Ultimately, I made this map to show a different side of the United States. Human geographers spend so much time thinking about where people are. I thought I might bring some new insight by showing where they are not, adding contrast and context to the typical displays of the country’s population geography.</p><p>I’ve all but scratched the surface of insight available from examining this map. There’s a lot of data here. What trends and patterns do you see?</p><h2>Errata</h2><ul><li>Due to a cartographic mishap, the Gulf of California was missing from the original version. Though it was quickly fixed, that version keeps popping up across the Internet. It displeases me I see it, yet I’m amused that people keep reposting it without noticing the error. The geography gods judge those people harshly.</li><li>Some islands may be missing on the <a href="https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=http%3A%2F%2Fmapsbynik.com%2Fmaps%2Fcensus0pop%2F&amp;t=MzI0MjA3ZDkyNTAxODhiMjIxM2YyMjNmMDU4Y2YxODljZjExMmRmMCx4ZmVCRFVSUQ%3D%3D&amp;b=t%3A08IjTEwOylSib4KWGzwNdw&amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Ftumblr.mapsbynik.com%2Fpost%2F82791188950%2Fnobody-lives-here-the-4-million-census-blocks&amp;m=0&amp;ts=1611234754">hi-res edition</a> if they were not a part of the waterbody data sets I used.</li></ul><h3>::</h3><p>©mapsbynik 2014<br>
Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike<br>
Block geography and population data from U.S. Census Bureau<br>
Water body geography from National Hydrology Dataset and Natural Earth<br>
Made with Tilemill<br>
USGS National Atlas Equal Area Projection</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://tumblr.mapsbynik.com/post/82791188950/nobody-lives-here-the-4-million-census-blocks</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25825390</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 19:17:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Degoogling My Life]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 125 | Comments 160 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25823645">thread link</a>) | @benrapscallion
<br/>
January 18, 2021 | https://thefiringneuron.com/2021/01/17/degoogling-my-life/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thefiringneuron.com/2021/01/17/degoogling-my-life/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-40">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	
	
	<div>
		<p>Privacy is a human right, when so much of our life is lived online. In my opinion, the two most evil companies on the planet with a blatant disregard for privacy because it is so fundamental to their business model are: Facebook (and by extension, WhatsApp and Instagram) and Google. A common argument against the need for privacy that I have definitely heard in my family is “but I have nothing to hide”. Well, neither do I and yet so does everyone. Does anyone really appreciate searching on Google for a vacuum cleaner and then seeing photos of vacuum cleaners follow them around all over the web for months afterwards? But I digress: I made a conscious decision to gradually rid myself of Google (Facebook was easier: just delete the app) to the extent possible.</p>
<p>I spent quite some time researching alternatives to each of Google services, and the list below tabulates what I have settled on. Importantly, I have reached the conclusion that viable (and often superior) alternatives exist. Nothing in life is free: one can pay with one’s privacy or with cash. It is no surprise this that most of these below are paid services. Personally, I am more than happy to support businesses where I know what I am paying for and my data is not being pilfered to create some Frankensteinian advertising profile on me.</p>
<p>1. <a href="https://ref.fm/u14223513">Fastmail</a> (email, contacts, and calendar): I have been using their email service for over a year now. They are a privacy-respecting email service based out of Australia. They’ve actually been around for a very long time: I remember a college friend in early 2000s (back when they were Fastmail.fm) showing me a cool feature to send a (fake) <em>email undelivered</em> response to an email. I believe they don’t have have that feature in their present-day incarnation. These days my most-used Fastmail feature is their ability to create an unlimited number of email aliases. I can create a new email address for every untrustworthy website and if I start receiving spam on an alias, not only do I know which website was the culprit behind it, but I can simply delete the alias and move on. Another favorite: the ability to block remote images (and as opposed to delivering them over a proxy server — see HEY below) which makes for a pleasant 90s-like (remember mutt?) text-only webmail interface. They have a high quality iOS app with both email and calendar. The service is mature and it has all standard email features (filters, forwarding, IMAP/POP, 2FA etc.). One situation where Fastmail beats Gmail is the ability to send emails from MATLAB or R, or from a cron script running on my own hosted domain: inevitably, these were rejected as “low quality” on Gmail. Well, I am not too keen on letting an AI make that decision for me. Unlike Gmail, Fastmail doesn’t hold immediate push notifications hostage for the native Mail app either.</p>
<p>Perhaps the more difficult task was to then go to all the places where I had signed up my Gmail and then replace that with my Fastmail address.</p>
<p>Yes, I do realize that the moment someone sends me an email from Gmail to my Fastmail (or when I respond to them), I am effectively enabling that same advertising profile. But we have to start somewhere and one can only hope that enough people will switch over from the dark side.</p>
<p>2. <a href="https://duckduckgo.com/">DuckDuckGo</a>: I mean, have you looked at Google search results lately? Once upon a time they used to be the 10 blue links company with one prominent and easily-identified, textual advertisement at the top. Contrast that with the situation now: it is impossible to find the organic result one wants amongst a sea of distractions and posers (ads cleverly disguised to resemble results). Admittedly, this Google service was the most difficult to be weaned away from, partly because when I tried DDG in the past, the results were less than spectacular. But I think the tide has turned now: DuckDuckGo is a viable and formidable competitor (remember when Google was just that against Altavista?) with two clear benefits: they have no intention to build an advertising profile on their users and there is a clearly demarcated ad at the top followed by organic search results. I am to understand that their results are based on Bing’s index. I would estimate that my average rate of going to Google when DDG can’t find an answer is 1 in 200, which is remarkable!</p>
<p>3. <a href="https://www.awstats.org/">AWStats</a>: This was easy. I just removed all Google Analytics code from my own domains. I cannot be, in good conscience, an enabler of that (creating advertising profiles based on which webpages a person visits) which I myself oppose.</p>
<p>4. <a href="https://www.apple.com/safari/">Safari</a>: Again, for someone who is 100% on the Mac/iOS bandwagon this is an easy one to accomplish. Of course, I have 1Blocker installed. The recent builds of Safari have this oddly satisfying Privacy Report where one can see how many of these creepy ad-trackers were blocked on a webpage and sometimes it is truly enlightening as to what the real business mode of some of the “free” websites is. For work, where we still use GSuite, I have isolated Gmail etc., into the Chrome browser. Firefox is an excellent alternative to Safari, especially for those not on Mac/iOS.</p>
<p>5. <a href="https://www.obdev.at/products/littlesnitch/index.html">Little Snitch</a>: A nifty little firewall for macOS to both see which apps are phoning back home (and where) as well as block any culprits from doing so. Bonus: they also sell another app called Micro Snitch that alerts the user whenever the camera or microphone are in use.</p>
<p>6. <strong>Apple Maps</strong>: This one is yet another example of a disappointing v1 that has now matured into a viable alternative. Maps is one area where my transition away from Google’s offerings is <em>not</em> complete: I still use Waze regularly mainly for their crowdsourced annotations (crashes, slowdowns, construction, etc.) which are unmatched on any other maps platform.</p>
<p>7. <a href="https://hey.com/">HEY</a>: This is definitely the new kid on the block. From the folks at Basecamp who have been writing software and books for over 20 years now, this is their “weird” interpretation of what email should be. It’s a bit pricey, no doubt, but what I did like was that I was able to get an OG email address <em>firstinitial lastname</em> @hey.com. HEY deserves a blog post of its own (coming soon).</p>
<p>In conclusion, I have taken the first steps in a journey that is likely to be a thousand miles long. By documenting my experiences here, I hope others can learn about these first-class alternatives.</p>
	</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thefiringneuron.com/2021/01/17/degoogling-my-life/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25823645</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 16:50:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The embedded YouTube player told me what you were watching]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 242 | Comments 101 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25823048">thread link</a>) | @hackerpain
<br/>
January 18, 2021 | https://bugs.xdavidhu.me/google/2021/01/18/the-embedded-youtube-player-told-me-what-you-were-watching-and-more/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bugs.xdavidhu.me/google/2021/01/18/the-embedded-youtube-player-told-me-what-you-were-watching-and-more/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
      <p><em>2019, October 11, 00:16:</em> <br>
I finish the cold frozen pizza that I made hours before but forgot to eat, finally write the report, press submit on the Google security bug submission form, and see the classic, <code>Thanks! We received your report.</code> message. That feeling is hard to beat.</p>

<p>I just submitted a bug, using which, I could simply send a link to someone, and when they click on it and visit my website, I could <strong>steal their YouTube watch history</strong>, the <strong>links to watch all of their unlisted videos</strong>, their <strong>Watch Later playlist</strong>, the list of <strong>videos they’ve liked</strong>, and more. It was pretty damn cool.</p>

<p>How was this possible? Let’s go back in time a little bit.</p>

<p><em>Already made some progress? Skip ahead to <a href="#chapter2" target="_self">Chapter 2</a>, <a href="#chapter3" target="_self">Chapter 3</a>, or <a href="#chapter4" target="_self">Chapter 4</a>!</em></p>

<h4 id="chapter1">Chapter 1: <br>Your special playlists you never created</h4>

<p>This issue requires a little bit of understanding about the inner-workings of YouTube. Most importantly, about these four interesting playlists:</p>

<p>Since YouTube is made up of videos, a bunch of internal stuff in YouTube is made up of <strong>playlists</strong>. Everybody has a few of them, even if they have never created one. I knew about these from previous research I have done (<em>by previous research, I just mean trying every feature and trying to understand how they work</em>), before finding this bug. Let’s look at these playlists one-by-one because they will be important later.</p>

<p><strong>The Watch History playlist:</strong></p>

<p>At the time of finding this bug, every YouTube user had a playlist with the ID <code>HL</code>, which stands for “History List” (I assume). This list contained every video you previously watched on YouTube.</p>

<p><strong>The Watch Later playlist:</strong></p>

<p>You have probably seen the little <code>clock</code> icon everywhere on YouTube, which when pressed, adds the video to your “Watch Later”. This is also just a special playlist internally, with the ID <code>WL</code>.</p>

<p><strong>The Liked Videos playlist:</strong></p>

<p>This is a tricky one. At the time of finding the bug, I was a bit confused about how this works, so I had to use a little bit of guessing. All I knew, that it was constructed by somehow modifying your channel ID, which is a 24 char long string, and can be found by going to your channel page, and looking at the URL:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>"</span><span>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBvX9uEO0a3fZNCK12MAgug</span><span>"</span>
<span>-&gt;</span> <span>channel_id</span> <span>=</span> <span>"</span><span>UCBvX9uEO0a3fZNCK12MAgug</span><span>"</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>After a bit of trial and error, and by looking at the playlists of my testing/personal accounts, I figured out a way to “guess” the special “Liked Videos” playlist. You just had to replace the first 3 characters of the channel ID with <code>LLD</code> or <code>LLB</code>:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>// one of them will be the “Liked Videos” playlist of the given channel</span>
<span>“</span><span>UCBvX9uEO0a3fZNCK12MAgug</span><span>”</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>“</span><span>LLDvX9uEO0a3fZNCK12MAgug</span><span>”</span>
<span>“</span><span>UCBvX9uEO0a3fZNCK12MAgug</span><span>”</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>”</span><span>LLBvX9uEO0a3fZNCK12MAgug</span><span>”</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p><strong>And finally, the most important, the Uploads playlist:</strong></p>

<p>This special playlist contains <strong>all of your videos</strong>. It has everything in it, regardless of the video’s privacy setting. So all <code>Public</code>, <code>Unlisted</code> and <code>Private</code> videos you have ever uploaded, are in your special “Uploads” playlist.</p>

<p>At the time of finding the bug, the same guessing thing had to be used as for the “Liked Videos” playlist, but this time first 3 characters of the channel ID had to be <code>UUD</code> or <code>UUB</code>:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>// one of them will be the “Uploads” playlist of the given channel</span>
<span>“</span><span>UCBvX9uEO0a3fZNCK12MAgug</span><span>”</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>“</span><span>UUDvX9uEO0a3fZNCK12MAgug</span><span>”</span>
<span>“</span><span>UCBvX9uEO0a3fZNCK12MAgug</span><span>”</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>”</span><span>UUBvX9uEO0a3fZNCK12MAgug</span><span>”</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Or, if you don’t want to do any of that, you can just go to the channel’s page, click the <code>Videos</code> tab, and click <code>Play All</code>. But only if that button is visible, which is unfortunately not always the case.</p>

<p>If you are interested in the details about how these playlists have changed since 2019, and how they work today at the time of writing this post, you can check out <a href="https://gist.github.com/xdavidhu/136c7dfa9247e4883c1e4dc7a77350e6">this Gist I made</a>.</p>

<p>So now you know about these special playlists every YouTube user has. Now, you might think that we should just open for example someone’s “Uploads” playlist like you would open any other playlist, and simply leak all of their unlisted videos:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>// how to steal someone's unlisted videos (very easy!!)

1. Open https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=[victims-uploads-playlist]
2. Profit!?
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Unfortunately, it’s not that easy. These playlists are special in another way too, which is that <strong>different users will see different videos in them</strong>. If the channel owner opens his/her “Uploads” playlist, she will see all of her videos, regardless of the privacy setting. If an attacker tries to open the victim’s “Uploads” playlist, <strong>only the <code>Public</code> videos will be shown</strong>, any other <code>Unlisted</code> and <code>Private</code> videos the victim has will just not be there.</p>

<p>As an attacker, we can clearly see that these playlists can contain very sensitive information about the users. We would like to steal these. But unfortunately, they seem to be well protected…</p>

<h4 id="chapter2">Chapter 2: <br>The Embedded Player and it’s API</h4>

<p>If you have a website and want to have a little YouTube player inside it, there is an app for that. And it’s called the <a href="https://developers.google.com/youtube/iframe_api_reference">YouTube IFrame Player</a>. Embedding this player into your website is quite easy, you just have to copy some HTML code with an <code>iframe</code> tag, and paste it into your site’s source:</p>

<p><img src="https://bugs.xdavidhu.me/assets/posts/2021-01-18-the-embedded-youtube-player-told-me-what-you-were-watching-and-more/embedded-player.png" alt="Screenshot of an empty webpage with an embedded YouTube player"></p>

<p>But today websites are rarely that simple, so you might wonder, what if I want to dynamically create a YouTube player with JavaScript? What if I want to automatically pause the video? These problems would seem quite hacky, or even impossible in some cases, due to the rules of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Same-origin_policy">Same-origin Policy</a>, and other protections modern browsers provide.</p>

<p>Thankfully, YouTube has a solution for this as well, the <a href="https://developers.google.com/youtube/iframe_api_reference">YouTube Player API</a>. This API allows you to just add a JS library to your site, and then simply create/modify/control the YouTube players on your site however you’d like, using JavaScript. For example, if you want to pause a video, you can just call <code>player.pauseVideo()</code>.</p>

<p><em>Hm..</em> This is pretty interesting, but how does it work? The answer might be obvious if you have previously worked with cross-origin (iframe) communication. The YouTube player uses the browser’s <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Window/postMessage">PostMessage API</a>, which allows different origins (in our case your site and the YouTube iframe), to send each other little messages over a secure channel. So the YouTube player has a <code>postMessage</code> listener where it listens to commands, and the JS library you put into your site sends messages to it when you want to perform some action, like pausing the video. Actually, the YouTube player is talking a lot, even if you don’t ask it anything. It immediately tells the JS library on your site if anything happens with the player. This makes it possible for your site to add event listeners, which get called when for example the user skips into a currently playing video.</p>

<p>Let’s see a quick example of how this communication works under the hood:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>// this postMessage is sent from your site to the iframe under the hood when you call “player.playVideo()”</span>
<span>-&gt;</span><span>&nbsp;</span><span>{</span><span>"</span><span>event</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>"</span><span>command</span><span>"</span><span>,</span><span>"</span><span>func</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>"</span><span>playVideo</span><span>"</span><span>,</span><span>"</span><span>args</span><span>"</span><span>:[],</span><span>"</span><span>id</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>1</span><span>,</span><span>"</span><span>channel</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>"</span><span>widget</span><span>"</span><span>}</span>

<span>// the iframe sends a lot of stuff back, here are some examples</span>
<span>&lt;-</span> <span>{</span><span>"</span><span>event</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>"</span><span>infoDelivery</span><span>"</span><span>,</span><span>"</span><span>info</span><span>"</span><span>:{</span><span>"</span><span>playerState</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>-</span><span>1</span><span>,</span><span>"</span><span>currentTime</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>0</span><span>,</span><span>"</span><span>duration</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>1344</span><span>,</span><span>"</span><span>videoData</span><span>"</span><span>:{</span><span>"</span><span>video_id</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>"</span><span>M7lc1UVf-VE</span><span>"</span><span>,</span><span>"</span><span>author</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>""</span><span>,</span><span>"</span><span>title</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>"</span><span>YouTube Developers Live: Embedded Web Player Customization</span><span>"</span><span>},</span><span>"</span><span>videoStartBytes</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>0</span><span>,</span><span>"</span><span>videoBytesTotal</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>1</span><span>,</span><span>"</span><span>videoLoadedFraction</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>0</span><span>,</span><span>"</span><span>playbackQuality</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>"</span><span>unknown</span><span>"</span><span>,</span><span>"</span><span>availableQualityLevels</span><span>"</span><span>:[],</span><span>"</span><span>currentTimeLastUpdated_</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>1610191891.79</span><span>,</span><span>"</span><span>playbackRate</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>1</span><span>,</span><span>"</span><span>mediaReferenceTime</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>0</span><span>,</span><span>"</span><span>videoUrl</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>"</span><span>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M7lc1UVf-VE</span><span>"</span><span>,</span><span>"</span><span>playlist</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>null</span><span>,</span><span>"</span><span>playlistIndex</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>-</span><span>1</span><span>},</span><span>"</span><span>id</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>1</span><span>,</span><span>"</span><span>channel</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>"</span><span>widget</span><span>"</span><span>}</span>
<span>&lt;-</span> <span>{</span><span>"</span><span>event</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>"</span><span>onStateChange</span><span>"</span><span>,</span><span>"</span><span>info</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>-</span><span>1</span><span>,</span><span>"</span><span>id</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>1</span><span>,</span><span>"</span><span>channel</span><span>"</span><span>:</span><span>"</span><span>widget</span><span>"</span><span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Just a reminder, I was often confused about this, but the “under-the-hood” commands I just showed an example of are sent <strong>by your site</strong>. By “under-the-hood”, I just mean that developers usually include YouTube’s library, to make communication easier, and that library simply abstracts the details away, so you can just call <code>pauseVideo()</code>, without worrying about anything else. But of course, if you would want, you could manually send these <code>postMessage</code>s to the player, via plain old vanilla JavaScript, and it would work in the exact same way as using the fancy JS library. So just think of it as an abstraction layer, which you have full control of.</p>

<p>If you want to see what <code>postMessage</code>s a page receives, you could just add an event listener to the page which prints every message to the console:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>// listen for all “message” events and log them to the console:</span>
<span>&gt;</span> <span>window</span><span>.</span><span>addEventListener</span><span>(</span><span>"</span><span>message</span><span>"</span><span>,</span> <span>function</span><span>(</span><span>event</span><span>){</span><span>console</span><span>.</span><span>log</span><span>(</span><span>event</span><span>.</span><span>data</span><span>)})</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Okay, so we can play and pause the player with JavaScript. That’s nothing crazy, but it’s cool. Is there anything else we can do? Yes, there is. Actually, if you read the documentation, there is a bunch of stuff we can do using this Player API. Let’s see some of them that might look interesting to us:</p>

<p><strong>The <code>player.getPlaylist()</code> function:</strong></p>

<p>If you want to embed a playlist into your site, you can use the <code>player.loadPlaylist(playlist_id)</code> method of the library to load a playlist into an existing embedded player. After this, you could call <code>playVideo()</code>, and start playing the first video, after which, the next one from the playlist will automatically start playing, and so on. So we have playlist support.</p>

<p>Now, what if you want to embed a playlist into your site, but want to know what videos are in it? There is a <a href="https://developers.google.com/youtube/iframe_api_reference#Retrieving_playlist_information">function</a> for that as well. Calling <code>player.getPlaylist()</code>, on a player that has a playlist currently loaded, will return <em>an array of the video IDs in the playlist as they are currently ordered</em>:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>&gt;</span> <span>player</span><span>.</span><span>getPlaylist</span><span>()</span>

<span>Array</span><span>(</span><span>20</span><span>)</span> <span>[</span> <span>"</span><span>KxgcVAuem8g</span><span>"</span><span>,</span> <span>"</span><span>U_OirTVxiFE</span><span>"</span><span>,</span> <span>"</span><span>rbez_1MEhdQ</span><span>"</span><span>,</span> <span>"</span><span>VpC9qeKUJ00</span><span>"</span><span>,</span>
            <span>"</span><span>LnDjm9jhkoc</span><span>"</span><span>,</span> <span>"</span><span>BQIOEdkivao</span><span>"</span><span>,</span> <span>"</span><span>layKyzA1ABc</span><span>"</span><span>,</span> <span>"</span><span>-Y9gdQnt7zs</span><span>"</span><span>,</span>
            <span>"</span><span>U_OX5vQ567Y</span><span>"</span><span>,</span> <span>"</span><span>ghOqpVet1uQ</span><span>"</span><span>,</span> <span>…</span> <span>]</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Good to know..</p>

<p><strong>The not-really deprecated <code>player.getVideoData()</code> function:</strong></p>

<p>If you look at the raw <code>postMessage</code> communication, often you can see an object named <code>videoData</code> being sent by the iframe to the page. This object contains a bunch of stuff about the currently playing video, …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://bugs.xdavidhu.me/google/2021/01/18/the-embedded-youtube-player-told-me-what-you-were-watching-and-more/">https://bugs.xdavidhu.me/google/2021/01/18/the-embedded-youtube-player-told-me-what-you-were-watching-and-more/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bugs.xdavidhu.me/google/2021/01/18/the-embedded-youtube-player-told-me-what-you-were-watching-and-more/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25823048</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 16:02:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[That XOR Trick (2020)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 401 | Comments 214 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25821718">thread link</a>) | @wagslane
<br/>
January 18, 2021 | https://florian.github.io/xor-trick | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://florian.github.io/xor-trick">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
    <p>There are a whole bunch of popular interview questions that can be solved in one of two ways:
Either using common data structures and algorithms in a sensible manner, or by using some properties of XOR in a seemingly hard to understand way.</p>

<p>While it seems unreasonable to expect the XOR solutions in interviews, it is quite fun to figure out how they work.
As it turns out, they are all based on the same fundamental trick, which we will derive in a bottom-up way in this post.
Afterwards we will look at a bunch of applications of <em>that XOR trick</em> ™, such as solving this popular interview question:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>You are given an array of n - 1 integers which are in the range between 1 and n. All numbers appear exactly once, except one number, which is missing. Find this missing number.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Of course, there are a number of straightforward ways to solve this problem, but there is also a perhaps surprising one using XOR.</p>

<h3 id="xor">XOR</h3>

<p>XOR is a logical operator that works on bits.
Let’s denote it by <code>^</code>.
If the two bits it takes as input are the same, the result is <code>0</code>, otherwise it is <code>1</code>.
This implements an <em>exclusive or</em> operation, i.e. exactly one argument has to be <code>1</code> for the final result to be <code>1</code>.
We can show this using a truth table:</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th><code>x</code></th>
      <th><code>y</code></th>
      <th><code>x ^ y</code></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>0</td>
      <td>0</td>
      <td>0</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>0</td>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>0</td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>0</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>Most programming languages implement <code>^</code> as a bitwise operator, meaning XOR is individually applied to each bit in a string of bits (e.g. a byte).</p>

<p>For example:</p>



<p>since</p>
<div><div><pre><code>0 ^ 0 = 0
0 ^ 1 = 1
1 ^ 0 = 1
1 ^ 1 = 0
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Because of this, we can apply XOR to anything, not just booleans.</p>

<h3 id="deducing-some-useful-properties">Deducing Some Useful Properties</h3>

<p>We can derive a bunch of properties from the previous definition.
Let’s go through them one by one, and then compose them to solve the interview questions previously mentioned.</p>

<h4 id="xor-and-0-x--0--x">XOR and 0: <code>x ^ 0 = x</code></h4>

<p>If one of the two arguments to XOR is <code>0</code>, then the remaining argument is the result.
This directly follows from the truth table by checking the rows where <code>y = 0</code>, namely the first and third row.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th><code>x</code></th>
      <th><code>y</code></th>
      <th><code>x ^ y</code></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>0</strong></td>
      <td><strong>0</strong></td>
      <td><strong>0</strong></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>0</td>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>1</strong></td>
      <td><strong>0</strong></td>
      <td><strong>1</strong></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>0</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h4 id="xor-on-the-same-argument-x--x--0">XOR on the same argument: <code>x ^ x = 0</code></h4>

<p>If the two arguments are the same, the result is always <code>0</code>.
Again, we can convince ourselves that this is true by inspecting the truth table.
This time we have to check the rows where <code>x = y</code>, i.e. the first and last row.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th><code>x</code></th>
      <th><code>y</code></th>
      <th><code>x ^ y</code></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>0</strong></td>
      <td><strong>0</strong></td>
      <td><strong>0</strong></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>0</td>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>0</td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>1</strong></td>
      <td><strong>1</strong></td>
      <td><strong>0</strong></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>Intuitively, this means that if we apply XOR to the same arguments, they cancel each other out.</p>

<h4 id="commutativity-x--y--y--x">Commutativity: <code>x ^ y = y ^ x</code></h4>

<p>XOR is commutative, meaning we can change the order in which we apply XOR.
To prove this, we can check the truth table for both <code>x ^ y</code> and <code>y ^ x</code>:</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th><code>x</code></th>
      <th><code>y</code></th>
      <th><code>x ^ y</code></th>
      <th><code>y ^ x</code></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>0</td>
      <td>0</td>
      <td>0</td>
      <td>0</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>0</td>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>0</td>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>0</td>
      <td>0</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>As we can see, <code>x ^ y</code> and <code>y ^ x</code> always end up with the same value.</p>

<h4 id="sequences-of-xor-operations">Sequences of XOR operations</h4>

<p>By combining all of this, we can deduce the central insight behind everything that is about to follow:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>The XOR trick</strong>: If we have a sequence of XOR operations <code>a ^ b ^ c ^ ...</code>, then we can remove all pairs of duplicated values without affecting the result.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Commutativity allows us to re-order the applications of XOR so that the duplicated elements are next to each other.
Since <code>x ^ x = 0</code> and <code>a ^ 0 = a</code>, each pair of duplicated values has no effect on the outcome.</p>

<p>Let’s go through an example of this:</p>
<div><div><pre><code>  a ^ b ^ c ^ a ^ b     # Commutativity
= a ^ a ^ b ^ b ^ c     # Using x ^ x = 0
= 0 ^ 0 ^ c             # Using x ^ 0 = x (and commutativity)
= c
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Because <code>^</code> is a bitwise operator, this will work regardless of what kind of values <code>a</code>, <code>b</code> and <code>c</code> are.
This idea is really at the heart of how XOR can be used seemingly magically in many situations.</p>

<h3 id="application-1-in-place-swapping">Application 1: In-Place Swapping</h3>

<p>Before we solve the problem of finding the missing number, let’s start with this simpler <a href="https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/swap-two-numbers-without-using-temporary-variable/">problem</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Swap two values x and y in-place, i.e. without using any helper variables.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>It turns out that one can easily solve this problem using the following three XOR instructions:</p>



<p>That seems a bit mysterious.
Why do we end up swapping <code>x</code>, <code>y</code> if we do this?</p>

<p>To see how it works, let’s go through this step by step.
The comment after each instruction shows the current values of <code>(x, y)</code>:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>x ^= y # =&gt;                      (x ^ y, y)
y ^= x # =&gt; (x ^ y, y ^ x ^ y) = (x ^ y, x)
x ^= y # =&gt; (x ^ y ^ x, x)     = (y, x)
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>We can see that this is really just using the properties derived earlier.</p>

<p>The fundamental insight here is that having <code>x ^ y</code> in one register and <code>x</code> in the other, allows us to perfectly reconstruct <code>y</code>.
Once <code>x ^ y</code> is stored (instruction 1), we can just put <code>x</code> into the other register (instruction 2), and then use it to change <code>x ^ y</code> to just <code>y</code> (instruction 3).</p>

<h3 id="application-2-finding-the-missing-number">Application 2: Finding the Missing Number</h3>

<p>Let’s finally solve the problem posed in the beginning of this post:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>You are given an array <code>A</code> of n - 1 integers which are in the range between 1 and n. All numbers appear exactly once, except one number, which is missing. Find this missing number.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Of course, there are many straightforward ways of solving this, but we did set out to do it using XOR.</p>

<p>From the XOR trick we know that having a sequence of XOR statements means we can remove all duplicated arguments.
If we just XOR all values in the given list, however, we cannot apply this trick because there are no duplicates:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>A[0] ^ A[1] ^ ... ^ A[n - 2]
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Note that <code>A[n - 2]</code> is the last index of a list of <code>n - 1</code> elements.</p>

<p>What we can do additionally is to also XOR all values between 1 and n:</p>
<div><div><pre><code>1 ^ 2 ^ ... ^ n ^ A[0] ^ A[1] ^ ... ^ A[n - 2]
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This will give us a sequence of XOR statements where elements appear as follows:</p>
<ul>
  <li>All values in the given list now appear twice:
    <ul>
      <li>once from taking all the values between 1 and n</li>
      <li>once because they were in the original list</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>The missing value appears exactly once:
    <ul>
      <li>once from taking all the values between 1 and n</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>If we XOR all of this, we essentially remove all values that appear twice, thanks to the XOR trick.
This means that we are left with the missing value, which happens to be exactly what we were looking for in the first place.</p>

<p>Coded up, it looks something like this:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>def</span> <span>find_missing</span><span>(</span><span>A</span><span>,</span> <span>n</span><span>):</span>
  <span>result</span> <span>=</span> <span>0</span>

  <span># XOR of all the values from 1 to n
</span>  <span>for</span> <span>value</span> <span>in</span> <span>range</span><span>(</span><span>1</span><span>,</span> <span>n</span> <span>+</span> <span>1</span><span>):</span>
    <span>result</span> <span>^=</span> <span>value</span>

  <span># XOR of all values in the given array
</span>  <span>for</span> <span>value</span> <span>in</span> <span>A</span><span>:</span>
    <span>result</span> <span>^=</span> <span>value</span>

  <span>return</span> <span>result</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Just looking at the code, this seems to be a difficult to understand algorithm.
When knowing how the XOR trick works, however, it becomes fairly trivial.
I think that also shows why it is unreasonable to expect this solution in an interview: It requires knowledge of a very specific trick but not much algorithmic thinking beyond that.</p>

<p>Before we move on to the next application, let me follow up with two remarks.</p>

<h4 id="generalizing-this-beyond-integers">Generalizing this beyond integers</h4>

<p>While we worked on integers from 1 to n so far, this is not required.
In fact, the previous algorithm works in any situation where there is (1) some set of potential elements and (2) a set of elements actually appearing.
The sets may only differ in the one missing element.
This worked out nicely for integers because the set of potential elements just corresponds to the elements from 1 to n.</p>

<p>One could imagine applications where the elements are not integers from 1 to n:</p>
<ul>
  <li>The set of potential elements are <code>Person</code> objects and we ought to find the <code>Person</code> missing from a list of values</li>
  <li>The set of potential elements are all nodes in a graph and we are looking for a missing node</li>
  <li>The set of potential elements are integers in general (not necessarily from 1 to n) and we want to find a missing integer</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="arithmetic-operators-instead-of-xor">Arithmetic operators instead of XOR</h4>

<p>If the algorithm still seems a bit magical – which I hope it does not – it might help to think about how one could achieve the same result using arithmetic operators.
This is actually fairly straightforward:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>def</span> <span>find_missing</span><span>(</span><span>A</span><span>,</span> <span>n</span><span>):</span>
  <span>result</span> <span>=</span> <span>0</span>

  <span># Add all the values from 1 to n
</span>  <span>for</span> <span>value</span> <span>in</span> <span>range</span><span>(</span><span>1</span><span>,</span> <span>n</span> <span>+</span> <span>1</span><span>):</span>
    <span>result</span> <span>+=</span> <span>value</span>

  <span># Subtract all values in the given array
</span>  <span>for</span> <span>value</span> <span>in</span> <span>A</span><span>:</span>
    <span>result</span> <span>-=</span> <span>value</span>

  <span>return</span> <span>result</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>We add all potential integers and then subtract the ones actually appearing.
The solution is not as nice because one would need to handle overflows and because it requires the type of the elements to support <code>+</code>, <code>-</code> with certain properties.
It, however, has the same logic of elements canceling each other out because they appear a certain number of times (once positive, once negative).</p>

<h3 id="application-3-finding-the-duplicate-number">Application 3: Finding the Duplicate Number</h3>

<p>Here’s where it gets fun: We can apply the <em>exact</em> same solution to a similar interview question:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>You are given an array <code>A</code> of <strong>n + 1</strong> integers which are in the range between 1 and n. All numbers appear exactly once, except one number, which is <strong>duplicated</strong>. Find this duplicated number.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Let’s think about what happens if we just apply the exact same algorithm as in the previous solution.
We would get a sequence of XOR statements where elements appear as follows:</p>
<ul>
  <li>The duplicated value appears three times:
    <ul>
      <li>once from taking all the values between 1 and n</li>
      <li>twice because it was duplicated in the original list</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>All other values in the given list appear twice:
    <ul>
      <li>once from taking all the values between 1 and n</li>
      <li>once because they were unique in the original list</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>As previously, all the duplicated elements cancel each other out.
This means we are left with exactly what we are looking for: the element that was duplicated in the original array.
This element appearing three times, combined with XOR, reduces to that very element:</p>


<p>All other elements cancel each other out because they appear exactly twice.</p>

<h3 id="application-4-finding-two-missingduplicate-numbers">Application 4: Finding Two Missing/Duplicate Numbers</h3>

<p>It turns out we can take this even further.
Consider the following, slightly more difficult, problem:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>You are given an array <code>A</code> of <strong>n - 2</strong> integers which are in the range between 1 and n. All numbers appear exactly once, except <strong>two</strong> numbers, which are missing. Find these two missing numbers.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>As before, the problem is completely equivalent when looking for two <em>duplicated</em> numbers, instead of two <em>missing</em> numbers.</p>

<p>And I am sure you guessed it, but we will stick with what worked before and start exactly the …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://florian.github.io/xor-trick">https://florian.github.io/xor-trick</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://florian.github.io/xor-trick</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25821718</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 13:49:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[GitHub Stale Bots – A False Economy]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 285 | Comments 147 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25821092">thread link</a>) | @gitgud
<br/>
January 18, 2021 | https://blog.benwinding.com/github-stale-bots/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.benwinding.com/github-stale-bots/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="wrap">
      
      <div>
        <section id="main"><article id="post-github-stale-bots" itemscope="" itemprop="blogPost">
  
  <div>
    
<div>
  <p><a href="https://i.imgur.com/OOBT9Ta.png" target="_blank" rel="gallery_ckk37lohp000g2nn56zob7isf noopener">
        <img src="https://i.imgur.com/OOBT9Ta.png" itemprop="image">
      </a>
    
  </p>
</div>

    
      <header>
        
  
    
  

      </header>
    
    <div itemprop="articleBody">
      
        <p><em>Stale Bot’s</em> are a type of automated bot on Github, which locks issues which are “stale” (as in have no recent activity). This seems like a helpful tool at first, but in reality it’s terrible for all parties involved.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/angular/angular/issues" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Angular has a popular repository</a> on github which receives hundreds of issues every day. They use the stale bot to lock old issues, which have no activity in order to reduce the amount of issues in the repository. On the surface the Stale Bot is doing great work, reducing the number of active issues in the repo, but in reality it’s a bit insane.</p>
<h2 id="Maintainer’s-perspective"><a href="#Maintainer’s-perspective" title="Maintainer’s perspective"></a>Maintainer’s perspective</h2><p>Issues are being automatically locked, new users can’t add to issue so they create a duplicate issue, or even worse, just don’t report that the issue still exists!</p>
<h2 id="User’s-perspective"><a href="#User’s-perspective" title="User’s perspective"></a>User’s perspective</h2><p>A user of Angular will <em>Google</em> the error text and will usually find the corresponding github issue. But more often than not, the issue is locked, by the heroic <em>lock bot</em>. So they have a few options, continue searching for another more recent (less SEO’d issue) OR either create another issue, effectively duplicating the bug.</p>
<p>If they decide to create a duplicate issue, it will often not be linked it to the original issue… Now there are 2 issues duplicating the same bug in the Angular repo, so what did “Stale Bot” achieve?</p>
<p>Well the stale bot has had the following effects on the repository:</p>
<ol>
<li>Reduce the metric of <em>Open Issues</em> in github</li>
<li>Made duplicate issues far more likely</li>
<li>Increased friction of users reporting that the issue still exists</li>
<li>Ultimately decreased the quality of the software, as the issues don’t accurately reflect reality</li>
</ol>
<p>For a moment, imagine that Stack Overflow did this. If there’s no interaction on a question, then the question should be locked… Well questions that don’t get consistent interaction are inevitably duplicated, or not updated with correct information, or people get frustrated and don’t ask the question again.</p>
<p>The best repo’s in my opinion, don’t prevent users from contributing to older issues. This gives a much better user experience, as friction to contribute to issues is much lower. It also lets the maintainers ensure that old issues aren’t needlessly duplicated. Finally, the community feels like the maintainers actually care about their input, which doesn’t feel that way when an automated <em>stale bot</em> locks and closes your inactive issue without any input from a human…</p>

      
    </div>
    
  </div>
  
    
<nav id="article-nav">
  
  
    <a href="https://blog.benwinding.com/easiest-static-sites-on-dokku/" id="article-nav-older">
      <strong>Older</strong>
      <p>Easiest Static Sites on Dokku!</p>
    </a>
  
</nav>

  
</article>



</section>
        
          
        
      </div>
      
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.benwinding.com/github-stale-bots/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25821092</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 12:28:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Fediverse is better than regular social media]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 72 | Comments 76 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25820646">thread link</a>) | @garritfra
<br/>
January 18, 2021 | https://slashdev.space/posts/2021-01-18-reasons-the-fediverse-is-better | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://slashdev.space/posts/2021-01-18-reasons-the-fediverse-is-better">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Social media sucks. Platforms like Twitter, Facebook and Instagram are designed to turn your precious free time into money. What we see as a nice way to stay in touch with our friends, in reality are just many hits of dopamine stimulating precise spots in your brain, leading to you spending more time on the platform consuming ads.</p><p>But what if I told you that there is a huge ad-free social network out there, not governed by a central authority, full of great people and completely free to use? This place is called the fediverse. Well, it's not really <strong>a</strong> place, it's many places.</p><h2>What is the fediverse?</h2><p>At its core, the fediverse is a mesh of interconnected nodes on the internet, all communicating in the same language. Every instance on the fediverse implements the <a href="https://activitypub.rocks/">ActivityPub</a> protocol, which allows it to talk to other instances on the network. The phrase "Fedi" comes from "federated", meaning that content on the network is shared and accessible by anyone.</p><p>There are many different software projects for the fediverse out there. If you like the concept of Twitter, you could take a look at <a href="https://joinmastodon.org/">Mastodon</a>, a microblogging-platform for the fediverse. There's also <a href="https://joinpeertube.org/">PeerTube</a>, a federated clone of YouTube (PeerTube recently <a href="https://framablog.org/2021/01/07/peertube-v3-its-a-live-a-liiiiive/">released support for peer2peer live streaming support</a>, like what?! 🤯). You like instagram? <a href="https://pixelfed.org/">Pixelfed</a> got you covered. Of course, there are many other services worth mentioning, so feel free to dig around a bit! As mentioned, the great thing about the fediverse is that all of these services are connected with each other. If I signed up for an account on a mastodon instance, I can subscribe to your posts on Pixelfed, and vice versa. If I want to get notified about your videos on PeerTube, I can just go ahead and follow your account and comment on your videos.</p><blockquote><p>"This all sounds great, but why should I bother?"</p></blockquote><p>Let me give you 6 reasons why the fediverse is far superior to all other social media platforms out there, and why you should consider signing up for an account on one of the many instances of the fediverse.</p><h2>Reason 1: It's decentralized</h2><p>Regular social media platforms like Facebook have a <strong>single point of failure</strong>. If their servers go down, your content goes down with it. Content on the fediverse on the other hand is scattered around many instances, which means it is very resilient. If your instance dies, you can move to a new instance. This goes hand in hand with the next reason.</p><h2>Reason 2: It can't be censored</h2><p>You probably heard that the Twitter-account of Donald Trump recently got compromised by the owners of the platform. I don't want to engage in any political discussions, but the main flaw with this is the violation of <strong>freedom of speech</strong>. Even if everything someone says is controversial nonsense, it is still in his good right to express his thoughts.</p><p>On the fediverse, a scenario like this would certainly not happen, given its decentralized nature. Some instances still moderate their content, meaning that if someone posts inappropriate content, it might get blocked. The twist here is, if that person disagrees with the rules of the instance, he is free to join another instance.</p><h2>Reason 3: Free as in freedom</h2><p>There's this saying, criticizing modern software projects:</p><blockquote><p>"If it's free, you're the product"</p></blockquote><p>This is not true in all cases. "Free" can be understood in two ways.</p><p><strong>"Free as in beer"</strong> means that something might seem free at first glance (E.g. Free beer at Oktoberfest), but in the end you often leave with less than you came with. In the case of beer, you often buy another beer after the first free one. Therefore, even though you think you've saved the money for one beer, in reality bought an extra beer. In the case of proprietary software, it's a similar story. While you think that a service is free, you give up your privacy and get monetized with ads.</p><p><strong>"Free as in freedom"</strong> on the other hand means that you won't get "screwed over" like this. Most, if not all of the software for the fediverse is <strong>free and open source software</strong> (FOSS). If you don't like how a certain feature works, <strong>you are completely free to change it</strong>. You can look at the source code and propose changes to the main project, or launch your own spin of that product.</p><p>Since everyone can openly look at the source code, it is <strong>audited</strong> by many people, including security experts. This vastly improves the security and stability of the product. If the developers would do shady things, they will most certainly get called out by people, as soon as that code enters the main repositories. Proprietary (closed sourced) platforms like Facebook and Twitter can not be audited. The owners can do whatever they want, including spying on their users, or collect and sell the data of their users.</p><h2>Reason 4: It respects your privacy</h2><p>Since the software on the fediverse is audited by a lot of people, you can be almost 100% certain that joining an instance will not collect any of your personal data. If you are still concerned about your privacy though, you can still be part of the network by launching your own instance, with your own rules. There are tutorials out there, explaining how you can set up a small instance for a very cheap price on your local network.</p><h2>Reason 5: It's all about the community</h2><p>I used to spend a lot of time on "regular" social media platforms. From personal experiences, these platforms are all about promoting yourself and building up your follower count. Connecting with your friends is of little importance. In the eye of some people, you are not worthy to talk to if the amount of followers or likes-per-post didn't exceed a certain threshold.</p><p>It has now been about 5 months since I created <a href="https://fosstodon.org/@garritfra">my mastodon account</a>. Talking to people on the fediverse is a completely different experience compared to Facebook or Twitter. Almost everyone I talked to is a polite, grounded person, willing to engage in constructive and fun discussions. I met many people who disagree with my views, but instead of leaving a comment saying that this post sucks, all of them took the time to express their alternative opinions. Every member of the fediverse wants to drive the network forward, which is reflected in their posts.</p><h2>Reason 6: There's an instance for everyone</h2><p>Whether you're into Gaming, Painting, or Spanish dancing music, there is an instance for you. If it isn't, you are free to create one and promote it to people of that niche. You won't loose the social aspect by launching your own instance, since you are still available to other people on the network. If you just want to get started with the fediverse, I recommend that you check out one of the many <a href="https://instances.social/">lists of mastodon instances</a>. If you like instagram and want to stay in a familiar environment, take a look at <a href="https://pixelfed.org/">Pixelfed</a>, and join an instance from the list they provide.</p><p>I myself am a person who cares a lot about free and open source software, therefore my choice of instance was <a href="https://fosstodon.org/">fosstodon.org</a>, a mastodon instance geared towards awesome like-minded people.</p><p><strong>Note</strong>: This post has generated some interesting discussions on <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25820646">Hacker News</a>.</p><p>This is post 005 of <a href="https://100daystooffload.com/">#100DaysToOffload</a>.</p><p>If you enjoyed this post, consider<!-- --> <a href="https://donate.slashdev.space/">buying me a coffee</a>! Got comments? Drop a mail in my<!-- --> <a href="https://lists.sr.ht/~garritfra/public-inbox">public inbox</a>, or send me a message on<!-- --> <a href="https://matrix.to/#/@garrit:matrix.slashdev.space">Matrix</a>.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://slashdev.space/posts/2021-01-18-reasons-the-fediverse-is-better</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25820646</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 11:27:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[GPT-Neo – Building a GPT-3-sized model, open source and free]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 698 | Comments 243 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25819803">thread link</a>) | @sieste
<br/>
January 18, 2021 | https://www.eleuther.ai/gpt-neo | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.eleuther.ai/gpt-neo">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.eleuther.ai/gpt-neo</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25819803</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 09:13:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Amiga 1000 Parceiro]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 134 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25818159">thread link</a>) | @jdkee
<br/>
January 17, 2021 | https://www.amigalove.com/viewtopic.php?t=1689 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.amigalove.com/viewtopic.php?t=1689">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/b0yBg6s99F0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>

<p><em>If you’d like to get an Amiga Parceiro for yourself, I explain how you can pre-order one at a heavily discounted rate at the end of the video and this article.</em></p><p>


A couple of years ago I made some videos where I showed my favorite Amiga 1000 setup at that time. It had two main hardware super powers that made it my daily driver. </p><p>

First, a fly-by of a glorious <a href="https://youtu.be/ZmW6LEwgruE">Rejuvenator board</a>, designed by the late Greg Tibbs out of Ohio (RIP Greg). A local good friend of mine here in Seattle named Christian Stich helped me upgrade that board to utilize a rare A3000 Agnus I found that can use 2MB of Chip RAM, which he custom built adapters for it to use. It also has a Kickstart 1.3 ROM chip to accelerate the boot up process and lose the typical Kickstart floppy. </p><div>

	
		
		

				<dl>
			<dt><img src="https://www.amigalove.com/download/file.php?id=6147&amp;sid=015f44f47298773d4880be19bf5f3683" alt="IMG_7827.jpg" onclick="viewableArea(this);"></dt>
						<!-- <dd>IMG_7827.jpg (278.04 KiB) </dd>-->
		</dl>
		
		


		
		
	
</div>

<div>

	
		
		

				<dl>
			<dt><img src="https://www.amigalove.com/download/file.php?id=6148&amp;sid=015f44f47298773d4880be19bf5f3683" alt="IMG_7842.jpg" onclick="viewableArea(this);"></dt>
						<!-- <dd>IMG_7842.jpg (275.15 KiB) </dd>-->
		</dl>
		
		


		
		
	
</div>

<p><em>Christian here is removing the old DRAMs, which were eight 256Kx4 in DIP format. He then installed four custom 1Mx4 in SOJ format  DRAMs with an adapter board that converts them to DIP format.</em></p><p>


The second thing was a hardware combo where I used a Microbotics Starboard expansion made back in 1987 that provided both extra fast RAM (in this case 1Mb), a real-time clock, and a SCSI module called the <a href="https://youtu.be/6BLXxY7FG5M">StarDrive which allowed me to use an Iomega SCSI Zip</a> as an external 100 MB hard drive. It used a custom Workbench boot disk that would pass control from the floppy over to the Zip drive and essentially turn the Zip into a semi-autobooting hard drive, which was a total game changer for that system. For all intents and purposes, that Amiga 1000 became one of my favorite, most treasured systems in my entire Amiga collection. </p><p>

<strong>A1000 equipped Starboard with SCSI Zip 100 as a hard drive </strong></p><p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6BLXxY7FG5M" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>

<p>
Fast-forward to today, as I made the difficult decision to <em>remove</em> the Starboard and Zip drive and replace it with a brand new device called the <strong>Amiga Parceiro</strong>. (Parceiro in Portuguese means “partner”.) So it’s the Friend Partner. <img src="https://www.amigalove.com/images/smilies/icon_e_wink.gif" width="15" height="17" alt=";)" title="Wink"></p><p>

The Amiga Parceiro was invented over the course of the past year by an Amiga hobbyist named David Dunklee who resides in a small town outside of Colorado Springs, CO. </p><p>

As Dunklee puts it:</p><div>

	
		
		

				<dl>
			<dt><img src="https://www.amigalove.com/download/file.php?id=6149&amp;sid=015f44f47298773d4880be19bf5f3683" alt="DDunklee.png" onclick="viewableArea(this);"></dt>
						<!-- <dd>DDunklee.png (152.05 KiB) </dd>-->
		</dl>
		
		


		
		
	
</div>

<p>
Fun Trivia: Mr Dunklee, now retired, was the CIO of the <a href="https://www.spaceforce.mil/">United States Space Force</a>, as well as an Air Force base commander. You heard that right, Number One. </p><p>


So let’s take a look at Mr. Dunklee’s new device for the Amiga 1000 and see what it can do. </p><p>

At a high level, the Parceiro can do everything my Starboard &amp; Zip combo could do except in a very tidy, modern package. And it can do it all faster and better. </p><div>

	
		
		

				<dl>
			<dt><img src="https://www.amigalove.com/download/file.php?id=6150&amp;sid=015f44f47298773d4880be19bf5f3683" alt="IMG_1027.JPG" onclick="viewableArea(this);"></dt>
						<!-- <dd>IMG_1027.JPG (356.15 KiB) </dd>-->
		</dl>
		
		


		
		
	
</div>

<p>
The Parceiro (sounds like par-say-ro) attaches to the side expansion port of the Amiga and is about the size of a harmonica that’s been run over by a steam roller as it’s only about 1/3 of an inch thick.</p><p>

It provides the following features: </p><ol><li> 8MB of Autoconfig Fast RAM. It is a single 8MB of SRAM versus DRAM, so it really and truly is indeed fast with zero wait states.</li> 
<li> Coin-cell battery backed Real Time Clock (RTC), which comes with its own clock software that gets put into your startup sequence.</li>
<li> SD Card Reader with 2GB MicroSD. It comes pre-formatted with the FAT32  file system and is readable on any PC as a result. This way you can quickly set up your new SD-based hard drive.</li></ol> <p>

It’s worth mentioning that this is running on period correct Amiga OS 1.3, too. </p><div>

	
		
		

				<dl>
			<dt><img src="https://www.amigalove.com/download/file.php?id=6151&amp;sid=015f44f47298773d4880be19bf5f3683" alt="IMG_1080_b.jpg" onclick="viewableArea(this);"></dt>
			<dd><em>She is almost completely camouflaged into the Amiga battlestation at this point.</em></dd>			<!-- <dd>IMG_1080_b.jpg (259.01 KiB) </dd>-->
		</dl>
		
		


		
		
	
</div>

<p>
Possibly the best unseen feature is the silkscreen prints Dunklee put around the various chips and resistors on the board. It’s a complete sci-fi treasure trove of labelling, from Back to the Future to Battlestar Galactica. </p><div>

	
		
		

				<dl>
			<dt><img src="https://www.amigalove.com/download/file.php?id=6153&amp;sid=015f44f47298773d4880be19bf5f3683" alt="IMG_1055_b.jpg" onclick="viewableArea(this);"></dt>
						<!-- <dd>IMG_1055_b.jpg (268.24 KiB) </dd>-->
		</dl>
		
		


		
		
	
</div>

<div>

	
		
		

				<dl>
			<dt><img src="https://www.amigalove.com/download/file.php?id=6152&amp;sid=015f44f47298773d4880be19bf5f3683" alt="IMG_1054_b.jpg" onclick="viewableArea(this);"></dt>
						<!-- <dd>IMG_1054_b.jpg (380.51 KiB) </dd>-->
		</dl>
		
		


		
		
	
</div>

<div>

	
		
		

				<dl>
			<dt><img src="https://www.amigalove.com/download/file.php?id=6154&amp;sid=015f44f47298773d4880be19bf5f3683" alt="IMG_1058_b.jpg" onclick="viewableArea(this);"></dt>
			<dd><em>This is where the brilliance really starts to shine.</em></dd>			<!-- <dd>IMG_1058_b.jpg (495.27 KiB) </dd>-->
		</dl>
		
		


		
		
	
</div>

<div>

	
		
		

				<dl>
			<dt><img src="https://www.amigalove.com/download/file.php?id=6155&amp;sid=015f44f47298773d4880be19bf5f3683" alt="circuitboard-cu.jpg" onclick="viewableArea(this);"></dt>
			<dd><em>Yes, you've actually died and gone to heaven via worm hole.</em></dd>			<!-- <dd>circuitboard-cu.jpg (689.75 KiB) </dd>-->
		</dl>
		
		


		
		
	
</div>

<p>
For his fantastic creativity on the silkscreen, I half-jokingly suggested to Mr. Dunklee a future 3D printed case in clear acrylic so I could totally nerd out with his hilarious labels. And I think he might actually take me up on that idea some day! </p><div>

	
		
		

				<dl>
			<dt><img src="https://www.amigalove.com/download/file.php?id=6156&amp;sid=015f44f47298773d4880be19bf5f3683" alt="clear-acryllic-case-parceiro.jpg" onclick="viewableArea(this);"></dt>
			<dd><em>UPDATE: He works really fast!</em></dd>			<!-- <dd>clear-acryllic-case-parceiro.jpg (248.37 KiB) </dd>-->
		</dl>
		
		


		
		
	
</div>

<p>
The Parceiro comes with instructions for creating your own KickWork disk to quickly boot up your machine and install all of the necessary software to run the device. This includes the necessary updates to your Mountlist, Startup-Sequence, adding fat95 drivers as well as the sd.device drivers. </p><p>

The <a href="https://amigalove.com/viewtopic.php?f=7&amp;t=312">KickWork disk idea</a> is based off a product developed in 1988 by Mr. Rudolph Loew (RIP). This is where a Kickstart disk is combined with a stripped down Workbench disk for faster machine boot ups off a single floppy rather than 2. </p><p>

With the Parceiro, Dunklee provides six pages of detailed instructions for getting you up and running in no time. The idea here is the modified KickWork (or Workbench) disk will begin the machine’s boot up process like normal then hand over total control to the SD card like a full-fledged autobooting hard drive. It’s not 100% autobooting, but it’s pretty danged close. And once the machine fully boots you just pop out the boot floppy disk and set it to the side. Mr Dunklee confided with me that in a distant hardware update he might take the next logical step and integrate an FPGA for a true autobooting experience. </p><p>

Since my machine is equipped with a Rejuvenator board, I didn’t need a KickWork disk. So I made a customized Workbench boot disk making the necessary adjustments following Mr Dunklee’s instructions for the RTC software, the SD card device driver and adding the FAT file system library. </p><p>

In the Amiga world, this is about as close to plug-and-play for a device with this many features that I’ve ever come across that doesn’t completely take over your machine and its identity like a Vampire, or some might argue even the ACA500+ (which basically uses the A1000's power to mostly take over). The Parceiro installation was absolutely seamless and I got it up and running without a hitch. </p><p>

Now some of you might be wondering how long it takes to boot this 2GB equipped Amiga. For example, on my Amiga 2000 I have a 40 MB mechanical boot drive, but I also have a SCSI2SD card with 2GB MicroSD for all of my software and data storage. When that machine boots it can sit on a gray screen for about 20 -25 seconds while the large drive is being validated. Once that process is done the A2K snaps to life and I’m on my way. </p><p>

With the Parceiro it’s a very different - and better - experience than I’m used to. The Parceiro still needs to validate the empty space on the drive, but instead it does it in the background. So the Amiga 1000 boots up without that normal long pause. While the background validation is going on, the volume is set to READ ONLY. I can still run programs but I simply can’t write to the drive while the validation is going on. To be honest I wouldn’t even know about this had it not been noted in the instructions, as I’m virtually never writing to the drive the moment I boot it up. And within a few seconds the little Cylon red LED light stops flickering and I know then it’s job is complete (which didn’t directly affect me anyway). </p><p>

Very, very cool! </p><p>

Now, this device is currently in extremely short supply. In fact, I happened to get S/N #1 and I know S/N #2 was sold a few hours after I got mine. At that stage the inventory was sold out. But several more will eventually get made over time so if you’re an Amiga 1000 fan that means you're patient by default. <img src="https://www.amigalove.com/images/smilies/icon_e_wink.gif" width="15" height="17" alt=";)" title="Wink"> I’d highly recommend you keep this on your radar and try to snag one of them for yourself. It’s simply bad ass and it didn’t require me to upgrade my OS beyond adding new drivers - or really change anything - like a lot of modern upgrades often do.  </p><p>

The Parceiro is a fantastic device, made in the USA, and is a very worthy successor to the Microbotics and Supra offerings from BITD. It is one of the few modern devices that is 100% designed for the Amiga 1000 for a change. And how cool and refreshing is that? </p><p>


<strong>Pre-Orders</strong></p><p>

If you’d like to pre-order one of these little technological marvels for yourself at a nearly <strong>20% discounted rate at $195</strong>, simply email <a href="https://www.amigalove.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#dd9cb0b4babcf38dbcafbeb8b4afb29db2a8a9b1b2b2b6f3beb2b0"><span data-cfemail="e4a5898d8385cab4859687818d968ba48b9190888b8b8fca878b89">[email&nbsp;protected]</span></a> to declare your interest <strong>and mention AmigaLove sent you</strong>. You will still need to cover expenses for shipping, of course, but you’ll get in line for your very own Parceiro. David Dunklee will manage the rest from there!</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.amigalove.com/viewtopic.php?t=1689</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25818159</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 04:28:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Tracking down a segfault that suddenly started happening]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 103 | Comments 25 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25818126">thread link</a>) | @zdw
<br/>
January 17, 2021 | https://www.downtowndougbrown.com/2021/01/tracking-down-a-segfault-that-suddenly-started-happening/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.downtowndougbrown.com/2021/01/tracking-down-a-segfault-that-suddenly-started-happening/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
				
<p>I wanted to share a story of a segmentation fault I helped track down this weekend. I thought the final root cause of the segfault was interesting because of how unrelated it was to the code I was trying to debug.</p>



<p>I’ve been maintaining a <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://github.com/dougg3/obs-ios-camera-source" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/dougg3/obs-ios-camera-source" target="_blank">Linux fork</a> of <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://github.com/wtsnz/obs-ios-camera-source" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/wtsnz/obs-ios-camera-source">obs-ios-camera-source</a>, which is an <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://obsproject.com/" target="_blank" data-type="URL" data-id="https://obsproject.com/">OBS</a> plugin that allows you to use an iPhone or iPad’s camera and microphone as a video and audio source in OBS. It works in conjunction with the “<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://obs.camera/" target="_blank">Camera for OBS Studio</a>” app in the App Store. This kind of thing is useful for online streamers who want to use their phone’s camera instead of buying a separate camera. For those of you who don’t know, OBS is short for Open Broadcaster Software. A lot of streamers use it to handle broadcasting their stream. It allows you to capture audio and video, mix it all together, do all kinds of cool things with it, and then record the final result and/or stream it to sites such as YouTube and Twitch.</p>



<p>Getting this plugin working on Linux wasn’t really complicated, because it was already well-written without much platform-specific code. After all, the existing codebase was already operational on both macOS and Windows. It mostly just required tweaking a few compile/link options to make the code run happily on Linux.</p>



<p>Anyway, I’m pretty sure a good number of people have been using my Linux port of this plugin without issues. I know it works fine for me when I test with it in Ubuntu 18.04 or 20.04. I’ve helped people on other distros get it working too. I don’t really do any streaming myself — maybe someday though!</p>



<p>On Friday, GitHub user rrondeau <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://github.com/dougg3/obs-ios-camera-source/issues/4" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/dougg3/obs-ios-camera-source/issues/4" target="_blank">reported an issue</a>: after a half a year of the obs-ios-camera-source plugin working without a problem, it suddenly started causing OBS to segfault on his computer (currently running Fedora 33). He provided a stack trace that showed that the segfault was happening because of something initiated by the plugin. Afterward, he used GDB to get a better stack trace that provided more info about the functions being called and the parameters being passed:</p>


<pre title="">#0  0x00007fffee7abc64 in socket_send () at /usr/lib64/samba/libsamba-sockets-samba4.so
#1  0x00007fff88b7813c in send_packet (sfd=50, message=8, tag=1, payload=0x1b22e60, payload_size=488) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-ios-camera-source/deps/libusbmuxd/src/libusbmuxd.c:400
#2  0x00007fff88b782a6 in send_plist_packet (sfd=50, tag=1, message=0x1ae53e0) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-ios-camera-source/deps/libusbmuxd/src/libusbmuxd.c:431
#3  0x00007fff88b7851b in send_list_devices_packet (sfd=50, tag=1) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-ios-camera-source/deps/libusbmuxd/src/libusbmuxd.c:499
#4  0x00007fff88b79367 in usbmuxd_get_device_list (device_list=0x7fffffffc740) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-ios-camera-source/deps/libusbmuxd/src/libusbmuxd.c:938
#5  0x00007fff88b725e1 in portal::Portal::addConnectedDevices() (this=0x1909378) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-ios-camera-source/deps/portal/src/Portal.cpp:109
#6  0x00007fff88b72684 in portal::Portal::reloadDeviceList() (this=0x1909378) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-ios-camera-source/deps/portal/src/Portal.cpp:126
#7  0x00007fff88b722db in portal::Portal::Portal(portal::PortalDelegate*) (this=0x1909378, delegate=0x1909240) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-ios-camera-source/deps/portal/src/Portal.cpp:57
#8  0x00007fff88b67053 in IOSCameraInput::IOSCameraInput(obs_source*, obs_data*) (this=0x1909240, source_=0x1aee000, settings=0x19210a0)
    at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-ios-camera-source/src/obs-ios-camera-source.cpp:74
#9  0x00007fff88b66358 in CreateIOSCameraInput(obs_data_t*, obs_source_t*) (settings=0x19210a0, source=0x1aee000) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-ios-camera-source/src/obs-ios-camera-source.cpp:371
#10 0x00007ffff6259c2a in obs_source_create_internal () at /lib64/libobs.so.0
#11 0x00007ffff626bb81 in obs_load_source_type () at /lib64/libobs.so.0
#12 0x00007ffff626e3c2 in obs_load_sources () at /lib64/libobs.so.0
#13 0x000000000049e750 in OBSBasic::Load(char const*) (this=0xa370b0, file=0x7fffffffd040 "/home/rrondeau/.config/obs-studio/basic/scenes/Untitled.json")
    at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-studio/UI/window-basic-main.cpp:973
#14 0x00000000004a2976 in OBSBasic::OBSInit() (this=0xa370b0) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-studio/UI/window-basic-main.cpp:1783
#15 0x000000000047feff in OBSApp::OBSInit() (this=0x7fffffffd690) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-studio/UI/obs-app.cpp:1415
#16 0x0000000000482503 in run_program(std::fstream&amp;amp;, int, char**) (logFile=..., argc=1, argv=0x7fffffffdd68) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-studio/UI/obs-app.cpp:2052
#17 0x0000000000484203 in main(int, char**) (argc=1, argv=0x7fffffffdd68) at /home/rrondeau/git/perso/obs-studio/UI/obs-app.cpp:2697
</pre>


<p>The actual segfault was happening inside of a function called “socket_send” in libsamba-sockets-samba4.so, which was being called by a function in libusbmuxd, which is bundled as part of the obs-ios-camera-source plugin source code and is used for communicating with iOS devices over USB. When I first saw this in the stack trace, my mind thought “Huh…that’s weird. Why does libusbmuxd use Samba’s library for its socket code instead of providing its own?” (<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.samba.org/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.samba.org/" target="_blank">Samba</a> is an implementation of the Windows file sharing protocol used by pretty much every Linux distribution)</p>



<p>I tested and couldn’t reproduce the issue in Ubuntu. I know basically nothing about Fedora, but I faked my way through grabbing a Fedora 33 virtual machine, installing OBS, and compiling the plugin. I ran into the exact same issue that he was seeing.</p>



<p>Before I had a chance to look deeper and understand what was going on, rrondeau beat me to the correct conclusion: code in Samba’s library was mistakenly being called. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://github.com/dougg3/obs-ios-camera-source/blob/8181922136e12ef618c8449f95a52e40d7104ded/deps/libusbmuxd/common/socket.h#L61" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/dougg3/obs-ios-camera-source/blob/8181922136e12ef618c8449f95a52e40d7104ded/deps/libusbmuxd/common/socket.h#L61" target="_blank">libusbmuxd has a function called socket_send</a>, but clearly <a href="https://github.com/samba-team/samba/blob/f52f531771d6a25b2e363384bf94a9fa14334e1b/source4/lib/socket/socket.h#L152" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/samba-team/samba/blob/f52f531771d6a25b2e363384bf94a9fa14334e1b/source4/lib/socket/socket.h#L152" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">libsamba-sockets-samba4’s function that is also named socket_send</a> was accidentally being called instead.</p>



<p>Honestly, that’s all we really needed to know. Renaming libusbmuxd’s socket_send function to something else, and updating all references to it to use the new name, fixed the issue. I still wanted to understand why this suddenly became an issue when it had been working fine prior to that. Why were we calling into Samba libraries? Why does an iOS USB multiplexing library even consider talking to a library associated with Windows file sharing?</p>



<p>Not knowing the answer to that question bothered me. I decided to dig deeper and understand exactly what was going on. I started by using <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ldd_(Unix)" data-type="URL" data-id="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ldd_(Unix)" target="_blank">ldd</a>, which lists all dynamic libraries used by a program or library:</p>


<pre title="">[fedora@fedora33 build]$ ldd obs-ios-camera-source.so 
	linux-vdso.so.1 (0x00007fffa599a000)
	libobs.so.0 =&gt; /lib64/libobs.so.0 (0x00007f0a3f688000)
	libavcodec.so.58 =&gt; /lib64/libavcodec.so.58 (0x00007f0a3e2db000)
	libavutil.so.56 =&gt; /lib64/libavutil.so.56 (0x00007f0a3e036000)
...
	libsamba-sockets-samba4.so =&gt; /usr/lib64/samba/libsamba-sockets-samba4.so (0x00007fd6af4b7000)
...
</pre>


<p>I truncated the output because it spit out a very long list of libraries. As we can see from ldd’s output, obs-ios-camera-source.so depends on libsamba-sockets-samba4.so. ldd lists all recursive dependencies as well, and I couldn’t find any references to “samba” in the plugin source code, so this was likely an indirect dependency instead. I confirmed this by using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Readelf" data-type="URL" data-id="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Readelf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">readelf</a> to show only the direct dependencies:</p>


<pre title="">[fedora@fedora33 build]$ readelf -d obs-ios-camera-source.so | grep NEEDED
 0x0000000000000001 (NEEDED)             Shared library: [libobs.so.0]
 0x0000000000000001 (NEEDED)             Shared library: [libavcodec.so.58]
 0x0000000000000001 (NEEDED)             Shared library: [libavutil.so.56]
 0x0000000000000001 (NEEDED)             Shared library: [libobs-frontend-api.so.0]
 0x0000000000000001 (NEEDED)             Shared library: [libstdc++.so.6]
 0x0000000000000001 (NEEDED)             Shared library: [libm.so.6]
 0x0000000000000001 (NEEDED)             Shared library: [libgcc_s.so.1]
 0x0000000000000001 (NEEDED)             Shared library: [libpthread.so.0]
 0x0000000000000001 (NEEDED)             Shared library: [libc.so.6]
</pre>


<p>At this point I used ldd and readelf to walk through the tree of dependencies and figure out what was actually linking against the Samba libraries. I later learned that I could have installed lddtree (part of the pax-utils package) to do this automatically. Either way, this led me to discover that the Samba libraries were being included through libsmbclient, which was a dependency of libavformat (part of FFmpeg). libavformat is a dependency of libobs.</p>



<p>Repeating this experiment on Ubuntu showed that libavformat on Ubuntu does not depend on libsmbclient. This explains why I couldn’t reproduce the issue on Ubuntu. So why does Fedora’s (well, <a href="https://rpmfusion.org/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://rpmfusion.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">RPM Fusion</a>‘s) version of libavformat depend on libsmbclient?</p>



<p>It turns out that it’s a compile-time option for FFmpeg. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://github.com/FFmpeg/FFmpeg/blob/master/libavformat/libsmbclient.c" data-type="URL" data-id="https://github.com/FFmpeg/FFmpeg/blob/master/libavformat/libsmbclient.c" target="_blank">libavformat contains code for talking with Windows servers using libsmbclient</a>, but it’s an optional thing that you can choose to enable at compile time. Clearly Ubuntu chooses not to enable it, but RPM Fusion does. <a href="https://lists.rpmfusion.org/archives/list/rpmfusion-commits@lists.rpmfusion.org/thread/57UYP4VFY3VCJFU3DGPHLUE3JPYP73HJ/">Actually, I found the exact post on RPM Fusion’s commits mailing list</a> where the patch was added for enabling SMB support in FFmpeg. This patch is what led to the whole issue happening. If Ubuntu’s version of FFmpeg was being built with SMB support, we would have seen this a long time ago. This commit to RPM Fusion was made on December 31, 2020, which explains why rrondeau had only recently begun seeing the problem.</p>



<p>The root cause here is that the obs-ios-camera-source plugin was linking against two libraries that both provided a function named socket_send: libsamba-sockets-samba4 (indirectly through libobs) and libusbmuxd. libusbmuxd was being linked statically, but <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/62884945/shared-library-symbol-conflicts-and-static-linking-on-linux" data-type="URL" data-id="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/62884945/shared-library-symbol-conflicts-and-static-linking-on-linux" target="_blank">that doesn’t prevent functions in it from being resolved through dynamic linking rules anyway</a>. So even though libusbmuxd was a static library with its own internal implementation of socket_send, it was using …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.downtowndougbrown.com/2021/01/tracking-down-a-segfault-that-suddenly-started-happening/">https://www.downtowndougbrown.com/2021/01/tracking-down-a-segfault-that-suddenly-started-happening/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.downtowndougbrown.com/2021/01/tracking-down-a-segfault-that-suddenly-started-happening/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25818126</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 04:25:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Body on a 3-day fast: Real-time data with Basis]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 63 | Comments 65 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25817380">thread link</a>) | @TheJurgen
<br/>
January 17, 2021 | https://basishealth.io/blog/real-time-fasting-data-with-basis | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://basishealth.io/blog/real-time-fasting-data-with-basis">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="single-content-content"><p>Caloric restriction is the practice of taking fewer calories than total daily energy needs. Caloric restriction without malnutrition is the most effective non-pharmacological intervention that enhances longevity and healthspan in numerous species. It has been proven to reduce oxidative stress through various pathways and a growing body of evidence shows that sustained periods of caloric restriction without malnutrition improves risk factors involved in the pathophysiology of type 2 diabetes, cardiovascular diseases, cancer, and neurological disorders in humans. (Weindruch, 1996)</p><p>But chronic caloric restriction is difficult to sustain and newer dietary strategies such as intermittent fasting and protein restriction have emerged as alternative approaches that still improve markers of aging. The most popular type of caloric restriction applied today is a 16:8 Time-Restricted Feeding schedule i.e. no eating for 16 hours, eat for 8 hours. While difficult for some to get started, Intermittent Fasting is generally easy to adopt and has important short and long-term health benefits such as metabolic, cardiovascular, and digestive health benefits. </p><p>Multi-day fasting is another form of fasting with a higher detoxifying effect that activates important an important cellular restoration process called autophagy. Autophagy is a super useful process that recycles, cleans up, and rids your body of damaged and misfolded proteins. When your cells are constantly fed, they aren't worried about efficiency and restoration - they're thinking that 'times are good, we don't need to work hard anymore.' In a well-fed state, your cells are only concerned with growing. Besides putting all their emphasis on growth, your well-fed cells also turn other genes off such as those related to fat metabolism, stress resistance, and damage repair. </p><p>During fasting (starvation), things are very different. We have a well-preserved starvation “program” that kicks our cell into a completely different state when food, particularly glucose or sugar, isn’t around. Your body reacts to the newfound stress by waking up cell functions to protect you and as a result, starts acting more efficiently and dynamically. This 'reactivation' of the cellular system leads to lowered inflammation, increases your brain's resistance to stress, and many other important long-term health benefits.</p><h2>So, what happens to your body on a fast?</h2><p>At Basis, we wanted to put the science to the test and really see what happens in real-time to your body when you’re following a prolonged fast. So I volunteered to be the guinea pig by spending last week doing a 3-day water fast and tracking my vitals in real-time with Basis to see the impact it has on my body.</p><p><img alt="Fasting data" src="https://images.ctfassets.net/xxkgr6gh5t72/3gyIfqHoGt8Iegl8jOcKxR/2eed6467ced1c30d17ca5fd14d27fbf3/Fasting_real_time_.png"></p><p>The Basis app added an extra layer of health confidence for me because I was getting real-time glucose data from my biosensor and could identify if I was going into a hypoglycemic attack; my wearable was connected to Basis and was giving me real-time heart rate data, and I was tracking my hydration and running a once-a-day urinalysis test in Basis to confirm that I wasn’t dealing with dehydration. In Basis, I was also getting my sleep reports for each night, including a time-specific snapshot of my glucose and heart rate - something of particular interest since more than 40% of hypoglycemic events happen during sleep. </p><p>For data sharing purposes, I also did a pre- and post-fast blood panel. You can see a table with the biomarkers I tested for at the top of this post. I've also provided body composition data because I'm sure most people think of fasting for weight loss purposes. </p><p>Disclaimer: Speak with your doctor before undertaking any type of fasting with or without Basis. Your doctor will advise you if any pre-existing condition or abnormalities in your biomarkers could create complications.</p><p>Without further ado, let’s jump into the Basis real-time data along with an explanation of the cellular process that happens as you hit different intervals in your fast. </p><h3><b>DAY 1</b></h3><p>Loading Chart</p><p>Glucose: Low 75 / High 119 / Average 94 </p><p>Glucose Variability: 10.31</p><p>Heart-rate: Low 49 / High 96 / Average 62</p><br><h4><b>12 hours - Hello ketosis. </b></h4><p>In this state, your body starts to break down and burn fat. This process creates ketones which serve as an alternative energy source when glucose isn’t available. </p><br><h4><b>18 hours - Fat-burning mode.</b> </h4><p>I'm now generating significant ketones and I can now begin to measure blood ketone levels above baseline values. Under normal conditions, the concentration of ketones in your plasma ranges below 20 mg/dL but when you fast this concentration can reach 80+ mg/dL. My ketones measured at 32 mg/dL compared to 80 mg/dL for my glucose. </p><br><h4><b>24 hours - Autophagy</b></h4><p>Autophagy can only happen when your glucose stores are significantly low. In humans, that usually happens after 24 hours of fasting. (Alirezaei et al., Autophagy 2010)</p><h3><b>DAY 2</b></h3><p>Loading Chart</p><p>Glucose: Low 69 / High 107 / Average 85 </p><p>Glucose variability: 9.96</p><p>Heart-rate: Low 45 / High 97 / Average 62 </p><br><h4><b>48 hours - Peak growth hormone</b> </h4><p>Growth hormone helps preserve lean muscle mass and reduces fat tissue accumulation, particularly as we age. It also appears to promote wound healing and cardiovascular health. After two days of fasting, the large number of circulating ketone bodies and the impact of ghrelin, the hunger hormone, promote increased growth hormone secretion (Hartman et al.,1992). </p><p>At this point in the fast, my glucose line is virtually flat, ranging between 75 - 85 mg/dL and I'm preserving my energy for essential activities and work. </p><h3><b>DAY 3</b></h3><p>Loading Chart</p><p>Glucose: Low 69 / High 90 / Average 78 </p><p>Glucose variability: 8.27</p><p>Heart-rate: Low 50 / High 120 / Average 64 </p><br><h4><b>72 hours - Checkpoint. </b></h4><p>At the 3-day mark, I've hit a key milestone in cellular regeneration. My body has broken down old immune cells and generated new ones (Cheng et al., 2014). Getting those Covid defenses up! Interestingly, through this same mechanism, prolonged fasting for at least 72 hours has been shown to also preserve healthy white blood cell or lymphocyte counts in patients undergoing chemotherapy. </p><p>Last ketone measurement before breaking the fast. Approaching the 80 mg/dL along with a 79mg/dL glucose level measurement.  </p><br><h4><b>Bonus stage: Refeeding!</b></h4><p>The fast isn’t done until you get some food back in your body. The most important thing to remember is that you should resist the temptation to chow down on a pizza or a burger because as amazing as that may seem in the moment, and trust me the temptation is always there, after 3 days of just sipping on water, it will feel absolutely terrible afterward. Your stomach has for all-intensive purposes shrunk and hasn’t gone through the process of digesting anything for 3 days. You’ll get bad stomach cramping and spend quite a bit of time in the bathroom if you eat a carb-heavy meal. </p><p>Beyond this practical reason, it’s important to break your fast with a nutritious, balanced meal that will further enhance the all-around cell and tissue health-boosting exercise you just undertook. </p><h3><b>Looking for a clearer view of your health?</b></h3><p><a href="https://basishealth.typeform.com/to/ovy5RnER">Sign up</a> for the Basis Early Access Beta and discover what having real-time access to your health data means. </p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://basishealth.io/blog/real-time-fasting-data-with-basis</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25817380</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 02:04:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
