<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 20]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 20. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 08:21:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-20.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 08:21:38 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Using an old BlackBerry as a portable SSH or Telnet terminal]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 38 | Comments 22 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24166402">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
August 14, 2020 | https://rqsall.com/posts/using-an-old-blackberry-as-a-portable-ssh-terminal | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rqsall.com/posts/using-an-old-blackberry-as-a-portable-ssh-terminal">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main-copy">


<h2 id="using-an-old-blackberry-as-a-portable-ssh-or-telnet-terminal">Using an old BlackBerry as a portable SSH (or Telnet) terminal</h2>
<p>You used to see BlackBerries everywhere. Sites such as CrackBerry detailed sightings of celebrities using them constantly. Nowadays, not so much. However, I believe they still have some usecases today. One of these is as a portable terminal. Here's why one might want to use one of these devices as a terminal:</p>
<ul>
<li>Nice built-in physical keyboard</li>
<li>Long standby battery life
<ul>
<li>Easily swappable batteries (see my Altoids tin filled with batteries below!)</li>
<li>The 7290 I'm using reportedly has a 216 hour standby battery life, and unlike modern phones this number seems to hold up relatively well even with network enabled</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Affordable
<ul>
<li>You can easily find these devices for ~$20 on eBay</li>
<li>You can get a 100 MB data plan from US Mobile for $2/mo. not including fees (closer to $5/mo. with fees)</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Extremely portable
<ul>
<li>Much smaller than other devices one might use for this kind of thing
<ul>
<li>OpenPandora</li>
<li>GPD Pocket</li>
<li>etc.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Much shorter than most modern phones</li>
<li>Cellular connection means you don't need a wireless router around</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Decently rugged
<ul>
<li>Not nearly as prone to failure after drops as modern smartphones (in my experience)
<ul>
<li>The screen is recessed, so it doesn't take the brunt of falls</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Easy to setup
<ul>
<li>You can simply browse to <a href="http://xk72.com/wap">http://xk72.com/wap</a> on the phone itself to install an SSH client (MidpSSH) over the air</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
<p>I've been using a BlackBerry 7290 on the US Mobile network, which still supports GSM for now. It's notable that the SSH negotiation is decently slow (~30-45 seconds), but is decently usable after connected (things are still a little sluggish however). Furthermore, I had to reenable the weak DSA public key algorithm as well. This doesn't bother me so much as I basically have a middleman server that allows this weak standard that I talk to everything else through rather than enabling it on every server.</p>
<p>To make things easier on myself, I wrote an <a href="https://rqsall.com/posts/files/postlogin.txt">interactive script</a> that is sourced by <code>.bashrc</code> upon logging in that asks what I actually want to connect to and then does so for me.</p>
<p>In the future, I might move to a BlackBerry 8700(c/g) as they support EDGE (much faster network speed), have much faster CPUs, and a higher standby time. I am not sure what I am going to do in the long run, as 2G networks in the US will probably all be shut down by the end of the year with 3G soon to follow. I guess I can just enjoy it while it lasts.</p>
<p>Here are the lines I added to my <code>sshd</code> config for the BlackBerry to be able to connect:</p>
<pre><code>HostKeyAlgorithms +ssh-dss
PubkeyAcceptedKeyTypes +ssh-dss
KexAlgorithms +diffie-hellman-group1-sha1
Ciphers +3des-cbc
</code></pre>
<p>And here are some pictures!</p>
<p><img src="https://rqsall.com/posts/files/connected.jpg"></p>
<p><em>Connected and at the interactive prompt</em></p>
<p><img src="https://rqsall.com/posts/files/top.jpg"></p>
<p><em><code>top</code> output from one server</em></p>
<p><img src="https://rqsall.com/posts/files/htop.jpg"></p>
<p><em><code>htop</code> output from another server</em></p>
<p><img src="https://rqsall.com/posts/files/altoids.jpg"></p>
<p><em>Spare batteries kept in an Altoids tin</em></p>


</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rqsall.com/posts/using-an-old-blackberry-as-a-portable-ssh-terminal</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24166402</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 06:06:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Mozilla’s Uncertain Future]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 161 | Comments 138 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24166385">thread link</a>) | @jonathankoren
<br/>
August 14, 2020 | https://civilityandtruth.com/2020/08/13/mozillas-uncertain-future/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://civilityandtruth.com/2020/08/13/mozillas-uncertain-future/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section itemprop="text">
        
        <figure>
  <p><a href="https://civilityandtruth.com/assets/images/mozilla-revenues-vs-expenses.png"><img src="https://civilityandtruth.com/assets/images/mozilla-revenues-vs-expenses.png" alt="Graph of Mozilla revenues compared to expenses"></a></p>
  <figcaption>The graph above shows the consolidated revenues and
expenses of the Mozilla Foundation and Mozilla Corporation from the
Foundation’s founding in 2003 through 2018. Almost all of the revenues
and expenses are associated with the Mozilla Corporation, and almost
all of the revenues of the Mozilla Corporation are from Google and
other search engine providers. Graph © 2020 Frank Hecker, made
available under the <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">Creative Commons
Attribution 4.0 International license</a>.</figcaption>
</figure>

<p><em>tl;dr: Some thoughts on Mozilla for people who don’t know Mozilla.</em></p>

<p>By now everyone in the tech world has heard of the major layoffs at
the Mozilla Corporation, the organization that creates and distributes
the Firefox web browser. (For those who haven’t heard, about 250
people were laid off, about a quarter of the work force.) Lots of
people in the tech world have spoken their piece about the
significance of this event and what it means for the future of
Mozilla, the web, and so on.</p>

<p>Rather than write something of and for the tech world, I wanted to
briefly explain what’s going on for those of my readers who don’t know
HTML from XML, and who are more familar with the worlds of nonprofits
and regular old businesses. I used to work for Mozilla, and have more
knowledge of it and (I hope) insight into it than most people, but
I’ve been gone from Mozilla for ten years now. Thus what I write below
is based on observing it from a distance, like seeing an old friend
whose life has long since diverged from mine.</p>

<p>Disclaimer: I work for a tech company, and I don’t usually write about
other tech companies. So I will strongly emphasize that what I write
here are my personal opinions only, and do not represent the positions
of my present employer or past employers.</p>

<h2 id="what-is-mozilla">What is Mozilla?</h2>

<p>Mozilla is actually two things, the Mozilla Foundation and the Mozilla
Corporation, which are often confused and conflated in public
discourse. (There’s actually at least one other piece, but these two
are the main ones.) The Mozilla Foundation, founded in 2003 to take
over development of the source code for the Netscape web browser, is a
501(c)(3) tax-exempt nonprofit organization, with a staff of 80 people
and a budget of about $27 million in 2018, the last year for which
figures are available. The Mozilla Corporation, founded in 2005, is a
for-profit business, wholly owned by the Mozilla Foundation, with a
staff of about a thousand and revenue of about $440 million, again
from the 2018 financials.</p>

<p>This organizational structure was designed to allow the Mozilla
Corporation to engage in business activities which would be
incompatible with 501(c)(3) status, with a portion of the revenues
from those activities directed to the Mozilla Foundation to help fund
its activities. Having a nonprofit parent also means that the
management and employees of the Mozilla Corporation can help serve the
public benefit goals of the Mozilla Foundation, while still having
interesting jobs, being paid reasonably well, and feeling themselves
to be part of the overall Silicon Valley high-tech milieu.</p>

<p>Second: The customers of the Mozilla Corporation are not the users of
Firefox (among whom you may count yourself). The Mozilla Corporation’s
customers are large corporations like Google that pay for things that
will help them make money, most notably having their Internet search
service be the default in the Firefox browser. And to complete the old
saying, “If you’re not the customer…”, then the 200+ million Firefox
users are the product, potential viewers of ads served up by Google or
others.</p>

<p>(The existence of the Firefox browser as a competitor to Google’s
Chrome browser also supposedly helps Google avoid unwelcome antitrust
attention, especially now that Microsoft has abandoned its own browser
development efforts to base its own browser on the Chrome code. But
it’s unclear how important this consideration actually is to Google
senior management.)</p>

<p>In the early days of the Mozilla Corporation these search engine
relationships proved extremely lucrative, jumping from less than $5
million in 2004 to over $50 million in 2005, the first year in which
the Mozilla Corporation reported financial results, and eventually
growing to a high of about $540 million in 2017.</p>

<p>But as the number of Firefox users decreases (due to the growing
market dominance of the Chrome browser), and those users click on
fewer online ads (for example, because they’re spending less during
the COVID-19 pandemic), the willingness of Google and other customers
to pay the Mozilla Corporation for those users decreases
accordingly. Thus the Mozilla Corporation cutting a quarter of its
workforce.</p>

<p>(In contrast, to my knowledge the Mozilla Foundation itself is not
laying off anyone, at least at this time. It gets its funding from a
combination of royalties from the Mozilla Corporation for use of the
Firefox and Mozilla trademarks, government and foundation grants, and
individual donations. For 2018 the royalties accounted for about half
of the Mozilla Foundation’s budget, with grants and individual donations
each accounting for about a quarter of the budget.)</p>

<p>So, if you’re an avid user of the Firefox browser and want to chip in
a few dollars to help support its development, there’s actually no way
for you to do so, at least not at present. Your donations will go to
the Mozilla Foundation, which will use them to help fund its outreach
and advocacy initiatives, of which it has several. The Mozilla
Foundation itself does not develop Firefox—or any other software, to
my knowledge.</p>

<h2 id="whence-mozilla">Whence Mozilla?</h2>

<p>How has Mozilla (or, more correctly, the Mozilla Corporation) come
to its present pass? The best way I can explain it is that the Mozilla
Corporation is not really a business in the way we’d normally think of
a business, profit-focused and subject to market discipline.</p>

<p>Instead you can think of the Mozilla Corporation as being analogous to
the Bell Labs or Xerox PARC of yore, R&amp;D organizations funded by a
seemingly-unending stream of profits earned by other businesses that
enjoyed dominant positions in their respective markets. In this sense
Google is to Mozilla as AT&amp;T was to Bell Labs, or Xerox to Xerox
PARC.</p>

<p>Like Bell Labs and Xerox PARC, the Mozilla Corporation provided a home
for some of the smartest software developers around. Like those
organizations, the Mozila Corporation has initiated a myriad of
projects ranging from the mundane and useful (like the Firefox
browser) to the esoteric and speculative. Like those organizations,
the Mozilla Corporation has given away much of what it has produced in
the form of public goods available to everyone at no charge.</p>

<p>Like Bell Labs and Xerox PARC, the Mozilla Corporation has indulged a
taste for “build it yourself” vertical integration, and in particular
for creating its own bespoke development tools and software stack. For
example, like those organizations the Mozilla Corporation has created
its own operating system (FirefoxOS), its own programming language
(Rust), and (of course) its own graphical user environment in the form
of the Firefox browser (not to mention yet another web browser, this
one more research-oriented, and various experiments in software for
virtual reality environments).</p>

<p>And finally, the Mozilla Corporation is engaged in the same struggle
that Bell Labs and Xerox PARC found themselves in: trying to convert a
research-oriented organization into an actual business, and capture
for itself more of the value that it has been providing to the world
(and to its past, present, and future competitors) for free.</p>

<h2 id="whither-mozilla">Whither Mozilla?</h2>

<p>What will happen to Mozilla, and to the Mozilla Corporation in
particular? The basic situation is that Mozilla has tried to be at
least three things simultaneously: an advocacy organization, a
developer and distributor of mass market consumer software and related
services, and (as noted above) a research lab.</p>

<p>Being an advocacy organization is relatively inexpensive, but the
other two functions are not: software development (including
research-related activities) and branding and marketing together
consumed almost three quarters of the combined Mozilla Corporation and
Foundation expense budget of $450 million in 2018. Thus when COVID-19
hit and the Mozilla Corporation hit a brick wall in terms of search
engine revenue, its choice was apparently either to stop being a
consumer software and services company, or to stop being a research
lab.</p>

<p>In the end Mozilla Corporation senior management apparently decided to
go for being a consumer software and services company, and to ditch
any activities not related to that, including research projects.
Having done so, the Mozilla Corporation faces a number of problems:</p>

<p>First, as noted above the Mozilla ethos is arguably more like that of
an R&amp;D lab than of a business proper. Just getting Mozilla
employees to think of themselves as working in the service of a
profit-driven business, and to act in accordance with that thought
every single day, may be an uphill battle.</p>

<p>Second, Mozilla is arguably becoming superfluous, at least as far as
its own largest customer, Google, is concerned. Google has its own
browser and browser development team, its own research lab, and
presumably an inclination to want to spend its R&amp;D money on things
it can control and direct itself. Google also has the ability and the
opportunity to capture the remaining base of Firefox users, at least
those that are monetizable.</p>

<p>There will always be a core of enthusiastic Firefox users, but a lot
of them switch their search engine to something other than Google, run
ad blockers, and don’t click on online ads. Thus they are for the most
part irrelevant from Google’s point of view. At some point the major
value Firefox has for Google will be as presumed insulation from
antitrust enforcement efforts targeting Chrome, but such insurance,
even if it’s of value to Google, doesn’t necessarily require a large
Firefox user base.</p>

<p>Finally, it’s …</p></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://civilityandtruth.com/2020/08/13/mozillas-uncertain-future/">https://civilityandtruth.com/2020/08/13/mozillas-uncertain-future/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://civilityandtruth.com/2020/08/13/mozillas-uncertain-future/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24166385</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 06:03:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Write Your Own Virtual Machine]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 113 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24166137">thread link</a>) | @ChankeyPathak
<br/>
August 14, 2020 | https://justinmeiners.github.io/lc3-vm/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://justinmeiners.github.io/lc3-vm/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
<section>

<a name="1:1"></a>
<a name="1:2"></a><div><a name="1:2"><h4>2. Introduction</h4></a>
<p>In this tutorial, I will teach you how to write your own virtual machine (VM) that can run assembly language programs, such as my friend's <a href="https://github.com/rpendleton/lc3-2048">2048</a> or my <a href="https://github.com/justinmeiners/lc3-rogue">Roguelike</a>. If you know how to program, but would like to gain a deeper understanding of what is going on inside a computer and better understand how programming languages work, then this project is for you. Writing your own VM may sound a little scary, but I promise that you will find it to be surprisingly simple and enlightening.
</p>
<p>The final code is about 250 lines of C (<a href="https://justinmeiners.github.io/lc3-vm/src/lc3.c">unix</a>, <a href="https://justinmeiners.github.io/lc3-vm/src/lc3-win.c">windows</a>).
All you need to know is how to read basic C or C++ and how to do <a href="https://www.swarthmore.edu/NatSci/echeeve1/Ref/BinaryMath/BinaryMath.html">binary arithmetic</a>.
</p>
<blockquote><p> <strong>Note:</strong> This VM is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Literate_programming">literate program</a>. This means you are reading the source code right now! Each piece of code from the project will be shown and explained thoroughly, so you can be sure nothing is left out. The final code was created by <a href="https://github.com/zyedidia/Literate">"weaving"</a> the blocks of code together.
</p>
</blockquote>
<h3> What is a virtual machine?</h3>
<p>A VM is a program that acts like a computer. It simulates a CPU along with a few other hardware components, allowing it to perform arithmetic, read and write to memory, and interact with I/O devices, just like a physical computer. Most importantly, it can understand a machine language which you can use to program it.
</p>
<p>The amount of computer hardware the VM attempts to simulate depends on its purpose. Some VMs are designed to reproduce the behavior of some particular computer, such as video game emulators. Most people don't have an NES lying around anymore, but we can still play NES games by simulating the NES hardware in a program. These emulators must <a href="http://wiki.nesdev.com/w/index.php/Tricky-to-emulate_games">faithfully recreate</a> every <a href="http://wiki.nesdev.com/w/index.php/Emulator_tests">detail</a> and major hardware component of the original device.
</p>
<p>Other VMs don't act like any real computer and are entirely made up! This is primarily done to make software development easier. Imagine you wanted to create a program that ran on multiple computer architectures. A VM could offer a standard platform which provided portability for all of them. Instead of rewriting a program in different dialects of assembly for each CPU architecture, you would only need to write the small VM program in each assembly language. Each program would then be written only once in the VM's assembly language.
</p>
<p><img src="https://justinmeiners.github.io/lc3-vm/img/no_vm.gif" alt="architecture specific implementation">
</p>
<p><img src="https://justinmeiners.github.io/lc3-vm/img/vm.gif" alt="vm for each architecture">
</p>
<blockquote><p> <strong>Note:</strong> A compiler solves a similar problem by compiling a standard <em>high-level language</em> to several CPU architectures. A VM creates one standard <em>CPU architecture</em> which is simulated on various hardware devices. One advantage of a compiler is that it has no runtime overhead while a VM does. Even though compilers do a pretty good job, writing a new one that targets multiple platforms is very difficult, so VMs are still helpful here. In practice, VMs and compilers are mixed at various levels.
</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Java_virtual_machine">Java Virtual Machine (JVM)</a> is a very successful example. The JVM itself is a moderately sized program that is small enough for one programmer to understand. This has made it possible to be written for thousands of devices including phones. Once the JVM is implemented on a new device, any Java, Kotlin, or Clojure program ever written can run on it without modification. The only cost is the overhead of the VM itself and the <a href="https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2002/11/11/the-law-of-leaky-abstractions/">further abstraction</a> from the machine. Most of the time, this is a pretty good tradeoff.
</p>
<p>A VM doesn't have to be large or pervasive to provide a similar benefit. Old <a href="https://fabiensanglard.net/anotherWorld_code_review/">video games</a> often used small VMs to provide simple <a href="https://sf2platinum.wordpress.com/page/1/">scripting systems</a>.
</p>
<p>VMs are also useful for executing code in a secure or isolated way. One application of this is garbage collection. There <a href="https://www.lua.org/pil/24.2.html">is no trivial way</a> to implement automatic garbage collection on top of C or C++ since a program cannot see its own stack or variables. However, a VM is “outside” the program it is running and can observe all of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tracing_garbage_collection">memory references</a> on the stack.
</p>
<p>Another example of this behavior is demonstrated by <a href="https://solidity.readthedocs.io/en/v0.4.24/introduction-to-smart-contracts.html">Ethereum smart contracts</a>. Smart contracts are small programs which are executed by each validating node in the blockchain network. This requires the node operators to run programs on their machines that have been written by complete strangers, without any opportunity to scrutinize them beforehand. To prevent a contract from doing malicious things, they are run inside a <a href="http://ethdocs.org/en/latest/introduction/what-is-ethereum.html#ethereum-virtual-machine">VM</a> that has no access to the file system, network, disc, etc. Ethereum is also a good application of the portability features that result when using a VM. Since Ethereum nodes can be run on many kinds of computers and operating systems, the use of a VM allows smart contracts to be written without any consideration of the many platforms they run on.
</p>

</div>
<a name="1:3"></a><div><a name="1:3"><h4>3. LC-3 Architecture</h4></a>
<p>Our VM will simulate a fictional computer called the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Little_Computer_3">LC-3</a>. The LC-3 is popular for teaching university students how to program in assembly language. It has a simplified instruction set <a href="http://ref.x86asm.net/coder64.html">compared to x86</a>, but contains all the main ideas used in modern CPUs.
</p>
<p>First, we need to simulate the essential hardware components of the machine. Try to understand what each component is, but don't worry right now if you are unsure of how it fits into the larger picture. Start by creating a C file. Each of the code snippets in this section should be placed in the global scope of this file.
</p>
<h3> Memory</h3>
<p>The LC-3 has 65,536 memory locations (the maximum that is addressable by a 16-bit unsigned integer <code>2^16</code>), each of which stores a 16-bit value. This means it can store a total of only 128kb, which is a lot smaller than you may be used to! In our program, this memory will be stored in a simple array:
</p>

<div>
<p><span>{Memory Storage <a href="https://justinmeiners.github.io/lc3-vm/index.html#1:3">3</a>}</span></p><pre>/* 65536 locations */
uint16_t memory[UINT16_MAX];
</pre>


<p>Used in section <a href="https://justinmeiners.github.io/lc3-vm/index.html#1:11">11</a></p>
</div>
<h3> Registers</h3>
<p>A register is a slot for storing a single value on the CPU. Registers are like the "workbench" of the CPU. For the CPU to work with a piece of data, it has to be in one of the registers. However, since there are just a few registers, only a minimal amount of data can be loaded at any given time. Programs work around this by loading values from memory into registers, calculating values into other registers, and then storing the final results back in memory.
</p>
<p>The LC-3 has 10 total registers, each of which is 16 bits. Most of them are general purpose, but a few have designated roles.
</p>
<ul>
<li>8 general purpose registers  (<code>R0</code>-<code>R7</code>)
</li>
<li>1 program counter (<code>PC</code>) register
</li>
<li>1 condition flags (<code>COND</code>) register
</li>
</ul>
<p>The general purpose registers can be used to perform any program calculations. The program counter is an unsigned integer which is the address of the next instruction in memory to execute. The condition flags tell us information about the previous calculation.
</p>

<div>
<p><span>{Registers <a href="https://justinmeiners.github.io/lc3-vm/index.html#1:3">3</a>}</span></p><pre>enum
{
    R_R0 = 0,
    R_R1,
    R_R2,
    R_R3,
    R_R4,
    R_R5,
    R_R6,
    R_R7,
    R_PC, /* program counter */
    R_COND,
    R_COUNT
};
</pre>



</div>
<p>Just like the memory, we will store the registers in an array:
</p>

<div>
<p><span>{Register Storage <a href="https://justinmeiners.github.io/lc3-vm/index.html#1:3">3</a>}</span></p><pre>uint16_t reg[R_COUNT];
</pre>


<p>Used in section <a href="https://justinmeiners.github.io/lc3-vm/index.html#1:11">11</a></p>
</div>
<h3> Instruction Set</h3>
<p>An instruction is a command which tells the CPU to do some fundamental task, such as add two numbers. Instructions have both an <strong>opcode</strong> which indicates the kind of task to perform and a set of <strong>parameters</strong> which provide inputs to the task being performed.
</p>
<p>Each <strong>opcode</strong> represents one task that the CPU "knows" how to do. There are just 16 opcodes in LC-3. Everything the computer can calculate is some sequence of these simple instructions. Each instruction is 16 bits long, with the left 4 bits storing the opcode. The rest of the bits are used to store the parameters.
</p>
<p>We will discuss, in detail, what each instruction does later. For now, define the following opcodes. Make sure they stay in this order so that they are assigned the proper enum value:
</p>

<div>
<p><span>{Opcodes <a href="https://justinmeiners.github.io/lc3-vm/index.html#1:3">3</a>}</span></p><pre>enum
{
    OP_BR = 0, /* branch */
    OP_ADD,    /* add  */
    OP_LD,     /* load */
    OP_ST,     /* store */
    OP_JSR,    /* jump register */
    OP_AND,    /* bitwise and */
    OP_LDR,    /* load register */
    OP_STR,    /* store register */
    OP_RTI,    /* unused */
    OP_NOT,    /* bitwise not */
    OP_LDI,    /* load indirect */
    OP_STI,    /* store indirect */
    OP_JMP,    /* jump */
    OP_RES,    /* reserved (unused) */
    OP_LEA,    /* load effective address */
    OP_TRAP    /* execute trap */
};
</pre>



</div>
<blockquote><p> <strong>Note:</strong> The Intel x86 architecture has hundreds of instructions, while others such as ARM and LC-3 have very few. Small instruction sets are referred to as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reduced_instruction_set_computer">RISCs</a> while larger ones are called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Complex_instruction_set_computer">CISCs</a>. Larger instruction sets typically do not provide any fundamentally new possibilities, but they <a href="https://cs.stanford.edu/people/eroberts/courses/soco/projects/risc/risccisc/">often make it more convenient</a> to write assembly for. A single instruction in CISC might take the place of several in RISC. However, they tend to be more complex and expensive for engineers to design and manufacture. This and other tradeoffs cause the designs to come <a href="https://cs.stackexchange.com/questions/269/why-would-anyone-want-cisc">in and out of style</a>.
</p>
</blockquote>
<h3> Condition Flags</h3>
<p>The <code>R_COND</code> register stores condition flags which provide information about the most recently executed calculation. This allows programs to check logical conditions such as <code>if (x &gt; 0) { ... }</code>.
</p>
<p>Each CPU has a variety of condition flags to signal various situations. The LC-3 uses only 3 condition flags which indicate the sign of the previous calculation.
</p>

<div>
<p><span>{Condition Flags <a href="https://justinmeiners.github.io/lc3-vm/index.html#1:3">3</a>}</span></p><pre>enum
{
    FL_POS = 1 &lt;&lt; 0, /* P */
    FL_ZRO = 1 &lt;&lt; 1, /* Z */
    FL_NEG = 1 &lt;&lt; 2, /* N */
};
</pre>



</div>
<blockquote><p> <strong>Note:</strong> (The <code>&lt;&lt;</code> symbol is called the <a href="https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/336xbhcz.aspx">left bitshift operator</a>. <code>(n &lt;&lt; k)</code> shifts the bits of <code>n</code> to the left <code>k</code> places. Thus <code>1 &lt;&lt; 2</code> will equal <code>4</code>. Read that link if you are not familiar. It will be important.)
</p>
</blockquote>
<p>We are finished setting up the hardware components of our VM! After adding standard includes (see reference), your file should look something like this:
</p>

<div>
<p><span>{<strong>lc3.c</strong> <a href="https://justinmeiners.github.io/lc3-vm/index.html#1:3">3</a>}</span></p><pre><span>{Includes, <a href="https://justinmeiners.github.io/lc3-vm/index.html#1:12">12</a>}</span>

<span>{Registers, <a href="https://justinmeiners.github.io/lc3-vm/index.html#1:3">3</a>}</span>
<span>{Opcodes, <a href="https://justinmeiners.github.io/lc3-vm/index.html#1:3">3</a>}</span>
<span>{Condition Flags, <a href="https://justinmeiners.github.io/lc3-vm/index.html#1:3">3</a>}</span>
</pre>
<p>Added to in section <a href="https://justinmeiners.github.io/lc3-vm/index.html#1:11">11</a></p>


</div>
</div>
<a name="1:4"></a><div><a name="1:4"><h4>4. Assembly Examples</h4></a>
<p>Now let's look at an LC-3 assembly program to get an idea of what the VM actually runs. You don't need to know how to program assembly or understand everything that is going on. Just try to get a general idea of what is going on. Here is a simple "Hello World":
</p>

<div>
<p><span>{Hello World Assembly <a href="https://justinmeiners.github.io/lc3-vm/index.html#1:4">4</a>}</span></p><pre>.O…</pre></div></div></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://justinmeiners.github.io/lc3-vm/">https://justinmeiners.github.io/lc3-vm/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://justinmeiners.github.io/lc3-vm/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24166137</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 05:10:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Brain Oriented Programming]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 55 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24165893">thread link</a>) | @pbw
<br/>
August 14, 2020 | https://tobeva.com/articles/brain-oriented-programming/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://tobeva.com/articles/brain-oriented-programming/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <div>
        
        
        <main role="main">
          
<div>
	
	<p>Write code that’s compatible with how your brain works.</p>
	
	<p><strong>Video</strong>: <a href="https://youtu.be/D8Pb8TvYsCE">Philip reading this essay</a>.</p>
<p>The 1956 paper <em><a href="http://psychclassics.yorku.ca/Miller/">The Magical Number Seven, Plus or Minus
Two</a></em> is the most widely cited paper
in the 126 year history of the journal <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychological_Review">Psychological
Review</a></em>. The author
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Armitage_Miller">George A. Miller</a> is
considered one of the founders in the field of cognitive science. His
historic claim is that you can only juggle <strong>between 5 and 9 things</strong> in
your brain at any one time.</p>
<p>To my knowledge, despite some
<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4486516/">controversy</a> over
the years, this 7 ± 2 figure has withstood the ongoing
<a href="https://www.nature.com/news/1-500-scientists-lift-the-lid-on-reproducibility-1.19970">reproducibility
crisis</a>
and it appears to capture a deep truth about how our brains actually
function.</p>
<p>Many people are skeptical of the claim because seven sounds like an
absurdly small number, surely if you are doing something complex like
writing software, or planning a wedding for that matter, you are juggling
dozens to hundreds of things? As it turns out you are not. At least not at
once.</p>







<div>
	<p><img src="https://tobeva.com/articles/brain-oriented-programming/pi_hu91e4edcab74d735c218b5a61e20b8fdd_76318_250x0_resize_q75_catmullrom.jpg" width="250" height="188"></p><p>
The first 225 digits of <a href="https://dancohen.org/2010/03/08/the-last-digit-of-pi/">Pi</a>.
</p>
	
</div>
<p>In 2005 <strong>Lu Chao</strong> recited <a href="https://www.livescience.com/50134-pi-day-memory-experts.html">67,890
digits</a> of
Pi, a mind-boggling demonstration of a gifted and well-trained mind. Yet
given a series of random single-digit numbers he can on average recall less
the than nine of them, to be exact he’s been measured to have a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Memory_span#Digit-span">digit
span</a> of 8.83 which
fits perfectly within Miller’s finding. Amazing!</p>
<p>Chao memorizes Pi the same way story tellers once memorized long tales
about <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gilgamesh">Gilgamesh</a>, yet he can only
juggle a handful of things at one time. I find this actually to be very
comforting, he is not a freak of nature, at least not as freaky as you
first thought.</p>
<p>The illusion we can hold many things in mind is almost identical to the
illusion that our field of view is high resolution everywhere. It’s
incredibly compelling because the instant we wonder <em>what’s over there</em> we
do a quick <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saccade">saccade</a> and are
immediately rewarded with a high resolution view of exactly <em>what’s over
there</em>. We ask the question and we get an instant answer, so it feels like
the answer was there the whole time.</p>







<div>
	<p><img src="https://tobeva.com/articles/brain-oriented-programming/fovea_hu32924f3118f640732af8b68aadca9340_30500_512x0_resize_q75_catmullrom.jpg" width="512" height="227"></p><p> This picture exaggerates how big the
fovea is, it's actually only about as big as quarter held at arm's length.
</p>
	
</div>
<p>Thinking in general works very much like vision. This is not surprising
since it’s implemented using the same brain hardware. As we rapidly flit
from idea to idea, from concept to concept, we page in the necessary
details, but at no time do we have more than about nine individual things
in the front of our minds.</p>
<p>How do we navigate a complex world with this seemingly crippling limit on
the size of our working memory? Two of the primary tools that we use are
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chunking_(psychology)">chunking</a> and
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hierarchy">hierarchy</a>.</p>
<p>When we think of a car we naturally divide the car into a handful of high
level chunks like the <em>engine</em>, the <em>dashboard</em>, the <em>seats</em>, the <em>wheels</em>.
When we mentally zoom into the engine, however, it effortlessly resolves
into more parts: the <em>engine block</em>, the <em>pistons</em>, the <em>spark plugs</em>. And
we can keep zooming in, although how far we can zoom in highly depends on
how much we know about cars and the world in general.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Object-oriented_programming">Object Oriented
Programming</a> one
of the simplest ways to tame complexity is to limit your objects to around
seven <em>attributes</em>. In some languages attributes are called <em>member
variables</em> or <em>fields</em>. Many programmers immediately balk at this
suggestion. Sure, that works for toy examples, but I’m writing serious
software and my objects sometimes need 10, 20 or 50 attributes. You must be
working on easy stuff, they will say. My problems are special, so my code
has to be different.</p>
<p>The biggest trap of software development is that it’s easy, trivial in
fact, to write software that you yourself cannot understand, and in turn no
one else can understand. Even a novice, <em>especially</em> a novice, can in a few
weeks write software that literally no one on the planet can easily think
or reason about. That’s depressing, but also kind of impressive in a way.
With great power comes great responsibility.</p>
<p>Objects which have too many attributes are a major cause of software that’s
too complicated to understand. Some people conclude the problem is Object
Oriented Programming itself. This is not a crazy idea, there are <a href="https://tobeva.com/resources/technical/programming/functional/">other
ways</a> to program, and they do
have advantages, but in my experience most of the flaws attributed to
Object Oriented Programming stem from having done it poorly, and boy is it
easy to do poorly.</p>







<div>
	<p><img src="https://tobeva.com/articles/brain-oriented-programming/complex_hua73d922edef0eeb6c3d75f190e4c0729_39455_350x0_resize_q75_catmullrom.jpg" width="350" height="197"></p><p>
Complexity grows without bound.
</p>
	
</div>
<p>The key thing to realize is a single object with a lot of attributes is
itself <em>not</em> Object Oriented. Instead, it’s a 1970s style <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Structured_programming">Structured
Program</a> in disguise.
The attributes of the object are the <strong>global variables</strong> of the program,
and the object’s methods are the program’s <strong>functions</strong>. Every function
can freely access every global variable which is what causes many of the
problems.</p>
<p>A structured program with more than seven global variables is trouble, and
if many objects in your program are effectively messy structured programs
themselves, you are in serious trouble indeed. At a high level you are
doing Object Oriented Programming, but at a low level you are right back in
the 1970s struggling to deal with one confusing program after the next.</p>
<p>How do we save this sinking ship? We save it by actively and aggressively
keeping the number of attributes per object <strong>at or below seven</strong>. If you
fail to do this you are punting the problem <em>to your future self</em>, a
problem that by definition your future self is going to have a hard time
solving.</p>
<p>Just today I had a <a href="https://www.python.org/">Python</a> class called
<code>PerfEvent</code> with these attributes:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="python">        <span>self</span><span>.</span><span>name</span> <span>=</span> <span>name</span>
        <span>self</span><span>.</span><span>start_ns</span> <span>=</span> <span>start_ns</span>
        <span>self</span><span>.</span><span>end_ns</span> <span>=</span> <span>end_ns</span>
        <span>self</span><span>.</span><span>category</span> <span>=</span> <span>category</span>
        <span>self</span><span>.</span><span>process_id</span> <span>=</span> <span>process_id</span>
        <span>self</span><span>.</span><span>thread_id</span> <span>=</span> <span>thread_id</span>
        <span>self</span><span>.</span><span>args</span> <span>=</span> <span>kwargs</span>
        <span>self</span><span>.</span><span>phase</span> <span>=</span> <span>phase</span></code></pre></div>
<p>That’s eight attributes, since eight is only one over the limit, should we
wait until the object grows bigger? No, let’s deal with it <em>now</em>. To reduce
the number of attributes we introduce two new classes or structs: <code>Span</code>
and <code>Origin</code>. Each only has two attributes, but now the original object has
been slimmed down to six attributes, all is well again:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="python">        <span>self</span><span>.</span><span>name</span> <span>=</span> <span>name</span>
        <span>self</span><span>.</span><span>span</span> <span>=</span> <span>Span</span><span>(</span><span>start_ns</span><span>,</span> <span>end_ns</span><span>)</span>
        <span>self</span><span>.</span><span>category</span> <span>=</span> <span>category</span>
        <span>self</span><span>.</span><span>origin</span> <span>=</span> <span>Origin</span><span>(</span><span>process_id</span><span>,</span> <span>thread_id</span><span>)</span>
        <span>self</span><span>.</span><span>args</span> <span>=</span> <span>kwargs</span>
        <span>self</span><span>.</span><span>phase</span> <span>=</span> <span>phase</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Although it’s a minor change, compare the two versions, the improved one
simply <em>looks</em> better, even if you stand far back and squint.</p>
<p>It seems minor, but if you don’t make these types of changes as you go it
will eventually lead to <em>intractable</em> complexity, the type of complexity
that causes projects and companies to fail, the type of complexity that
seduces humans into wasting <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/computing/software/why-software-fails">billions of
dollars</a>
every year writing software that does not work.</p>
<p>The benefits of introducing sub-objects goes far beyond just reducing the
number of attributes. While accessing the attributes is slightly more
verbose, I like the sound of <code>self.span.start_ns</code> compared to just
<code>self.start_ns</code>, but more importantly we can now pass <code>Span</code>'s and
<code>Owner</code>'s to functions, slimming down and chunking <em>their</em> argument lists.</p>
<p>We’ve introduced two natural and useful concepts that will pay ongoing
dividends, but even better don’t just think of how your code is today,
think about how it’s going to grow over time. Your single monolithic object
has sprouted two buds. You can now push functionality down into these buds,
and they can grow into branches, which later can sprout buds of their own.</p>
<p>For example we can now give <code>Span</code> a <code>get_duration_ns()</code> method. Again it seems
minor, but writing <code>span.get_duration_ns()</code> is better than writing
<code>span.end_ns - span.start_ns</code> especially if you are going to do that in
many different places.</p>
<p>The real magic though is that the benefits of being disciplined will accrue
like <a href="https://youtu.be/GtaoP0skPWc">compound interest</a> as you convert your
monolithic object into an intricately structured tree which buds and
sprouts and branches organically. You will benefit from this better design
every minute you are working on the software, and the software will benefit
greatly from your improved mood and ability to sustain focus.</p>







<div>
	<p><img src="https://tobeva.com/articles/brain-oriented-programming/featured-tree_hu59909ef0ac042e2e36ece8869e025722_141987_512x0_resize_q75_catmullrom.jpg" width="512" height="256"></p><p> 
A carefully tended <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bonsai">Bonsai</a> tree.
</p>
	
</div>
<p>Code, like most human created artifacts, can be beautiful, so there is an
aesthetic pay off here, but the real jackpot is that if you assiduously
tend and groom this tree you will create a software design that slides into
your head with minimal fuss and friction, and slides similarly into the
heads of other people.</p>
<p>It’s no accident that we find natural environments to be more soothing than
the made world, than the concrete jungle. The design of the natural world
tends to be more in harmony with how our brains think about that world.
Game recognizes game.</p>
<p>Over time, you will grow a system that you and others can <strong>understand</strong>,
<strong>maintain</strong>, <strong>debug</strong> and <strong>extend</strong>. When people look at your code years
from now, maybe even in the <a href="https://archiveprogram.github.com/">far
future</a>, they will benefit from your
diligence and hard work. And the punchline is doing all this is not hard.
In fact, it’s <em>much easier</em> to do this work than not to not do it.</p>
<p>It’s easier and more pleasant to work with something that’s well crafted
and simpatico with your thinking. It’s hard and unpleasant to constantly
wrestle with something you don’t understand. Trim, prune and shape your
objects early and often. Your brain will thank you.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>See Also:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Hacker News <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24165893">comments</a> on this article.</li>
<li>Find your own digit span with this <a href="https://www.memorylosstest.com/digit-span/">Digit Span Memory Test</a>.</li>
<li>Some Chimpanzees have <a href="https://youtu.be/nTgeLEWr614?t=7">better working memory</a> than humans!</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Postscript on APIs:</strong></p>
<p><em>The article discusses objects and attributes, not methods and APIs. NumPy’s</em>
<em><a href="https://numpy.org/doc/stable/reference/arrays.ndarray.html">ndarray</a> has</em>
<em>15 attributes but 50 methods. That’s totally fine, but imagine the</em>
<em>opposite, if it had 50 attributes? That would probably be a mess.</em></p>
<p><em>Attributes are global variables in the structured program that is the</em>
<em>object, so each additional attribute potentially complicates the</em>
<em>implementation of every other method in the object, present and future.</em></p>
<p><em>In contrast, adding a new …</em></p></div></main></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://tobeva.com/articles/brain-oriented-programming/">https://tobeva.com/articles/brain-oriented-programming/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://tobeva.com/articles/brain-oriented-programming/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24165893</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 04:18:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[My best SEO tactic so far]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 200 | Comments 52 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24163658">thread link</a>) | @AlchemistCamp
<br/>
August 14, 2020 | https://questinglog.com/my-best-seo-tactic-so-far/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://questinglog.com/my-best-seo-tactic-so-far/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>Over the years, I've worked on building search traffic for two kinds of sites.</p> <p>The first, was working for companies that already had hundreds of thousands or millions of monthly users and were trying to build their traffic via a team of writers. I did this first for Verbling (as a side component to my work as a full-time dev), and then later for Codementor, as a remote growth consultant.</p> <p>The second, was my own sites or apps where 100% of the content was produced by me. I've also helped several other independent solo-founders do essentially the same for their own projects. Today's advice is for 2nd type of site—the ones with just one writer.</p> <p>For a quick point of reference, I'll what I'm currently working on so you can get an idea of how applicable my experience is or isn't to you:  <a href="https://alchemist.camp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Alchemist Camp</a>. It targets an extremely small programming niche and is hovering around Alexa 700k (10-15k uniques/month with decent visit time). I add new content about once a week. Previously, I built a considerably larger personal blog that peaked at about Alexa 300k, but it's no longer up.</p> <h2 id="work-with-the-search-engine"><a href="#work-with-the-search-engine">#</a> Work <em>with</em> the search engine</h2> <p>There's a lot of competition for attention from search engines and an entire industry of people trying to game them. It's possible to do that successfully in the short term, but people who do that generally get crushed when new search ranking updates. The more egregious marketers sometimes get penalized or banned entirely.</p> <p>There are certain technical SEO basics to pay attention to, such as having a reasonable site structure, a sitemap and appropriate meta-tags. I'm going to assume you've got that covered. WordPress or any other modern CMS will do an adequate job out of the box.</p> <p>So with the above assumptions, what's a good way to cut through the competition?</p> <h2 id="pay-attention-when-a-search-is-frustrating"><a href="#pay-attention-when-a-search-is-frustrating">#</a> Pay attention when a search is frustrating</h2> <p>The single most successful strategy I've found for getting search engine traffic for a more niche site has been to pay very close attention when something is difficult to find online. This isn't very difficult to do, since it's easy to notice when something is frustrating. The key is to be aware and take notes.</p> <p>Look at your browser history and write down <em>the exact queries</em> you typed into Google, Duckduckgo or your search engine of choice. Ask yourself <em>what</em> you were hoping to find online and why you tried each query after the first.</p> <h2 id="create-what-you-hoped-your-search-would-find"><a href="#create-what-you-hoped-your-search-would-find">#</a> Create what you hoped your search would find</h2> <p>Then, after you've learned what you were trying to learn during your frustrating search, create the very thing you were trying to find.</p> <p>Usually a search is difficult because the ideal answer doesn't exist in a single document online or video. Instead, finding the answer involves piecing the information together from numerous sources. If that was the case with your frustrating search, then the next step is to create the answer to the search and publish it.</p> <p>Occasionally after a long and frustrating search, you <em>will</em> find a single resource that answers exactly what you wanted. In this case the question is, "Why didn't my first several searches return this document?" Maybe it used different terminology than you did. Maybe it was comment on an ancient forum post. Maybe it was on an extremely slow site. Make your own version of the resource you finally found, but fix whatever issue made it difficult to find.</p> <h3 id="an-example"><a href="#an-example">#</a> An example</h3> <p>One direct example of using this strategy was when it took me about 20 minutes of searching to find out how to do a certain kind of query with Elixir's main DB-related library, Ecto. Elixir maps are stored in Postgres as JSONB fields, and I wanted to query fields within the JSONB.</p> <p>I saw I'd made 8 searches, starting with <em>"query nested fields of a map ecto"</em>. Ultimately the whole answer to what I was looking for was split between a Thoughtbot post, a Stack Overflow answer and a Postgres documentation page.</p> <p>Then I wrote a short article called, <a href="https://alchemist.camp/articles/querying-nested-map-ecto" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Querying nested fields of a map with Ecto</a> that contained exactly the information I'd been looking for, and it's since brought in a thousand visitors from search in under a year.</p> <h2 id="why-does-this-work"><a href="#why-does-this-work">#</a> Why does this work?</h2> <p>This strategy tends to be stable because it works with the search engine and doesn't tend to get crushed by updates the way more aggressive techniques do. It leads to creating genuinely helpful resources for people to find online and Google has every incentive to return them in its results.</p> <p>Content created this way tends to rank well because the entire strategy revolves around escaping competition. If there is a lot of competition around a query, it's generally well-answered and you'll find an adequate (though possibly spammy, advertising-stuffed) result within a search or two. The searches that are <em>really</em> frustrating are usually not going to have much competition.</p> <p>Unless your interests are <strong>truly</strong> rare, others will search for what you did and find your page.</p>  <br></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://questinglog.com/my-best-seo-tactic-so-far/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24163658</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 21:44:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Sea of Nodes (2015)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 22 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24163263">thread link</a>) | @ingve
<br/>
August 14, 2020 | https://darksi.de/d.sea-of-nodes/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://darksi.de/d.sea-of-nodes/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://darksi.de/d.sea-of-nodes/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24163263</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 21:05:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Colorize Old Photos with DeOldify]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 55 | Comments 14 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24162561">thread link</a>) | @aliabd
<br/>
August 14, 2020 | https://www.gradio.app/hub/hub-deoldify | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.gradio.app/hub/hub-deoldify">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.gradio.app/hub/hub-deoldify</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24162561</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 20:01:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Using 'this' incorrectly in C#]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 45 | Comments 121 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24158180">thread link</a>) | @jermaustin1
<br/>
August 14, 2020 | https://jeremyaboyd.com/post/you-are-using-this-incorrectly | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jeremyaboyd.com/post/you-are-using-this-incorrectly">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
        <div>
            <div>
                <div>
                    <p>I'm a highly opinionated developer. I've been doing it a little while, and worked with a few other developers, and this is a pet peeve of mine. The <code>this</code> keyword, at least in C#, is oft misused and abused. From henceforth, the context of this post is C# development.</p>
<p>This post seems to have caused a bit of controversy. More to my point, even in base Visual Studio, there are warnings to remove <code>this</code> from your code:
<img src="https://i.imgur.com/9F6Lyx8.png" alt="visual studio 2019"></p>
<p>I've had managers want developers to use <code>this</code> to signify calling a base class's method, which is incorrect. You should be using <code>base</code>.</p>
<pre><code>public class MyClass : YourClass {
    public void MyMethod() {
        if(!base.YourMethod()) return;
    }
}</code></pre>
<p>I've had coworkers who would put <code>this</code> before every method call, because...? When calling your own method, in your own class, that inherits/implements no other classes, why on earth would you decorate your own method call with <code>this</code>?</p>
<p>The only time I have seen prepending <code>this</code> to anything as <em>kind of</em> acceptable, is when you have parameters in a method that are the same as fields/properties on your class, and you need to access those fields/properties inside said method. I am still not a fan of this, but the closest I will get to accepting it is in a constructor where you are passing values that will be stored as <strong>private</strong> fields.</p>
<pre><code>public class SomeClass {
    int maxAmount;
    SomeClass(int maxAmount) =&gt; this.maxAmount = maxAmount;
    ValidateMe(int someValue) =&gt; someValue &lt;= maxAmount;
}</code></pre>
<p>But even in this case, you should really be using Pascal casing as per <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dotnet/standard/design-guidelines/capitalization-conventions">Microsoft's Capitalization Conventions</a>. I know, capitalization conventions change over time, and I could have <strong>sworn</strong> there was a time when camel casing was the recommended approach for fields (specifically private fields), but times they are a changing, and cleaner code will hopefully prevail, especially cleaner code without the misuse/abuse of <code>this</code>.</p>
<p>Maybe I'm the only one this matters for, or maybe I'm just having a bad day and came across <code>this</code> too many times this morning. I do hope you agree though.</p>

                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jeremyaboyd.com/post/you-are-using-this-incorrectly</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24158180</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 14:11:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Unicode in five minutes (2013)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 263 | Comments 31 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24157201">thread link</a>) | @jstanley
<br/>
August 14, 2020 | https://richardjharris.github.io/unicode-in-five-minutes.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://richardjharris.github.io/unicode-in-five-minutes.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <!-- /.post-info -->      <h2>Why</h2>
<p>One encoding covering <em>most</em> of the world’s writing systems. Standard
encoding of the web, most operating systems, Java and .NET.</p>
<p>Before Unicode, each script (or script family) had its own encoding, or
worse, lots of different incompatible encodings. Unicode is a superset
of almost all of them, so can be used for interchange.</p>
<p>It’s been around for <a href="http://www.unicode.org/history/unicode88.pdf">over 30 years</a>.</p>
<p><em>Note: code examples are Perl-centric so far, because it has really good Unicode
support and I know it; if you have examples for other languages, please do post
a comment!</em></p>
<h2>What</h2>
<p><img alt="Unicode character examples" src="https://richardjharris.github.io/static/images/unichar-examples.png"></p>
<p>Unicode defines a <em>code point</em> (number) for every character, such as <span><span data-code="0061" data-name="LATIN SMALL LETTER A" title="LATIN SMALL LETTER A (U+0061)">a</span></span>, <span><span data-code="00E3" data-name="LATIN SMALL LETTER A WITH TILDE" title="LATIN SMALL LETTER A WITH TILDE (U+00E3)">ã</span></span>,
<span><span data-code="06D0" data-name="ARABIC LETTER E" title="ARABIC LETTER E (U+06D0)">ې</span></span>, <span><span data-code="4E0D" data-name="CJK UNIFIED IDEOGRAPH-4E0D" title="CJK UNIFIED IDEOGRAPH-4E0D (U+4E0D)">不</span></span> and <span><span data-code="2603" data-name="SNOWMAN" title="SNOWMAN (U+2603)">☃</span></span>. As of <a href="http://www.unicode.org/versions/Unicode6.2.0/">Unicode 6.2</a> there are <strong>109,976</strong> code points!
<em>(You can mouseover any highlighted character for more information.)</em></p>
<p>It also includes <em>combining characters</em> such as <span><span data-code="0300" data-name="COMBINING GRAVE ACCENT" title="COMBINING GRAVE ACCENT (U+0300)">◌̀</span></span> which can be added to
other characters; this way, Unicode does not need a code point for every possible
combination of letter and accent. On the other hand, Unicode <em>generally</em> doesn’t care
about fonts or stylistic differences: it gives <img alt="a (double-story)" src="https://richardjharris.github.io/static/images/a1.png">
and <img alt="a (single-story)" src="https://richardjharris.github.io/static/images/a2.png"> the same codepoint.</p>
<p>It’s <em>more than just a character set</em>: it also covers standard encodings such
as UTF-8; <nobr>lower/upper/title</nobr> case mapping; collation (sorting); line breaks;
rendering; right-to-left script handling, and more.</p>
<h2>Normalization</h2>
<p>For compatibility with other encodings Unicode sometimes includes <em>precomposed</em>
versions of characters, for example, these three:</p>
<ul>
<li><span><span data-code="00C5" data-name="LATIN CAPITAL LETTER A WITH RING ABOVE" title="LATIN CAPITAL LETTER A WITH RING ABOVE (U+00C5)">Å</span><span> LATIN CAPITAL LETTER A WITH RING ABOVE (U+00C5)</span></span></li>
<li><span><span data-code="212B" data-name="ANGSTROM SIGN" title="ANGSTROM SIGN (U+212B)">Å</span><span> ANGSTROM SIGN (U+212B)</span></span></li>
<li><span><span data-code="0041" data-name="LATIN CAPITAL LETTER A" title="LATIN CAPITAL LETTER A (U+0041)">A</span><span> LATIN CAPITAL LETTER A (U+0041)</span></span> + <span><span data-code="030A" data-name="COMBINING RING ABOVE" title="COMBINING RING ABOVE (U+030A)">◌̊</span><span> COMBINING RING ABOVE (U+030A)</span></span></li>
</ul>
<p>For these to be treated as the same string in equality tests etc. you should
run all input through <a href="http://unicode.org/reports/tr15/">Unicode normalisation</a>. The most common form is
<abbr title="Normalisation Form C (canonical decomposition + canonical composition)">NFC</abbr>, which uses pre<strong>C</strong>omposed characters where possible, and defines a strict ordering
of diacritics if more than one exists. <abbr title="Normalization Form D (canonical decomposition)">NFD</abbr> <strong>D</strong>ecomposes characters where possible.<sup id="fnref:gory"><a href="#fn:gory" rel="footnote">1</a></sup></p>
<p>It doesn’t matter what form you use as long as you are consistent; NFD is
faster in general (fewer codepoints) and <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/6163129/74496">tchrist</a> suggests running input
through NFD and output through NFC.</p>
<p><strong>Compatibility decomposition</strong> also maps characters such as <span><span data-code="FB03" data-name="LATIN SMALL LIGATURE FFI" title="LATIN SMALL LIGATURE FFI (U+FB03)">ﬃ</span></span>, <span><span data-code="2168" data-name="ROMAN NUMERAL NINE" title="ROMAN NUMERAL NINE (U+2168)">Ⅸ</span></span>
and even <span><span data-code="2075" data-name="SUPERSCRIPT FIVE" title="SUPERSCRIPT FIVE (U+2075)">⁵</span></span> to ‘ffi’, ‘IX’ and ‘5’ respectively. This <abbr title="Normalization Form KC (compatibility decomposition + canonical composition)">NFKC</abbr> normalisation
helps when searching for text.</p>
<div><pre><span>#!/usr/bin/perl</span>
<span>use</span> <span>Unicode::</span><span>Normalize</span><span>;</span>
<span>my</span> <span>$norm</span> <span>=</span> <span>NFD</span><span>(</span><span>$str</span><span>);</span>
</pre></div>


<hr>
<div><pre><span>#!/usr/bin/python</span>
<span>import</span> <span>unicodedata</span>
<span>norm</span> <span>=</span> <span>unicodedata</span><span>.</span><span>normalize</span><span>(</span><span>'NFC'</span><span>,</span> <span>string</span><span>)</span>
</pre></div>


<hr>
<div><pre><span>#!/usr/bin/ruby</span>
<span># gem install unicode_utils</span>
<span>require</span> <span>"unicode_utils/nfc"</span>
<span>norm</span> <span>=</span> <span>UnicodeUtils</span><span>.</span><span>nfc</span><span>(</span><span>string</span><span>)</span>
</pre></div>


<h2>Casefolding</h2>
<p>Casing is not so simple in the Unicode world:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Some strings actually change length when they change case: <span><span data-code="00DF" data-name="LATIN SMALL LETTER SHARP S" title="LATIN SMALL LETTER SHARP S (U+00DF)">ß</span></span> uppercases
  to ‘SS’.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><span><span data-code="017F" data-name="LATIN SMALL LETTER LONG S" title="LATIN SMALL LETTER LONG S (U+017F)">ſ</span><span> LATIN SMALL LETTER LONG S</span></span> should be seen as equal to ‘s’ and ‘S’ in case-insensitive comparisons.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><span><span data-code="03A3" data-name="GREEK CAPITAL LETTER SIGMA" title="GREEK CAPITAL LETTER SIGMA (U+03A3)">Σ</span><span> GREEK CAPITAL LETTER SIGMA</span></span> has <em>two</em> lowercase forms: <span><span data-code="03C3" data-name="GREEK SMALL LETTER SIGMA" title="GREEK SMALL LETTER SIGMA (U+03C3)">σ</span></span> at the beginning or middle of the
  word, and <span><span data-code="03C2" data-name="GREEK SMALL LETTER FINAL SIGMA" title="GREEK SMALL LETTER FINAL SIGMA (U+03C2)">ς</span></span> at the end of a word.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Casing is <em>mostly</em> consistent across locales, but Turkish is an exception: it
  has both a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dotted_and_dotless_I">Dotted and dotless I</a>, in both lower and upper cases.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>To ensure your code handles these cases, and any new ones, Unicode provides a
<em>one-way</em> ‘casefold’ operation that allows case-insensitive comparison:</p>
<div><pre><span>#!/usr/bin/perl</span>
<span>use</span> <span>Unicode::</span><span>CaseFold</span><span>;</span>   <span># or: use v5.16;</span>
<span>sort</span> <span>{</span> <span>fc</span><span>(</span><span>$a</span><span>)</span> <span>cmp</span> <span>fc</span><span>(</span><span>$b</span><span>)</span> <span>}</span> <span>@stuff</span><span>;</span>
</pre></div>


<p>Casefolding does <em>not</em> include normalization, so do that too.</p>
<h2>Sorting</h2>
<p>Sorting (or <em>collation</em>) is <strong>locale specific</strong> and just as riddled with
pecularities as casing:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>German and Swedish both have ä and ö but sort them differently - German
    treats them as variants of the same letters without umlauts (i.e. ‘a<strong>ä</strong>bcdefghijklmno<strong>ö</strong>pqrstuvwxyz’)
    whereas Swedish considers them new letters, and puts them at the end (‘abcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz<strong>äö</strong>‘)</p>
<p>It’s important that things are sorted in the order the user expects.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Sorting varies by application too; phonebooks are often sorted differently to book
    indices, for example.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>For Chinese characters and other ideographs, there are many possible orders, e.g.
    pinyin (phonetic), by stroke count, etc.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Collations can be <em>tailored</em> based on user preferences, e.g. lower or upper-case first?</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>It’s not enough to just sort by binary comparison. And codepoints aren’t generally in any
sensible order either. Fortunately Unicode specifies a <a href="http://www.unicode.org/reports/tr10/">Collation Algorithm</a>
that is immensely customisable, covers all the edge-cases, and does clever things to make
it reasonably fast. Here’s an example:<sup id="fnref:locale"><a href="#fn:locale" rel="footnote">2</a></sup></p>
<div><pre><span>#!/usr/bin/perl</span>
<span>use</span> <span>Unicode::Collate::</span><span>Locale</span><span>;</span>
<span>my</span> <span>$collator</span> <span>=</span> <span>Unicode::Collate::</span><span>Locale</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>new</span><span>(</span><span>locale</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>'DE'</span><span>);</span>
<span>my</span> <span>@sorted</span> <span>=</span> <span>$collator</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>sort</span><span>(</span><span>@array</span><span>);</span>
<span>$collator</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>cmp</span><span>(</span><span>$word</span><span>,</span> <span>$another_word</span><span>);</span>  <span># -&gt; -1, 0 or 1</span>
</pre></div>


<p>The <abbr title="Unicode Collation Algorithm">UCA</abbr> can do other clever things, such as sort ‘10’ after ‘2’ numerically, or sort
the character ‘?’ as if it was the string ‘question mark’.</p>
<h2>Encodings</h2>
<p>The big ones are <code>UTF-8</code>, <code>UTF-16</code> and <code>UTF-32</code>. Each one guarantees a reversible
mapping of almost every codepoint<sup id="fnref:every"><a href="#fn:every" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> to a byte sequence.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>UTF-32</strong> is dead simple: each codepoint gets four bytes. Takes up tons of space,
  not recommended for interchange.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>UTF-8</strong> is very common the web. It’s byte-oriented (no endianness issues),
  handles corruption well, is ASCII-compatible and takes up minimal space for text
  that is mostly ASCII (e.g. HTML).</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Code points between U+0800 and U+FFFF, which includes commonly used <abbr title="Chinese, Japanese, Korean and Vietnamese">CJKV</abbr>
  characters, will take up 3 bytes instead of 2. So UTF-16 may be more space
  efficient.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>ASCII-compatibility is helpful to allow UTF-8 to stealth its way through
  scripts and processes that are not Unicode-aware. But if such a system tries to
  do anything with the data (casing, sub-strings, regex), that data may be
  corrupted.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>UTF-16</strong> is used by Java, .NET and Windows. It uses 2 bytes (16-bit) to
  represent the most common 63K codepoints, and 4 bytes for the less common 1M
  codepoints (using two ‘surrogate’ codepoints).</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Contrary to popular belief, UTF-16 is not a fixed-width encoding. But as
  long as it contains no surrogates, it can be treated as one, which can speed
  up string operations.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>UTF-16 streams typically begin with <span><span data-code="FEFF" data-name="ZERO WIDTH NO-BREAK SPACE" title="ZERO WIDTH NO-BREAK SPACE (U+FEFF)">U+FEFF</span></span><sup id="fnref:bomnote"><a href="#fn:bomnote" rel="footnote">4</a></sup> to detect the endianness
  (byte order) of the stream. Otherwise, you can explicitly encode or decode
  via ‘UTF-16BE’ or ‘UTF-16LE’ to specify the endianness.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2>Unicode and internationalised domain names</h2>
<p>International characters create a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IDN_homograph_attack">big problem</a>
for domain names. Just as <span><span data-code="0049" data-name="LATIN CAPITAL LETTER I" title="LATIN CAPITAL LETTER I (U+0049)">I</span></span> and <span><span data-code="006C" data-name="LATIN SMALL LETTER L" title="LATIN SMALL LETTER L (U+006C)">l</span></span> look similar, Unicode multiplies that problem
by 1,000, in addition to adding numerous invisible control characters, spacing characters
and right-to-left text.</p>
<p>Browsers and registrars have implemented several measures against this:</p>
<ul>
<li>Many TLDs restrict which characters can be used in domain names.</li>
<li>Browsers may display the domain in Punycode (see below) if the domain includes characters
  from multiple scripts and/or characters not belonging to one of the user’s preferred languages.</li>
<li>Internationalised country codes such as .рф (Russia) only accept Cyrillic names.</li>
</ul>
<h3>nameprep/stringprep</h3>
<p><a href="http://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc3491">RFC 3491</a> defines <em>nameprep</em>, a mechanism
to case-fold, normalize and sanitize strings before they can be used in domain names. This
removes many invisible characters and throws an error if prohibited code points are in use.</p>
<p>It is implemented in terms of a wider framework called <em>stringprep</em>. In Perl, one can use
<a href="https://metacpan.org/module/Net::IDN::Encode">Net::IDN::Encode</a> which will also perform Punycode conversion.</p>
<h3>Punycode</h3>
<p>For legacy reasons DNS does not allow extended characters outside of ASCII, so Punycode
is an ASCII-compatible encoding scheme. For example, <code>café.com</code> becomes <code>xn--caf-dma.com</code>.
All Punycode-encoded domain components are instantly recognisable by their <code>xn--</code> prefix.</p>
<p>This goes for TLDs too: .中国 is really known as <em>xn—fiqs8s</em>.</p>
<h2>The problem of ‘user characters’</h2>
<p>In Perl at least, everything (<code>substr</code>, <code>length</code>, <code>index</code>, <code>reverse</code>…) works on the level
of codepoints. This is often not what you want, because what a user considers to be a
character such as ў is actually two codepoints (<span><span data-code="0079" data-name="LATIN SMALL LETTER Y" title="LATIN SMALL LETTER Y (U+0079)">y</span></span> + <span><span data-code="0306" data-name="COMBINING BREVE" title="COMBINING BREVE (U+0306)">◌̆</span></span>). Here’s a <a href="http://www.nntp.perl.org/group/perl.perl5.porters/2011/10/msg178687.html">really good
usenet post</a> on the subject.</p>
<p>Even seemingly innocuous things like <code>printf "%-10s", $str</code> breaks completely for combining characters,
double-width characters (e.g. Chinese/Japanese) or zero-width characters.</p>
<p>Fortunately Perl provides the <code>\X</code> regular expression metachar which matches exactly one
‘extended grapheme cluster’, i.e. what a user would consider a character to be. A more robust
solution is to install <a href="https://metacpan.org/module/Unicode::GCString">Unicode::GCString</a>:</p>
<div><pre><span>#!/usr/bin/perl</span>
<span>use</span> <span>Unicode::</span><span>GCString</span><span>;</span>
<span>use</span> <span>Unicode::</span><span>Normalize</span><span>;</span>
<span>use</span> <span>utf8</span><span>;</span>
<span>use</span> <span>open</span> <span>qw(:std :encoding(UTF-8))</span><span>;</span>

<span>my</span> <span>$s</span> <span>=</span> <span>NFD</span><span>(</span><span>"crème brûlée"</span><span>);</span>  <span># ensure combining marks get their own codepoint</span>
<span>my</span> <span>$g</span> <span>=</span> <span>Unicode::</span><span>GCString</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>new</span><span>(</span><span>$s</span><span>);</span>

<span>print</span> <span>$g</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>length</span><span>,</span> <span>"\n"</span><span>;</span>       <span># 12, not 15</span>
<span>print</span> <span>reverse</span><span>(</span><span>@$g</span><span>),</span> <span>"\n"</span><span>;</span>     <span># 'eélûrb emèrc', not 'éel̂urb em̀erc'</span>
<span>print</span> <span>$g</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>substr</span><span>(</span><span>0</span><span>,</span><span>5</span><span>),</span> <span>"\n"</span><span>;</span>  <span># 'crème', not 'crèm'</span>
<span>print</span> <span>$g</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>substr</span><span>(</span><span>0</span><span>,</span><span>3</span><span>),</span> <span>"\n"</span><span>;</span>  <span># 'crè', not 'cre'</span>

<span>print</span> <span>"1234512345123451234512345|\n"</span><span>;</span>
<span>printf</span> <span>"%s%*s|\n"</span><span>,</span> <span>$g</span><span>,</span> <span>(</span><span>25</span> <span>-</span> <span>$g</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>columns</span><span>),</span> <span>''</span><span>;</span>  <span># 25 columns long (ᵔᴥᵔ)</span>

<span>printf</span> <span>"%-25s|\n"</span><span>,</span> <span>$s</span><span>;</span>                          <span># 22 columns long (╯°□°）╯︵ ┻━┻</span>
</pre></div>


<h3>Line breaks</h3>
<p>Line breaking (or word wrapping) is another thing that becomes <a href="http://www.unicode.org/reports/tr14/">insanely complicated</a>
once Unicode is involved. You have to account for various non-breaking and breaking control
and spacing characters, punctuation in every language (e.g. <span><span data-code="00AB" data-name="LEFT-POINTING DOUBLE ANGLE QUOTATION MARK" title="LEFT-POINTING DOUBLE ANGLE QUOTATION MARK (U+00AB)">«</span></span> and <span><span data-code="00BB" data-name="RIGHT-POINTING DOUBLE ANGLE QUOTATION MARK" title="RIGHT-POINTING DOUBLE ANGLE QUOTATION MARK (U+00BB)">»</span></span> quotes, or the
full stop or comma being used in numerics such as <code>2,140</code>) and the width of each character.</p>
<p>In Perl, this has all been handled for you - just use <a href="https://metacpan.org/module/Unicode::LineBreak">Unicode::LineBreak</a>.</p>
<h2>Regular expressions</h2>
<p>Some useful Perl regular expression syntax:</p>
<dl>
<dt><code>\R</code></dt>
<dd>Match any Unicode linebreak sequence (including <code>\n</code>, <code>\r\n</code> and six others)</dd>
<dt><code>\p</code>, <code>\P</code></dt>
<dd>Match any codepoint possessing (or not possessing) a Unicode property.</dd>
<dd>Common ones are <code>\pL</code> (Letter), <code>\pU</code> (Uppercase), <code>\pS</code> (Symbol), or even <code>\p{script=Latin}</code>,
<code>\p{East_Asian_Width=Wide}</code>, <code>\p{Numeric_Value=4}</code>.</dd>
<dd>See <a href="http://perldoc.perl.org/perluniprops.html">perluniprops</a> for a big list.</dd>
<dd>Built-in character classes such as <code>\w</code>, <code>\b</code>, <code>\s</code> and <code>\d</code> are Unicode-aware since Perl
5.6 (though you need to make sure your string or pattern has the <code>UTF8</code> flag on!) Disable this
with the <code>/a</code> flag (see <a href="http://perldoc.perl.org/perlre.html#Character-set-modifiers">perlre</a>).</dd>
<dt><code>\X</code></dt>
<dd>Match an extended grapheme cluster, which is basically …</dd></dl></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://richardjharris.github.io/unicode-in-five-minutes.html">https://richardjharris.github.io/unicode-in-five-minutes.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://richardjharris.github.io/unicode-in-five-minutes.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24157201</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 12:51:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[JavaScript Code Plays Google Dinosaur/T-Rex Game Automatically]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 25 | Comments 17 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24156685">thread link</a>) | @truly_furqan
<br/>
August 14, 2020 | https://www.edopedia.com/blog/javascript-code-plays-google-dinosaur-t-rex-game-automatically/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.edopedia.com/blog/javascript-code-plays-google-dinosaur-t-rex-game-automatically/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.edopedia.com/blog/javascript-code-plays-google-dinosaur-t-rex-game-automatically/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24156685</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 11:53:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Precise Higher-Order Meshing of Curved 2D Domains]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 27 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24156522">thread link</a>) | @wowsig
<br/>
August 14, 2020 | http://graphics.cs.uos.de/bezierguarding.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://graphics.cs.uos.de/bezierguarding.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://graphics.cs.uos.de/bezierguarding.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24156522</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 11:26:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Redefining what sustainable fishing means]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 150 | Comments 109 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24156319">thread link</a>) | @dnetesn
<br/>
August 14, 2020 | http://oceans.nautil.us/article/600/its-time-to-redefine-what-sustainable-fishing-means | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://oceans.nautil.us/article/600/its-time-to-redefine-what-sustainable-fishing-means">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
        <p><span>S</span>arah Dolman heard the porpoiseâ€™s cries not in the waters where the animalâ€™s voice was actually recorded, but on the sound system at a marine mammal conference held in late 2019. To Dolman, policy manager at the nonprofit UK-based conservation organization <a href="https://uk.whales.org/" target="_blank">Whale and Dolphin Conservation,</a> time and distance made the experience no less painful.</p>

<p>The porpoise was using its voice—which sounds alternately like a buzzing insect, a creaky door blowing open then clicking shut, and a high-frequency whistle that humans cannot hear without the aid of sound-amplifying technologies—to call to another porpoise who was caught in a fishing net. The entangled porpoise struggled to surface while trying to break free. That proved impossible, and the porpoise drowned. But the dead creatureâ€™s companion stayed nearby for hours, speaking in protracted clicks, buzzes and whistles—in mourning or perhaps confusion, alarmed by the sudden death of its friend.</p>
<p>Globally, fishing gear kills <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/B9780123735539000444" target="_blank">at least 300,000 marine mammals</a> every year, and leaves many more individuals with scars both physical and psychological. Some governments, including those of the U.S. and E.U., may temporarily close fisheries or regulate gear after a specified number of marine mammals are killed, but those measures are limited. At a moment when the cruel captivity of several dozen orcas inspires public outrage and aquarium boycotts and new laws, the global fishing industry and its regulators generally accept the widespread killing and maiming of marine mammals as a part of doing business. And so we unwittingly continue to eat fish, in huge amounts, and marine mammals continue to suffer.</p>
<p>Dolman says present approaches, which focus on maintaining specific populations above a minimum size, still allow too much killing and preventable suffering. She says itâ€™s time for fisheries policies to consider the welfare of individual whales and dolphins and other marine mammals. â€œBeing caught in fishing gear is a horrible way to die,â€� says Dolman. â€œHow would the public feel about this when theyâ€™re eating fish and seafood, if they knew about these animalsâ€™ suffering? We need another solution.â€�</p>
<p>Dolman and her colleague Philippa Brakes, a research fellow at Whale and Dolphin Conservation, outlined their approach for regulating â€œbycatch,â€� as unintentionally caught animals are called, and preventing entanglement in fishing gear in a <a href="https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fvets.2018.00287/full" target="_blank">2018 paper</a> published in the journal <em>Frontiers in Veterinary Science</em>. They say that fisheries policies must account for the well-being of individuals, not just populations, ideally with zero tolerance for marine mammal bycatch.</p>
<p>They also argue for updating the definition of â€œsustainableâ€� fisheries, now set according to whether the exploitation of a given fish population can be continued without jeopardizing it, to include marine mammals killed as bycatch. In their paper, Dolman and Brakes point out that â€œbuying â€˜sustainableâ€™ fish or indeed some fish products labeled â€˜dolphin-friendlyâ€™ provide no guarantees that incidental bycatch of protected species does not occur alongside the targeted catch.â€�&nbsp; And not only should sustainability encompass mortality, but also the suffering of survivors—something thatâ€™s a bit more challenging to measure, though scientists acknowledge that itâ€™s real, and goes beyond the pain of scars and severed limbs caused by the constricting ropes of the gear they carry.</p><figure><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/nautilus-vertical/oceans_911411818e26b80488c996ad7cfe7d4d.jpg" alt="nautilus whale calf"><figcaption><span>A humpback whale mother swims with her newborn calf in their traditional breeding waters in the Hawaiian Islands Humpback Whale National Marine Sanctuary. </span><br><span>Credit: NOAA News</span></figcaption></figure><p>Even if we are quite far from fully understanding the experiences of animals who spend their lives primarily underwater, <a href="https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-030-31011-0_10" target="_blank">research clearly reveals</a> that harbor porpoises like the one whose cries haunted Dolman and other marine mammals are, like us, highly intelligent and social creatures. Ecologist and author <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2015/08/04/science/review-beyond-words-carl-safina.html" target="_blank">Carl Safina</a>, who has written extensively about the inner lives of nonhuman animals including orcas and sperm whales, says the loss of even one individual whale—particularly if she happens to be an adult female—can be catastrophic for others.<br></p>
<p>â€œSperm whales stay together their entire lives, very intentionally living together in a family the way elephants live together in a family,â€� says Safina. â€œIf you lose even one member of that female support group, you increase the risks and hazards to the young ones.â€�&nbsp;</p>
<p>Like baby humans, young marine mammals depend on their eldersâ€™ vigilance and protection, as well as their practical knowledge and cultural wisdom, for survival. Older animals in a family bestow younger members with all sorts of knowhow, such as what to eat and how to hunt for food. Scientists have discovered that <a href="https://science.sciencemag.org/content/337/6100/1313" target="_blank">orca grandmothers</a> play an outsized role in the lives of young orcas, boosting youngstersâ€™ chances of survival. Even for less family-oriented marine mammal species, like humpback whales, notes Safina, â€œthe death of a mother—or severe distress of a mother due to entanglement in fishing gear—can be, depending on age of a young one, completely devastating or very stressful.â€�
</p>
<p>Research like this â€œopens a rich seam of understanding,â€� Brakes says. â€œSuch understanding shows us that we can no longer treat marine mammals like a homogenous group or numbers on a spreadsheet.â€� She and Dolman propose a multi-pronged strategy of implementing fisheries closures and new fishing practices, as well as requiring new gear that minimizes bycatch and entanglements. Fisheries regulation would need to include enhanced monitoring and reporting systems that keep track of every harmed marine mammal. Right now basic data about bycatch and entanglements, much less the long-term physiological and psychological affects, are not being collected.</p>
<blockquote>â€œWe can no longer treat marine mammals like a homogenous group or numbers on a spreadsheet.â€�</blockquote>
<p>According to Dolman, the Marine Stewardship Council (MSC), a key independent labeler of sustainable seafood, has received much criticism in recent years about its inadequate consideration of bycatch. â€œMSC bycatch standards are under review at the moment,â€� Dolman said. â€œThis is something thatâ€™s long overdue. But, I have to say, Iâ€™m not feeling very positive about whatâ€™s coming. The fishing industry is very vocal and oppositional to regulatory change. Consumers and scientists must begin pushing for laws and certification schemes to seriously incorporate welfare into the â€˜sustainableâ€™ label. Most of the public feels comfortable when they see a dolphin-safe label—though really, right now, they shouldnâ€™t.â€�<strong>
</strong></p>
<p>Adding to marine mammalsâ€™ collective challenges is the fact that fishing isnâ€™t their only threat. In addition to depleting populations of the fish they eat, humans have made the oceans a much noisier place, with engine noise and seismic surveys and naval tests causing both chronic stress and acute damage. We push ship traffic into ever-more remote areas once only known to marine animals; disrupt marine life by developing coastlines and dredging channels; pollute with plastic and toxic chemicals; and cause ocean-warming climate change.
</p>
<p>These are not matters to frame purely in terms of populations and environments, but the lived experiences of animals who share many intellectual properties with us. â€œPeople need to understand that other living things can suffer and that these individuals donâ€™t want to suffer. They want to exist in a state of wellbeing. Thatâ€™s what they strive to do,â€� says Safina. â€œI think the big first step is for people to understand and talk about that and drive away from things that cause suffering.â€�</p>

<ul><li> is a writer, artist and wildlife rehabilitator who explores the intersection of the human and nonhuman worlds. She is currently writing a book about plastic pollution around the world and is a junior fellow at the not-for-profit conservation organization The Safina Center, with which Carl Safina is affiliated. See more of her work at <a href="https://www.ericacirino.com/">www.ericacirino.com</a>. </li></ul>
<p>Lead image:&nbsp;A male right whale entangled in heavy fishing rope off the coast of Florida. Biologists were able to remove the rope. Credit: Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, taken under NOAA research permit #15488.</p>





            </article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://oceans.nautil.us/article/600/its-time-to-redefine-what-sustainable-fishing-means</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24156319</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 10:54:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Duality of Vector Spaces (2017)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 31 | Comments 9 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24156082">thread link</a>) | @hosolmaz
<br/>
August 14, 2020 | https://solmaz.io/notes/duality-vector-spaces/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://solmaz.io/notes/duality-vector-spaces/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>



<p>When I was learning about Continuum Mechanics for the first time, the <em>covariance
and contravariance of vectors</em> confused the hell out of me. The concepts gain
meaning in the context of Riemannian Geometry, but it was surprising to find
that one doesn’t need to learn an entire subject to grasp the logic behind
co-/contravariance. An intermediate knowledge of linear algebra is enough—that
is, one has to be acquainted with the concept of vector spaces and one-forms.</p>
<p>The duality of co-/contravariance arises when one has to define vectors in terms
of a non-orthonormal basis. The reason such terminology doesn’t show up
in engineering education is that Cartesian coordinates are enough for most
engineering problems. But every now and then, a complex problem with funky
geometrical requirements show up, like one that requires measuring distances and
areas on non-flat surfaces. Then you end up with dual vector spaces. I’ll try to
give the basics of duality below.</p>
<p><strong>Definition:</strong> Let $\CV$ be a finite-dimensional real vector space.
The space $\CV^\ast = \CL(\CV,\IR)$,
defined as the
the space of all one-forms $\Balpha:\CV\to\IR$, is called the
<strong>dual space</strong> to $\CV$.</p>
<p>Let $B=\cbr{\Be_1,\dots,\Be_n}$ be a basis of $\CV$. Any vector $\Bv\in\CV$ can be written
in terms of $B$ as</p>

<p>with the components $a_1,\dots,a_n\in\IR$.
For any $i=1,\dots,n$, we can define the $i$-th component $a_i$ by a one-form as</p>

<p>These elements are linear and thus are in the space
$\CL(\CV,\IR)$<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup>.
Given any basis $B=\setveci{\Be}$, we call $B^\ast = \setveciup{\Be}$
the basis of $\CV^\ast$ <strong>dual</strong> to $B$.
The fact that $B^\ast$ really is a basis of $\CV^\ast$ can be proved
by showing that $\Be^i$ are linearly independent.
Then $\Bv$ has the following
representation</p>

<p>Instead of $a_i$, it is practical to denote the components of $\Bv$ as $v^i$,
lightface of the same symbol with a raised index corresponding to
the raised index of the dual basis:</p>

<p>In fact, this convention is more compatible with
the symmetry caused by the duality.
This point will be more clear after the introduction of
dual basis representation of one-forms.</p>
<p><strong>Proposition:</strong> Each $\Be^i \in \CL(\CV,\IR)$ can be identified by its action on the basis
$B$:</p>

<p><strong>Proof:</strong> For any $\Bv\in\CV$, $\Be^i(\Bv)$ must give $v^i$, the
$i$-th component of $\Bv$.
Setting $\Bv = \Be_j$, one sees that
$\Be^i(\Bv)=v^i = 1$ when $i=j$, and is zero otherwise.</p>
<p>Geometrically, \eqref{eq:dualbasis2} implies that a basis vector is
perpendicular to all the dual basis vectors, except its own dual.</p>
<h2 id="dual-basis-representation-of-one-forms">Dual Basis Representation of One-Forms</h2>
<p>Let $\Balpha$ be a one form in $\CV^\ast$ with the corresponding
dual basis $\setveciup{\Be}$. Then similar to a vector,
$\Balpha$ has the following representation</p>

<p>where the <strong>components of the one-form</strong> $\Balpha$
are defined as</p>

<p><strong>Proof:</strong> We substitute \eqref{eq:vectorrep2} and obtain</p>

<p>using $\Balpha$’s linearity.</p>
<p><strong>Notation:</strong>
Let $\CV$ be a finite-dimensional real vector space.
For $\Bv\in\CV$ and $\Balpha\in\CV^\ast$</p>

<p>denotes the action of $\Balpha$ on $\Bv$, and is called
a <strong>natural pairing</strong> or <strong>dual pairing</strong>
between a vector space and its dual.
<em>It is of the essence to understand that $\abrn{\cdot,\cdot}$ does not
denote an inner product in $\CV$</em>; that is,
$\abr{\Bv,\Balpha}$ means $\Balpha(\Bv)$.</p>
<p>With this notation, \eqref{eq:vectorrep2} can be written as</p>

<p>and \eqref{eq:dualbasis2} as</p>

<p>Using the convention that $\Be_i$ are column vectors and
$\Be^i$ are row vectors,
\eqref{eq:dualbasis1} can be rearranged in the following manner</p>

<p>which can be used to compute a dual basis.</p>
<p><strong>Example:</strong> Given a two-dimensional vector space $\CV$ with a basis
$\Be_1=[2,-0.5]\tra$, $\Be_2=[1,1]\tra$, we use
\eqref{eq:computedualbasis1} to compute</p>

<p>and obtain the dual basis vectors as
$\Be^1=[0.4,-0.4]$ and $\Be^2=[0.2,0.8]$.
The result is given in the
following figure,</p>
<figure>
<p><img src="https://solmaz.io/img/duality_vector_spaces/fig2.svg"></p>
</figure>
<p>where one can see that $\Be_1\perp\Be^2$, $\Be^1\perp\Be_2$.</p>
<figure>
<p><img src="https://solmaz.io/img/duality_vector_spaces/fig1.svg">
A body $\CB$ embedded in $\IR^2$ with curvilinear coordinates.
Every point $\CP$ at $\BX$ has an associated two-dimensional vector space,
called $\CB$’s tangent space at $\BX$, denoted $\tang_\BX\CB$. The basis
$\Be_i$ corresponding to coordinates $\theta_i$ are not necessarily
orthogonal and can admit corresponding duals $\Be^i$, due to
curvilinearity.
The coordinates appear to be affine at the point’s immediate vicinity,
and thus in the tangent space.</p>
</figure>
<p>The introduction of the dual space
allows us to reinterpret a one-form $\Balpha$
as an object residing in the dual space. In fact,
the <strong>canonical duality</strong> $\CV^{\ast\ast}=\CV$
states that every vector $\Bv$ can be interpreted as a functional
on the space $\CV^\ast$ via</p>


</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://solmaz.io/notes/duality-vector-spaces/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24156082</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 10:22:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Implementing a Type-safe printf in Rust]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 116 | Comments 57 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24154263">thread link</a>) | @lukastyrychtr
<br/>
August 13, 2020 | https://willcrichton.net/notes/type-safe-printf/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://willcrichton.net/notes/type-safe-printf/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  
  
  <p>
    
    Will Crichton
    
    &nbsp; — &nbsp;
    June 21, 2020
  </p>
  <p>I show how to use heterogeneous lists and traits to implement a type-safe printf in Rust. These mechanisms can ensure that two variadic argument lists share important properties, like the number of format string holes matches the number of printf arguments.</p>
  <p><em>Part of an ongoing series about type-level programming in Rust. Consider reading <a href="http://willcrichton.net/notes/type-level-programming/">part one</a> first! All code in this note can be found in <a href="https://gist.github.com/willcrichton/e7fcf1b0e84b4be7f172f0e0245cf149">this gist</a>.</em></p>

<p>Rust has a great printf function, <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/macro.println.html"><code>println!</code></a>. It has a rich formatting language, but also catches mistakes at compile-time. For example, <code>println!</code> will check that the number of arguments matches the number of holes in the format string:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>error: 2 positional arguments in format string, but there is 1 argument
  --&gt; src/printf.rs:36:13
   |
36 |   println!("{} {}", "Hello");
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>How does the Rust compiler make this check? Because both the format string and the argument are within the macro, Rust will check that the number of holes matches the number of arguments. Consequently, format strings <em>have</em> to be within the macro. If we write:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>let</span> <span>s</span> <span>=</span> <span>"{} {}"</span><span>;</span>
<span>println!</span><span>(</span><span>s</span><span>,</span> <span>"hi"</span><span>)</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This code fails to compile with the error:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>error: format argument must be a string literal
  --&gt; src/printf.rs:42:12
   |
42 |   println!(s, "hi");
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>I’ll show you how to implement type-safe printf without using procedural macros. More generally, this note contains a Rust recipe for functions where:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Arguments are variadic</li>
  <li>Each argument can be a different type (<code>Vec&lt;T&gt;</code> not allowed)</li>
  <li>Multiple variadic inputs share a parallel property, e.g. the number of arguments should match the number of format holes</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="core-mechanism-hlist">Core mechanism: HList</h2>

<p>First, we need to understand the main type-level mechanism: a heterogeneous list (or H-list). An H-list is a sequence of values of potentially different types. For example, <code>[1, "a", true]</code> is an H-list, but not a valid Rust vector. H-lists are implemented in Rust using a linked-list style:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>struct</span> <span>HNil</span><span>;</span>
<span>struct</span> <span>HCons</span><span>&lt;</span><span>Head</span><span>,</span> <span>Tail</span><span>&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>head</span><span>:</span> <span>Head</span><span>,</span>
  <span>tail</span><span>:</span> <span>Tail</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>let</span> <span>example</span><span>:</span> <span>HCons</span><span>&lt;</span><span>i32</span><span>,</span> <span>HCons</span><span>&lt;</span><span>bool</span><span>,</span> <span>HNil</span><span>&gt;&gt;</span> <span>=</span>
  <span>HCons</span><span>{</span><span>head</span><span>:</span> <span>1</span><span>,</span> <span>tail</span><span>:</span> <span>HCons</span><span>{</span><span>head</span><span>:</span> <span>true</span><span>,</span> <span>tail</span><span>:</span> <span>HNil</span><span>}};</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The key idea is that the type of an H-list changes every time you make a change to it. By contrast, if you push to a <code>Vec&lt;T&gt;</code>, the type of the vector stays the same.</p>

<p>Just like Rust has <code>vec![]</code>, we can use the <a href="https://github.com/lloydmeta/frunk#hlist">frunk</a> crate to get an <code>hlist!</code> macro.</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>let</span> <span>example</span> <span>=</span> <span>hlist!</span><span>[</span><span>1</span><span>,</span> <span>true</span><span>];</span> <span>// same as above</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="setting-up-printf">Setting up printf</h2>

<p>Let’s go back to the ingredients of printf. We need a format string and an argument list. The key idea is to represent both with an H-list, and carefully use Rust’s traits to ensure our desired property: the number of arguments should match the number of holes.</p>

<p>First, to represent format strings, we will have a sequence of structs that represent each part of the string.</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>pub</span> <span>struct</span> <span>FString</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>'static</span> <span>str</span><span>);</span>
<span>pub</span> <span>struct</span> <span>FVar</span><span>;</span>

<span>// Assume that we compile "Hello {}! The first prime is {}" into this code.</span>
<span>// That would be a simple syntactic transformation.</span>
<span>let</span> <span>example</span> <span>=</span> <span>hlist!</span><span>[</span>
  <span>FString</span><span>(</span><span>"Hello "</span><span>),</span> <span>FVar</span><span>,</span> <span>FString</span><span>(</span><span>"! The first prime is "</span><span>),</span> <span>FVar</span>
<span>];</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>To represent arguments, we will use a matching H-list of values. For example:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>let</span> <span>args</span> <span>=</span> <span>hlist!</span><span>[</span><span>"world"</span><span>,</span> <span>2</span><span>];</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Then, our goal is to create a function <code>format</code> such that this is true:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>assert_eq!</span><span>(</span>
  <span>example</span><span>.format</span><span>(</span><span>args</span><span>),</span>
  <span>"Hello world! The first prime is 2"</span>
<span>);</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And this should be a compile-time (NOT run-time) error:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>example</span><span>.format</span><span>(</span><span>hlist!</span><span>[</span><span>"Only one arg"</span><span>]);</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="the-format-trait">The Format trait</h2>

<p>In the spirit of type-level computation, we start by defining a trait.</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>trait</span> <span>Format</span><span>&lt;</span><span>ArgList</span><span>&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>fn</span> <span>format</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>self</span><span>,</span> <span>args</span><span>:</span> <span>ArgList</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>String</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Here, <code>self</code> is the H-list of the format directives, and <code>ArgList</code> is the H-list of the variadic arguments. <code>Format</code> need to take <code>ArgList</code> as a type parameter, because its type will change as we remove elements from the <code>ArgList</code> list.</p>

<p>Now, we proceed to implement the <code>Format</code> trait by cases. First, the base case for reaching the end of the format list <code>HNil</code>:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>impl</span> <span>Format</span><span>&lt;</span><span>HNil</span><span>&gt;</span> <span>for</span> <span>HNil</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>fn</span> <span>format</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>self</span><span>,</span> <span>_</span><span>args</span><span>:</span> <span>HNil</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>String</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>""</span><span>.to_string</span><span>()</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This impl says that when we reach the end of a format list, just return the empty string. And the only argument we will accept is an empty argument list. Combined with the next impls, this inductively ensures that extra arguments are not accepted.</p>

<p>Next, we will implement <code>FString</code>. This implementation should use the string constant contained in the <code>FString</code> struct, and combine it recursively with the rest of the format list. We don’t use variadic arguments for <code>FString</code>, so they get passed along. In Rust, this English specification becomes:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>impl</span><span>&lt;</span><span>ArgList</span><span>,</span> <span>FmtList</span><span>&gt;</span> <span>Format</span><span>&lt;</span><span>ArgList</span><span>&gt;</span>
<span>for</span> <span>HCons</span><span>&lt;</span><span>FString</span><span>,</span> <span>FmtList</span><span>&gt;</span>
<span>where</span> <span>FmtList</span><span>:</span> <span>Format</span><span>&lt;</span><span>ArgList</span><span>&gt;</span>
<span>{</span>
  <span>fn</span> <span>format</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>self</span><span>,</span> <span>args</span><span>:</span> <span>ArgList</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>String</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>self</span><span>.head</span><span>.</span><span>0</span><span>.to_owned</span><span>()</span> <span>+</span> <span>&amp;</span><span>self</span><span>.tail</span><span>.format</span><span>(</span><span>args</span><span>)</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Note that we have to add <code>FmtList: Format&lt;ArgList&gt;</code> to ensure the recursive call to <code>self.tail.format</code> works. Also note that we aren’t implementing <code>Format</code> directly on <code>FString</code>, but rather on an H-list containing <code>FString</code>.</p>

<p>Finally, the most complex case, <code>FVar</code>. We want this impl to take an argument from the <code>ArgList</code>, then format the remaining format list with the remaining arguments.</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>impl</span><span>&lt;</span><span>T</span><span>,</span> <span>ArgList</span><span>,</span> <span>FmtList</span><span>&gt;</span> <span>Format</span><span>&lt;</span><span>HCons</span><span>&lt;</span><span>T</span><span>,</span> <span>ArgList</span><span>&gt;&gt;</span>
<span>for</span> <span>HCons</span><span>&lt;</span><span>FVar</span><span>,</span> <span>FmtList</span><span>&gt;</span>
<span>where</span>
  <span>FmtList</span><span>:</span> <span>Format</span><span>&lt;</span><span>ArgList</span><span>&gt;</span><span>,</span>
  <span>T</span><span>:</span> <span>ToString</span><span>,</span>
<span>{</span>
  <span>fn</span> <span>format</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>self</span><span>,</span> <span>args</span><span>:</span> <span>HCons</span><span>&lt;</span><span>T</span><span>,</span> <span>ArgList</span><span>&gt;</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>String</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>args</span><span>.head</span><span>.to_string</span><span>()</span> <span>+</span> <span>&amp;</span><span>self</span><span>.tail</span><span>.format</span><span>(</span><span>args</span><span>.tail</span><span>)</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Be careful to observe which H-list is being accessed by <code>head</code> and <code>tail</code>. Here, the <code>args</code> H-list provides the data to fill the hole via <code>args.head</code>.</p>

<h2 id="checking-our-properties">Checking our properties</h2>

<p>With this implementation, our correct example successfully compiles and runs:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>let</span> <span>example</span> <span>=</span> <span>hlist!</span><span>[</span>
  <span>FString</span><span>(</span><span>"Hello "</span><span>),</span> <span>FVar</span><span>,</span> <span>FString</span><span>(</span><span>"! The first prime is "</span><span>),</span> <span>FVar</span>
<span>];</span>
<span>assert_eq!</span><span>(</span>
  <span>example</span><span>.format</span><span>(</span><span>hlist!</span><span>[</span><span>"world"</span><span>,</span> <span>2</span><span>]),</span>
  <span>"Hello world! The first prime is 2"</span>
<span>);</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>What about our incorrect example? If we write this:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>example</span><span>.format</span><span>(</span><span>hlist!</span><span>[</span><span>"just one arg"</span><span>]);</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This code fails to compile with the error:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>error[E0308]: mismatched types
  --&gt; src/printf.rs:48:18
   |
48 |   example.format(hlist!["just one arg"]);
   |                  ^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^
   |                  expected struct `Cons`, found struct `HNil`
   |
   = note: expected struct `HCons&lt;_, HNil&gt;`
              found struct `HNil`
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>While the error is enigmatic, our mistake is at least correctly caught at compile-time. This is because Rust deduces that <code>example.format()</code> expects an H-list of the shape <code>HCons&lt;_, HCons&lt;_, HNil&gt;&gt;</code>, but it finds <code>HNil</code> too soon in our 1-element H-list. A similar error occurs when providing too many args.</p>

<p>Stupendous! We have successfully implemented a type-safe printf using H-lists and traits.</p>

<h2 id="extending-our-abstraction">Extending our abstraction</h2>

<p>Right now, our <code>Format</code> function just checks that the format list and argument list are the same length. We could extend our format structures, for example to ensure that an <code>FVar</code> must be a particular type, or must use <code>Debug</code> vs. <code>Display</code>. Here’s the sketch of such a strategy:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>use</span> <span>std</span><span>::</span><span>marker</span><span>::</span><span>PhantomData</span><span>;</span>

<span>// Add flags for whether using Display or Debug</span>
<span>pub</span> <span>struct</span> <span>FDisplay</span><span>;</span>
<span>pub</span> <span>struct</span> <span>FDebug</span><span>;</span>

<span>// Use a type parameter with PhantomData to represent the intended type</span>
<span>pub</span> <span>struct</span> <span>FVar</span><span>&lt;</span><span>T</span><span>,</span> <span>Flag</span><span>&gt;</span><span>(</span><span>PhantomData</span><span>&lt;</span><span>(</span><span>T</span><span>,</span> <span>Flag</span><span>)</span><span>&gt;</span><span>);</span>

<span>// Now, T has to be the same between the format list and arg list</span>
<span>// Also, FDisplay flag requires that `T: Display`</span>
<span>impl</span><span>&lt;</span><span>T</span><span>,</span> <span>ArgList</span><span>,</span> <span>FmtList</span><span>&gt;</span> <span>Format</span><span>&lt;</span><span>HCons</span><span>&lt;</span><span>T</span><span>,</span> <span>ArgList</span><span>&gt;&gt;</span>
<span>for</span> <span>HCons</span><span>&lt;</span><span>FVar</span><span>&lt;</span><span>T</span><span>,</span> <span>FDisplay</span><span>&gt;</span><span>,</span> <span>FmtList</span><span>&gt;</span>
<span>where</span>
  <span>FmtList</span><span>:</span> <span>Format</span><span>&lt;</span><span>ArgList</span><span>&gt;</span><span>,</span>
  <span>T</span><span>:</span> <span>Display</span><span>,</span>
<span>{</span>
  <span>fn</span> <span>format</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>self</span><span>,</span> <span>args</span><span>:</span> <span>HCons</span><span>&lt;</span><span>T</span><span>,</span> <span>ArgList</span><span>&gt;</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>String</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>// using format! is cheating, but you get the idea</span>
    <span>format!</span><span>(</span><span>"{}"</span><span>,</span> <span>args</span><span>)</span> <span>+</span> <span>&amp;</span><span>self</span><span>.tail</span><span>.format</span><span>(</span><span>args</span><span>.tail</span><span>)</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>// Similar impl for `T: Debug` when `FDebug` is used</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>With this approach, if our format list and arg list differ in type:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>let</span> <span>fmt</span> <span>=</span> <span>hlist!</span><span>[</span><span>FString</span><span>(</span><span>"n: "</span><span>),</span> <span>FVar</span><span>::</span><span>&lt;</span><span>i32</span><span>,</span> <span>FDisplay</span><span>&gt;</span><span>(</span><span>PhantomData</span><span>)];</span>
<span>fmt</span><span>.format</span><span>(</span><span>hlist!</span><span>[</span><span>"not a number"</span><span>]);</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Then the code will not compile with the error, <code>&amp;'static str is not i32</code>.</p>

<p>Shout-out to <a href="https://www.servant.dev/posts/2018-07-12-servant-dsl-typelevel.html">this blog post</a> from Haskell’s servant framework which got me thinking about adapting their strategy into Rust.</p>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://willcrichton.net/notes/type-safe-printf/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24154263</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 06:07:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Save the USPS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 192 | Comments 236 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24153311">thread link</a>) | @mooreds
<br/>
August 13, 2020 | https://2pml.com/2020/08/10/usps/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://2pml.com/2020/08/10/usps/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-12653">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>
		<p><img data-attachment-id="12682" data-permalink="https://2pml.com/2020/08/10/usps/cvbbjbi0/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/2pml.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/cVBbjbi0.jpg?fit=1600%2C1144&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1600,1144" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="cVBbjbi0" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/2pml.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/cVBbjbi0.jpg?fit=300%2C215&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/2pml.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/cVBbjbi0.jpg?fit=740%2C529&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/2pml.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/cVBbjbi0.jpg?resize=740%2C529&amp;ssl=1" alt="cVBbjbi0" width="740" height="529" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/2pml.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/cVBbjbi0.jpg?w=1600&amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i0.wp.com/2pml.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/cVBbjbi0.jpg?resize=300%2C215&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/2pml.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/cVBbjbi0.jpg?resize=1024%2C732&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/2pml.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/cVBbjbi0.jpg?resize=768%2C549&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/2pml.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/cVBbjbi0.jpg?resize=1536%2C1098&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/2pml.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/cVBbjbi0.jpg?w=1480&amp;ssl=1 1480w" sizes="(max-width: 740px) 100vw, 740px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p>
<p>There are three types of infrastructure. One is visible: roads, dams and bridges. The second is invisible: broadband internet provisions and the entirety of our cellular infrastructure. Both are still vital in building our present. The third form of infrastructure is one being rebuilt in order to be repurposed for future use. I explained in <em>J-Curves and Agglomeration</em>:</p>
<blockquote><p>The U.S. Postal Service is a key component of the eCommerce economy. Packages are just 5% of its shipping volume but eCommerce accounts for nearly 30% of the agency’s revenue. Partnerships with vendors like Amazon (or providers like FedEx and UPS) provide a majority of its package volume but small businesses and direct-to-consumer brands rely on USPS’ pricing. Raising costs on retailers may lead to more attrition. […]</p>
<p>By raising prices to combat Amazon’s growing influence over the economy, disrupting the postal economy is no different than digging up paved roads before a period of heightened freight transit. [<a href="https://2pml.com/2020/05/18/agglomeration/">2PM, 1</a>]</p></blockquote>
<p>The U.S. Postal Service is all three. When an American institution is 250 years old, it may as well be the ground that we stand on. The service has contributed services and innovations that we don’t readily attribute to it. Consider its contribution to the middle class: the U.S. Postal Service is one the country’s biggest employers with nearly 330,000 career employees and an average salary of $50,000. They are building the future of eCommerce, a still-nascent industry.</p>
<p>Critics of the USPS will cite cost of labor as a reason for the service’s obsolescence. A common refrain is “Why couldn’t Amazon takeover the service?” Consider that in the fourth quarter of 2019, eCommerce was just 11.9% of all retail. Amazon constituted right under half of that volume. And without the postal service, Amazon would not exist. The market costs of shipment subsidized a number of Amazon’s operations, allowing it to capture market share.</p>
<h2>“The Ground We Stand On”</h2>
<p>The postal service began before the founding of the United States. Benjamin Franklin was fired from his role as postmaster due to his involvement with the American Revolution. Just one year later in 1775, the Continental Congress appointed Franklin the Postmaster General of the “United Colonies.” His tenure left a mail system that offered service between the then-colonies and Great Britain. By 1802, the first African-Americans to work for the Postal Service were enslaved mail carriers. Senator James Jackson of Georgia, Chairman of the Committee of the Senate on the Post Office Establishment, once wrote:</p>
<blockquote><p>… The most active and intelligent [slaves] are employed as post riders. By travelling from day to day, and hourly mixing with people […] they will acquire information. They will learn that a man’s rights do not depend on his color. They will, in time, become teachers to their brethren.</p></blockquote>
<p>Within two months of Senator Jackson’s proclamation, African-Americans would be banned from the postal service, lasting from 1802 to March 1865, just one month before the conclusion of the Civil War. This disbarment ended by congressional decree.</p>
<blockquote><p>No person, by reason of color, shall be disqualified from employment in carrying the mails. (13 Stat. 515)</p></blockquote>
<p>The next decades would see an unparalleled push for African-American financial stability. Nearly 800 would serve as postal employees prior to the 20th century. More than 200 African Americans are known to have served in the high rank of postmaster prior to the conclusion of Reconstruction and the Progressive Era (1863-1920). Of them, nearly 20 were women. The postal service has always been politicized.</p>
<p>Soon after, the U.S. Government expanded on the postal service’s role in democratizing America, both literally and figuratively. President Theodore “Teddy” Roosevelt expanded on this with the <em>Square Deal</em> in 1902, communicating a fairness policy in hiring and leadership. The result was momentous for many. Roosevelt stated:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>It is and should be my consistent policy in every State, where their numbers warranted it, to recognize colored men of good repute and standing in making appointments to office. […] I can not consent to take the position that the door of hope – the door of opportunity – is to be shut upon any man, no matter how worthy, purely upon the grounds of race or color. <a href="https://about.usps.com/who-we-are/postal-history/african-american-workers-20thc.htm#_edn2" name="_ednref2">[2]</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Today, 21% (or nearly 70,000) of the agency’s employees are African-American. However, the postal service was consequential beyond matters of social equity. By 1823, the U.S. Postal Service and the U.S. Government established 80,000 miles of “post roads” to help carriers navigate new rural areas. By 1860, these roads connected nearly 28,000 post offices. Today, the postal service maintains nearly 40,000 post offices, clearing 212 billion letters and mail to 144 million homes.</p>
<blockquote data-card-controls="1" data-card-align="center" data-card-theme="light" data-card-key="3101080c845e4679b6077080f81a573e">
<h4><a href="https://twitter.com/web/status/1292117127055519744">No Title</a></h4>
<p>Save the @USPS.There is no institution more critical to the next phases of our commerce economy.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Today, the service is tasked with another generational shift: supporting online retail. The pandemic shifted the American consumer towards online retail, this while reducing the number of units shipped. As such, companies like UPS and FedEx have responded by hiking prices. In response to USPS’ distress, FedEx recently stated:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The COVID-19 pandemic has negatively impacted mail volumes and mix resulting in a further decrease in revenues and negative financial impact for the USPS. Additionally, the USPS continues to experience budgetary uncertainty as well as increased political debate regarding potential privatization or restructuring of its operations.</p>
</blockquote>

<figure id="attachment_12683" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-12683"><img data-attachment-id="12683" data-permalink="https://2pml.com/2020/08/10/usps/sleikjxu/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/2pml.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/sLEikjXU-scaled.jpg?fit=2048%2C1259&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2048,1259" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="sLEikjXU" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/2pml.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/sLEikjXU-scaled.jpg?fit=300%2C184&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/2pml.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/sLEikjXU-scaled.jpg?fit=740%2C455&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" src="https://i2.wp.com/2pml.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/sLEikjXU-scaled.jpg?resize=740%2C455&amp;ssl=1" alt="sLEikjXU" width="740" height="455" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/2pml.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/sLEikjXU-scaled.jpg?w=2048&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i2.wp.com/2pml.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/sLEikjXU-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C184&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/2pml.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/sLEikjXU-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C630&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/2pml.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/sLEikjXU-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C472&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/2pml.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/sLEikjXU-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C944&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i2.wp.com/2pml.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/sLEikjXU-scaled.jpg?w=1480&amp;ssl=1 1480w" sizes="(max-width: 740px) 100vw, 740px" data-recalc-dims="1"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-12683">The most popular government sites: June 18, 2020</figcaption></figure>
<p>Cost inflation is the most concerning obstacle ahead for digitally native retailers. Without the treatment that the United States’ oldest civilian service afforded Amazon in its infancy, it will be more difficult to build more businesses of Amazon’s scale. The economics were difficult enough as is; these added costs will only add pressure to pass along costs to consumers, many of whom are facing down one of the most economically vulnerable periods since 2008.We should consider the postal service an investment into our present and future and a monument to our past.</p>
<p>If our economy is to begin addressing the shortfalls caused by the overwhelming contraction in the traditional retail industry, it will need the support of the postal service. For eCommerce, their service is the industry’s last mile for thousands of direct-to-consumer small businesses. The postal service uniquely sits at the intersection of our physical roads and our digital infrastructure. There isn’t a direct substitute and we shouldn’t wait to find out the hard way. Save the USPS. We will need more companies like the the successful hundreds that were built on its 250 year old infrastructure. That includes Amazon.</p>
<p><strong>By Web Smith | Editor: Hilary Milnes | Art by Alex Remy | <a href="http://2pml.com/about">About 2PM</a></strong></p>
			</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	
	</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://2pml.com/2020/08/10/usps/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24153311</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 04:18:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
