<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 5]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 5. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 16:48:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-5.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 16:48:57 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years (2018)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 211 | Comments 46 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26033689">thread link</a>) | @allenleein
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | https://www.cake.co/conversations/jNZlq6j/the-man-who-produced-steve-jobs-keynotes-for-20-years | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cake.co/conversations/jNZlq6j/the-man-who-produced-steve-jobs-keynotes-for-20-years">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Posts"><li><div data-context="conversation" data-first="true"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><div><p>Wayne Goodrich was the producer for every keynote Steve gave after his return to Apple. Before that, Wayne helped him create presentations at NeXT and Pixar. He is writing a book about what it was like on the inside.</p><p><em>This is a panel conversation, which works the same on Cake as panels do in the real world: the audience may be vast, but it’s in everyone’s interest to let the panel speak. You can add energy to Wayne’s fascinating stories in this conversation with emojis like </em><span><span>😱</span></span><em>, just like clapping and laughing does in a physical-world panel. To post comments &amp; questions check out </em><a href="https://www.cake.co/conversations/2Jf7ksx/questions-comments-about-the-wayne-goodrich-panel" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>this conversation</em></a><em>.&nbsp;</em>&nbsp;</p><p>Wayne, we knew each other at NeXT when you were working in hardware product marketing. At the time, I had the harrowing but amazing experience of <a href="https://www.cake.co/conversations/rZXhqtP/that-time-i-had-steve-jobs-keynote-at-unix-expo" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">helping Steve do his Unix Expo keynote</a>.</p><div><div><a href="https://cake.imgix.net/m/QLZzngCrcmXX_1531329024912.png" itemprop="sharedContent" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject"><img src="https://cake.imgix.net/m/QLZzngCrcmXX_1531329024912.png?fit=max&amp;fm=pjpg&amp;h=640&amp;q=65&amp;w=680"><meta content="https://cake.imgix.net/m/QLZzngCrcmXX_1531329024912.png" itemprop="contentUrl"></a></div></div></div></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><div><p>I was, but when NeXT stopped making hardware they laid me off. A week later, Steve called me and started to say “okay Wayne, we need to...” I interjected “what do you mean we need to? You laid me off.” He said “oh” and then click.&nbsp;</p><p>Eight months later I heard from my brother, who was still working customer support, “Steve wants you to call. He won’t call you but you should call him.” The result of that conversation led to working directly with Steve on all his most important presentations at Pixar and Apple for nearly the next two decades.&nbsp;</p><div><div><a href="https://cake.imgix.net/m/mg9r4Mmq9NF9_1531329508101.jpeg" itemprop="sharedContent" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject"><img src="https://cake.imgix.net/m/mg9r4Mmq9NF9_1531329508101.jpeg?fit=max&amp;fm=pjpg&amp;h=640&amp;q=65&amp;w=680"><meta content="https://cake.imgix.net/m/mg9r4Mmq9NF9_1531329508101.jpeg" itemprop="contentUrl"></a></div></div></div></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>And now you’re writing a book about it!</p></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>Yes, I’m working on it because I was a a unique Insider for 20 years and I'm disappointed at the liberties that people like Aaron Sorkin have taken. I would have gladly helped tell the story the way it really happened, or at least lent some credibility to the parts that should have been historically correct.</p></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><div><p>I spoke to Andy Hertzfeld about that. He said Aaron explained that he was making a painting, not a photograph. It’s not supposed to be a documentary, so he felt he had creative license.</p><div><div><a href="https://cake.imgix.net/m/LJ88BGP2DN4b_1531330037651.jpeg" itemprop="sharedContent" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject"><img src="https://cake.imgix.net/m/LJ88BGP2DN4b_1531330037651.jpeg?fit=max&amp;fm=pjpg&amp;h=640&amp;q=65&amp;w=680"><meta content="https://cake.imgix.net/m/LJ88BGP2DN4b_1531330037651.jpeg" itemprop="contentUrl"></a></div></div></div></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>I know they're making movies, but let's at least get some of the real stuff in there about who Steve was. Let's not purposely put fictitious information into the world that people are going to believe was reality. That’s just wrong in my opinion.</p></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><div><p>I’ve heard people say that Steve’s iPhone launch was the greatest presentation in business history. It had heroes and villains, plot twists, humorous sidebars… Did the time you and Steve spend with Pixar influence his keynotes?</p><div><div><a href="https://cake.imgix.net/m/SdQxm9XxprMv_1531330726448.png" itemprop="sharedContent" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject"><img src="https://cake.imgix.net/m/SdQxm9XxprMv_1531330726448.png?fit=max&amp;fm=pjpg&amp;h=640&amp;q=65&amp;w=680"><meta content="https://cake.imgix.net/m/SdQxm9XxprMv_1531330726448.png" itemprop="contentUrl"></a></div></div></div></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><div><p>Oh, absolutely! If you look at the primitive narratives in Steve’s presentations at NeXT, you can see the influence that our experience at Pixar had on the storytelling over time that resulted in events like the iPhone launch.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>What few people realize is that, like Pixar movies, there is a color scheme throughout the 90 minutes, and an emotional ramp. And yes there are heroes and villains, action sequences, humor and plot twists. You have to be careful not to wear the audience out. You have to manage building to a climax. Steve understood this better than anyone.</p></div></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>How much time went into preparing the iPhone demo?</p></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><div><p>Quite a lot! That’s the thing, no other CEO would have imagined spending the time Steve invested in his keynotes. For the most important ones, we started 3 or so months out. He would run the company until maybe 2:00 pm and then spend a few hours with me. Then he may start in again in the evening, me at my house and him at his, and we’d stay up until midnight. Sometimes we’d be at it again at 6 am.&nbsp;</p><p>I saw part of my job—and Steve never knew this—as managing his emotional ramp to the event. I’ve even described my job much like being a product manager. There were all kinds of things that could mess that up: the product timing, or the photos that were taken weren’t good enough, or he had a bad day, or we didn’t have all the assets he needed… or at times too many!&nbsp;</p><p>With movies, you never want anything to affect suspension of belief. You want your audience to stay in that magical moment and not think about how things are done.&nbsp;&nbsp;With the iPhone, we wanted to show that if you rotate your phone to landscape mode, the photo would automatically rotate too. But we were not projecting a video of the actual iPhone that Steve was holding in his hand, only the video from the iPhone. That would have made it shaky on the big screen with distracting reflections. </p><p>So we showed a graphic of an iPhone, to look like the Keynote slides, and projected Steve’s demo iPhone screen into the exact right position in the graphic.&nbsp;The trick was that when Steve rotated the iPhone to landscape mode, the right thing to do to keep customers in the moment was to rotate the iPhone graphic with its inserted video feed rotating in sync as well. But how?</p><div><div><a href="https://cake.imgix.net/m/FYLjTlvKhnRr_1531331370341.png" itemprop="sharedContent" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject"><img src="https://cake.imgix.net/m/FYLjTlvKhnRr_1531331370341.png?fit=max&amp;fm=pjpg&amp;h=640&amp;q=65&amp;w=680"><meta content="https://cake.imgix.net/m/FYLjTlvKhnRr_1531331370341.png" itemprop="contentUrl"></a></div></div></div></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><div><p>It took a month for one of the brilliant Apple engineers to work out how to do this. It looked natural to the audience and no one had to think about how it happened.&nbsp;</p><p>When Steve saw this happen he first time, he knew it’d be magic and it had to be shown live. He rotated it back and forth several times in his demo and no one ever questioned what they were seeing because it looked exactly they way it should.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>If I remember, the internal estimate of the marketing power of the iPhone demo Steve did that day was in excess of $1 billion of PR spend from demo until we shipped.</p><div><div><a href="https://cake.imgix.net/m/DYlF8vV1XR09_1531331556178.png" itemprop="sharedContent" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject"><img src="https://cake.imgix.net/m/DYlF8vV1XR09_1531331556178.png?fit=max&amp;fm=pjpg&amp;h=640&amp;q=65&amp;w=680"><meta content="https://cake.imgix.net/m/DYlF8vV1XR09_1531331556178.png" itemprop="contentUrl"></a></div></div></div></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>Amazing! Did he take feedback from other people at Apple as the presentation was being constructed?</p></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>He did. We learned from the creative process Pixar uses: iteration in front of people who can shape it by adding constructive feedback. We held high level slide and demo reviews in the town hall facility with people from each group that would be affected by the presentation. These would happen usually a week or two before the event and rehearsals onsite.</p></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>Steve was incredibly demanding when I was at NeXT and a lot of people didn’t last. How did you make it 20 years?</p></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>I know that I quit 3 times, one kind of officially via email to HR. God only knows how many times I was actually yelled at and fired but it never went anywhere. Essentially I never really wanted to leave so I didn’t.</p></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>That’s insane. I read an interview of Andy Cunningham who said, “I loved working for Steve Jobs even though he fired me 5 times.” What do you mean it never went anywhere?</p></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><div><div><p>One afternoon he told me, “God dammit, Wayne. I want you to fucking go home right now and tell me why I shouldn’t fire you tomorrow.” So I went home that night and I probably worked on 15 or 16 versions of an email trying to explain everything. But then I just decided to say “Steve, you know how I feel, but you’re the boss. You let me know tomorrow whether I’m fired or not.” I never heard another word about it.</p><p>The mythology of him mostly comes from individuals that didn't survive around him. The people who got close knew the rules, knew how to work with him, knew his core desires and what he was trying to achieve. They never really had problems with it.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p></div><div><p>Someone told me early on that if you do something great, you just have to acknowledge it yourself because you’re not going to get it from him except on a rare occasion. A lot of people who weren’t used to that would come in to present their product plan or whatever, and they would be seeking to make themselves look good and get praise from Steve. If he got a whiff of that, he would rip you down a peg.&nbsp;</p><p>He was usually right because the person usually didn’t do a great job. Those are the ones who flamed out and then had the horrible things to say because they couldn’t admit to themselves that they couldn’t cut the mustard.</p><p>He was a complex individual but he always desired the best out of everybody. He was ultimately very caring. He had his own relationship with my daughter from the age of 4 years old and let her come to rehearsals and events. He even asked her opinion a few times when the team couldn’t decide between particular graphics to use.</p></div><div><div><a href="https://cake.imgix.net/m/j4D3PCrR4Pyl_1531332483022.jpeg" itemprop="sharedContent" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject"><img src="https://cake.imgix.net/m/j4D3PCrR4Pyl_1531332483022.jpeg?fit=max&amp;fm=pjpg&amp;h=640&amp;q=65&amp;w=680"><meta content="https://cake.imgix.net/m/j4D3PCrR4Pyl_1531332483022.jpeg" itemprop="contentUrl"></a></div></div></div></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>Give us an example of when he went off on you because he expected better.</p></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><div><div><p>When we launched the Lifesaver iMacs (the color ones), Steph Adams [Owner of Adams &amp; Asscociates—the outside production company for Apple] and I were trying to bring them out from behind the screen and raise them up out of their pedestals. A week before the event and we were still struggling to synchronize them and make the motion smooth. This was before computer-controlled movement machinery was readily available.</p><p>After mentioning this to Steve, he literally says, “I know the guys from Cirque du Soleil, why don’t you call them?” With one week left, we couldn’t do that so we stuck with our way. It was a hand-crank thing. When you looked at it close, it was really bad. But when you were in the audience, you couldn’t tell unless you knew what to look for. However, Steve was on the stage watching these things not perfectly aligned with a little bit of stuttering. He wasn’t happy and we could see it in the video feed we were watching.</p><p>The show went off, no one ever noticed or mentioned it in the press, but yet he noticed. He pulled me and Steph aside. There were people all around so he didn’t scream or yell at us. It was one of those “I’m really disappointed. At any other time I’d probably fire you.” For ten minutes he went on and on. We looked at each other and just melted into the floor.</p><p>But we came back the next show having done our research. We now had the beginnings of our computer-controlled systems. We could bring things from the back of the stage, under the stage, or out of a cabinet—and twirl them as they emerged. Cirque du Soleil couldn’t do it better than we did it.</p><p>As I look back, if we had not been berated so much, we wouldn’t have seen that these were amazing products and they could have been launched so much better.</p></div><div><div><a href="https://cake.imgix.net/m/wl9s4Lpk9wHX_1531333042972.jpeg" itemprop="sharedContent" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject"><img src="https://cake.imgix.net/m/wl9s4Lpk9wHX_1531333042972.jpeg?fit=max&amp;fm=pjpg&amp;h=640&amp;q=65&amp;w=680"><meta content="https://cake.imgix.net/m/wl9s4Lpk9wHX_1531333042972.jpeg" itemprop="contentUrl"></a></div></div></div></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>When I did his keynotes at NeXT, I don’t remember him ever being scripted. Did that change?</p></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><div><div><p>That’s the thing most executives don’t get. We never wrote a script. The preview monitor was just the next slide coming up. The Keynote development, the slide sequencing, the simplifying and honing were all part of his method for being as empathetic, emotive, charismatic and precise as he was on stage. It came from time spent …</p></div></div></div></div></article></div></li></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.cake.co/conversations/jNZlq6j/the-man-who-produced-steve-jobs-keynotes-for-20-years">https://www.cake.co/conversations/jNZlq6j/the-man-who-produced-steve-jobs-keynotes-for-20-years</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cake.co/conversations/jNZlq6j/the-man-who-produced-steve-jobs-keynotes-for-20-years</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26033689</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 06:29:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Universal Warrior: The Many Faces of Battle]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 21 | Comments 9 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26033359">thread link</a>) | @parsecs
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | https://acoup.blog/2021/02/05/collections-the-universal-warrior-part-iia-the-many-faces-of-battle/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://acoup.blog/2021/02/05/collections-the-universal-warrior-part-iia-the-many-faces-of-battle/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>This is the second part of a three part (<a href="https://acoup.blog/2021/01/29/collections-the-universal-warrior-part-i-soldiers-warriors-and/">I</a>, II) discussion of the idea of a ‘universal warrior’ – the assumption that there is a transcendent sameness about either the experience of war or ‘warrior values’ which might provide some sort of fundamental truth for understanding war, either in the past or present, or else a useful blueprint for current life more generally.  In investigating this question, we are using Steven Pressfield’s <a href="https://stevenpressfield.com/category/the-warrior-archetype/">recent video series</a> as our foil, since it is a more completely explained expression of this idea and one should always try to debate the stronger form of the opposing argument.</p>



<p><a href="https://acoup.blog/2021/01/29/collections-the-universal-warrior-part-i-soldiers-warriors-and/">Last time we took a look at the social place of people involved in war</a>.  We found that, far from there being a universal combatant, distinctions between soldiers and warriors are both significant for the present and important for understanding the past.  Moreover, beyond that simple dichotomy, the idea of a universal war experience in turn conceals the basic fact that many people who were neither warriors nor soldiers, not properly combatants of any kind, experienced war in unique ways, be they victims of warfare, homefront supporters, or economically invested in the enterprise.  Already we have seen that there’s far more than just one sort of person <em>with</em> a war experience.</p>



<p>This week (and next), we’re narrowing our focus just to the combatants and asking to what degree is even the experience of combat and soldiering (or ‘warrioring’) common.  Does it evoke the same emotions or require the same kinds of character?  Is it conditioned on the same values?  Does it involve the same activities or experiences?  Is combat understood the same, from one society to another?</p>



<p>Even so narrowed, our topic is necessarily massive, since we are considering the experience of <em>all</em> wars at <em>all</em> times.  But fortunately (for the wear and tear on my keyboard, if nothing else) our thesis – that there are quite a lot of broad universals in the war experience – does not need to be tested <em>everywhere</em> if it can be shown to fail in many places.  Consequently, we are going to bounce around a bit here; I hope the reader will understand that I mean these examples to be broadly representative, rather than exhaustive.</p>



<p>If that method seems a bit patchwork, it is important to remember just how <em>expansive</em> the argument implied by this notion of a ‘universal’ warrior or war experience is.  <strong>In arguing for a ‘warrior archetype’ that recurs in all cultures</strong> (<a href="https://stevenpressfield.com/2020/09/warrior-episode-eight/">as Steven Pressfield does</a>),<strong> or more obliquely in arguing that some given sort of long vanished ‘warrior culture’ </strong>(like the Spartans) <strong>provides material for emulation today, they are making a claim for a <em>human universal</em>, and a profound one at that</strong>.  After all, the suggestion is not that, for instance, some particular Spartan (or knightly, or Viking, or Samurai, or Apache, or…) tactic or weapon should today be used, but that the <em>ethos</em> and worldview of those ‘warriors’ is valuable because it taps into a true human <em>constant</em>.</p>



<p><strong>Because after all, a lot has changed!</strong>  We no longer fight with spears, or muskets.  Our wars are, in some obvious ways, vastly different from the conflicts of the past.  <strong>Yet for these past values, social systems, or habits to be directly applicable to the present, <em>something</em> would have to be fundamentally constant, at a deep and fairly profound level, in human conflict</strong>.  And it has to be something rather more than ‘people die in war, and that is sad for some people.’  After all, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/12/27/the-10-most-dangerous-jobs-in-america-according-to-bls-data.html">people die in logging</a>, and you don’t hear all of these fellows waxing lyrical about the ‘universal lumberjack’ (though I can assure you, if it does exist well…<a href="https://youtu.be/pfRdur8GLBM">then he’s a lumberjack and he’s ok</a>).  It has to be something more than ‘war is scary’ because after all so too is running <em>into </em>burning buildings, but we’re not discussing patterning our lives around the ‘universal firefighter’ either.  There would have to be some more profound truth to the phrase – to abuse the <em>Fallout</em> series – that ‘War, war never changes.’</p>



<p>And that is a thesis we can test!  Does war change from one culture to the next?  From one period to the next?  From one place to the next?  Let’s find out!</p>



<p>But first (and you knew there was a but first, didn’t you?) if you like what you are reading here, please share it; if you really like it, you can support me on <a href="https://www.patreon.com/user?u=20122096">Patreon</a>. And if you want updates whenever a new post appears, you can click below for email updates or follow me on twitter (@BretDevereaux) for updates as to new posts as well as my occasional ancient history, foreign policy or military history musings.</p>






<h2>Raids and Battles</h2>



<p>So what is the experience of combat like?  Well, first we have to ask, <em>what sort of combat do you mean?</em></p>



<p>As I’ve noted before, the branch of military history most focused on the experience of combat is what is sometimes called the ‘Face of Battle’ school, after John Keegan’s <em>The Face of Battle</em> (1976).  Taking three battles from English history (Agincourt, Waterloo and the Somme), Keegan aimed to reconstruct the experience of those battles in its own long chapter, beginning with the campaign that led to them, then discussing the interaction of men and weapons (infantry vs. cavalry, cavalry vs. cavalry and so on) seeking to use the physics of the battlefield to explain how these interactions would go.  He then focuses on how men cohered in the face of terror; then on to the casualties and the aftermath.</p>



<p>We might imagine that this standard order (replicated, I might add, in <em>The Western Way of War </em>(1989), albeit with more problems of evidence) implies a standard sequence of events, moments and emotions in a battle.</p>



<p>Except that for most of the human experience, this sort of battle was rare and generally indecisive when it did happen (a point which leads to the marvelous title of the upcoming, <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Other-Face-Battle-Forgotten-Experience/dp/0190920645">The Other Face of Battle</a></em>).  This ‘Face of Battle’ kind of war – formally constituted field armies meeting in set-piece battles out on open fields, with a clearly defined ‘peace’ before and after the war, along with a zone of conflict and a ‘home front’ – is the kind of war modern folks tend to be quickest to imagine, because in most of the industrialized world, we imagine this as <em>our</em> way of war.  But it not the oldest, or most common, or original way of war.</p>



<p>The oldest way of war was what Native North Americans called – evocatively – the ‘cutting off’ way of war (a phrase I am borrowing from W. Lee, “The Military Revolution of Native North America” in <em>Empires and Indigines</em>, ed. W. Lee (2011)), but which was common among non-state peoples <em>everywhere</em> in the world for the vast stretch of human history (and one may easily argue much of modern insurgency and terrorism is merely this same toolkit, updated with modern weapons).  <a href="https://youtu.be/4I8kic8xZh8">The goal of such warfare was not to subjugate a population but to drive them off, forcing them to vacate resource-rich land which could then be exploited by your group</a>.  To do this, you wanted to inflict maximum damage (casualties inflicted, animals rustled, goods stolen, people captured) at minimum risk, until the lopsided balance of pain you inflicted forced the enemy to simply move away from you to get out of your operational range.</p>



<p>The main tool of this form of warfare (detailed more extensively in A. Gat, <em>War in Human Civilization</em> (2006) and L. Keeley, <em>War Before Civilization</em> (1996)) was the raid.  Rather than announcing your movements, a war party would attempt to advance into enemy territory in secret, hoping (in the best case) to catch an enemy village or camp unawares (typically by night) so that the population could be killed or captured (<em>mostly</em> killed; these are mostly non-specialized societies with limited ability to incorporate large numbers of subjugated captives) safely.  Then you <em>quickly</em> get out of enemy territory before villages or camps allied to your target can retaliate.  If you detected an incoming raid, you might rally up <em>your</em> allied villages or camps and ambush the ambusher in an equally lopsided engagement.</p>



<p>Only rarely in this did a <em>battle</em> result – typically when both the surprise of the raid and the surprise of the counter-raid ambush failed.  At that point, with the chance for surprise utterly lost, both sides might line up and exchange missile fire (arrows, javelins) at fairly long range.  Casualties in these battles were generally very low – instead the battle served both as a display of valor and a signal of resolve by both sides to continue the conflict.  That isn’t to say these wars were bloodless – indeed the overall level of military mortality was much <em>higher</em> than in ‘pitched battle’ cultures, but the killing was done almost entirely in the ambush and the raid.</p>



<p><strong>We may call this the first system of war.</strong>  It is the oldest, but as noted above, never entirely goes away.  We tend to call this style ‘asymmetric’ or ‘unconventional’ war, but it is the <em>most</em> conventional war – it was the first convention, after all.  It is also sometimes denigrated as primitive, but should not be judged so quickly – first system armies have managed to frustrate far stronger opponents when terrain and politics were favorable.</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="6138" data-permalink="https://acoup.blog/morella_combate-de-arquero/" data-orig-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/02/morella_combate-de-arquero.png" data-orig-size="1000,954" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="morella_combate-de-arquero" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/02/morella_combate-de-arquero.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/02/morella_combate-de-arquero.png?w=1000" src="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/02/morella_combate-de-arquero.png?w=1000" alt="" srcset="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/02/morella_combate-de-arquero.png 1000w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/02/morella_combate-de-arquero.png?w=150 150w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/02/morella_combate-de-arquero.png?w=300 300w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/02/morella_combate-de-arquero.png?w=768 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px"><figcaption>Via Wikipedia, a Mesolithic painting of a battle from Morella la Vella, Spain (c. 10,000BP), showing what looks to be an ambush, a normal occurrence in first system war.</figcaption></figure>



<p>What changed?  Very briefly, agriculture, cities and the state.  Agriculture created a stationary population that both wouldn’t move but which could also be dominated, subjugated and have their production extracted from them.  Their wealth was clustered in towns which could be fortified with walls that would resist any quick raid, but control of that fortified town center (and its administrative apparatus of taxation) meant control of the countryside and its resources.  Taking such a town meant a siege – delivering a large body of troops and keeping them there long enough to either breach the walls or starve out the town into surrender.  This created a war where …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://acoup.blog/2021/02/05/collections-the-universal-warrior-part-iia-the-many-faces-of-battle/">https://acoup.blog/2021/02/05/collections-the-universal-warrior-part-iia-the-many-faces-of-battle/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://acoup.blog/2021/02/05/collections-the-universal-warrior-part-iia-the-many-faces-of-battle/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26033359</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 05:11:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Disqus, a dark commenting system]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 159 | Comments 72 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26033052">thread link</a>) | @supz_k
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | https://supunkavinda.blog/disqus | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://supunkavinda.blog/disqus">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div id="content-real">
<p>Disqus is a free commenting system and a great example of "if you're not paying for it, you become the product". Unfortunately, in Disqus' case, your website visitors become the product too.</p><p>Today, I'm going to analyze what happens when you embed Disqus on your website.</p><p>I signed up at <a href="https://disqus.com/">Disqus</a> and added the installation code to a <strong>blank page</strong> (So, I'm sure every HTTP request that the browser makes is from Disqus).</p><p>Disqus makes 76 HTTP requests and fetches 2MB of data! (even with 0 comments). And, it took 7 seconds to load.</p><p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/tCZxbmi.png" alt="Disqus HTTP Requests"></p><p>Disqus <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/12/05/zeta-global-acquires-commenting-service-disqus/">was acquired</a> by an advertising company called Zeta Global in 2017. Obviously, advertising companies do everything to increase their revenue (Ex: the Big G).</p><p>I analyzed the network requests log. Disqus makes HTTP requests to 11 different third-party domains through the browser. <strong>All of these websites are trackers/pixels</strong> (Even some were detected as malware by my security guard).</p><p>Here are the external domains:</p><ul><li><a href="https://viglink.com/">viglink.com</a>* - One of Disqus's major partners. Disqus use Viglink to personalize ads.</li><li><a href="http://io.narrative.io/">io.narrative.io</a> - "The data streaming platform that makes it easy to buy, sell, and win."</li><li><a href="http://live.rezync.com/">live.rezync.com</a> - a pixel website</li><li><a href="https://idsync.rlcdn.com/">idsync.rlcdn.com</a> - another pixel (website returns 404)</li><li><a href="https://netc.sfr.fr/">netc.sfr.fr</a> - another pixel (website returns 404)</li><li><a href="https://p.rfihub.com/">p.rfihub.com</a> - another pixel, malware reports on Google (website returns 404)</li><li><a href="https://pixel.tapad.com/">pixel.tapad.com</a> - pixel, main site titled "WE PROVIDE THE WORLD’S LEADING DIGITAL CROSS-DEVICE GRAPH"</li><li><a href="http://pippio.com/">pippio.com</a> - redirects to liveramp.com, titled "Build better data-driven customer experiences."</li><li><a href="https://ei.rlcdn.com/">ei.rlcdn.com</a>, <a href="https://idsync.rlcdn.com/">idsync.rlcdn.com</a> - website returns 404, GIF pixel used</li><li><a href="http://tag.clrstm.com/">tag.clrstm.com</a></li><li><a href="https://ib.adnxs.com/">ib.adnxs.com</a> - Malware site, "Adnxs appeared as the eighth-biggest name in our Tracking the Trackers data."</li></ul><p>If you are not familiar with Pixels/Trackers, take Facebook as an example. You can place a pixel on your website to share your website traffic data with Facebook. Facebook uses this data for better personalized targeting. According to GDPR, you cannot place the code without your users' consent in the EU region. But, Disqus places all of these pixels on your website (inside their iframe) without any consent.</p><p>*In 2014, Disqus inserted Viglink affiliate links to their client sites intrusively (<a href="https://poststatus.com/disqus-potentially-adding-affiliate-links-users-content-opted/">Source</a>)</p><p>When you provide a free product, money should come from somewhere. Disqus uses advertising for that. Now, I subscribed to a paid plan trial of Disqus to see if things change or not. No! Even in the paid plans, the same pixels are loaded on the client-side. Looks like there's no way to opt-out from tracking.</p><p>Even I title the article "the dark commenting system", I'm not sure if Disqus is a commenting system. Journalist Martin Gundersen once called Disqus a "data machine".</p><blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Uncovering the Disqus data machine: <a href="https://twitter.com/disqus?ref_src=twsrc^tfw">@disqus</a> shared the personal data of tens of millions of users without them or the websites knowing about it. thread - 1/13 <a href="https://t.co/bLW4Gl2Rhf">pic.twitter.com/bLW4Gl2Rhf</a></p>— Martin Gundersen (@martingund) <a href="https://twitter.com/martingund/status/1207327648093003777?ref_src=twsrc^tfw">December 18, 2019</a></blockquote>  <p>As I stated earlier, Disqus is owned by data/ad company ("Data-driven marketing powered by AI"). This is a large company with more than <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/marketing-software-firm-zeta-global-eyes-ipoonce-again-11583348234">$400 million in annual revenue</a>. They own the "The Web's Largest First-Party Data Set". While Disqus allows third parties like Viglink to directly access your website, they also collect information by themselves and shares them with more third-parties. Twitter has also been one of their old customers. (see <a href="https://data.disqus.com/">data.disqus.com</a>)</p><p>Actually, you give them the consent when you agree to their <a href="https://help.disqus.com/en/articles/1717103-disqus-privacy-policy">privacy policy</a>.</p><div><p> "Advertising is the predominant way Disqus makes money. Advertising revenue allows Disqus to support and improve the Service. Disqus uses, and also engages third party ad partners and affiliates who use cookie IDs, device IDs (including mobile), hashed email addresses, IP address, ISP and browser information, demographic or interest data, content viewed and actions taken on the Service or Partner Sites, including information about the websites you’ve viewed and advertisements you’ve interacted within order to provide you with more relevant advertising targeted to your preferences and interests derived from your interaction with the Service, Partner Sites or other third party websites." </p><p> "We partner with third parties that collect information across various channels, including offline and online, for purposes of delivering more relevant advertising to you or your business. Our partners use this information to recognize you across different channels and platforms, including but not limited to, computers, mobile devices, over time for advertising (including addressable TV), analytics, attribution, and reporting purposes." - Disqus Privacy Policy</p></div><h3 id="considerprivacyfirstalternatives">Consider Privacy-First Alternatives</h3><p>If you are currently using Disqus on your website and value your user's privacy, consider migrating from Disqus to a privacy-first commenting system. One such service is <a href="https://talk.hyvor.com/">Hyvor Talk</a>, which I founded as a hobby project and now has grown into a profitable SaaS business in less than one year (with 3 employees and growing). At the time of writing this article, we serve 30 million page views per month and provide our privacy-first service for 2000 customers. You can also <a href="https://talk.hyvor.com/docs/import-disqus">import your old Disqus comments</a> to Hyvor Talk.</p><blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I got so fed up with <a href="https://twitter.com/disqus?ref_src=twsrc^tfw">@disqus</a>'s obnoxious ads and disregard for privacy that I finally migrated the comments of my main blog (<a href="https://t.co/2gUgV3yVEM">https://t.co/2gUgV3yVEM</a>) to <a href="https://twitter.com/HyvorTalk?ref_src=twsrc^tfw">@HyvorTalk</a>, a comment system that actual values your privacy. I highly recommend you to do the same!</p>— Bozhidar Batsov (Bug) (@bbatsov) <a href="https://twitter.com/bbatsov/status/1335891387489914880?ref_src=twsrc^tfw">December 7, 2020</a></blockquote>  <p>Feel free to leave a comment below if you have any questions.</p>  <p><strong>Tagged</strong>:
<span>Privacy</span></p></div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://supunkavinda.blog/disqus</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26033052</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 04:17:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Great SameSite Confusion]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 56 | Comments 19 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26032896">thread link</a>) | @arkadiyt
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | https://jub0bs.com/posts/2021-01-29-great-samesite-confusion/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jub0bs.com/posts/2021-01-29-great-samesite-confusion/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                <p>In this post,
I dissect a common misconception about the <code>SameSite</code> cookie attribute
and I explore its potential impact on Web security.</p>
<h2 id="tldr">TL;DR <a href="#tldr">¶</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The <code>SameSite</code> cookie attribute is not well understood.</li>
<li>Conflating <em>site</em> and <em>origin</em> is a common but harmful mistake.</li>
<li>The concept of <em>site</em> is more difficult to apprehend than meets the eye.</li>
<li>Some requests are cross-origin but same-site.</li>
<li><code>SameSite</code> is only concerned with cross-site requests.</li>
<li><code>SameSite</code> paints a target on your subdomains' back.</li>
<li>Misguided practitioners may unduly eschew <code>SameSite=Strict</code>.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="the-advent-of-samesite">The advent of <code>SameSite</code> <a href="#the-advent-of-samesite">¶</a></h2>
<p>You have no doubt heard of the
<a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-us/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Set-Cookie/SameSite" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><code>SameSite</code> cookie attribute</a>.
It made headlines when, in February 2020,
Chrome started rolling out changes to <code>SameSite</code>’s default behaviour;
Firefox <a href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2020/08/changes-to-samesite-cookie-behavior/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">followed suit</a> a few months later.</p>
<p>Intended as a defense-in-depth mechanism against cross-site attacks,
such as <a href="https://owasp.org/www-community/attacks/csrf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cross-site request forgery (CSRF)</a>
and <a href="https://www.scip.ch/en/?labs.20160414" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cross-site script inclusion (XSSI)</a>,
<code>SameSite</code> had been lying dormant at the heart of implementing browsers
since <a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/draft-west-first-party-cookies-07" target="_blank" rel="noopener">its inception in 2016</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://blog.chromium.org/2020/02/samesite-cookie-changes-in-february.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><code>SameSite</code>’s activation in early 2020</a>
required labourious adjustments
by some websites to maintain third-party access,
but was widely hailed as a welcome addition to browser defences.
Both in anticipation and in reaction to <code>SameSite</code>’s activation in browsers,
posts started
sprouting on blogs all over the Web to spread the word
about the mechanics of the “new” cookie attribute.</p>
<h2 id="playing-fast-and-loose-with-terminology">Playing fast and loose with terminology <a href="#playing-fast-and-loose-with-terminology">¶</a></h2>
<p>Some of those posts were of admirable precision,
such as <a href="https://twitter.com/rowan_m" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rowan Merewood</a>’s <a href="https://web.dev/samesite-cookies-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">web.dev piece</a>
entitled “SameSite cookies explained”.
Unfortunately, relatively few of the posts about <code>SameSite</code>
went to the effort of clarifying the concept of <em>site</em>,
from which the concepts of <em>same-site request</em> and <em>cross-site request</em>
are of course derived.</p>
<p>Moreover, many posts,
including those produced by influential members of the infosec community,
appeared to use the terms “origin” and “site” interchangeably or, at least,
somewhat loosely.</p>
<p>Back in February 2019, Kristian Bremberg <a href="https://blog.detectify.com/2019/02/05/guide-http-security-headers-for-better-web-browser-security/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote the following</a>
on the venerable Detectify blog:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The SameSite attribute is rather new and provides excellent protection
against CSRF attacks. If a cookie uses the SameSite attribute,
the web browser will make sure that the request made with the cookie came
from the <strong>origin</strong> that sat [sic] the cookie.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>(my emphasis)</p>
<p>Infosec superstar <a href="https://twitter.com/troyhunt" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Troy Hunt</a> himself,
in <a href="https://www.troyhunt.com/promiscuous-cookies-and-their-impending-death-via-the-samesite-policy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a seminal post</a> entitled
“Promiscuous Cookies and Their Impending Death via the SameSite Policy”
and published in early January 2020, described the effects of the different
<code>SameSite</code> attribute values as follows:</p>
<blockquote>
<ol>
<li>None: what Chrome defaults to today without a SameSite value set</li>
<li>Lax: some limits on sending cookies on a <strong>cross-origin</strong> request</li>
<li>Strict: tight limits on sending cookies on a <strong>cross-origin</strong> request</li>
</ol>
</blockquote>
<p>(my emphasis)</p>
<p>And a few months later, in an otherwise fascinating <a href="https://blog.reconless.com/samesite-by-default/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">post</a>
analysing how the advent of <code>SameSite</code> was affecting a range of vulnerabilities
cherished by hackers,
the <a href="https://twitter.com/0xReconless" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reconless team</a> wrote the following:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>After the update, all cookies without an explicit <code>SameSite</code> attribute will
be treated as having <code>SameSite=Lax</code>.
This means <strong>cross-origin</strong> requests no longer carry cookies,
except for top-level navigations.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>(my emphasis)</p>
<p><em>Domain</em>, <em>host</em>, <em>origin</em>, <em>site</em>…
Using those terms loosely in informal communication is natural;
such laxity in the use of terminology can be forgiven,
and if you’ve been guilty of it yourself, you’re in good company.</p>
<h2 id="are-site-and-origin-interchangeable">Are “site” and “origin” interchangeable? <a href="#are-site-and-origin-interchangeable">¶</a></h2>
<p>However, the advent of the <code>SameSite</code> cookie attribute raises some questions…</p>
<ul>
<li>Is a careful distinction between “origin” and “site” warranted, here?</li>
<li>Is it just a distinction without a difference?</li>
<li>Is a <em>cross-site</em> request no different from a <em>cross-origin</em> request?</li>
<li>Could the cookie attribute have as well been named “SameOrigin”, then?</li>
<li>Or, if there is indeed a real difference between “site” and “origin”,
does it matter to practitioners?</li>
<li>And, if the difference does matter, how so?</li>
</ul>
<p>You may have already guessed the answers from the title of this post:
“site” has a very technical meaning in the context of <code>SameSite</code>,
yet it is unduly neglected;
and the distinction between <em>site</em> and <em>origin</em> <em>does</em> matter,
yet the two concepts are frequently conflated.</p>
<p>This lapse in terminology didn’t escape everyone.
That Google’s <em>Developer Advocate of Web</em> <a href="https://twitter.com/agektmr" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Eiji Kitamura</a>
felt the need to dedicate
a whole <a href="https://web.dev/same-site-same-origin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">blog post</a>
about the distinction between “origin” and “site”,
only a few months after Chrome activated <code>SameSite</code>, is revealing.</p>
<p>In order to understand why the distinction matters,
you first need to understand the difference between <em>origin</em> and <em>site</em>.</p>
<h2 id="what-do-we-mean-by-origin">What do we mean by “origin”? <a href="#what-do-we-mean-by-origin">¶</a></h2>
<p>If you work with Web technologies,
you have at least some familiarity with the
<a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Security/Same-origin_policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Same-Origin Policy (SOP)</a>,
arguably one of the main pillar of Web security.
The concept of <em>origin</em> of a URI is of course central to the SOP and,
as such, it is relatively well-understood.
<a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc6454#section-3.2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Section 3.2 of RFC 6454</a> defines an <em>origin</em> as a triple:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Roughly speaking, two URIs are part of the same origin
(i.e., represent the same principal) if they have the same
scheme, host, and port.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The port is optional; if not specified, the default port associated to the scheme
is implied (e.g. 80 for <code>http</code> and 443 for <code>https</code>).
<a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-us/docs/Glossary/Origin" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MDN Web Docs</a> has a series of useful examples.</p>
<h2 id="what-do-we-mean-by-site">What do we mean by “site”? <a href="#what-do-we-mean-by-site">¶</a></h2>
<p>Behind the painfully generic term that is “site”
hides a concept fundamentally more difficult to grasp
than that of <em>origin</em>.
For one thing, the term “site” was not always a technical one:
it predates the SOP and was in in common use
<a href="https://blog.jeremiahgrossman.com/2006/07/origins-of-cross-site-scripting-xss.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">when attacks like cross-site scripting came onto the scene</a>.
Furthermore, the modern concept of <em>site</em> is fraught with technical difficulties.
It is intimately linked to that of a host’s <em>registrable domain</em>,
which the <a href="https://url.spec.whatwg.org/#host-registrable-domain" target="_blank" rel="noopener">URL Living Standard</a> defines as</p>
<blockquote>
<p>[…] a domain formed by the most specific public suffix,
along with the domain label immediately preceeding it, if any.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>(A host’s registrable domain is also known as its “eTLD+1”, short for
“effective top-level domain plus one”.)</p>
<p>In the simplest of cases, <strong>the site of an origin simply corresponds
to the registrable domain (if any) of the origin’s host</strong>.</p>
<p>Two examples, to fix ideas:</p>
<ul>
<li>The site of <code>https://www.example.org</code> is <code>example.org</code>,
because <code>org</code> is the host’s most specific public suffix
and, therefore, <code>example.org</code> is the host’s eTLD+1.</li>
<li>The site of <code>https://jub0bs.github.io</code> is <code>jub0bs.github.io</code>,
because <code>github.io</code> is the host’s most specific public suffix
and, therefore, <code>jub0bs.github.io</code> is the host’s eTLD+1.</li>
</ul>
<p>Yes! Perhaps surprisingly, <a href="https://publicsuffix.org/list/public_suffix_list.dat" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><code>github.io</code> is a public suffix</a>!</p>
<p>It’s worth noting, however, that the concept of registrable domain is a fluid one,
because it relies on the <a href="https://publicsuffix.org/list/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Public-Suffix List</a>,
a list which is not set in stone but <a href="https://github.com/publicsuffix/list/blob/master/public_suffix_list.dat" target="_blank" rel="noopener">subject to change over time</a>.
Not to mention that different browsers may not necessarily stay abreast of
changes to the Public-Suffix list at the same pace.</p>
<p>The technicalities do not end there!
As <a href="https://web.dev/schemeful-samesite/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">web.dev warns us</a>,
the concept of <em>site</em> is still evolving and
will soon incorporate the scheme also.
The change currently sits behind a flag in Chrome but will soon be rolled out.
However, to sidestep this difficulty and prolong the relevance of this post,
I’ll only consider origins whose scheme is <code>https</code> in what follows.</p>
<h2 id="same-site-vs-cross-site-requests">Same-site vs. cross-site requests <a href="#same-site-vs-cross-site-requests">¶</a></h2>
<p>Now that we’ve dealt with the concept of <em>site</em>,
we can finally discuss the concepts of <em>same-site</em> and <em>cross-site</em> requests.
A given request is either <em>same-site</em> or <em>cross-site</em>.
Whether a request is same-site or cross-site depends on the comparison
between the sites of the request’s source origin and target origin:</p>
<ul>
<li>If the two sites are identical, the request is said to be <em>same-site</em>;</li>
<li>If the two sites are different, the request is said to be <em>cross-site</em>.</li>
</ul>
<p>Here are three examples:</p>
<ol>
<li>A request sent from <code>https://foo.example.org</code> to <code>https://bar.example.org</code>
is same-site,
because the site of both origins is <code>example.org</code>.</li>
<li>A request sent from <code>https://foo.github.io</code>
to <code>https://bar.github.io</code> is cross-site,
because the site of the first origin is <code>foo.github.io</code>,
whereas the site of the second origin is <code>bar.github.io</code>.</li>
<li>A request sent from <code>https://foo.bar.example.org</code> to <code>https://bar.example.org</code>
is same-site, because the site of both origins is <code>example.org</code>.</li>
</ol>
<p>If you’ve made it this far down the present post, I thank you for your patience.
Take heart: the payoff is near!</p>
<h2 id="cross-origin-same-site-requests">Cross-origin, same-site requests <a href="#cross-origin-same-site-requests">¶</a></h2>
<p>All cross-site requests are necessarily cross-origin; that much is clear.
However, as shown by the first and third examples above,
not all cross-origin requests are cross-site.</p>
<p><img src="https://jub0bs.com/images/cor_vs_csr.svg" alt="Venn-diagram"></p>
<p>And the <code>SameSite</code> cookie attribute is only concerned with cross-site requests;
it has no effect on cross-origin requests that happen to be same-site.
This is why the distinction between <em>origin</em> and <em>site</em> is important.</p>
<h2 id="online-demo">Online demo <a href="#online-demo">¶</a></h2>
<p>To prove my point,
I’ve drawn inspiration from <a href="https://www.troyhunt.com/promiscuous-cookies-and-their-impending-death-via-the-samesite-policy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Troy Hunt’s post</a> and
I’ve deployed a simple Go server to <code>samesitedemo.jub0bs.com</code> composed
of two simple endpoints.
Endpoint <code>/setcookie</code> sets a <code>SameSite=Strict</code> cookie, like so</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="http"><span>Set-Cookie: StrictCookie=foo; Path=/; Max-Age=3600; SameSite=Strict
</span></code></pre></div><p>Endpoint <code>/readcookie</code> prints the cookie (if any) attached to the request.
I’ve also set up two “attacking” pages:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://jub0bs.github.io/samesitedemo-attacker-foiled" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://jub0bs.github.io/samesitedemo-attacker-foiled</a></li>
<li><a href="https://samesitedemo-attacker.jub0bs.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://samesitedemo-attacker.jub0bs.com/</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Both pages simply consist in a single link to
<code>https://samesitedemo.jub0bs.com/readcookie</code>.</p>
<p>To fix ideas, here’s what you can do:</p>
<ol>
<li>Navigate to
<a href="https://samesitedemo.jub0bs.com/setcookie" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://samesitedemo.jub0bs.com/setcookie</a>.
Doing so will set the <code>Strict</code> cookie in your browser.</li>
<li>Navigate to
<a href="https://jub0bs.github.io/samesitedemo-attacker-foiled" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://jub0bs.github.io/samesitedemo-attacker-foiled</a>
and follow the link on that page.
Because the site of the attacking URI (<code>jub0bs.github.io</code>)
is different from that of the target URI (<code>jub0bs.com</code>),
the browser does not attach the cookie to the request resulting from
following the link, and no cookie gets printed in the response.
<code>SameSite=Strict</code> works as expected, and the “attack” is foiled.</li>
<li>Now navigate to
<a href="https://samesitedemo-attacker.jub0bs.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://samesitedemo-attacker.jub0bs.com/</a>
and follow the link on that page.
Because the site of the …</li></ol></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://jub0bs.com/posts/2021-01-29-great-samesite-confusion/">https://jub0bs.com/posts/2021-01-29-great-samesite-confusion/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jub0bs.com/posts/2021-01-29-great-samesite-confusion/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26032896</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 03:51:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Road to Utopia: A manifesto for reclaiming a humanist future (2020)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 49 | Comments 94 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26032587">thread link</a>) | @durakot
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | https://culture.io/manifesto | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://culture.io/manifesto">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<div>
<article id="1892">
<section id=""><div>
<h2>☼</h2>
<p><span>A manifesto for<br>
</span></p>
<p><span><span>reclaiming a humanist future.</span></span></p>
</div>
<div><figure>
<picture data-loaded="false"><source data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/hills-dither.png" media="(min-width: 1000px)">
<source data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/hills-dither-682x1024.png, https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/hills-dither.png 2x" media="(min-width: 400px)">
<img src="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/hills-dither-33x50.png" data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/hills-dither-341x512.png, https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/hills-dither-682x1024.png 2x" alt="Image" width="1992" height="2992">
</picture>
</figure></div>
</section>
<section id=""><div><h3><strong>Introduction</strong></h3>
<blockquote>
<p><span><em>“Bathed in light, the world remains our first and last love.” —Albert Camus</em></span></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Anyone writing seriously about utopia in September of 2020 will seem—to be charitable—a little disconnected from reality.</p>
<p>The American West is burning. The Arctic is melting. Populism and authoritarianism are on the rise. Nearly a million people have died from the coronavirus. Economic inequality continues to grow, only accelerated by the pandemic.</p>
<p>If there’s anything like a road to utopia—if we can even begin to entertain such an idea—we don’t seem to be on it. The belief that society’s problems can be solved seems ridiculous when each day brings fresh horrors. Our collective failure to make so much as a dent on climate change, the cancerous spread of polarizing misinformation with its fracturing of society, and the irretrievable damage we are inflicting on the biosphere, only deepen a sense that the best we can hope for now is adaptation and survival in an environment increasingly hostile (physically, psychologically, spiritually) to the individual.</p>
<p>But hope, as “Mad” Max Rockatansky <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MaN4sboc7E8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reminds us from the other side of collapse</a>, is a mistake, and despair paralyzes. What we need are viable alternatives. Alternatives that go beyond bolt-on fixes to broken systems. Alternatives we can imagine living—and thriving—in. And most importantly, alternatives we can look for in our present and in our past, not in some idealized future.</p>
<p>Utopia is in the air again, though few dare call it by that name. Ideas that would be dismissed just a few short years ago as “utopian”—a word that has been cut down to pejorative status—are entering into the mainstream. Political programs like the Green New Deal promise solutions that could spare us from the worst effects of climate change while stimulating the economy. Universal Basic Income and its brethren suggest how we might mend broken social safety nets and ease economic inequality. But what we lack, and urgently need, is a vision of the world we want to bring into being. That’s all utopianism is: the audacity to imagine the world we want, and then living as though that world were possible.</p>
<p>Metals become malleable when subjected to heat. In higher temperatures, they melt, making it possible to cast existing forms into new shapes. Culture I/O is premised on a belief that under certain conditions, the malleability of our society increases as well. The coming decade, more than any other in recent memory, will be turbulent and heated. In the words of Arundhati Roy: <em>“We can choose to walk through it, dragging the carcasses of our prejudice and hatred, our avarice, our data banks and dead ideas, our dead rivers and smoky skies behind us. Or we can walk through lightly, with little luggage, ready to imagine another world. And ready to fight for it.”</em> </p>
<p>The Culture I/O Working Group<br>
Los Angeles &amp; Berlin, 09/2020</p>
</div>
</section>
<section id=""><div><blockquote>
<p><span><em>“If you wish to make an apple pie from scratch, you must first invent the universe.” —Carl Sagan</em></span></p>
</blockquote>
<p>A guide to utopia has to start with a foundation of all the concepts feeding into it: ourselves, nature, technology, society, and the other Big Things. It’s easier to go on a journey together if we all leave from the same place.</p>
</div>

</section>
<section id="individuals"><div><h3><span>1. Individuals</span></h3>
<blockquote>
<p><span><em>“I am neither a liberal nor a conservative…. My holy of holies is the human body, health, intelligence, talent, inspiration, love, and absolute freedom.” —Anton Chekhov</em></span></p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>A society consists of individuals. Only individuals suffer, experience joy, love, longing, pleasure, pain, act with intent, die. They can do so collectively, but always and only as individuals. <strong>In the end, only individuals matter.</strong></li>
<li>This is an ontological position, not a value judgement. A family or society exists only insofar as its individual members exist.</li>
<li>Because of this, we should reject any ideology that stresses the primacy of a group at the expense of individuals.</li>
<li>Similarly, we should reject any ideology that places a system (such as markets) above individuals.</li>
<li>This should not be taken as an endorsement of individualism. Individuals do not exist in isolation. The point is simply that we should always treat individuals as <em>ends</em>, never as <em>means</em>.</li>
<li>Humans are complex, emotional, self-aware animals with a degree of free will—not rational agents, logic machines, or biological algorithms.</li>
<li>Humans are not the only complex, emotional, self-aware animals on this planet.</li>
<li>The quickest path to dooming any human undertaking is to assume that we can become, or even reliably pretend to be, anything other than what we are—both at our best and at our worst.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div><figure>
<picture data-loaded="false"><source data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/12050980663_2aea498c77_b-e1604267228399.jpg" media="(min-width: 1000px)">
<source data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/12050980663_2aea498c77_b-e1604267228399.jpg, https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/12050980663_2aea498c77_b-e1604267228399.jpg 2x" media="(min-width: 400px)">
<img src="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/12050980663_2aea498c77_b-e1604267228399-40x50.jpg" data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/12050980663_2aea498c77_b-e1604267228399-412x512.jpg, https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/12050980663_2aea498c77_b-e1604267228399.jpg 2x" alt="Image" width="544" height="676">
</picture>
</figure></div>
</section>
<section id="minds"><div><h3><span>2. Minds</span></h3>
<blockquote>
<p><span><em>“Use your head, can’t you, use your head, you’re on earth, there’s no cure for that!” —Samuel Beckett</em></span></p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>The human brain is the most mysterious and versatile physical structure in the known world. We know more about how the universe came to be than how the brain works.</li>
<li>The nature of the relationship between brain, mind, and consciousness is the greatest scientific question of our time.</li>
<li>Though we are emotional creatures first and foremost, we are wired for reason. Using only his mind and some crude observations, Aristarchus of the Greek island of Samos figured out that the Earth orbits the Sun almost 2,000 years before this became accepted fact. Einstein produced four of his groundbreaking papers in one year spent hunched over a desk in a musty Bern patent office, with reason as his only instrument.</li>
<li>In spite of these impressive abilities, we are extremely susceptible to biases and fallacies in our thinking—and to those who would exploit these biases.</li>
<li>The either/or fallacy is one of the most pernicious of these errors, passed down to us by Aristotle. It suggests that everything must be either this, or that. Good or bad. Nature or nurture. Introvert or extrovert. Liberal or conservative. It is the binary logic of machines applied to an analog world full of semantic nuance, contradiction, and mystery. If we are, on a species-level, in trouble, it is in large part because of our inability to internalize the fact that multiple ideas which seem opposed to each other can simultaneously be true.</li>
<li>This does not mean that truth is relative. It isn’t. Only that out in the world, truth is more complicated than it seems. If we simplify the world in order to function in it, we do so at our peril.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div><figure>
<picture data-loaded="false"><source data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/CC0-img-119-e1604267877321.jpg" media="(min-width: 1000px)">
<source data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/CC0-img-119-e1604267877321-768x1024.jpg, https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/CC0-img-119-e1604267877321.jpg 2x" media="(min-width: 400px)">
<img src="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/CC0-img-119-e1604267877321-38x50.jpg" data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/CC0-img-119-e1604267877321-384x512.jpg, https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/CC0-img-119-e1604267877321-768x1024.jpg 2x" alt="Image" width="1920" height="2560">
</picture>
</figure></div>
</section>
<section id="language"><div><h3><span>3. Language</span></h3>
<blockquote>
<p><span><em>“The map is not the territory.” —Alfred Korzybski</em></span></p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Words are not reality—they represent abstractions that allow us to make sense of reality, to think and talk about it.</li>
<li>This is important because it means that words do not and cannot map perfectly to reality, and that different languages—systems of words—can reflect reality in subtly different ways.</li>
<li>Words matter. Words and mind are inextricably linked and together they create the feedback loop that makes reasoning possible.</li>
<li>The abuse of language is a form of psychological abuse. George Orwell memorably took it to task in <a href="https://www.orwellfoundation.com/the-orwell-foundation/orwell/essays-and-other-works/politics-and-the-english-language/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Politics and the English Language</em></a> three quarters of a century ago, but we’ve been at it for much, much longer. What is new is the degree to which words have saturated our lives. Social media and 24 hour news have made it impossible to escape.</li>
<li>Precision and clarity are how we push back against the abuse of language. Because we use words to think, choosing them with care leads to clearer arguments and thoughts. We should always strive to practice good linguistic hygiene, and to use language in good faith—for our own sanity, if nothing else.</li>
<li>Where pushing back is impossible, we must step away. Silence can be a virtue.</li>
<li>The only way to have a productive discussion involving abstractions (democracy, justice, utopia) is to clearly and rigorously define them first. Often we’ll find that the discussion ends up fixating on the definitions of the words themselves. This is a good thing.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div><figure>
<picture data-loaded="false"><source data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/11/2952px-Pieter_Bruegel_the_Elder_-_The_Tower_of_Babel-scaled.jpg" media="(min-width: 1000px)">
<source data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/11/2952px-Pieter_Bruegel_the_Elder_-_The_Tower_of_Babel-1024x749.jpg, https://api.culture.io/static/2020/11/2952px-Pieter_Bruegel_the_Elder_-_The_Tower_of_Babel-scaled.jpg 2x" media="(min-width: 400px)">
<img src="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/11/2952px-Pieter_Bruegel_the_Elder_-_The_Tower_of_Babel-50x37.jpg" data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/11/2952px-Pieter_Bruegel_the_Elder_-_The_Tower_of_Babel-512x375.jpg, https://api.culture.io/static/2020/11/2952px-Pieter_Bruegel_the_Elder_-_The_Tower_of_Babel-1024x749.jpg 2x" alt="Image" width="2560" height="1873">
</picture>
</figure></div>
</section>
<section id="systems"><div><h3><span>4. Systems</span></h3>
<blockquote>
<p><em><span>“The Matrix is everywhere. It is all around us. Even now, in this very room. You can see it when you look out your window or when you turn on your television.” —Morpheus</span></em></p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>We are surrounded by and enmeshed in systems.</li>
<li>Thinking in terms of systems helps us to make sense of a chaotic and unpredictable world.</li>
<li>Societies are systems. Culture is a system. Governments, markets, weather, language, and the biosphere are all examples of systems.</li>
<li>Some complex systems are too big and too complicated to think about coherently. We call these types of systems <em><strong>hyperobjects</strong></em>.</li>
<li>Complex systems can be broken down into simpler ones for the purpose of thinking about them.</li>
<li>It’s possible to understand how a system works without being able to make accurate predictions about it. But we should be wary of our tendency to believe that we understand systems which we do not.</li>
<li>It’s impossible to make accurate long-term predictions about most complex systems.</li>
<li>Some systems tend towards stability through self-regulation, while others are inherently unstable.</li>
<li>It’s not necessary to understand how a system works before acting to change it. In fact, history is the story of humans collectively changing or dismantling systems before understanding them—often with serious consequences (like climate). But a system must be understood in order to effectively change it <em>with a specific outcome in mind</em>.</li>
<li>It’s unproductive to approach systems dogmatically. No system is inherently good or bad. But we should evaluate systems, especially those created by humans, based on our convictions about what is desirable and undesirable.</li>
<li>Most complex systems are interwoven with others and cannot be fully understood in isolation.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div><figure>
<picture data-loaded="false"><source data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/systems.png" media="(min-width: 1000px)">
<source data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/systems-1024x1024.png, https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/systems.png 2x" media="(min-width: 400px)">
<img src="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/systems-50x50.png" data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/systems-512x512.png, https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/systems-1024x1024.png 2x" alt="Image" width="2440" height="2440">
</picture>
</figure></div>
</section>
<section id="rules"><div><h3><span>5. Rules<br>
</span></h3>
<blockquote>
<p><em><span>“The creation of rules is more creative than the destruction of them. Creation demands a higher level of reasoning and draws connections between cause and effect. The best rules are never stable or permanent, but evolve, naturally according to content or need.” —Andrea Zittel</span></em></p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>All systems are governed by rules. Nature provides an immutable set of rules, in the form of physics. These rules cannot be broken.</li>
<li>Science is the system we use to learn about nature’s …</li></ul></div></section></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://culture.io/manifesto">https://culture.io/manifesto</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://culture.io/manifesto</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26032587</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 03:05:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What Google recruiters look for in a technical resume]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 35 | Comments 66 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26030737">thread link</a>) | @mcenedella
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | https://leetresumes.com/blog/what-google-recruiters-look-for-in-a-technical-resume | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://leetresumes.com/blog/what-google-recruiters-look-for-in-a-technical-resume">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content"><div><div><p>Google technical recruiter Jeremy Ong and colleague Lizi Lopez created a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BYUy1yvjHxE">video</a> providing Google’s advice for resumes, both technical and non-technical. At Leet Resumes, we write <a href="https://leetresumes.com/">experienced engineers’ resumes for free</a>, so we thought we’d share and compare Google’s advice with our own, show where they mostly line up, and show where your resume needs to appeal to employers beyond Google. Given our focus, we’ll concentrate on how this advice applies to experienced technical or engineering professionals.</p><p>With three exceptions, the Google recruiters’ advice matches up with Leet Resumes’ advice, and I’ll explain why their advice is so very accurate, and also where we differ and why (the Google way is not everybody’s way). Further, we explain our design choices in detail in our <a href="https://leetresumes.com/blog/leet-resumes-technical-resume-documentation%C2%A0">documentation</a>.&nbsp;</p><p><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/41QpzF22JQx1YWrqtbdI56bA9Tp4VDHJlk6zX3z0Zk1T3PfU-chPyOcDFcCefMOOOIdxjJZOkOktgrpXBtUiitjiiluKsA7BSY0BeOOaccP_D8jWO6hndjFKtUOJDzUojsL0-dCp" alt="Google's resume advice"></p><p>First off, Jeremy and Lizi advise, “Make sure the format is simple and consistent in design, font, sizing, and spacing throughout so that the person reviewing your resume can easily scan and find information quickly.”</p><p>This sounds like obvious advice, but many engineers complicate their resumes with colors, columns, graphics, multiple fonts, font colors, and font sizes, that they put a tremendous burden on the people reading their resumes. Simple is better.</p><p><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/tv3HpXghtb62OxzGg0kDxdHB9icAzEmefiNvqiu-oRsy-rqXTshmq0a-Bn0L0Ll-mIf-Uxa1EYNyvVHmB2-m0UH-iw3_HaIh_9CNwBbJU-_LWRqK8tuKpdVWcX7Sw98F6Isrndrk" alt="Google's Resume Basics"></p><p>They continue, “Include your contact information and email at the top. You don't have to include objective statements [or] references. Use bullet points with consistent formatting and structure throughout the resume rather than long paragraphs.&nbsp;</p><p>“Keep your resume to… no longer than two pages for engineering roles. And perhaps the most important tip we have overall is to always check for typos.”</p><p>We agree with all of this advice at Leet. Bullet points and quick, scannable text are far superior to long paragraphs. It’s how readers ingest resumes in 2021.</p><p>On resume length, in our <a href="https://leetresumes.com/blog/leet-resumes-technical-resume-documentation%C2%A0">documentation</a>, we advise 1 page for those with 10 years’ or fewer experience, and 2 pages for those with 10 or more years of experience.</p><p>Typos might seem like a small matter, but many engineering managers have learned that engineers who aren’t careful with their resumes, also aren’t careful with their code. Be smart about it and check very carefully.</p><p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/VFrSANgZ36uEfJ41lzjU8mNBtKwQW9i1lYqONH1QTq51yYw94r6TauDAjsjnJr2QPOZXPeiZTdrHRBrUcjR2NdBvusvD6rDQukbbOElz7FxaIiYwJaMRBtVMIPhZqDEK625_R2hs" alt="Google Resume Basics: Lengths"></p><p>Lizi and Jeremy continue, “It's also critical you list your GitHub profile or other prominent open source work that shows us you're contributing to the open source community, passionate about the work you're doing, and looking to improve your skills.”</p><p>We agree that your Github link should be in your contact information, and that your LinkedIn (which is a subset of your resume info, and therefore extraneous) should not be.</p><p>Jeremy and Lizi further comment that, “Experience should take up the bulk of your resume.”</p><p>Another obvious point, perhaps, but the most popular formats online, including those at the top of Google search results for software engineering resume template, break this good advice. These complex formats often push the experience section into as little as 25% of the available surface area of a resume. Again, simple is better.</p><p><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/P5XdrU6yP7ny6VNex_pCz7s3iuLbHuWZFfzvhB9of3mF_LKl9WN4jBKO7wuYoJ8wiMa8KHg8we-irDUWmE0EvBPPCAOZ471Dk7ITzqIttWRxc2n_4J-pZZk0FQcIWNxkXd3h5KVL" alt="Google Resume Advice: Experience"></p><p>The Google duo share: “List everything in reverse chronological order with your most recent experience first. Include your employer, position, and dates employed for all jobs… in the month-year format. Keep your bullet point descriptions concise and clear, and make the most of your space by streamlining bullet points that spill over onto the next line by only one or two words.”</p><p>Again, we agree and the resumes we write for experienced engineers follow these same guidelines. Concise and clear is usually a problem for engineers writing their own resumes, and that’s where Leet can be a big help in cutting out words, phrases, and even whole bullets that don’t advance your story.</p><p>“For each bullet, use action words like created, designed, debugged, negotiated, developed, managed, and so on, so the person reading your resume can easily and quickly understand your skills and experience.”</p><p>At Leet, we go further and suggest that you use success verbs - verbs that show how your work created successes - rather than simply using verbs such as managed or developed, which are more focused on duties and responsibilities instead of outcomes.&nbsp;</p><p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/yXV2gqPytpBnWWAETYkNC0dIysQ4DTUjMzKtasBMyzvIlwAVR_aXM_EVUmNAcLNpXQFJZRlxihRFc91s9HK2o3Zg1exQ9cESP6hEzXFdIUrnSLrggUNPCi74z5QVMTcgJMnU1vHk" alt="null"></p><p>“It's important to focus on the results and impact of your work, so list metrics and examples concisely rather than writing long descriptions. We value data at Google and want to see you know how to apply it when speaking to your accomplishments. Use data and comparisons or averages to provide context.</p><p>“To ensure you focus on results and impact in this section, we recommend using this helpful framework – accomplished X as measured by Y by doing Z.”</p><p>Google is exactly right on this advice - use data, numbers, and metrics, to explain your results. Instead of writing that you reduced page load time, write that you reduced page load time from 700 ms to 322 ms. Numbers make your accomplishments seem more real, and are more persuasive.</p><p>Lizi continues, “Let's walk through a few examples for different types of experience.”</p><p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/rGmPHOn7Y7NP4NGMbiRYaRw0uhuUtNJ0Pas5lVfhUyu_2jzHHj5g355j45sLsvwepTZRJk52Fb1jIlTfeKxWN0L5g2Uxlfb7TSzSBMR-47glDip-Yn6w-WRp5nKq1C4Fcsb49RTD" alt="Googel Metrics on your resume"></p><p>“If you're applying for technical or engineering roles, this example should be particularly helpful… ‘Increased server query response time by 15% by restructuring API.’</p><p>“This concisely conveys the impact backed up by data and communicates a skill. In this case, it's restructuring an API, but it could be an experience like adding new hardware, algorithmic improvements, caching answers, or implementing machine learning.”</p><p>Three cheers for Google on making this point so effectively.&nbsp; <a href="https://leetresumes.com/blog/why-you-should-include-numbers-on-your-technical-resume%C2%A0">Your technical resume should include numbers</a>.</p><p>A few more good points from the Google folks before we get into our disagreements.</p><p>“Include any relevant leadership positions, awards, university honors, scholarships, or other types of recognition.”</p><p>Remember, recognition indicates that someone else thought you were good, worthy, and successful. Including these external validations help show that your career progress is already endorsed by others - a good sign for a future boss.</p><p>And they also mention, “If you're applying for technical or engineering roles, be sure to include the programming language you used in bold for each project you include.”</p><p>This is advice unique to Google, and I feel more targeted towards junior engineers, for whom the particular language experience is important in hiring. The further you rise in your engineering career, the more the specifics of language choice and deployment fall away, and the bigger architectural issues come to predominate in any assessment of your capabilities.</p><p>Ok, so we’ve agreed with everything Google has to say, right? They’re flawless, right? Well, not quite. There are a few bits of advice that aren’t effective for candidates who are not applying to Google. Specifically:</p><p>“PDF formatting is preferred.”</p><p>As I’ve shared in my <a href="https://www.theladders.com/career-advice/resume-parser-ceos-advice-for-your-resume%C2%A0">mega-interview with the CEOs and technical experts at resume parsing</a> companies, PDFs can sometimes render in a graphical format that evade the comprehension of companies’ HR systems.&nbsp; MS Word, Google Docs, or even .txt should be preferred over PDF.&nbsp;</p><p><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/h_35s4QCEIIqyHzXasPCxCgdxtH55imC75BRzAa2zNi5pSD7NKiSp_JQA7smxG10Ollge5rr7Gibcckbo6ubCzspbUVqr91HCEq_fGKVRFGxFJsruYYUR66-xqy_2lEzwOoA3-SS" alt="null"></p><p>“List your programming languages at the top of your resume and make sure you're comfortable interviewing in them.”</p><p>In contrast to most other technical resume advice, Google suggests putting your programming languages at the top of your resume. I honestly don’t see how this advice can be realistic for most experienced programmers, and Leet Resumes places your technologies at the bottom of your resume.</p><p>To take just two examples, here are the technologies listed by two Leet Resumes users today:</p><p><u>Example 1</u></p><p><strong>Languages:</strong> Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, SQL, Python, Java</p><p>Frameworks/Libraries: Express, NestJS, React, Redux, Cypress, Jest, Selenium, ReactNative, Node.js</p><p><strong>Database:</strong> PostgreSQL, MongoDB, TypeORM, Mongoose</p><p><strong>Certification:</strong> Certified Scrum Master</p><p><u>Example 2</u></p><p><strong>Languages:</strong> Python, Terraform, Java, JavaScript, SQL, HTML, Bash, CSS</p><p><strong>Tools:</strong> AWS Services, Git, Jenkins, Docker, Postgres, Camunda (BPM Engine), Gradle, Maven</p><p><strong>Libraries/Frameworks:</strong> SQLAlchemy, boto3, JUnit, Pytest, Spring/Spring Boot</p><p><strong>Other:</strong> Node.js, SocketCluster, REST APIs, Dreamfactory</p><p>It does not seem possible or realistic that either of these technology professionals could fit their technologies at the top of their resume without breaking the important formatting conventions that both Leet and Google advocate regarding placement of work experience and professional summary.</p><p>And finally, their advice to customize your resume per job simply isn’t accurate, “A big tip here is to read the job description and look at the language it uses. Writing a resume for a specific job description takes a little bit of effort, but it can really help your application stand out. You can even bold and italicize keywords related to the job description to highlight your relevant skills and experience.”</p><p>As with all users, there is a difference between what technical recruiters believe they do, and what they actually do. Given the amount of time spent in reviewing a resume, only the absolutely most relevant keywords are considered - perhaps 2 or 3, sometimes as many as 6.&nbsp; But never, ever dozens.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Your Leet resume will list all of the technologies in which you are proficient, and all of your major accomplishments. So if your well-constructed, thorough, thought-through resume doesn’t already have those 2-6 keywords on it, are you really a fit for the job?&nbsp;</p><p>It’s simply unlikely that your primary resume is truly missing a critical keyword that can be added to a secondary resume to catch a recruiter’s eye, and there is therefore no need to customize multiple resumes with keywords.</p><p>I hope you’ve enjoyed this review of the advice Google recruiters have for your technical resume. If you’d like Leet to <a href="https://leetresumes.com/">write your technical resume for free,</a> please sign up.&nbsp; You can also read the stories of other engineers - there’s a reason we can say users love us!</p></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://leetresumes.com/blog/what-google-recruiters-look-for-in-a-technical-resume</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26030737</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 22:54:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Python interpreter rewritten in Rust, that can run pip]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 143 | Comments 45 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26030269">thread link</a>) | @andrew-ld
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | https://rustpython.github.io/featured/2021/01/26/pip-support.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rustpython.github.io/featured/2021/01/26/pip-support.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
  <div>
    <div>
        <p>7380 commits and 1940 pull requests later, <strong>pip</strong> and <strong>get-pip.py</strong> are working with RustPython 🎉  🎉. pip can install itself and setuptools!</p>

<p>This update is brought to you from <a href="https://github.com/coolreader18">@coolreader18’s</a> terminal by asciinema 🍿.</p>

<h2 id="get-pippy">get-pip.py</h2>
<p><a href="https://asciinema.org/a/3pAZSfrFeIbEUzpPyXtvYZCeN"><img src="https://asciinema.org/a/3pAZSfrFeIbEUzpPyXtvYZCeN.svg" alt="asciicast"></a></p>

<h2 id="get-pippy--pip-install-requests">get-pip.py + pip install requests</h2>
<p><a href="https://asciinema.org/a/fuTmP0wMD8HnvwsOkPRPuVHoa"><img src="https://asciinema.org/a/fuTmP0wMD8HnvwsOkPRPuVHoa.svg" alt="asciicast"></a></p>


<p><a href="https://asciinema.org/a/y2rIeqELmzn5LCaWI6MLMvujz"><img src="https://asciinema.org/a/y2rIeqELmzn5LCaWI6MLMvujz.svg" alt="asciicast"></a></p>

<h2 id="what-you-need-to-do">What you need to do</h2>
<p>This update is so fresh, things are not merged into the <code>master</code> or <code>release</code> branches yet. For now, to test this out, you have to checkout the <code>pip-merg</code> branch, and make sure to build with the <code>ssl</code> feature:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>    <span>$ </span><span>cd </span>RustPython
    <span>$ </span>git fetch <span>--all</span>
    <span>$ </span>git checkout pip-merg
    <span>$ </span>cargo <span>install</span> <span>--path</span> <span>.</span> <span>--features</span> ssl
    <span>$ </span>curl https://bootstrap.pypa.io/get-pip.py <span>-O</span>
    <span>$ </span>rustpython get-pip.py
    ...lots of work...
    <span>$ </span>rustpython <span>-m</span> pip <span>--version</span>
    pip 21.0 from /home/.../.local/lib/rustpython3.9/site-packages/pip <span>(</span>python 3.9<span>)</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

    </div>
  </div>
</section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rustpython.github.io/featured/2021/01/26/pip-support.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26030269</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 21:57:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Arctic Ocean was covered by a shelf ice and filled with freshwater]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 97 | Comments 30 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26030092">thread link</a>) | @gmays
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | https://www.awi.de/en/about-us/service/press/single-view/arktischer-ozean-bedeckt-von-schelfeisen-und-voller-suesswasser.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.awi.de/en/about-us/service/press/single-view/arktischer-ozean-bedeckt-von-schelfeisen-und-voller-suesswasser.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
			<h3>Geosciences</h3>
		

		
			
		

		
			<p><b>Scientists from Alfred Wegener Institute: “We need to have a fresh look at the role of the Arctic Ocean.”</b></p>
		

		<p><span>[03. February 2021]&nbsp;</span>
			
			
				<b><p>The Arctic Ocean was covered by up to 900 m thick shelf ice and was filled entirely with freshwater at least twice in the last 150,000 years. This surprising finding, reported in the latest issue of the journal Nature, is the result of long-term research by scientists from the Alfred Wegener Institute and the MARUM. With a detailed analysis of the composition of marine deposits, the scientists could demonstrate that the Arctic Ocean as well as the Nordic Seas did not contain sea-salt in at least two glacial periods. Instead, these oceans were filled with large amounts of freshwater under a thick ice sheet. This water could then be released into the North Atlantic in very short periods of time. Such sudden freshwater inputs could explain rapid climate oscillations for which no satisfying explanation had been previously found.</p></b>
			
		</p>

		
			
					
				
		

		
			
				<div id="c81029">
	
		

    



	

	<div>
		

		<div>
			
			<p>About 60.000 to 70.000 years ago, in a particularly cold part of the last glacial period, large parts of Northern Europe and North America were covered by ice sheets. The European ice sheet spanned a distance of more than 5000 kilometres, from Ireland and Scotland via Scandinavia to the Eastern rim of the Kara Sea (Arctic Ocean). In North America, large parts of what is now known as Canada were buried under two large ice sheets. Greenland and parts of the Bering Sea coastline were glaciated too. What was the ice situation like even further North, in the Arctic Ocean? Was it covered by thick sea-ice, or maybe with the tongues of these vast ice sheets were floating on it, far beyond the North Pole?</p>
<p>Scientific answers to these questions were more or less hypothetical so far. In contrast to deposits on land, where erratic boulders, moraines and glacial valleys are the obvious landmarks of glaciers, only few traces of vast ice shelves had been found so far in the Arctic Ocean. Geoscientists from the Alfred Wegener Institute Helmholtz Centre for Polar and Marine Research (AWI) and MARUM Center for Marine Environmental Sciences at the University of Bremen have now compiled existing evidence from the Arctic Ocean and the Nordic Seas, and combined it with new data to arrive at a surprising conclusion.</p>
<p>According to their study, the floating parts of the northern ice sheets covered large parts of the Arctic Ocean in the past 150,000 years. Once about 70,000-60,000 years ago and also about 150,000-130,000 years ago. In both periods, freshwater accumulated under the ice, creating a completely fresh Arctic Ocean for thousands of years.</p>
		</div>

		
			















		
	</div>

	



</div>

			
				<div id="c81030">
	
		

    



	

	<div>
		
			


    
            <div>
        

    
        

            
                <figure>
                    
                            
    
            
					<a href="https://www.awi.de/fileadmin/_processed_/6/5/csm_Eisdamm_III_1_quer-20_50d7a9c4cd.jpg" title="Simplified view of the Arctic Ocean and a glacial Arctic ice sheet. In glacial periods with low sea levels, exchange with the Pacific was halted and exchange with the North Atlantic was extremely reduced, while the Arctic basin was still receiving freshwater input. Exchange could only occur through narrow gateways in the Greenland-Scotland-Ridge. The sequence of three sketches shows (1) a period of freshening of the Arctic Ocean followed by (2) the release of freshwater to the North Atlantic, when saline water entered the Arctic Ocean and (3) sudden melting of the Arctic ice sheet upon contact with the relatively warm and salty Atlantic water. (: Martin Künsting)" data-download="/fileadmin/user_upload/AWI/Ueber_uns/Service/Presse/2021/1_Quartal/PM_Arktischer_Ozean_voller_S%C3%BC%C3%9Fwasser/Eisdamm_III_1_quer-20.jpg">
						
	
			
			<img title="The Arctic Ocean and a glacial Arctic ice sheet" alt="The Arctic Ocean and a glacial Arctic ice shield" src="https://www.awi.de/fileadmin/_processed_/6/5/csm_Eisdamm_III_1_quer-20_5792be1210.jpg" width="313" height="209">
		

					</a>
                
        

                        

                    
                        <figcaption>
                            The Arctic Ocean and a glacial Arctic ice sheet (Graphic: Martin Künsting)
                        </figcaption>
                    
                </figure>
            
        
    
    </div>














		

		<div>
			
			<p>“These results mean a real change to our understanding of the Arctic Ocean in glacial climates. To our knowledge, this is the first time that a complete freshening of the Arctic Ocean and the Nordic Seas has been considered - happening not just once, but twice,” says the first author, Dr Walter Geibert, geochemist at the Alfred Wegener Institute.</p>

		</div>

		
	</div>

	



</div>

			
				<div id="c81031">
	
		

    



	

	<div>
		
			















		

		<div>
			
			<h3><span>Thorium is absent in the sediments, so saline water must have been absent</span></h3>
<p>Their finding is based on geological analyses of ten sediment cores from different parts of the Arctic Ocean, Fram Strait and the Nordic Seas. The stacked deposits mirror the climate history of the past glacials. When investigating and comparing the sediment records, the geoscientists found that an important indicator was missing, always in the same two intervals. “In saline sea water, the decay of naturally occurring uranium always results in the production of the isotope thorium-230. This substance accumulates at the sea floor, where it remains detectable for a very long time due to its half-life of 75,000 years,” Walter Geibert explains.</p>
<p>Therefore, geologists often use this thorium-isotope as a natural clock. “Here, its repeated and wide-spread absence is the giveaway that reveals to us what happened. According to our knowledge, the only reasonable explanation for this pattern is that the Arctic Ocean was filled with freshwater twice in its younger history- in frozen and liquid form,” co-author and micropalaeontologist Dr Jutta Wollenburg, also from the AWI, explains. &nbsp;</p>
		</div>

		
	</div>

	



</div>

			
				<div id="c81032">
	
		

    



	

	<div>
		
			















		

		<div>
			
			<h3><span>A new picture of the Arctic Ocean</span></h3>
<p>How can a large ocean basin, connected by several straits with the North Atlantic and the Pacific Ocean, turn entirely fresh? “Such a scenario is perceivable if we realize that in glacial periods, global sea levels were up to 130 m lower than today, and ice masses in the Arctic may have restricted ocean circulation even further,” states co-author Professor Ruediger Stein, geologist at the AWI and the MARUM.</p>
<p>Shallow connections like Bering Strait or the sounds of the Canadian Archipelago were above sea level at the time, cutting off the connection with the Pacific Ocean entirely. In the Nordic Seas, large icebergs or ice sheets extending onto the sea floor restricted the exchange of water masses. The flow of glaciers, ice melt in summer, and rivers draining into the Arctic Ocean kept delivering large amounts of fresh water to the system, at least 1200 cubic kilometres per year. A part of this amount would have been forced via the Nordic Seas through the sparse narrow deeper connections in the Greenland-Scotland Ridge into the North Atlantic, hindering saline water from penetrating further north. This resulted in the freshening of the Arctic Ocean.</p>
		</div>

		
	</div>

	



</div>

			
				<div id="c81033">
	
		

    



	

	<div>
		
			


    
            <div>
        

    
        

            
                <figure>
                    
                            
    
            
					<a href="https://www.awi.de/fileadmin/_processed_/3/b/csm_Eisdamm_III_1_quer-21_1a1957dee7.jpg" title="Simplified view of the Arctic Ocean and a glacial Arctic ice sheet shown with exaggerated depths and the surface level cut off at a constant depth to reveal the restriction of flow paths during periods of lower sea level, and to show possible contact layers between land surface and an ice sheet. (: Martin Künsting)" data-download="/fileadmin/user_upload/AWI/Ueber_uns/Service/Presse/2021/1_Quartal/PM_Arktischer_Ozean_voller_S%C3%BC%C3%9Fwasser/Eisdamm_III_1_quer-21.jpg">
						
	
			
			<img title="Simplified view of the Arctic Ocean and a glacial Arctic ice sheet shown " alt="Simplified view of the Arctic Ocean and a glacial Arctic ice shield shown" src="https://www.awi.de/fileadmin/_processed_/3/b/csm_Eisdamm_III_1_quer-21_c0e20c6910.jpg" width="313" height="209">
		

					</a>
                
        

                        

                    
                        <figcaption>
                            Simplified view of the Arctic Ocean and a glacial Arctic ice sheet shown  (Graphic: Martin Künsting)
                        </figcaption>
                    
                </figure>
            
        
    
    </div>














		

		<div>
			
			<p>“Once the mechanism of ice barriers failed, heavier saline water could fill the Arctic Ocean again,” Walter Geibert says. “We believe that it could then quickly displace the lighter freshwater, resulting in a sudden discharge of the accumulated amount of freshwater over the shallow southern boundary of the Nordic Seas, the Greenland-Scotland-Ridge, into the North Atlantic.”</p>
<p>A concept that assumes that enormous amounts of freshwater were stored in the Arctic Ocean and available for rapid release would help understanding the connection between a range of past climate fluctuations. It would also offer an explanation for some apparent discrepancies between different ways of reconstructing past sea levels. “The remains of coral reefs have pointed to a somewhat higher sea level in certain cold periods than reconstructions from Antarctic ice cores, or reconstructions from the calcareous shells of small marine organisms, would suggest,” explains Walter Geibert. “If we now accept that freshwater may not only have been stored in solid form on land, but some of it also in liquid form in the ocean, the different sea level reconstructions agree better and we can reconcile the location of the coral reefs with calculations of the freshwater budget.”</p>
<p>Freshwater release from the Arctic Ocean might also serve as an explanation for some abrupt climate change events during the last glacial period. &nbsp;During such events, temperatures in Greenland could rise by 8-10 degree centigrade within a few years, only returning to the original cold glacial temperatures over the course of hundreds or thousands of years. “We see an example here of a past Arctic climate tipping point of the Earth system. Now we need to investigate in more detail how these processes were interconnected, and evaluate how this new concept of the Arctic Ocean helps in closing further gaps in our knowledge, in particular in view of the risks of manmade climate change,” says Walter Geibert.</p>
		</div>

		
	</div>

	



</div>

			
		

		

		
			<h2>Original publication</h2>
			
	<p>Walter Geibert, Jens Matthiessen, Ingrid Stimac, Jutta Wollenburg, Ruediger Stein: Glacial episodes of a freshwater Arctic Ocean covered by a thick ice shelf. Nature (2021), DOI: <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-021-03186-y" target="_top">10.1038/s41586-021-03186-y</a></p>

		
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.awi.de/en/about-us/service/press/single-view/arktischer-ozean-bedeckt-von-schelfeisen-und-voller-suesswasser.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26030092</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 21:37:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why Security Defects Go Unnoticed During Code Reviews? [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 63 | Comments 37 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26028901">thread link</a>) | @chx
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | http://amiangshu.com/papers/paul-ICSE-2021.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://amiangshu.com/papers/paul-ICSE-2021.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://amiangshu.com/papers/paul-ICSE-2021.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26028901</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 19:33:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What we’ve learned from 200 teams on managing product copy]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 19 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26028539">thread link</a>) | @jolenam
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | https://www.dittowords.com/blog/building-a-copy-collaboration-workflow?source=hn | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.dittowords.com/blog/building-a-copy-collaboration-workflow?source=hn">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>While building Ditto, we've gotten the chance to talk to 200+ teams about what the process of collaborating on copy looks like for them.</p><p>Our key finding? Copy is end-to-end — it exists from the early phases of discovery and design all the way to development.</p><p>This means that working on copy doesn't just involve writers drafting text on their own. It's the back-and-forth between designers and writers about how copy and visuals can work together. It's conversations with PMs to understand the goals of a new feature and what language will help users navigate successfully. It's working with legal to get a particular term approved for use, or talking to brand about how to name a new feature. It's getting copy translated and following up to fix phrases that are too long in another language. It's handing copy off to developers and making sure it gets into production error-free. It's developers sifting through hardcoded strings when copy already in production needs to get updated.</p><p>In other words, the process of getting copy written and in front of users relies on a <em>lot</em> of people.</p><p>On most teams, though, this process is still fragmented and unreliable. And though we're seeing companies realize how impactful copy is on user experience and business goals, most still have a long way to go in embedding copy into their product development workflows.</p><p>In almost all of our conversations, we heard the same challenges come up:</p><ol role="list"><li><strong>How do we integrate copy into the design process?</strong></li><li><strong>How do we manage stakeholder feedback and review of copy?</strong></li><li><strong>What's the best way to hand copy off to developers?</strong></li><li><strong>How do we establish lasting copy consistency across our product?</strong></li></ol><p>In this post, we're sharing what we've learned about the state of copy workflows from our conversations: the issues that teams are currently facing and strategies they've come up with for tackling them.</p><p>‍</p><div><p>1. Integrating copy into the design process</p>
</div><p>Copy is as much a part of the user experience as the layout and the visuals. But translating this into your product development process — making sure that copy and visual design evolve together — is tricky. Visuals often get prioritized over copy, and some words inevitably end up getting written last-minute, in a mad dash to replace lingering <em>lorem ipsums.</em></p><p>Part of the reason is that design and copy often don't share a toolset. Designers work in their design tools, but copy can exist in any number of places (think: external copy docs and spreadsheets, design tools, Jira, Slack, email). Between the annotated screenshots being messaged back-and-forth in Slack and copy tables in word documents, copy ends up increasingly detached from its goal of designing for users.<br>‍</p><p><strong>Strategies</strong></p><p>From our conversations, we've learned a few tips for fostering more effective copy-design collaboration:</p><ul role="list"><li><strong>Think about copy early on.</strong> Copy is an integral part of the user experience and should be part of the decision-making process from the start. This means thinking about copy even when the design problem is still being framed and user goals are still being established. Copy is more than just the words that eventually end up in the design. Understanding what content a user needs to feel reassured or successfully complete a task can inform the structure of a user flow or even highlight UI issues.<br>In practice, this can look like a few different things: Try designing with real content from the very beginning, and consider mapping out the flow and structure of copy <em>before</em> you start on the visuals. If your company has a dedicated content team, make sure they're kept in the loop on upcoming projects, whether that means inviting them to meetings or sending over post-kickoff notes.</li></ul><ul role="list"><li><strong>Take an overhead view on copy.</strong> As with visual design, successful copy requires thinking about the product as a whole. Consider how the text in one part of the product will interact with copy that already exists elsewhere. Think about how copy for a particular feature fits into the overarching journey of what else a user is reading and experiencing. See if you can reuse copy (more on this below!) to maintain consistency and overall usability across surfaces of the product.</li><li><strong>Make sure the mockups have up-to-date copy.</strong> This ensures that the text and visuals on a design are continuously aligned.</li></ul><p>For teams with dedicated content roles like UX writers and content designers:</p><ul role="list"><li><strong>Try using collaborative design tools (Figma, Adobe XD, etc.).</strong> Writers will be able to work side-by-side with designers, edit directly in the mockups, try out variations, and view changes in realtime. Just make sure to establish a clear process for how writers should work out of the design files. For example, if a mockup is particularly complex, this could mean creating a separate page in the file just for writers to play around with copy.</li><li><strong>Define a method for giving status updates</strong>. If writers are working directly out of the design file, it can be tricky to know what copy is final and what's not. Try indicating status in the file itself (ex: colored badges), or deciding on one communication tool like Slack.</li><li><strong>Determine what level of content work each project requires.</strong> While copy is important on every project, it'll be more important on some than others. Chances are, content designers will be supporting many teams at once, so prioritization is key. For writers, establish a process for receiving requests for copy help (we've heard Airtable or Google Forms work well!), and feel free to push back on "quick" requests when you don't have the bandwidth. Try building up a database of reusable text (more on this below) so designers can self-serve.</li></ul><p>‍</p><p>‍</p><div><p>2. Managing stakeholder feedback and review</p>
</div><p>Part of what makes collaborating on copy challenging is the number of stakeholders involved — almost every role at a company, from writers and designers to engineers, PMs, and legal, can touch the copy during any one project.</p><p>Compared to traditional content marketing workflows, product copy review is less linear and more iterative, relying on back-and-forth discussions more than explicit approvals. While compliance and brand teams may give one-and-done responses, folks like product owners and engineers are much more likely to give ongoing feedback as the design evolves.</p><p>Even more, every project involves different stakeholders who each have a set of tools they're comfortable with. For every team we talked to, copy review took place in some combination of the following places:</p><ul role="list"><li>Design tools (ex: Figma, Sketch, Adobe XD, Abstract)</li><li>Spreadsheets and documents (ex: Google Sheets, Google Docs, Airtable)</li><li>Communication tools (ex: Slack, email)</li><li>Project management tools (ex: Jira, Trello, Confluence)</li><li>Codebase + code management tools (ex: Github, Bitbucket)</li></ul><p>When some comments are added to Google Docs and others to an email thread, and the copy in mockups differs from that in the spreadsheet, stakeholders don't know where to find the most recent discussions or even version of copy. Tool overload makes it difficult to find alignment and make decisions, ultimately slowing the entire team down.</p><p>Beyond setting up a repeatable process for getting feedback, there are also challenges with getting the right feedback at the right time. Stakeholders (who usually aren't involved from the very beginning of the project) have to get up-to-speed on context — what this copy looks like in the design, where it sits in the UX flow, what the overarching project business and user goals are. Stakeholders also often have the mentality that "anyone can write," which can lead to unsolicited suggestions or unproductive feedback loops.</p><p><strong><br>Strategies</strong></p><p>Here are a few ways we've heard teams combat these issues:</p><ul role="list"><li><strong>Designate a single source of truth for all the copy in your project, and enforce that!</strong> Make sure it's kept up-to-date with the latest copy so everyone can stay on the same page. Limit all copy-related discussion to this source of truth, and make sure it's easily accessible by stakeholders. It should also allow you to easily track progress, record iterations, and document who's making changes and the rationale behind those decisions.</li><li><strong>Ensure stakeholders get the context they need off-the-bat.</strong> This could mean linking documentation in the request for review, hopping on a brief call to fill them in, or recording a video walkthrough of the flow. Whenever possible, present copy with visual context. It can also be helpful include what stage the copy is at (was it just drafted, or has it already been rewritten and reviewed by three other teams?) so you get the correct level of feedback.</li><li><strong>Build up relationships with stakeholders</strong>. Sync regularly with key stakeholders, and start to understand their challenges and definitions of success. Look for shared goals and opportunities to advocate for copy and its impact on business and user experience across different parts of the company. Whenever possible, measure copy ROI, tie those to business outcomes, and share those wins so stakeholders are more likely to give copy a seat at the table.</li></ul><p>👉 <em>At Ditto, we're helping teams </em><a href="http://bit.ly/ditto-workflow-single-source" target="_blank"><em>create a single source of truth</em></a><em> for all of their product copy.</em></p><p>‍</p><div><p>3. Handing copy off to developers</p>
</div><p>For all the work that goes into designing and reviewing copy, dealing with copy in production can be equally as challenging.</p><p>Several issues that came up repeatedly:</p><ul role="list"><li>developers don't know when copy is finalized, or even where to find the latest copy,</li><li>developers have to copy and paste text from the copy doc/mockup/other tool, which is time-consuming and error-prone,</li><li>if copy is hardcoded, even small copy changes require developers to hunt down strings down, which diverts them from more impactful work and makes it hard to rapidly change copy or do A/B tests,</li><li>copy often goes un-QA'd, resulting in costly post-production fixes,</li><li>localization involves a whole other set of people, tools, and processes that must also integrate with development.</li></ul><p>‍<br>‍<strong>Strategies</strong></p><p>Here are strategies we heard for getting copy into production more efficiently:</p><ul role="list"><li><strong>Establish a clear process for communicating when copy has been finalized.</strong> This was by …</li></ul></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.dittowords.com/blog/building-a-copy-collaboration-workflow?source=hn">https://www.dittowords.com/blog/building-a-copy-collaboration-workflow?source=hn</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.dittowords.com/blog/building-a-copy-collaboration-workflow?source=hn</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26028539</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 18:54:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Black Hat Rust – I'm writing a book about offensive security with Rust]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 12 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26027996">thread link</a>) | @sylvain_kerkour
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | https://academy.kerkour.com/black-hat-rust | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://academy.kerkour.com/black-hat-rust">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://academy.kerkour.com/black-hat-rust</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26027996</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 18:04:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Peter Naur's view of programming]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 264 | Comments 156 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26027448">thread link</a>) | @cloogshicer
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | https://hiringengineersbook.com/post/autonomy | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://hiringengineersbook.com/post/autonomy">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

  <div role="main">
    <div>
      

      <article>
      

<p>Let me ask you a question: How much value do you think your source code has?</p>

<p>To answer this question, let me take you a few years back, when I worked with a small high tech startup. We were working on a pretty complex augmented reality system spanning all layers from low-level computer vision components to cross-platform mobile and web apps. Especially for the lower-level components, a good amount of research had been involved. We worked closely with an academic institute that specialized in computer vision.</p>

<p>In short, this project wasn’t something that anybody could just easily recreate. So one of the assumptions we had implicitly made was that our source code was one of the company’s major assets.</p>

<p>When we hired a new COO, who had mainly worked at bigger companies before, he was shocked to hear that all our code, communication infrastructure and internal systems were living in the cloud. He argued that we should move to on-premise solutions as soon as possible, partially out of fear of intellectual property theft, partially to appease investors with similar fears.</p>

<p>While I had no say in it, his arguments seemed somewhat unreasonable to me at the time and I couldn’t put my finger on it. But the CTO was on board. So we installed a cheapo server in one of our office’s closets, even though someone had just broken into our building earlier that month. We got rid of GitLab, and moved away from Slack and Trello in favor of an on-prem Jira installation. The whole ordeal took months to complete, and I’m guessing that all things considered, it cost the small company of ~6 people about half a year of development time. There was also the ongoing opportunity cost of no longer being able to use any new tools that involved the cloud.</p>

<p>But the whole thing got me thinking about an interesting question: What would happen if someone just took all our code? Going even further, what would happen if we ourselves just put it all on GitHub, with a permissive license like MIT? Short of making investors think we’re crazy, what direct impact would that have had on the company?</p>

<p>I thought long and hard about these questions, and I think in our situation back then, the answer would have been: absolutely none.</p>

<h2 id="your-source-code-is-worthless">Your source code is worthless</h2>

<p>Let’s face it, we were still a fast-moving startup, even if the above anecdote might give you the opposite picture. Our code was still changing drastically every couple weeks. Changes of the entire architecture or complete re-writes of components were not uncommon, as is usual for some early stage startups. And as you might expect in such a situation, the code wasn’t of the highest quality either: Half the time, the build would be broken. Testing and documentation were basically non-existent. It was unlikely that anyone from outside the team would even have gotten the thing up and running. Even if they did, it would be outdated a moment later.</p>

<p>One of the fears from management was that a big company like Google could take our code and build a competing service. After thinking about this in more detail, the idea now seems laughable to me: They would be much faster just building it themselves from scratch, than trying to understand the crummy code we had hacked together.</p>

<p>But let’s take a step back and assume the opposite for a moment: Beautifully written, clean code with complete test coverage. One-click build process. Exceptionally well-written documentation of the architecture and components. Would this have changed the situation? I really don’t think it would have.</p>

<p>You see, in 2017, there actually was an incident of a high profile source code theft: Panic, a company that makes high quality Mac and iOS software, had the full source code for most of their apps <a href="https://panic.com/blog/stolen-source-code" target="_blank">stolen by hackers</a>. While the attackers demanded a ransom to prevent the public release of the code, Panic refused to pay. They came to the conclusion that the worst thing that could happen would be people building cracked versions of their Apps, full of malware. But that was already happening anyways (as with most software), even before the source code was stolen. Don’t get me wrong, I’m sure this was a pretty bad blow for Panic, and I’m in no way arguing that source code theft can’t be damaging. But even Panic says in their blog post that they were not too concerned with competitors using their code either, mainly because it would quickly become outdated:</p>

<p><em>“That source is already missing a ton of fixes and improvements we committed over the last week alone, and six months from now it will be missing major critical new features. In short: it’s old and getting older.”</em></p>

<p>So maybe code by itself is not that valuable, and yet, software companies still have value. If the tangible aspects of the technology, the code and documentation, are not the main assets of a company, what is?</p>

<div>
    <div>
        <h6>Get notified when the next post comes out! Sign up for our newsletter.</h6>
                
    </div>
</div>

<h3 id="what-is-programming">What is programming</h3>

<p>I couldn’t really wrap my head around the previous question until I stumbled upon a wonderful article, <a href="http://pages.cs.wisc.edu/~remzi/Naur.pdf" target="_blank">Programming as Theory Building</a>, written by none other than <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turing_Award" target="_blank">Turing Award</a> winner <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_Naur" target="_blank">Peter Naur</a>. If you’ve ever taken any formal computer science classes, you may have already heard his name: He’s the N in BNF, or Backus-Naur form, an important and widely-used notation for describing programming languages.</p>

<p>In the article, Naur describes his view of what programming really is. He argues that the main activity a programmer does is building a theory or model of the problem space in their head:</p>

<p><em>“[…] programming properly should be regarded as an activity by which the programmers form or achieve a certain kind of insight, a theory, of the matters at hand.”</em></p>

<p>He calls this view of programming the <em>“Theory Building View”</em> and puts it in contrast to what he calls the <em>“Production View”</em>, in which <em>“[…] programming is regarded as a production of a program and certain other texts.”</em></p>

<p>Naur argues that the production view, while it is widespread, contradicts many things we observe empirically in software projects. In contrast, the Theory Building View allows us to explain many phenomena, such as the observation I made in this article, that the source code itself holds little to no value.<sup id="fnref:naurwasfaster"><a href="#fn:naurwasfaster">1</a></sup> One of Naur’s main conclusions is that making changes to an existing program (to accommodate changing requirements) is often more costly than writing new code from scratch, at least if done by people from a different team. This is because there are intangible aspects of the model/theory in the programmer’s heads, which can’t be expressed in code and documentation:</p>

<p><em>“A main claim of the Theory Building View of programming is that an essential part of any program, the theory of it, is something that could not be conceivably expressed, but is inextricably bound to human beings.”</em></p>

<p>When a new team obtains the source code, they thus have to first re-build the original theory in their heads, which, Naur argues, can be more work than building their own theory from the ground up.</p>

<p>Naur brings multiple examples of real life product development where teams were asked to modify or extend a program, but couldn’t do it without help from the original development team, or otherwise they would be <em>“destroying its power and simplicity”</em>:</p>

<p><em>“[…] the program text and its documentation has proved insufficient as a carrier of some of the most important design ideas.”</em></p>

<p>Naur further says:</p>

<p><em>“The conclusion seems inescapable that at least with certain kinds of large programs, the continued adaptation, modification, and correction of errors in them, is essentially dependent on a certain kind of knowledge possessed by a group of programmers who are closely and continuously connected with them.”</em></p>

<p>Since this knowledge is inherently intangible, it can’t be communicated through the code or documentation - it has to be experienced anew by each new programmer joining the team. While the previous programmers can help new team members in this task, the code itself and any written documentation is not very useful in this process. What are these intangible elements/aspects?</p>

<div>
    <div>
        <h6>Get notified when the next post comes out! Sign up for our newsletter.</h6>
                
    </div>
</div>

<h3 id="intangible-aspects-of-software">Intangible aspects of software</h3>

<p>According to Naur, there are three aspects that are difficult or impossible to express in any written form of code or documentation, and yet the original programmer can easily explain them:</p>

<p><strong>1)</strong> The programmer knows and understands the relationship of the real world problem and the program. They can explain how the details of the problem are mapped into the code and into additional documentation:
<em>“Thus the programmer must be able to explain, for each part of the program text and for each of its overall structural characteristics, what aspect or activity of the world is matched by it.”</em></p>

<p>While I think it’s possible in theory to make this knowledge more tangible through documentation, doing so exhaustively would be wholly impractical. And yet, Naur notes, an exhaustive understanding of the real world problem is necessary to understand the theory of the program:</p>

<p><em>“By far the largest part of the world will of course lie outside the scope of the program text, being irrelevant in the context. However, the decision that a part of the world is relevant can only be made by someone who understands the whole world. This understanding must be contributed by the programmer.”</em></p>

<p>Let me give you an example from my own experience. A few years back, I was working on a project that improved the processes of a production line in a factory. The workers there were still using paper checklists for quality assurance, making the process labor-intense and error prone. We replaced those paper checklists with a mobile app that runs on a tablet. While the app itself was fairly simple, the underlying business processes were complex - multiple different assembly lines and a variety of different machines were …</p></article></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://hiringengineersbook.com/post/autonomy">https://hiringengineersbook.com/post/autonomy</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://hiringengineersbook.com/post/autonomy</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26027448</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 17:19:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Powerpaste, the hydrogen technology for small vehicles]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 125 | Comments 74 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26027288">thread link</a>) | @apsec112
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | https://www.fraunhofer.de/en/press/research-news/2021/february-2021/hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.fraunhofer.de/en/press/research-news/2021/february-2021/hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
	<figure>
    <a href="https://www.fraunhofer.de/en/press/research-news/2021/february-2021/hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters/jcr:content/contentPar/sectioncomponent/sectionParsys/textwithinlinedimage/imageComponent1/image.img.4col.large.jpg/1607945604152/ifam-hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters-pic-1.jpg" data-type="image" data-allow-save="true" data-download-href="/en/press/research-news/2021/february-2021/hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters/jcr:content/contentPar/sectioncomponent/sectionParsys/textwithinlinedimage/imageComponent1/image.img.jpg/1607945604152/ifam-hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters-pic-1.jpg?download" data-btn-save-label="Download" data-alt=" POWERPASTE" title="Hydrogen-powered drives for e-scooters" data-lightbox-caption=" POWERPASTE" data-lightbox-copyright="© Fraunhofer IFAM">
			<picture>
				    <!--[if IE 9]><video style="display: none;"><![endif]-->
				    <source srcset="https://www.fraunhofer.de/en/press/research-news/2021/february-2021/hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters/jcr:content/contentPar/sectioncomponent/sectionParsys/textwithinlinedimage/imageComponent1/image.img.4col.jpg/1607945604152/ifam-hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters-pic-1.jpg" media="(min-width: 1841px)">
				    <source srcset="https://www.fraunhofer.de/en/press/research-news/2021/february-2021/hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters/jcr:content/contentPar/sectioncomponent/sectionParsys/textwithinlinedimage/imageComponent1/image.img.2col.jpg/1607945604152/ifam-hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters-pic-1.jpg" media="(min-width: 769px)">
				    <source srcset="https://www.fraunhofer.de/en/press/research-news/2021/february-2021/hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters/jcr:content/contentPar/sectioncomponent/sectionParsys/textwithinlinedimage/imageComponent1/image.img.2col.jpg/1607945604152/ifam-hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters-pic-1.jpg" media="(min-width: 480px)">
				    <source srcset="https://www.fraunhofer.de/en/press/research-news/2021/february-2021/hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters/jcr:content/contentPar/sectioncomponent/sectionParsys/textwithinlinedimage/imageComponent1/image.img.1col.jpg/1607945604152/ifam-hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters-pic-1.jpg" media="(min-width: 320px)">
				    <!--[if IE 9]></video><![endif]-->
				    <img alt=" POWERPASTE" data-width="1600.0" title="Hydrogen-powered drives for e-scooters" data-height="1167.0" src="https://www.fraunhofer.de/en/press/research-news/2021/february-2021/hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters/jcr:content/contentPar/sectioncomponent/sectionParsys/textwithinlinedimage/imageComponent1/image.img.jpg/1607945604152/ifam-hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters-pic-1.jpg">
				    </picture>
			</a>
			<figcaption>
        <span>© Fraunhofer IFAM</span>
        <p> POWERPASTE</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure><figure>
    <a href="https://www.fraunhofer.de/en/press/research-news/2021/february-2021/hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters/jcr:content/contentPar/sectioncomponent/sectionParsys/textwithinlinedimage/imageComponent2/image.img.4col.large.jpg/1607945604152/ifam-hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters-pic-2.jpg" data-type="image" data-allow-save="true" data-download-href="/en/press/research-news/2021/february-2021/hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters/jcr:content/contentPar/sectioncomponent/sectionParsys/textwithinlinedimage/imageComponent2/image.img.jpg/1607945604152/ifam-hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters-pic-2.jpg?download" data-btn-save-label="Download" data-alt="TRL 5 demonstrator of a power generator with a POWERPASTE cartridge and a 100 watt PEM fuel cell." title="Hydrogen-powered drives for e-scooters" data-lightbox-caption="TRL 5 demonstrator of a power generator with a POWERPASTE cartridge and a 100 watt PEM fuel cell." data-lightbox-copyright="© Fraunhofer IFAM">
			<picture>
				    <!--[if IE 9]><video style="display: none;"><![endif]-->
				    <source srcset="https://www.fraunhofer.de/en/press/research-news/2021/february-2021/hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters/jcr:content/contentPar/sectioncomponent/sectionParsys/textwithinlinedimage/imageComponent2/image.img.4col.jpg/1607945604152/ifam-hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters-pic-2.jpg" media="(min-width: 1841px)">
				    <source srcset="https://www.fraunhofer.de/en/press/research-news/2021/february-2021/hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters/jcr:content/contentPar/sectioncomponent/sectionParsys/textwithinlinedimage/imageComponent2/image.img.2col.jpg/1607945604152/ifam-hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters-pic-2.jpg" media="(min-width: 769px)">
				    <source srcset="https://www.fraunhofer.de/en/press/research-news/2021/february-2021/hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters/jcr:content/contentPar/sectioncomponent/sectionParsys/textwithinlinedimage/imageComponent2/image.img.2col.jpg/1607945604152/ifam-hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters-pic-2.jpg" media="(min-width: 480px)">
				    <source srcset="https://www.fraunhofer.de/en/press/research-news/2021/february-2021/hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters/jcr:content/contentPar/sectioncomponent/sectionParsys/textwithinlinedimage/imageComponent2/image.img.1col.jpg/1607945604152/ifam-hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters-pic-2.jpg" media="(min-width: 320px)">
				    <!--[if IE 9]></video><![endif]-->
				    <img alt="TRL 5 demonstrator of a power generator with a POWERPASTE cartridge and a 100 watt PEM fuel cell." data-width="1600.0" title="Hydrogen-powered drives for e-scooters" data-height="2036.0" src="https://www.fraunhofer.de/en/press/research-news/2021/february-2021/hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters/jcr:content/contentPar/sectioncomponent/sectionParsys/textwithinlinedimage/imageComponent2/image.img.jpg/1607945604152/ifam-hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters-pic-2.jpg">
				    </picture>
			</a>
			<figcaption>
        <span>© Fraunhofer IFAM</span>
        <p>TRL 5 demonstrator of a power generator with a POWERPASTE cartridge and a 100 watt PEM fuel cell.</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure></div><div>
		<p>Gasoline and diesel engines, which are powered by fossil fuels, will soon be sidelined by climate change. Instead, new propulsion systems will be required. One fuel with a big potential is hydrogen. Hydrogen vehicles are equipped with a reinforced tank that is fueled at a pressure of 700 bar. This tank feeds a fuel cell, which converts the hydrogen into electricity. This in turn drives an electric motor to propels the vehicle. In the case of passenger cars, this technology is well advanced, with several hundred hydrogen-powered automobiles already in operation on German roads. At the same time, the network of hydrogen stations in Germany is projected to grow from 100 to 400 over the next three years. Yet hydrogen is not currently an option for small vehicles such as electric scooters and motorcycles, since the pressure surge during refilling would be too great. Does this effectively shut out such vehicles from hydrogen technology?</p> 
<h4><b>POWERPASTE: the hydrogen technology for small vehicles</b></h4> 
<p>Not at all! Researchers from the Fraunhofer Institute for Manufacturing Technology and Advanced Materials IFAM in Dresden have now come up with a hydrogen-based fuel that is ideal for small vehicles: POWERPASTE, which is based on solid magnesium hydride. “POWERPASTE stores hydrogen in a chemical form at room temperature and atmospheric pressure to be then released on demand,” explains Dr. Marcus Vogt, research associate at Fraunhofer IFAM. And given that POWERPASTE only begins to decompose at temperatures of around 250 °C, it remains safe even when an e-scooter stands in the baking sun for hours. Moreover, refueling is extremely simple. Instead of heading to the filling station, riders merely have to replace an empty cartridge with a new one and then refill a tank with mains water. This can be done either at home or underway.</p> 
<p>The starting material of POWERPASTE is magnesium, one of the most abundant elements and, therefore, an easily available raw material. Magnesium powder is combined with hydrogen to form magnesium hydride in a process conducted at 350 °C and five to six times atmospheric pressure. An ester and a metal salt are then added in order to form the finished product. Onboard the vehicle, the POWERPASTE is released from a cartridge by means of a plunger. When water is added from an onboard tank, the ensuing reaction generates hydrogen gas in a quantity dynamically adjusted to the actual requirements of the fuel cell. In fact, only half of the hydrogen originates from the POWERPASTE; the rest comes from the added water. “POWERPASTE thus has a huge energy storage density,” says Vogt. “It is substantially higher than that of a 700 bar high-pressure tank. And compared to batteries, it has ten times the energy storage density.” This means that POWERPASTE offers a range comparable to – or even greater than – gasoline. And it also provides a higher range than compressed hydrogen at a pressure of 700 bar.</p> 
<h4><b>Suitable for e-scooters – and other applications as well</b></h4> 
<p>With its huge energy storage density, POWERPASTE is also an interesting option for cars, delivery vehicles and range extenders in battery-powered electric vehicles. Similarly, it could also significantly extend the flight time of large drones, which would thereby be able to fly for several hours rather than a mere 20 minutes. This would be especially useful for survey work, such as the inspection of forestry or power lines. In another kind of application, campers might also use POWERPASTE in a fuel cell to generate electricity to power a coffeemaker or toaster.</p> 
<h4><b>POWERPASTE helps overcome lack of infrastructure</b></h4> 
<p>In addition to providing a high operating range, POWERPASTE has another point in its favor. Unlike gaseous hydrogen, it does not require a costly infrastructure. This makes it ideal for areas lacking such an infrastructure. In places where there are no hydrogen stations, regular filling stations could therefore sell POWERPASTE in cartridges or canisters instead. The paste is fluid and pumpable. It can therefore be supplied by a standard filling line, using relatively inexpensive equipment. Initially, filling stations could supply smaller quantities of POWERPASTE – from a metal drum, for example – and then expand in line with demand. This would require capital expenditure of several tens of thousands of euros. By way of comparison, a filling station to pump hydrogen at high pressure currently costs between one and two million euros for each fuel pump. POWERPASTE is also cheap to transport, since no costly high-pressure tanks are involved nor the use of extremely cold liquid hydrogen.</p> 
<h4><b>Pilot center planned for 2021</b></h4> 
<p>Fraunhofer IFAM is currently building a production plant for POWERPASTE at the Fraunhofer Project Center for Energy Storage and Systems ZESS. Scheduled to go into operation in 2021, this new facility will be able to produce up to four tons of POWERPASTE a year – not only for e-scooters.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.fraunhofer.de/en/press/research-news/2021/february-2021/hydrogen-powered-drives-for-e-scooters.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26027288</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 17:04:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A better way to build ML: Why you should be using Active Learning]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 129 | Comments 47 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26026949">thread link</a>) | @razcle
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | https://humanloop.com/blog/why-you-should-be-using-active-learning/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://humanloop.com/blog/why-you-should-be-using-active-learning/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>

    

    <div>
        <p>Data labelling is often the biggest bottleneck in machine learning — finding, managing and labelling vast quantities of data to build a sufficiently performing model can take weeks or months. Active learning lets you train machine learning models with <strong>much</strong> less labelled data. The best AI-driven companies, like <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oBklltKXtDE&amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;t=475s">Tesla, already use active learning</a>. We think you should too.</p><h2 id="the-conventional-approach-vs-active-learning-creating-a-spam-filter">The conventional approach vs active learning - creating a spam filter</h2><p>Imagine that you wanted to build a spam filter for your emails. The conventional approach (<a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/spam.html">at least since 2002</a>) is to collect a large number of emails, label them as "spam" or "not spam" and then train a machine learning classifier to distinguish between the two classes. The conventional approach assumes all the data is equally valuable, but in most datasets there are class imbalances, noisy data and lots of redundancy.</p><blockquote><strong>The conventional approach wastes time labelling data that doesn't improve your model's performance. And you don't even know if your model is useful until you've finished labelling all the data.</strong></blockquote><p>Humans don't require thousands of randomly labelled examples to learn the difference between spam and legitimate email. If you were teaching a human to solve this task you'd expect to be able to give them a few examples of what you want, have them learn quickly and ask questions when they were unsure.</p><p>Active learning operates using the same intuition, using the model you're training to find and label only the most valuable data.</p><p>In active learning, you first provide a small number of labelled examples. The model is trained on this "seed" dataset. Then, the model "asks questions" by selecting the unlabeled data points it is unsure about, so the human can "answer" the questions by providing labels for those points. The model updates again and the process is repeated until the performance is good enough. <strong>By having the human iteratively teach the model, it's possible to make a better model, in less time, with much less labelled data.</strong></p><p>So how can the model find the next data point that needs labelling? Some commonly used methods are:</p><ol><li>select the data points where the model's predictive distribution has highest entropy</li><li>pick data points where the model's favored prediction is least confident</li><li>train an ensemble of models and focus on the data points where they disagree</li></ol><p>At Humanloop we actually use custom methods that leverage Bayesian deep learning to get better uncertainty estimates.</p><h2 id="three-benefits-of-using-active-learning">Three Benefits of Using Active Learning</h2><h3 id="1-you-spend-less-time-and-money-on-labelling-data">1. You spend less time and money on labelling data</h3><p>Active learning has been shown to deliver large savings in data labelling across a wide range of tasks and data sets ranging from computer vision to NLP. Since data labelling is one of the most expensive parts of training modern machine learning models this should be enough justification on its own!</p><figure><img src="https://humanloop.com/blog/content/images/2021/01/learning_curves.png" alt="" srcset="https://humanloop.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2021/01/learning_curves.png 600w, https://humanloop.com/blog/content/images/2021/01/learning_curves.png 700w"><figcaption>Using active learning gets to higher model accuracies with less labelled data</figcaption></figure><h3 id="2-you-get-faster-feedback-on-model-performance">2. You get faster feedback on model performance</h3><p>Usually people label their data <em>before</em> they train any models or get any feedback. Often, it takes days or weeks of iterating on annotation guidelines and re-labelling only to discover that model performance falls far short of what is needed, or different labelled data is required. Since Active Learning trains a model frequently <em>during</em> the data labelling process, it's possible to get feedback and correct issues that might otherwise be discovered much later.</p><h3 id="3-your-model-will-have-higher-final-accuracy">3. Your model will have higher final accuracy</h3><p>People are often surprised that models trained with active learning not only learn faster but can actually converge to a better final model (with less data). We're told so often that more data is better, that it's easy to forget that the quality of the data matters just as much as the quantity. If the dataset contains ambiguous examples which are hard to label accurately this can actually degrade your final model performance.</p><p>The order the model sees examples also matters. There's an entire sub-field of machine learning, called curriculum learning, which studies how you can improve model performance by first teaching about simple concepts before teaching complex ones. &nbsp;Think "Arithmetic before advanced calculus". Active learning naturally enforces a curriculum on your models and helps them achieve better overall performance.</p><h2 id="if-active-learning-is-so-great-then-why-doesn-t-everyone-use-it">If active learning is so great, then why doesn't everyone use it?</h2><p>Most of our tools and processes for building machine learning models weren't designed with Active Learning in mind. There are often different teams of people responsible for data labelling vs model training but active learning requires these processes to be coupled. If you do get these teams to work together, you still need a lot of infrastructure to connect model training to annotation interfaces. Most of the software libraries being used assume all of your data is labelled before you train a model, so to use active learning you have to write a tonne of boiler plate. You also need to figure out how best to host your model, have the model communicate with a team of annotators and update itself as it gets data asynchronously from different annotators.</p><p>On top of this, modern deep learning models are very slow to update, so frequently retraining them from scratch is painful. Nobody wants to label a hundred examples then wait 24 hours for a model to be fully re-trained before labelling the next 100. Deep learning models also tend to have millions or billions of parameters and getting good uncertainty estimates from these models is an open research problem.</p><p>If you read academic papers on active learning, you might think active learning will give you a small saving in labels but for a huge amount of work. The papers are misleading though because they operate on academic datasets that tend to be balanced/clean. They almost always label one example at a time and they forget that not every data-point is equally easy to label. On more realistic problems with large class imbalances, noisy data and variable labelling costs, the benefits can be much bigger than the literature suggests. In some cases there can be a 10x reduction in labelling costs.</p><h2 id="how-to-use-active-learning-today">How to use Active Learning today</h2><figure><img src="https://humanloop.com/blog/content/images/2021/02/logos-1.png" alt="" srcset="https://humanloop.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2021/02/logos-1.png 600w, https://humanloop.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2021/02/logos-1.png 1000w, https://humanloop.com/blog/content/images/size/w1600/2021/02/logos-1.png 1600w, https://humanloop.com/blog/content/images/size/w2400/2021/02/logos-1.png 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Many of the biggest hurdles to using active learning are just a question of having the right infrastructure. Just as tools like Keras and PyTorch dramatically reduced the pain of deriving gradients, new tools are emerging to make active learning much easier.</p><p>There are open source python libraries such as <a href="https://github.com/modAL-python/modAL">modAL</a> that take away much of the boilerplate. ModAL is built on top of scikit-learn and lets you combine different models with any active learning strategy you like. It takes much of the work out of implementing different uncertainty measures, is open source and modular. The pros of ModAL are the range of methods it provides out of the box and the fact that it's open source. The downside of libraries like modAL is they don't include any annotation interfaces and still leave the work of hosting a model and connecting it to annotation interfaces up to you.</p><p>That brings us to annotation interfaces:</p><p>Probably the most popular tool for individual data scientists is Prodigy. Prodigy is an annotation interface built by the makers of Spacy and so can naturally be combined with their fantastic NLP library to use basic active learning. It's not open-source but you can download it as a pip wheel and install it locally. Whilst Prodigy is a good tool for individuals, it hasn't been designed to support teams of annotators and only implements the most basic forms of Active Learning. To make this work with teams, still requires you to host prodigy yourself and can be a lot of work to set up.</p><p>Labelbox provides interfaces for a variety of image annotations and has recently added support for text as well. Unlike Prodigy, Labelbox has been designed with teams of annotators in mind and has more tools for ensuring that your labels are correct. They don't have any native support for active learning or model training but do allow you to upload predictions from your model to the annotation interface via API. This means that if you have implemented an active learning acquisition function and are training a model, you can set up an active learning loop. Though the most of the work is left to you.</p><h2 id="humanloop">Humanloop</h2><p>We built Humanloop to solve many of the problems of existing tools. Our goal is to make deploying and maintaining natural language models faster and easier than ever before.</p><p>Humanloop provides an annotation interface for NLP tasks that lets you train a model as you annotate and uses active learning out of the box. We support teams of annotators and have incorporated state of the art techniques for active learning and quality assurance. This makes it possible to get real time feedback during training, even when using modern deep models. We also make it easy to deploy to an optimised model run-time immediately after training and to even update your data post deployment.</p><h2 id="in-summary">In Summary</h2><p>Active Learning:</p><ul><li>reduces how much data you need to label, dramatically reducing one of your biggest costs.</li><li>gives you faster feedback on your model's performance.</li><li>producer higher performing models.</li></ul><p>At Humanloop we think that active learning should be a standard tool for data scientists. We also believe that good tools should make this easy.</p><p>There's more to Humanloop than active learning though. We're building infrastructure for AI models and human teams to work alongside each other so that anyone can quickly augment their team with AI assistance.</p><p>If you're interested in finding out more, send us a message or <a href="https://humanloop.com/demo">book a demo!</a></p>
    </div>

    

</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://humanloop.com/blog/why-you-should-be-using-active-learning/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26026949</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 16:38:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Snowflake Generator]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 11 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26025846">thread link</a>) | @woodgrainz
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | https://viviariums.com/projects/snowflake/interactive/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://viviariums.com/projects/snowflake/interactive/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="mobile-controls">
    
    <table>
      <tbody><tr>
        <td>
          Parameters:
        </td>
        <td>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;</td>
        <td>
          Growth:
        </td>
        <td>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;</td>
        <td>
          Kaleidoscope:
        </td>
        <td>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;</td>
        <td>
          Background:
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          
        </td>
        <td>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;</td>
        <td>
          
        </td>
        <td>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;</td>
        <td>
          
        </td>
        <td>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;</td>
        <td>
          
        </td>
      </tr>
    </tbody></table>
    <p>
      This is a simplified version for mobile.
      For all parameters, please visit this website on desktop.
      Made by <a href="https://viviariums.com/">Vivian Wu</a>.
    </p>
  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://viviariums.com/projects/snowflake/interactive/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26025846</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 15:01:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Collection of Human Interface and Software Design Guides]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 165 | Comments 17 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26025339">thread link</a>) | @ingve
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | http://www.geofcrowl.com/blog/articles/2020/2/17/collection-higs/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.geofcrowl.com/blog/articles/2020/2/17/collection-higs/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">

    

<section>

    

    

</section>





<section>

    <div>

        <article>

            <p>Monday, Feb. 17th 2020</p>

            <h3>
                Collection of Human Interface and Software Design Guides
                
            </h3>

            
                <p>After posting about the <a href="http://www.geofcrowl.com/blog/articles/2020/2/13/openstep-user-interface-guidelines/">OpenStep User Interface Guide</a>, I started to wonder how many different human interface guides or software design guides that I could find from the past and present. It doesn’t seem like there’s a good collection of these anywhere on the internet, especially in regard to past software design guides. I think there’s a lot of value in these even outside of just being a historic reference.</p>
<p>If you have a link or PDF of human interface or software design guidelines to past or present software that you think I should include, please contact me: <a href="https://twitter.com/rectangular">@rectangular</a>.</p>
<h5>Current</h5>
<p>Apple</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://developer.apple.com/design/human-interface-guidelines/macos/">macOS</a></li>
<li><a href="https://developer.apple.com/design/human-interface-guidelines/ios/">iOS</a></li>
<li><a href="https://developer.apple.com/design/human-interface-guidelines/watchos/">watchOS</a></li>
<li><a href="https://developer.apple.com/design/human-interface-guidelines/tvos/">tvOS</a></li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.elementary.io/">Elementary OS</a></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://elementary.io/docs/human-interface-guidelines#human-interface-guidelines">Elementary OS Human Interface Guidelines</a></li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.gnome.org/">Gnome Desktop Environment</a></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://developer.gnome.org/hig/stable/">GNOME 3.0 Human Interface Guidelines</a></li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.haiku-os.org/">Haiku</a></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.haiku-os.org/docs/HIG/index.xml">How to Design Software Good</a></li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://kde.org/">KDE</a></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://hig.kde.org/">KDE Human Interface Guidelines</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Microsoft</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/uwp/design/">Windows UWP: Design and code Windows apps</a></li>
</ul>
<h5>Archival</h5>
<p>Apple</p>
<ul>
<li>Macintosh Human Interface Guidlines: <a href="https://blog-geofcrowl-static-images.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/2020-02-17-collection-higs/Apple_HIGuidelines-1992.pdf">c. 1992</a>, <a href="https://blog-geofcrowl-static-images.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/2020-02-17-collection-higs/Apple_HIGuidelines-1995.pdf">c. 1995</a></li>
<li>Mac OS X Human Interface Guidelines: <a href="https://blog-geofcrowl-static-images.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/2020-02-17-collection-higs/APPLE-Guidelines-2005.pdf">c. 2005</a></li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.gnome.org/">Gnome Desktop Environment</a></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://developer.gnome.org/hig-book/2.32/">Gnome 2 Human Interface Guidelines</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blog-geofcrowl-static-images.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/2020-02-17-collection-higs/gnome-hig-1.0.pdf">Gnome 1 Human Interface Guidelines</a></li>
</ul>
<p>IBM</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://blog-geofcrowl-static-images.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/2020-02-17-collection-higs/IBM-UI-Guide-1988.pdf">User Interface Guidelines c. November 1988</a><sup>1</sup></li>
</ul>
<p>NeXT</p>
<ul>
<li>NeXTSTEP User Interface Guidelines: <a href="https://blog-geofcrowl-static-images.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/2020-02-17-collection-higs/NeXTSTEP_User_Interface_Guidelines_Release_3_Nov93.pdf">Release 3 c. Nov 1993</a></li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OpenStep">OpenStep</a> </p>
<ul>
<li>OpenStep User Interface Guidelines: <a href="https://blog-geofcrowl-static-images.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/2020-02-17-collection-higs/OpenStepUserInterfaceGuidelines.pdf">c. 1996</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Silicon Graphics, Inc.</p>
<ul>
<li>Indigo Magic User Interface Guidelines: <a href="https://blog-geofcrowl-static-images.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/2020-02-17-collection-higs/Indigo-Magic-User-Inteface-Guidelines-1994.pdf">c. 1994</a>, <a href="https://blog-geofcrowl-static-images.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/2020-02-17-collection-higs/Indigo-Magic-User-Inteface-Guidelines-1996.pdf">c. 1996</a>, <a href="https://blog-geofcrowl-static-images.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/2020-02-17-collection-higs/Indigo-Magic-User-Inteface-Guidelines-1996-2.pdf">c. 1996 v2</a></li>
<li>IRIX User Interface Guidelines: <a href="https://blog-geofcrowl-static-images.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/2020-02-17-collection-higs/IRIX-User-Inteface-Guidelines-1998.pdf">c. 1998</a>, <a href="https://blog-geofcrowl-static-images.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/2020-02-17-collection-higs/IRIX-User-Inteface-Guidelines-2001.pdf">c. 2001</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Sun Microsystems</p>
<ul>
<li>Common Desktop Environment: <a href="https://blog-geofcrowl-static-images.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/2020-02-17-collection-higs/CDE-style-guide-2002.pdf">c. 2002</a></li>
</ul>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> This is before IBM OS/2, so I assume it’s referencing DOS based applications.</small></p>
            


            
            <p>Updated on Saturday, Jan. 2nd 2021</p>
            

            
            
            

        </article>

    </div>

</section>







</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.geofcrowl.com/blog/articles/2020/2/17/collection-higs/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26025339</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 13:59:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Weave.jl – Scientific Reports Using Julia]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 123 | Comments 17 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26025265">thread link</a>) | @phillc73
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | https://weavejl.mpastell.com/stable/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://weavejl.mpastell.com/stable/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="documenter-settings"><div><header><p>Settings</p></header><section><p><label>Theme</label></p><hr><p>This document was generated with <a href="https://github.com/JuliaDocs/Documenter.jl">Documenter.jl</a> on <span title="Friday 2 October 2020 21:19">Friday 2 October 2020</span>. Using Julia version 1.5.2.</p></section></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://weavejl.mpastell.com/stable/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26025265</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 13:49:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Is __int128 Integral? A Survey]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 40 | Comments 16 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26025117">thread link</a>) | @ingve
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | https://quuxplusone.github.io/blog/2019/02/28/is-int128-integral/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://quuxplusone.github.io/blog/2019/02/28/is-int128-integral/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p>How well is <code>__int128</code> supported, and what are its
properties? A Godbolt-based survey of the Big Four compilers.
Spoiler alert: libc++ thinks it’s integral, libstdc++ thinks it’s integral
only in <code>-std=gnu++XX</code> mode(!), and MSVC thinks it doesn’t exist at all.</p>

<p>Many thanks to Rein Halbersma for alerting me to libstdc++’s different behavior
in <code>-std=gnu++XX</code> mode versus <code>-std=c++XX</code> mode.</p>

<h2 id="compiler-support">Compiler support</h2>



<p>GCC, Clang, and Intel ICC all support a built-in <code>__int128</code> type.
Microsoft MSVC does not support any 128-bit integral type as far as I’m aware.</p>

<p>On GCC, Clang, and ICC, <code>__int128</code> is a token similar to <code>int</code>: you can modify
it with <code>unsigned</code> to produce <code>unsigned __int128</code>. However, all three front-ends
also support the built-in synonyms <code>__int128_t</code> and <code>__uint128_t</code>.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>static_assert(std::is_same_v&lt;__int128_t, __int128&gt;);
static_assert(std::is_same_v&lt;__uint128_t, unsigned __int128&gt;);
    // PASSES on all three compilers
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Both <code>__int128_t</code> and <code>__uint128_t</code> are safe to use in non-type template parameters
and constant expressions, on all compilers that support them.</p>

<h2 id="sneaky-macros">Sneaky macros</h2>

<p>The story on libstdc++ is complicated. Libstdc++ doesn’t do anything special for
<code>__int128</code>, but it does provide <em>macro hooks</em>
(<a href="https://github.com/gcc-mirror/gcc/blob/87798f3f2cf97b30e75110b5a8d2964aef62be02/libstdc%2B%2B-v3/include/std/type_traits#L285-L293">link</a>)
so that for example
<code>__GLIBCXX_TYPE_INT_N_0</code> will be treated as an integral type, whatever that macro
expands to. (If it doesn’t expand to anything, it’ll be ignored.)</p>

<p>If you compile with GCC in <code>-std=c++XX</code> mode (for any <code>XX</code>),
<code>__GLIBCXX_TYPE_INT_N_0</code> won’t be defined and so libstdc++ will consider
<code>__int128</code> a non-integral type.</p>

<p>But if you compile with GCC in <code>-std=gnu++XX</code> mode (for any <code>XX</code>), then the compiler
will pre-define these two macros:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>#define __GLIBCXX_BITSIZE_INT_N_0 128
#define __GLIBCXX_TYPE_INT_N_0 __int128
</code></pre></div></div>

<p><a href="https://bugs.llvm.org/show_bug.cgi?id=23156">As of July 2016-ish</a>, Clang also
defines these two macros in <code>-std=gnu++XX</code> mode.</p>

<p>By the way, you can use the options <code>-dM -E</code> to view all your compiler’s pre-defined macros:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>clang++ -std=c++17 -dM -E test.cc
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The upshot is, if you compile in <code>-std=gnu++XX</code> mode, libstdc++ will treat <code>__int128</code> and
<code>unsigned __int128</code> as integral types with the proper numeric limits; but if you
compile in the usual <code>-std=c++XX</code> mode, libstdc++ will not do any of that.</p>

<p>On the other hand, libc++ treats <code>__int128</code> as an integer type, full stop.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I’ve worked on several projects that compiled with <code>-std=c++17 -D_GNU_SOURCE</code>. That
will give you a lot of GNU library extensions, but it will not give you <code>__int128</code> support.
libstdc++ is looking specifically for the two macros defined above, and <code>-D_GNU_SOURCE</code>
doesn’t enable those macros.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="relationship-to-integer-types-and-intmax_t">Relationship to integer types and <code>intmax_t</code></h2>

<div><div><pre><code>static_assert(std::is_integral_v&lt;__int128&gt;);
    // TRUE on libc++, "it depends" on libstdc++
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>libstdc++ (in standard, non-<code>gnu++XX</code> mode) leaves <code>is_integral_v&lt;__int128&gt;</code> as <code>false</code>.
This makes a certain amount of sense from the library implementor’s point of view,
because <code>__int128</code> is not one of the <em>standard</em> integral types, and furthermore,
if you <em>call</em> it integral, then you have to face the consequence that <code>intmax_t</code>
(which is 64 bits on every ABI that matters) is kind of lying about being the
“max.”</p>

<p>In <code>-std=gnu++XX</code> mode, libstdc++ makes <code>is_integral_v&lt;__int128&gt;</code> come out to <code>true</code>,
as described in the previous section on sneaky macros.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, libc++ simply
<a href="https://github.com/llvm-mirror/libcxx/blob/aeeba70ab15e1469841c0f3f1f9c78211a541699/include/type_traits#L738-L741">sets</a>
sets <code>is_integral_v&lt;__int128&gt;</code> to <code>true</code>, unconditionally.</p>

<p>Yes, this means that on libc++ (or on libstdc++ with <code>-std=gnu++17</code>), there exist
integral values that do not fit in <code>intmax_t</code>! (<a href="https://godbolt.org/z/lMD4Iu">Godbolt.</a>)</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>In case you’re wondering: libstdc++ in standard C++17 mode considers <code>__int128</code> a “compound” type.
The definition of “compound type” is simply “anything that’s not a fundamental type,”
where “fundamental” encompasses the arithmetic types (both integral and floating-point), <code>void</code>,
and <code>nullptr_t</code>. So for example <code>int*</code> is also a compound type.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="numeric-limits">Numeric limits</h2>

<p>In standard (non-<code>gnu++XX</code>) mode, libstdc++ does not specialize <code>numeric_limits</code> for <code>__int128</code> at all.
This <a href="https://godbolt.org/z/RpaD-7">has the unfortunate effect</a> of</p>

<div><div><pre><code>constexpr __int128 int128_max =
    std::numeric_limits&lt;__int128&gt;::max();
static_assert(int128_max == 0);  // TRUE on libstdc++ in standard mode
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>libc++ (and libstdc++ in <code>gnu++XX</code> mode) provides the appropriate specialization, so that
<code>numeric_limits&lt;__int128&gt;::min()</code> and <code>numeric_limits&lt;__int128&gt;::max()</code>
have the appropriate values instead of zero.</p>

<p>On libc++ <a href="https://godbolt.org/z/ZR_nn6"><code>numeric_limits</code> reports <code>__int128</code> as an integral type</a>,
whereas on libstdc++ in standard mode it doesn’t (again because there is no specialization for
<code>__int128</code> at all).</p>

<div><div><pre><code>static_assert(std::numeric_limits&lt;I128&gt;::is_integer);
    // TRUE on libc++, "it depends" on libstdc++
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="signedness">Signedness</h2>

<p>libc++ reports that <code>is_signed_v&lt;__int128&gt;</code> and <code>is_unsigned_v&lt;unsigned __int128&gt;</code>.
libstdc++ in standard mode of course denies both, because only arithmetic types can be
signed or unsigned, and libstdc++ denies that <code>__int128</code> is arithmetic.</p>

<p>As for <code>make_signed</code>, libc++ (and libstdc++ in <code>gnu++XX</code> mode) reports what you’d expect —
<code>make_signed&lt;__uint128_t&gt;::type</code> is <code>__int128_t</code>, and <code>make_unsigned&lt;__int128_t&gt;::type</code> is <code>__uint128_t</code>.</p>

<p>Trying to instantiate <code>make_signed&lt;__uint128_t&gt;</code> on libstdc++ in standard mode
<a href="https://godbolt.org/z/j7BvKB">results in</a> a hard error which is not SFINAE-friendly.
(It’s undefined behavior to instantiate <code>make_signed</code> of any type which is neither
integral nor an enumeration type.)</p>

<p>Incidentally, today I learned that <code>is_signed_v&lt;float&gt; == true</code> but <a href="https://godbolt.org/z/t6v1CJ"><code>make_signed_t&lt;float&gt;</code>
is a hard error</a>.</p>

<hr>

<p>For more on <code>__uint128_t</code> arithmetic, see
<a href="https://quuxplusone.github.io/blog/2020/02/13/wide-integer-proof-of-concept/">“The abstraction penalty for wide integer math on x86-64”</a> (2020-02-13).</p>

  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://quuxplusone.github.io/blog/2019/02/28/is-int128-integral/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26025117</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 13:28:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What Is React: A Visual Introduction for Beginners]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 98 | Comments 73 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26025085">thread link</a>) | @focuser
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | https://learnreact.design/posts/what-is-react | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://learnreact.design/posts/what-is-react">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><h2><a id="introduction" href="#introduction"><svg stroke="currentColor" fill="none" stroke-width="2" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" height="20" width="20" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71"></path><path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71"></path></svg>Introduction</a></h2><blockquote><p>React is a JavaScript library for building user interfaces.</p></blockquote><p>This is the official definition of React. But what if you are not familiar with JavaScript? What if you are not a developer? Would you still be able to make sense of (and learn) React?</p><p>My answer is a firm YES. That's why I wrote this article: what is React exactly? Why is it so popular? What problems does React solve?</p><p>This article is an introduction to React for beginners. It's the first post you'd want to read before learning the specifics of React. I'll explain the core ideas of React in plain English (and doodles <span>🌴</span>). No JavaScript experience? No problem! As long as you have some basic HTML knowledge (e.g. the format of an HTML tag), you should be able to enjoy this article.</p><p>This is a bird's-eye view <span>🦅</span> but I'll also equip you with a pair of binoculars <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="25" height="25" viewBox="0 -48 512 512"><g fill="#40404c"><path d="M211.023 137.027h89.95v145.938h-89.95zm0 0M298.3 72.402V52.211c0-24.637 19.973-44.61 44.614-44.61a44.665 44.665 0 0124.809 7.528 44.657 44.657 0 0116.425 20.066l7.207 17.473"></path><path d="M279.29 123.621v171.84l128.757-23.563 89.082-16.308L430.344 93.69a78.505 78.505 0 00-28.906-35.308 78.457 78.457 0 00-47.641-13.153c-41.5 2.067-74.508 36.383-74.508 78.391zm0 0"></path></g><path fill="#5b5b68" d="M353.797 45.23l54.25 226.668 89.082-16.308L430.344 93.69a78.505 78.505 0 00-28.906-35.308 78.457 78.457 0 00-47.641-13.153zm0 0"></path><path fill="#e4e4ef" d="M504.398 295.457c0 62.164-50.394 112.559-112.558 112.559-62.164 0-112.555-50.395-112.555-112.559 0-62.164 50.39-112.559 112.555-112.559 62.164 0 112.558 50.395 112.558 112.559zm0 0"></path><path fill="#40404c" d="M471.434 295.457c0 43.957-35.637 79.59-79.594 79.59-43.953 0-79.59-35.633-79.59-79.59s35.637-79.59 79.59-79.59c43.957 0 79.594 35.633 79.594 79.59zm0 0"></path><path fill="#589ce0" d="M314.191 277.918c7.985 35.52 39.715 62.062 77.641 62.062 37.922 0 69.664-26.542 77.648-62.062-7.984-35.52-39.714-62.055-77.64-62.055-37.934 0-69.664 26.535-77.649 62.055zm0 0"></path><path fill="#40404c" d="M120.645 52.668l7.203-17.473a44.69 44.69 0 0116.43-20.066 44.665 44.665 0 0124.808-7.527c24.637 0 44.613 19.972 44.613 44.609v20.191"></path><path fill="#5b5b68" d="M232.71 123.621v171.84l-128.757-23.563-89.082-16.308L81.656 93.69a78.522 78.522 0 0128.903-35.308 78.479 78.479 0 0147.644-13.153c41.5 2.067 74.508 36.383 74.508 78.391zm0 0"></path><path fill="#40404c" d="M158.203 45.23l-54.25 226.668-89.082-16.308L81.656 93.69a78.522 78.522 0 0128.903-35.308 78.479 78.479 0 0147.644-13.153zm0 0"></path><path fill="#e4e4ef" d="M232.715 295.457c0 62.164-50.39 112.559-112.555 112.559-62.164 0-112.558-50.395-112.558-112.559 0-62.164 50.394-112.559 112.558-112.559 62.164 0 112.555 50.395 112.555 112.559zm0 0"></path><path fill="#40404c" d="M199.75 295.457c0 43.957-35.637 79.59-79.59 79.59-43.957 0-79.594-35.633-79.594-79.59s35.637-79.59 79.594-79.59c43.953 0 79.59 35.633 79.59 79.59zm0 0"></path><path fill="#589ce0" d="M197.809 277.918c-7.985 35.52-39.715 62.062-77.641 62.062-37.922 0-69.664-26.542-77.648-62.062 7.984-35.52 39.714-62.055 77.64-62.055 37.934 0 69.664 26.535 77.649 62.055zm0 0"></path><path fill="#357fbc" d="M89.21 295.46c0 15.548 4.45 30.04 12.165 42.29-29.281-7.094-52.234-30.371-58.863-59.832 7.988-35.52 39.718-62.055 77.64-62.055a79.306 79.306 0 0124.325 3.793C112.422 229.93 89.21 259.98 89.21 295.461zm0 0M360.89 295.46c0 15.548 4.45 30.04 12.165 42.29-29.282-7.094-52.235-30.371-58.864-59.832 7.989-35.52 39.72-62.055 77.641-62.055 8.484 0 16.66 1.328 24.324 3.793-32.054 10.274-55.265 40.324-55.265 75.805zm0 0"></path><path d="M120.16 208.266c-48.078 0-87.191 39.113-87.191 87.191s39.113 87.191 87.191 87.191c48.074 0 87.188-39.113 87.188-87.191s-39.114-87.191-87.188-87.191zm0 15.203c33.645 0 61.961 23.203 69.817 54.445-3.766 15.024-12.426 28.625-24.551 38.45-12.75 10.327-28.824 16.015-45.262 16.015-16.441 0-32.516-5.688-45.27-16.016-12.124-9.824-20.789-23.425-24.554-38.449 7.855-31.242 36.172-54.445 69.82-54.445zm0 143.976c-33.863 0-62.32-23.504-69.96-55.05a87.387 87.387 0 0015.128 15.78c15.45 12.516 34.922 19.407 54.836 19.407 19.91 0 39.383-6.89 54.832-19.406a87.712 87.712 0 0015.121-15.778c-7.644 31.543-36.097 55.047-69.957 55.047zm0 0"></path><path d="M504.188 252.852a225.242 225.242 0 00-2.055-5.059l-64.762-157c-7.98-19.344-22.355-34.59-40.105-43.727l-6.09-14.77A52.095 52.095 0 00371.94 8.81 52.135 52.135 0 00342.911 0c-28.79 0-52.212 23.422-52.212 52.21v17.528c-11.883 14.766-19.02 33.504-19.02 53.887v5.8h-31.363v-5.8c0-20.383-7.136-39.121-19.02-53.887V52.211C221.297 23.42 197.876 0 169.087 0c-10.36 0-20.399 3.047-29.04 8.816a52.092 52.092 0 00-19.226 23.48l-6.09 14.77C96.984 56.203 82.605 71.45 74.63 90.793l-16.625 40.3a7.6 7.6 0 004.129 9.927 7.593 7.593 0 009.922-4.13l16.625-40.3c10.992-26.645 36.718-43.86 65.539-43.86 39.09 0 70.894 31.801 70.894 70.895V237.02c-20.566-36.79-59.902-61.723-104.957-61.723-28.219 0-54.191 9.785-74.719 26.129l16.407-39.774c1.601-3.879-.25-8.324-4.13-9.925-3.878-1.602-8.323.25-9.925 4.128L9.867 247.79c-.594 1.367-2.215 5.414-2.289 5.672C2.684 266.539 0 280.69 0 295.457c0 66.254 53.902 120.156 120.16 120.156 66.254 0 120.156-53.902 120.156-120.156v-4.89h31.368v4.89c0 66.254 53.902 120.156 120.156 120.156 66.258 0 120.16-53.902 120.16-120.156 0-14.996-2.77-29.355-7.813-42.605zM154.217 37.527c-6.874 0-13.6.82-20.081 2.36l.738-1.793a36.915 36.915 0 0113.621-16.64 36.969 36.969 0 0120.59-6.255c20.406 0 37.012 16.606 37.012 37.012v2.754c-14.438-10.934-32.41-17.438-51.88-17.438zM342.915 15.2c7.344 0 14.461 2.164 20.578 6.246a36.926 36.926 0 0113.633 16.649l.738 1.793a86.64 86.64 0 00-20.086-2.36c-19.465 0-37.437 6.504-51.875 17.438V52.21c0-20.406 16.602-37.012 37.012-37.012zm-56.027 108.426c0-39.094 31.8-70.895 70.894-70.895 28.82 0 54.547 17.215 65.535 43.86l43.247 104.836c-20.528-16.344-46.504-26.13-74.723-26.13-45.055 0-84.39 24.934-104.953 61.72zm-15.203 21.004v72.969h-31.368v-72.97zM120.16 400.414c-57.875 0-104.957-47.082-104.957-104.957S62.285 190.5 120.16 190.5c57.871 0 104.953 47.082 104.953 104.957S178.031 400.414 120.16 400.414zm120.156-125.05v-42.567h31.368v42.566zm151.524 125.05c-57.871 0-104.953-47.082-104.953-104.957S333.969 190.5 391.84 190.5c57.875 0 104.957 47.082 104.957 104.957S449.715 400.414 391.84 400.414zm0 0"></path><path d="M450.883 241.547c-3.356 2.523-4.024 7.289-1.5 10.644 5.844 7.758 9.976 16.438 12.289 25.66-3.758 15.047-12.426 28.676-24.57 38.512-12.747 10.328-28.82 16.016-45.262 16.016-16.438 0-32.516-5.688-45.266-16.016-12.125-9.82-20.789-23.422-24.554-38.441 7.851-31.246 36.171-54.453 69.82-54.453 14.426 0 28.344 4.25 40.242 12.289a7.599 7.599 0 0010.555-2.043 7.6 7.6 0 00-2.043-10.555c-14.422-9.742-31.282-14.894-48.754-14.894-48.078 0-87.192 39.113-87.192 87.191s39.114 87.191 87.192 87.191 87.191-39.113 87.191-87.191c0-19.082-6.054-37.207-17.508-52.41-2.52-3.356-7.285-4.027-10.64-1.5zM391.84 367.445c-33.856 0-62.313-23.5-69.953-55.043a87.422 87.422 0 0015.12 15.774c15.45 12.515 34.923 19.406 54.837 19.406 19.91 0 39.383-6.89 54.832-19.406A87.382 87.382 0 00461.8 312.39c-7.64 31.55-36.098 55.054-69.961 55.054zm0 0"></path></svg> . You'll not only see the <strong>big picture</strong> of what makes React special, but also zoom in to get some <strong>hands-on experience</strong> of writing an actual React component. And yes, no JS knowledge required!</p><p>Remember: You don't need to be an experienced developer to understand the core ideas of React!</p><p>Ready to start the journey?</p><div><p>Of course, eventually you'd need to write code to use React. That's why I'm building an email course to help you on that.</p><p>I believe you'd be able to do useful work with React after a few days of learning, <strong>even if you are new to coding</strong>. If you are interested, sign up and I'll let you know when the course is ready!</p></div><h2><a id="a-few-things-about-the-web" href="#a-few-things-about-the-web"><svg stroke="currentColor" fill="none" stroke-width="2" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" height="20" width="20" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71"></path><path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71"></path></svg>A few things about the Web</a></h2><p>Let's get started with something you might have heard many times, the DOM.</p><h3><a id="what-is-the-dom" href="#what-is-the-dom"><svg stroke="currentColor" fill="none" stroke-width="2" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" height="20" width="20" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71"></path><path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71"></path></svg>What is the DOM?</a></h3><p>When you enter the address of your favorite website into a browser, your computer starts a conversation with another computer far away, commonly referred to as <em>server</em>. Typically your computer makes a request for some information and the server responds:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Your computer:</strong> Yo, what's good about this random site learnreact.design?</p><p><strong>The server:</strong> Hang on, let me grab something for you. Beep. Boop.</p></blockquote><p>The main part of the server's response usually includes three items: HTML, CSS and JavaScript.</p><p>HTML lists the content of a web page and describes its structure. How many headings and paragraphs are there? What images should a user see? Are this button and that textbox contained in the same box?</p><p>Using this information, the browser creates something called... the DOM!</p><div><p><img alt="Introducing the DOM" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7" decoding="async"></p></div><p>Wait a second, the DOM is a ... tree? Yup, a tree! Oddly enough, a lot of things in our computer look like a tree. Let's give our tree friend a nickname... hmm what about Domo?</p><p>Domo works as a model at the prestigious art studio "Web Browser". His job is to pose in front of the artist who paints a portrait (or perhaps millions of portraits).</p><div><p><img alt="Domo at the art studio Web Browser" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7" decoding="async"></p></div><p>In real life, DOM stands for Document Object Model. It's indeed a model -- a model of the document (aka the web page). It strikes a pose. The browser paints a portrait. The portraits are what we see on a web page: the textboxes, the paragraphs, the images and so on. A developer's job is like that of a director who tells Domo what to wear and what pose to strike. This determines what those portraits look like in the end.</p><p>To check out what the DOM looks like, if you are using a desktop browser, right-click on this very page and choose "Inspect". Can you make sense of what's in the Elements tab?</p><div><p><img alt="Inspect in Chrome" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7" decoding="async"></p></div><h3><a id="the-dom-api" href="#the-dom-api"><svg stroke="currentColor" fill="none" stroke-width="2" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" height="20" width="20" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71"></path><path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71"></path></svg>The DOM API</a></h3><p>We often want a web page to be dynamic and interactive -- that means its content changes from time to time: adding or removing text here and there, showing a modal, or updating a chart based on some new data coming from the server.</p><p>Remember, in order to change what's on a web page, we need to update the DOM. The artist isn't able to paint new portraits until Domo changes to a new pose.</p><p>How would we get Domo to change to a new pose?</p><p>We just talk to him. He listens. Interestingly, Domo's ears happen to have a name: <em>DOM API</em>.</p><div><p><img alt="A developer works with DOM API" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7" decoding="async"></p></div><p>To manipulate the DOM, a developer would write code in JavaScript which talks to the DOM API, and in turn, updates the content of the web page.</p><h3><a id="the-increasing-complexity" href="#the-increasing-complexity"><svg stroke="currentColor" fill="none" stroke-width="2" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" height="20" width="20" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71"></path><path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71"></path></svg>The increasing complexity</a></h3><p><em>Directly</em> talking to Domo has been the standard approach of web development for years, especially when the web content was mostly static. A developer would sprinkle some interactivity on top of the static pages by writing small amount of JavaScript code.</p><p>However, with the emergence of SPAs (Single Page Application) such as Gmail and Google Maps, people started to expect a lot more. Instead of mostly static web <em>pages</em>, they want web <em>apps</em> that are interactive, fast and responsive.</p><p>The code required to build web apps becomes increasingly large and complex. It often requires the collaboration of many team members.</p><p>The traditional approach stopped working. It becomes chaotic and inefficient to always directly talk to Domo.</p><div><p><img alt="Directly working with the DOM API is getting chaotic" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7" decoding="async"></p></div><h2><a id="the-core-ideas-of-react" href="#the-core-ideas-of-react"><svg stroke="currentColor" fill="none" stroke-width="2" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" height="20" width="20" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71"></path><path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71"></path></svg>The Core Ideas of React</a></h2><p>Let me introduce you to the superhero, React:</p><div><p><img alt="Introducing React" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7" decoding="async"></p></div><p>With React, developers no longer directly talk to Domo. React acts as an agent between a developer and Domo. He smoothens the communication and streamlines the process of portrait creation.</p><div><p><img alt="React as an agent between a developer and the DOM" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7" decoding="async"></p></div><p>React is made up of JavaScript code. It's built in a way that we no longer need to directly work with the DOM API in most cases. Instead, we write simpler code while React handles the conversation with the DOM under the hood.</p><p>React has a few superpowers to tackle the ever-growing complexity of web development:</p><ul><li>Components</li><li>Declarative UI</li><li>Reactive DOM updates</li></ul><p>If these terms sound scary to you, don't be intimidated! As promised, I'll use plain English and doodles to help you make sense of them. Trust me, it's not that hard!</p><p>Just read on!</p><h3><a id="components" href="#components"><svg stroke="currentColor" fill="none" stroke-width="2" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" height="20" width="20" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71"></path><path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71"></path></svg>Components</a></h3><p>Components are the flagship feature of React. The core idea is based on a simple strategy: divide-and-conquer. If it's difficult to grok a problem all at once, we break it into smaller problems, solve them one at a time and then combine the results.</p><div><p><img alt="React breaks a problem into components" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7" decoding="async"></p></div><p>Building an app in React is almost all about working with components: breaking the app into components, finding the best components for the job, fitting one with another, creating new components from existing ones etc.</p><p>Nowadays, design tools such as Framer and Figma have components too (and symbols in Sketch). They are a lot like React components, except that the latter are more flexible and powerful. In fact, the inspiration of components in design tools came directly from components in software engineering. Once a component is created, we can create multiple instances of it. We can use it to construct other components. If we change a component, everything that includes this component will be updated automatically.</p><p>Components in React have two important properties:</p><ol><li>Components are <em>composable</em>. They are made for reuse. We can make a new component with other components.</li><li>Components are <em>independent</em> of each other. If we change the code in one place, other parts don't break.</li></ol><p>If this sounds abstract to you, don't worry! I'll show you some examples and explain these properties in details soon.</p><h3><a id="declarative-ui" href="#declarative-ui"><svg stroke="currentColor" fill="none" stroke-width="2" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" height="20" width="20" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71"></path><path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71"></path></svg>Declarative UI</a></h3><h4><a id="imperative-vs-declarative" href="#imperative-vs-declarative"><svg stroke="currentColor" fill="none" stroke-width="2" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" height="20" width="20" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71"></path><path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71"></path></svg>Imperative vs. declarative</a></h4><p>When directly working with the DOM API, we'd have to specify what element to change at the right time, in the right order. This is equivalent to describing to Domo how to position his head, arms and legs step by step, for each and every portrait.</p><div><p><img alt="Imperative programming" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7" decoding="async"></p></div><p>Heck, this sounds tedious and error-prone! Why can't we just tell Domo <em>what</em> we want instead of <em>how</em> to pose? In fact, this is exactly how to build a UI in React. A developer draws a quick sketch of what he or she wants. React explains it to Domo how to pose.</p><div><p><img alt="Declarative programming in React" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7" decoding="async"></p></div><p>Because the apps we build are dynamic, we often want Domo to change poses fairly quickly. We draw many sketches and hand them to React in a big pile. React stacks these sketches together and flips them like a flipbook. A dynamic UI comes live!</p><div><p><img alt="React treats input as a flipbook" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7" decoding="async"></p></div><p>In tech terms, if the code defines <em>how</em> we want it to be done, it's <strong>imperative</strong>; if it defines <em>what</em> we want, it's <strong>declarative</strong>. The traditional way of directly working with the DOM API is imperative, and the React way is declarative.</p><p>Imperative programming emerged from the day when the computers were primitive. People had to instruct them in detail: where to store the numbers, how to multiply etc. But this eventually got unmanageable, people wrote smart software that convert definition of problems into detailed instructions. Declarative programming was born.</p><h4><a id="virtual-dom" href="#virtual-dom"><svg stroke="currentColor" fill="none" stroke-width="2" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" height="20" width="20" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71"></path><path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71"></path></svg>Virtual DOM</a></h4><p>Besides making the life of a developer easier, declarative programming in React also offers opportunities for performance optimization.</p><p>When React has all the sketches beforehand, he can sort through them, remove any duplication and make sure that Domo and the artist do as little work as possible.</p><div><p><img alt="React diffing with virtual DOM" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7" decoding="async"></p></div><p>These sketches are called <em>Virtual DOM</em>. Virtual DOM is much faster to manipulate than the DOM. Developers work with Virtual DOM most of the time instead of directly managing the DOM. React handles the dirty work of managing the slow DOM.</p><h3><a id="reactive-dom-updates" href="#reactive-dom-updates"><svg stroke="currentColor" fill="none" stroke-width="2" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" height="20" width="20" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71"></path><path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71"></path></svg>Reactive DOM updates</a></h3><p>Even cooler, imagine if we can leave placeholders in our sketches to represent different variations of a same pose. This way, when somebody asks for portraits of Domo wearing a different hat, we don't have to talk to React again. We can just sit back and let React change it for us.</p><div><p><img alt="Thinker with a hat: Placeholder in JSX" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7" decoding="async"></p></div><p>This trick is how React got its name. The UI built with React is <strong>reactive</strong> -- it appears that the DOM "reacts" to any changes to the underlying data. No need to track the data. No need to worry about when to update the DOM. It just gets updated automatically (by React). The idea of reactive UI greatly simplifies UI development.</p><div><div><p>Now let's review what we have learned so far and get our hands dirty on a few real React components. To make it easy for you to understand, I left out some details in the code (notedly JavaScript). The goal is to let the core ideas shine through without being bogged down by JS syntax. If you are comfortable with reading JavaScript code, feel free to check out the <a href="https://codesandbox.io/s/domos-hat-shop-4x7n0?file=/src/App.js" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">real source code</a>.</p><p>Alright. Let's say we want to help Domo build an online hat store 🧢 .</p><h3><a id="components-are-composable" href="#components-are-composable"><svg stroke="currentColor" fill="none" stroke-width="2" viewBox="0 0 24 24" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" height="20" width="20" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path d="M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71"></path><path d="M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71"></path></svg>Components are composable</a></h3><p>We can break the UI into a few parts:</p><ul><li>Header: the header on the top</li><li>Main: the main content area</li><li>Footer: the footer on …</li></ul></div></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://learnreact.design/posts/what-is-react">https://learnreact.design/posts/what-is-react</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://learnreact.design/posts/what-is-react</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26025085</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 13:23:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Improving texture atlas allocation in WebRender]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 73 | Comments 11 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26025053">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | https://nical.github.io/posts/etagere.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nical.github.io/posts/etagere.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p>Lately I have been working on improving texture atlas allocation in WebRender. It isn't an outstanding technical feat, but the journey towards achieving this goal was quite pleasant. </p>
<p>This is a longer version of the piece I published in the <a href="https://mozillagfx.wordpress.com/2021/02/04/improving-texture-atlas-allocation-in-webrender/">mozilla gfx team blog</a> where I focus on the atlas allocation algorithms. In this one I'll go into more details about the process and methodology behind these improvements.</p>
<p>The first part is about the making of guillotiere, a crate that I first released in March 2019. In the second part we'll have a look at more recent work building upon what I did with guillotiere, to improve texture memory usage in WebRender/Firefox.</p>

<p>In order to submit work to the GPU efficiently, WebRender groups as many drawing primitives as it can into what we call batches. A batch is submitted to the GPU as a single drawing command and has a few constraints. for example a batch can only reference a fixed set of resources (such as GPU buffers and textures). So in order to group as many drawing primitives as possible in a single batch we need to place as many drawing parameters as possible in few resources. When rendering text, WebRender pre-renders the glyphs before compositing them on the screen  so this means packing as many pre-rendered glyphs as possible into a single texture, and the same applies for rendering images and various other things.</p>
<p>For a moment let's simplify the case of images and text and assume that it is the same problem: input images (rectangles) of various rectangular sizes that we need to pack into a larger rectangle. This is the job of the texture atlas allocator. Another common name for this is rectangle bin packing.</p>
<p><img alt="Atlas allocation" src="https://nical.github.io/images/atlas/atlas-allocation.svg"></p>
<p>Many in game and web development are used to packing many images into fewer assets. In most cases this can be achieved at build time Which means that the texture atlas allocator only needs to find a good layout for a fixed set of rectangles without supporting dynamic deallocation and allocation within the atlas at run time. I call this "static" atlas allocation as opposed to "dynamic" atlas allocation.</p>
<p>There's a lot more literature out there about static than dynamic atlas allocation. I recommend reading <a href="http://pds25.egloos.com/pds/201504/21/98/RectangleBinPack.pdf"><em>A thousand ways to pack the bin</em></a> which is a very good survey of various static packing algorithms. Dynamic atlas allocation is unfortunately more difficult to implement while keeping good run-time performance. WebRender needs to maintain texture atlases into which items are added and removed over time. In other words we don't have a way around needing dynamic atlas allocation.</p>

<p>A while back, WebRender had a naive implementation of the guillotine algorithm (explained in <a href="http://pds25.egloos.com/pds/201504/21/98/RectangleBinPack.pdf"><em>A thousand ways to pack the bin</em></a>). This algorithm strikes a good compromise between packing quality and implementation complexity.
The main idea behind it can be explained simply: "Maintain a list of free rectangles, find one that can hold your allocation, split the requested allocation size out of it, creating up to two additional rectangles that are added back to the free list.". There is subtlety in which free rectangle to choose and how to split it, but the overall, the algorithm is built upon reassuringly understandable concepts.</p>
<p><img alt="Guillotine allocation steps" src="https://nical.github.io/images/atlas/guillotine-alloc.svg"></p>
<p>Deallocation could simply consist of adding the deallocated rectangle back to the free list, but without some way to merge back neighbor free rectangles, the atlas would quickly get into a fragmented stated with a lot of small free rectangles and can't allocate larger ones anymore.</p>
<p><img alt="Fragmented state" src="https://nical.github.io/images/atlas/fragmented.svg"></p>
<p>To address that, WebRender's implementation would regularly do a O(n²) complexity search to find and merge neighbor free rectangles, which was very slow when dealing with thousands of items. Eventually we stopped using the  guillotine allocator in systems that needed support for deallocation, replacing it with a very simple slab allocator which I'll get back to later in this post.</p>
<p>I wasn't satisfied with moving to a worse allocator because of the run-time defragmentation issue, so as a side project I wrote a guillotine allocator that tracks rectangle splits in a tree in order to find and merge neighbor free rectangle in constant instead of quadratic time. I published it in the <a href="https://crates.io/crates/guillotiere">guillotiere</a> crate. I wrote about how it works in details in <a href="https://docs.rs/guillotiere/0.6.0/guillotiere/struct.AtlasAllocator.html">the documentation</a> so I won't go over it here. I'm quite happy about how it turned out, although I haven't pushed to use it in WebRender, mostly because I wanted to first see evidence that it would help and I already had evidence that many other things needed to be worked on.</p>
<h2>Visualizing program state using SVG</h2>
<p>guillotiere lets you dump a visualization of the atlas in SVG format.</p>
<p><img alt="Guillotine allocation visualization" src="https://nical.github.io/images/atlas/guillotine-example-1.svg"></p>
<p>The image above shows the state of the atlas after a few allocations. Allocated space is represented in light blue while free space is in dark gray. It is much easier to work with than a list of coordinates in plain text. It was handy when developing and tuning the algorithm, but also when using it in other projects. While looking at the visual representation of the state animate you quickly develop an intuition of how the algorithm unfolds Concepts that are hard to explain in written form sometimes just "make sense" visually.</p>
<p>Dumping visual representations in a .svg file is not only a powerful tool when exploring problem some spaces, it is also surprisingly simple to do. SVG is a straightforward XML type of format which is annoying to type by hand but effortless to generate with very simple helpers. Here is how it looks using a tiny helper crate called <a href="https://crates.io/crates/svg_fmt">svg_fmt</a>:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>    </span><span>use</span><span> </span><span>svg_fmt</span>::<span>*</span><span>;</span><span></span>

<span>    </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>mut</span><span> </span><span>output</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>std</span>::<span>fs</span>::<span>File</span>::<span>create</span><span>(</span><span>"tmp.svg"</span><span>).</span><span>unwrap</span><span>();</span><span></span>

<span>    </span><span>// Need this at the beginning of the file. Set the size of the drawable area to 800x600.</span>
<span>    </span><span>writeln</span><span>!</span><span>(</span><span>output</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>"{}"</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>BeginSvg</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span> </span><span>w</span>: <span>800.0</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>h</span>: <span>600.0</span><span> </span><span>})</span><span>?</span><span>;</span><span></span>

<span>    </span><span>// Draw a rectangle.</span>
<span>    </span><span>writeln</span><span>!</span><span>(</span><span></span>
<span>        </span><span>output</span><span>,</span><span></span>
<span>        </span><span>r#"    {}"#</span><span>,</span><span></span>
<span>        </span><span>rectangle</span><span>(</span><span>10.0</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>10.0</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>100.0</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>200.0</span><span>)</span><span></span>
<span>            </span><span>.</span><span>fill</span><span>(</span><span>rgb</span><span>(</span><span>40</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>40</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>40</span><span>))</span><span></span>
<span>            </span><span>.</span><span>stroke</span><span>(</span><span>Stroke</span>::<span>Color</span><span>(</span><span>black</span><span>(),</span><span> </span><span>1.0</span><span>))</span><span></span>
<span>    </span><span>)</span><span>?</span><span>;</span><span></span>

<span>    </span><span>// Draw some text at position 100.0 100.0</span>
<span>    </span><span>writeln</span><span>!</span><span>(</span><span>output</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>"{}"</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>text</span><span>(</span><span>100.0</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>100.0</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>"Some text!"</span><span>.</span><span>to_string</span><span>()));</span><span></span>

<span>    </span><span>// Need this at the end.</span>
<span>    </span><span>writeln</span><span>!</span><span>(</span><span>output</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>"{}"</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>EndSvg</span><span>)</span><span>?</span><span>;</span><span></span>
</code></pre></div>


<p>So many useful visualizations can be easily built out of simple colored rectangles and text and there's other primitives provided by svg_fmt. Rectangles were all I needed in guillotiere.</p>
<p>You can look at <a href="https://github.com/nical/rust_debug/blob/492600cac47f64bcadaf9ad037ed64c5fecc8e63/svg_fmt/src/svg.rs">how simple the svg_fmt code is</a>. It has become a dependency to most of the things I've worked on lately, including WebRender which uses it to dump visualizations of texture atlases and the render graph.</p>
<p><img alt="Render graph visualization" src="https://nical.github.io/images/atlas/rendergraph.svg"></p>
<p>My hope by now is that if you are working on problems that can be represented in 2D space, I've managed to convince you of how easily you can supplement or break free of reading text in your debugger/terminal. If anything, just <code>println!(r#"&lt;rect x="{}" y="{}" width="{}" height="{}" fill:rgb(100,0,0)" /&gt;""#, x, y, w, h);</code> your way into looking at your algorithms unfolding.</p>
<h2>Making/testing/debugging a small rust crate</h2>
<p>I had a great time writing guillotiere for several reasons. The problem itself had some nice properties:</p>
<ul>
<li>It's a well defined problem with simple input and output data. As a result it is very easy to write unit tests and fuzz the code.</li>
<li>No nebulous design space for fancy abstractions. A retained state, query a size in, get a rectangle out. Simple.</li>
<li>Can be implemented in its own library outside of a big rendering engine, and enjoy fast compile/debug iterations.</li>
</ul>
<p>It was the Rust programming language and ecosystem that really made it a such pleasant journey.</p>
<p>Bootstrapping a simple library, creating unit tests, adding dependencies is simple and effortless in Rust. This alone is a huge time saver for me compared to when I would do this sort of thing in C++ (I can only hope that the situation has improved in C++ since). Fellow Rust developers are pretty used to that so let's move on.</p>
<p>I quickly wrote a simple command-line application to interactively play with the packing algorithm.
The application deserializes the state of the atlas from a file, execute a command (for example allocation or deallocation) and serializes back into the file (using the .ron file format). In addition, the command-line application could dump a visualization of the atlas in SVG.</p>
<p>The command-line app was put together very quickly thanks to fantastic pieces of the Rust ecosystem:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://crates.io/crates/serde">serde</a> for serialization/deserialzation,</li>
<li><a href="https://crates.io/crates/ron">ron</a> providing a nice and readable serialized file format,</li>
<li>and <a href="https://crates.io/crates/clap">clap</a> for parsing command-line arguments.</li>
</ul>
<p>Put together, this gave me an interactive playground to test the algorithm. Playing around in a terminal would look like:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code>$ guillotiere init <span>1024</span> <span>1024</span>
$ guillotiere allocate <span>16</span> <span>32</span>
Allocated rectangle r1 of size 16x32 at origin <span>[</span><span>0</span>, <span>0</span><span>]</span>
$ guillotiere allocate <span>200</span> <span>100</span> --svg <span>01</span>.svg
Allocated rectangle r2 of size 200x100 at origin <span>[</span><span>16</span>, <span>0</span><span>]</span>
$ guillotiere deallocate r1 --svg <span>02</span>.svg

etc...
</code></pre></div>


<p>At any time in that sequence of commands I can open the <code>atlas.ron</code> file and read the state of the atlas as if I was in a debugger, can also copy it around to save the state in a way that almost feels as powerful as using <a href="https://rr-project.org/">record-and-replay debugging</a>.</p>
<h2>Fuzzing</h2>
<p>I mentioned fuzzing earlier. <a href="https://github.com/rust-fuzz/cargo-fuzz">Cargo fuzz</a> is a joy and I really recommend using it whenever possible. It's very easy to setup, I wouldn't necessarily run it on every push, but every once in a while to find some bugs and/or get a bit of confidence about the robustness of your code. It's great. It has plenty of well written <a href="https://rust-fuzz.github.io/book/">documentation</a> so I won't go into details here. I'll just mention that it's a very well made piece of Rust's ecosystem that contributes to the greatness of the whole in my opinion.</p>

<p>Fast forward the end of 2020. Ah 2020.</p>
<p>I was investigating further improvements to draw call batching and texture upload overhead which are big performance bottlenecks on low end Intel GPUs, especially on Windows.</p>
<p>Gathering some statistics about what causes new batches to be generated shows that it is often happening when multiple primitives use the same shader but are …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://nical.github.io/posts/etagere.html">https://nical.github.io/posts/etagere.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nical.github.io/posts/etagere.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26025053</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 13:16:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Lose Money with 25 Years of Failed Businesses]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 48 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26022293">thread link</a>) | @codazoda
<br/>
February 3, 2021 | https://joeldare.com/how-to-lose-money-with-25-years-of-failed-businesses | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://joeldare.com/how-to-lose-money-with-25-years-of-failed-businesses">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      
      
      

      

<p><strong>1. Close your business while it’s working</strong></p>

<p>I opened my first business right out of high school. I had a few thousand dollars saved up and I wanted to start a business. I found a tiny office space on a busy road and shook hands with the landlord. My Dad helped me make a sign using a piece of wood and a vinyl sticker. I purchased two computer systems and set them up on folding tables. I purchased a desk and a chair and put those in the back of my space, like a small used car salesman. Suddenly, I was selling custom built computer systems using off the shelf parts.</p>

<p>A few months later I got a call from my high school. I told the caller what I was up to and he informed me that the school would receive a small grant because I was working in the industry I had aspired to less than a year after graduation.</p>

<p>Then, I fell in love. No, that’s not right, I was in love before I had even started this. But, the conversation had turned to marriage and children. The business was working okay, but I didn’t think I was doing well enough to support a family. I needed a real job making real money. After working in the store for just nine months, I applied at a local tech company and walked away from my little business.</p>

<p>Three months later I would hire an accountant to do my taxes. I handed him a shoe box full of receipts and invoices and let him figure it out. When he handed me my first <em>Schedule C</em> I nearly hit the floor. I was showing a business loss that was more money than I had ever imagined. He explained that I would be able to write this loss off, in parts, over the next seven years.</p>

<p>But, remember, I had come into this business with only a few thousand dollars. If I had <em>lost</em> that kind of money, I had also <em>made</em> that money to lose. If I were paying attention, I think the business would have been profitable. But, I wasn’t paying attention, and the business had closed months ago.</p>

<p><strong>2. Get a cease and desist from your own employer</strong></p>

<p>Remember that Tech job I landed to make real money? Turns out, that was a good move. The company I joined was Iomega and they were roaring. They had recently released the Zip drive and had gone from 100k in annual revenue to a two billion dollar company. With that kind of growth, money and promotions were all around me. I loved the job and the people I was working with. I was climbing the corporate ladder and loving it.</p>

<p>Iomega also made the higher end Jaz drive, and all of us had one (or two) on our desks. Some of my co-workers were complaining about a problem though. The Jaz drive would spin-down, after two minutes or so, to conserve energy. The next time you accessed the drive, it took 20 or 30 seconds for it to spin up.</p>

<p>I had access to an internal engineering manual for the drive, so I dived in. I concluded that the drives were designed to spin down mostly to save energy. Based on the numbers I had, I figured they would last more than 10 years, even if they were running 24/7. But, there was no way to configure them to stay spinning. The sleep was built into the firmware of the drive itself.</p>

<p>That’s when I got the idea for my first Shareware program. It was a simple Windows utility that I called JazAwake. It would write a tiny file to the Jaz drive every 60 seconds and then delete it. The file was just big enough that it would flush it to disk. Because the drive was being written too every minute or so, it would no longer spin down.</p>

<p>The program was popular both inside the company and out. All of my co-workers were using it and people were starting to pay to register it.</p>

<p>Then I got a letter from one of the lawyers at Iomega. It was addressed to my software company. It was a cease and desist asking me to stop using the Jaz trademark and remove JazAwake from the Internet. At first, I laughed. How can you remove a piece of software from the Internet? That’s impossible. But, nothing short of that would stop them from suing me.</p>

<p>Luckily, they didn’t realize I also worked there, or I imagine I would have lost my job too.</p>

<p>I went to work creating my own cease and desist letter explaining what I had done and started mailing them to every organization that had written about or linked to my software. I had to send these letters to over a hundred different companies. I went back and forth with the lawyers at Iomega for about 6 months and when they could no longer find the software online, they were satisfied.</p>

<p>I stayed at Iomega for a couple more years and I created another popular Shareware program called ButtonWiz. When Iomega started to lose steam, I left for a smaller company.</p>

<p><strong>3. Close your side business and focus on the promise of becoming CEO</strong></p>

<p>I got a job at a small technology company that served only about 100 customers. But, the owner had created something useful and he was making enough money to pay for himself and another employee. He didn’t want to make too much profit, because that meant paying more taxes and quarterly tax paperwork. He would watch the books so that his profit was less than $4k per year. If we had made too much money for the year, by October or November, he would spend some of it on new things we needed for the office or employee bonuses. It worked out really well.</p>

<p>The owner was getting up there in age and he figured he would like to retire in another 10 years or so. None of his family was interested in the business he had built and he had no real plan to exit. So, he had the idea that he would hand the business to me at some point and I would continue to pay him well into retirement. He purchased a life insurance policy and set me as the beneficiary. If he died before he was able to retire, I could pay his family and continue to run the business.</p>

<p>ButtonWiz continued to get more and more popular and was now bringing in a few hundred dollars a month. One day the boss suggested that I stop working on my side projects and double-down at the office. So, I shelved work on ButtonWiz and let it wither away over the next few years while I focused on the company I worked for.</p>

<p>Now eight years into my Career here, the company had grown from the two of us to around ten employees. Among those employees a few family members had been introduced, but I was still employee number two. Then the boss dropped a bomb that didn’t completely surprise me. There were people in the family showing interest now and he had decided to keep the business in the family. I can’t blame him. One of the reasons I’ve always wanted to build a business is to support my family and, if it’s really successful, more of those around me. But, suddenly, my career felt like another job, so I started to look elsewhere.</p>

<p><strong>4. Break Googles TOS and accidentally commit click fraud while your at it</strong></p>

<p>Growing more and more frustrated with the stress of my job, I started to run. I would run at a park by my office every day on my lunch break. I also started watching my weight and I started writing software again.</p>

<p>I had tried a bunch of calorie trackers but logging all the specific foods I ate was too much for me. I decided to create a calorie tracker that was fast. I would just enter the number of calories I ate and the web app would timestamp them. No more looking up foods.</p>

<p>At the top of the app I created a search box and I pointed that to a webview that opened to Google. I modified the search a little by adding the word “calories” to the end of it. That way, I could search for something like “pizza” and it would return a set of results for “pizza calories”, often with the actual number of calories right there at the top. I also signed up for Google advertising and embedded a mobile ad unit on the page. I released it for the iPhone and published it free on the web app directory on Apple.com (the App Store didn’t exist yet).</p>

<p>The money started rolling in. Lots of users were downloading the app and using it and the ad revenue was crazy high. It made a ton of money for a couple weeks and then I started looking at my ad click rates. They were astronomical. In fact, my click through rate was so high, it had to be an error. I started digging in.</p>

<p>What I found is that the search box and the ad unit were in close proximity to each other and users were accidentally clicking on the ad when they were trying to enter calorie counts. Oops.</p>

<p>I adjusted the placement of the two UI elements to be far apart. While I was doing that, I found a piece of information in Google’s Terms of Service that said you weren’t allowed to alter the search term a user entered. I was relying on Google for all my income here, so I also updated my search box so that it didn’t add the word “calories”, even though it made the search results significantly less relevant. Hopefully users would learn to do that themselves.</p>

<p>When I released the new version, as you might expect, the ad revenue tanked. Nearly all of the advertising clicks were users clicking by mistake.</p>

<p><strong>5. Write a book about a platform that changes a lot</strong></p>

<p>Since I was writing software again, I decided to give Facebook Apps a try. The app setup process was complex and confusing so I started to take detailed notes. After creating a “Hello World” app, I followed my instructions again and repeated the process for something more interesting. I refined my notes as I went, creating several test apps along the way. When I got done, I realized I had enough information to teach other developers how to do this. At the time, the Facebook documentation was sparse and hard to find. I had learned most of it by trial and error. I was also interested in trying self publishing. So, I decided I would spend the next weekend formatting this into a small book and self-publishing it on Amazon.</p>

<p>The book was selling a few copies a week and was getting great reviews.</p>

<p>About three months later, the book suddenly started to get bad reviews. I opened the book and followed it myself. Facebook had updated the process and things were different now. I made new notes and figured out the new process and …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://joeldare.com/how-to-lose-money-with-25-years-of-failed-businesses">https://joeldare.com/how-to-lose-money-with-25-years-of-failed-businesses</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://joeldare.com/how-to-lose-money-with-25-years-of-failed-businesses</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26022293</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 03:35:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
