<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 20]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 20. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 12:25:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-20.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 12:25:09 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Too many “two-pizza” teams]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 33 | Comments 20 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23984098">thread link</a>) | @kislayverma
<br/>
July 28, 2020 | https://kislayverma.com/organizations/independence-autonomy-and-too-many-small-teams/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://kislayverma.com/organizations/independence-autonomy-and-too-many-small-teams/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>

<div>
<div data-url="https://kislayverma.com/organizations/independence-autonomy-and-too-many-small-teams/" data-title="Independence, autonomy, and too many small teams">
<p>“The two pizza team” paradigm has become really popular in the context of organizing software teams. The idea is to have small, self-reliant teams working independently to solve problems. The “two-pizza” refers to the guidance to keep the team small enough that we need not order more than two pizzas to feed them.</p>
<figure><img src="https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/dev-prod-with-team-size-1024x701.jpg" data-src="https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/dev-prod-with-team-size-1024x701.jpg" alt="" data-srcset="https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/dev-prod-with-team-size-1024x701.jpg 1024w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/dev-prod-with-team-size-300x205.jpg 300w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/dev-prod-with-team-size-768x526.jpg 768w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/dev-prod-with-team-size-1070x732.jpg 1070w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/dev-prod-with-team-size.jpg 1505w" data-sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/dev-prod-with-team-size-1024x701.jpg 1024w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/dev-prod-with-team-size-300x205.jpg 300w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/dev-prod-with-team-size-768x526.jpg 768w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/dev-prod-with-team-size-1070x732.jpg 1070w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/dev-prod-with-team-size.jpg 1505w"></figure>
<p>These teams are all around us today, but we are not seeing the kind of productivity or shipping velocity that we expected to see. Most developers, especially in larger organizations, complain about meetings, the burden of communication, the slow pace of change etc. Startups often sell themselves to potential candidates by touting their agility. But why should larger companies be slow if everyone is using the same “empowered team”/”autonomous team” model for organizing themselves?</p>
<p>I argue that <strong>we have lost the original intent of the “two pizza teams”</strong> (aka autonomous teams). The way we are organizing and scaling teams as companies grow larger is exactly opposite to the spirit of the idea, and this is making the already difficult problem of keeping teams motivated and agile even more difficult.</p>
<h3><strong>Why two pizza teams</strong></h3>
<p>The concept of the “two pizza”/”autonomous” team arose from attempts to minimize communication between multiple teams and empowering a single team to be in complete control of delivering customer value.</p>
<p>Before this idea gained popularity, the most common way of organizing teams was in terms of Backend, UI, DBA, Ops etc.. Building any feature required a lot of communication, collaboration, and alignment between all these groups.</p>
<p>The notion of a small team which had all the skills required to solve a single specific problem was intended to solve this problem. A single team would be given the entirety of the problem statement and the tools it needed to solve it. This would ideally remove the problem of aligning multiple teams around shared roadmaps and delivery schedules and allow the team to own the problem solving process end-to-end.</p>
<p>There are two core concepts underlying the two-pizza team – <strong>mission</strong> and<strong> independence</strong>. Ideally, end-to-end means all the way to the customer or the business. Hence, <strong>every autonomous team is expected to generate direct business value all by itself</strong>, without a lot of overlap with other teams. Additionally, <strong>the team should be able to meets its goals independently</strong> (i.e. without reliance on or interference from other teams) This reduces the cross team communication overhead because its members have all the skills needed to solve the problem.</p>
<h3>What went wrong</h3>
<p>Somewhere along the line, we forgot about “reducing communication” just started fixating on assigning independent teams to problem statements that were essentially tiny slices of business problems. As the problem space gets more finely sliced in hopes of achieving scale at each step, so does the number of teams. e.g. What might have been a “Data Delivery Team” charged with delivering fresh data to customers unfortunately becomes “Data ingestion Team”, “Data processing Team” and “Data Release Team” (real world example).</p>
<p>This causes problems with both the core tenets of the autonomous team philosophy.</p>
<figure><img src="https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/narrow-missions-1024x809.jpg" data-src="https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/narrow-missions-1024x809.jpg" alt="" data-srcset="https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/narrow-missions-1024x809.jpg 1024w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/narrow-missions-300x237.jpg 300w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/narrow-missions-768x607.jpg 768w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/narrow-missions-1070x845.jpg 1070w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/narrow-missions.jpg 1484w" data-sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/narrow-missions-1024x809.jpg 1024w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/narrow-missions-300x237.jpg 300w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/narrow-missions-768x607.jpg 768w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/narrow-missions-1070x845.jpg 1070w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/narrow-missions.jpg 1484w"></figure>
<p>The <strong>mission is diluted because most of the teams are now working on problems which are subsets of the original problem and as such not valuable in themselves</strong>. The success of a team can no longer guarantee the improvement of at least one business metric. The team’s work is not tied to a business objective any longer, so it gets tied to tightly defined execution scopes.”Data ingestion team” is supposed to pull in data, that’s it. While the team is still allowed to do this however it wants, succeeding in its objective will not mean that fresh data is being delivered to the customer. </p>
<p>Autonomy is diluted as a direct fallout. <strong>Where a single team could have come together to solve problems of data delivery, now multiple teams with different managers and different roadmaps must come together to deliver anything to the customer</strong>. This creates exactly the kind of coordination overhead that these small teams were created to solve in the first place.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Coordination, also known as alignment, communication, shared roadmap, Gantt chart and many other positive sounding names, is the arch-enemy of the autonomous team</strong>. </p>
<p>We have lots of small teams with lots of independence and no direct impact that keeping everyone pointed in one direction has become a nightmare. Program Managers paper over the ever-increasing complexity involved in coordinating priorities, efforts, and timelines, with developers and managers increasingly wash their hands of the whole business of communicating with other teams.</p>
<p>We took a good idea too far. The current “small” team is certainly small, but we forgot the part about reducing communication. Instead we are now offered “small, highly collaborative” teams as some sort of new ideal, as if high collaboration is something to be desired during execution.</p>
<p>This is a huge blind spot for organizations. The implicit goodness of small teams (devoid of any of the original context) is now internalized to such an extent that deep collaboration between small teams is considered a good thing in the organization. Team productivity and motivation keeps falling even as their sizes increase. And somehow we still believe this way of organizing work among teams is efficient, and something else must be causing the diminishing productivity.</p>
<hr>


<hr>
<h3>Collaboration is not good</h3>
<p>Collaboration is a great idea during ideation and brainstorming. It helps in getting a lot of input from lots of different people and can help us discover new aspects which we may not consider ourselves. It can expose other approaches to solving the problem, or even some versions of this problem that have already been solved by others. <strong>Broad stroked collaboration between people and systems is how we build something that is greater than the sum of its parts.</strong></p>
<p>However, <strong>once we reach the execution phase, collaboration is extremely costly.</strong> Collaboration means that two people or teams cannot just focus on doing their jobs, they also have to worry about when the other person is going to finish theirs and how they are going to synchronize with each other to hit the finish line.</p>
<figure><img src="https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/org-prod-with-team-count-1024x801.jpg" data-src="https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/org-prod-with-team-count-1024x801.jpg" alt="" data-srcset="https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/org-prod-with-team-count-1024x801.jpg 1024w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/org-prod-with-team-count-300x235.jpg 300w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/org-prod-with-team-count-768x600.jpg 768w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/org-prod-with-team-count-1070x837.jpg 1070w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/org-prod-with-team-count.jpg 1494w" data-sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/org-prod-with-team-count-1024x801.jpg 1024w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/org-prod-with-team-count-300x235.jpg 300w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/org-prod-with-team-count-768x600.jpg 768w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/org-prod-with-team-count-1070x837.jpg 1070w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/org-prod-with-team-count.jpg 1494w"></figure>
<p>I can quote any number of engineering principles to refute the deification of collaborative teams which seems to be the norm today.</p>
<p>In general, it is assumed that multithreading improves the performance of a system. This is completely true if each thread can execute completely independently on its own core without talking to any other thread or sharing any data. However, the moment we end with some shared state or more threads than CPUs, the synchronization overhead can quickly outstrip all the performance gains from using the technique.</p>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amdahl%27s_law" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Amdahl’s law</a> puts a finite upper limit on the increased output when an extra worker is added into the mix. The well-known problem is that every extra worker imposes non-parallelizable, exponentially increasing communication overhead. At some point, adding another worker makes things worse rather than better.</p>
<p>“<em>9 developers cannot finish a 9 month project in one month</em>” is a well-known idea in software management. And yet we see managers trying to grow and manage their teams in isolation. Why is that?</p>
<p>My hypothesis is that we see individual teams delivering quickly and we interpret this to mean that adding more members to these teams will further scale the output. In a world where we examine teams by isolating them from the overall system context, it is very easy to confuse independent with autonomous.</p>
<h3>Independence is not Autonomy</h3>
<p>In a highly collaborative setup, the correct way of looking at the organization is like a factory floor. <strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Theory_of_constraints#:~:text=The%20theory%20of%20constraints%20(TOC)%20is%20an%20overall%20management%20philosophy,Critical%20Chain%2C%20published%20in%201997." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Theory of constraints</a></strong> tells us that the only way to increase output in this situation is to broaden the bottlenecks and widen the entire “flow of work” from conception to final delivery to the customer.</p>
<figure><img src="https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/sequential-teams-1024x349.jpg" data-src="https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/sequential-teams-1024x349.jpg" alt="" data-srcset="https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/sequential-teams-1024x349.jpg 1024w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/sequential-teams-300x102.jpg 300w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/sequential-teams-768x262.jpg 768w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/sequential-teams-1536x523.jpg 1536w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/sequential-teams-1070x365.jpg 1070w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/sequential-teams.jpg 1916w" data-sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/sequential-teams-1024x349.jpg 1024w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/sequential-teams-300x102.jpg 300w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/sequential-teams-768x262.jpg 768w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/sequential-teams-1536x523.jpg 1536w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/sequential-teams-1070x365.jpg 1070w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/sequential-teams.jpg 1916w"></figure>
<p>But when we look at each step individually and out of context of the rest of the “pipeline”, “delivery” takes on a very different meaning. It just means “out of my door”. Any attempts to improve output with such a perspective will only create local maxima which means nothing for the final output – it might even be detrimental.</p>
<p>This is where we end up with too many small teams which are only looking at their little slice of work. That is what they are incentivised to do. If the outputs of our teams are arranged sequentially, they are not autonomous in delivery, no matter how independent they might be in their day to day work.</p>
<p>Anyone who has managed a supply chain can tell, independent teams organized in a sequential manner MANDATE a lot of communication and feedback. The lines of communication have not been removed by the creating small teams – they have been multiplied manifold. What’s worse, communication is happening at team boundaries where it is actually the weakest (the <a href="https://kislayverma.com/programming/overcoming-io-overhead-in-micro-services/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">communication overhead in microservices</a> springs to mind readily).</p>
<figure><img src="https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/too-many-small-teams-1024x742.jpg" data-src="https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/too-many-small-teams-1024x742.jpg" alt="" data-srcset="https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/too-many-small-teams-1024x742.jpg 1024w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/too-many-small-teams-300x217.jpg 300w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/too-many-small-teams-768x557.jpg 768w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/too-many-small-teams-1070x776.jpg 1070w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/too-many-small-teams.jpg 1334w" data-sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/too-many-small-teams-1024x742.jpg 1024w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/too-many-small-teams-300x217.jpg 300w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/too-many-small-teams-768x557.jpg 768w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/too-many-small-teams-1070x776.jpg 1070w, https://kislayverma.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/too-many-small-teams.jpg 1334w"></figure>
<p>Without an autonomous mission, independent teams are forever shackled by the communication overhead.</p>
<h3><strong>Autonom</strong><strong>y</strong><strong> is a customer facing construct</strong></h3>
<p>What happens if we organize our independent teams by problem statement rather than function? A team that is authorized to solve a customer problem using any means at its disposal in essence owns the entire “pipeline” of tasks that need to be done. There is no cross-team collaboration and communication required for this team to do its job. This team not only operates independently, it also delivers value to the customer independently.</p>
<p><strong>A team is autonomous when it “delivers value to the customer” independently</strong>. In his novel “<a href="https://www.amazon.in/gp/product/8185984565?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=kislayverma-21&amp;camp=3638&amp;linkCode=xm2&amp;creativeASIN=8185984565" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Goal</a>“, Eliyahu M. Goldratt highlights this beautifully by having his protagonist (who is plant manager) define his success to mean increased sales. Sales is usually not the problem of the manufacturing team, but the novel highlights how defining a customer facing “global” goal transforms the poorly performing plant.</p>
<p>Scaling this team …</p></div></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://kislayverma.com/organizations/independence-autonomy-and-too-many-small-teams/">https://kislayverma.com/organizations/independence-autonomy-and-too-many-small-teams/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://kislayverma.com/organizations/independence-autonomy-and-too-many-small-teams/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23984098</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 06:58:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[MailTrackerBlocker – email tracker and spy pixel blocker plugin for Apple Mail]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 52 | Comments 31 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23979578">thread link</a>) | @guessmyname
<br/>
July 28, 2020 | https://apparition47.github.io/MailTrackerBlocker/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://apparition47.github.io/MailTrackerBlocker/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <div>
      <p><img width="374" height="292" src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/3298414/88930093-f89a5980-d2b5-11ea-85f6-37020305a450.png">
      </p>
      <h2>
        <svg width="12" height="12" viewBox="0 0 12 12" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">
        <path d="M8.5 0L12 3.5v5L8.5 12h-5L0 8.5v-5L3.5 0h5zm-.025 2.818L6 5.293 3.525 2.818l-.707.707L5.293 6 2.818 8.475l.707.707L6 6.707l2.475 2.475.707-.707L6.707 6l2.475-2.475-.707-.707z" fill="#3B8294" fill-rule="evenodd"></path>
        </svg>MailTrackerBlocker</h2>
      <p>An email tracker, read receipt and spy pixel blocker plugin for <b>macOS Apple Mail</b>.</p>

      

      <h3>What is this?</h3>
      <p>MailTrackerBlocker is a plugin for the default Mail app built-in to macOS. When you view your email a <span>ⓧ #</span> button will appear to indicate the number of services blocked. Tap on the button to show which services have been blocked. Disabling "load remote content" should no longer be necessary just to read your emails privately!</p>

      <h3>Blocked Trackers</h3>
      <p><span> ActiveCampaign</span>
        <span> Amazon SES</span>
        <span> AWeber</span>
        <span> Bananatag</span>
        <span> Boomerang</span>
        <span> Campaign Monitor</span>
        <span> Cirrus Insight</span>
        <span> Close</span>
        <span> Constant Contact</span>
        <span> ContactMonkey</span>
        <span> ConvertKit</span>
        <span> Critical Impact</span>
        <span> Emarsys</span>
        <span> Gem</span>
        <span> Getnotify</span>
        <span> GetResponse</span>
        <span> GitHub</span>
        <span> GrowthDot</span>
        <span> FreshMail</span>
        <span> Hubspot</span>
        <span> iContact</span>
        <span> Intercom</span>
        <span> Litmus</span>
        <span> Mailchimp</span>
        <span> Mailgun</span>
        <span> Mailjet</span>
        <span> Mailspring</span>
        <span> MailTrack</span>
        <span> Mandrill</span>
        <span> Marketo</span>
        <span> MixMax</span>
        <span> Mixpanel</span>
        <span> NetHunt</span>
        <span> Outreach</span>
        <span> phpList</span>
        <span> Polymail</span>
        <span> Postmark</span>
        <span> Return Path</span>
        <span> Sailthru</span>
        <span> Salesforce</span>
        <span> SendGrid</span>
        <span> Sendy</span>
        <span> Streak</span>
        <span> Superhuman</span>
        <span> Thunderhead</span>
        <span> Tinyletter</span>
        <span> Wix</span>
        <span> YAMM</span>
        <span> Yesware</span>
        <span> Zendesk Sell</span>
      </p>

      <h3>How can I enable this?</h3>
      <p>To enable, first install the <span>.pkg</span> file then enable the plugin by (see <a href="https://gpgtools.tenderapp.com/kb/gpg-mail-faq/enable-gpg-mail-on-macos-mojave-or-newer">similar guide for nice pictures</a>):</p>
      <ol>
        <li>In Mail, open <span>Preferences &gt; General &gt; Manage Plug-ins...</span></li>
        <li>Check <span>MailTrackerBlocker.mailbundle</span></li>
        <li>Click <span>Apply and Restart Mail</span></li>
      </ol>

      <h3>Credits</h3>
      <p>Thanks to the <a href="https://github.com/GPGTools/GPGMail">GPGMail team</a> for a lot of the work in hooking into Mail.app, <a href="https://github.com/dhh">@dhh</a> for sharing his spy pixel list and <a href="https://github.com/bitmanic">@bitmanic</a> for the UI design.</p>

      <h3>Contact</h3>
      <p>Tell me your story. <a href="https://twitter.com/apparition47" role="button">
        
        @apparition47
      </a>
      <a href="https://github.com/apparition47" role="button">
        
        @apparition47
      </a></p>

      <p><small>© 2020 Aaron Lee</small></p>
    </div>

  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://apparition47.github.io/MailTrackerBlocker/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23979578</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 19:15:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Benchmarking the Major Cloud Vision AutoML Tools]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 29 | Comments 10 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23979451">thread link</a>) | @rocauc
<br/>
July 28, 2020 | https://blog.roboflow.ai/automl-vs-rekognition-vs-custom-vision/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.roboflow.ai/automl-vs-rekognition-vs-custom-vision/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <div>
              <div><h3 id="comparing-aws-rekognition-google-cloud-automl-and-azure-custom-vision-for-object-detection">Comparing AWS Rekognition, Google Cloud AutoML, and Azure Custom Vision for Object Detection</h3><figure><img src="https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/2020/07/image-53.png" alt="" srcset="https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/image-53.png 600w, https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/size/w1000/2020/07/image-53.png 1000w, https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/size/w1600/2020/07/image-53.png 1600w, https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/size/w2400/2020/07/image-53.png 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption>Big Cloud AutoML solutions face off on a shared task in this post</figcaption></figure><p>All three major cloud providers have recently launched no-code tools for training custom object detection models. But, until now, there has been little independent research published on their performance (both relative to each other and against state of the art open source models). We ran a standard dataset through all three tools to see how they stack up against each other.</p><p>If you are considering using computer vision services from Google Cloud, AWS, or Azure in your product (or you have trained an object detection model of your own and are wondering where you stand in comparison to AutoML) this is the post for you.</p><p>In this post, we review <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/rekognition/custom-labels-features/">Amazon Rekognition Custom Labels</a>, <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/cognitive-services/custom-vision-service/">Azure Custom Vision</a>, and <a href="https://cloud.google.com/automl">Google Cloud AutoML Vision</a>. We'll weigh the pros/cons between them and we'll also compare them against results from <a href="https://models.roboflow.ai/object-detection/yolov5">YOLOv5x</a>, a current-generation open source model.</p><p>We evaluate each product on the following factors:</p><ul><li>Training Time (how long to train the model)</li><li>Training Cost (how much to train the model)</li><li>Model Performance (how accurate is the model)</li><li>Inference Time (how long to predict on a test image)</li><li>Inference Costs (how much to predict once on a test image)</li></ul><p>We also provide insight into the major limitations of each platform and ease of use.</p><h3 id="summary-">Summary:</h3><figure><img src="https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/2020/07/autoML_table.002.jpeg" alt="google cloud automl vs aws rekognition vs azure custom-vision" srcset="https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/autoML_table.002.jpeg 600w, https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/2020/07/autoML_table.002.jpeg 1000w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p><strong>Our overall conclusion:</strong> AutoML tools are a great way to assess the feasibility of a computer vision project, even if you plan to eventually train a custom model architecture. Evaluating tradeoffs among the big three cloud providers depends on your project specifications (how important is inference speed; what accuracy threshold is required; what inference volume do you expect; what is the size of your dataset). Open source model architectures, while expensive to build and maintain, perform on par with big cloud provider options.</p><p>Unfortunately, each platform uses its own proprietary API and data format so it is very cumbersome to get started and compare solutions. Moreover, once you're up and running, you're locked in. (Luckily, <a href="https://roboflow.ai/">Roboflow</a> solves this by seamlessly integrating with all three.)</p><h2 id="overview-of-the-automl-process">Overview of the AutoML Process</h2><p>No matter which platform you choose, you will be entering a similar workflow to create and deploy your computer vision model.</p><figure><img src="https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/2020/07/image-54.png" alt="" srcset="https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/image-54.png 600w, https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/2020/07/image-54.png 750w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption>The AutoML Process in a diagram</figcaption></figure><p><strong>Data Preparation</strong> - In order to train a computer vision model, you first need to acquire images that appear in your domain of interest. The narrower you keep your domain the better your model will perform. Then, your images will need to be labeled providing supervision to train your model to learn the vision concepts in question.</p><p><strong>Model Training and Evaluation</strong> - you will kick of training, a process where the computer formulates an algorithm based on training images to apply to images that it has never seen. Your model will then be evaluated based on how well it performs during predictions. This may be an iterative process as you add data and adjust training length. </p><p><strong>Model Deployment and Inference - </strong>Once you have a suitable model, you will deploy this model to a compute instance and stand up an API endpoint that you can hit to receive predictions based on what your model is seeing in your production images. </p><p>The cloud providers separate data labeling from AutoML, and we will be focusing on reviewing the AutoML service in this post, <strong>assuming you have already collected a labeled dataset.</strong></p><h2 id="the-big-cloud-automl-challenge-ms-coco">The Big Cloud AutoML Challenge - MS COCO</h2><p>The original plan was to benchmark these services on the modern standard, the <a href="https://cocodataset.org/#home">Microsoft Common Objects in Context Object Detection</a> (COCO) dataset.</p><p>Unfortunately, <strong>all three tools failed this challenge</strong> and we were unable to complete training on COCO.</p><p><strong>Rekognition Custom Labels</strong><em> -</em> has a hard-cap on the maximum training time of 72 node-hours per job. If your dataset takes longer than that to converge, the job will time out. Rekognition did not complete the MS COCO job before its time limit was exceeded and, thus, failed our test. <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/rekognition/latest/customlabels-dg/limits.html">Limits Page</a></p><p><strong>Google Cloud AutoML</strong> - there was a limit of 100MB for annotation upload. We were able to work around this by splitting the file into several chunks but the estimated budget for training MS COCO on Google Cloud AutoML was $6000. Sorry, but there's no way we're spending that on a blog post... <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vision/automl/object-detection/quotas">Quotas and Limits Page</a></p><p><strong>Azure Custom Vision</strong> - maxes out at 100,000 training images (COCO has over 200,000). <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/cognitive-services/custom-vision-service/limits-and-quotas">Limits and Quotas Page</a></p><h2 id="the-big-cloud-automl-challenge-pascal-voc">The Big Cloud AutoML Challenge - Pascal VOC</h2><p>In order to compare the accuracy of AutoML vision solutions, we fell back to an older benchmark object detection task, the<a href="http://host.robots.ox.ac.uk/pascal/VOC/voc2012/"> Pascal VOC 2012 Object Detection dataset</a>.</p><p><strong>The object detection task - </strong>Object detection challenges the computer to learn to draw bounding boxes around objects belonging to collection of object classes of interest.</p><figure><img src="https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/2020/07/image-55.png" alt=""><figcaption>Azure Custom Vision displays an image in Pascal VOC</figcaption></figure><p>The Pascal VOC 2012 dataset has 13,690 training images and 3,428 validation images across 20 object classes.</p><figure><img src="https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/2020/07/image-56.png" alt="" srcset="https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/image-56.png 600w, https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/size/w1000/2020/07/image-56.png 1000w, https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/2020/07/image-56.png 1324w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption>The class distribution for the Pascal VOC 2012 dataset (via <a href="https://docs.roboflow.ai/dataset-health-check">Roboflow Dataset Health Check</a>).</figcaption></figure><p>Pascal VOC withholds the dataset's test set so we evaluate the cloud platforms with their performance on the validation set.</p><h2 id="training-costs">Training Costs</h2><p>Once you have loaded your dataset into Amazon Rekognition, Google Cloud AutoML Vision, or Azure Custom Vision, you are ready to train your model.</p><figure><img src="https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/2020/07/image-57.png" alt="" srcset="https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/image-57.png 600w, https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/size/w1000/2020/07/image-57.png 1000w, https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/2020/07/image-57.png 1449w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption>Kicking off training on Pascal VOC in Amazon Rekognition Custom Labels</figcaption></figure><p>Training a model is a computationally intensive task, as the computer iterates through your dataset it will be optimizing millions of neural network parameters. To do this efficiently, the AutoML services will boot up GPU nodes.</p><p><strong>Amazon Rekognition Custom Labels Training Cost - </strong>Training is started and runs until the model has reached maximum performance. You are unable to control how long training occurs for. Training costs $1/hr/instance and Amazon may provision multiple compute instances to train your model. So your training job may complete in two hours but you will be billed for more if more instances were started. Training can run for a maximum of 72 node hours. If it times out, your training cost is refunded. Be careful, you cannot stop training jobs that have started! <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/rekognition/pricing/">Pricing Page</a>.</p><p><strong>Google Cloud AutoML Vision Training Cost - </strong>Google Cloud AutoML Vision trains their model with 8 nodes with Tesla V100 GPUs. Each node hour is $3.15/hr, so ~$25 per wall clock hour. AutoML Vision allows you the ability to start, stop, and resume model training, which can be nice to anticipate the costs before the training job has started. There is no limit to the amount of training time you can provision in Google Cloud AutoML Vision. <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vision/automl/pricing">Pricing Page</a>.</p><p><strong>Azure Custom Vision Training Cost - </strong>Azure Custom Vision is less verbose in explaining their training costs - it costs $20/compute hour, but the underlying hardware is undisclosed so it is unclear how this stacks up against the Google and Amazon price/performance. <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/pricing/details/cognitive-services/custom-vision-service/">Pricing Page</a>.</p><h2 id="training-time">Training Time</h2><p>It is hard to benchmark training costs without factoring in training time. Each service may be running a larger or smaller model architecture, and may have varying levels of training time software optimization.</p><figure><img src="https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/2020/07/ezgif.com-video-to-gif--10-.gif" alt=""><figcaption>Waiting for training to complete in Google Cloud AutoML Vision</figcaption></figure><p>When starting your training job, you have the ability to choose between large or compact models based on your downstream inference time needs in Azure and Google Cloud. Amazon Rekognition just provides one size fits all. </p><p>Smaller models train faster, infer faster, but perform less well.</p><figure><img src="https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/2020/07/image-59.png" alt=""><figcaption>Choosing model size in Google Cloud AutoML Vision</figcaption></figure><p>In this face off, we optimized all models for accuracy (and tried to train with a similar budget).</p><p><strong>Amazon Rekognition Custom Labels Training Time- </strong>Rekognition completed the training job on the Pascal VOC 2012 training set in 26 node hours, costing $26. To make a fair comparison, we sought to use this as our training budget across platforms.</p><p><strong>Google Cloud AutoML Vision Training Time - </strong>To stick with with the Rekognition training cost baseline, we would need to use 9 node hours in Google Cloud AutoML Vision, but the minimum time allowed was 20 hours for our PascalVOC 2012 dataset, costing $60. The <strong>recommended</strong> training time was 1,080 node hours - which would have cost a whopping $3402. We chose to train for the minimum time allowed (which still cost &gt;2x Rekognition).</p><p><strong>Azure Custom Vision Training Time - </strong>Sticking with the Rekognition baseline, we provisioned 1 hour of training time for Azure Custom Vision, costing $20.</p><p>It is worth noting that Google Cloud AutoML Vision and Azure Custom Vision could have likely earned better evaluation performance with a larger training budget. Rekognition does not let you configure this tradeoff at all.</p><h2 id="reported-evaluation-metrics">Reported Evaluation Metrics</h2><p>Object detection systems are rated by <a href="https://blog.roboflow.ai/what-is-mean-average-precision-object-detection/">the mean average precision metric</a>, a measure of how well the model is detecting objects in test images that it has never seen.</p><p>Google Cloud AutoML Vision is the only platform that reports unbiased evaluation metrics. <strong>Azure Custom Vision and Rekognition are slanting their results in their favor. Here are the gory details. </strong></p><p>As a primer, you may consider reading the blog regarding <a href="https://blog.roboflow.ai/what-is-mean-average-precision-object-detection/">what is mean average precision in object detection</a> or really getting into it with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oqXDdxF_Wuw&amp;t=2s">the mean average precision YouTube</a>. </p><p><strong>Google Cloud AutoML Vision Evaluation Methodology</strong> - Google Cloud reports performance according to the mAP @ 0.5. This means the mean average precision metric calculated at 50% Intersection over Union.</p><figure><img src="https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/2020/07/image-60.png" alt="Graphical depiction of the Intersection over Union" srcset="https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/image-60.png 600w, https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/size/w1000/2020/07/image-60.png 1000w, https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/2020/07/image-60.png 1002w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption>Graphical depiction of the Intersection over Union</figcaption></figure><p>The Intersection over Union threshold means that the intersection of the predicted box and the ground truth box relative to their union must be at least 50%. The less the IoU the easier it is to make the mAP metric higher.</p><figure><img src="https://blog.roboflow.ai/content/images/2020/07/image-61.png" alt=""><figcaption>Pascal VOC 2012 evaluation results displayed in Google Cloud AutoML Vision - mAP@.5</figcaption></figure><p><strong>Amazon Rekognition Custom Labels Evaluation Methodology</strong> - Rekognition does …</p></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.roboflow.ai/automl-vs-rekognition-vs-custom-vision/">https://blog.roboflow.ai/automl-vs-rekognition-vs-custom-vision/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.roboflow.ai/automl-vs-rekognition-vs-custom-vision/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23979451</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 19:01:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[US universities announcing online Fall 2020]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 39 | Comments 52 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23979045">thread link</a>) | @mjn
<br/>
July 28, 2020 | https://www.kmjn.org/notes/online_fall2020.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.kmjn.org/notes/online_fall2020.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="note"><p>

A list of four-year universities in the United States who've announced that
their fall 2020 undergraduate classes will be taught all or almost all online,
sorted by date of announcement.
</p><p>
There's variation within the plans in the list. Some are exclusively online,
while others plan to have a limited number of in-person courses, e.g.  science
labs.  Also, some universities plan to have the dorms and on-campus services
open at reduced capacity, while others plan to have the campus mostly closed.

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www2.calstate.edu/csu-system/news/Pages/CSU-Chancellor-Timothy-P-Whites-Statement-on-Fall-2020-University-Operational-Plans.aspx">May
5</a></b> – California State University system: "our planning approach will result
in CSU courses primarily being delivered virtually for the fall 2020 term, with
limited exceptions".

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://uci.edu/coronavirus/messages/200611-sa-academic-year-info.php">June
11</a></b> – University of California Irvine (Irvine, CA): "Almost all
undergraduate courses will be delivered in a remote format in the fall quarter.
A few exceptions are being evaluated, and consist of specialized upper-division
labs, specific clinical and experiential courses, and some design courses in
Engineering."

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www.fas.harvard.edu/fas-coronavirus-updates">June 15</a></b> –
Harvard University (Cambridge, MA): "regardless of where our students are
living, whether on campus or at home, learning will continue to be remote next
year, with only rare exceptions" (Faculty of Arts and Sciences, which includes
the undergraduate college).

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www.ucdavis.edu/news/uc-davis-plans-welcome-students-back-campus-fall/">June
16</a></b> – University of California Davis (Davis, CA): "When fall quarter
instruction starts Sept. 30, the campus plans to offer most courses remotely,
though some courses will also be available in person, depending on health
guidelines and instructor preference."

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://insideucr.ucr.edu/announcements/2020/06/17/ucr-announces-fall-quarter-instruction-plans">June
17</a></b> – University of California Riverside (Riverside, CA): "No instructor
will be required to teach in-person and no student will be required to
participate in-person until the campus returns to normal operations".

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://news.ucsc.edu/2020/06/planning-for-academic-year-2020-2021.html">June
17</a></b> – University of California Santa Cruz (Santa Cruz, CA): "UC Santa
Cruz will offer most courses remotely or online and provide in-person
instruction for a small number of courses that cannot be delivered remotely, as
is the case for some laboratory, studio and field study courses".

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www.bowdoin.edu/president/writings-and-addresses/messages-to-the-community/2020/june-22.html">June
22</a></b> – Bowdoin College (Brunswick, ME): "In order to provide the best
learning experience possible, nearly all classes, including those on campus,
will be taught online."

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www.umb.edu/editor_uploads/images/covid_19/Fall_Plan_Finalized_06.22.20.pdf">June
22</a></b> – University of Massachusetts Boston (Boston, MA): "Certain lab
courses in the sciences and nursing courses that require the use of the
simulation center will remain on campus. The rest of the curriculum will be
delivered to you via remote instruction."

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www2.ljworld.com/news/general-news/2020/jun/25/haskell-students-will-not-return-this-fall-all-classes-to-be-held-online/">June
25</a></b> – Haskell Indian Nations University (Lawrence, KS): "Haskell President
Ronald Graham told the Journal-World Thursday that all classes would be held
virtually for the fall semester".

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://blogs.newschool.edu/community-messages/2020/06/26/update-on-plans-for-2020-2021-academic-year/">June
26</a></b> – New School (New York, NY): "All classes will be online this fall.
Given what we know today, we believe that remote learning is the best option
for the health and safety of the entire New School community and for preventing
the spread of the virus".

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www.umass.edu/coronavirus/chancellors-letter-community-0">June
29</a></b> – University of Massachusetts Amherst (Amherst, MA): "Only essential
face-to-face labs, studios, performance, and other courses involving hands-on
work will be conducted on campus and in-person. ... All other courses will be
delivered remotely."

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www.wilmu.edu/alerts/coronavirus-20200630-classes-online-fall-2020.aspx">June
30</a></b> – Wilmington University (New Castle, DE): "No one knows if COVID-19
will continue to spread at its current pace. The virus is still in its first
phase, and there is growing concern that numbers will increase, or possibly
result in a second wave. Due to these uncertainties and the need to keep our
community safe, courses will remain online for the fall 2020 semester."

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://zaytuna.edu/academics/fall2020-update">June 30</a></b> –
Zaytuna College (Berkeley, CA): "Zaytuna's leadership has decided that
instruction for the Fall 2020 semester will be conducted online for both the
undergraduate and graduate programs".

</p><p>
<b><a href="http://news.hamptonu.edu/release/President%27s-Letter-to-the-HU-Community-07|01|2020">July
1</a></b> – Hampton University (Hampton, VA): "out of an abundance of caution for
the health, safety and welfare of our students as well as the faculty,
administrative staff, administrators, maintenance and custodial staff, and
others with whom students might interact, Hampton University will provide
remote instruction only for the first semester of academic year 2020-2021".

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www.texascollege.edu/uploads/blog/4c5d6e2b76ec71eb3d4bd767344e9680fb2f93f1.pdf">July
1</a></b> – Texas College (Tyler, TX): "Our efforts are not to compete with other
entities and how they respond, but rather give consideration to the needs of
our students, faculty and staff and internally assess what is needed for a safe
environment pursuant to the resources we have available to us. With this as the
backdrop of our planning, a decision has been made to offer online instruction
only for the fall term."


</p><p>
<b><a href="https://coronavirus.usc.edu/2020/07/01/7-1-letter-on-student-housing-and-course-schedules/">July
1</a></b> – University of Southern California (Los Angeles, CA): "our undergraduate
students primarily or exclusively will be taking their courses online in the
fall term".

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://fall2020.princeton.edu/news/president-eisgrubers-message-university-community-about-2020-21-academic-year">July
6</a></b> – Princeton University (Princeton, NJ): "Based on the information now
available to us, we believe ... we will need to do much of our teaching online
and remotely."

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www.rutgers.edu/president/plans-for-fall-2020">July 6</a></b> –
Rutgers University (New Brunswick, NJ): "I am writing today to inform you that
after careful consideration of all possible models for safely and effectively
delivering instruction during the ongoing coronavirus pandemic, Rutgers is
planning for a Fall 2020 semester that will combine a majority of remotely
delivered courses with a limited number of in-person classes".

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www.mmm.edu/live/news/3859-president-walk-announces-mmcs-fall-2020-restart">July
7</a></b> – Marymount Manhattan College (New York, NY): "Given new developments in
the COVID-19 global pandemic, we have adopted a Virtual Classes/Open Campus
model in which all classes will be offered in an online format".

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www.pomona.edu/coronavirus/updates/posts/plans-fall-semester-7820">July
8</a></b> – Pomona College (Claremont, CA): "As the public health situation
deteriorated over the last two weeks, we had to look at the facts and make a
responsible decision: In this unfolding emergency, we will not be able to bring
students back to campus in the fall."

</p><p>
<b><a href="http://www.scrippscollege.edu/news/campus-news/fall-2020-decision-from-the-president">July
8</a></b> – Scripps College (Claremont, CA): "The Administration and Board of
Trustees of the College have determined that our community can best achieve its
mission and maintain safety by offering Scripps classes online during the fall
2020 semester".

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www.jarvis.edu/blog/post/jarvis-online-for-fall-2020">July
10</a></b> – Jarvis Christian College (Hawkins, TX): "To limit exposure to the
virus, we will continue our online classes for fall 2020".

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www.scad.edu/coronavirus">July 10</a></b> – Savannah College of
Art and Design (Savannah/Atlanta, GA): "Following careful deliberation of all
reasonable options, the university is announcing that, as of right now, Fall
2020 on-ground courses will be delivered primarily virtually for SCAD Atlanta
and SCAD Savannah students — with some exceptions to address the needs of
certain programs and students".

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www.wcupa.edu/healthNotices/7.10Update.aspx">July
10</a></b> – West Chester University (Chester County, PA): "My leadership team
and I have made the decision to continue remote learning through the fall 2020
semester, with a few courses delivered in a hybrid format, meaning both
in-person and remote, in order to assist those students with clinical
placements, student teaching, performance obligations, internship sites, and
similar academic responsibilities."

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www.luc.edu/coronavirus/previousmessages/2020-0713-1fall2020.shtml">July
13</a></b> – Loyola University Chicago (Chicago, IL): "we have decided that the
best plan for the upcoming fall semester is to shift most of our class
offerings online".

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www.bennett.edu/fall-2020/">July 14</a></b> – Bennett College
(Greensboro, NC): "After careful research, analysis and consideration, we have
made a decision to operate remotely for the Fall semester."

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www.lmu.edu/together/communitymessages/fall2020reopening/">July
14</a></b> – Loyola Marymount University (Los Angeles, CA): "This fall will be
unlike any other semester: Our undergraduate courses will be principally and
primarily conducted remotely".

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www.simmons.edu/coronavirus/undergraduate-fall-2020">July
14</a></b> – Simmons University (Boston, MA): "Our thoughtful process has led us to
decide that all of our teaching and activities will be online for the Fall 2020
semester, with very few exceptions".

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://myusf.usfca.edu/announcement/fall-semester-will-be-remote">July
14</a></b> – University of San Francisco (San Francisco, CA): "Based on the
surge of COVID-19 cases in San Francisco and California, Gov. Newsom’s
announcements yesterday about rolling back the state’s reopening plans, and
specific instructions issued to higher education institutions today by the San
Francisco Department of Public Health (SFDPH), it is clear that we need to
pivot to USF’s operations being primarily remote for the fall 2020 semester.
This means nearly all academic courses will be online — save for certain
exceptions such as those in clinical nursing programs."

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www.dickinson.edu/homepage/1434/reopening_dashboard">July
15</a></b> – Dickinson College (Carlisle, PA): "we have come to the very difficult
decision that the fall 2020 semester will be remote".

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://lesley.edu/students/health-wellness-safety/coronavirus-disease/fall-2020-plan">July
15</a></b> – Lesley University (Cambridge, MA): "We do not want to repeat the
disruptive experience of last spring where we had to shut down our campus on
short notice, so most campus facilities will remain closed at least through the
end of 2020".

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www.oxy.edu/covid-19/community-messages/updated-plans-fall-2020">July
15</a></b> – Occidental College (Los Angeles, CA): "Today we are announcing that
for the Fall 2020 semester all instruction will be remote".

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://t.e2ma.net/webview/7iapec/b013fe568270cafb59428c2cce86260e">July
15</a></b> – Rhodes College (Memphis, TN): "I write with a heavy heart to let you
know that despite our hopes and plans, the external health conditions in
Memphis do not support an on-campus fall semester".

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www.pacific.edu/campus-life/student-services/student-health-services/fall-semester-2020.html">July
17</a></b> – University of the Pacific (Stockton, CA): "Unfortunately, our
regions’ flat and comparatively low rates of COVID-19 cases experienced through
the spring have rapidly accelerated over the past month. Therefore, we have
determined that it would be unwise to reopen our campuses as we had hoped and
planned."

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://portal.cca.edu/thriving/health-wellness/novel-coronavirus-covid19/fall-2020-semester-will-be-online/">July
20</a></b> – California College of the Arts (San Francisco/Oakland, CA): "We write
today with the unfortunate news that our fall semester courses will be
conducted entirely remotely (online)."

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www.cau.edu/news/2020/07/Offer-Remote-Instruction-for-the-Fall-2020-Semester.html">July
20</a></b> – Clark Atlanta University (Atlanta, GA): "Today, Clark Atlanta
University (CAU) announced the move to remote learning for all students during
the Fall 2020 semester, taking the necessary precautions to ensure the safety
of its students and entire CAU community."

</p><p>
<b><a href="https://www.grinnell.edu/messages/important-changes-to-fall-plans">July
20</a></b> – Grinnell College (Grinnell, IA): "It is thus with a heavy heart that,
after consulting with campus leaders and the Board of Trustees Executive
Committee, and discussing a multitude of options, we …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.kmjn.org/notes/online_fall2020.html">https://www.kmjn.org/notes/online_fall2020.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.kmjn.org/notes/online_fall2020.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23979045</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 18:25:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Iroquois Nationals, barred from World Games, gave gift of lacrosse to the world]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 136 | Comments 24 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23978237">thread link</a>) | @YeGoblynQueenne
<br/>
July 28, 2020 | https://www.cbc.ca/radio/asithappens/as-it-happens-monday-edition-1.5664460/iroquois-nationals-barred-from-world-games-say-their-people-gave-gift-of-lacrosse-to-the-world-1.5664618 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/radio/asithappens/as-it-happens-monday-edition-1.5664460/iroquois-nationals-barred-from-world-games-say-their-people-gave-gift-of-lacrosse-to-the-world-1.5664618">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>The Haudenosaunee&nbsp;gave lacrosse to the&nbsp;world, and now they're&nbsp;being prevented from playing the game on the world stage, says the&nbsp;executive director of the Iroquois Nationals team.&nbsp;</p><div><figure><div><p><img alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5664712.1595882556!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/iroquois-nationals.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>The Iroquois Nationals were the bronze medal winners in 2018 Men’s Field Lacrosse World Championship. Teams that failed to outperform them have been invited to the World Games, while the Nationals have not.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Canadian Lacrosse Association)</figcaption></figure><p><span></span><span>Listen</span><span>6:30</span></p><p><span><p><a href="https://www.cbc.ca/radio/asithappens/as-it-happens-monday-edition-1.5664460/july-27-2020-episode-transcript-1.5667107">Read Story Transcript</a></p>  <p>The Haudenosaunee&nbsp;gave lacrosse to the&nbsp;world, and now they're&nbsp;being prevented from playing the game on the world stage, says the&nbsp;executive director of the Iroquois Nationals team.&nbsp;</p>  <p>The team, which represents the Haudenosaunee Confederacy in international field lacrosse, <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/indigenous/supporters-challenge-iroquois-nationals-exclusion-from-2022-world-games-1.5662381">has been deemed ineligible for 2022 World Games in Birmingham, Ala</a>., despite coming in third at the qualifying men's world championships. Several teams that&nbsp;ranked behind the Iroquois Nationals have been invited to compete in Alabama.</p>  <p>The Haudenosaunee —&nbsp;a confederacy of six First Nations: Mohawk, Oneida, Onondaga, Cayuga, Seneca and Tuscarora Nations — invented lacrosse and call it the&nbsp;Creator's Game.</p>  <p>The Iroquois Nationals are member in good standing of World Lacrosse. But it's the International World Games Association (IWGA) that determines eligibility for the Alabama tournament.</p>  <p>The IWGA has not responded to requests for comment. The organizing committee for the World Games in Birmingham&nbsp;<a href="https://www.aptnnews.ca/national-news/petition-calls-for-boycott-of-world-lacrosse-games-after-iroquois-nationals-excluded/">told APTN</a>&nbsp;that IWGA follows the&nbsp;criteria established by the International Olympics Committee, which states that "the expression country means an independent State recognized by the international community."</p>  <p>The Haudenosaunee Confederacy more than meets that definition, says Iroquois Nationals executive director Leo Nolan, a Mohawk from the Onondaga Nation. Here is part of his conversation with&nbsp;<em>As It Happens </em>guest host Susan Bonner.</p>  <p><strong>Take us through the moment you found out the Nationals were not invited to the World Games. What was your reaction?</strong></p>  <p>We found out through a third party in late September, early October.</p>  <p>We immediately sent a letter to World Lacrosse asking about our lack of inclusion. And the response back was that we didn't meet what they believed were — and this is their belief — that we wouldn't meet that criteria as a nation state to be included in the Olympics.</p>  <p>All of this is a precursor of the Olympics, which, you know, we're right now on provisional status, lacrosse as a sport. And once the provisional status is lifted, then hopefully lacrosse will be reintroduced to the Olympics in 2028 in Los Angeles.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.2707570.1595882465!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/haudenosaunee-passport.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.2707570.1595882465!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/haudenosaunee-passport.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.2707570.1595882465!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/haudenosaunee-passport.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.2707570.1595882465!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/haudenosaunee-passport.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.2707570.1595882465!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/haudenosaunee-passport.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.2707570.1595882465!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/haudenosaunee-passport.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>The Iroquois Nationals travel with Haudenosaunee passports — a fact that has led to travel delays in previous competitions. <!-- --> <!-- -->(Submitted by Candace Maracle)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p><strong>How does the team rank worldwide?</strong></p>  <p>In the men's ... we are third in the world. And we've won the bronze medal the last two competitions, in 2014 in Denver and then in 2018 in Israel.</p>  <p>In the indoor game, we've won a silver every year it's been competed since 2003.</p>  <p><strong>So what do you think this is about then, Mr. Nolan?</strong></p>  <p>I'm not one to point fingers or to speak ill of anyone. I mean, I don't think that's the way we should operate in this time and age.</p>  <p>I think part of it could be a lack of appreciation, understanding and just basic knowledge about who&nbsp;we are as a nation state, so to speak.&nbsp;</p>  <p>There's always speculation about, you know, racism, and I think that it's wrong for us to even push that kind of thing. I don't have strong evidence of that aspect of it, and I don't think that that's the way we want to go forward with this. So I think it's more a lack of ...&nbsp;understanding our status.</p>    <blockquote><span><span><svg version="1.1" focusable="false" x="0px" y="0px" width="30px" height="25px" viewBox="0 0 52.157 39.117" enable-background="new 0 0 52.157 39.117" space="preserve"><g><g><path fill="000000" d="M22.692,10.113c-5.199,1.4-8.398,4.4-8.398,8.801c0,2.4,2,3,3.6,4.199c2.2,1.602,3.4,3.4,3.4,6.602   c0,3.799-3.4,6.799-7.4,6.799c-4.6,0-8.8-3.199-8.8-10.6c0-13.6,7-20,17.599-21.799V10.113z M45.692,10.113   c-5.199,1.4-8.399,4.4-8.399,8.801c0,2.4,2,3,3.601,4.199c2.2,1.602,3.399,3.4,3.399,6.602c0,3.799-3.399,6.799-7.399,6.799   c-4.601,0-8.8-3.199-8.8-10.6c0-13.6,7-20,17.599-21.799V10.113z"></path></g></g><g display="none"><g display="inline"> <path fill="000000" d="M6.648,29.759c5.199-1.4,8.398-4.4,8.398-8.801c0-2.398-2-3-3.599-4.199c-2.2-1.6-3.399-3.4-3.399-6.6   c0-3.801,3.399-6.801,7.399-6.801c4.599,0,8.8,3.201,8.8,10.6c0,13.6-7,20-17.6,21.801V29.759z M29.648,29.759   c5.199-1.4,8.398-4.4,8.398-8.801c0-2.398-2-3-3.599-4.199c-2.2-1.6-3.401-3.4-3.401-6.6c0-3.801,3.401-6.801,7.401-6.801   c4.599,0,8.8,3.201,8.8,10.6c0,13.6-7,20-17.6,21.801V29.759z"></path></g></g></svg>We are the originators of the game. It came to us, it was given to us by the Creator as a medicine game to help heal us. And then&nbsp;it transcended into what we see today as a lacrosse game.<svg focusable="false" x="0px" y="0px" width="23px" height="22px" viewBox="0 0 52.157 39.117" enable-background="new 0 0 52.157 39.117" space="preserve"><g display="none"><g display="inline"><path fill="000000" d="M22.692,10.113c-5.199,1.4-8.398,4.4-8.398,8.801c0,2.4,2,3,3.6,4.199c2.2,1.602,3.4,3.4,3.4,6.602   c0,3.799-3.4,6.799-7.4,6.799c-4.6,0-8.8-3.199-8.8-10.6c0-13.6,7-20,17.599-21.799V10.113z M45.692,10.113   c-5.199,1.4-8.399,4.4-8.399,8.801c0,2.4,2,3,3.601,4.199c2.2,1.602,3.399,3.4,3.399,6.602c0,3.799-3.399,6.799-7.399,6.799   c-4.601,0-8.8-3.199-8.8-10.6c0-13.6,7-20,17.599-21.799V10.113z"></path></g></g><g><g><path fill="000000" d="M6.648,29.759c5.199-1.4,8.398-4.4,8.398-8.801c0-2.398-2-3-3.599-4.199c-2.2-1.6-3.399-3.4-3.399-6.6   c0-3.801,3.399-6.801,7.399-6.801c4.599,0,8.8,3.201,8.8,10.6c0,13.6-7,20-17.6,21.801V29.759z M29.648,29.759   c5.199-1.4,8.398-4.4,8.398-8.801c0-2.398-2-3-3.599-4.199c-2.2-1.6-3.401-3.4-3.401-6.6c0-3.801,3.401-6.801,7.401-6.801   c4.599,0,8.8,3.201,8.8,10.6c0,13.6-7,20-17.6,21.801V29.759z"></path></g></g></svg></span><cite>- Leo Nola, executive dictor of the Iroquois Nationals</cite></span></blockquote>    <p><strong>You qualified, but it's a question of sovereignty?</strong></p>  <p>Yes, I believe it is a question of sovereignty.&nbsp;</p>  <p>We have treaties with the Dutch, the French, the English, with the United States.&nbsp;</p>  <p>Beside the treaties, you know, we have our passports, which we've utilized for four international [competitions]. There have been times where we've been challenged, you know, about these passports because the officials looking at our passports may not recognize them, but that's something we established.</p>  <p>Clearly, our international efforts have been longstanding, not just on lacrosse, but just in our relationship with governments.</p>  <p>[In] the United States, we have a government-to-government relationship, and it's unique.</p>  <p><span><blockquote lang="en"><p>📰 READ | Canadian Lacrosse Association Statement on Iroquois Nationals and the World Games &lt;a href="https://t.co/jn4Lh9NJJ5"&gt;https://t.co/jn4Lh9NJJ5&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;---&lt;br&gt;📰 LIRE | Énoncé de l’Association canadienne de crosse à propos des Iroquois Nationals et les Jeux mondiaux &lt;a href="https://t.co/vHRkxePceV"&gt;https://t.co/vHRkxePceV&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/IRQ_Nationals?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@IRQ_Nationals&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TWG2022?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@TWG2022&lt;/a&gt;</p>&amp;mdash;<a href="https://twitter.com/LacrosseCanada/status/1287426740537757696">@LacrosseCanada</a></blockquote></span></p>  <p><strong>Can you tell me what it means to you personally and to the players to compete on the world stage in lacrosse as a Haudenosaunee&nbsp;team?</strong></p>  <p>It really enhances our standing internationally and I think, domestically, our sovereignty. It really shows who we are. We have our own territories ... First Nation communities that, as you know, are sovereign territory.</p>  <p>So it means a&nbsp;lot to us to represent a Six Nations Confederacy for our players. I've talked to many of our players and, you know, one of the great things about our community and our young folks is they all ... aspire to be Iroquois Nationals lacrosse players, both men and women, boys and girls.</p>  <p>So I think it means a lot to our Haudenosaunee&nbsp;and to all the Indigenous communities around the world. We get a lot of inquiries from a lot of different places about our ability to be in the game and how much it means to them to showcase a sovereign nation to really represent our interests.</p>  <p><span><blockquote lang="en"><p>More information on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TWG2022?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@TWG2022&lt;/a&gt; decision to NOT include Haudenosaunee athletes at the 2022 Birmingham Games&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/IRQtoBHM?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#IRQtoBHM&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/QSU2Lf3wFy"&gt;pic.twitter.com/QSU2Lf3wFy&lt;/a&gt;</p>&amp;mdash;<a href="https://twitter.com/IRQ_Nationals/status/1286077197602689026">@IRQ_Nationals</a></blockquote></span></p>  <p><strong>And what is it about lacrosse specifically that is so special?</strong></p>  <p>We are the originators of the game. It came to us. It was given to us by the Creator as a medicine game to help heal us. And then&nbsp;it transcended into what we see today as a lacrosse game.&nbsp;</p>  <p>And part of that responsibility the Creator gave to us was to share this with others, which, as you know, now 66 countries play lacrosse. It was a gift that we gave to the rest of the world. So I think it means a lot for us to be able to continue that.</p>  <p>And we have probably, I believe, the world's best player in lacrosse right now.</p>  <p><span><blockquote lang="en"><p>A statement from World Lacrosse: &lt;a href="https://t.co/dAraJftRdQ"&gt;pic.twitter.com/dAraJftRdQ&lt;/a&gt;</p>&amp;mdash;<a href="https://twitter.com/worldlaxsport/status/1286131256095199232">@worldlaxsport</a></blockquote></span></p>  <p><strong>The World Games are in 2022. That gives you some time. What do you do now? What's next?</strong></p>  <p>We are working very closely with the World Games organizing committee in Birmingham, Ala.</p>  <p>I don't want to speak for them, but they obviously have a lot of concern about whether we're in or not. I think, just based on a few conversations, I think they see the value of us being there.</p>  <p>Why would you exclude some of the best players in the world [from] a world competition?</p>    <p><strong>So you're hopeful.</strong></p>  <p>Always optimistic. You know, you've got to take that kind of optimistic turn and help people understand better what this is about and how it's going to benefit all of us. All of us, you know, world lacrosse, in general, I think it will benefit.</p>  <p>The more and more we can get more countries to come in and play this wonderful game, I think the better off we're all going to be.</p>  <p>So, yes, we are very optimistic.</p>  <hr>  <p><em>Written by Sheena Goodyear with files from CBC&nbsp;Indigenous. Interview produced by Mehek&nbsp;Mazhar.</em></p></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/radio/asithappens/as-it-happens-monday-edition-1.5664460/iroquois-nationals-barred-from-world-games-say-their-people-gave-gift-of-lacrosse-to-the-world-1.5664618</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23978237</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 17:20:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[U.S. citizens no longer have access to most of the world]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 176 | Comments 245 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23976930">thread link</a>) | @colinprince
<br/>
July 28, 2020 | https://www.cbc.ca/radio/thesundayedition/the-sunday-edition-for-july-19-2020-1.5647948/u-s-citizens-no-longer-have-access-to-most-of-the-world-the-global-south-never-had-it-1.5648022 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/radio/thesundayedition/the-sunday-edition-for-july-19-2020-1.5647948/u-s-citizens-no-longer-have-access-to-most-of-the-world-the-global-south-never-had-it-1.5648022">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>United States citizenship is one of the most prized citizenships in the world, giving citizens to both live and work inside the country and travel, hassle-free, to 185 others. Because of COVID-19, that number is down to 28.</p><div><figure><div><p><img alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5282546.1568389321!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/canadapassportominous.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>As the COVID-19 pandemic continues to spread around the United States, Americans have joined the ranks of people whose passports are viewed with suspicion by the rest of the world.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Sean Kilpatrick/The Canadian Press)</figcaption></figure><p><span></span><span>Listen</span><span>19:31</span></p><p><span><p>Americans used to have one of the most prized passports in the world, considered a golden ticket to wealth, travel and opportunity.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>  <p>With an American passport in your bag, you could arrive at the doors of 185 countries and get visa-free entry. No big questions —&nbsp; just business or pleasure?&nbsp;</p>  <p>But with the onset of COVID-19, Americans are <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/07/travel/american-travelers-restrictions-coronavirus.html?action=click&amp;module=Well&amp;pgtype=Homepage&amp;section=Travel" target="_blank"><u>limited to just 28 countries</u></a>, mostly in the <a href="https://medium.com/@indica/the-plague-states-of-america-53b20678a80e" target="_blank"><u>Caribbean and Eastern Europe</u></a>. That number drops if you exclude countries that require a two-week quarantine, such as the the United Kingdom or South Korea.</p>  <p>On July 18, the European Union renewed its recommendation that&nbsp;U.S. residents be banned from entry to any member-states. The same day, Canada confirmed the U.S. border would remain closed to non-essential travel for another month.</p>  <p>More than 3.5 million U.S. residents have caught COVID-19 since the start of the pandemic, and by mid-July, the disease killed more than 138,000 people, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2020/us/coronavirus-us-cases.html"><u>according to the New York Times</u></a>.</p>  <h2>Travel limitations in the rest of the world</h2>  <p>If U.S. citizens are feeling like they've suddenly lost access to most of the world, they should probably talk to citizens of countries like Sri Lanka. For decades, the island nation, along with many other developing nations, have had to jump over hurdles to leave their country.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5653616.1595005076!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/tse-july-19-2020-covid-19-passports-indi-samarajiva-headshot.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5653616.1595005076!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/tse-july-19-2020-covid-19-passports-indi-samarajiva-headshot.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5653616.1595005076!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/tse-july-19-2020-covid-19-passports-indi-samarajiva-headshot.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5653616.1595005076!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/tse-july-19-2020-covid-19-passports-indi-samarajiva-headshot.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5653616.1595005076!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/tse-july-19-2020-covid-19-passports-indi-samarajiva-headshot.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5653616.1595005076!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/tse-july-19-2020-covid-19-passports-indi-samarajiva-headshot.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Indi Samarajiva is a Canadian-born, American-raised Sri Lankan writer living in Colombo, Sri Lanka.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Shruthi Mathews)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>Indi Samarajiva, a writer based in Colombo, Sri Lanka, was born in Canada, and has a Canadian passport to boot. With access to 183 countries visa-free, Samarajiva was rarely concerned about access to other nations, until he had children.</p>  <p>When Samarajiva decided to visit South Korea, along with his wife, son and daughter, he quickly ran into roadblocks.</p>  <p>His daughter has a British passport, inherited through Samarajiva's wife. His son is eligible for a British citizenship, but they haven't done the paperwork just yet. That meant all his son had was his Sri Lankan citizenship to enter South Korea.</p>  <p>The Sri Lankan passport is in the bottom 10 per cent internationally when it comes to visa-free travel, according to the <a href="https://www.henleypassportindex.com/passport" target="_blank"><u>Henley Passport Index</u></a>.</p>  <p>"When we're going to Korea, my daughter just sails through," said Samarajiva.</p>  <p>"But for my son, I have to go to the embassy. I have to bring bank statements. I have to bring letters. [...] It's honestly like a humiliating and unnecessary process. And of course, they also make you pay for it."</p>    <p>The pandemic has prompted lawmakers around the world to close national borders, and no passport holders have regained the number of visa-free travel destinations they had prior to the pandemic.</p>  <p>"I think Americans, and honestly, the world can see what I've seen my whole life, which is that these borders are real, they're sharp and they hurt people," said Samarajiva.</p>  <p>"I can see the absurdity of the situation because [my] kids are basically the same. And just based on paperwork, they're treated so differently."</p>  <h2>A likely return to normal?</h2>  <p>Dimitry Kochenov, chair in European constitutional law and citizenship at Groningen University, believes that these limitations can be painful for Americans to witness because they've never had to experience them.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5653605.1595004453!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/tse-july-19-2020-dimitry-kochenov-headshot.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5653605.1595004453!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/tse-july-19-2020-dimitry-kochenov-headshot.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5653605.1595004453!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/tse-july-19-2020-dimitry-kochenov-headshot.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5653605.1595004453!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/tse-july-19-2020-dimitry-kochenov-headshot.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5653605.1595004453!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/tse-july-19-2020-dimitry-kochenov-headshot.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5653605.1595004453!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/tse-july-19-2020-dimitry-kochenov-headshot.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Dimitry Kochenov studies global, EU citizenship and European constitutionalism. <!-- --> <!-- -->(Submitted by Dimitry Kochenov)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>"They're simply confronted with this reality that is well known for for the holders of the absolute majority of other passports all around the world," Kochenov said.</p>  <p>He argues in his book&nbsp;<a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/citizenship" target="_blank"><em>Citizenship</em></a>&nbsp;that citizenships recreate class structures between the poor and rich internationally, and&nbsp;mean people of&nbsp;certain nationalities&nbsp;are&nbsp;landlocked to poorer countries.</p>  <p>"If you are Sri Lankan, if you're Iraqi, if you are a Central African, [...] then you are not welcome anywhere," he said.</p>  <p>"And instead of rights, your citizenship actually gives you liabilities because it locks you in a poor space where you cannot possibly realise your potential."</p>    <p>Kochenov said that the COVID-19-prompted travel restrictions are likely temporary, and there's a high chance that U.S. citizens&nbsp;will&nbsp;regain their broader ability to travel, once the pandemic ends.</p>  <p>For example, though the European Union recommended that member-countries ban U.S. residents from entering, current American citizens living in Europe are not being expelled.</p>    <p>The biggest concern for Kochenov remains whether politicians will use the opportunity to keep borders closed to potential immigrants from around the world.&nbsp;</p>  <p>"This situation [...] unfortunately, is perceived by some parts of our occupations as normal. So the task number one now in Europe and elsewhere is to ensure that the world opens up at least to the same level which we could observe before the pandemic has started," said Kochenov.</p>  <p><em>Click 'listen' above to hear the full interview.</em></p></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/radio/thesundayedition/the-sunday-edition-for-july-19-2020-1.5647948/u-s-citizens-no-longer-have-access-to-most-of-the-world-the-global-south-never-had-it-1.5648022</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23976930</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 15:42:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[DNS-over-TLS vs. DNS-over-HTTPS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 44 | Comments 20 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23976491">thread link</a>) | @serenadns
<br/>
July 28, 2020 | https://www.dnsfilter.com/blog/dns-over-tls/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.dnsfilter.com/blog/dns-over-tls/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="3613" data-elementor-settings="[]"><div><div><section data-particle_enable="false" data-particle-mobile-disabled="false" data-id="a4cd4d9" data-element_type="section"><div><div><div data-id="d14b000" data-element_type="column"><div><div><div data-id="4c9be67" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default"><div><div><h2><span>DNS-over-TLS Vs. DNS-over-HTTPS</span></h2><p><span>As the need for DNS encryption evolves, there seems to be a growing debate between DNS-over-TLS (DoT) and DNS-over-HTTPS (DoH). With </span><a href="https://www.securityweek.com/google-makes-dns-over-https-generally-available" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span>Google</span></a><span> (and </span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/25/21152335/mozilla-firefox-dns-over-https-web-privacy-security-encryption" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span>Firefox</span></a><span>) adopting DoH as their DNS encryption method for their browsers, there seems to be a belief that DoH is superior to DoT.</span></p><p><span>But that’s not the case.</span></p><p><span>The reality is that DNS-over-HTTPS and DNS-over-TLS are slightly different standards for implementing the same DNS protections.</span></p><p><span>Both prevent:</span></p><ul><li><span>Spoofing – Forged DNS requests, these usually come in the form of a man-in-the-middle attack where a malicious actor will temporarily redirect users to a fake login page to collect personal information or login credentials</span></li><li><span>Tracking – When untrustworthy entities can view your DNS requests and collect information on you, this data can be sold to advertisers*</span></li></ul><p><span>To simplify this further, the end goal of DNS encryption is to prevent DNS requests from being </span><i><span>read</span></i><span> and from being </span><i><span>modified</span></i><span>.</span></p><h6><span>*Privacy policies are not just a box you need to check. They tell you exactly how a company will use your data. The absence of a privacy policy is a warning sign. We take privacy seriously at DNSFilter, you can check out our </span><a href="https://www.dnsfilter.com/privacy-policy/"><span>Privacy Policy</span></a><span> and the </span><a href="https://go.dnsfilter.com/rs/997-HCT-261/images/DNSF-DNSFilterSecurityPractices-DS.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span>security best practices</span></a><span> we follow to keep our customers safe.</span></h6><h2><span>DoT and DoH aren’t implemented at the same layer</span></h2><p><span>The main difference between DoT and DoH are the layers at which the encryption is enabled. DNS-over-HTTPS is applied at the application layer (two layers removed from the Internet layer) while DNS-over-TLS is applied at the transport layer (one layer removed from the Internet layer).</span></p><p><img src="https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_04222020_OSIModel-e1594910843640.png" data-src="https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_04222020_OSIModel-e1594910843640.png" alt="dns-over-tls OSI model" width="600" height="248" data-srcset="https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_04222020_OSIModel-e1594910843640.png 1920w, https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_04222020_OSIModel-e1594910843640-300x124.png 300w, https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_04222020_OSIModel-e1594910843640-1024x422.png 1024w, https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_04222020_OSIModel-e1594910843640-768x317.png 768w, https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_04222020_OSIModel-e1594910843640-1536x634.png 1536w, https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_04222020_OSIModel-e1594910843640-500x206.png 500w" data-sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" srcset="https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_04222020_OSIModel-e1594910843640.png 1920w, https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_04222020_OSIModel-e1594910843640-300x124.png 300w, https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_04222020_OSIModel-e1594910843640-1024x422.png 1024w, https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_04222020_OSIModel-e1594910843640-768x317.png 768w, https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_04222020_OSIModel-e1594910843640-1536x634.png 1536w, https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_04222020_OSIModel-e1594910843640-500x206.png 500w"></p><p><span>When it comes to implementing DoT or DoH, it really depends on what exactly you’re looking to encrypt and </span><i><span>where</span></i><span>.</span></p><p><span>Since Google and Firefox are browsers, they are already using HTTPS, so implementing DNS-over-HTTPS makes the most sense for them. DNS-over-HTTPS isn’t used by Firefox and Google because it’s </span><i><span>superior</span></i><span> to DoT. It’s used because browsers operate at the HTTPS layer by default, so DNS-over-TLS doesn’t make sense (as things stand now) for a browser to implement.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>Google can’t use DNS-over-TLS in their browser because they can’t modify the code on Windows or MacOS operating systems (which only support DoT at the moment)&nbsp; in order to encrypt DNS requests done outside of the browser. And that works for Google and Firefox, because they only need to encrypt DNS requests </span><i><span>inside</span></i><span> of their browsers.</span></p><p><span>Meanwhile at DNSFilter, we need to operate DNS encryption not just in the browser, but at the operating system level. That’s why we use DNS-over-TLS: Because it can be enabled at a </span><i><span>lower</span></i><span> layer and protect DNS requests outside of the browser (e.g. Slack messages, links embedded in Excel, or miscellaneous desktop applications). And right now, DoT is the primary way to enable standardized DNS encryption at the operating system level.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>Note that DoH is being enabled at the OS level for new versions of iOS, MacOS, and Windows. Because Android is a Google product, and Google Chrome uses DoH, Android devices are already using DoH at the operating system level.</span></p><h2><span>Which is better?</span></h2><p><span>DoH is on everyone’s minds because it’s what Google uses, but it’s not necessarily </span><i><span>better</span></i><span> than DoT. It’s just </span><i><span>different</span></i><span>, and in some ways it’s actually inferior to DoT.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>In a lot of ways, DoT is more efficient because of which layer within the TCP/IP model it is enabled in. Remember, DoH is </span><b>two</b><span> layers removed from the internet layer while DoT is only </span><b>one</b><span> layer removed.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>Because there is another layer of encapsulation in DoH, it results in:</span></p><ul><li><span>More coding required</span></li><li><span>More libraries required</span></li><li><span>Packet sizes are larger than DoT</span></li><li><span>Ever-so-slightly higher latency</span></li></ul><p><span>These are a few of the reasons why DNSFilter chose DoT over DoH. Basically, we would have needed to send more data across another layer. Though it should be noted that both DoT </span><i><span>and</span></i><span> DoH increase latency, DoT has lower latency because of where it’s enabled.</span></p><p><span>But the most important reason for us, and our users, in choosing DoT was the ability to enable DNS encryption at the </span><i><span>lowest possible layer</span></i><span> since our users do not just send DNS requests over their browsers. That’s why we use DoT.</span></p><p><span>But that doesn’t mean we think DoT is the </span><i><span>only</span></i><span> answer. We </span><i><span>are</span></i><span> planning on having a DoH implementation for clients who need it.</span></p><p><span>As an example, Android devices, such as Chromebooks, use DoH. This is because Android devices were created by Google. While Windows and MacOS do not currently support DoH, Google was able to modify their Android devices so that DoH would be possible.</span></p><p><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/microsoft-is-adding-dns-over-https-doh-to-windows-10/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span>Microsoft has even announced adding support for DoH</span></a><span>, while also keeping their DoT support.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>Though, just because Microsoft supports DoH for their operating system doesn’t mean the higher latency or additional coding requirements go away. No matter what, DoH is still implemented at a higher layer than DoT. The only change would be that now DoH can be implemented at the operating system level.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>This addition of DoH support is likely less about Microsoft giving their users more options and more about them following Google’s lead.</span></p><h2><span>Other DNS protocol variations</span></h2><p><span>DoH and DoT are not the only encryption protocols available, though at this point they are more robust and the most widely used. But before encryption standards were available, there was also DNSSEC.</span></p><p><span>DNSSEC was an early DNS standard that provided </span><i><span>no</span></i><span> encryption or privacy for your DNS requests. It </span><i><span>only</span></i><span> prevents man-in-the-middle attacks. And if it is not applied properly, it will </span><i><span>break</span></i><span> your website. </span><a href="https://ianix.com/pub/dnssec-outages.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span>You can check out a feed of websites broken by improper DNSSEC implementations here</span></a><span>.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>DNSSEC is prone to frequent outages and it was never widely adopted. Due to that, and because it only does a portion of what DoH and DoT do, are just a few reasons that at DNSFilter we don’t recommend using DNSSEC, though we do support it.</span></p><p><span>DNSCrypt is another DNS encryption option, though far less popular than the two protocols we’re comparing right now. Like DNS-over-TLS, it is applied at the transport layer. DNSCrypt prevents localized man-in-the-middle attacks and encrypts DNS traffic between the user and recursive DNS servers, though it does not provide end-to-end encryption.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>But the biggest difference between DNSCrypt and other standards (like DoT) is that there is no </span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Request_for_Comments" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span>RFC</span></a><span> (Request for Comments) like there is for DoH or DoT. This means it hasn’t been peer-reviewed and battle-tested. Implementations can vary greatly, and all of the definitions and specifications for DNSCrypt come from a single source.</span></p><p><span>You can access the RFCs for </span><a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc7858" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span>DoT</span></a><span> and </span><a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc8484" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span>DoH</span></a><span> here.</span></p><h2><span>DNS encryption is </span><em><span>still</span></em><span> evolving</span></h2><p><span>There is no right answer when it comes to DoT or DoH, because these standards support varying use cases. But if DoH continues to be adopted like it has been, we might see DoT go by the wayside.</span></p><p><span>With that being said, it’s not just a matter of choosing DoT or DoH. There is still work that needs to be done in both DNS encryption </span><i><span>and</span></i><span> SNI (Server Name Indication) encryption.</span></p><p><span>SNI is the layer above TLS and an extension of the TLS layer. Once you make a DNS request and TLS makes a secure connection with that IP address, SNI tells the server in clear text (not encrypted) what the name of that domain is. While this does not impact things like man-in-the-middle attacks, it </span><i><span>does</span></i><span> impact privacy. Currently, SNI is </span><i><span>not</span></i><span> encrypted, though it is something that is being worked on.</span></p><p><span>While DoT and DoH are the most secure and standardized methods for encrypting DNS, they </span><i><span>do not</span></i><span> encrypt the request that goes to the authoritative DNS. That request is received in clear text. This is a point of vulnerability in both DoT and DoH, as well as DNSCrypt. Right now there is no standard for encrypting this information.</span></p><p><img src="https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_07162020_AuthoritativeDNS-e1594910168526.png" data-src="https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_07162020_AuthoritativeDNS-e1594910168526.png" alt="authoritative dns" width="600" height="145" data-srcset="https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_07162020_AuthoritativeDNS-e1594910168526.png 1920w, https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_07162020_AuthoritativeDNS-e1594910168526-300x73.png 300w, https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_07162020_AuthoritativeDNS-e1594910168526-1024x248.png 1024w, https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_07162020_AuthoritativeDNS-e1594910168526-768x186.png 768w, https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_07162020_AuthoritativeDNS-e1594910168526-1536x372.png 1536w, https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_07162020_AuthoritativeDNS-e1594910168526-500x121.png 500w" data-sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" srcset="https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_07162020_AuthoritativeDNS-e1594910168526.png 1920w, https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_07162020_AuthoritativeDNS-e1594910168526-300x73.png 300w, https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_07162020_AuthoritativeDNS-e1594910168526-1024x248.png 1024w, https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_07162020_AuthoritativeDNS-e1594910168526-768x186.png 768w, https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_07162020_AuthoritativeDNS-e1594910168526-1536x372.png 1536w, https://www.dnsfilter.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/DoT-or-DoH-Blog_07162020_AuthoritativeDNS-e1594910168526-500x121.png 500w"></p><p>As a DNS resolver, we support and welcome a standard for encrypting messages to authoritative DNS, and we’d love to work with providers to help put this in place.</p><p><span>But the point I’m trying to make here is that neither DoT nor DoH are perfect DNS encryption solutions at this moment. More work still needs to be done, like enabling 0-RTT for all DNS-over-TLS and DNS-over-HTTPS implementations.</span></p><p><span>While everyone is talking about DoH, it’s not because it’s the most secure or most efficient solution. It’s because right now, it’s the solution that’s getting the most press. </span><a href="https://dfarq.homeip.net/why-vhs-beat-betamax/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span>When VHS overtook Betamax</span></a><span>, it wasn’t because VHS was better in every way. Betamax actually provided better video quality, but VHS was cheaper and allowed people to record longer programs. VHS and Betamax both achieve the same end (recording and displaying video), </span><a href="https://www.infosecmonkey.com/2019/11/19/betamax-doh-vs-vhs-dot-in-the-secure-dns-wars/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span>similar to how DoT and DoH both provide encryption</span></a><span> through slightly different methods.</span></p><p><span>One of the biggest impacts of the “DoH vs. DoT” debate is the way MSPs implement network-level DNS filtering. With DoH becoming the de facto standard, it makes performing DoH bypasses on system-level DNS settings nearly impossible. There’s no standard method at this time for alternative workarounds. We’ll go into this subject in more detail in a later blog post, as there is a lot to consider when discussing the impact on MSPs.</span></p><p><span>For more reading on DNS-over-TLS and how it’s implemented by DNSFilter, </span><a href="https://docs.dnsfilter.com/docs/dns-over-tls" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span>visit our support documentation</span></a><span>.</span></p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section></div></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.dnsfilter.com/blog/dns-over-tls/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23976491</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 15:00:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Density raises $51M Series C led by Kleiner Perkins]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 91 | Comments 48 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23975998">thread link</a>) | @jordanmessina
<br/>
July 28, 2020 | https://www.density.io/blog/kleiner/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.density.io/blog/kleiner/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">

			<section>
			<div>
				<div>
					<div>
						<picture><img width="960" height="540" src="https://mk0densityseiwq9asus.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Density__KP.001-960x540.png" alt="" srcset="https://mk0densityseiwq9asus.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Density__KP.001-960x540.png 960w, https://mk0densityseiwq9asus.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Density__KP.001-300x169.png 300w, https://mk0densityseiwq9asus.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Density__KP.001-1024x576.png 1024w, https://mk0densityseiwq9asus.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Density__KP.001-768x432.png 768w, https://mk0densityseiwq9asus.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Density__KP.001-1536x864.png 1536w, https://mk0densityseiwq9asus.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Density__KP.001-640x360.png 640w, https://mk0densityseiwq9asus.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Density__KP.001-255x143.png 255w, https://mk0densityseiwq9asus.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Density__KP.001-555x312.png 555w, https://mk0densityseiwq9asus.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Density__KP.001-1191x670.png 1191w, https://mk0densityseiwq9asus.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Density__KP.001.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px"></picture>					</div> <!--  .blog-slider-image -->

					<div>
						<div>
							 <!--  .entry-links -->

							 <!--  .entry-title -->

							
<p>
	<span>
		Jul 28th, 2020	</span>

			 / <span>2 min read</span>
	</p> <!--  .entry-meta -->

							
						</div> <!--  .entry entry-minimal -->
					</div> <!--  .blog-slider-content -->
				</div> <!--  .blog-slider-item -->
			</div> <!-- .blog-slider -->
		</section> <!--  .section-blog-slider -->
	
	<section>
		<div>
			<div>
				<div id="primary">
					<main id="main">
						
 <!--  .post-author-wrapper -->

						

						
<article id="post-9965">
	<div>
		
<p><strong>When we first</strong> <strong>conceived of Density six years ago</strong>, we just wanted to know if there was a line at our favorite coffee shop. We thought it was odd there was an API for inclement weather but there wasn't an API for how many people were in a space. We reasoned, if a solution didn't already exist â€” which surely it must â€” it shouldn't be more than a weekend project. How hard could it be to count people?</p>



<p>We were optimistic and wrong by about three years. As we tried to solve our own problem, we learned two important lessons. First, people are weird. They do things you wouldn't expect â€” they bump into each other, take phone calls, and they bring a lot of stuff with them: bags and boxes, bicycles and baskets, tv's and trash cans, chairs, carts, iPads, lunch, even other people sometimes. This makes counting them unfathomably complex. You can't fault commodity products for being bad at the analysis. People are just really weird.</p>



<p>Second, we learned we weren't alone. We met hundreds and now thousands of others trying to answer the same question â€” how many people used my office, bank, lounge, desk, space, floor, building, campusâ€¦ city. If only we knew, we could reduce waste and energy use, improve access and productivity, clean the spaces that need it and skip the ones that don't. If only we knew, we could A/B test physical space or even use less concrete! If only we knew how the world was used, we could measure how it works, identify its inefficiencies, and remake it.</p>



<p>Until recently, we had been helping hundreds of companies do just this â€” quantify how buildings were used so they could design them more effectively. Today, things have changed. We've been asked to help those same companies and hundreds more reopen their buildings and businesses safely. We're helping them avoid leases they don't need in order to prioritize payroll. We're working to keep meat processing plants, distribution centers, manufacturers, offices, universities, even an entire village in Ohio open and safe.</p>



<p>The built world was modernizing before the pandemic. It will continue to modernize well after it's over. In the meantime, we're proud to say we're not going anywhere and we're eager to help.</p>



<p><em>Andrew Farah, Density CEO</em></p>



<hr>



<p><em>*Density will be using this investment to support its rapidly scaling customer base â€” customer success, sales, infrastructure, ops, manufacturing, engineering, and core product. Interested? <a href="https://www.density.io/jobs" target="_blank" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener">We're hiring</a>.</em></p>



<p><em>** Thank you to Ilya Fushman, GP at Kleiner Perkins, who will be joining Density's Board of Directors, and to the singular teams at KP, 01 Advisors, Upfront Ventures, Founders Fund, Launch, Ludlow Ventures, LPC Ventures, Greenoaks, and DTA.</em></p>



<p><em>*** And a sincere thank you to the litany of operators and individuals who have participated and helped along the way: Mark Suster, Dick Costolo, Jason Calacanis, Jonathon Triest, Joanna Coles, John Luttig, Alex Davis, Alex Rodriguez, Kevin and Julia Hartz, Cyan and Scott Banister, Adam Bain, Heather Podesta, Jeff Weinstein, Vinay Menda, Moshe Lifschitz, Nate Bosshard, Brian Silverstein, and so many others.</em></p>
	</div><!-- .entry-content -->
</article><!-- #post-## -->
					</main><!-- #main -->
				</div><!-- .content-area -->
			</div><!-- .columns medium-16 -->

			<!-- .columns medium-8 -->
		</div><!-- .row -->
	</section><!-- .section-fullwidth section-main -->
	
	
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.density.io/blog/kleiner/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23975998</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 14:15:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[List of Peter Thiel's Online Writings]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 31 | Comments 15 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23975518">thread link</a>) | @leon500
<br/>
July 28, 2020 | https://thememeticist.com/other/2020/07/28/thiel-online-writing-list.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thememeticist.com/other/2020/07/28/thiel-online-writing-list.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thememeticist.com/other/2020/07/28/thiel-online-writing-list.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23975518</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 13:29:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Regular Expression Visualizer, Simulator and Cross-Compiler Tool]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 187 | Comments 39 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23975041">thread link</a>) | @robertelder
<br/>
July 28, 2020 | https://blog.robertelder.org/regular-expression-visualizer/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.robertelder.org/regular-expression-visualizer/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<h3>Permalink:</h3>
		<p>
		<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JSgTok3ZwbE" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
		</p>

		
		<pre></pre>

	

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The C source code below is the common code that is required by any of the code samples that are generated above. &nbsp;Simply copy and paste the following code into a file called 'main.c' along with the dynamically generated code above in order to make a hard-coded program that will perform your intended regex search. &nbsp;Make sure the code below is passed before the dynamically generated code above. &nbsp;You can compile the code using this command:</p>

<p><code><pre>gcc main.c
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The code should compile without any issues and produce the executable program 'a.out'. &nbsp;You can run this program with this command:</p>

<p><code><pre>./a.out
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Note that code does not represent a <em>fast</em> implementation of the regular expression (in fact it's one of the slowest implementations possible). &nbsp;The goal here is to produce a program that is very short and easy to understand for educational purposes rather than to produce one that is fast and complicated.</p>

		<p><code><pre><span>#include </span><span>&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>
<span>#include </span><span>&lt;unistd.h&gt;</span>
<span>#include </span><span>&lt;stdarg.h&gt;</span>
<span>#include </span><span>&lt;stdlib.h&gt;</span>
<span>#include </span><span>&lt;sys/wait.h&gt;</span>
<span>#include </span><span>&lt;string.h&gt;</span>

<span>#define GREEDY_BRANCH </span><span>1</span>
<span>#define LAZY_BRANCH </span><span>0</span>

<span>int</span> split(<span>int</span> branch1, <span>int</span> branch2){
  



<span>0</span>
  pid_t child_pid;
  pid_t wpid;
  <span>int</span> status = <span>0</span>;

  <span>if</span>((child_pid = fork()) &gt; <span>0</span>)
    <span>while</span> ((wpid = wait(&amp;status)) &gt; <span>0</span>);
  <span>else</span>
    <span>return</span> branch1;

  <span>if</span>(WIFEXITED(status)){
    <span>if</span>(WEXITSTATUS(status) == <span>0</span>) <span>0.</span>
      exit(<span>0</span>);
    <span>else</span>
      ;
  }<span>else</span>{
    printf(<span>"Unexpected Error Case.</span><span>\n</span><span>"</span>);
    exit(<span>1</span>);
  }

  <span>if</span>((child_pid = fork()) &gt; <span>0</span>)
    <span>while</span> ((wpid = wait(&amp;status)) &gt; <span>0</span>);
  <span>else</span>
    <span>return</span> branch2;

  <span>if</span>(WIFEXITED(status)){
    <span>if</span>(WEXITSTATUS(status) == <span>0</span>) <span>0.</span>
      exit(<span>0</span>);
    <span>else</span>
      exit(<span>1</span>); 
  }<span>else</span>{
    printf(<span>"Unexpected Error Case.</span><span>\n</span><span>"</span>);
    exit(<span>1</span>);
  }
}

<span>int</span> matches_one_of_these_characters(<span>char</span> c, <span>int</span> num_chars, ...){
  <span>va_list</span> arglist;
  va_start(arglist, num_chars);
  <span>int</span> i;
  <span>int</span> found = <span>0</span>;
  <span>for</span>(i = <span>0</span>; i &lt; num_chars; i++){
    <span>int</span> d = (<span>char</span>)va_arg(arglist, <span>int</span>);
    <span>if</span>(c == d){
      found = <span>1</span>;
    }
  }
  va_end(arglist);
  <span>return</span> found;
}

<span>int</span> matches_this_character(<span>char</span> available, <span>char</span> required){
  <span>if</span>(available == required){
    <span>return</span> <span>1</span>;
  }<span>else</span>{
    <span>return</span> <span>0</span>;
  }
}

<span>char</span> safely_get_character(<span>const</span> <span>char</span> * str, <span>int</span> offset, <span>int</span> pos, <span>int</span> str_len){
  <span>if</span>(offset + pos &lt; str_len){
    <span>return</span> str[offset + pos];
  }<span>else</span>{
    exit(<span>1</span>); 
  }
}

<span>int</span> is_beginning_of_text(<span>int</span> position_in_string){
  <span>return</span> position_in_string == <span>0</span>;
}

<span>int</span> is_end_of_text(<span>int</span> position_in_string, <span>int</span> str_len){
  <span>return</span> str_len == position_in_string;
}
</pre></code></p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Above, you'll find an interactive visualization that you can use to simulate regular expressions. &nbsp;You can type any regular expression and the tool will automatically create two diagrams that correspond to your regular expression. &nbsp;Both of these diagrams are interactive, zoomable and include support for a fullscreen mode.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The first diagram is a parse tree. &nbsp;Constructing a parse tree is the first step that a regular expression engine will perform in order to decide what meaning each character will have.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;You can click on individual nodes in the parse tree to highlight the corresponding character in your regular expression. &nbsp;You can also go the other way and click on individual characters in the regular expression to quickly find the corresponding characters in the parse tree. &nbsp;By reviewing how the characters are grouped together in the parse tree, you can gain insights about the meanings of individual characters and how they relate to each other in the regular expression.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The second diagram shows a control flow graph corresponding to your regular expression. &nbsp;This control flow graph illustrates the step by step process that is undertaken whenever your regex is matched against a piece of text. &nbsp; When attempting to match your regular expression, the process starts at the 'BEGIN' node and ends at either the 'MATCH' or 'FAILURE' node. &nbsp;Any path from the 'BEGIN' node to the 'MATCH' node corresponds to a piece of text that matches your regular expression.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Most of the nodes in the control flow graph correspond directly to one or more characters in your regular expression. &nbsp;You can click on nodes in the control flow graph to see the corresponding nodes highlighted in your original regular expression and the parse tree. &nbsp;Also note that clicking on characters in your regex will also highlight any associated nodes in the control flow graph.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;It's difficult to truly understand how your regular expression works without seeing the decisions it makes when attempting to match a given piece of text. &nbsp;For this reason, every time you make changes to your regular expression, this visualization tool will automatically generate a piece of text that contains at least one match to your regular expression. &nbsp;If you want to review how the matching process work with your own customized piece of text, simply change the input value for the search string and the animation will update automatically.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The process of matching the regular expression starts at the 'BEGIN' node and continues by following the arrows to arrive at the nodes that actually do the work of the regular expression itself.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;At the time of writing this sentence, all regular expressions that this visualizer tool supports are ultimately transformed into an control flow graph that consists of the following 5 types of nodes:</p>

<ul>
<li>1) &nbsp;<strong>CHAR</strong>&nbsp;This node type checks for a specific character at the current position in the text that is being searched. &nbsp;If the character matches, we continue to the next node in the control flow graph. &nbsp;If it doesn't match, the control flow graph moves to the 'FAILURE' 'node'.</li>
<li>2) &nbsp;<strong>CLASS</strong>&nbsp;This node type checks for a class of characters at the current position in the text that is being searched. &nbsp;This node type effectively does the same thing as the first node type, except it allows for more than one possible character at the current position in the search text. &nbsp;If the current character in the text is among the list of acceptable characters specified by this node, we continue to the next node in the control flow graph. &nbsp;If it doesn't match, the control flow graph moves to the 'FAILURE' 'node'.</li>
<li>3) &nbsp;<strong>SPLIT</strong>&nbsp;This node type performs a 'split' operation. &nbsp;This is a situation where the regular expression matcher has a more than one possible path to continue through the control flow graph. &nbsp;In programming terms, this node effectively does the same thing as forking a process or splitting off work into two separate threads. &nbsp;This can also be implemented in a single thread by trying both paths one at time and pushing saved information onto a stack. &nbsp;In computer science theory, this node type should remind you of the difference between DFAs and NFAs.</li>
<li>4) &nbsp;<strong>ANCHOR</strong>&nbsp;This node type represents the commonly used 'beginning of string' or 'end of string' regular expression characters. &nbsp;This node is type is quite simple, as it simply checks whether the current position in the string is, respectively, at the first position, or the last position. &nbsp;If the check succeeds, we continue to the next node in the control flow graph. &nbsp;If it doesn't, the control flow graph moves to the 'FAILURE' 'node'.</li>
<li>5) &nbsp;<strong>PROGRESS</strong>&nbsp;This node type is necessary to avoid infinite loops in certain regular expressions that can include repetitions of possibly zero length strings. &nbsp;Without this node, there are cases where the control flow graph could potentially contain cycles that cause us to move around forever without making any progress. &nbsp;Each time a progress node is visited, it makes sure that we've made some progress in matching the regex since the last visit. &nbsp;If we have made progress, we move to the next node in the control flow graph. &nbsp;If not, the control flow graph moves to the 'FAILURE' 'node'.</li>
</ul>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;You may find it surprising, but most commonly used regular expressions can be described in terms of the above 5 simple node types.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The primary purpose of this visualization tool is help you understand the precise meaning of the characters in a regular expression. &nbsp;Therefore, this the tool will also cross-compile your regular expression into a hard-coded C program that implements a search for the regex pattern that you specified. &nbsp;Each of the nodes in the control flow graph has a direct correspondence to several lines of C source code that are expressed below the two diagrams. &nbsp;You can click on nodes in the control flow graph to see which lines of code correspond to the node that you've selected.</p>



<p><code><pre>current_character = safely_get_character(str, offset, pos, str_len);
<span>if</span>(matches_this_character(current_character, CHARACTER_TO_MATCH)){
  pos++;
}<span>else</span>{
  exit(<span>1</span>);
}
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;For the implementation of a 'CHAR' node, we first use the 'safely_get_character' function to pick out the next character from the string being searched. &nbsp;The implementation of the 'safely_get_character' function is listed above in the 'Common C Code' section. &nbsp;This function is very simple since it just checks to make sure we're still within the bounds of the string that's being search, and if so, it returns character at the current position. &nbsp;If we're past the end of the string, we just directly exit the process. &nbsp;This corresponds to moving to the 'failure' node in the control flow graph.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;After we've obtained the current character, we check to make sure that it matches the literal character that was specified in the regular expression using the 'matches_this_character' function. &nbsp;Here is the implementation of the matches_this_character function. &nbsp;As you can see, this function is very simple since it just checks to make sure that the current character in the string being searched is the same as the literal character that was supplied in the regex.</p>



<p><code><pre>current_character = safely_get_character(str, offset, pos, str_len);
<span>if</span>(matches_one_of_these_characters(current_character, NUM_CHARACTERS, CHARACTER_1, CHARACTER_2, CHARACTER_3, ..., CHARACTER_N)){
  pos++;
}<span>else</span>{
  exit(<span>1</span>);
}
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The implementation of the 'CLASS' node …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.robertelder.org/regular-expression-visualizer/">https://blog.robertelder.org/regular-expression-visualizer/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.robertelder.org/regular-expression-visualizer/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23975041</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 12:36:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[WasmBoxC: Simple, Fast, and VM-Less Sandboxing]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 216 | Comments 104 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23972929">thread link</a>) | @syrusakbary
<br/>
July 27, 2020 | https://kripken.github.io/blog/wasm/2020/07/27/wasmboxc.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://kripken.github.io/blog/wasm/2020/07/27/wasmboxc.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>The software ecosystem has a lot of useful but unsafe code, and the easier it is to sandbox that code, the more
often that’ll happen. If it were as simple as passing the compiler a <code>--sandbox</code> flag
that makes an unsafe library unable to see or affect anything
outside of it, that would be incredible! We can’t get it quite that easy,
but this post describes <strong>WasmBoxC</strong>, a sandboxing approach that is
very simple to use. All you need to do is:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Compile the unsafe library using a <a href="https://webassembly.org/">WebAssembly</a> (wasm) compiler instead of the normal system compiler</strong>.
That uses wasm internally, but you don’t need to care about that —
all you see is it emits a C file with sandboxed code.</li>
  <li><strong>Write some C to interface with the compiled C of the unsafe library</strong>. (This is
necessary because the sandboxed code can’t access outside memory, and also it
uses the portable wasm ABI.)</li>
</ul>

<p>Compile and link that C code, and now that unsafe library is sandboxed from the rest of your application!
In a later section we’ll see concrete examples of how easy both those steps are.</p>

<p>Here is the approach in more detail:</p>

<p><img src="https://kripken.github.io/blog/assets/wasmboxc.png" alt="unsafe code => safe wasm => safe c => safe native"></p>

<p>By <strong>compiling to wasm</strong> we sandbox the code, preventing it from accessing
anything on the outside.
That includes both <em>memory</em> - the sandboxed code can’t read or write to anywhere outside it -
and <em>capabilities</em> - the sandboxed code can’t do anything but pure computation,
unless you give it a function to call to do things like read from a file, tell
the time, etc.
We also get the rest of the wasm guarantees on
<a href="https://webassembly.org/docs/security/">safety</a> and
<a href="https://webassembly.org/docs/portability/">portability</a>. Wasm
sandboxing is even safe to run in the same process as other code (at least modulo
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spectre_(security_vulnerability)">Spectre-type</a>
vulnerabilities), much like
<a href="http://www.cse.psu.edu/~gxt29/papers/sfi-final.pdf">Software Fault Isolation (SFI)</a>.</p>

<p>After we’ve compiled an unsafe library to wasm, how can we run it as part of our
application?
We could integrate a wasm VM and run the wasm there. But instead,
with WasmBoxC we take a <strong>VM-less</strong> approach and compile the wasm into native
code, while preserving the wasm semantics, including the sandboxing.
That native code can be linked normally into an application, which
is much simpler than integrating a wasm VM.</p>

<p>The specific approach WasmBoxC takes to compile wasm into native code is to
<strong>compile it to C</strong> using
<a href="https://github.com/WebAssembly/wabt">wabt</a>’s
<a href="https://github.com/WebAssembly/wabt/tree/master/wasm2c">wasm2c</a> tool,
and then run a standard C compiler on it. In fact,
WasmBoxC’s approach compiles into a <strong>simple subset of C</strong>.
This is a big part of what makes this approach so simple, and
brings several advantages:</p>

<ul>
  <li>It’s easy to read and verify the generated C for security.</li>
  <li>It lets us use a C compiler like clang or gcc to make the sandboxed
code very fast.</li>
  <li>It’s very easy to use the code in existing build systems.</li>
  <li>It’s easy to write code to interact with the sandbox.</li>
  <li>A single build of C code can be compiled and run on practically any platform,
and code to interact with the sandbox also only needs to be written once.</li>
</ul>

<p>Despite the simplicity of using C, WasmBoxC sandboxing has low
overhead: just <strong>14%</strong> with some non-portable C code (the
“signal handler trick”, see later), or <strong>42%</strong> in 100% portable C
(with no OS- or CPU-specific operations at all). We’ll also see that there are options
in between those 14% and 42% numbers.</p>

<p>The basic idea in WasmBoxC is simple and
<a href="https://twitter.com/FlohOfWoe/status/1011523018428780544">not original</a>.
What is
new in this post is showing that the approach works, doing
benchmarking on real-world code to show it is fast, presenting complete examples of how
easy it is to sandbox real-world libraries, and writing up the approach in
detail to describe the benefits (see in particular the section on memory-safe
languages).
This post also invents a name for the technique.</p>

<h2 id="speed">Speed</h2>

<p>To get an idea of WasmBoxC’s speed, let’s take a look at
<a href="https://github.com/emscripten-core/emscripten/blob/master/tests/test_benchmark.py">20 benchmarks</a>,
comparing clang 9.0.1, clang 11 (dev version as of May 23 2020), gcc 9.2.1, and
WasmBoxC. All numbers are normalized to clang 9 (which is therefore equal to 1; lower numbers are better).</p>

<p><img src="https://kripken.github.io/blog/assets/wasmboxc-perf.png" alt="performance results"></p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>compiler</th>
      <th>relative speed</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>clang 9.0.1</td>
      <td>1.00</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>clang 11 (dev)</td>
      <td>0.97</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>gcc 9.2.1</td>
      <td>0.93</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>WasmBoxC (explicit)</td>
      <td>1.42</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>WasmBoxC (OS-based)</td>
      <td>1.14</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>These benchmarks include a wide variety of code, and the ones prefixed with <code>zzz_</code> are real-world
codebases or benchmarks:
the 
<a href="https://box2d.org/">Box2D</a> and
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bullet_(software)">Bullet</a>
physics engines, the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coremark">CoreMark</a> and
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LINPACK_benchmarks">LINPACK</a>
benchmarks, the
<a href="https://www.lua.org/">Lua</a> VM (one GC and one computational benchmark),
the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lempel%E2%80%93Ziv%E2%80%93Markov_chain_algorithm">LZMA</a>
and
<a href="https://zlib.net/">zlib</a>
compression libraries,
and the
<a href="https://www.sqlite.org/index.html">SQLite</a> database.
Incidentally, this shows WasmBoxC can run all of
these today!</p>

<p>Two results are shown for WasmBoxC, representing two implementations of memory sandboxing. The first is <strong>explicit</strong> sandboxing, in which each memory load and store is explicitly verified to be within the sandboxed memory using an explicit check (that is, an <code>if</code> statement is done before each memory access). This has <strong>42%</strong> overhead.</p>

<p>The <strong>OS-based</strong> implementation uses the
“<a href="https://github.com/WebAssembly/wabt/pull/1442/files#diff-e962256d2c336a13791ce03c1dae5d2fR106">signal handler trick</a>” that
<a href="https://hg.mozilla.org/mozilla-central/file/3334d8dff757051c7a359818e0ceb5ad7852fdbc/js/src/wasm/WasmSignalHandlers.cpp">wasm</a>
<a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/17y4kxuHFrVxAiuCP_FFtFA2HP5sNPsCD10KEx17Hz6M/edit#heading=h.tbi7hpbheoai">VMs</a>
use.
This technique reserves lots of memory around the valid range and relies on
CPU hardware to give us a signal if an access is out of bounds
(for more background see section 3.1.4 in
<a href="http://www.cse.psu.edu/~gxt29/papers/sfi-final.pdf">Tan, 2017</a>).
That is fully safe and has the benefit of avoiding explicit bounds checks. It has
just <strong>14%</strong> overhead! However, it cannot be used everywhere (it needs
signals and CPU memory protection, and only works on 64-bit systems).</p>

<p>There are more options in between those 14% and 42% figures.
Explicit and OS-based sandboxing preserve wasm semantics perfectly, that is, a trap
will happen exactly when a wasm VM would have trapped. If we are willing to relax
that
(but we may not want to <a href="https://github.com/WebAssembly/wabt/pull/1432">call it wasm</a> if we do)
then we can use masking sandboxing instead
(see section 3.1.3 in
<a href="http://www.cse.psu.edu/~gxt29/papers/sfi-final.pdf">Tan, 2017</a>),
which is 100% portable like explicit sandboxing and also prevents any accesses
outside of the sandbox, and is somewhat faster at <strong>29%</strong> overhead. Other sandboxing
improvements are possible too - almost no effort has gone into this yet.</p>

<p>An interesting thing happens in the <code>lua_binarytrees</code> and <code>havlak</code> benchmarks,
where WasmBoxC is actually faster than both gcc and clang in all sandboxing modes,
up to 32%! How can we beat normal native builds, and by so much?
<a href="https://twitter.com/kripken/status/1262092956070109185">Looking into this</a>,
both of these benchmarks use a lot of <code>malloc</code>s and data structures with pointers.
Like the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/X32_ABI">x32 ABI</a>, wasm is 32-bit,
so pointers take half the space. Measuring the maximum process memory used
in <code>lua_binarytrees</code>, WasmBoxC uses 33% less which helps a lot with CPU cache usage.
While this makes a big difference on these two benchmarks, we are likely
getting some speedup on the others as well due to this factor, as on average x32
is faster than normal x64
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/X32_ABI#Details">by around 5-8%</a>.
Wasm is a nice way to get something
like x32’s benefits!</p>

<p>The benchmarking here measures performance <em>within</em> the sandbox. It
does not measure the speed of calls from the outside in or inside out. Such
calls can be very fast because the sandboxed code is just C, which means that
we can even inline across the sandbox boundary — safely! — if we do
LTO. I verified that happens in the sandboxing example in the next section,
see later. (Note, however, then using the signal handler trick may make things
more complicated here.)</p>

<p>Some final notes on performance:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>We can compile WasmBoxC’s C code with any native compiler. In the
above we did so always with clang 9 for simplicity. The results vary a little
when changing the compiler, for example the “explicit” sandboxing results go from
14% up to 16% with gcc 9.2 or down to 11% with clang 11. There’s nothing magical about
that 14% figure — we are at the point where native compiler differences matter.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Results should improve over time as wasm adds more performance features
like <a href="https://github.com/WebAssembly/simd">simd</a> (note that the native compilers we
compared to may have gained an advantage from autovectorization).</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>That WasmBoxC can reach 14% overhead shows that the
cost of compiling through wasm (which cannot represent irreducible control
flow, for example) is fairly low, and also that current compilers to wasm are
not introducing significant unnecessary overhead.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>I’ve done my best to measure everything here carefully and accurately, but
it’s possible I’ve made a mistake somewhere. Please check my work and see if you
get similar results!</p>

<h2 id="ease-of-use">Ease of use</h2>

<p>This section has a full example of WasmBoxC usage. Here are the source files:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>// my-code.c</span>

<span>#include &lt;stdint.h&gt;
#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;
</span>
<span>// We could also include the .wasm.h file for these,</span>
<span>// but let's declare externs manually for the example.</span>

<span>extern</span> <span>void</span> <span>wasmbox_init</span><span>(</span><span>void</span><span>);</span>

<span>extern</span> <span>uint32_t</span> <span>(</span><span>*</span><span>Z_twiceZ_ii</span><span>)(</span><span>uint32_t</span><span>);</span>

<span>extern</span> <span>uint32_t</span> <span>(</span><span>*</span><span>Z_do_bad_thingZ_ii</span><span>)(</span><span>uint32_t</span><span>);</span>

<span>int</span> <span>main</span><span>()</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>puts</span><span>(</span><span>"Initializing sandboxed unsafe library"</span><span>);</span>
  <span>wasmbox_init</span><span>();</span>
  <span>printf</span><span>(</span><span>"Calling twice on 21 returns %d</span><span>\n</span><span>"</span><span>,</span> <span>Z_twiceZ_ii</span><span>(</span><span>21</span><span>));</span>
  <span>puts</span><span>(</span><span>"Calling something bad now..."</span><span>);</span>
  <span>Z_do_bad_thingZ_ii</span><span>(</span><span>1</span><span>);</span>
  <span>puts</span><span>(</span><span>"(this will never be printed, as the bad thing will trap)"</span><span>);</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p><code>main()</code> is pretty simple: Initialize, call something in the sandbox that does a
computation for us, and call something that will trap inside the sandbox.
(What’s with the <code>Z_</code> stuff? See later in “API”.)</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>// unsafe-lib.c</span>

<span>#include &lt;stdlib.h&gt;
</span>
<span>__attribute__</span><span>((</span><span>used</span><span>))</span>
<span>int</span> <span>twice</span><span>(</span><span>int</span> <span>x</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>return</span> <span>x</span> <span>+</span> <span>x</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>__attribute__</span><span>((</span><span>used</span><span>))</span>
<span>int</span> <span>do_bad_thing</span><span>(</span><span>int</span> <span>size</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>// Allocate an unknown size here (so the LLVM optimizer doesn't know if the</span>
  <span>// store later down is valid or not).</span>
  <span>char</span><span>*</span> <span>x</span> <span>=</span> <span>malloc</span><span>(</span><span>size</span><span>);</span>
  <span>// Write to an address that is definitely not in the sandbox (the default</span>
  <span>// memory size is much smaller), which in wasm will trap.</span>
  <span>x</span><span>[</span><span>1024</span> <span>*</span> <span>1024</span> <span>*</span> <span>1024</span><span>]</span> <span>=</span> <span>42</span><span>;</span>
  <span>// Avoid the optimizer knowing the store can never be observed.</span>
  <span>return</span> <span>(</span><span>int</span><span>)</span><span>x</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p><code>twice()</code> does what you’d expect, and <code>do_bad_thing</code> does a store that will
definitely trap. (Ignore the details there; for this example we need the LLVM optimizer not to
remove the bad code as undefined behavior!)</p>

<p>And here’s how easy it is to use WasmBoxC to get a fully sandboxed library linked with our normal code:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span># build our main code to an object normally</span>
<span>$ </span>clang my-code.c         <span>-c</span> <span>-O3</span> <span>-o</span> my-code.o
<span># build the unsafe library to C with emcc</span>
<span>$ </span>emcc unsafe-lib.c          <span>-O3</span> <span>-o</span> unsafe-lib.wasm <span>-s</span> WASM2C <span>--no-entry</span>
<span># build the unsafe …</span></code></pre></div></div></div></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://kripken.github.io/blog/wasm/2020/07/27/wasmboxc.html">https://kripken.github.io/blog/wasm/2020/07/27/wasmboxc.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://kripken.github.io/blog/wasm/2020/07/27/wasmboxc.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23972929</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 06:34:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Fewer premature babies born since Covid-19 lockdown]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 202 | Comments 172 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23972152">thread link</a>) | @breitling
<br/>
July 27, 2020 | https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/calgary/fewer-premature-preterm-babies-born-during-pandemic-calgary-around-the-world-1.5665089 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/calgary/fewer-premature-preterm-babies-born-during-pandemic-calgary-around-the-world-1.5665089">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Doctors in countries&nbsp;including Denmark, Ireland, Australia, the U.S. and Canada&nbsp;have been reporting that fewer preterm babies are being born.</p><div><p><span><span><span></span><span>Dr. Belal Alshaikh says COVID-19 has brought a curious development to some maternity wards, and he is trying to help researchers from around the world find out why.<!-- --> <!-- -->4:35</span></span></span></p><p><span><p>Count this one as a positive side-effect of the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>  <p>Doctors in countries&nbsp;including Denmark, Ireland, Australia, the U.S. and Canada&nbsp;have been reporting that fewer preterm babies are being born.</p>  <p>While&nbsp;peer-reviewed studies investigating the drop&nbsp;are pending, and the downward&nbsp;trend across countries is currently anecdotal,&nbsp;Neonatologist Dr. Belal Alshaikh has been studying the possible&nbsp;phenomenon&nbsp;in Calgary.</p>  <p>"It's actually not that common to see this drop down in the numbers in many countries," said Alshaikh, who is&nbsp;also the medical director of the neonatal intensive care unit at the South Health Campus,&nbsp;and&nbsp;has seen the trend right here in Calgary.</p>  <p>Alshaikh told<em> <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/listen/live-radio/1-97-the-homestretch">The Homestretch</a></em> there are two ways to measure preterm birth — gestational age and actual birth weight. And by both measures, the numbers are dramatically lower.</p>  <p>Births considered very premature —&nbsp;born at fewer than 29 to 32 weeks&nbsp;— have&nbsp;dropped by&nbsp;34&nbsp;to 40 per cent, he said.</p>  <p>"If we use their gestational age and if we are talking about the very earliest preemies,"&nbsp;Alshaikh&nbsp;said.</p>  <p>"That's kind of dramatic, actually, and surprising for us."</p>  <p>The numbers are even more dramatic for babies under one kilogram.</p>  <p>"If we used birth weight, those babies born less than one kilo, the number was actually very low and half of what we used to see in the last few years, during the same period of time of the year."</p>    <p>Alshaikh said the trend is very unusual.</p>  <p>"Soon after the lockdown in mid-March, we started to see fewer babies coming to our unit and to intensive care units, and these numbers of preemies were also low in April and mid-May," Alshaikh said.&nbsp;</p>  <p>"So by that time, by late May, we felt like we needed to look at the numbers, and see where we are. And also at that time we started hearing that other hospitals, in Ireland and Denmark, have also noticed the drop down in the number of preemies."</p>  <p>When Calgary doctors took a good look at the numbers and compared them to the same time last year, it was an eyeopener.</p>  <p>"We were surprised," Alshaikh said. "We saw that our number is way lower than what we used to see during this period of time."</p>  <p>There are three main causes that doctors are looking at.</p>  <p>One is social distancing, which may have cut down on the amount of general infection from contact with others.</p>  <p>Another is less air pollution, from fewer cars being on the roads.</p>  <p>"This might actually help because studies in the past showed that air pollution actually increases the risk for preterm birth," Alshaikh said.</p>  <p>And simply not going out to work — resting — may be a final key.</p>  <p>"By staying home, a pregnant woman may have less stress from commuting and from work,&nbsp; and that might have helped them," Alshaikh said, adding it's too soon to know for sure which of these lockdown-related factors have contributed the most.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.3068968.1431344120!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/premature-babies.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.3068968.1431344120!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/premature-babies.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.3068968.1431344120!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/premature-babies.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.3068968.1431344120!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/premature-babies.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.3068968.1431344120!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/premature-babies.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.3068968.1431344120!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/premature-babies.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Calgary doctors who noticed a reduced number of premature births during the pandemic lockdown, are seeing those numbers rise again as restrictions have eased.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Jim Lynch, Flickr cc)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>&nbsp;"We see sometimes variation during the year, but it's not to the degree that we see fewer babies," Alshaikh said. "And the fact that we see the same trend in Ireland, in Denmark in Australia, it's kind of surprising for everyone working in this field."</p>  <p>Preterm birth comes with a host of challenges for the babies and their parents.</p>  <p>"The risk is high on children and their families, and also medical care resources," Alshaikh said. "For children, the risk increases for vision and hearing problems, and also for learning disability. It's higher even as the gestational age goes down. For example,&nbsp; 24 weeks is at very high risk compared to babies born at 28 weeks gestation or at 32 weeks gestation."</p>  <h2>Doctors teaming up to study</h2>  <p>The Calgary doctors will continue to study the phenomenon, which could hold clues to reducing preterm births in general.</p>  <p>For now, Alshaikh said it's too early to provide any specific advice to pregnant woman — other than to avoid stress, try to rest at home, get a lot of sleep&nbsp;and focus on good nutrition.&nbsp;</p>  <p>"We've teamed up, actually, with the teams across the world, in Ireland and also in Denmark, and there is also a group in Manitoba working on this project, and we are hoping to understand more the ways to prevent the preterm birth, and also like to see if we can understand more on risk factors that are affecting preterm birth," Alshaikh said.&nbsp;</p>  <p>But the Calgary doctor said there is one alarming development already —&nbsp;as the lockdown restriction ease, those preterm birth numbers are already on the rise again.</p>  <p>"We are actually noticing, even in Calgary, that when the restrictions started to be eased, the number of preterm babies coming to our unit and intensive care is going up again, which is quite actually interesting for us," Alshaikh said. "And we are trying to tease out what factors are affecting this trend."</p>  <p><strong>With files from <em><a href="https://www.cbc.ca/listen/live-radio/1-97-the-homestretch">The Homestretch</a></em>.</strong></p></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/calgary/fewer-premature-preterm-babies-born-during-pandemic-calgary-around-the-world-1.5665089</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23972152</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 04:00:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Double-Entry Counting Method (2016)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 119 | Comments 28 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23971567">thread link</a>) | @dragonsh
<br/>
July 27, 2020 | https://beancount.github.io/docs/the_double_entry_counting_method.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://beancount.github.io/docs/the_double_entry_counting_method.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
<div>

<p>Martin Blais, December 2016</p>
<p><a href="http://furius.ca/beancount/doc/double-entry"><span>http://furius.ca/beancount/doc/double-entry</span></a></p>
<p><a href="#introduction"><span>Introduction</span></a></p>
<p><a href="#basics-of-double-entry-bookkeeping"><span>Basics of Double-Entry Bookkeeping</span></a></p>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="#statements"><span>Statements</span></a></p>
<p><a href="#single-entry-bookkeeping"><span>Single-Entry Bookkeeping</span></a></p>
<p><a href="#double-entry-bookkeeping"><span>Double-Entry Bookkeeping</span></a></p>
<p><a href="#many-accounts"><span>Many Accounts</span></a></p>
<p><a href="#multiple-postings"><span>Multiple Postings</span></a></p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="#types-of-accounts"><span>Types of Accounts</span></a></p>
<p><a href="#trial-balance"><span>Trial Balance</span></a></p>
<p><a href="#income-statement"><span>Income Statement</span></a></p>
<p><a href="#clearing-income"><span>Clearing Income</span></a></p>
<p><a href="#equity"><span>Equity</span></a></p>
<p><a href="#balance-sheet"><span>Balance Sheet</span></a></p>
<p><a href="#summarizing"><span>Summarizing</span></a></p>
<p><a href="#period-reporting"><span>Period Reporting</span></a></p>
<p><a href="#chart-of-accounts"><span>Chart of Accounts</span></a></p>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="#country-institution-convention"><span>Country-Institution Convention</span></a></p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="#credits-debits"><span>Credits &amp; Debits</span></a></p>
<p><a href="#accounting-equations"><span>Accounting Equations</span></a></p>
<p><a href="#plain-text-accounting"><span>Plain-Text Accounting</span></a></p>
<p><a href="#the-table-perspective"><span>The Table Perspective</span></a></p>
<h2 id="introduction">Introduction<a id="introduction"></a><a href="#introduction" title="Permanent link"></a></h2>
<p>This document is a gentle introduction to the double-entry counting method, as written from the perspective of a computer scientist. It is an attempt to explain basic bookkeeping using as simple an approach as possible, doing away with some of the idiosyncrasies normally involved in accounting. It is also representative of how <a href="http://furius.ca/beancount/"><span>Beancount</span></a> works, and it should be useful to all users of <a href="http://plaintextaccounting.org/"><span>plain-text accounting</span></a>.</p>
<p>Note that I am not an accountant, and in the process of writing this document I may have used terminology that is slightly different or unusual to that which is taught in perhaps more traditional training in accounting. I granted myself license to create something new and perhaps even unusual in order to explain those ideas as simply and clearly as possible to someone unfamiliar with them.</p>
<p>I believe that the method of double-entry counting should be taught to everyone at the high school level everywhere as it is a tremendously useful organizational skill, and I hope that this text can help spread its knowledge beyond professional circles.</p>
<h2 id="basics-of-double-entry-bookkeeping">Basics of Double-Entry Bookkeeping<a id="basics-of-double-entry-bookkeeping"></a><a href="#basics-of-double-entry-bookkeeping" title="Permanent link"></a></h2>
<p>The double-entry system is just a simple <em>method of counting</em>, with some simple rules.</p>
<p>Let’s begin by defining the notion of an <strong>account</strong>. An account is something that can contain things, like a bag. It is used to count things, to accumulate things. Let’s draw a horizontal arrow to visually represent the evolving contents of an account over time:</p>
<p><img src="https://beancount.github.io/docs/the_double_entry_counting_method/media/5b1da6643866c557b2a5ce687e70ee1db16b14de.png"></p>
<p>On the left, we have the past, and to the right, increasing time: the present, the future, etc.</p>
<p>For now, let’s assume that accounts can contain only one kind of thing, for example, <em>dollars</em>. All accounts begin with an empty content of zero dollars. We will call the number of units in the account the <strong>balance</strong> of an account. Note that it represents its contents at a particular point in time. I will draw the balance using a number above the account’s timeline:</p>
<p><img src="https://beancount.github.io/docs/the_double_entry_counting_method/media/842dcb36da9e0e70c35d1023d65d8a571062baf0.png"></p>
<p>The contents of accounts can change over time. In order to change the content of an account, we have to add something to it. We will call this addition a <strong>posting</strong> to an account, and I will draw this change as a circled number on the account’s timeline, for example, adding $100 to the account:</p>
<p><img src="https://beancount.github.io/docs/the_double_entry_counting_method/media/5e5e7897a346355eccd4d21ec9485c3464a2d996.png"></p>
<p>Now, we can draw the updated balance of the account after the posting with another little number right after it:</p>
<p><img src="https://beancount.github.io/docs/the_double_entry_counting_method/media/0c8a78dac61ae7fddde25761f036e7f379cad247.png"></p>
<p>The account’s balance, after adding $100, is now $100.</p>
<p>We can also remove from the contents of an account. For example, we could remove $25, and the resulting account balance is now $75:</p>
<p><img src="https://beancount.github.io/docs/the_double_entry_counting_method/media/98e314125325ecc72262a73a21b74db3200414fd.png"></p>
<p>Account balances can also become <em>negative</em>, if we remove more dollars than there are in the account. For example, if we remove $200 from this account, the balance now becomes $-125:</p>
<p><img src="https://beancount.github.io/docs/the_double_entry_counting_method/media/bdc8a23347040de123e3359a7c8f0cc253c6d7d2.png"></p>
<p>It’s perfectly fine for accounts to contain a negative balance number. Remember that all we’re doing is counting things. As we will see shortly, some accounts will remain with a negative balance for most of their timeline.</p>
<h3 id="statements">Statements<a id="statements"></a><a href="#statements" title="Permanent link"></a></h3>
<p>Something worthy of notice is how the timeline notation I’ve written in the previous section is analogous to paper account statements institutions maintain for each client and which you typically receive through the mail:</p>
<table><thead><tr><th><em><strong>Date</strong></em></th><th><em><strong>Description</strong></em></th><th><em><strong>Amount</strong></em></th><th><em><strong>Balance</strong></em></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>2016-10-02</td><td>...</td><td>100.00</td><td>1100.00</td></tr><tr><td>2016-10-05</td><td>...</td><td>-25.00</td><td>1075.00</td></tr><tr><td>2016-10-06</td><td>...</td><td>-200.00</td><td>875.00</td></tr><tr><td><em><strong>Final Balance</strong></em></td><td>875.00</td><td></td><td></td></tr></tbody></table>
<p>Sometimes the amount column is split into two, one showing the positive amounts and the other the negative ones:</p>
<table><thead><tr><th><em><strong>Date</strong></em></th><th><em><strong>Description</strong></em></th><th><em><strong>Debit</strong></em></th><th><em><strong>Credit</strong></em></th><th><em><strong>Balance</strong></em></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>2016-10-02</td><td>...</td><td></td><td>100.00</td><td>1100.00</td></tr><tr><td>2016-10-05</td><td>...</td><td>25.00</td><td></td><td>1075.00</td></tr><tr><td>2016-10-06</td><td>...</td><td>200.00</td><td></td><td>875.00</td></tr><tr><td><em><strong>Final Balance</strong></em></td><td>875.00</td><td></td><td></td><td></td></tr></tbody></table>
<p>Here, “debit” means “removed from your account” and “credit” means “deposited in your account.” Sometimes the words “withdrawals” and “deposits” will be used. It all depends on context: for checking and savings accounts it is usual to have both types of postings, but for a credit card account typically it shows only positive numbers and then the occasional monthly payment so the single column format is used.</p>
<p>In any case, the “balance” column always shows the resulting balance <em>after</em> the amount has been posted to the account. And sometimes the statements are rendered in decreasing order of time.</p>
<h3 id="single-entry-bookkeeping">Single-Entry Bookkeeping<a id="single-entry-bookkeeping"></a><a href="#single-entry-bookkeeping" title="Permanent link"></a></h3>
<p>In this story, this account belongs to someone. We’ll call this person the <strong>owner</strong> of the account. The account can be used to represent a real world account, for example, imagine that we use it to represent the content of the owner’s checking account at a bank. So we’re going to label the account by giving it a name, in this case “Checking”:</p>
<p><img src="https://beancount.github.io/docs/the_double_entry_counting_method/media/380ec8fea9ee9069411a61ccabcc838de44042ef.png"></p>
<p>Imagine that at some point, this account has a balance of $1000, like I’ve drawn on the picture. Now, if the owner spends $79 of this account, we would represent it like this:</p>
<p><img src="https://beancount.github.io/docs/the_double_entry_counting_method/media/b24d8c1e40edf6fd7e9d768ba8f0df279cd41f0e.png"></p>
<p>Furthermore, if the expense was for a meal at a restaurant, we could flag the posting with a <strong>category</strong> to indicate what the change was used for. Let’s say, “Restaurant”, like this:</p>
<p><img src="https://beancount.github.io/docs/the_double_entry_counting_method/media/7ee843cd9b997a9447bb022d7d35121a820e296d.png"></p>
<p>Now, if we have a lot of these, we could write a computer program to accumulate all the changes for each category and calculate the sums for each of them. That would tell us how much we spent in restaurants in total, for example. This is called the <strong>single-entry method</strong> of accounting.</p>
<p>But we’re not going to do it this way; we have a better way. Bear with me for a few more sections.</p>
<h3 id="double-entry-bookkeeping">Double-Entry Bookkeeping<a id="double-entry-bookkeeping"></a><a href="#double-entry-bookkeeping" title="Permanent link"></a></h3>
<p>An owner may have multiple accounts. I will represent this by drawing many similar account timelines on the same graphic. As before, these are labeled with unique names. Let’s assume that the owner has the same “Checking” account as previously, but now also a <strong>“</strong>Restaurant<strong>”</strong> account as well, which can be used to accumulate all food expenses at restaurants. It looks like this:</p>
<p><img src="https://beancount.github.io/docs/the_double_entry_counting_method/media/3c380375442a643877c59660832bd7df6192e9cb.png"></p>
<p>Now, instead of <em>categorizing</em> the posting to a “restaurant category” as we did previously, we could create a matching posting on the “Restaurant” account to record how much we spent for food, with the amount spent ($79):</p>
<p><img src="https://beancount.github.io/docs/the_double_entry_counting_method/media/b86a7242b92effc613f88bc0cc70381d72e774f0.png"></p>
<p>The “Restaurant” account, like all other accounts, also has an accumulated balance, so we can find out how much we spent in “Restaurant” in total. This is entirely symmetrical to counting changes in a checking account.</p>
<p>Now, we can associate the two postings together, by creating a kind of “parent” box that refers to both of them. We will call this object a <strong>transaction</strong>:</p>
<p><img src="https://beancount.github.io/docs/the_double_entry_counting_method/media/b77efafcf2d6a6f1afbfb13da70be2f892b339b4.png"></p>
<p>Notice here that we’ve also associated a description to this transaction: “Dinner at Uncle Boons”. A transaction also has a <strong>date</strong>, and all of its postings are recorded to occur on that date. We call this the transaction date.</p>
<p>We can now introduce the fundamental rule of double-entry bookkeeping system:</p>
<pre><code>The sum of all the postings of a transaction must equal zero.
</code></pre>
<p>Remember this, as this is the foundation of the double-entry method, and its most important characteristic. It has important consequences which I will discuss later in this document.</p>
<p>In our example, we remove $79 from the “Checking” account and “give it” to the “Restaurant” account. ($79) + ($-79) = $0. To emphasize this, I could draw a little summation line under the postings of the transaction, like this:</p>
<p><img src="https://beancount.github.io/docs/the_double_entry_counting_method/media/b4182b9f64113868123cbcec20d468ab18b2786f.png"></p>
<h3 id="many-accounts">Many Accounts<a id="many-accounts"></a><a href="#many-accounts" title="Permanent link"></a></h3>
<p>There may be many such transactions, over many different accounts. For example, if the owner of the accounts had a lunch the next day which she paid using a credit card, it could be represented by creating a “Credit Card” account dedicated to tracking the real world credit card balance, and with a corresponding transaction:</p>
<p><img src="https://beancount.github.io/docs/the_double_entry_counting_method/media/f85a66510ce2e3bb614edca76463a9c4752a7d26.png"></p>
<p>In this example, the owner spent $35 at a restaurant called “Eataly.” The previous balance of the owner’s credit card was $-450; after the expense, the new balance is $-485.</p>
<p>For each real world account, the owner can create a bookkeeping account like we did. Also, for each category of expenditure, the owner also creates a bookkeeping account. In this system, there are no limits to how many accounts can be created.</p>
<p>Note that the balance in the example is a negative number; this is not an error. Balances for credit card accounts are normally negative: they represent an amount <em>you owe</em>, that the bank is lending you <em>on credit</em>. When your credit card company keeps track of your expenses, they write out your statement from their perspective, as positive numbers. For you, those are amounts you need to eventually pay. But here, in our accounting system, we’re representing numbers from the owner’s point-of-view, and from her perspective, this is money she owes, not something she has. What we have is a meal sitting in our stomach (a positive number of $ of “Restaurant”).</p>
<h3 id="multiple-postings">Multiple Postings<a id="multiple-postings"></a><a href="#multiple-postings" title="Permanent link"></a></h3>
<p>Finally, transactions may have more than two postings; in fact, they may have any number of postings. The only thing that matters is that the sum of their amounts is zero (from the rule of double-entry bookkeeping above).</p>
<p>For example, let’s look at what would happen if the owner gets her salary paid for December:</p>
<p><img src="https://beancount.github.io/docs/the_double_entry_counting_method/media/18980f41275676c5c7cf3b39dd256512bb45b78b.png"></p>
<p>Her gross salary received in this example is recorded as $-2,905 (I’ll explain the sign in a moment). $905 is set aside for taxes. Her “net” salary of $2,000, the remainder, is deposited in her “Checking” account and the resulting balance of that account is $2,921 (the previous balance of $921 + $2,000 = $2,921). This transaction has three postings: (+2,000) + (-2,905) + (+905) = 0. The double-entry rule is respected.</p>
<p>Now, you may ask: Why is her salary recorded as a negative number? The reasoning here is similar to that of the credit card above, though perhaps a bit more subtle. These accounts exist to track all the amounts from the owner’s point-of-view. The owner gives out work, and receives money and taxes in exchange for it …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://beancount.github.io/docs/the_double_entry_counting_method.html">https://beancount.github.io/docs/the_double_entry_counting_method.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://beancount.github.io/docs/the_double_entry_counting_method.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23971567</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 01:59:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Alignment]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 27 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23971455">thread link</a>) | @gazzini
<br/>
July 27, 2020 | https://gazzini.com/essays/posts/alignment/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://gazzini.com/essays/posts/alignment/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <h2 id="internally">Internally</h2>
<p>I’ve managed a few small teams, and the worst situations always happen when I avoid conflict early.</p>
<p>Hypothetically, if Sam does 3 problematic things, I might only address 2 of them. Maybe I don’t want Sam to think I’m mean, or maybe I need Sam to stay encouraged. Regardless of my intent, it becomes increasingly difficult for me to address that 3rd behavior, and increasingly burdensome to spin my wheels serving as an unnecessary intermediary in Sam’s interactions, trying to create a buffer between that 3rd behavior and the rest of the office. This is obviously stupid and unsustainable, and becomes more awkward to correct over time.</p>
<p>This often creeps up in more subtle ways. A developer might provide a lot of critical feedback on every new round of designs. I want the designer to feel empowered and trusted, but I also want the developer to care about the overall product. It’s perfectly possible to strike a good balance &amp; accurately communicate with everybody… However, it’s human-instinct to optimize each message for the receiver, and to sliiiightly oversell the degree to which I agree with the developer’s criticisms, or to soften those same criticisms when speaking with the designer. These little tweaks, which feel like hard work &amp; good management in the short-term, can really snowball over time.</p>

  <p><img src="https://gazzini.com/essays/posts/alignment/expectations.jpg" alt="A graph with time on the X axis and reckoning on the Y axis. It demonstrates that for any initial degree of misunderstanding, the expectations deviate further from reality until it is corrected."></p><p>To minimize the magnitude of reckoning:</p>
<ul>
<li>A good manager will force the reckoning sooner</li>
<li>A great manager will avoid the misalignment in the first place</li>
<li>An excellent manager will avoid this misalignment without making anyone feel bad</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="externally">Externally</h2>
<p>Unfortunately, many people believe that the role of a great recruiter (or salesperson, marketer, director, or anybody) is to actually increase the degree of misalignment in the above graph… In other words, that they should oversell. In a large enough company, someone else downstream will have to deal with the reckoning:</p>

  <p><img src="https://gazzini.com/essays/posts/alignment/before.jpg" alt="A graph where most recruiters tell the truth, but 1 evil recruiter lies and is rewarded for it."></p><p>If this incentive system goes unchecked, it quickly devolves into a situation where everybody knows that everybody oversells, and so the common wisdom is to mentally discount any promise made by a salesperson, recruiter, marketer, engineer, or really anybody:</p>

  <p><img src="https://gazzini.com/essays/posts/alignment/after.jpg" alt="A graph where most recruiters lie, but the candidates all adjust their expectations accordingly. This causes the truthful recruiters to suffer, because their truth is also discounted."></p><p>I’ve noticed that a lot of mentorship involves helping newcomers recognize the overselling for themselves &amp; learn to navigate these worlds of semi-truths &amp; complex incentives. I’ve also noticed that this flavor of BS is always bad for the overall system / company / marketplace / world.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Externally, this pattern is unavoidable. Free markets will always be susceptible to some assumed misalignment, although regulations can help.</p>
<p>Within a company, however, this behavior is toxic. Whenever I see a team sugar-coating metrics, I know that it won’t be fun to work in implementation at that company. When the rubber meets the road, the fingers will start pointing.</p>
<h2 id="misc">Misc</h2>
<p>Here are some other things that I did to make myself miserable as a new manager:</p>
<ul>
<li>Lacking the confidence to make hard decisions, and offloading them to someone more confident but less informed</li>
<li>Waiting waaaay too long to fire people</li>
<li>Reading a lot of books on management, and expecting <em>my</em> manager to immediately live the ideals of those specific books</li>
<li>Trying to manage former peers without intentionally, drastically resetting the relationship</li>
</ul>
<p>I can avoid most of these by constantly asking myself what issues I’m avoiding today, and pursuing the ones that might turn into big issues later.</p>

  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://gazzini.com/essays/posts/alignment/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23971455</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 01:44:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Would You Survive the Titanic?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 25 | Comments 19 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23971143">thread link</a>) | @aliabd
<br/>
July 27, 2020 | https://www.gradio.app/hub/hub-titanic | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.gradio.app/hub/hub-titanic">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.gradio.app/hub/hub-titanic</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23971143</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:54:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A collection of free Physics books from Springer]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 29 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23971096">thread link</a>) | @dricornelius
<br/>
July 27, 2020 | https://hnarayanan.github.io/springer-books/#Physics%20and%20Astronomy | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://hnarayanan.github.io/springer-books/#Physics%20and%20Astronomy">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

      

      

      <h2 id="Categories">Categories</h2>

      <ul>
        
        <li><a href="#Behavioral Science">Behavioral Science</a></li>
        
        <li><a href="#Behavioral Science and Psychology">Behavioral Science and Psychology</a></li>
        
        <li><a href="#Biomedical and Life Sciences">Biomedical and Life Sciences</a></li>
        
        <li><a href="#Business and Economics">Business and Economics</a></li>
        
        <li><a href="#Business and Management">Business and Management</a></li>
        
        <li><a href="#Chemistry and Materials Science">Chemistry and Materials Science</a></li>
        
        <li><a href="#Computer Science">Computer Science</a></li>
        
        <li><a href="#Earth and Environmental Science">Earth and Environmental Science</a></li>
        
        <li><a href="#Economics and Finance">Economics and Finance</a></li>
        
        <li><a href="#Education">Education</a></li>
        
        <li><a href="#Energy">Energy</a></li>
        
        <li><a href="#Engineering">Engineering</a></li>
        
        <li><a href="#Humanities, Social Sciences and Law">Humanities, Social Sciences and Law</a></li>
        
        <li><a href="#Intelligent Technologies and Robotics">Intelligent Technologies and Robotics</a></li>
        
        <li><a href="#Law and Criminology">Law and Criminology</a></li>
        
        <li><a href="#Literature, Cultural and Media Studies">Literature, Cultural and Media Studies</a></li>
        
        <li><a href="#Mathematics and Statistics">Mathematics and Statistics</a></li>
        
        <li><a href="#Medicine">Medicine</a></li>
        
        <li><a href="#Physics and Astronomy">Physics and Astronomy</a></li>
        
        <li><a href="#Religion and Philosophy">Religion and Philosophy</a></li>
        
        <li><a href="#Social Sciences">Social Sciences</a></li>
        
      </ul>

      
      <h2 id="Behavioral Science">Behavioral Science</h2>

      <div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Social Anxiety and Social Phobia in Youth</h5>
              <h6>Christopher Kearney<br><small>2005</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-0-387-22592-0">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
            
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Acquired Brain Injury</h5>
              <h6>Jean Elbaum, Deborah Benson<br><small>2007</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-0-387-37575-5">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Psychology, Religion, and Spirituality</h5>
              <h6>James M. Nelson<br><small>2009</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-0-387-87573-6">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
            
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Child Neuropsychology</h5>
              <h6>Margaret Semrud-Clikeman, Phyllis Anne Teeter Ellison<br><small>2nd ed. 2009</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-0-387-88963-4">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
            
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Clinical Assessment of Child and Adolescent Personality and Behavior</h5>
              <h6>Paul J. Frick, Christopher T. Barry, Randy W. Kamphaus<br><small>3rd ed. 2010</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-1-4419-0641-0">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
            
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>A Clinical Guide to the Treatment of the Human Stress Response</h5>
              <h6>George S. Everly, Jr., Jeffrey M. Lating<br><small>3rd ed. 2013</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-1-4614-5538-7">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
            
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>The Psychology of Social Status</h5>
              <h6>Joey T. Cheng, Jessica L. Tracy, Cameron Anderson<br><small>2014</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-1-4939-0867-7">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
            
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Psychoeducational Assessment and Report Writing</h5>
              <h6>Stefan C. Dombrowski<br><small>2015</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-1-4939-1911-6">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
            
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Evidence-Based Interventions for Children with Challenging Behavior</h5>
              <h6>Kathleen Hague Armstrong, Julia A. Ogg, Ashley N. Sundman-Wheat, Audra St. John Walsh<br><small>2014</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-1-4614-7807-2">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>MATLAB for Psychologists</h5>
              <h6>Mauro Borgo, Alessandro Soranzo, Massimo Grassi<br><small>2012</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-1-4614-2197-9">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
            
            
          </div>
        </div>
        

        
      </div>
      
      <h2 id="Behavioral Science and Psychology">Behavioral Science and Psychology</h2>

      <div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>International Perspectives on Psychotherapy</h5>
              <h6>Stefan G. Hofmann<br><small>1st ed. 2017</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-3-319-56194-3">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Applied Behavior Analysis</h5>
              <h6>Kimberly Maich, Darren Levine, Carmen Hall<br><small>1st ed. 2016</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-3-319-44794-0">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Psychology of Perception</h5>
              <h6>Simon Grondin<br><small>1st ed. 2016</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-3-319-31791-5">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
            
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Handbook of Consumer Finance Research</h5>
              <h6>Jing Jian Xiao<br><small>2nd ed. 2016</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-3-319-28887-1">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Clinical Methods in Medical Family Therapy</h5>
              <h6>Tai Mendenhall, Angela Lamson, Jennifer Hodgson, Macaran Baird<br><small>1st ed. 2018</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-3-319-68834-3">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Motivation and Action </h5>
              <h6>Jutta Heckhausen, Heinz Heckhausen<br><small>3rd ed. 2018</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-3-319-65094-4">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
            
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Perceptual Organization</h5>
              <h6>Stephen Handel<br><small>1st ed. 2019</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-3-319-96337-2">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Foundations of Behavioral Health</h5>
              <h6>Bruce Lubotsky Levin, Ardis Hanson<br><small>1st ed. 2020</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-3-030-18435-3">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Social Psychology in Action</h5>
              <h6>Kai Sassenberg, Michael L.W. Vliek<br><small>1st ed. 2019</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-3-030-13788-5">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
          </div>
        </div>
        

        
      </div>
      
      <h2 id="Biomedical and Life Sciences">Biomedical and Life Sciences</h2>

      <div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Developmental Neurobiology</h5>
              <h6>Mahendra S. Rao, Marcus Jacobson<br><small>4th ed. 2005</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-0-387-28117-9">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
            
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Fundamentals of Biomechanics</h5>
              <h6>Duane Knudson<br><small>2nd ed. 2007</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-0-387-49312-1">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
            
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Plant Physiological Ecology</h5>
              <h6>Hans Lambers, F Stuart Chapin III, Thijs L. Pons<br><small>2nd ed. 2008</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-0-387-78341-3">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
            
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>The Joy of Science</h5>
              <h6>Richard A. Lockshin<br><small>2007</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-1-4020-6099-1">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
            
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Metabolism of Human Diseases</h5>
              <h6>Eckhard Lammert, Martin Zeeb<br><small>2014</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-3-7091-0715-7">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Integrative Human Biochemistry</h5>
              <h6>Andrea T. da Poian, Miguel A. R. B. Castanho<br><small>1st ed. 2015</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-1-4939-3058-6">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Fundamentals of Biomechanics</h5>
              <h6>Nihat Özkaya, Dawn Leger, David Goldsheyder, Margareta Nordin<br><small>4th ed. 2017</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-3-319-44738-4">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
            
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Human Chromosomes</h5>
              <h6>Orlando J. Miller, Eeva Therman<br><small>4th ed. 2001</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-1-4613-0139-4">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
            
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Phylogenomics</h5>
              <h6>Christoph Bleidorn<br><small>1st ed. 2017</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-3-319-54064-1">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
            
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Principles of Terrestrial Ecosystem Ecology</h5>
              <h6>F Stuart Chapin III, Pamela A. Matson, Peter Vitousek<br><small>2nd ed. 2012</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-1-4419-9504-9">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
            
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Learning Landscape Ecology</h5>
              <h6>Sarah E. Gergel, Monica G. Turner<br><small>2nd ed. 2017</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-1-4939-6374-4">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
            
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Epidemiological Research: Terms and Concepts</h5>
              <h6>O. S. Miettinen<br><small>2011</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-94-007-1171-6">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
            
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Statistical Analysis of Clinical Data on a Pocket Calculator</h5>
              <h6>Ton J. Cleophas, Aeilko H. Zwinderman<br><small>2011</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-94-007-1211-9">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Clinical Data Analysis on a Pocket Calculator</h5>
              <h6>Ton J. Cleophas, Aeilko H. Zwinderman<br><small>2nd ed. 2016</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-3-319-27104-0">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Essentials of Cerebellum and Cerebellar Disorders</h5>
              <h6>Donna L. Gruol, Noriyuki Koibuchi, Mario Manto, Marco Molinari, Jeremy D. Schmahmann, Ying Shen<br><small>1st ed. 2016</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-3-319-24551-5">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Handbook of Cardiac Anatomy, Physiology, and Devices</h5>
              <h6>Paul A. Iaizzo<br><small>3rd ed. 2015</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-3-319-19464-6">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>The Gastrointestinal System</h5>
              <h6>Po Sing Leung<br><small>2014</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-94-017-8771-0">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>SPSS for Starters and 2nd Levelers</h5>
              <h6>Ton J. Cleophas, Aeilko H. Zwinderman<br><small>2nd ed. 2016</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-3-319-20600-4">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Machine Learning in Medicine - a Complete Overview</h5>
              <h6>Ton J. Cleophas, Aeilko H. Zwinderman<br><small>2015</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-3-319-15195-3">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
            
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <h5>Pharmaceutical Biotechnology</h5>
              <h6>Daan J. A. Crommelin, Robert D. Sindelar, Bernd Meibohm<br><small>4th ed. 2013</small></h6>
              <p><a href="http://link.springer.com/openurl?genre=book&amp;isbn=978-1-4614-6486-0">Go get it</a>
            </p></div>
            
            
            
          </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
          …</div></div></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://hnarayanan.github.io/springer-books/#Physics%20and%20Astronomy">https://hnarayanan.github.io/springer-books/#Physics%20and%20Astronomy</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://hnarayanan.github.io/springer-books/#Physics%20and%20Astronomy</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23971096</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:45:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How Did the Casio F91W Become a Terrorist Icon?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 261 | Comments 134 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23971045">thread link</a>) | @joeschmoe83
<br/>
July 27, 2020 | https://reaperfeed.com/how-did-the-casio-f91w-become-a-terrorist-icon/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://reaperfeed.com/how-did-the-casio-f91w-become-a-terrorist-icon/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The humble Casio F91W has been an iconic watch since it was first made in Japan back in 1989. Upon its release, it was sold for around $20 making it one of the world’s first affordable digital watches. Today, Casio still produces over 3 million of the F91W every year. The prevalence of this iconic timepiece through the years means it’s likely you’ve worn one at some point. If you have, then it’s probably the only thing you have in common with Osama bin Laden, Chechen militants, and Napoleon Dynamite. Congratulations!</p>



<p>As a kid in school, I personally remember being told off for talking in the back of the class. I had been caught excitedly telling my friends that I had just figured out what kind of watch the most wanted man on earth, Osama bin Laden, wears. As punishment, I was called up to answer the maths question on the board, at which I failed miserably. <em>”You need to focus on what matters! You can’t solve maths problems but you can tell everyone about the watches worn by terrorists?”</em> screamed my teacher. <a href="https://reaperfeed.com/about-reaper-feed/">Looking back</a>, I feel I prioritized the right kind of knowledge.</p>



<figure><img src="https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Casio-G-Shock-Designer-Moriai-aBlogtoWatch-67.jpg?w=696&amp;ssl=1" alt="Inventor of the Casio FW91" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Casio-G-Shock-Designer-Moriai-aBlogtoWatch-67.jpg?w=860&amp;ssl=1 860w, https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Casio-G-Shock-Designer-Moriai-aBlogtoWatch-67.jpg?resize=300%2C228&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Casio-G-Shock-Designer-Moriai-aBlogtoWatch-67.jpg?resize=768%2C584&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Casio-G-Shock-Designer-Moriai-aBlogtoWatch-67.jpg?resize=696%2C529&amp;ssl=1 696w, https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Casio-G-Shock-Designer-Moriai-aBlogtoWatch-67.jpg?resize=552%2C420&amp;ssl=1 552w, https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Casio-G-Shock-Designer-Moriai-aBlogtoWatch-67.jpg?resize=80%2C60&amp;ssl=1 80w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px" data-recalc-dims="1"><figcaption>Inventor of the Casio F91W, Ryusuke Moriai, polishes a Samurai sword in Tokyo. Photo from <a href="https://www.ablogtowatch.com/tokyo-man-designs-casio-g-shock-watches-ryusuke-moriai/">A Blog to Watch.</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>The Casio F91W was designed by Ryusuke Moriai which he described as “small, flat and simple”. The watch features a seven-segment numerical display on a grey LCD screen. Water-resistant, extremely durable and accurate to within 30 seconds a month, it’s a tried and tested piece of kit.</p>



<hr>



<figure><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Military-Grade-Travel-Guide-Dangerous-ebook/dp/B086JBW97K"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Corporate-Work-Blog-Banner-2.png?resize=696%2C392&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Corporate-Work-Blog-Banner-2.png?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Corporate-Work-Blog-Banner-2.png?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Corporate-Work-Blog-Banner-2.png?resize=768%2C432&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Corporate-Work-Blog-Banner-2.png?resize=1536%2C864&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Corporate-Work-Blog-Banner-2.png?resize=2048%2C1152&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Corporate-Work-Blog-Banner-2.png?resize=696%2C392&amp;ssl=1 696w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Corporate-Work-Blog-Banner-2.png?resize=1068%2C601&amp;ssl=1 1068w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Corporate-Work-Blog-Banner-2.png?resize=1920%2C1080&amp;ssl=1 1920w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Corporate-Work-Blog-Banner-2.png?resize=747%2C420&amp;ssl=1 747w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Corporate-Work-Blog-Banner-2.png?w=1392&amp;ssl=1 1392w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></figure>



<hr>



<p>If there’s one thing that’s to be said for international terrorists, they know a thing or two about choosing reliable products for waging war. The F-91W joined the ranks of other terrorist accessories like the Kalashnikov and the Toyota technical because it’s cheap, solid, and reliable. Oh, and it also doubles as a bombmaking accessory which we’ll look into later.</p>



<h3><strong><em>A Terrorist Fashion Icon</em></strong></h3>



<p>Whilst Casio has advanced further into combat watches through its iconic Casio G-Shock range, the F91W has remained the true battlefield accessory throughout modern warfare. Aside from iconic weapons, the Casio F-91W is the only branded accessory that Osama bin Laden was ever seen wearing in the open. Al-Qaeda was reported to <a href="https://wikileaks.org/gitmo/prisoner/720.html">hand the watches out to recruits</a> at their terror training camps across Afghanistan and Pakistan throughout the 1990s and early 2000s. Thus, it was al-Qaeda and bin Laden who arguably started the terrorist trend surrounding the watch.</p>



<div><figure><img src="https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/obl_AP070817055372-1.jpg?w=696&amp;ssl=1" alt="Osama Bin Laden wearing Casio FW91" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/obl_AP070817055372-1.jpg?w=371&amp;ssl=1 371w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/obl_AP070817055372-1.jpg?resize=239%2C300&amp;ssl=1 239w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/obl_AP070817055372-1.jpg?resize=335%2C420&amp;ssl=1 335w" sizes="(max-width: 371px) 100vw, 371px" data-recalc-dims="1"><figcaption>Osama bin Laden wearing the iconic F-91W.</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>During the height of the War on Terror, it didn’t take long for the US government to spot the prevalence of the Casio F91W amongst terrorists. In 2011, Wikileaks released a document labeled the “Matrix of Threat Indicators for Enemy Combatants” which was intended to assist staff at Guantanamo decide which detainees are more likely to carry out suicide attacks. According to the document, owning an F-91W was the biggest giveaway of a serious terror suspect alongside ownership of a satellite phone, a radio transceiver, or large quantities of cash.</p>



<p>However, this wasn’t just paranoia. Statistics in other similar documents released by Wikileaks revealed that around a third of inmates being held at Guantanamo that were captured whilst wearing an F-91W had a known correlation with explosives. The F-91W watch came up almost 150 times in the piles of leaked <a href="https://wikileaks.org/gitmo/pdf/ym/us9ym-000840dp.pdf">Guantanamo prisoner assessments</a>. Ironically, four of the chaplains who worked at Guantanimo Bay also wore the watch.</p>



<figure><img src="https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/5cc7041ab14bf43772045166.jpg?fit=696%2C348&amp;ssl=1" alt="Casio FW91 Guantanamo Bay" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/5cc7041ab14bf43772045166.jpg?w=1100&amp;ssl=1 1100w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/5cc7041ab14bf43772045166.jpg?resize=300%2C150&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/5cc7041ab14bf43772045166.jpg?resize=1024%2C512&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/5cc7041ab14bf43772045166.jpg?resize=768%2C384&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/5cc7041ab14bf43772045166.jpg?resize=696%2C348&amp;ssl=1 696w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/5cc7041ab14bf43772045166.jpg?resize=1068%2C534&amp;ssl=1 1068w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/5cc7041ab14bf43772045166.jpg?resize=840%2C420&amp;ssl=1 840w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px"></figure>



<p>One of the detainees at Guantanamo was grilled over the prevalence of the watch amongst suspected terrorists. He claimed that the water-resistant feature of the F91W watch was handy due to the Islamic requirement for followers to wash up to their elbows before prayers. Innocent enough explanation, right? Well not really. Interrogators smelled a rat when another prisoner claimed the prevalence of the watch amongst Jihadi inmates was simply due to the built-in compass that helped them pray towards Mecca. However, there is no compass in the F91W.</p>



<p>Despite the fairly frosty relationship between the two, ISIS didn’t let it get in between their choice of a good wristwatch. The F-91W was a feature of various ISIS militants including Tunisian born Tariq al-Harzi who was a high ranking Emir of the Islamic State. It was also worn by Kevin Chassin who was a French-born Jihadist who went to Syria to join ISIS. He was subsequently utilized for his high propaganda value in ISIS videos. </p>



<figure><img src="https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Untitled-design-3.jpg?resize=696%2C364&amp;ssl=1" alt="Casio F91W." srcset="https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Untitled-design-3.jpg?resize=1024%2C536&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Untitled-design-3.jpg?resize=300%2C157&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Untitled-design-3.jpg?resize=768%2C402&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Untitled-design-3.jpg?resize=696%2C364&amp;ssl=1 696w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Untitled-design-3.jpg?resize=1068%2C559&amp;ssl=1 1068w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Untitled-design-3.jpg?resize=803%2C420&amp;ssl=1 803w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Untitled-design-3.jpg?w=1200&amp;ssl=1 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px" data-recalc-dims="1"></figure>



<p>However, the leader of ISIS Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi wasn’t so fond of the cheap Casio F91W. Instead, al-Baghdadi opted for a flashy watch that sparked debate over the exact model. The watch was spotted during his infamous speech in Mosul that declared the formation of the so-called Caliphate. It was believed to be either a Rolex or an Omega Seamaster, both of which run north of $3,000 and contradict the contents of his speech as well as his ideals.</p>



<p>It’s not just Jihadist terrorist groups that wear the watch. Introducing Subcomandante Marcos who, until recently, led the Zapatista National Liberation Army (EZLN) in Mexico. The photogenic insurgent leader was pictured in an iconic photo on horseback while smoking a pipe and wearing, you guessed it! </p>



<figure><img src="https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Untitled-design-6.jpg?fit=696%2C364&amp;ssl=1" alt="subcomandante Marcos Casio FW91" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Untitled-design-6.jpg?w=1200&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Untitled-design-6.jpg?resize=300%2C157&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Untitled-design-6.jpg?resize=1024%2C536&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Untitled-design-6.jpg?resize=768%2C402&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Untitled-design-6.jpg?resize=696%2C364&amp;ssl=1 696w, https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Untitled-design-6.jpg?resize=1068%2C559&amp;ssl=1 1068w, https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Untitled-design-6.jpg?resize=803%2C420&amp;ssl=1 803w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px"><figcaption>Subcomandante Marcos wearing the Casio F91W</figcaption></figure>



<p>Of course, the watch is not only appreciated by the terrorists of the world but likewise by the people who combat them. Various fighting forces across the Middle East have been seen using the watch. Such as the Syrian Democratic Forces which is a coalition waging an anti-ISIS campaign across war-torn Syria.</p>



<h3><em><strong> How the Casio F91W Became a Bomb Makers Accessory</strong></em></h3>



<p>The Casio F91W is not only the terrorist’s timepiece of choice due to its ruggedness and reliability. Due to its long-lead timer, it also doubles as a bomb-making accessory for various terror groups around the world from Afghanistan to Chechnya. Deadly usage of the watch has been well documented through various case studies.</p>



<figure><img src="https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/photo-casio-f91w-is-a-favourite-of-cia-s-terrorist-arm-al-qaeeda-supposedly.jpg?resize=696%2C500&amp;ssl=1" alt="Casio FW91" width="696" height="500" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/photo-casio-f91w-is-a-favourite-of-cia-s-terrorist-arm-al-qaeeda-supposedly.jpg?w=600&amp;ssl=1 600w, https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/photo-casio-f91w-is-a-favourite-of-cia-s-terrorist-arm-al-qaeeda-supposedly.jpg?resize=300%2C216&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/photo-casio-f91w-is-a-favourite-of-cia-s-terrorist-arm-al-qaeeda-supposedly.jpg?resize=585%2C420&amp;ssl=1 585w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px" data-recalc-dims="1"></figure>



<p>According to US intelligence officials, the watch doubles as a bomb timer as its alarm can be set beyond a 24-hour period. During the War on Terror, Pakistani ISI officials found more than 600 of the watches in a terrorist safe house in Karachi which led to a period of anybody being found wearing an F91W watch to be liable for arrest and questioning. However, with the watch being available for $4 dollars on Pakistani markets, simply possessing a Casio watch doesn’t prove anything and this tactic of arrest was soon dropped.</p>



<p>In September 1999, a series of bombs were detonated inside four Russian apartment buildings in the cities of Moscow, Volgodonsk, and Buinaksk. The blasts killed 367 people and injured over 1,000 others. Russian investigators concluded that the attackers had been trained in terror camps being run by Ibn al-Khattab inside Chechnya which had recently gained unstable independence following the First Chechen War.</p>



<figure><img src="https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/ap_99090902501_custom-0dbb7e58420fd5260bf942910bfb61bd5c7c782f-s800-c85.jpg?w=696&amp;ssl=1" alt="Casio F91W" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/ap_99090902501_custom-0dbb7e58420fd5260bf942910bfb61bd5c7c782f-s800-c85.jpg?w=800&amp;ssl=1 800w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/ap_99090902501_custom-0dbb7e58420fd5260bf942910bfb61bd5c7c782f-s800-c85.jpg?resize=300%2C195&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/ap_99090902501_custom-0dbb7e58420fd5260bf942910bfb61bd5c7c782f-s800-c85.jpg?resize=768%2C498&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/ap_99090902501_custom-0dbb7e58420fd5260bf942910bfb61bd5c7c782f-s800-c85.jpg?resize=696%2C452&amp;ssl=1 696w, https://i1.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/ap_99090902501_custom-0dbb7e58420fd5260bf942910bfb61bd5c7c782f-s800-c85.jpg?resize=647%2C420&amp;ssl=1 647w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px" data-recalc-dims="1"><figcaption>Fire and smoke rise from a destroyed apartment building as Russian firefighters try to save people in Moscow on Sept. 9, 1999.&nbsp;</figcaption></figure>



<p>Investigations carried out inside Chechnya discovered that the bombs used in the attacks were comprised of ammonium nitrate and aluminum powder, with plastic serving as an intermediate explosive. The detonator? A combination of a Krona battery and a Casio F-91W. </p>



<blockquote><p>“about a third of inmates at JTF-GTMO [the unit in charge of Guantanamo] who were captured wearing one of these watches had a known correlation with explosives”.</p><cite>– Prisoner evaluation sheet from Guantanamo.</cite></blockquote>



<p>In 1994, an al-Qaeda militant named Ramzi Yousef used the Casio F-91W as a 4-hour timer on the bomb he constructed in an airplane toilet of Philippine Airlines Flight 434. He proceeded to leave his deadly work under the seat before leaving the plane. It detonated on the next flight, killing a Japanese businessman named Haruki Ikegami who sat in Yousef’s seat. Thankfully, the bomb’s orientation caused the energy to be mostly absorbed by Ikegami. Thus other passengers and the plane were not catastrophically damaged.</p>



<p>So, to round off this article I feel it’s fitting to make a comparison between Ryusuke Moriai and Mikhail Kalashnikov. Just like when Kalashnikov designed the AK47 intended solely for the defense of his motherland, the innovative inventor Ryusuke Moriai could never have predicted that his creation would go on an unstoppable path of its own and be used for far more sinister purposes than ever intended. Mr. Moriai had unwittingly created a watch ideal for modern warfare.</p>



<figure><img src="https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/e5d2ebf24cf0e901f0be47c23482b2e8_0.jpg?fit=696%2C923&amp;ssl=1" alt="Casio F91W" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/e5d2ebf24cf0e901f0be47c23482b2e8_0.jpg?w=1200&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/e5d2ebf24cf0e901f0be47c23482b2e8_0.jpg?resize=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1 226w, https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/e5d2ebf24cf0e901f0be47c23482b2e8_0.jpg?resize=772%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 772w, https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/e5d2ebf24cf0e901f0be47c23482b2e8_0.jpg?resize=768%2C1018&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/e5d2ebf24cf0e901f0be47c23482b2e8_0.jpg?resize=1159%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 1159w, https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/e5d2ebf24cf0e901f0be47c23482b2e8_0.jpg?resize=696%2C923&amp;ssl=1 696w, https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/e5d2ebf24cf0e901f0be47c23482b2e8_0.jpg?resize=1068%2C1416&amp;ssl=1 1068w, https://i2.wp.com/reaperfeed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/e5d2ebf24cf0e901f0be47c23482b2e8_0.jpg?resize=317%2C420&amp;ssl=1 317w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px"></figure>



<p>I was hoping to find a profound statement from Casio on the watch being used for deadly means by some pretty evil people. I was looking for something similar to what Kalashnikov said about the violent impact of his life’s work. <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2011/apr/28/casio-f-91w-watch-design-hipsters-al-qaida">The Guardian</a> approached the PR department for Casio hoping for a similar statement on the widespread use of the F-91W amongst global terrorists. But they just received a blunt email stating: “Casio is not making any further comment on the F-91W watch at this point in time.” Damn.</p>



<p>For more stories like this as well as photography from the more bizarre sides of human conflict, you can stay up to speed with us on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/reaperfeed1/">Instagram</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/Reaperfeed1">Twitter</a>.</p>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://reaperfeed.com/how-did-the-casio-f91w-become-a-terrorist-icon/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23971045</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:40:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
