<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 20]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 20. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 12:48:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-20.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 12:48:12 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Docker, Django, Traefik, and IntercoolerJS: My go-to stack for building a SaaS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 215 | Comments 212 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25973242">thread link</a>) | @simplecto
<br/>
January 30, 2021 | https://www.simplecto.com/docker-django-traefik-intercoolerjs-is-my-stack-for-2021/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.simplecto.com/docker-django-traefik-intercoolerjs-is-my-stack-for-2021/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
				<!--kg-card-begin: html--><p>This article has been updated. It was previously dated for 2020. Very little has changed, but I call it out where needed.
</p><!--kg-card-end: html--><p>In case you are wondering, that SaaS is Curabase:</p><p><a href="https://www.curabase.com/">https://www.curabase.com</a></p><figure><a href="https://www.curabase.com/"><div><p>Curabase: We make it easy to curate, collaborate, and share bookmarks.</p><p>Curabase makes group bookmarking easier, the same way that Github eases the pain of software development collaboration easier.</p><p><img src="https://www.curabase.com/static/images/favicon/favicon-color-194.png"><span>Curabase</span></p></div><p><img src="https://www.curabase.com/static/images/curabase-opengraph-image.jpg"></p></a></figure><hr><p>I recently published some thoughts on <a href="https://www.simplecto.com/docker-django-traefik-intercoolerjs-is-my-stack-for-2020/">Django being a great framework for applications</a>. This post expands on that to include the other pieces of infrastructure from development to production environments.</p><p>I have used this stack (or ones that look a lot like it) to build small SaaS apps in 2018, 2019, 2020, and now in 2021.</p><h3 id="my-entire-stack">My entire stack</h3><ul><li>Linux Server/VM Hosted anywhere (I like Azure, Digital Ocean, or Scaleway) <em>(edit: 2021 – I'm in the process of moving everything over to a dedicated server at <a href="https://www.hetzner.com/">Hetzner</a>.)</em></li><li>Docker. Just plain docker</li><li>Traefik for reverse proxy and TLS with LetsEncrypt</li><li>Postgresql running in docker</li><li>Django in a container</li><li>Intercoolerjs for easy and slick Ajax-like front-end work <em>(Edit: 2021 - the creator of intercooler has released <a href="https://htmx.org/">HTMX</a>, the successor to IntercoolerJS.)</em></li><li>Sentry for catching production bugs (easy three-lines added to your config)</li><li>Bitbucket pipelines for CI/CD <em>(Edit: 2021 - I no longer bother with CI / CD for personal projects. It it too much tooling for no benefit)</em></li><li>ZeroTier for VPN/ControlPlane</li></ul><p>For smaller projects I run tests locally in docker containers and then push directly into production. I &nbsp;don't bother with full CI/CD because I don't need the complexity of it all. That said, I do like Bitbucket Pipelines.</p><figure><img src="https://www.simplecto.com/content/images/2020/02/mytechstack.jpg" alt=""><figcaption>A simple diagram of my go-to tech stack</figcaption></figure><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>Woah! that is a lot to unpack here. Let's visualize this another way.</p>
<ul>
<li>Virtual Machine
<ul>
<li>Docker
<ul>
<li>Django
<ul>
<li>Volume mounted data disks</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Workers (Long-running django commands)
<ul>
<li>Volume mounted data disks</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Postgres
<ul>
<li>Volume-mounted data disks</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Traefik</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Zero-Tier</li>
<li>SSH</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Was this helpful? Let me know...</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><h3 id="hosting">Hosting</h3><p>Your stuff needs a home (yes, even in the "serverless" world. LOL). My personal preferences are <a href="https://azure.com/">Azure</a>, <a href="https://m.do.co/c/c844c6492d23">Digital Ocean</a> <em>(affiliate link)</em>, or <a href="https://scaleway.com/">Scaleway</a>. They each offer enough compute, networking options, storage, and basic services to build out proofs-of-concept or whatever you might need.</p><p>Another honorable mention here is <a href="https://hetzner.com/">Hetzner</a>. They offer a good level of hardware, service and price.</p><h3 id="the-virtual-machines">The Virtual Machines</h3><p>For those side projects and many enterprise applications, <strong>scale is not an issue</strong>. That means that I will not serve thousands of simultaneous users or handling terabytes of data. Therefore I can get by on the smaller offerings – usually under $20/month. Even Azure (the most expensive of the three) offer their burstable VMs. Generally I like to go with <a href="https://www.scaleway.com/en/virtual-instances/development/">Scaleway's Developer line of servers</a>.</p><p><em><strong>Notice that Kubernetes is missing from my stack? When scale is not an issue then you don't need Kubernetes.</strong></em></p><h3 id="docker-just-plain-docker-">Docker. Just plain Docker.</h3><p>I do not rely on the OS vendor (Ubuntu) to make sure that I run the latest Docker on new VMs. Therefore I use the nice little <code>curl|bash</code> technique.</p><pre><code>curl -s https://get.docker.com | sudo bash</code></pre><p>This cure one-liner will get the best and most recent version for your machine running.</p><h3 id="traefik-for-reverse-proxy">Traefik for Reverse Proxy</h3><p>Traefik has been a God-send since I found it. Nginx is great, but it was not built for the Docker universe. Traefik has two killer features that have saved me hours upon hours:</p><ol><li>Automatic TLS with LetsEncrypt. Literally set-it-and-forget-it. With the right API keys and DNS provider you can also do verification with DNS.</li><li>Automatic no-reload configuration using docker labels. When you spin up new services Traefik will pickup the changes automatically because it listens to all Docker-related events. This makes it incredibly convenient to add, remove, or merge services as needed without any hassle.</li></ol><p>My only comment on Traefik is that there is a bit of a learning curve. You have to decide how you want to configure it (config file, command line options, yaml, or docker labels, or use a combination!)</p><!--kg-card-begin: html--><p>Another note here: I have already <a href="https://www.simplecto.com/traefik-2-0-docker-and-letsencrypt/" title="Traefik 2 production ready configurations">published my production configuations for Traefik</a> here.</p><!--kg-card-end: html--><h3 id="postgres-for-database">Postgres for Database</h3><p>Tried and True, PostgreSQL has never let me down. I usually attach one of these containers to a project that needs it without any difficulty. I simply spin up the container, bind the ports, and then bind the data volume to my host disk. Done and Done.</p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><h3 id="dockercomposeyml">docker-compose.yml</h3>
<pre><code>version: '3.1'

services:

  db:
    container_name: postgres
    hostname: postgres
    image: postgres:11
    restart: always
    environment:
      POSTGRES_PASSWORD: secretsonly
    volumes:
      - ./data:/var/lib/postgresql/data
    ports:
      - 5432:5432
    networks:
      - web

networks:
    web:
        external: true
</code></pre>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><h3 id="dockerized-django-for-web">Dockerized Django for Web</h3><p>Docker deploys nicely in a container, and I have been doing it for a few years now. The benefits of matching your development environment to your production one cannot be overstated, and I have Docker to thank for that.</p><p>Edit: 2021, I've got a reference Django project up that I use as my template for new projects: <a href="https://github.com/simplecto/django-reference-implementation">https://github.com/simplecto/django-reference-implementation</a></p><h3 id="django-commands-for-asynchronous-tasks">Django commands for Asynchronous tasks</h3><p>Also, for asynchronous tasks I simply use <a href="https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/3.0/howto/custom-management-commands/">custom Django commands</a> which are a part of the standard framework. The pattern here is a simple <code>while</code> loop with a <code>sleep()</code> period. It polls the database for relevant actions and then does it's thing. &nbsp;</p><p>Edit: 2021 - This has paid off in a big way. I have been running a website screenshot project for over a year now with this pattern. It takes about 1500 website screenshots per day. All of it is scheduled and managed by a Django command.</p><p>That project lives here: https://github.com/simplecto/screenshots</p><h3 id="intercoolerjs-because-who-needs-the-complexity">IntercoolerJS, because who needs the complexity?</h3><p>I have a lot to say about this, but that will have to go into a series of posts. The tldr; here that I use this lovely little javascript library along with jQuery (<em>yeah, it is 2020, and I still use jQuery</em>) to make parts of my applications <em>feel</em> like single-page-apps but not really.</p><p>IntercoolerJS keeps that old-school "Ajax" (remember that word) goodness and allows me to update the DOM with HTML from the backend. It is seamless, smooth, and really convenient for things like logins and small form updates.</p><p>I strongly suggest you check it out: <a href="https://intercoolerjs.org/">Learn more about IntercoolerJS</a></p><p>Edit 2021: The creator has released <a href="https://htmx.org/">HTMX</a>, the successor to IntercoolerJS.</p><h3 id="sentry-to-catch-production-errors">Sentry to catch production errors</h3><p>I make mistakes. Lots of mistakes--but there is no need to show them to my users, right? Sentry gives me an easy and convenient way to capture production bugs as they happen. Some cool things about them:</p><ol><li>Open source-ish (<a href="https://blog.sentry.io/2019/11/06/relicensing-sentry">relicensed here</a>), so you can host yourself if that is your thing.</li><li>Easy few lines added to your <code>settings.py</code> file in Django and that is it.</li><li>Tight integration to your Git repos and Issue tracking systems for full production defect traceability.</li></ol><p>Another nice thing is that you can disable it for development.</p><p><a href="https://sentry.io/">Check out Sentry here</a>.</p><h3 id="bitbucket-pipelines-for-ci-cd">Bitbucket Pipelines for CI/CD</h3><p>Edit: 2021 - I no longer use CI/CD for deployment of my one-man projects. It is too much tooling and complexity. I simply run tests with PyCharm and ship directly to production from my development machine.</p><p>There are so many CI/CD offerings out there today, but I have been happy with Bitbucket's offering called Pipelines. They offer you a few hundred minutes free every month with the option to top-up as needed for a small fee. I have rarely had problems, and I really enjoy their YAML configuraiton / directive files. </p><p>Using the <code>bitbucket-pipelines.yml</code> file I have been able to do full end-to-end testing by spinning up multiple docker containers, loading the databases, and running hundreds of test in just a few minutes. This was key in speeding things up in our team and enabling 5+ pushes to production per day.</p><p><a href="https://bitbucket.org/">Checkout Bitbucket here</a>.</p><h3 id="zerotier-for-vpn-control-plane">ZeroTier for VPN/Control Plane</h3><p>Finally, we come to the bit of tech that is largely optional but nice to have. &nbsp;Zerotier is a unique kind of network/VPN that I use to link all my personal machines. It works though firewalls (at home, in office) and offers an easy 1 minute setup.</p><p>Using ZeroTier in my last company we were able to remove the SSH Jump Servers which caused a headache in terms of key management and shared bandwidth on a single machine.</p><p>Zerotier work on Linux, Mac, Windows, Android, and iPhone, so you are pretty much covered.</p><p>The one downside to ZeroTier is that I don't entirely understand how it works. It is a lot like MacOS or iPhone in that it "just works" as expected and I rarely (never) have problems. That is a strength from a user experience perspective but a WTF? from a CTO perspective. </p><h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3><p>Hopefully this deeper-dive will prompt some interest and curiosity about Docker, Django, Traefik, and especially IntercoolerJS. It is simple, easy to work with, and allows you to grow out of it when the time comes.</p><p>Edit 2021 - As you can see not a lot has changed. I've been able to add more code to my public repositories that flesh out the ideas expressed here over a year ago.</p>
			</section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.simplecto.com/docker-django-traefik-intercoolerjs-is-my-stack-for-2021/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25973242</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 21:35:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Fixing 200 broken raspberry Pis to prevent e-waste and donating the money raised]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 79 | Comments 9 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25972094">thread link</a>) | @technlogger
<br/>
January 30, 2021 | https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/i-bought-200-raspberry-pi-model-bs-and-im-going-to-fix-them-part-4/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/i-bought-200-raspberry-pi-model-bs-and-im-going-to-fix-them-part-4/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-3651">

	

	<div>
		
<h2>Introduction</h2>



<div><p>The first batch of the repaired Raspberry Pi’s have been sold! If you missed out on this, don’t worry! There are more to come as I repair them. </p><p>I sold a total of 27 Raspberry Pi’s, 3 people cancelled their orders as they somehow thought these were Raspberry Pi 4’s?! I will relist these  during the week along with a few freshly repaired devices with upgraded SD card slots.</p></div>



<p>After ebay fees and P&amp;P the total was £400 which I have donated to the Raspberry Pi Foundation as can be seen below, more will be coming in a future post to show what this money will go towards. </p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="3653" data-permalink="https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/i-bought-200-raspberry-pi-model-bs-and-im-going-to-fix-them-part-4/image-9/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/image-9.png?fit=1128%2C1062&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1128,1062" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="image-9" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/image-9.png?fit=300%2C282&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/image-9.png?fit=750%2C706&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="750" height="706" src="https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/image-9.png?resize=750%2C706&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-src="https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/image-9.png?resize=750%2C706&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-srcset="https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/image-9.png?resize=1024%2C964&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/image-9.png?resize=300%2C282&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/image-9.png?resize=768%2C723&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/image-9.png?w=1128&amp;ssl=1 1128w" data-sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-old-src="https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/image-9.png?resize=750%2C706&amp;ssl=1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/image-9.png?resize=1024%2C964&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/image-9.png?resize=300%2C282&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/image-9.png?resize=768%2C723&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/image-9.png?w=1128&amp;ssl=1 1128w" data-lazy-src="https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/image-9.png?resize=750%2C706&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><figcaption>Donation to the Raspberry Pi foundation</figcaption></figure>



<h2>Replacing and Upgrading Damaged SD Card Slots</h2>



<p>A large amount of the Pi’s had damaged SD card slots, the original slots are made of plastic which was fairly brittle in 2012 when they were released and they really haven’t aged well! </p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="3649" data-permalink="https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/img_1561/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1561-scaled.jpg?fit=1920%2C2560&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1920,2560" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone 8 Plus&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1612006255&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;3.99&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;80&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.16666666666667&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="img_1561" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1561-scaled.jpg?fit=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1561-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="750" height="1000" src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1561.jpg?resize=750%2C1000&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1561.jpg?resize=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-srcset="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1561-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1561-scaled.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1561-scaled.jpg?resize=1600%2C2133&amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1561-scaled.jpg?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1561-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-old-src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1561.jpg?resize=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1561-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1561-scaled.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1561-scaled.jpg?resize=1600%2C2133&amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1561-scaled.jpg?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1561-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-lazy-src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1561.jpg?resize=750%2C1000&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure>



<p>As can be seen on this image the slots have crumbled meaning they no longer hold an SD card. I managed to source the original SD card slots although the seller wanted £2 each for them which just wasn’t worthwhile. I managed to source upgraded metal SD card slots for £0.14p each on aliexpress here: <a href="https://www.aliexpress.com/item/33012711993.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.aliexpress.com/item/33012711993.html</a></p>



<div><p>Removing the old SD card slot was easy, using a pair of snips I cut as much of the plastic away as possible leaving only the pins to remove. I did this using a soldering iron rather than hot air. </p><p>Installing the new SD card slot was equally as easy, the new slots don’t have the SD card detection switch built in meaning that the detection pads need to be bridged with Solder as can be seen in the image below:</p></div>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="3650" data-permalink="https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/img_1562/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1562-scaled.jpg?fit=1920%2C2560&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1920,2560" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone 8 Plus&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1612006273&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;3.99&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;100&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.066666666666667&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="img_1562" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1562-scaled.jpg?fit=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1562-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="750" height="1000" src="https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1562.jpg?resize=750%2C1000&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-src="https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1562.jpg?resize=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-srcset="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1562-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1562-scaled.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1562-scaled.jpg?resize=1600%2C2133&amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1562-scaled.jpg?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1562-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-old-src="https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1562.jpg?resize=750%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1562-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1562-scaled.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1562-scaled.jpg?resize=1600%2C2133&amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1562-scaled.jpg?w=1920&amp;ssl=1 1920w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1562-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-lazy-src="https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/img_1562.jpg?resize=750%2C1000&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><figcaption>Raspberry Pi with the SD card slot replaced. </figcaption></figure>



<p>Overall this was a very easy repair, I will post some detailed guides or maybe even videos on the repairs once I get through some of the backlog so don’t worry if this repair wasn’t in-depth enough for you. </p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<div><p>This SD card slots arriving from China allows me to repair a further 30 of the damaged Raspberry Pi’s which will be for sale soon – Remember that the profits from these sales goes to the Raspberry Pi Foundation. </p><p>The pace will be slowing down a little once this batch of repairs are complete as I have some upcoming hardware reviews I need to prepare for which will be showcased in future posts. </p></div>



<p>As always please leave a comment and share your thoughts on the repair process. </p>

	</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->

				
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/i-bought-200-raspberry-pi-model-bs-and-im-going-to-fix-them-part-4/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25972094</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 19:26:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Universal Basic Income Is Superior to a $15 Minimum Wage (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 91 | Comments 160 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25971227">thread link</a>) | @joeyespo
<br/>
January 30, 2021 | https://basicincometoday.com/opinion-universal-basic-income-is-superior-to-a-15-minimum-wage/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://basicincometoday.com/opinion-universal-basic-income-is-superior-to-a-15-minimum-wage/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-id="53c18a7c" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="theme-post-content.default">
				<div>
			<p><em>In this piece, author Jessica Flanigan makes the case that UBI is a better solution than raising the minimum wage, because UBI reaches all workers, paid and unpaid, and would also provide all workers the bargaining power to better choose where and how they want to work. — Scott Santens, Editor, BIT</em></p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.bls.gov/news.release/empsit.nr0.htm?source=post_page---------------------------">latest jobs report from the BLS</a> reports a sudden acceleration of an ongoing trend of job growth, and unemployment in the US is now around 3.7 percent. Despite these impressive job numbers, <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/up-front/2018/10/04/if-real-wages-arent-rising-how-is-household-income-going-up/?source=post_page---------------------------">real wages remain low</a> for American workers. Perhaps in light of this, The U.S. House of Representatives passed the <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/house-democratic-push-to-raise-minimum-wage-opens-rift-over-amount-of-hike/2019/04/12/05711400-5d2d-11e9-98d4-844088d135f2_story.html?utm_term=.70a79b170fa0&amp;source=post_page---------------------------">Raise the Wage Act</a> this week, which reflects the goal of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fight_for_$15?source=post_page---------------------------">Fight for $15</a> campaign: increase the federal minimum wage from $7.25 to $15 an hour.</p>
<p>The idea polls well. A <a href="https://thehill.com/hilltv/what-americas-thinking/426780-poll-a-majority-of-voters-want-a-15-minimum-wage?source=post_page---------------------------">majority of voters</a> support raising the federal minimum wage to $15 per hour as well. And most <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/politics/2020-democratic-candidates-embrace-a-15-minimum-wage?source=post_page---------------------------">2020 Democratic presidential candidates</a>, including Joe Biden, Elizabeth Warren, and Bernie Sanders, support a $15 federal minimum wage too.</p>
<p>And it may seem that conditions are perfect for changing the federal minimum wage — unemployment is low, and the idea has a lot of support. But it’s worth thinking about proposals for a $15 federal minimum wage not only in light of Americans’ current economic circumstances but also in light of projected changes to the workforce going forward.</p>
<blockquote><p>A higher minimum wage may benefit people who have jobs, but it doesn’t make life easier for people who aren’t workers. This is what makes the idea of a Universal Basic Income or Negative Income Tax a more promising route. Essentially, if we are interested in helping those most in need, we should focus on policies that put cash in all people’s pockets instead of just the pockets of hourly employees.</p></blockquote>
<p>Ultimately, the advantage of these programs over a $15 minimum wage is that they benefit all citizens and do not disproportionately benefit workers and burden employers. And unlike other costly redistributive policies such as student loan forgiveness and universal healthcare, UBI is better suited to reflect each person’s distinctive circumstances, preferences, and personal values. Below, I outline several reasons why more people should consider the UBI as a viable public policy.</p>
<p>Considering the UBI over the Fight for $15</p>
<p>Overall, the UBI does not rely on maintaining our current economic order in the way that policies that focus on benefiting workers do. This is an advantage because the economy is very likely going to change radically in the next century. Though today’s workers are <a href="http://rh-us.mediaroom.com/2019-06-05-49-Of-Workers-Believe-AI-And-Automation-Will-Have-No-Impact-On-Their-Job?source=post_page---------------------------">not very concerned</a> about automation, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/2/17524822/robot-automation-job-threat-what-happens-next?source=post_page---------------------------">economists</a> and <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2018/aug/06/automation-destroy-millions-jobs-change?source=post_page---------------------------">policy experts</a> argue that they should be.</p>
<p>Even if new technology does not cause significant job losses, workplace transformations associated with new technology are likely to have significant <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/techtank/2018/04/18/will-robots-and-ai-take-your-job-the-economic-and-political-consequences-of-automation/?source=post_page---------------------------">political and economic consequences</a>. Tying the provision of public benefits to participation in the workforce needlessly raises the stakes of any policy that could change the composition of the workforce, and therefore increases the political and economic risks associated with automation. Moreover, the UBI doesn’t limit its benefits to people who are engaged in paid employment. This has four benefits that a higher minimum wage does not.</p>
<p>First, a UBI would benefit people who do valuable unpaid labor, such as childcare and eldercare, as well as people who are employees.</p>
<p>Second, a UBI would not interfere with workers’ and employers’ freedom to set the terms and conditions of their labor. If it is possible to benefit low-income Americans without restricting their freedom to negotiate the terms and conditions of their employment relationships, officials should favor the less restrictive policies.</p>
<p>Third, a UBI would not tie people to their employers. This means that a basic income would potentially enable more economic mobility, enhance workers’ bargaining power, and enable people to stop working if they need to leave the workforce due to disability or caregiving obligations.</p>
<p>Fourth, policies that do not tie assistance to employment would not disproportionately burden employers. The debate over minimum wage increases is often framed as if employers are failing to benefit workers sufficiently. But low-wage work often helps low-skill workers more than anyone else. Without these employment opportunities, they would be even less capable of meeting their basic needs. If the justification for a higher minimum wage is that everyone should be able to support themselves, why should employers bear the full cost of meeting that goal? In contrast, a basic income enables citizens to share the cost of supporting a social safety net rather than treating employers as the only way to achieve it.</p>
<p>A significant benefit of a UBI, in contrast to other recent entitlement reforms such as student loan forgiveness and universal healthcare, is that it doesn’t tell people how to spend it. People have different values, but in-kind benefits assume that all people have the same interest in healthcare or being debt-free. This may be broadly true, but there are tradeoffs. Given the cost of these programs, it’s fair to ask whether people would be better off if we just gave them the money instead. But evidence from developing countries suggests that<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2014/06/30/opinion/let-them-eat-cash.html?source=post_page---------------------------"> cash does help people better than alternatives</a>.</p>
<p>As I see it, the main challenge to a Basic Income proposal is affordability. Estimates vary, and some argue that a UBI would be <a href="https://socialprotection-humanrights.org/resource/universal-basic-income-proposals-in-light-of-ilo-standards-key-issues-and-global-costing-ess-%e2%94%80-working-paper-no-62/?source=post_page---------------------------">catastrophically</a> <a href="https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2015/05/23/basically-unaffordable?source=post_page---------------------------">expensive</a> whereas others suggest that it is “<a href="https://medium.com/basic-income/basic-income-is-easily-affordable-8389995528b3?source=post_page---------------------------">easily affordable</a>.” Plausibly, while a UBI would save on administrative costs, it does seem that funding sustainable UBI could require making some <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/timworstall/2016/06/04/of-course-we-can-afford-a-universal-basic-income-do-we-want-one-though/?source=post_page---------------------------#50c7d99f323c">hard choices</a> about other social programs such as healthcare, education, and defense.</p>
<p>The UBI and Social Security</p>
<p>UBI may seem like a radical idea, but there’s a precedent for it in America. Elderly people already receive what is effectively a basic income through Social Security. Some of them continue to work, while others use their basic income (and retirement savings) to pay their bills so that they can focus on spending time with loved ones or pursuing new hobbies. Some elderly people are disabled, and Social Security enables them to leave the workforce.</p>
<p>Yet older voters <a href="https://thehill.com/hilltv/what-americas-thinking/435278-poll-most-voters-oppose-a-universal-basic-income-programs?source=post_page---------------------------">consistently</a> <a href="https://thehill.com/policy/technology/375587-gallup-poll-americans-split-on-giving-a-universal-basic-income-to-workers?source=post_page---------------------------">oppose</a> Universal Basic Income proposals while younger voters are in favor of it. Even more curiously, older voters <a href="https://www.pollingreport.com/social.htm?source=post_page---------------------------">consistently</a> <a href="https://socialsecurityworks.org/2019/03/26/social-security-polling/?source=post_page---------------------------">oppose</a> cuts to their basic income, Social Security. The difficult position for older voters is that the reasons for opposing a basic income are also reasons to oppose social security. And those who support Social Security should support a basic income as well. Those who oppose the UBI should rethink their support for Social Security. If anything, the case for a UBI is stronger than the case for Social Security because as it is currently structured, <a href="https://www.nber.org/digest/may00/w7520.html?source=post_page---------------------------">Social Security may be a slightly regressive policy</a>, in part <a href="https://www.latimes.com/business/hiltzik/la-fi-hiltzik-mortality-social-security-20180912-story.html?source=post_page---------------------------">because wealthy people live longer.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://bleedingheartlibertarians.com/2014/09/political-authority-and-the-basic-income/?source=post_page---------------------------">Elsewhere</a>, I have argued in favor of a basic income because it is a kind of compensation for the injustices associated with our existing property system. In contrast, minimum wage requirements only compound the injustices of the current system by doubling down on the idea that elevates paid employment over other kinds of potentially valuable work, discourages opportunities for low-skilled workers, and leaves non-workers out of the social safety net. A basic income is more respectful of people’s freedom, more sensitive to recipients’ values, and better suited for a rapidly changing economy.</p>
		</div>
				</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://basicincometoday.com/opinion-universal-basic-income-is-superior-to-a-15-minimum-wage/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25971227</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 17:56:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to stream media using WebRTC and FFmpeg, and why it's a bad idea]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 117 | Comments 36 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25970843">thread link</a>) | @dimes
<br/>
January 30, 2021 | https://blog.maxwellgale.com/2021/01/30/streaming-video-over-webrtc-using-ffmpeg/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.maxwellgale.com/2021/01/30/streaming-video-over-webrtc-using-ffmpeg/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>

                                            
                                                    <header>

    
    <!-- start: .meta -->
    
    <!-- end: .meta -->

	

</header>                        
                        <section>

                            
                            
                            <div>
                                
<p><strong>Note: </strong>The original version of this post highlighted the disadvantages of using a fixed key frame interval. I’ve since learned that this problem can be avoided using intra refresh in the H264 stream.</p>



<p>Streaming media. specifically video, is a fickle beast. This will be a short post, but it will cover everything you need to know to stream media using FFmpeg to WebRTC clients. This technique has many applications, such as streaming synchronized videos to users. </p>



<h2>Setting up the input</h2>



<p>Before inputting a file into FFmpeg, we need to pass a few flags:</p>



<pre><code>&gt; ffmpeg \
  -v info \
  -fflags +genpts \
  -protocol_whitelist pipe,tls,file,http,https,tcp,rtp \</code></pre>



<p>These flags set the log level to info, generate pts if they’re missing, and sets up the protocols we can use. Next we need to provide the input to FFmpeg.</p>



<pre><code>-i in.mp4</code></pre>



<p>In this example, a file name <code>in.mp4</code> is used, but a http(s) URL could also be used. This command starts playback at the beginning of the input file. If you want to start playback in the middle of the input file, then you can add the <code>-ss &lt;time in secs&gt;</code> flag <strong>before</strong> <code>-i</code>.</p>



<h2>Video arguments</h2>



<p>Now the video needs to be converted to an appropriate format for streaming. The format is specific to the application, but common codecs are H264, VP8, and VP9. This example uses H264 due to its ubiquitous support.</p>



<pre><code>-vf realtime,scale=w=min(iw\,1280):h=-2 \
-map 0:v:0 \
-c:v libx264 \
-x264-params intra-refresh=1,fast-pskip=0
-threads 3 \
-profile:v baseline \
-level:v 3.1 \
-pix_fmt yuv420p \
-tune zerolatency \
-minrate 500K \
-maxrate 1.3M \
-bufsize 500K \</code></pre>



<p><code>-vf</code> specifies the video filters to apply. Here, two filters are applied. The first is <code>realtime</code>, which causes playback to happen in real time, which is necessary for streaming. This filter is similar to the <code>-re</code> flag, but works much better with the start time flag (<code>-ss</code>). The second filter scales the video width to a maximum of 1280 pixels while maintaining the aspect ratio. This is important to keep the bitrate appropriate for real time streaming. </p>



<p>The <code>intra-refresh</code> parameter allows users to consume the video stream mid-way through by providing enough metadata over multiple inter frames to decode a full frame. The <code>fast-pskip=0</code>is required for <code>intra-refresh</code> to work if the source video files contains very few frames, which can happen if the video displays static images for long periods of time. There may be another way around this, but I’m not aware of it. </p>



<p>Another important parameter is the <code>-threads 3</code> flag. FFmpeg will use many threads by the default. Normally, this is good because it produces the final result as fast as possible. For real time encoding, however, using a large number of threads has some overhead that can slow down real time output. Using many threads is also a bad idea if you’re running multiple instances of FFmpeg concurrently.</p>



<p>The next two parametrs <code>-profile:v</code> and <code>-level:v</code> specify the profile and level to use for the encoding. These are specific to H264. WebRTC clients can only decode certain profiles and levels, so these need to match the specific configuration of the application. These roughly correspond to the profile-level-id of <code>42e01f</code>. </p>



<p>The pixel format is set to <code>yuv420p</code> using the <code>-pix_fmt</code> flag. This is required as this is the only pixel format supported by WebRTC. <code>-tune zerolatency</code> tunes the encoder for low latency streaming.</p>



<p>Next up are the bitrate parameters. When streaming media, the bitrate should be as low as possible while maintaining the desired quality. This ensures all clients can consume the video in real time. Omitting the <code>-minrate</code> parameter can cause FFmpeg to produce output with an unnecessarily high bitrate. Setting the <code>-maxrate</code> is equally important. A DSL connection can only pull down around 2 Mbps. In order for users to watch the video, they must be able to download it in real time, so the maximum bitrate has to be lower than the slowest connection among your users. Another consideration is that the streaming video might not be the only bandwidth consuming task on the user’s network.</p>



<h2>Audio arguments</h2>



<p>The audio arguments are much simpler.</p>



<pre><code>-af arealtime \
-map 0:a:0 \
-c:a libopus \
-ab 128k \
-ac 2 \
-ar 48000 \</code></pre>



<p>The main thing to note here is that the <code>arealtime</code> filter is used, which is similar to the <code>realtime</code> filter, but for audio.</p>



<h2>Output arguments</h2>



<p>The output can be piped to an RTP endpoint using the <code>tee</code> psuedomuxer. Unfortunately, FFmpeg does not support multiplexing over RTP, so you’ll need two separate RTP endpoints, one for the video stream and one for the audio stream. </p>



<pre><code>-f tee \
[select=a:f=rtp:ssrc=1111:payload_type=&lt;audio-payload_type&gt;]rtp://&lt;audio-ip&gt;:&lt;audio-port&gt;?rtcpport=&lt;audio-rtcpport&gt;|[select=v:f=rtp:ssrc=2222:payload_type=&lt;video-payload_type&gt;]rtp://&lt;video-ip&gt;:&lt;video-port&gt;?rtcpport=&lt;video-rtcpport&gt;</code></pre>



<p>Now you can stream video over RTP! The full command is</p>



<pre><code>&gt; ffmpeg \
  -v info \
  -fflags +genpts \
  -protocol_whitelist pipe,tls,file,http,https,tcp,rtp \
  -i in.mp4
  -vf realtime,scale=w=min(iw\,1280):h=-2 \
  -map 0:v:0 \
  -c:v libx264 \
  -x264-params intra-refresh=1,fast-pskip=0
  -threads 3 \
  -profile:v baseline \
  -level:v 3.1 \
  -pix_fmt yuv420p \
  -tune zerolatency \
  -minrate 500K \
  -maxrate 1.3M \
  -bufsize 500K \
  -af arealtime \
  -map 0:a:0 \
  -c:a libopus \
  -ab 128k \
  -ac 2 \
  -ar 48000 \
  -f tee \
  [select=a:f=rtp:ssrc=1111:payload_type=&lt;payload_type&gt;]rtp://&lt;ip&gt;:&lt;port&gt;?rtcpport=&lt;rtcpport&gt;|[select=v:f=rtp:ssrc=2222:payload_type=&lt;payload_type&gt;]rtp://&lt;ip&gt;:&lt;port&gt;?rtcpport=&lt;rtcpport&gt;</code></pre>
                                                            </div>
                            

                              

                                                        
                                                            
                                                        
                                                            
                            
                            

                            	                           

                            
                        </section>

                    </article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.maxwellgale.com/2021/01/30/streaming-video-over-webrtc-using-ffmpeg/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25970843</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 17:17:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A few HiDPI tricks for Linux]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 130 | Comments 142 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25970690">thread link</a>) | @woodruffw
<br/>
January 30, 2021 | https://blog.yossarian.net/2020/12/24/A-few-HiDPI-tricks-for-Linux | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.yossarian.net/2020/12/24/A-few-HiDPI-tricks-for-Linux">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">


<h2><em>Programming, philosophy, pedaling.</em></h2>

<ul>
    <li><a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/">Home</a></li>
    <li><a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/tags">Tags</a></li>
    <li><a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/favorites">Favorites</a></li>
    <li><a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/archive">Archive</a></li>
    
      <li><a href="https://yossarian.net/">Main Site</a></li>
    
</ul>

<hr>



<h2>
  <em>Dec 24, 2020</em>
</h2>

  <p>Tags:
  
    
    <a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/tags#workflow">workflow</a>
    
  
  </p>


<h2 id="background">Background</h2>

<p>I recently switched my home office to a 2-by-4K HiDPI setup, like so:</p>

<p><a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/assets/hidpi-setup.jpg"><img src="https://blog.yossarian.net/assets/hidpi-setup.jpg" alt="A picture of my home office."></a></p>

<p>As part of that switch, I needed to configure parts of my Linux environment (which was originally
stock Ubuntu, but is now <a href="https://i3wm.org/">i3</a> with a heavily customized userspace) to function
correctly on HiDPI displays.</p>

<p>This post will document most of the changes I applied. Hopefully others will find it useful for
their own HiDPI setups.</p>

<h2 id="90-of-the-way-x11-resources">90% of the way: X11 resources</h2>

<p>As it turns out, there’s a (nearly) one-stop location for configuring the default DPI for
X11 applications: the <code>Xft.dpi</code> setting.</p>

<p>There are lots of ways to configure X11, but I personally use an <code>~/.Xresources</code> file:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><table><tbody><tr><td><pre>1
2
3
</pre></td><td><pre><span>Xft</span>.<span>dpi</span>: <span>163</span>
<span># not used directly; more on this later
</span><span>janus</span>.<span>fractionalDpi</span>: <span>1</span>.<span>63</span>
</pre></td></tr></tbody></table></code></pre></div></div>

<p>Where <code>163</code> and <code>1.63</code> are my DPI and its fractional form, respectively.</p>

<p>On my system, <code>~/.Xresources</code> gets loaded into the X resource database automatically by some
magic that I never configured. However, if yours doesn’t (or you use a different resource file),
you can always tell i3 (or your WM of choice) to load it explicitly with <code>xrdb</code>.</p>

<p>For example, in <code>~/.config/i3/config</code>:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><table><tbody><tr><td><pre>1
</pre></td><td><pre><span>exec</span> <span>--no-startup-id</span> xrdb ~/.Xresources
</pre></td></tr></tbody></table></code></pre></div></div>

<p>With just this, about 90% of my applications (including GTK based ones, like Firefox) scaled
correctly and were usable without any font or custom scaling changes. Not bad for a single line!</p>

<h2 id="per-application-fixes">Per-application fixes</h2>

<h3 id="spotify">Spotify</h3>

<p>Spotify’s Linux application is a <a href="https://bitbucket.org/chromiumembedded/cef/src/master/">CEF</a>
shell. For reasons that are unclear to me, it doesn’t respect <code>Xft.dpi</code> while normal Chromium
(via <code>snap</code> or <code>apt</code>) does.</p>

<p>To get it to scale correctly, I needed to pass <code>--force-device-scale-factor=1.63</code> to it:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><table><tbody><tr><td><pre>1
</pre></td><td><pre>spotify <span>--force-device-scale-factor</span><span>=</span>1.63
</pre></td></tr></tbody></table></code></pre></div></div>

<p>At this point, it became clear to me that the fractional form of my DPI would be nice to set in
as few places as possible, to avoid duplication. Hence the <code>janus.fractionalDpi</code><sup id="fnref:hostname" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:hostname">1</a></sup> above,
and
<a href="https://github.com/woodruffw/dotfiles/blob/master/scripts/spotify">this little <code>spotify</code> wrapper</a>:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><table><tbody><tr><td><pre>1
2
3
4
5
6
</pre></td><td><pre><span># see the actual script linked above for some program-finding stupidity</span>
<span>real_spotify</span><span>=</span>/snap/bin/spotify

<span># grab the correct fractional DPI from the X resource DB</span>
<span>dpi</span><span>=</span><span>$(</span>xrdb <span>-query</span> | <span>grep</span> <span>"</span><span>$(</span><span>hostname</span><span>)</span><span>.fractionalDpi"</span> | <span>cut</span> <span>-f2</span><span>)</span>
<span>"</span><span>${</span><span>real_spotify</span><span>}</span><span>"</span> <span>--force-device-scale-factor</span><span>=</span><span>"</span><span>${</span><span>dpi</span><span>}</span><span>"</span> <span>"</span><span>${</span><span>@</span><span>}</span><span>"</span>
</pre></td></tr></tbody></table></code></pre></div></div>

<h3 id="sublime-text">Sublime Text</h3>

<p>I use <a href="https://www.sublimetext.com/3">Sublime Text 3</a> as my primary editor. As far as I can tell
it doesn’t use either GTK or Qt (or any other open-source GUI framework), which is probably why
it doesn’t respect <code>Xft.dpi</code>.</p>

<p>To get Sublime Text to scale correctly, I had to set <code>ui_scale</code> to the appropriate fractional DPI
in my user preferences (<code>~/.config/sublime-text-3/Preferences.sublime-settings</code>):</p>

<div><div><pre><code><table><tbody><tr><td><pre>1
2
3
</pre></td><td><pre><span>{</span><span>
  </span><span>"ui_scale"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>1.63</span><span>,</span><span>
</span><span>}</span><span>
</span></pre></td></tr></tbody></table></code></pre></div></div>

<p>Some lingering pain points:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Sublime Text’s input is noticeably laggy when the UI is scaled. It’s not so laggy as to be
unusable, but it’s definitely noticeable even if you aren’t sensitive to latencies (I’m not).</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Mousing between Sublime Text and other windows causes noticeable stutter/hiccuping during
video playback. I haven’t dug into the X events yet, but my guess is that it’s got some kind
of pessimistic (and serial) <code>XFlush</code> or <code>XSync</code> that takes a decent bit of time on a larger window
buffer. It doesn’t happen with smaller windows (either floating or fixed).</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h3 id="open-broadcaster-software-obs">Open Broadcaster Software (OBS)</h3>

<p>I haven’t used it recently, but I used to use <a href="https://obsproject.com/">OBS</a> to stream myself
working on open source projects.</p>

<p>When I switched monitors, I noticed that the embedded preview window for my scenes had stopped
working. OBS <em>itself</em> was still fully functional and the <em>separate</em> preview window still worked,
but the embedded preview was always filled in with black pixels.</p>

<p>After a decent bit of hair-pulling, I found a Qt environment variable that “fixed” it:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><table><tbody><tr><td><pre>1
</pre></td><td><pre><span>QT_AUTO_SCREEN_SCALE_FACTOR</span><span>=</span>0 obs
</pre></td></tr></tbody></table></code></pre></div></div>

<p>I still don’t understand why that fixed it, but now my OBS is scaled correctly <strong>and</strong> has a
functional preview embed. I also posted this fix to the
<a href="https://obsproject.com/forum/threads/bug-fix-black-preview-embed-window-on-linux-w-hidpi-monitors.135041/">OBS forum</a>.</p>

<h3 id="feh">feh</h3>

<p>I use <a href="https://github.com/derf/feh"><code>feh</code></a> as my image viewer. By default, it seems to use
a bitmap font that’s incredibly small on HiDPI displays.</p>

<p>To fix it, I modified by default theme to use my distro supplied Ubuntu Roman-face font in
14pt.</p>

<p>In <code>~/.config/feh/themes</code>:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><table><tbody><tr><td><pre>1
2
</pre></td><td><pre>feh <span>--borderless</span> <span>--scale-down</span> <span>--conversion-timeout</span> 1 <span>\</span>
  <span>--fontpath</span> /usr/share/fonts/truetype/ubuntu <span>--menu-font</span> Ubuntu-R/14
</pre></td></tr></tbody></table></code></pre></div></div>

<p>One thing I haven’t figured out: when I open some higher-resolution images in <code>feh</code>, they’re
occasionally shifted to the right with transparent pixels where some of the image should be.
Clicking and dragging inside the image window causes it to re-render correctly, as does
resizing the window. Not a huge deal, but slightly annoying.</p>

<h3 id="dunst">dunst</h3>

<p>I use <a href="https://dunst-project.org/"><code>dunst</code></a> as my notification daemon.</p>

<p>It didn’t <strong>need</strong> any HiDPI-specific configuration, but I took the opportunity to make its
notifications slightly more readable on these newer displays.</p>

<p>In <code>~/.config/dunst/dunstrc</code> (among many other settings):</p>

<div><div><pre><code><table><tbody><tr><td><pre>1
2
3
4
5
6
</pre></td><td><pre><span>monitor</span> = <span>0</span>
<span>follow</span> = <span>mouse</span>
<span>geometry</span> = <span>"600x120-30+20"</span>
<span>icon_position</span> = <span>left</span>
<span>max_icon_size</span> = <span>64</span>
<span>icon_path</span> = /<span>usr</span>/<span>share</span>/<span>icons</span>/<span>gnome</span>/<span>64</span><span>x64</span>/<span>status</span>/:/<span>usr</span>/<span>share</span>/<span>icons</span>/<span>gnome</span>/<span>64</span><span>x64</span>/<span>devices</span>/
</pre></td></tr></tbody></table></code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="other-bits">Other bits</h2>

<h3 id="mouse-acceleration">Mouse acceleration</h3>

<p>My new displays are individually larger and significantly more dense than my previous ones, making
my mouse feel sluggish. I originally configured my mouse acceleration with
<a href="https://www.x.org/archive/X11R7.5/doc/man/man1/xset.1.html"><code>xset</code></a>, but at some point my
system switched to <code>libinput</code> and <code>libinput</code>-based inputs apparently don’t respect <code>xset</code> anymore
(or never did?). Sigh.</p>

<p>The fix is to use <code>xinput</code> instead, with either symbolic names or XIDs for the device and setting
being controlled. For example, this is what I use to set my mouse’s acceleration to the maximum
(<code>1.0</code>):</p>

<div><div><pre><code><table><tbody><tr><td><pre>1
</pre></td><td><pre>xinput <span>--set-prop</span> <span>"USB Optical Mouse"</span> <span>"libinput Accel Speed"</span> 1.0
</pre></td></tr></tbody></table></code></pre></div></div>

<p>Your device and setting names may vary, of course, as may their value ranges (mine happened to be
<code>0.0</code> to <code>1.0</code>). You can use <code>xinput</code> on its own to list the names and XIDs of your devices;
<code>xinput list-props &lt;XID-or-name&gt;</code> can be used to dump a particular device’s properties and
their current values.</p>

<h3 id="i3-workspaces">i3 workspaces</h3>

<p>I use i3’s <a href="https://i3wm.org/docs/layout-saving.html">layout saving/restoring</a> functionality
to automatically load all of my workspaces and their applications when I log in.</p>

<p>Those layouts are stored in a (relaxed) JSON format via <code>i3-save-tree</code>, and contain hardcoded
coordinates. To update them for my new monitors, I just had to recreate each of my workspaces
once on my new monitors and dump them:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><table><tbody><tr><td><pre>1
2
</pre></td><td><pre><span># for each workspace (1A, 1B, ...)</span>
i3-save-tree <span>--workspace</span> 1A <span>&gt;</span> ~/.config/i3/workspaces/1A.json
</pre></td></tr></tbody></table></code></pre></div></div>

<p>…and then fix them up manually to enable the appropriate application swallowing rules.</p>

<h3 id="hexchat">HexChat</h3>

<p>I use <a href="https://hexchat.github.io/index.html">HexChat</a> for IRC.</p>

<p>HexChat’s config file includes individual offsets for each of the sub-panes in the GUI,
which means that it breaks badly if you change your monitor dimensions. I couldn’t figure out
how to fix them, so I ended up deleting my main <code>~/.config/hexchat/hexchat.conf</code> entirely and
recreating my preferred layout from memory. YMMV.</p>

<h3 id="system-icons">System icons</h3>

<p>I didn’t have to make any changes with respect to my system icon sizes, which is <em>probably</em>
because I actually see very few icons during normal i3 usage. Once again, YMMV.</p>

<h2 id="wrapup">Wrapup</h2>

<p>Switching from a set of 3 FHD monitors to two 4K HiDPI ones was <em>relatively</em> painless. The
problems that I had, unsurprisingly, were primarily with the few proprietary applications I use
needing to be spoon-feed DPI information in their own ways — every other problem was
either a bug (OBS + Qt) or a matter of more general reconfiguration.</p>

<hr>



<hr>


<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/enosuchblog/comments/kjhhp8/a_few_hidpi_tricks_for_linux/">Reddit discussion</a>

<hr>



  


  





</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.yossarian.net/2020/12/24/A-few-HiDPI-tricks-for-Linux</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25970690</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 17:01:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Oneness via gurus, psychedelics and the hidden code in Jordan Mechner's Karateka]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 36 | Comments 19 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25970184">thread link</a>) | @schmudde
<br/>
January 30, 2021 | https://schmud.de/posts/2020-12-16-be-here-now.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://schmud.de/posts/2020-12-16-be-here-now.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section itemprop="articleBody" role="main"><p>A reflection on Ram Dass’ 1971 classic, <em>Be Here Now</em>, and the book’s connection to information and our state of being.</p>

<p>Like many who walk the hallways of elite institutions, Ram Dass’ life intersected with influential mid-century thinkers and doers. His most famous collaborator might have been Timothy Leary in the early 1960s. Their landmark studies of psychedelic drugs lead to his dismissal from Harvard in 1963.</p>
<p>Ram Dass’ association with David Padwa is of more immediate interest to me. Padwa established a company called Basic Systems and became a millionaire by the time he met the young author in the late 1960s.<span><label for="sn-0"></label><span>From David Padwa’s <a href="http://www.cuke.com/people/padwa.htm">Curriculum Vitae</a>: “1960-1965. Founder and CEO of Basic Systems Inc.&nbsp;Principal offices in Cambridge, New York, Chicago, Pasadena, and Washington, DC. Firm specialized in educational and curricular technologies as well as the provision of systems integration services in education and training markets. In 1964 Xerox Corporation acquired Basic Systems; continued as division executive at Xerox and Director of Planning for educational markets.”</span></span> Basic Systems automated employee training and student education, often integrating into an institution’s existing computer infrastructure.</p>
<p>The company caught the eye of Xerox Corporation and was soon acquired. It fit nicely with Xerox’s growing digital portfolio. As the copier company sought to establish the office of the future, it would soon acquire the influential minicomputer manufacturer <a href="https://www.computerhistory.org/revolution/minicomputers/11/340">Scientific Data Systems</a> and establish the legendary <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PARC_(company)">Xerox PARC</a>.</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://schmud.de/img/2020-12-16-be-here-now/karateka-2.png" alt="Karateka Atari 7800 (1988)"> <em>Karateka</em> Atari 7800 (1988) <i></i> <a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/images/thing/77183/karateka-1984">Board Game Geek</a>
</figure>
<p>Padwa founded Basic Systems with the influential psychologist Francis Mechner. I was first exposed to Francis Mechner as a child playing <em>Karateka</em> (1984) on my Atari 7800<span><label for="sn-1"></label><span>The original version was written by Jordan Mechner and published by Broderbund in 1984. The Atari 7800 version was written by Jack Sandberg, Sr.&nbsp;at Ibid Inc.&nbsp;and published by Atari in 1987.</span></span> and then later <em>Prince of Persia</em> (1989) on my family’s PC. Francis Mechner was the composer for these games, both written by his son <a href="http://jordanmechner.com/">Jordan Mechner</a>. The elder Mechner is something of a renaissance man: starting several successful businesses, speaking five languages, publishing cross-disciplinary theoretical insights, performing as a concert pianist, and achieving a 5-dan rating in Go.<span><label for="sn-2"></label><span>Padwa and Mechner’s company also published the <a href="https://books.google.it/books?id=TnVYAAAAYAAJ&amp;redir_esc=y">original edition</a> of “Bobby Fischer Teaches Chess” in 1966. The best-selling book is still in print today.</span></span></p>
<p>These characters provide a sampling of the environment that nurtured Ram Dass. He would soon leave these comforts to join Padwa and his Land Rover on a road trip from Tehran to India in search of a spiritual awakening.</p>
<p>Ram Dass ultimately stayed in India for some time (as did Padwa’s Land Rover), leading to the insights that birthed the book <em>Be Here Now</em>. This book’s influence is without question. It was a significant contributor to the American counterculture movement and a starting point for many Western practitioners of Buddhism and Yoga.</p>

<figure>
<img src="https://schmud.de/img/2020-12-16-be-here-now/be-here-now.webp" alt="Be Here Now by Ram Dass (1971)"> <em>Be Here Now</em> by Ram Dass (1971) <i></i> <a href="https://www.gardenfairyco.com/product/be-here-now-ram-dass">Garden Fairy Co.</a>
</figure>
<p>Ram Dass spends the first part of the book describing his journey. It involves a dive into the world of psychedelic drugs and their benefits and limitations. His experience essentially opens him up to Eastern mysticism. He finds surprisingly few charlatans on the road through Central Asia and India. The book’s pivotal guru broadens Ram Dass’ mind through a process of “no teaching” because “his lessons aroused in me just affirmation… as if I knew it all already.”</p>
<p>The author strikes an important difference between <em>teacher</em> and <em>guru</em>. “A teacher points the way” while “a guru is the way.” Ram Dass’ awakening, and this book, is the result of the guru’s care.</p>
<p>This leads to a beautifully illustrated but overtly dogmatic section where Ram Dass attempts wake the reader up. The writer’s intention is rooted in Buddhism’s long practice of shifting the practitioner’s habitual and unquestioned perception of the world.<span><label for="sn-3"></label><span>The guru offers a few clever turns of phrases in this effort, “If a pickpocket meets a saint, he sees only his pockets” and “If you wear shoe leather, the whole earth is covered with leather.”</span></span> Ram Dass’ spiritual youth feels most pronounced here. He doesn’t have the language of a guru or a teacher; it is the voice of an enthusiastic lecturer who is convinced that he has uncovered the Truth.</p>
<p>The final section of the book is a collection of quotes and techniques divided into various “ingredients for a sacred life” such as <em>Sleeping</em>, <em>Truth</em>, <em>Time and Space</em>, <em>Pranayam</em>, etc…. It is pleasant reading.</p>
<p>Ram Dass makes it clear that there can be no <em>knower</em> if one truly wants to <em>know</em> the wisdom contained in <em>Be Here Now</em>; the rational mind that separates <em>subject</em> from <em>object</em> is an illusion.<span><label for="sn-4"></label><span>(Loc. 4594, 4613)</span></span> This illusion is driven by an attachment to the self as special and wholly separate from everything else.</p>

<figure>
<img src="https://schmud.de/img/2020-12-16-be-here-now/karateka-3.png" alt="Karateka Atari 7800 (1988)"> <em>Karateka</em> Atari 7800 (1988) <i></i> <a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/images/thing/77183/karateka-1984">Board Game Geek</a>
</figure>
<p>Deep within the cartridge of <em>Karateka</em> on the Atari 7800 are a list of instructions that drive the machine. But the programmer did mix in one human-readable message with the computer code: “Mommy and Me Are One.” This bizarre statement is unique to the Atari 7800 cartridge. It does not appear in other versions. It never appears on screen. It is only visible to those who are looking at the code contained within.<span><label for="sn-5"></label><span>“<a href="https://www.digitpress.com/eastereggs/78karateka.htm">Digital Press Easter Eggs: Karateka</a>”, <em>digitpress.com</em>, 2010.</span></span></p>
<p>The phrase is almost certainly related to a paper published by Lloyd Silverman and Joel Weinberger in a 1985 edition of <em>American Psychologist</em> entitled “<a href="https://content.apa.org/doiLanding?doi=10.1037%2F0003-066X.40.12.1296">Mommy and I Are One: Implications For Psychotherapy</a>”. The authors assert that the titular message can help motivate people even when stated subliminally.</p>
<p>Countless studies have attempted to demonstrate the benefits of “oneness.” In the case of the mother, oneness is self-evident. We were all physically connected at one point. And deep within us exists a DNA code that has been directly passed from mother to child for millennia. This is the ancient information that sets the foundation for consciousness.</p>
<p>The reality of a consciousness larger than ourselves is at the root of <em>Be Here Now.</em> But rather than establish a God or a single methodology, Ram Dass continually asserts that the ego blinds us to the grand web of connections that pervade our everyday experience. The way to lift the veil is to simply practice living in the moment. Or as Suzuki Roshi is quoted, “a Zen student must learn to waste time conscientiously.”<span><label for="sn-6"></label><span>(Loc. 4728)</span></span></p>

<p>Events from this post have been added to a <a href="https://schmud.de/pages/timeline.html">timeline</a> of significant events in the history of information.</p>
<section id="david-padwa-co-founds-basic-systems-with-francis-mechner" data-date-is="1960" data-machine-date="1960">
<h2>David Padwa Co-Founds Basic Systems With Francis Mechner</h2>
<p>“1960-1965. Founder and CEO of Basic Systems Inc.&nbsp;Principal offices in Cambridge, New York, Chicago, Pasadena, and Washington, DC. Firm specialized in educational and curricular technologies as well as the provision of systems integration services in education and training markets. In 1964 Xerox Corporation acquired Basic Systems; continued as division executive at Xerox and Director of Planning for educational markets.”</p>

</section>
</section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://schmud.de/posts/2020-12-16-be-here-now.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25970184</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 16:11:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Clojure/Script mode for CodeMirror 6]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 34 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25968289">thread link</a>) | @tosh
<br/>
January 30, 2021 | https://nextjournal.github.io/clojure-mode/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nextjournal.github.io/clojure-mode/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <h2 id="try-it">
        <a href="#try-it">🤹‍♀️ Try it for yourself</a>
      </h2>
      <div>
        <div>
          <h3>Try evaluating any of these forms with <span>Alt</span> <span>+</span> <span>⏎</span> !</h3>
          <p>
            In-browser eval is powered by <a href="https://github.com/borkdude/sci">Sci</a>.
          </p>
          
        </div>
        <div>
          <ul>
            <li>
              <span>⚡️</span>
              <div>
                <p><span>Lightning-fast</span> with <a href="https://lezer.codemirror.net/">lezer incremental parsing</a><br>
                <span>
                  Copy <a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/clojure/clojure/master/src/clj/clojure/core.clj" target="_blank"><code>clojure/core.clj</code></a> into 👈 <span>to try!</span>
                </span>
              </p></div>
            </li>
            <li>
              <span>🥤</span>
              <div>
                <p><span>Slurping &amp; 🤮 Barfing</span></p><table>
                  <tbody>
                    <tr>
                      <td>forward</td>
                      <td>
                        <span>Ctrl</span> + <span>←</span> / <span>→</span>
                      </td>
                      <td>
                        <span>or</span> <span>Mod</span> + <span>⇧</span> + <span>j</span> / <span>k</span>
                      </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                      <td>backward</td>
                      <td>
                        <span>Ctrl</span> + <span>Alt</span> + <span>←</span> / <span>→</span>
                      </td>
                      <td></td>
                    </tr>
                  </tbody>
                </table>
              </div>
            </li>
            <li>
              <span>💗</span>
              <div>
                <p><span>Semantic Selections</span></p><table>
                  <tbody>
                    <tr>
                      <td>Expand / Contract</td>
                      <td>
                        <span>Alt</span> + <span>↑</span> / <span>↓</span>
                      </td>
                      <td>
                        <span>or</span> <span>Mod</span> + <span>1</span> / <span>2</span>
                      </td>
                    </tr>
                  </tbody>
                </table>
              </div>
            </li>
            <li>
              <span>🧙</span>
              <div>
                <p><span>Evaluation</span></p><table>
                  <tbody>
                    <tr>
                      <td>
                        At Cursor
                      </td>
                      <td>
                        <span>Alt</span> + <span>⏎</span>
                      </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                      <td>
                        Top-level form
                      </td>
                      <td>
                        <span>Alt</span> + <span>⇧</span> + <span>⏎</span>
                      </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                      <td>
                        Cell
                      </td>
                      <td>
                        <span>Mod</span> + <span>⏎</span>
                      </td>
                    </tr>
                  </tbody>
                </table>
              </div>
            </li>
            <li>
              <span>🧹</span>
              <div>
                <p><span>Autoformatting</span></p><p>
                  following <a href="https://tonsky.me/blog/clojurefmt/">Tonsky’s Better Clojure Formatting</a>
                </p>
              </div>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nextjournal.github.io/clojure-mode/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25968289</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 11:39:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Creating my awesome Windows 10 dev setup]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 114 | Comments 147 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25965231">thread link</a>) | @indigodaddy
<br/>
January 29, 2021 | https://chimerical.ca/posts/creating-my-awesome-windows-10-dev-setup/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://chimerical.ca/posts/creating-my-awesome-windows-10-dev-setup/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 id="background"><a href="#background">→</a>Background</h2><p>I recently got the chance to completely reset my Windows 10 machine, and took advantage of the
opportunity to create a dev environment I would love. These were my high-level goals:</p><ul><li>Make WSL my primary dev environment</li><li>Use VSCode as my primary editor</li><li>Have a beautiful terminal</li></ul><h2 id="wsl-%26-vscode"><a href="#wsl-%26-vscode">→</a>WSL &amp; VSCode</h2><p>To achieve this, I started by installing WSL 2. I went with an Ubuntu distro because that's what
I've had the most experience with in the past. You can find instructions on installing WSL and/or
upgrading it to WSL 2 in the <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/install-win10">official
docs</a>.</p><p>Next I installed <a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/">VSCode</a>, and the <a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=ms-vscode-remote.vscode-remote-extensionpack">Remote Development extension
pack</a>
which is where things start to get fun. With this extension pack installed, you can edit files in
the WSL filesystem seamlessly with VSCode.</p><h2 id="windows-terminal"><a href="#windows-terminal">→</a>Windows Terminal</h2><p>To get my beautiful terminal going, I installed <a href="https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/windows-terminal-1-0/">Windows
Terminal</a> (WT), which is an
awesome new terminal experience for Windows from Microsoft.</p><p>Although I wanted WSL to be my primary dev environment, I still wanted working in Windows to be a
nice experience as well, so I wanted to make sure my PowerShell terminal was great too. To get that
going, I also installed the latest <a href="https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powershell/announcing-powershell-7-0/">PowerShell
7</a>.</p><p>Now it was time to setup my WT profiles. By default, WT creates a profile for WSL, PowerShell, cmd,
and Azure Cloud Shell. I'm not interested in using cmd or Azure Cloud Shell, and I'm going to be
using PowerShell 7 instead of PowerShell, so I disabled all but the WSL shell. To do this, simply
add the <code>"hidden": true</code> property to the profiles in the WT settings file (click the dropdown in the
header bar and then Settings or <span><kbd>Ctrl</kbd>+<kbd>,</kbd></span>).</p><h3 id="powershell-wt-profile"><a href="#powershell-wt-profile">→</a>PowerShell WT Profile</h3><p>Now to create my PowerShell 7 profile, I added the following object to the profiles array:</p><pre data-language="json" data-index="0"><code><span><span>{</span></span>
<span><span>  </span><span>"guid"</span><span>: </span><span>"</span><span>{346d54ee-6282-41c7-846a-0a2fa38ff66b}</span><span>"</span><span>,</span></span>
<span><span>  </span><span>"name"</span><span>: </span><span>"</span><span>PowerShell</span><span>"</span><span>,</span></span>
<span><span>  </span><span>"commandline"</span><span>: </span><span>"</span><span>pwsh.exe</span><span>"</span><span>,</span></span>
<span><span>  </span><span>"icon"</span><span>: </span><span>"</span><span>%SystemRoot%</span><span>\\</span><span>Installer</span><span>\\</span><span>{8B844F39-E6EE-486B-BE85-96A485AE2B96}</span><span>\\</span><span>PowerShellExe.ico</span><span>"</span><span>,</span></span>
<span><span>  </span><span>"startingDirectory"</span><span>: </span><span>"</span><span>D:</span><span>\\</span><span>code</span><span>"</span></span>
<span><span>}</span></span></code></pre><p>A few things to note:</p><ul><li>To generate a GUID, you can use the <a href="https://www.guidgenerator.com/online-guid-generator.aspx">Online GUID
Generator</a> website</li><li>I am using the <code>pwsh.exe</code> command instead of <code>powershell.exe</code> to use PowerShell 7</li><li>Follow these steps to find the icon path on your system:<ol><li>Open your Start menu and search for PowerShell 7</li><li>Right click on the app and click "Open file location"</li><li>In the file explorer that opens, right click the shortcut and click "Properties"</li><li>On the "Shortcut" tab, click the "Change Icon..." button and copy the file path</li></ol></li><li>I like to set the starting directory to be where I keep all my projects, and ideally this is near
the root of a drive to keep file paths as short as possible</li></ul><h3 id="ubuntu-wt-profile"><a href="#ubuntu-wt-profile">→</a>Ubuntu WT Profile</h3><p>Since I want to make WSL my primary environment, I moved its profile object to the top of the list
so that it will appear first in the new tab dropdown. Then I replaced the top-level <code>defaultProfile</code>
property with the WSL profile's <code>guid</code> property to make it the profile that is opened automatically
when WT launches.</p><p>Similarly to PowerShell, I wanted the starting directory to be <code>~/code</code>. If you try setting that
directly in the WT configuration, you'll find it doesn't work because WT doesn't know how to resolve
it. You can use an absolute path to get there instead, and you need to use a Windows file path that
WT can understand. You can access a WSL distro's file system from Windows using <code>\\wsl$\&lt;distro&gt;</code>, so, I added this property to the Ubuntu profile object: <code>"startingDirectory": "\\\\wsl$\\Ubuntu\\home\\blake\\code"</code> (where <code>Ubuntu</code> should be replaced with the name of your WSL
distro and <code>blake</code> with your WSL username).</p><h3 id="wt-theme"><a href="#wt-theme">→</a>WT Theme</h3><p>Finally, I wanted to get a new theme for my WT. I decided I would like to use the same colour scheme
as I was using for VSCode at the time, which was the <a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=sdras.night-owl">Night
Owl</a> theme. So (naturally), <a href="https://chimerical.ca/posts/generate-windows-terminal-scheme">I
created</a> a <a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=blake-mealey.generate-wt-scheme">VSCode
plugin</a> to
automatically generate a WT theme.</p><p>Here's what my terminal looks like with the Night Owl theme:</p><p><span>
      <a href="https://chimerical.ca/static/20a8faf4783f0c30ece0bcfc207c1fed/1628f/terminal.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="Windows Terminal with Night Owl" title="Windows Terminal with Night Owl" src="https://chimerical.ca/static/20a8faf4783f0c30ece0bcfc207c1fed/00d43/terminal.png" srcset="https://chimerical.ca/static/20a8faf4783f0c30ece0bcfc207c1fed/63868/terminal.png 250w,https://chimerical.ca/static/20a8faf4783f0c30ece0bcfc207c1fed/0b533/terminal.png 500w,https://chimerical.ca/static/20a8faf4783f0c30ece0bcfc207c1fed/00d43/terminal.png 1000w,https://chimerical.ca/static/20a8faf4783f0c30ece0bcfc207c1fed/1628f/terminal.png 1232w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></p><h2 id="shell-profiles"><a href="#shell-profiles">→</a>Shell Profiles</h2><p>Next up I wanted to get my shell profiles started. We'll iterate on these more later on. Your shell
profile is a script that gets run when the terminal starts which can be used to configure the
current environment. For PowerShell, this will be a PowerShell script and for WSL it will be a bash
script.</p><h3 id="powershell-profile"><a href="#powershell-profile">→</a>PowerShell Profile</h3><p>Let's start with PowerShell again. You can run <code>echo $PROFILE</code> to see if a profile script already
exists. For me it did, and it was located at
<code>C:\Users\blake\Documents\PowerShell\Microsoft.PowerShell_profile.ps1</code>. If it doesn't exist for you,
it's not a big deal. It seems that PowerShell looks in a <a href="https://devblogs.microsoft.com/scripting/understanding-the-six-powershell-profiles/">variety of
places</a> and you
can just create a script in the appropriate place and it should work. Here's what I added to my
profile script:</p><pre data-language="ps1" data-index="1"><code><span><span>#</span><span> C:\Users\blake\Documents\PowerShell\Microsoft.PowerShell_profile.ps1</span></span>
<span></span>
<span><span>Set-Alias</span><span> </span><span>-</span><span>Name editor </span><span>-</span><span>Value nano</span></span>
<span><span>Set-Alias</span><span> </span><span>-</span><span>Name edit </span><span>-</span><span>Value editor</span></span>
<span></span>
<span><span>function</span><span> </span><span>profile_alias</span><span> { editor $PROFILE }</span></span>
<span><span>Set-Alias</span><span> </span><span>-</span><span>Name profile </span><span>-</span><span>Value profile_alias</span></span>
<span></span>
<span><span>function</span><span> </span><span>reload_alias</span><span> { </span><span>&amp;</span><span> $PROFILE }</span></span>
<span><span>Set-Alias</span><span> </span><span>-</span><span>Name reload </span><span>-</span><span>Value reload_alias</span></span></code></pre><p>Let's break this down a bit. First of all, I am creating a couple aliases (<code>editor</code> and <code>edit</code>) for
my in-terminal editor. I prefer to use a terminal editor instead of a GUI editor because it reduces
context switching when working in the terminal, and is much faster to load the file to make a quick
edit. That said, if you wanted to use VSCode, you could replace <code>nano</code> with <code>code</code>.</p><p>The reason I create an alias for my editor command is so that I can change the editor at any time
and not have to change my muscle memory to use the new command. It also means I can create more
aliases that open the editor without having to change all of them if I change my editor.</p><p>Next, I add the <code>profile</code> alias which opens the profile script in my editor (the <code>editor</code> alias is
already coming in handy!). This is great because now I don't need to remember where my profile is
ever again, I can just run <code>profile</code> and can start editing it right away. I also add a <code>reload</code>
alias which simply reloads the shell using the profile script. This lets me use my changes to the
profile script without having to create a new terminal instance.</p><h3 id="bash-profile"><a href="#bash-profile">→</a>Bash Profile</h3><p>Now let's do the same thing for bash. In bash, the profile is a bash script located at <code>~/.bashrc</code>.
By default it contains a lot of stuff already, so I like to add my changes to the bottom of the
script. Here's what I added:</p><pre data-language="bash" data-index="2"><code><span><span>#</span><span> ~/.bashrc</span></span>
<span></span>
<span><span>export</span><span> EDITOR=</span><span>"</span><span>nano</span><span>"</span></span>
<span><span>alias</span><span> editor=</span><span>"</span><span>$EDITOR</span><span>"</span></span>
<span><span>alias</span><span> edit=</span><span>"</span><span>editor</span><span>"</span></span>
<span></span>
<span><span>export</span><span> PROFILE=</span><span>"</span><span>~/.bashrc</span><span>"</span></span>
<span><span>alias</span><span> profile=</span><span>"</span><span>editor </span><span>$PROFILE</span><span>"</span></span>
<span><span>alias</span><span> reload=</span><span>"</span><span>source </span><span>$PROFILE</span><span>"</span></span>
<span></span>
<span><span>alias</span><span> explorer=</span><span>"</span><span>explorer.exe</span><span>"</span></span></code></pre><p>This is very similar to the PowerShell script. First, we create an <code>EDITOR</code> environment variable.
Some Linux programs respect the <code>EDITOR</code> variable, so it's a good idea to set it if you want more
programs to know which editor you want to use. Then we use <code>EDITOR</code> to create our <code>editor</code> and
<code>edit</code> aliases just like before.</p><p>Then, I add the same <code>profile</code> and <code>reload</code> aliases to edit and reload the profile script.</p><p>Finally, I added another alias which maps <code>explorer</code> to <code>explorer.exe</code> which makes it the same
command for opening the Windows File Explorer in WSL as in PowerShell.</p><h2 id="terminal-editor"><a href="#terminal-editor">→</a>Terminal Editor</h2><p>Let's revisit our terminal editor. I started with nano because it's a pretty intuitive and easy to
use editor for terminals. I don't have a lot of terminal editor experience, so I'm not very handy
with Vim, and even nano can be a bit awkward to use.</p><p>So, I did a bit of research to see if there were any editors that had more similar keyboard
shortcuts and navigation to a modern GUI text editor, like VSCode. I found
<a href="https://micro-editor.github.io/">micro</a> which is available cross-platform, which is perfect!</p><h3 id="powershell-editor"><a href="#powershell-editor">→</a>PowerShell Editor</h3><p>Let's install it. In PowerShell, it's most easily installed via <a href="https://scoop.sh/">scoop</a> or
<a href="https://chocolatey.org/">Chocolatey</a>. If you don't have either installed yet I'd highly recommend
you do, as it makes installing programs in Windows a much easier experience. I'm going to use scoop
for the purposes of this guide. With scoop installed, simply run <code>scoop install micro</code>. Now you can
run <code>micro</code> to edit your files.</p><p>Let's update our profile script to use it:</p><pre data-language="ps1" data-index="3"><code><span><span>#</span><span> C:\Users\blake\Documents\PowerShell\Microsoft.PowerShell_profile.ps1</span></span>
<span></span>
<span><span>Set-Alias</span><span> </span><span>-</span><span>Name editor </span><span>-</span><span>Value micro</span></span></code></pre><h3 id="ubuntu-editor"><a href="#ubuntu-editor">→</a>Ubuntu Editor</h3><p>To install on Ubuntu, we can run the install script from the micro website:</p><pre data-language="bash" data-index="4"><code><span><span>curl https://getmic.ro </span><span>|</span><span> bash</span></span></code></pre><p>Now we can update our bash profile to use it:</p><pre data-language="bash" data-index="5"><code><span><span>#</span><span> ~/.bashrc</span></span>
<span></span>
<span><span>export</span><span> EDITOR=</span><span>"</span><span>micro</span><span>"</span></span></code></pre><h3 id="micro-theme"><a href="#micro-theme">→</a>Micro Theme</h3><p>One issue you might notice once you start editing in micro is that it's theme clashes with your WT
theme. One option could be to port your WT theme to micro, but this is quite a bit of work. I found
using the built-in <code>simple</code> theme uses your terminal theme's background colour and seems to fit
quite well for me.</p><p>To do this, you'll have to configure micro for PowerShell and WSL separately. To configure it, open
micro, press <span><kbd>Ctrl</kbd>+<kbd>E</kbd></span> to open the command prompt, then enter the command <code>set colorscheme simple</code>.</p><h2 id="terminal-prompt"><a href="#terminal-prompt">→</a>Terminal Prompt</h2><p>Finally, to make our terminal really pretty, we need to customize the prompt. There's lots of
options out there for this, but the most popular one seems to be
<a href="https://github.com/ohmyzsh/ohmyzsh">ohmyzsh</a> for Bash and
<a href="https://github.com/JanDeDobbeleer/oh-my-posh">oh-my-posh</a> for PowerShell. I'm not a huge fan of
these because in my experience they slow down the terminal to a point which makes me frustrated to
use them, and since they are separate solutions for each environment they must be configured separately.</p><p>Enter <a href="https://starship.rs/">Starship</a>, a "blazing-fast," cross-platform alternative with a
delightfully simple prompt and some awesome customization (with the promise of even more coming in
future releases). Since WSL and PowerShell both have access to the Windows filesystem, we can even
store the Starship configuration in a central place and have both pull from it.</p><h3 id="powershell-starship"><a href="#powershell-starship">→</a>PowerShell Starship</h3><p>To install Starship for PowerShell, we can again use scoop: <code>scoop install starship</code>. To load
starship, we again need to edit our profile (now with our snazzy editor and single-command alias):</p><pre data-language="ps1" data-index="6"><code><span><span>#</span><span> C:\Users\blake\Documents\PowerShell\Microsoft.PowerShell_profile.ps1</span></span>
<span></span>
<span><span>Invoke-Expression</span><span> (</span><span>&amp;</span><span>starship init powershell)</span></span></code></pre><p>Now we can run our <code>reload</code> alias and see the beautiful prompt immediately.</p><h3 id="bash-starship"><a href="#bash-starship">→</a>Bash Starship</h3><p>Installing Starship for …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://chimerical.ca/posts/creating-my-awesome-windows-10-dev-setup/">https://chimerical.ca/posts/creating-my-awesome-windows-10-dev-setup/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://chimerical.ca/posts/creating-my-awesome-windows-10-dev-setup/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25965231</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 01:53:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Siliconpr0n: High Resolution Chip Maps]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 281 | Comments 76 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25964865">thread link</a>) | @lelf
<br/>
January 29, 2021 | https://siliconpr0n.org/map/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://siliconpr0n.org/map/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://siliconpr0n.org/map/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25964865</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:55:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
