<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 08:17:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 08:17:31 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Git commit accepts several message flags (-m) to allow multiline commits]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 96 | Comments 61 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23767866">thread link</a>) | @stefanjudis
<br/>
July 8, 2020 | https://www.stefanjudis.com/today-i-learned/git-commit-accepts-several-message-flags-m-to-allow-multiline-commits/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.stefanjudis.com/today-i-learned/git-commit-accepts-several-message-flags-m-to-allow-multiline-commits/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>When you use git on the command line you might have used the message flag (<code>-m</code>). It allows developers to define commit messages inline when calling git commit. </p>
<pre><code>git commit -m "my commit message"</code></pre><p>I'm not the biggest fan of this approach because I prefer to edit the commit message in vim (which I only use for writing commit messages). It gives me the opportunity to double-check the files I'm committing.</p>
<p>Today I learned that the git commit command accepts multiple message flags. <span role="img" aria-label="Astonished Face" tabindex="0">😲</span></p>
<p>It turns out that you can use the <code>-m</code> option multiple times. <a href="https://git-scm.com/docs/git-commit#Documentation/git-commit.txt--mltmsggt">The git documentation</a> includes the following paragraph:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If multiple -m options are given, their values are concatenated as separate paragraphs</p>
</blockquote>
<p>If you run the following command</p>
<pre><code>git co -m "commit title" -m "commit description"</code></pre><p>it will result in this commit.</p>
<pre><code>Author: stefan judis <stefanjudis @gmail.com="">
Date:   Tue Jul 7 21:53:21 2020 +0200

    commit title

    commit description

 test.txt | 0
 1 file changed, 0 insertions(+), 0 deletions(-)</stefanjudis></code></pre><p>You can use multiple <code>-m</code> flags to create "multiline commits", and I have to admit that this can be very handy in some cases.</p>
<p><em>Edited</em>: Several people pointed out that you can achieve the same commit structure including a title and body (multiple lines) by opening quotes, pressing enter and closing the commit with quotes again.</p>
<pre><code>git commit -m "commit title
&gt;
&gt; commit description"
[master 2fe1ef8] commit title
 1 file changed, 0 insertions(+), 0 deletions(-)
 create mode 100644 test-2.txt</code></pre><hr>
<p>If you want to see this command in action, <a href="https://twitter.com/stefanjudis/status/1280493911434297344?s=20">I shared a short terminal session on Twitter with a little video</a>.</p>
<p>And thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/zcei_GER">Stephan Schneider</a> who shared that little git tip in our company slack. <span role="img" aria-label="undefined" tabindex="0">🙇‍♂️</span></p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.stefanjudis.com/today-i-learned/git-commit-accepts-several-message-flags-m-to-allow-multiline-commits/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23767866</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 07:58:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I got 400 signups with a video of a product that didn’t exist]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 92 | Comments 40 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23764098">thread link</a>) | @semy
<br/>
July 7, 2020 | https://www.lunadio.com/blog/i-got-400-signups-with-a-video-of-a-product-that-didnt-exist/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.lunadio.com/blog/i-got-400-signups-with-a-video-of-a-product-that-didnt-exist/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article><div><p>In this blog post, I would like to show you a practical example of a “fake it till you make it” approach to product development. To my mind, it basically means that you are trying to stay a few steps ahead of your current situation. You are “faking” the idea that you have progressed more, but you actually haven’t. This approach gave me invaluable answers for my product which were hard to get otherwise.</p><h2 id="here-is-my-story">Here is my story:</h2><p>3 years ago, my former manager came to me and told me to do around 1500 banner ads. The company I worked for got new products and they wanted to market them in different countries. We got 6 products in 5 colors and the aim was to create ad banners for 3 countries. The goal was to create 15 formats of each banner ad. It was a nightmare for the graphic department. And I was its team leader.</p><p>When I imagined myself doing 1500 banner ads, I wanted to cry. This scenario of creating thousands of banners could happen easily every month. It is possible to do manually 1500 ad banners, but it is just… too boring! I wanted to be a creator, not a generator.</p><p>I started immediately googling how I can automate the process of creating banners sets. I found some solutions but they were pretty useless. They weren’t flexible enough.</p><p>I decided to create my own solution. I experimented with Photoshop, more specifically with the “Actions” feature there. Basically, the Actions feature was recording my steps in Photoshop. So, I could record how I manually generated banners, then play it again and&nbsp;generate the banners. It was pretty simple: Yet powerful. With this script I created, I was able to automate some parts of the process and help our department to be faster.</p><p>I was interested in a community of graphic designers who had the same problem. With my friend <a href="https://twitter.com/iChangeTheWay" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer">Ivan</a>, I created a landing page in a few hours. <a href="https://twitter.com/tmvst" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer">Tomas</a> sketched the logo in 5 minutes, then we came up with pricing. I created a video of the script and…</p><p>I posted it to a local Facebook designers’ community group.</p><p>And this is what happened:</p><p><span>
      <span></span>
  <picture>
        <source srcset="https://www.lunadio.com/static/95d0df87d8da034d24483b75d2251286/f4429/a85fdc4a-a52b-200a-d884-31ab650ffc31.webp 530w" sizes="(max-width: 530px) 100vw, 530px" type="image/webp">
        <source srcset="https://www.lunadio.com/static/95d0df87d8da034d24483b75d2251286/dd866/a85fdc4a-a52b-200a-d884-31ab650ffc31.png 530w" sizes="(max-width: 530px) 100vw, 530px" type="image/png">
        <img src="https://www.lunadio.com/static/95d0df87d8da034d24483b75d2251286/dd866/a85fdc4a-a52b-200a-d884-31ab650ffc31.png" alt="Bannerium Alpha post to a local Facebook designers’ community group.
">
      </picture>
    </span>
<em>My post to a local Facebook designers’ community group.</em></p><p>I was amazed by how many people had the same problem as us. What was more amazing was that 5 people bought the script. It wasn’t cheap, it cost around 110€. Looking back retrospectively, I think it was… a miracle. It showed me that the problem was there and people were willing to pay for the solution.</p><p>At that time I didn’t know anything about building a product, selling, consumer behavior, or SaaS (Software as a Service). Well, I knew the theory, but just from videos, friends, or lectures. But I didn’t have any tangible experience.</p><h2 id="i-started-with-experimentation">I started with experimentation.</h2><p>I created <strong>a free version of a Photoshop ad generator as a Freemium model,</strong> which could automate only 6 banner formats in contrast to the full version which could automate 20 formats. I gave it for free to people in exchange for getting feedback from them.</p><p>To be honest…</p><p>0 people bought the full version after they tried the free version.</p><p>Frankly put, it failed. I was overly optimistic&nbsp;and thought that the product would do better. On the other hand, It motivated me to ask people what was not working for them and how I could get better. I even gave the full professional freelancers version, which cost 110€, for free in exchange for feedback.</p><p>And what happened?</p><p><strong>Nobody wrote me back.</strong></p><p>It sucked. I didn’t know what to do next.</p><p>At that time I let it go. I didn’t have money to build the product and I didn’t feel that I had enough experience to build the software from scratch.</p><h2 id="after-more-than-a-year-break">After more than a year break</h2><p>After a year and a half, I decided to explore this topic again. I learned new things from Product Management, User Experience design, I was closer to friends who were dealing with product development on a daily basis. So I gave it a try.</p><p>The last script didn’t work for all graphics of banners, it worked only for a few specific graphics. It was good, but once you wanted to generate some complicated banner, this script did not work smoothly. Meanwhile, Photoshop developed a few other features, which changed the game. My game.</p><h2 id="little-technical-context">Little technical context</h2><p>Scripts are technically the easiest to do however, they are quite limited. I decided to learn more about what was feasible in Photoshop. I’d learned about plugins, which seemed like the right way to do things. However, to do a plugin, I needed a front end developer, because I couldn’t code on a sufficient level.</p><p>The problem is that building something with a developer is the most expensive thing to do. And I didn’t even know if people were still interested in the solution. The only thing I knew was that I wanted to improve generating ad banners as much as I could, but how it should work? I had no clue.</p><h2 id="just-do-it">Just do it!</h2><p>But I had something that I believed was powerful. Designer superpower. Really, Sam? Superpower?… Yes, superpower. Let me explain.</p><p>If I want to get rid of generating, what should I do? I could&nbsp; just hit some magic button and everything would be set. But how would it work? It’s time for 🥁 designer superpower, (which I believe is a designers’ toolset).</p><p><span>
      <span></span>
  <picture>
        <source srcset="https://www.lunadio.com/static/8f073372c757154040975d2e8aa7322b/a35e2/1c0d2543-eaab-1927-33e6-ed8ad4e8921b.webp 970w" sizes="(max-width: 970px) 100vw, 970px" type="image/webp">
        <source srcset="https://www.lunadio.com/static/8f073372c757154040975d2e8aa7322b/84019/1c0d2543-eaab-1927-33e6-ed8ad4e8921b.png 970w" sizes="(max-width: 970px) 100vw, 970px" type="image/png">
        <img src="https://www.lunadio.com/static/8f073372c757154040975d2e8aa7322b/84019/1c0d2543-eaab-1927-33e6-ed8ad4e8921b.png" alt="Designer superpower - designers' toolset">
      </picture>
    </span>
<em>Designer superpower - designers<!-- -->’<!-- --> toolset</em></p><p>I realized that I could “fake” the whole plugin and interactions in it. The reason for faking the plugin was that I needed to see if people were still interested in my solution.</p><p>I knew that the demo of the plugin would serve me as a great tool for explaining graphic designers the power of that extension and could give developers a vision of what to build.</p><h2 id="so-i-started">So I started:</h2><p>I created basic wireframes of Photoshop plugin in Sketch.</p><p><span>
      <span></span>
  <picture>
        <source srcset="https://www.lunadio.com/static/45430bd91642a28ebc94468ffd5d724f/a35e2/e4527606-43e4-1ce6-dd0c-6af52bf6536a.webp 970w" sizes="(max-width: 970px) 100vw, 970px" type="image/webp">
        <source srcset="https://www.lunadio.com/static/45430bd91642a28ebc94468ffd5d724f/84019/e4527606-43e4-1ce6-dd0c-6af52bf6536a.png 970w" sizes="(max-width: 970px) 100vw, 970px" type="image/png">
        <img src="https://www.lunadio.com/static/45430bd91642a28ebc94468ffd5d724f/84019/e4527606-43e4-1ce6-dd0c-6af52bf6536a.png" alt="First ketch wireframes of Photoshop plugin Bannerium - Photoshop plugin for generating ads.">
      </picture>
    </span>
<em>Preparation for video.</em></p><p>Then I needed somehow to fake the algorithm of generating banners. So I recorded screen videos and I got rid of some parts. I removed these parts where I needed to manually re-organize components in banners. In the end, these screen recordings looked like a great generating algorithm.</p><p>Now the final part. I needed to connect these parts. For this purpose I used Adobe After Effects.</p><p>And this is the final video which took me 2 weeks to do:</p><p><a href="https://youtu.be/JWApMjQ3-jE" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer">https://youtu.be/JWApMjQ3-jE</a></p><p>I showed this video to friends of mine and they thought that I had learned how to code. At that point, I knew I had done it well.</p><p><strong>🗒Side note:</strong> When you think of that, this is a superpower. With some tools, you can show people (in my case graphic designers) the future them and spark imagination. You can take some ideas and make them look real. Suddenly, all the people can see how your product should behave and what it should do. Isn’t that powerful?</p><p><span>
      <span></span>
  <picture>
        <source srcset="https://www.lunadio.com/static/5ae22898c4f073ca65670bb6bedda258/a35e2/549e8b44-33ab-3699-1a5a-e2fa3ef7862e.webp 970w" sizes="(max-width: 970px) 100vw, 970px" type="image/webp">
        <source srcset="https://www.lunadio.com/static/5ae22898c4f073ca65670bb6bedda258/84019/549e8b44-33ab-3699-1a5a-e2fa3ef7862e.png 970w" sizes="(max-width: 970px) 100vw, 970px" type="image/png">
        <img src="https://www.lunadio.com/static/5ae22898c4f073ca65670bb6bedda258/84019/549e8b44-33ab-3699-1a5a-e2fa3ef7862e.png" alt="Picture showing how to understand your solution. Ultimate goal is to solve the user's problem.">
      </picture>
    </span>
<em>Ultiimate goal of your product is to solve user<!-- -->’<!-- -->s problem</em></p><p>After the video was complete, I created a landing page and posted the plugin into local facebook design/marketing communities</p><p><span>
      <span></span>
  <picture>
        <source srcset="https://www.lunadio.com/static/1d266b5754999b47d6d0fac1a66e9883/30224/bb768f3f-f15f-dae9-1565-9cbe4f966957.webp 547w" sizes="(max-width: 547px) 100vw, 547px" type="image/webp">
        <source srcset="https://www.lunadio.com/static/1d266b5754999b47d6d0fac1a66e9883/bb683/bb768f3f-f15f-dae9-1565-9cbe4f966957.png 547w" sizes="(max-width: 547px) 100vw, 547px" type="image/png">
        <img src="https://www.lunadio.com/static/1d266b5754999b47d6d0fac1a66e9883/bb683/bb768f3f-f15f-dae9-1565-9cbe4f966957.png" alt="Facebook post with faked video. I got valuable 400 signups">
      </picture>
    </span>
<em>Facebook post with video which gave me 400 signups</em></p><p>I added my <a href="https://www.bannerium.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer">landing page</a> in the post, then I shared it to other groups/forums and I got 400 signups.</p><p>I even got some deal with a design agency, which told me that they would give us some money to develop a plugin. Moreover, I even had 2 meetings with them. Just based on the video.</p><p>In the end, nothing came from this deal. That was reasonable. Here is why: The truth was, that I had just released the video. I didn’t have anything else. Just some parts connected with duct tape. At that time, I had no clue how close we could get with the real code.</p><p><strong>💡Lesson learned</strong></p><p>Showing a “fake” video is powerful for sharing a vision and testing if there is a need for a solution. On the other hand, if the video is too ambitious, people will take it as a norm and will base their expectations on the video. If the real product doesn’t match the video afterward, they will probably be unsatisfied because the product is&nbsp;incomplete. This thing happened to me when I had a call with a user during beta testing. She expected that the complete product should work as it was on the video. So sometimes it is better to be realistic. Otherwise, you will create unhappy initial users. But I believe it is a trade-off and you need to count on that.</p><p>Once I saw that the product was still in demand I found a programmer called Petr and we started with the development of the plugin. The video was also a great tool for how to communicate what I wanted to achieve. Of course, video showed happy path&nbsp;and I needed to design “what if” scenarios, afterwards. But it served my expectations&nbsp;perfectly.</p><p>Then we went through beta testing, which 50 people joined. Nowadays the <a href="https://bannerium.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer">product is live.&nbsp;</a></p><h2 id="summary">Summary:</h2><h3 id="a-designer-toolset-is-a-superpower-you-can-easily-create-something-that-was-not-on-the-market-before-and-validate-your-idea-just-in-a-week">A Designer toolset is a superpower. You can easily create something that was not on the market before and validate your idea. Just in a week.</h3><ul><li>Creating a video is a powerful tool but if it is too ambitious, you will create unhappy first users.</li><li>Count on the trade-off that some people will think that product is actually working, but are unsure. I suggest you create beta testers out of them. It can bring you value afterward, <a href="https://www.lunadio.com/blog/4-cognitive-bias-examples-you-should-be-aware-of-as-a-designer" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer">as I wrote in my previous article.</a></li></ul><p>After this example, I would use a fake demo of the product more sensitively. I still believe it can save you a lot of money, help you validate your idea and get you traction in your idea.</p><p>I hope this example will show designers how powerful they are. Furthermore, it will show non-designers what they can achieve with designers onboard.</p><p>If you are interested in my future content about building products through designer eyes, feel free to join the newsletter below.</p></div></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.lunadio.com/blog/i-got-400-signups-with-a-video-of-a-product-that-didnt-exist/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23764098</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 21:09:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Help Message for Shell Scripts]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 412 | Comments 106 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23763166">thread link</a>) | @reconquestio
<br/>
July 7, 2020 | https://samizdat.dev/help-message-for-shell-scripts/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://samizdat.dev/help-message-for-shell-scripts/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">
<article>
    <p>Have you ever thought how good it would be to have a help message for your shell script
that you wrote a month ago and already forgot what it is supposed to do?</p>
<p>Yeah, there is always a way to show a message using cat (meow) or a bunch of echo
calls.</p>
<p>But there is a neat trick.</p>
<p>Add your message with all the required information on top of your file, just right
after the shebang.</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash"><span>#!/bin/bash
</span><span></span><span>###</span>
<span>### my-script — does one thing well</span>
<span>###</span>
<span>### Usage:</span>
<span>###   my-script &lt;input&gt; &lt;output&gt;</span>
<span>###</span>
<span>### Options:</span>
<span>###   &lt;input&gt;   Input file to read.</span>
<span>###   &lt;output&gt;  Output file to write. Use '-' for stdout.</span>
<span>###   -h        Show this message.</span>
</code></pre></div><p>Halfway done, now need to get this message in runtime with sed.</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">help<span>()</span> <span>{</span>
    sed -rn <span>'s/^### ?//;T;p'</span> <span>"</span><span>$0</span><span>"</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div><p><code>$0</code> means a filename of a file that is being executed.</p>
<p>A bit about the magic that is going here:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>s</code> — stands for substitute the following pattern;</li>
<li><code>/</code> — keyword to define start/end of the pattern;</li>
<li><code>^### ?</code> — match a string starting with ### and an optional space after;</li>
<li><code>//</code> — there could be something between the slashes, but since nothing is here, replace
the pattern with an empty string;</li>
<li><code>T</code> — Jumps to the end of sed-script if no s/// has done a successful substitution;</li>
<li><code>p</code> — Prints the result of the substitution.</li>
</ul>
<p>Now just call the <code>help</code> function if an arg <code>-h</code> or no args passed.</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash"><span>if</span> <span>[[</span> <span>$#</span> <span>==</span> <span>0</span> <span>]]</span> <span>||</span> <span>[[</span> <span>"</span><span>$1</span><span>"</span> <span>==</span> <span>"-h"</span> <span>]]</span><span>;</span> <span>then</span>
    <span>help</span>
    <span>exit</span> <span>1</span>
<span>fi</span>
</code></pre></div><p>Hope it helps, cheers!</p>
<p>Full gist is available on GitHub: <a href="https://gist.github.com/kovetskiy/a4bb510595b3a6b17bfd1bd9ac8bb4a5">https://gist.github.com/kovetskiy/a4bb510595b3a6b17bfd1bd9ac8bb4a5</a></p>
</article>

        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://samizdat.dev/help-message-for-shell-scripts/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23763166</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 19:40:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pattern Matching, Racial Diversity and the Hypocrisy of Big Tech Media]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 130 | Comments 82 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23762876">thread link</a>) | @OoTheNigerian
<br/>
July 7, 2020 | https://oonwoye.com/2020/07/06/diversity-and-big-tech-media/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://oonwoye.com/2020/07/06/diversity-and-big-tech-media/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<h2><em>It’s Time to Watch the Watchmen – The Diversity Report of TechCrunch, Recode, The Information, Business Insider and Protocol.</em></h2>



<div><figure><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/QTSx6MgSrYd5pwZwobk89Xec66X0GkNbYOHlVXsLtIl7k72caVj3WcuYrYU5eWrBc_LqSI2hj7n9-Z-5crONenrK8bPF6nQjAbPYgsXtnAppymJwHTVpYzXR0OR6M7FcKGRnjhwV" alt="" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><figcaption><strong>The Big Dogs of Big Tech Media.</strong> <br>Clockwise from top left: Lessin of The Information, Swisher of Recode (Vox), Panzarino of TechCrunch, Shontell of Business Insider and Pierce of Protocol are Editors-in-Chief of the most influential tech publications in the world.</figcaption></figure></div>



<h2>Prelude</h2>



<p><em>I have been writing about </em><a href="https://oonwoye.com/2010/04/05/black-founders/"><em>Diversity in Tech for over a decade now</em></a><em> – a long time. However, my self-published posts have never really got the audience it was targeted at, which is, the Silicon Valley Main Street. This time around, I wanted to do something different with regard to distribution.&nbsp;</em></p>



<p><em>Since I completed this post over two weeks ago, I’ve hawked it as an Op-Ed to </em><strong><em>ALL</em></strong><em> main street US (Tech) media – 22 of them. Sadly, but unsurprisingly and understandably, I’ve had no takers. It is a big request to ask anyone, including journalists, to give a dissenting voice an audience, so I have decided to self-publish again, but this time around, I hope the primary intended audience gets to see it and the conversation happens. <strong>Abeg (please), share it</strong> as you wish me luck holding these very powerful people to account.</em></p>



<h2>Introduction</h2>



<p>No thanks to the brutal execution of George Floyd and more importantly, thanks to the persistence of protesters, the conversation about institutional racism in various parts of American life is back to the fore and has been sustained. The tech industry has not been exempted.</p>



<p>As with previous cycles, it has cast blame towards the typical suspects: Big Tech and Venture Capital. And as with previous conversation cycles, one key player in the diversity deficient tech world is wriggling away unscathed, yet again. Silicon Valley Big Tech Media.</p>



<h2>Pattern Matching in Tech</h2>



<p><em>Pattern matching</em> is a colloquial terminology in the tech industry that refers to the propensity for established players in tech e.g. Venture Capitalists, taking superficial patterns of successful founders (young white boys who have dropped out of Stanford or Harvard) and using them to determine future investment decisions.</p>



<blockquote><p>“I can be tricked by anyone who looks like Mark Zuckerberg”</p><cite><em>Paul Graham (According to The New York Times)</em></cite></blockquote>



<p>Though <a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/tricked.html">eventually clarified by Paul Graham</a>, that attributed quote articulately captures the spirit of Pattern Matching. Since how one “looks” is one of the obvious patterns one can observe in a human, it is believed that pattern matching disproportionally affects “people of colour” (why do we use this term?).</p>



<p>I have no problem with pattern matching. In psychology it is known as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pattern_recognition_(psychology)">pattern recognition</a>, which is natural and critical for survival. It is how human beings recognise things and make vital decisions quickly, with little data.</p>



<p>My first memory of Pattern Matching was while playing football (the real one) as a kid. The guys with the bow-legged swagger, wearing boots and a shin guard were always picked first. It was almost automatic because they looked like talented footballers. And that’s how I learned to pick my teams. After missing out on some straight legged barefoot talents and picking several kitted-out clowns, I adjusted and used more sensible parameters.</p>



<p>I learned something from that though: Pattern matching is all well and good until it receives contradicting data. It’s all about the data.</p>



<h2>The Role of Big Tech Media in Pattern Matching</h2>



<p>In the past decade, Big Tech Media has rightfully shone the light on racial inequality in the ranks of Big Corporations and Venture Capital in the tech industry. The Diversity Reports — as they are known, of Big Tech and VC have been published routinely.</p>



<p>The media are very powerful. It is through them we learn and understand the world beyond ourselves. Their importance and power in shaping opinions cannot be overstated as they are very key in providing the data which influences patterns that lead to decisions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In Tech, when it comes to personnel, a lot of that data comes in the form of presence. The Big Tech Media controls it all via narrative and coverage in their publications and mega conferences. It is through the media that every player – VCs, Tech Executives, Founders etc learn about the tech world that exists outside of their immediate spheres.</p>



<p>However, when it comes to the diversity in tech debate, I wonder: how have Big Tech Media, the primary opinion shapers of the tech industry, escaped any scrutiny? Then it hit me: when you are busy pointing your torch at others, you forget to point it at yourself.</p>



<p>Since Big Tech Media remains a critical piece if we are to rejig the data to alter diversity-deficient patterns in tech, it’s high-time we shone the light on Big Tech Media.</p>



<p><em>[RANDOM: Watching the film </em><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt4846340/"><em>Hidden Figures</em></a><em> made me almost cry. I had </em><strong><em>absolutely no idea</em></strong><em> that in the 60s, there were Black women mathematicians and programmers who were good enough to work for the NASA Space Program. Imagine if this was always common knowledge. I can only imagine how many more black folks it would have influenced to take up a career in Computer Science and Technology].</em></p>



<h2>Diversity Report of (Silicon Valley) Big Tech Media</h2>



<p>In 2015, I looked at <a href="https://oonwoye.com/2015/10/15/where-are-the-black-tech-foundersexecutive-speakers-at-major-tech-conferences/">the racial makeup of the largest tech conferences in the world</a>. The results were damning. I wondered how these organisers could be so oblivious. It then occurred to me to check out the people making these decisions, and it was clear why they were colour blind; they didn’t have the right ‘lenses’ i.e., makeup of the editorial/media team, to notice the absence of certain colours.</p>



<p>In this report card, I will look at the racial diversity makeup of both speaker line-ups and the editorial teams of Big Tech Media – who are mostly in Silicon Valley, and contrast their 2015 with today.</p>



<h2>The Candidates</h2>



<h3><strong>TechCrunch</strong></h3>



<p>TechCrunch, owned by AOL/Verizon has been the Big Dog of tech startup chronicling and commentary since 2005. More so, they host arguably the largest and most influential startup conference called Disrupt. I have followed TechCrunch since 2007 and experienced the startup evolution through them.</p>



<h3><strong>Recode</strong></h3>



<p>In the past decade, Recode has evolved from being All Things Digital at WSJ to being Independent to now being a unit at Vox Media. One constant throughout its evolution has been the very formidable Kara Swisher, who is arguably the single most influential person in Big Tech Media.&nbsp;</p>



<h3><strong>The Information</strong></h3>



<p>This subscription-based tech publication is high up the list in shaping opinion among Venture Capitalists in Silicon Valley. It was started by Jessica Lessin who is a formidable reporter and an Alumnus of WSJ. They have a <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/vc-diversity-index">VC Diversity Index</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<h3><strong>Business Insider</strong></h3>



<p>Based in New York and founded by the great Henry Blodget, Business Insider is a top 3 tech voice in the tech industry.</p>



<h3><strong>Protocol</strong></h3>



<p>Backed by a bunch of heavyweights, this publication launched this year with a lot of panache.&nbsp;</p>



<p>How well have they done?</p>



<h2>Racial Diversity Report Card of Major US/Silicon Valley Tech Media</h2>



<figure><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/Zd5PvX7kGrFnUadYJgep593NbaDVe1T6PYMlXsDtanuGqwQyV7qBIsH9SUo8e2vdWelOEfqmzDYcv8VyV-U909zgRSOcL3c2J7QQgNrsEr5CQbZ3zh6iNZdeuXbYdHwXDqIa8pzG" alt="" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><figcaption>The diversity report of Big Tech Media</figcaption></figure>



<p><a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1l6Bmj3M1sgqCR3PijCsyoYF5OrovGUDFEEujYSItZb0/edit?usp=sharing">Here is the data for this table</a> in spreadsheet format and links to sources.</p>







<p>It is good to highlight problems but better to proffer solutions. But first, do these people recognise that there is a problem? Do they want to solve it?&nbsp;</p>



<p>In 2015 when I wrote my previous post, I had the impression some did. In my <a href="https://twitter.com/OoTheNigerian/status/738076047539896321">Twitter engagement with Kara Swisher</a> after my first post, Aunty Kara gave the patronising response by referencing “the adept use of social media” as a representation of Black in Tech, I offered to engage privately (I threw in my<a href="https://twitter.com/OoTheNigerian/status/802151006754795520"> beer diplomacy</a> for good measure). It came to nought.</p>



<p><em>[Shalaye (Explanation): Aunty Kara took me up on the offer. As agreed, I reached out on 3 subsequent trips to the US and Silicon Valley. After sending about half a dozen emails, initially replied with excuses, Kara went cold and stopped responding. She is not the first Silicon Valley person whose Twitter (public) position contrasts with their private ones, so I haven’t taken it personally. I’d be more than happy to grab that beer if she’s open to it]</em></p>



<p>If Big Tech companies especially the media wish to change things, they have to first stop being colour-blind and get competent people who have eyes for the blind spots. A deliberate, sincere effort will yield good fruit.</p>



<p><strong>If you are a privileged person in the tech industry who wants to be a true “ally” and see things improve, here are some actionable things to do:&nbsp;</strong></p>



<ol><li>If you are on yet another panel and you notice the absence of accomplished Black tech players, speak up. Make recommendations. I am happy for you to ask me if your black network isn’t that vast. See Appendix (<strong>Note:</strong> Black folks have great competence about things outside the diversity topic).</li><li>If you are a VC and you are in on a good deal, try to work with the founder and carve out an allocation for those good black investors that aren’t as opportune to have your network. We all know the deal flow is the <em>koko (main thing).</em> If you want to help, share the deal.</li><li>If you are recruiting for a senior role in your executive team or board, you can take a book from the NFL beyond Colin Kaepernick’s brave kneeling protest; the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rooney_Rule">Rooney Rule</a>. Just make sure you have a qualified black person in your interview shortlist. That’s not too much of an ask.&nbsp;</li></ol>



<p>I wrote in an email to my white founder friend recently: <em>I see many organisations “fighting” systemic racism by opening their cheque books. A donation here, a freebie there. It makes them feel good, perhaps. It’s like a retweet but with money.</em></p>



<p>So, decide if you want to show concern or effect change. I prefer both.</p>







<ol><li>Every company (including Big Tech Media) has the prerogative to invite or cover anyone they like. However, the proprietors of Tech Media cannot play watchmen and feign concern about the diversity in tech debate while their actions are in direct contrast.</li><li>In this post, I focused on these …</li></ol></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://oonwoye.com/2020/07/06/diversity-and-big-tech-media/">https://oonwoye.com/2020/07/06/diversity-and-big-tech-media/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://oonwoye.com/2020/07/06/diversity-and-big-tech-media/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23762876</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 19:08:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Analysis of all YouTube trending videos in US for 2019]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 81 | Comments 38 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23762180">thread link</a>) | @ammar_x
<br/>
July 7, 2020 | https://ammar-alyousfi.com/2020/youtube-trending-videos-analysis-2019-us | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ammar-alyousfi.com/2020/youtube-trending-videos-analysis-2019-us">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p><img src="https://ammar-alyousfi.com/assets/images/2020/yta2-cover.png"></p>

<p>Around 1.5 years ago, I did an <a href="https://www.kaggle.com/ammar111/youtube-trending-videos-analysis">analysis of YouTube trending videos</a> in US. That analysis was performed on trending videos of some months in 2017 and 2018. The analysis received a lot of interest on <a href="https://www.kaggle.com/ammar111/youtube-trending-videos-analysis">Kaggle</a> and <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/datascience/comments/9kpmcn/i_analyzed_more_than_40000_youtube_trending/">Reddit</a>; I also received some emails praising the work done. That was 1.5 years ago.</p>

<p><strong>Today</strong>, I present an improved and expanded version of that analysis. This analysis is more advanced and contains new interesting elements. In this analysis, <strong>All trending videos for the whole year of 2019</strong> were analyzed (More than <strong>70,000</strong> videos).</p>

<p>Titles, descriptions, thumbnails, tags, views, likes/dislikes, and comments were all analyzed to produce the results shown in this post. Continue reading to know more about the analysis and the data or you can <a href="#analysis-res">jump directly to the results section</a>.</p>

<ul id="markdown-toc">
  <li><a href="#what-are-youtube-trending-videos" id="markdown-toc-what-are-youtube-trending-videos">What are YouTube Trending Videos?</a></li>
  <li><a href="#goals-of-the-analysis" id="markdown-toc-goals-of-the-analysis">Goals of the Analysis</a></li>
  <li><a href="#tools-used" id="markdown-toc-tools-used">Tools Used</a>    <ul>
      <li><a href="#code-used" id="markdown-toc-code-used">Code Used</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#data-source" id="markdown-toc-data-source">Data Source</a></li>
  <li><a href="#data-size-and-description" id="markdown-toc-data-size-and-description">Data Size and Description</a></li>
  <li><a href="#analysis-results" id="markdown-toc-analysis-results">Analysis Results</a>    <ul>
      <li><a href="#trending-videos-and-views" id="markdown-toc-trending-videos-and-views">Trending Videos and Views</a>        <ul>
          <li><a href="#how-many-views-videos-had-when-they-first-became-trending" id="markdown-toc-how-many-views-videos-had-when-they-first-became-trending">How Many Views Videos Had When they First Became Trending?</a></li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li><a href="#trending-for-30-days" id="markdown-toc-trending-for-30-days">Trending for 30 days!</a></li>
      <li><a href="#trending-videos-titles" id="markdown-toc-trending-videos-titles">Trending Videos Titles</a>        <ul>
          <li><a href="#number-of-fully-uppercase-words-in-titles" id="markdown-toc-number-of-fully-uppercase-words-in-titles">Number of Fully-Uppercase Words in Titles</a></li>
          <li><a href="#what-are-the-most-common-words-in-video-titles" id="markdown-toc-what-are-the-most-common-words-in-video-titles">What are the Most Common Words in Video Titles?</a></li>
          <li><a href="#what-are-the-most-common-2-grams-in-video-titles" id="markdown-toc-what-are-the-most-common-2-grams-in-video-titles">What are the Most Common 2-Grams in Video Titles?</a></li>
          <li><a href="#titles-lengths" id="markdown-toc-titles-lengths">Titles Lengths</a></li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li><a href="#trending-channels" id="markdown-toc-trending-channels">Trending Channels</a></li>
      <li><a href="#trending-videos-categories" id="markdown-toc-trending-videos-categories">Trending Videos Categories</a></li>
      <li><a href="#when-were-trending-videos-published" id="markdown-toc-when-were-trending-videos-published">When were Trending Videos Published?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#trending-videos-and-comments" id="markdown-toc-trending-videos-and-comments">Trending Videos and Comments</a>        <ul>
          <li><a href="#how-many-comments-videos-had-when-they-first-became-trending" id="markdown-toc-how-many-comments-videos-had-when-they-first-became-trending">How Many Comments Videos Had When they First Became Trending?</a></li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li><a href="#trending-videos-and-likes-and-dislikes" id="markdown-toc-trending-videos-and-likes-and-dislikes">Trending Videos and Likes.. and Dislikes</a></li>
      <li><a href="#how-long-does-it-take-a-video-to-become-trending" id="markdown-toc-how-long-does-it-take-a-video-to-become-trending">How Long Does it Take a Video to Become Trending?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#trending-videos-descriptions" id="markdown-toc-trending-videos-descriptions">Trending Videos Descriptions</a>        <ul>
          <li><a href="#how-long-is-the-description" id="markdown-toc-how-long-is-the-description">How Long is the Description?</a></li>
          <li><a href="#most-common-words-in-trending-videos-descriptions" id="markdown-toc-most-common-words-in-trending-videos-descriptions">Most Common Words in Trending Videos Descriptions</a></li>
          <li><a href="#does-trending-videos-descriptions-contain-hashtags" id="markdown-toc-does-trending-videos-descriptions-contain-hashtags">Does Trending Videos Descriptions Contain Hashtags?</a></li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li><a href="#trending-videos-tags" id="markdown-toc-trending-videos-tags">Trending Videos Tags</a>        <ul>
          <li><a href="#most-common-words-in-trending-videos-tags" id="markdown-toc-most-common-words-in-trending-videos-tags">Most Common Words in Trending Videos Tags</a></li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li><a href="#correlations-of-trending-videos" id="markdown-toc-correlations-of-trending-videos">Correlations of Trending Videos</a></li>
      <li><a href="#what-are-the-most-used-colors-in-trending-videos-thumbnails" id="markdown-toc-what-are-the-most-used-colors-in-trending-videos-thumbnails">What are the Most Used Colors in Trending Videos Thumbnails?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#whats-inside-trending-videos-thumbnails" id="markdown-toc-whats-inside-trending-videos-thumbnails">What’s Inside Trending Videos Thumbnails?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#conclusion" id="markdown-toc-conclusion">Conclusion</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>
<h2 id="what-are-youtube-trending-videos">What are YouTube Trending Videos?</h2>

<p>YouTube, as you know, is the most popular and most used video platform in the world today. YouTube has <a href="https://www.youtube.com/feed/trending">a list of <strong>trending videos</strong></a>. I’ll quote the description of trending videos from <a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/7239739?hl=en">YouTube itself</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Trending helps viewers see what’s happening on YouTube and in the world. Trending aims to surface videos that a wide range of viewers would find interesting. Some trends are predictable, like a new song from a popular artist or a new movie trailer. Others are surprising, like a viral video. Trending isn’t personalized and displays the same list of trending videos in each country to all users.</p>

  <p>The list of trending videos is updated roughly every 15 minutes. With each update, videos may move up, down, or stay in the same position in the list.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="goals-of-the-analysis">Goals of the Analysis</h2>

<p>The main goal of the analysis is to find interesting facts and patterns by exploring the data and by using effective visualizations.</p>

<p>Some of the questions the analysis will answer:</p>

<ul>
  <li>What is the average/minimum/maximum view count for 2019’s trending videos?</li>
  <li>Which videos appeared on the trending list the most (because some videos might appear on the trending list for more than one day)?</li>
  <li>What are the most common words in the titles/descriptions/tags of trending videos?</li>
  <li>What are the title lengths of the trending videos? What is the average/minimum/maximum title length?</li>
  <li>Which channels have more trending videos than others?</li>
  <li>What are the top categories of trending videos? Are “Entertainment” videos more trending than “Gaming” videos?</li>
  <li>How many views/comments/likes trending videos have when first appearing on the trending list?</li>
  <li>How many days are between publishing a video and its first appearance on the trending list?</li>
  <li>How long are the descriptions/tags of trending videos?</li>
  <li>What are the most used colors in the thumbnails of trending videos?</li>
  <li>What are the most common objects in the thumbnails of trending videos? (Running AI object detection algorithm on all thumbnails)</li>
</ul>

<p>The analysis covers much more topics as you will see soon.</p>



<p>This analysis was performed using Python and a powerful group of Python libraries including Pandas, Matplotlib, NLTK, ImageAI, WordCloud, and more.</p>

<p>The analysis were performed in a Jupyter Notebook.</p>

<h3 id="code-used">Code Used</h3>

<p>You can find all the code used for this analysis in a Jupyter notebook <a href="https://github.com/ammar1y/YouTube-Trending-Videos-Analysis-2019">on this link</a>. Feel free to read the code and re-use it however you want. Also note that the notebook contains more analyses than the ones shown here in this post, so if you want to see everything, refer to the notebook after you finish reading this post.</p>

<h2 id="data-source">Data Source</h2>

<p>The data used in this analysis was retrieved using YouTube API. A script was scheduled to run <strong>each day throughout 2019 and fetch data from YouTube API about the trending videos of that day</strong>. The script would then process the data received from YouTube and store them in text files.</p>

<p>The scraping script is not my work. It can be found on Github: <a href="https://github.com/mitchelljy/Trending-YouTube-Scraper"> Trending-YouTube-Scraper</a>. I put the script on a AWS EC2 instance and scheduled it—using Crontab—to run every day at a specific time.</p>

<p>After 2019 ended, I connected to the AWS instance using FileZilla application and downloaded all the data produced by the script. There was a file for each day of 2019. To perform the analysis, I needed to process the data in order to merge the files into a single CSV file.</p>

<p>If you want to <strong>download the data used in this analysis</strong> which describes 2019's trending videos in the United States, you can buy it securely on Gumroad <u><strong><a href="https://gum.co/qEzKK" target="_blank">on this link</a></strong></u> or by using the button below. Along with United States, you'll also get trending-videos data for United Kingdom, Canada, Denmark, Malaysia, Saudi Arabia, and other countries as well.</p>

<h2 id="data-size-and-description">Data Size and Description</h2>

<p><strong>In this post, United-States trending videos will be analyzed</strong>, which constitute a total of <strong>72,994</strong> videos. YouTube usually place 200 videos in the trending list each day which would mean that we should have 73,000 (365 x 200) videos. We have 72,994. This is probably because on a few days, the number of Trending videos was slightly less than 200.</p>

<p>So we have data on 72,994 trending videos to analyze. On YouTube, <strong>the same video might appear on the trending list for many days. This means that the 72,994 videos are not unique videos</strong>. In fact, among the 72,994 videos, <strong>we have 11,177 unique videos</strong>.</p>

<p>In other words, 11,177 videos showed on the trending list throughout 2019. Some of them might have stayed on the list for 10 days, some for 20 days, etc. We will see later in the analysis more info about this.</p>

<p>The following table shows an example of <strong>the data that we have for each video</strong>:</p>



<p><img src="https://ammar-alyousfi.com/assets/images/2020/yta2-data.png" alt=""></p>

<p><br>
As we can see, we have the ID of the video which is a unique value for the video across YouTube (No two videos have the same ID). We also have the title of the video, its publishing date and time, the channel that published it, its category, and its description and tags. We also have the number of the views, likes, dislikes, and comments of the video. There are also a few more data shown in the table.</p>

<p>We can see that there is a field named “trending_date”. This field specifies the date on which this video was trending. As we said earlier, the same video might appear on the trending-videos list for more than one day. This means that we might find another record in the data for the same video ID but with different “trending_date” and maybe different number of views, comments, likes, etc. (because those numbers are likely to increase from one day to another).</p>



<h2 id="analysis-results">Analysis Results</h2>

<p>Now let’s start the best part of this post, let’s see the analysis results.</p>

<p><span id="note-uniq"></span><strong>Please note</strong> that for the following analyses, <strong>unless otherwise stated</strong>, we applied the analysis on all of the <strong>72,994</strong> trending videos, <strong>not</strong> on the unique trending videos only. The reasoning behind this is that we are interested in videos considered trending by YouTube. So if a video is considered trending for 3 days, then we believe that it has more trending power and more trending characteristics than a video that was trending for 1 day only; thus, it should have more weight. So <strong>we include the 3 occurrences of that video in the analysis</strong>.</p>

<p>For some analyses, considering only unique videos is more appropriate. When that is the case, you will see a note telling you about that.</p>

<h3 id="trending-videos-and-views">Trending Videos and Views</h3>

<p><strong>The Trending Video with the Highest Number of Views</strong> is a song by BTS band named “Boy With Luv”. The video was published on 12/April/2019 and on 23/04/2019, it appeared on the trending list with 195,376,667 views which is the highest number of views a trending video had in 2019.</p>

<p>In the table below, you can see <strong>the top 3 trending videos based on the number of views</strong>. These trending videos had views when they appeared on the trending list more than any other trending video. This table was produced by considering unique trending videos only (<a href="#note-uniq">For more</a>).</p>



<p><img src="https://ammar-alyousfi.com/assets/images/2020/yta2-top-views.png" alt=""></p>



<p>And now we will look at the distribution of views for trending videos. The histogram below shows this distribution:</p>



<p><img src="https://ammar-alyousfi.com/assets/images/2020/yta2-view-dist.png" alt=""></p>



<p><em>Notice that the y-axis is <a href="https://www.mathsisfun.com/definitions/logarithmic-scale.html">log scaled</a>. It is 10, 100, 1000… not 10, 20, 30…</em></p>

<p>We can see that the vast majority of trending videos had less than 20 million views when they became trending. In fact, when they became trending, around <strong>94% of trending videos had less than 10 million views</strong> and around 99.9% had less than 100 million views.</p>

<p>Now, we might ask: <strong>What are the trending videos with the least amount of views?</strong> The table below shows the 3 trending videos with the lowest number of views when appearing on the trending list. This table was produced by considering unique trending videos only (<a href="#note-uniq">For more</a>).</p>



<p><img src="https://ammar-alyousfi.com/assets/images/2020/yta2-least-views.png" alt=""></p>



<p>You can see that these three videos appeared on the trending list on the same day they were published on. Maybe they received a high number of views in the first few hours after they were published which sent them to the trending list.</p>

<h4 id="how-many-views-videos-had-when-they-first-became-trending">How Many Views Videos Had When they First Became Trending?</h4>

<p>We mentioned earlier that there were many videos that appeared on the trending list on more than one day. We now want to consider the first appearance only of each video. We …</p></div></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://ammar-alyousfi.com/2020/youtube-trending-videos-analysis-2019-us">https://ammar-alyousfi.com/2020/youtube-trending-videos-analysis-2019-us</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ammar-alyousfi.com/2020/youtube-trending-videos-analysis-2019-us</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23762180</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 18:07:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Dune: The Battle for Arrakis – Extended Reference (2003)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 170 | Comments 96 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23762027">thread link</a>) | @tosh
<br/>
July 7, 2020 | http://ledmeister.com/dunexref.htm | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://ledmeister.com/dunexref.htm">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://ledmeister.com/dunexref.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23762027</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 17:54:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Google Common Lisp style guide]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 188 | Comments 86 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23761346">thread link</a>) | @fanf2
<br/>
July 7, 2020 | https://google.github.io/styleguide/lispguide.xml | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://google.github.io/styleguide/lispguide.xml">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div title="Google Common Lisp Style Guide">


<p>

Revision 1.28
</p>


<address>
Robert Brown
</address>
<address>
  <a href="mailto:tunes@google.com">FranÃ§ois-RenÃ© Rideau</a>
</address>

<address>
   In memoriam Dan Weinreb
</address>

<p>
<cite>Patterns mean "I have run out of language."</cite> â€” Rich Hickey
</p>


<overview>
<category title="Important Note">
  <stylepoint title="Note: Displaying Hidden Details in this Guide">
     <summary>
       This style guide contains many details
       that are initially hidden from view.
       They are marked by the triangle icon, which you see here on your left.
       Click it now. You should see "Hooray" appear below.
     </summary>
     
       <p>
        Hooray!  Now you know you can expand points to get more details.
        Alternatively, there's an "expand all" at the top of this document.
       </p>
     
  </stylepoint>
</category>
<category title="Background">
  <p>
    Common Lisp is a powerful multiparadigm programming language.
    With great power comes great responsibility.
  </p>
  <p>
    This guide recommends formatting and stylistic choices
    designed to make your code easier for other people to understand.
    For those internal applications and free software libraries that
    we develop at Google,
    you should keep within these guidelines when making changes.
    Note however that each project has its own rules and customs
    that complement or override these general guidelines;
    the speed-oriented QPX low fare search engine notably
    has a very different style and feel from the QRes reservation system.
  </p>
  <p>
    If you're writing Common Lisp code outside Google,
    we invite you to consider these guidelines.
    You may find some of them useful
    where they don't conflict with other priorities you have.
    We welcome remarks and constructive feedback
    on how to improve our guide, and
    on what alternate styles work for you and why.
  </p>
  
  <p>
    This guide is not a Common Lisp tutorial.
    For basic information about the language, please consult
    <a href="http://www.gigamonkeys.com/book/">Practical Common Lisp</a>.
    For a language reference, please consult the
    <a href="http://www.lispworks.com/documentation/HyperSpec/Front/index.htm">Common Lisp HyperSpec</a>.
    For more detailed style guidance, take (with a pinch of salt)
    a look at Peter Norvig and Kent Pitman's
    <a href="http://norvig.com/luv-slides.ps">style guide</a>.
  </p>
</category>
</overview>
<category title="Meta-Guide">
  <stylepoint title="Must, Should, May, or Not">
    <summary>
      Each guideline's level of importance is indicated
      by use of the following keywords and phrases, adapted from
      <a href="https://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc2119.txt">RFC 2119</a>.
    </summary>
    
      <table>
        <tbody><tr>
          <th>MUST</th>
          <td>
            <p>
              This word, or the terms "REQUIRED" or "SHALL",
              means that the guideline is an absolute requirement.
              You must ask permission to violate a MUST.
            </p>
          </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <th>MUST NOT</th>
          <td>
            <p>
              This phrase, or the phrase "SHALL NOT",
              means that the guideline is an absolute prohibition.
              You must ask permission to violate a MUST NOT.
            </p>
          </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <th>SHOULD</th>
          <td>
            <p>
              This word, or the adjective "RECOMMENDED", means that
              there may exist valid reasons in particular circumstances
              to ignore the demands of the guideline, but
              the full implications must be understood and carefully weighed
              before choosing a different course.
              You must ask forgiveness for violating a SHOULD.
            </p>
          </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <th>SHOULD NOT</th>
          <td>
            <p>
              This phrase, or the phrase "NOT RECOMMENDED", means that
              there may exist valid reasons in particular circumstances
              to ignore the prohibitions of this guideline, but
              the full implications should be understood and carefully weighed
              before choosing a different course.
              You must ask forgiveness for violating a SHOULD NOT.
            </p>
          </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <th>MAY</th>
          <td>
            <p>
              This word, or the adjective "OPTIONAL",
              means that an item is truly optional.
            </p>
          </td>
        </tr>
      </tbody></table>
      <p>
        Unlike RFCs, we don't capitalize every instance of one of the above
        keywords when it is used.
      </p>
    
  </stylepoint>
  <stylepoint title="Permission and Forgiveness">
    <summary>
      There are cases where transgression of some of these rules
      is useful or even necessary.
      In some cases, you must seek permission or obtain forgiveness
      from the proper people.
    </summary>
    
      <p>
        Permission comes from the owners of your project.
      </p>
      
      <p>
        Forgiveness is requested in a comment
        near the point of guideline violation,
        and is granted by your code reviewer.
        The original comment should be signed by you, and
        the reviewer should add a signed approval to the comment at review time.
      </p>
      
    
  </stylepoint>
  <stylepoint title="Conventions">
    <summary>
      You MUST follow conventions. They are not optional.
    </summary>
    
      <p>
        Some of these guidelines are motivated by universal principles of good programming.
        Some guidelines are motivated by technical peculiarities of Common Lisp.
        Some guidelines were once motivated by a technical reason,
        but the guideline remained after the reason subsided.
        Some guidelines, such those about as comments and indentation,
        are based purely on convention, rather than on clear technical merit.
        Whatever the case may be, you must still follow these guidelines,
        as well as other conventional guidelines
        that have not been formalized in this document.
      </p>
      <p>
        You MUST follow conventions.
        They are important for readability.
        When conventions are followed by default,
        violations of the convention are a signal
        that something notable is happening and deserves attention.
        When conventions are systematically violated,
        violations of the convention are a distracting noise
        that needs to be ignored.
      </p>
      <p>
        Conventional guidelines <em>are</em> indoctrination.
        Their purpose is to make you follow the mores of the community,
        
        so you can more effectively cooperate with existing members.
        It is still useful to distinguish the parts that are technically motivated
        from the parts that are mere conventions,
        so you know when best to defy conventions for good effect,
        and when not to fall into the pitfalls that the conventions are there to help avoid.
      </p>
    
  </stylepoint>
  <stylepoint title="Old Code">
    <summary>
      Fix old code as you go.
    </summary>
    
      <p>
        A lot of our code was written before these guidelines existed.
        You should fix violations as you encounter them
        in the course of your normal coding.
      </p>
      <p>
        You must not fix violations en masse
        without warning other developers and coordinating with them,
        so as not to make the merging of large branches
        more difficult than it already is.
      </p>
    
  </stylepoint>
  <stylepoint title="Future Topics">
    <summary>
      There are many topics for additional standardization
      not covered by current version of this document,
      but deferred to future versions.
    </summary>
    
      <ul>
        <li>
          File and directory structure
        </li>
        <li>
          Packages and modularity
        </li>
        <li>
          Threads and locking
        </li>
        <li>
          How to add configurable components
        </li>
        <li>
          CLOS style: initforms, slot and accessor names, etc.
        </li>
        <li>
          Recommendations on max number of slots per class.
        </li>
        <li>
          More concrete examples of good code:
          <ul>
            <li>
              exceptions
            </li>
            <li>
              transactions, with retry
            </li>
            <li>
              XML
            </li>
            <li>
              typing
            </li>
            <li>
              encapsulation / abstraction
            </li>
            <li>
              class and slot names
            </li>
            <li>
              etc.
            </li>
          </ul>
        </li>
        <li>
          When (not) to use conditional compilation:
          <ul>
            <li>
              modifying the product
            </li>
            <li>
              conditional debugging/console output/etc.
            </li>
            <li>
              "temporarily" commenting-out blocks of code
            </li>
            <li>
              etc.
            </li>
          </ul>
        </li>
      </ul>
    
  </stylepoint>
  </category>
<category title="General Guidelines">
  <stylepoint title="Principles">
    <summary>
      There are some basic principles for team software development
      that every developer must keep in mind.
      Whenever the detailed guidelines are inadequate, confusing or contradictory,
      refer back to these principles for guidance:
      <ul>
        <li>
          Every developer's code must be easy for another developer
          to read, understand, and modify
          â€” even if the first developer isn't around to explain it.
          (This is the "hit by a truck" principle.)
        </li>
        <li>
          Everybody's code should look the same.
          Ideally, there should be no way to look at lines of code
          and recognize it as "Fred's code" by its style.
        </li>
        <li>
          Be precise.
        </li>
        <li>
          Be concise.
        </li>
        <li>
          KISS â€” Keep It Simple, Stupid.
        </li>
        <li>
          Use the smallest hammer for the job.
        </li>
        <li>
          Use common sense.
        </li>
        <li>
          Keep related code together.
          Minimize the amount of jumping around
          someone has to do to understand an area of code.
        </li>
      </ul>
    </summary>
    
    
  </stylepoint>
  <stylepoint title="Priorities">
    <summary>
      <p>
        When making decisions about how to write a given piece of
        code, aim for the following -ilities in this priority order:
      </p>
      <ul>
        <li>
          Usability by the customer
        </li>
        <li>
          Debuggability/Testability
        </li>
        <li>
          Readability/Comprehensibility
        </li>
        <li>
          Extensibility/Modifiability
        </li>
        <li>
          Efficiency (of the Lisp code at runtime)
        </li>
      </ul>
    </summary>
    
      <p>
        Most of these are obvious.
      </p>
      <p>
        Usability by the customer means that the system has to do what the
        customer requires; it has to handle the customer's transaction
        volumes, uptime requirements; etc.
      </p>
      <p>
        For the Lisp efficiency point,
        given two options of equivalent complexity,
        pick the one that performs better.
        (This is often the same as the one that conses less,
        i.e. allocates less storage from the heap.)
      </p>
      <p>
        Given two options where one is more complex than the other,
        pick the simpler option and revisit the decision only if
        profiling shows it to be a performance bottleneck.
      </p>
      <p>
        However, avoid premature optimization.
        Don't add complexity to speed up something that runs rarely,
        since in the long run, it matters less whether such …</p></stylepoint></category></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://google.github.io/styleguide/lispguide.xml">https://google.github.io/styleguide/lispguide.xml</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://google.github.io/styleguide/lispguide.xml</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23761346</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 17:07:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Reclaim – an adaptive calendar app that plans time for your routines]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 103 | Comments 41 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23760278">thread link</a>) | @Lightbody
<br/>
July 7, 2020 | https://reclaim.ai/daily-habits/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://reclaim.ai/daily-habits/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    
<!-- bloc-menu -->
<div id="bloc-menu">
	<div>
		<div>
			<div>
				<nav role="navigation">
					<a href="https://reclaim.ai/"><img src="https://reclaim.ai/img/Primary_FullColor.svg" alt="Reclaim"></a>
					
					
					
				</nav>
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>
<!-- bloc-menu END -->

<!-- bloc-hero -->
<div id="bloc-hero">
	<div>
		<div>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://reclaim.ai/img/lazyload-ph.png" data-src="../img/undraw_healthy_habit_bh5w.svg" alt="PersonalityIcon"></p>
				<h2>
					Habits is a better way to ensure you always get time during the week for the things you do most often.<p>In just a few steps, Reclaim will find and defend time on your calendar for anything you want to do regularly.
				</p></h2>
				<div>
					<p><a href="https://app.reclaim.ai/signup">Get started for free</a></p><p>
						* We may occasionally contact you with product-related updates when you sign up. No spam, we promise.
					</p>
				</div>
			</div>
			<p><img src="https://reclaim.ai/img/lazyload-ph.png" data-src="../img/undraw_healthy_habit_bh5w.svg" alt="PersonalityIcon">
			</p>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>
<!-- bloc-hero END -->

<!-- bloc-63 -->

<!-- bloc-63 END -->

<!-- bloc-get-instant-insights -->
<div id="bloc-get-instant-insights">
	<div>
		<div>
			<p><img src="https://reclaim.ai/img/lazyload-ph.png" data-src="../img/HabitsList.svg" alt="Reclaim">
			</p>
			<div>
				<h2>
					<strong>Make time for work (and life)</strong>
				</h2>
				<p>
					With Habits, you can tell Reclaim things that you want to get done regularly, give a rough idea of when you want them to happen, and Reclaim finds the time to get them done.<br>
				</p>
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>
<!-- bloc-get-instant-insights END -->

<!-- bloc-rapidly-map-priorities -->
<div id="bloc-rapidly-map-priorities">
	<div>
		<div>
			<p><img src="https://reclaim.ai/img/lazyload-ph.png" data-src="../img/Reclaimv2.svg" alt="Habits">
			</p>
			<div>
				<h2>
					<strong>Keep your schedule agile</strong>
				</h2>
				<p>
					Habits aren’t just recurring events — they’re intelligent, adaptive calendar events that automatically move and change status as your week changes.&nbsp;
				</p>
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>
<!-- bloc-rapidly-map-priorities END -->

<!-- bloc-identify-additional-time -->
<div id="bloc-identify-additional-time">
	<div>
		<div>
			<p><img src="https://reclaim.ai/img/lazyload-ph.png" data-src="../img/HabitEdit.svg" alt="Tasks">
			</p>
			<div>
				<h2>
					<strong>Set rules for time defense</strong>
				</h2>
				<p>
					With every Habit you create, you can tell Reclaim the ideal times for it to happen as well as define how aggressively you want to defend the time on your calendar.
				</p>
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>
<!-- bloc-identify-additional-time END -->

<!-- bloc-67 -->
<div id="bloc-67">
	<div>
		<div>
			<p><img src="https://reclaim.ai/img/lazyload-ph.png" data-src="../img/Interruptions.svg" alt="PersonalSyncOnTravelOnv2">
			</p>
			<div>
				<h2>
					<strong>Avoid duplication &amp; interruptions</strong>
				</h2>
				<p>
					Just like an Out-of-Office event, you can tell Reclaim to decline interruptions that interfere with your Habits. You can also give Reclaim a list of words to look for on your calendar and avoid duplicating the Habit if it’s already on your calendar.
				</p>
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>
<!-- bloc-67 END -->

<!-- bloc-68 -->
<div id="bloc-68">
	<div>
		<div>
			<p><img src="https://reclaim.ai/img/SlackIntegrationHabits.png" data-src="../img/SlackIntegrationHabits.png" alt="LunchOnv2">
			</p>
			<div>
				<h2>
					<strong>Stay on track in Slack</strong>
				</h2>
				<p>
					With Reclaim’s Slack integration, your Habits are only a click away. You can view which Habits are scheduled, decide to delay ones that you don’t want to do that day, and modify Habits on-the-fly.
				</p>
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>
<!-- bloc-68 END -->

<!-- bloc-69 -->

<!-- bloc-69 END -->

<!-- bloc-70 -->
<div id="bloc-70">
	<div>
		<div>
			<p><img src="https://reclaim.ai/img/HIW_01.png" data-src="../img/HIW_01.png" alt="SlackIntegrationTask">
			</p>
			<div>
				<h2>
					<strong>1. Communicate your routines</strong>
				</h2>
				<p>
					You can add anything you want to get done regularly — exercise, coding, reading, taking a walk, or whatever matters to you — to Reclaim as a Habit.
				</p>
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>
<!-- bloc-70 END -->

<!-- bloc-71 -->
<div id="bloc-71">
	<div>
		<div>
			<p><img src="https://reclaim.ai/img/HIW_02.png" data-src="../img/HIW_02.png" alt="Logos">
			</p>
			<div>
				<h2>
					<strong>2. Tell us when to block them</strong>
				</h2>
				<p>
					Give Reclaim a rough idea of when you’d like the the Habit to happen, a range for how long you’d like to spend on it, and set how aggressively you want Reclaim to defend the time on your calendar.&nbsp;
				</p>
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>
<!-- bloc-71 END -->

<!-- bloc-72 -->
<div id="bloc-72">
	<div>
		<div>
			<p><img src="https://reclaim.ai/img/HIW_03.png" data-src="../img/HIW_03.png" alt="SlackIntegrationTask">
			</p>
			<div>
				<h2>
					<strong>3. Your routines get defended</strong>
				</h2>
				<p>
					Reclaim starts to add your Habit to your calendar! Reclaim will look ahead at your schedule and determine how busy your week looks. If your week is pretty free, the blocks will initially be added as Free time and then change to Busy as your days fill up.
				</p>
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>
<!-- bloc-72 END -->

<!-- bloc-73 -->

<!-- bloc-73 END -->

<!-- bloc-74 -->

<!-- bloc-74 END -->

<!-- bloc-75 -->

<!-- bloc-75 END -->

<!-- bloc-76 -->
<div id="bloc-76">
	<div>
		<div>
			<div>
				<p>
					<i>“Reclaim takes a ton of methods I’ve been using at work for years -- blocking time for tasks, mapping my calendar to my priorities, and safeguarding time for personal events -- and makes them 10x easier to implement. It’s like they read my mind and built a product out of it.”</i>
				</p>
				<p>
					<strong>- Jade Rubick, VP of Engineering, Gremlin</strong>
				</p>
			</div>
			<div>
				<p>
					<i>“Reclaim keeps my calendar aligned with my priorities, plain and simple. It’s a whole new way to visualize my schedule and understand where my time is going every week.”</i>
				</p>
				<p>
					<strong>- James Ferguson, Head of Design, Atlassian</strong>
				</p>
			</div>
			<div>
				<p>
					<i>"I’ve introduced Reclaim to the entire Packet team and now they spend less time tinkering with their calendars and are able to focus more, prioritize what really matters and carve out time for their own mental and personal health.”</i><br>
				</p>
				<p>
					<strong>- Zac Smith, Managing Director, Equinix and Founder of Packet</strong><br>
				</p>
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>
<!-- bloc-76 END -->

<!-- bloc-77 -->

<!-- bloc-77 END -->

<!-- bloc-13 -->
<div id="bloc-13">
	<div>
		<div>
			<div>
				<nav role="navigation">
					<a href="https://reclaim.ai/"><img src="https://reclaim.ai/img/lazyload-ph.png" data-src="../img/Primary_FullColor.svg" alt="Reclaim"></a>
					
					
				</nav>
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>
<!-- bloc-13 END -->

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://reclaim.ai/daily-habits/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23760278</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 15:34:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why Go's Error Handling Is Awesome]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 59 | Comments 90 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23758509">thread link</a>) | @michaelanckaert
<br/>
July 7, 2020 | https://rauljordan.com/2020/07/06/why-go-error-handling-is-awesome.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rauljordan.com/2020/07/06/why-go-error-handling-is-awesome.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  
  
  
  
  <p>Published on 06 Jul 2020</p>
  
  <p>Go’s <a href="https://github.com/golang/go/issues/32825">infamous error handling</a> has caught quite the attention from outsiders to the programming language, often touted as one of the language’s most questionable design decisions. If you look into any project on Github written in Go, it’s almost a guarantee you’ll see the lines more frequently than anything else in the codebase:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>if</span><span> </span><span>err</span><span> </span><span>!=</span><span> </span><span>nil</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span>
    </span><span>return</span><span> </span><span>err</span><span>
</span><span>}</span><span>
</span></code></pre></div></div>
<p>Although it may seem redundant and unnecessary for those new to the language, the reason errors in Go are treated as first-class citizens (values) has a deeply-rooted history in programming language theory and the main goal of Go as a language itself. Numerous efforts have been made to change or improve how Go deals with errors, but so far, one proposal is winning above all others:</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/QvF1AbH.png" alt="Image"></p>

<p>- <a href="https://github.com/golang/go/issues/32825">Leave if err != nil alone!</a></p>

<h2 id="gos-error-philosophy">Go’s error philosophy</h2>

<p>Go’s philosophy regarding error handling forces developers to incorporate errors as first class citizens of most functions they write. Even if you ignore an error using something like:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>func</span><span> </span><span>getUserFromDB</span><span>()</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>*</span><span>User</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>error</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span> </span><span>...</span><span> </span><span>}</span><span>

</span><span>func</span><span> </span><span>main</span><span>()</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span>
    </span><span>user</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>_</span><span> </span><span>:=</span><span> </span><span>getUserFromDB</span><span>()</span><span>
</span><span>}</span><span>
</span></code></pre></div></div>
<p>Most linters or IDEs will catch that you’re ignoring an error, and it will certaintly be visible to your teammates during code review. However, in other languages, it may not be clear that your code is not handling a potential exception in a <code>try catch</code> code block, being completely opaque about handling your control flow.</p>

<p>If you handle errors in Go the standard way, you get the benefits of:</p>

<ol>
  <li>No hidden control-flows</li>
  <li>No unexpected <code>uncaught exception</code> logs blowing up your terminal (aside from actual program crashes via panics)</li>
  <li>full-control of errors in your code as <em>values</em> you can handle, return, and do anything you want with</li>
</ol>

<p>Not only is the syntax of <code>func f() (value, error)</code> easy to teach to a newcomer, but also a standard in any Go project which ensures consistency.</p>

<p>It’s important to note Go’s error syntax does not <strong>force</strong> you to handle every error your program may throw. Go simply provides a pattern to ensure you think of errors as critical to your program flow, but not much else. At the end of your program, if an error occurs, and you find it using <code>err != nil</code>, and your application doesn’t do something actionable about it, you’re in trouble either way - <strong>Go can’t save you</strong>. Let’s take a look at an example:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>if</span><span> </span><span>err</span><span> </span><span>:=</span><span> </span><span>criticalDatabaseOperation</span><span>();</span><span> </span><span>err</span><span> </span><span>!=</span><span> </span><span>nil</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span>
    </span><span>// Only logging the error without returning it to stop control flow (bad!)</span><span>
    </span><span>log</span><span>.</span><span>Printf</span><span>(</span><span>"Something went wrong in the DB: %w"</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>err</span><span>)</span><span>
</span><span>}</span><span>

</span><span>if</span><span> </span><span>err</span><span> </span><span>:=</span><span> </span><span>saveUser</span><span>(</span><span>user</span><span>);</span><span> </span><span>err</span><span> </span><span>!=</span><span> </span><span>nil</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span>
    </span><span>return</span><span> </span><span>fmt</span><span>.</span><span>Errorf</span><span>(</span><span>"Could not save user: %w"</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>err</span><span>)</span><span>
</span><span>}</span><span>
</span></code></pre></div></div>

<p>If something goes wrong and <code>err != nil</code> in calling <code>criticalDatabaseOperation()</code>, we’re not doing anything with the error aside from logging it! We might have data corruption or an otherwise unexpected issue that we are not handling intelligently, either via retrying the function call, canceling further program flow, or in worst-case scenario, shutting down the program. Go isn’t magical and can’t save you from these situations. Go only provides a standard approach for returning and using errors as values, but you still have to figure out how to handle the errors yourself.</p>

<h3 id="how-other-languages-do-it-throwing-exceptions">How other languages do it: throwing exceptions</h3>

<p>In something like the Javascript Node.js runtime, you can structure your programs as follows, known as throwing <code>exceptions</code>:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>try</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>criticalOperation1</span><span>();</span>
    <span>criticalOperation2</span><span>();</span>
    <span>criticalOperation3</span><span>();</span>
<span>}</span> <span>catch</span> <span>(</span><span>e</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>console</span><span>.</span><span>error</span><span>(</span><span>e</span><span>);</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>If an error occurs in any of these functions, the stack trace for the error will pop up at runtime and will be logged to the console, but there is no explicit, programmatic handling of what went wrong.</p>

<p>Your <code>criticalOperation</code> functions don’t need to explicitly handle error flow, as any exception that occurs within that try block will be raised at runtime along with a stack trace of what went wrong.
A benefit to exception-based languages is that, compared to Go, even an unhandled exception will still be raised via a stack trace at runtime if it occurs. In Go, it is possible to not handle a critical error at all, which can arguably be much worse. Go offers you full control of error handling, but also <strong>full responsibility</strong>.</p>

<p>EDIT: Exceptions are definitely not the only way other languages deal with errors. Rust,  for example, has a good compromise of using option types and pattern matching to find error conditions, leveraging some nice syntactic sugar to achieve similar results.</p>

<h3 id="why-go-doesnt-use-exceptions-for-error-handling">Why Go doesn’t use exceptions for error handling</h3>

<h4 id="the-zen-of-go">The Zen of Go</h4>

<p>The Zen of Go mentions two important proverbs:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Simplicity matters</li>
  <li>Plan for failure, not success</li>
</ol>

<p>Using the simple <code>if err != nil</code> snippet to all functions which return <code>(value, error)</code> helps ensure failure in your programs is thought of <em>first and foremost</em>. You don’t need to wrangle with complicated, nested <code>try catch</code> blocks which appropriately handle all possible exceptions being raised.</p>

<h4 id="exception-based-code-can-often-be-opaque">Exception-based code can often be opaque</h4>

<p>With exception-based code, however, you’re forced to be aware of every situation in which your code could have exceptions without actually handling them, as they’ll be caught by your <code>try catch</code> blocks. That is, it encourages programmers to never check errors, knowing that at the very least, some exception will be handled automatically at runtime if it occurs.</p>

<p>A function written in an exception-based programming language may often look like this:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>item</span> <span>=</span> <span>getFromDB</span><span>()</span>
<span>item</span><span>.</span><span>Value</span> <span>=</span> <span>400</span>
<span>saveToDB</span><span>(</span><span>item</span><span>)</span>
<span>item</span><span>.</span><span>Text</span> <span>=</span> <span>'price changed'</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This code does nothing to ensure exceptions are properly handled. Perhaps the difference between making the code above become aware of exceptions is to switch the order of <code>saveToDB(item)</code> and <code>item.Text = 'price changed</code>, which is <strong>opaque</strong>, hard to reason about, and can encourage some lazy programming habits. In functional programming jargon, this is known as the fancy term: <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/28992625/exceptions-and-referential-transparency/28993780#28993780">violating referential transparency</a>. This <a href="https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/?p=36693">blog post</a> from Microsoft’s engineering blog in 2005 still holds true today, namely:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>My point isn’t that exceptions are bad.
My point is that exceptions are too hard and I’m not smart
enough to handle them.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="benefits-of-gos-error-syntax">Benefits of Go’s error syntax</h2>

<h3 id="easy-creation-of-actionable-error-chains">Easy creation of actionable error chains</h3>

<p>A superpower of the pattern <code>if err != nil</code> is how it allows for easy error-chains to traverse a program’s hierarchy all the way to where they need to be handled. For example, a common Go error handled by a program’s <code>main</code> function might read as follows:</p>

<p>[2020-07-05-9:00] ERROR: Could not create user: could not check if user already exists in DB: could not establish database connection: no internet</p>

<p>The error above is (a) clear, (b) actionable, (c) has sufficient context as to what layers of the application went <em>wrong</em>. Instead of blowing up with an unreadable, cryptic stack trace, errors like these that are a result of factors we can add human-readable context to, and should be handled via clear error chains as shown above.</p>

<p>Moreover, this type of error chain arises naturally as part of a standard Go program’s structure, likely looking like this:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>// In controllers/user.go</span><span>
</span><span>if</span><span> </span><span>err</span><span> </span><span>:=</span><span> </span><span>db</span><span>.</span><span>CreateUser</span><span>(</span><span>user</span><span>);</span><span> </span><span>err</span><span> </span><span>!=</span><span> </span><span>nil</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span>
    </span><span>return</span><span> </span><span>fmt</span><span>.</span><span>Errorf</span><span>(</span><span>"could not create user: %w"</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>err</span><span>)</span><span>
</span><span>}</span><span>

</span><span>// In database/user.go</span><span>
</span><span>func</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>db</span><span> </span><span>*</span><span>Database</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>CreateUser</span><span>(</span><span>user</span><span> </span><span>*</span><span>User</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>error</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span>
    </span><span>ok</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>err</span><span> </span><span>:=</span><span> </span><span>db</span><span>.</span><span>DoesUserExist</span><span>(</span><span>user</span><span>)</span><span>
    </span><span>if</span><span> </span><span>err</span><span> </span><span>!=</span><span> </span><span>nil</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span>
        </span><span>return</span><span> </span><span>fmt</span><span>.</span><span>Errorf</span><span>(</span><span>"could not check if user already exists in db: %w"</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>err</span><span>)</span><span>
    </span><span>}</span><span>
    </span><span>...</span><span>
</span><span>}</span><span>

</span><span>func</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>db</span><span> </span><span>*</span><span>Database</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>DoesUserExist</span><span>(</span><span>user</span><span> </span><span>*</span><span>User</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>error</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span>
    </span><span>if</span><span> </span><span>err</span><span> </span><span>:=</span><span> </span><span>db</span><span>.</span><span>Connected</span><span>();</span><span> </span><span>err</span><span> </span><span>!=</span><span> </span><span>nil</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span>
        </span><span>return</span><span> </span><span>fmt</span><span>.</span><span>Errorf</span><span>(</span><span>"could not establish db connection: %w"</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>err</span><span>)</span><span>
    </span><span>}</span><span>
    </span><span>...</span><span>
</span><span>}</span><span>

</span><span>func</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>db</span><span> </span><span>*</span><span>Database</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>Connected</span><span>()</span><span> </span><span>error</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span>
    </span><span>if</span><span> </span><span>!</span><span>hasInternetConnection</span><span>()</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span>
        </span><span>return</span><span> </span><span>errors</span><span>.</span><span>New</span><span>(</span><span>"no internet connection"</span><span>)</span><span>
    </span><span>}</span><span>
    </span><span>...</span><span>
</span><span>}</span><span>
</span></code></pre></div></div>

<p>The beauty of the code above is that each of these errors are completely namespaced by their respective function, are informative, and only handle responsibility for what they are aware of. This sort of error chaining using <code>fmt.Errorf("something went wrong: %w", err)</code> makes it trivial to build awesome error messages that can tell you <em>exactly</em> what went wrong based on how <em>you</em> defined it.</p>

<p>On top of this, if you want to also attach a stack trace to your functions, you can utilize the fantastic <a href="https://godoc.org/github.com/pkg/errors">github.com/pkg/errors</a> library, giving you functions such as:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>errors</span><span>.</span><span>Wrapf</span><span>(</span><span>err</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>"could not save user with email %s"</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>email</span><span>)</span><span>
</span></code></pre></div></div>

<p>which print out a stack trace <em>along</em> with the human-readable error chain you created through your code. If I could summarize the most important pieces of advice I’ve received regarding writing idiomatic error handling in Go:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Add stack traces when your errors are actionable to developers</strong></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Do something with your returned errors, don’t just bubble them up to main, log them, and forget them</strong></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Keep your error chains unambiguous</strong></p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>When I write Go code, error handling is the one thing I <em>never</em> worry about, because errors themselves are a central aspect of every function I write, giving me full control in how I handle them safely, in a readable manner, and responsibly.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“if …; err != nil” is something you’ll probably type if you write go. I don’t think it’s a plus or a negative. It gets the job done, it’s easy to understand, and it empowers the programmer to do the right thing when the program fails. The rest is up to you.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>- From <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20303468">Hacker News</a></p>

<h2 id="key-readings">Key Readings</h2>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/golang/go/issues/32825">Leave if err != nil alone!</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://godoc.org/github.com/pkg/errors">Go pkg errors</a></li>
</ul>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rauljordan.com/2020/07/06/why-go-error-handling-is-awesome.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23758509</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 12:33:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Snapchat Detection on iOS (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 81 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23757666">thread link</a>) | @mpweiher
<br/>
July 7, 2020 | https://aeonlucid.com/Snapchat-detection-on-iOS/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://aeonlucid.com/Snapchat-detection-on-iOS/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p>Previously we took a look at <a href="https://aeonlucid.com/Snapchat-detection-on-Android/">Snapchat’s root detection methods on Android</a>. This time we are taking a look at how they detect jailbreaks, tweaks and hooks on iOS.</p>



<p>All the research in this post is based on Snapchat 10.65.0.66 (832559634).</p>

<p><img src="https://aeonlucid.com/images/snapchat/ios_login_message.png" alt="Login Message">
</p>

<p>This is the message you see when you try to login with a detected tweak, although not all tweaks trigger this message. Two examples that trigger this message are <a href="http://cydia.saurik.com/package/com.johncoates.flex3/">Flex 3</a> and <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/jailbreak/comments/9baacc/release_wraith_snapchatphantom_replacement/">Wraith</a>. Some just flag your account and will get you banned later in a ban wave if you are unlucky.</p>

<h2 id="avoiding-bans">Avoiding bans</h2>

<p>So obviously the first thing we want to look at is, what has the community tried so far to stay hidden? If you google around a bit you will most likely end up with these result. For a few of them, I will list the most notable features.</p>

<ul>
  <li>NoSub (or variants)
    <ul>
      <li>Disable Cydia Substrate / Substitute entirely for specific apps.</li>
      <li>Only if you can find an updated version and don’t want to use tweaks on Snapchat.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/NepetaDev/UnSub/blob/master/Tweak/Tweak.xm">UnSub</a>
    <ul>
      <li>Hooks and filters libc file system calls.</li>
      <li>Spoofs the libc getenv to remove the <code>DYLD_INSERT_LIBRARIES</code> variable.</li>
      <li>Spoofs <code>_dyld_image_count</code> and <code>_dyld_get_image_name</code> to hide tweak related dylibs.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/jjolano/shadow/blob/master/Tweak.xm">Shadow</a>
    <ul>
      <li>Too much to list.. it hooks way too much.</li>
      <li>Still misses lots of stuff for Snapchat specifically.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Even <a href="https://support.snapchat.com/en-US/a/jailbroken-iphone">Snapchat themselves recommend NoSub</a>..</p>

<p><img src="https://aeonlucid.com/images/snapchat/ios_snapchat_jailbroken_support.png" alt="Login Message">
</p>

<p>But it seems that nobody knows what Snapchat is <strong>exactly</strong> doing to detect everything. Which is why I am writing this post. Only one that I have seen <a href="https://twitter.com/cokepokes/status/1023114963550797824">publicly making efforts</a> to figure this out is the developer of Phantom, CokePokes.</p>

<h2 id="how-are-they-doing-it">How are they doing it?</h2>

<p>I will try my best to explain every check they do in Snapchat 10.65.0.66.</p>

<p>When you launch the app they create a new thread using <a href="http://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man3/pthread_create.3.html">pthread_create</a> that runs all the checks. At the end of these checks an integer is stored with flags of everything that was detected on the device. Some of these checks are then ran every 31 seconds.</p>

<p>All the code executed for these checks is obfuscated with <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/strong-codes">Snapchats in-house obfuscation tools</a> and thus very annoying to look at using tools such as IDA.</p>

<h3 id="code-signature-checks">Code signature checks</h3>

<p>One of the first things they do is checking and storing stuff from the code signature. This happens using the <code>sys_csops(169)</code> syscall, which is pretty much undocumented but is very similar to the code here.</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://fergofrog.com/code/cbowser/xnu/bsd/kern/kern_proc.c.html#csops">xnu/bsd/kern/kern_proc.c.html#csops</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://fergofrog.com/code/cbowser/xnu/bsd/kern/kern_proc.c.html#csops_internal">xnu/bsd/kern/kern_proc.c.html#csops_internal</a></li>
</ul>

<p>They execute the following operations:</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>CS_OPS_STATUS</code></li>
  <li><code>CS_OPS_CDHASH</code></li>
  <li><code>CS_OPS_ENTITLEMENTS_BLOB</code></li>
</ul>

<p>The most important one of this is the <code>CS_OPS_STATUS</code>, this retrieves the current codesigning status of the process. A jailbroken device can respond with messy status flags. Such as:</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>CS_GET_TASK_ALLOW</code></li>
  <li><code>CS_INSTALLER</code></li>
  <li><code>CS_PLATFORM_BINARY</code></li>
  <li><code>CS_DEBUGGED</code> (Process was debugged / is being debugged)</li>
  <li>Or missing <code>CS_VALID</code>.</li>
</ul>

<p>A normal device would have these flags:</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>CS_VALID</code></li>
  <li><code>CS_HARD</code></li>
  <li><code>CS_KILL</code></li>
  <li><code>CS_ENFORCEMENT</code></li>
  <li><code>CS_REQUIRE_LV</code></li>
  <li><code>CS_DYLD_PLATFORM</code></li>
  <li><code>CS_SIGNED</code></li>
</ul>

<p>For all available flags and their descriptions, see <a href="https://fergofrog.com/code/cbowser/xnu/BUILD/obj/EXPORT_HDRS/osfmk/kern/cs_blobs.h.html#_M/CS_VALID">this page</a>.</p>

<p>The result of <code>CS_OPS_STATUS</code> and <code>CS_OPS_CDHASH</code> are stored and later sent to the Snapchat servers, encrypted.</p>

<h3 id="bundle-check">Bundle check</h3>

<p>This is a simple check but quite effective if not noticed by a tweak developer. Pseudo code looks like this.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>x0 = CFBundleGetMainBundle()
x1 = CFBundleGetIdentifier(x0)
x2 = CFStringGetCStringPtr(x1)
strncmp("com.toyopagroup.picaboo", x2)
</code></pre></div></div>

<h3 id="dyld-check">Dyld check</h3>

<p>Snapchat has two methods to iterate all loaded dylibs.</p>

<h4 id="first-attempt">First attempt</h4>

<p>One way is using <a href="https://github.com/theos/sdks/blob/master/iPhoneOS11.2.sdk/usr/include/mach-o/dyld.h#L48">dyld_get_image_header</a> and <a href="http://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man3/dladdr1.3.html">dladdr</a>. They iterate over <code>dyld_get_image_header</code> until it returns null and checks if it has seen everything with <a href="https://github.com/theos/sdks/blob/master/iPhoneOS11.2.sdk/usr/include/mach-o/dyld.h#L47">dyld_image_count</a>. The <code>dladdr</code> method provides them with the path of the dylib. These are checked against a few unknown strings but removing everything substrate related from the dyld list fixes this check.</p>

<h4 id="second-attempt">Second attempt</h4>

<p>The other method they use is calling <a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/kernel/1537934-task_info">task_info</a> with flavor <code>TASK_DYLD_INFO</code>. This also gives them a list of all loaded dylibs and must be fixed separately from the first dyld check.</p>

<h3 id="file-system-checks">File system checks</h3>

<p>There are a couple of file system checks, of which all use the <code>sys_access(33)</code> syscall.</p>

<h4 id="first-list">First list</h4>

<ul>
  <li>/Library/Application Support/PhLite/phlite.bundle/AuthAPI.pem</li>
  <li>/private/var/tmp/cydia.log</li>
  <li>/bin/bash</li>
  <li>/usr/sbin/sshd</li>
  <li>/usr/libexec/ssh-keysign</li>
  <li>/usr/libexec/sftp-server</li>
  <li>/etc/ssh/sshd_config</li>
  <li>/.installed_yaluX</li>
  <li>/Library/LaunchDaemons/dropbear.plist</li>
  <li>/usr/local/bin/dropbear</li>
  <li>/System/Library/Caches/com.apple.dyld/enable-dylibs-to-override-cache</li>
  <li>/.cydia_no_stash</li>
  <li>/var/log/jailbreakd-stdout.log</li>
  <li>/etc/motd</li>
  <li>/usr/lib/libsubstitute.dylib</li>
  <li>/var/tmp/slide.txt</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="second-list">Second list</h4>

<ul>
  <li>/private/var/containers/Bundle/Application/AD659AF8-68C3-4E4B-BF02-236E1F733005/Snapchat.app/Ghay</li>
  <li>/private/var/containers/Bundle/Application/AD659AF8-68C3-4E4B-BF02-236E1F733005/Snapchat.app/Snapchat.crc</li>
  <li>/private/var/containers/Bundle/Application/AD659AF8-68C3-4E4B-BF02-236E1F733005/Snapchat.app/embedded.mobileprovision</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="last-one-and-expected-to-exist">Last one (and expected to exist)</h4>

<ul>
  <li>/private/var/containers/Bundle/Application/AD659AF8-68C3-4E4B-BF02-236E1F733005/Snapchat.app/PlugIns</li>
</ul>

<p>The last one makes it a bit harder to fix, since you can not simply replace the arm instructions with something that makes it always return false. Thus requiring an inline hook as replacement for the syscall so you gain full control over it.</p>

<h3 id="obj-c---class-checks">Obj-C - Class checks</h3>

<p>A lot of classes are checked from a lot of different tweaks. This is done using <a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/objectivec/1418952-objc_getclass">objc_getClass</a>.</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>SCOthmanPrefs</code></li>
  <li><code>SCOthmanSnapSaver</code></li>
  <li><code>SCOFiltersOthman</code></li>
  <li><code>SCSnapchPrefs</code></li>
  <li><code>SCSnapchLocation</code></li>
  <li><code>SCOFiltersSnapch</code></li>
  <li><code>PHSnapSaver</code></li>
  <li><code>PHRegisterViewController</code></li>
  <li><code>phlite</code></li>
  <li><code>dfnvrknsv</code></li>
  <li><code>PHSSaver</code></li>
  <li><code>PHMainSettingsVC</code></li>
  <li><code>SCPPrivacySettings</code></li>
  <li><code>SCPSettings</code></li>
  <li><code>SCPSavedMediaSettings</code></li>
  <li><code>SNAPCHAT_SCPSnapUsageSettings</code></li>
  <li><code>SNAPCHAT_SCPSegmentedController</code></li>
  <li><code>SNAPCHAT_CZPickerView</code></li>
  <li><code>CTAdBase</code></li>
  <li><code>CTRequestModel</code></li>
  <li><code>CTBannerView</code></li>
  <li><code>CPAdManager</code></li>
  <li><code>MMNativeAdController</code></li>
  <li><code>TweakBoxStartupManager</code></li>
  <li><code>SNAPCHAT_GPHelper</code></li>
  <li><code>SCKsausaPrefs</code></li>
  <li><code>SCSCGoodSnapSaver</code></li>
  <li><code>SNAPCHAT_XXXXXXX_GPHelper</code></li>
  <li><code>SCOFiltersHelper</code></li>
  <li><code>_xxx</code></li>
  <li><code>PHSSaver</code></li>
  <li><code>SIGMAPOINT_GPHelper</code></li>
  <li><code>SCS     SnapSaver</code></li>
  <li><code>SCW    wSnapSaver</code></li>
  <li><code>CYJSObject</code></li>
  <li><code>P         D</code></li>
  <li><code>R              t</code></li>
  <li><code>AVCameraViewControlIer</code></li>
  <li><code>SCAppDeIegate</code></li>
  <li><code>FLEXManager</code></li>
  <li><code>oJXM</code></li>
  <li><code>fJWs</code></li>
  <li><code>yytp</code></li>
  <li><code>FLManager</code></li>
  <li><code>DecryptScriptAlertView</code></li>
  <li><code>DzAdsManager</code></li>
</ul>

<h3 id="obj-c---method-checks">Obj-C - Method checks</h3>

<p>They also check methods. This happens using <a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/objectivec/1418952-objc_getclass">objc_getClass</a> and then <a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/objectivec/1418530-class_getinstancemethod">class_getInstanceMethod</a>. If any exists, you get flagged.</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>NSMutableString</code>
    <ul>
      <li><code>a</code></li>
      <li><code>b</code></li>
      <li><code>c</code></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><code>SCAppDelegate</code>
    <ul>
      <li><code>MZ42SGH98C:</code></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><code>SCOperaPageViewController</code>
    <ul>
      <li><code>saveButtonPressed</code></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><code>UIViewController</code>
    <ul>
      <li><code>dzDidTapGalleryButton</code></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<h3 id="obj-c---method-integrity-checks">Obj-C - Method integrity checks</h3>

<p>Next up is Snapchats own methods. For the classes listed below they first call <a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/objectivec/1418490-class_copymethodlist">class_copyMethodList</a>. Then for every <a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/objectivec/method?language=objc">Method</a> they check if the <code>IMP</code> pointer (address of the function) is within its own <code>__text</code> segment. This is how they detect whether a method has been hooked.</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>SCAppDelegate</code></li>
  <li><code>MainViewController</code></li>
  <li><code>SCChatMainViewController</code></li>
  <li><code>SCChatViewControllerV3</code></li>
  <li><code>SCScreenshotDetector</code></li>
  <li><code>SCBaseMediaOperaPresenter</code></li>
  <li><code>SCOperaPageViewController</code></li>
  <li><code>SCLoginService</code></li>
  <li><code>SCAdsHoldoutExperimentContext</code></li>
  <li><code>SCExperimentManager</code></li>
  <li><code>SCCaptionDefaultTextView</code></li>
  <li><code>SCChatTypingHandler</code></li>
  <li><code>Story</code></li>
  <li><code>SCChatMessageV3</code></li>
  <li><code>SCOperaViewersLayer</code></li>
</ul>

<p>Thanks to <code>dzan</code> for telling me to check the <code>__text</code> segment. :-)</p>

<h3 id="symbol-checks">Symbol checks</h3>

<p>They also check for a couple of symbols using <a href="https://linux.die.net/man/3/dlsym">dlsym</a>. If the result is not null, you get flagged.</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>MSHookMessageEx</code></li>
  <li><code>MSHookFunction</code></li>
  <li><code>_Z17replaced_readlinkPKcPcm</code></li>
  <li><code>hooksArray</code></li>
  <li><code>_OBJC_METACLASS_$__xxx</code></li>
  <li><code>_OBJC_CLASS_$_PHSSaverV2</code></li>
  <li><code>plist</code></li>
  <li><code>flexBreakPoint</code></li>
  <li><code>convert_coordinates_from_device_to_interface</code></li>
  <li><code>OBJC_METACLASS_$_DzSnapHelper</code></li>
  <li><code>ChKey2</code></li>
</ul>

<h3 id="symbol-hook-checks">Symbol hook checks</h3>

<p>A few symbols are resolved using <a href="https://linux.die.net/man/3/dlsym">dlsym</a> to check whether they have been hooked. They first resolve <code>dlsym</code> using <code>dlsym</code>.. yeah.. That result gets used for the <code>dlsym</code> of the symbols below. For every address returned, the first 4 bytes are checked for common hook related instructions.</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>dlsym</code></li>
  <li><code>objc_getClass</code></li>
  <li><code>class_getInstanceMethod</code></li>
  <li><code>sel_registerName</code></li>
  <li><code>class_copyMethodList</code></li>
  <li><code>_dyld_image_count</code></li>
  <li><code>_dyld_get_image_header</code></li>
  <li><code>dladdr</code></li>
</ul>

<h3 id="environment-variables">Environment variables</h3>

<p>I need to be honest, this is a very annoying way how they check for injection because it is annoying to fix. Instead of using <a href="http://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man3/getenv.3.html">getenv</a> they use the <a href="http://sourceware.org/git/?p=glibc.git;a=blob;f=posix/environ.c">environ</a> variable. Since it is a variable, you can not “hook” it.</p>

<p>At least the following variables are detected.</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>DYLD_INSERT_LIBRARIES=/usr/lib/TweakInject.dylib</code></li>
  <li><code>_MSSafeMode=0</code></li>
</ul>

<h3 id="sandbox-check">Sandbox check</h3>

<p>Probably not an issue for anyone.</p>

<p><img src="https://aeonlucid.com/images/snapchat/ios_sandbox.png" alt="iOS sandbox">
</p>

<h3 id="fingerprinting">Fingerprinting</h3>

<p>Not much detection done here but still relevant, using <code>sys_sysctl(202)</code> they request at least the following properties.</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>kern.version</code></li>
  <li><code>kern.osversion</code></li>
  <li><code>kern.proc.pid.&lt;PID&gt;</code></li>
  <li><code>hw.machine</code></li>
</ul>

<h3 id="other">Other</h3>

<p>The syscall <code>sys_proc_info(33)</code> is also called a couple of times, which could reveal stuff that is ptracing the process. They also use <code>sys_open(5)</code>, <a href="http://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man2/mmap.2.html">mmap</a>, <code>sys_close(6)</code> and <code>sys_lstat64(340)</code> on the <code>Snapchat</code> binary. Probably to check for modifications or generating a checksum.</p>

<h2 id="how-all-this-stuff-was-found">How all this stuff was found</h2>

<p>A lot of the work was done using a small iOS emulator build on top of <a href="https://github.com/unicorn-engine/unicorn">Unicorn</a>. Using an emulator you can see everything they do. Building this was also teached me a lot about the CoreFoundation library of iOS.</p>

<p><img src="https://aeonlucid.com/images/snapchat/ios_emulator.png" alt="iOS emulator">
</p>

<p>Later I implemented a counter for all of my discoveries in a tweak called <a href="https://github.com/AeonLucid/SnapHide">SnapHide</a> while carefully keeping track of how my changes modified the detection flags and slowly getting rid of all of them. You can easily find fixes for checks mentioned in this blog post in the “Detections” directory.</p>

<p>You could alternatively trace the syscalls using any of the methods discussed in the WhoYouGonnaSyscall talk by <a href="https://twitter.com/hexploitable">Hexploitable</a>. Slides of the talk can be found <a href="https://github.com/radareorg/r2con2019/blob/master/talks/WhoYouGonnaSyscall/Hex-r2con2019-WhoYouGonnaSyscall.pdf">here</a>.</p>

<h3 id="a-story-on-how-i-wasted-hours-on-fixing-syscalls">A story on how I wasted hours on fixing syscalls</h3>

<p>Let’s take <code>sys_access(33)</code> as an example. It’s implementation looks like <a href="http://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man2/access.2.html">this</a>. In short, when a file exists and permission is granted, return <code>0</code>. Otherwise return <code>-1</code>. First thing I did was force both of the results in my emulator but I saw no changes happening to the detection flags.</p>

<p>Later when implementing a fix for this in the <a href="https://github.com/AeonLucid/SnapHide">SnapHide</a> tweak, I was unable to have it fail. The arm instructions look like this:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>MOV             X0, X27 ; path
MOV             X1, #0  ; mode
MOV             X16, #0x21
SVC             0x80    ; SYS_access
MOV             X0, #0xFFFFFFFFFFFFFFFF
CSEL            X0, X0, XZR, CS
MOV             X27, X0 ; Use result
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>In …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://aeonlucid.com/Snapchat-detection-on-iOS/">https://aeonlucid.com/Snapchat-detection-on-iOS/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://aeonlucid.com/Snapchat-detection-on-iOS/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23757666</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 10:35:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Complete Spectrum ROM Disassembly]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 105 | Comments 52 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23757449">thread link</a>) | @MindGods
<br/>
July 7, 2020 | https://speccy.xyz/rom/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://speccy.xyz/rom/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://speccy.xyz/rom/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23757449</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 10:01:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: I built a desktop radiation monitor with Raspberry Pi, brass and wood]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 349 | Comments 63 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23756964">thread link</a>) | @chrisys
<br/>
July 7, 2020 | https://www.balena.io/blog/show-tell-a-steampunk-desktop-background-radiation-monitor/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.balena.io/blog/show-tell-a-steampunk-desktop-background-radiation-monitor/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
            <p>I was always a fan of the steampunk style, and having also had experience building steam engines in the past, there was only one real direction this project could go. Once I had my radiation detector kit hooked up to my Raspberry Pi running InfluxDB and Grafana, I found myself woodworking, machining, and fabricobbling an enclosure out of mahogany, brass, copper, toggle switches and, because it just had to be done, nixie tubes.</p>

<p>Read the story of the almost year-long journey (<em>cough</em> some other stuff cropped up…) I went on to make my steampunk vision a reality below, and if you want to get up and running quickly, find out how to <a href="https://www.balena.io/blog/build-a-simple-radiation-monitor-using-a-raspberry-pi-influxdb-and-grafana/">build your own simple version right here</a>!</p>

<p><img src="https://www.balena.io/blog/content/images/2020/07/geiger-main.jpg" onclick="openModal();currentSlide(56)">  
</p>

<iframe width="100%" height="500" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lEL_XkN69n8" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<hr>

<h2 id="contents">Contents</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="#intro">Introduction</a></li>
<li><a href="#inspiration">Inspiration &amp; Design</a></li>
<li><a href="#build">The build</a>
<ul><li><a href="#panel">The front panel</a></li>
<li><a href="#wood">Working with wood</a></li>
<li><a href="#brass">Top brass</a></li>
<li><a href="#dekatrons">Imitation Dekatrons</a></li>
<li><a href="#fasteners">Fussy about fasteners</a></li>
<li><a href="#pi">Plumbing in a Pi project</a></li>
<li><a href="#nixie">Nixie tubes</a></li>
<li><a href="#counter">Electrifying a mechanical counter</a></li>
<li><a href="#electronics">Electronics</a></li>
<li><a href="#geiger">Relocating the Geiger tube</a></li></ul></li>
<li><a href="#final">Final assembly</a></li>
<li><a href="#software">Programming and software</a></li>
<li><a href="#end">You have come to the end of your journey</a></li>
</ul>

<hr>

<h2 id="introductionspanidintrospan">Introduction <span id="intro"></span></h2>

<p>Low cost radiation monitors and Geiger counter kits have been available online for around $30-50US/£25-45 for a while, but standing alone they don’t do much other than make the recognizable “clicking” sound we all know from movies and TV. I decided to up the ante by connecting one to a Raspberry Pi, storing the data with InfluxDB, and showing the readings with a Grafana dashboard.</p>



<p>I updated the tech, gave it a web interface, added remote management, and built a custom mahogany housing with brass and copper fittings to show everything off, because it’s important to look suitably <em>hip</em> when sitting on the desk next to your <a href="https://www.balena.io/blog/build-a-raspberry-pi-powered-train-station-oled-sign-for-your-desk/">train sign</a>… right?</p>

<p><img src="https://www.balena.io/blog/content/images/2020/07/header.jpg" onclick="openModal();currentSlide(58)">  
</p>

<p>Anyway, I’m gonna show what I built to hopefully provide some inspiration, then show you how to get up and running with a simpler version of the project that anyone can build at home without any special tools. Let’s hit this.</p>

<hr>

<h2 id="inspirationdesignspanidinspirationspan">Inspiration &amp; design <span id="inspiration"></span></h2>

<p>I’ve always found the idea of radiation fascinating; how there are invisible particles moving around at incredibly high speeds, crashing into things and flipping bits all around us. Due to my fascination, it doesn’t take a lot to capture my interest when it comes to this field.</p>

<p>One day last year I was reminiscing over the <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-44606771">now defunct</a> UK-based electronics retailer Maplin, and how they sold all sorts of interesting kits for the aspiring engineer. This led me to <a href="https://www.richardmudhar.com/blog/2019/09/maplin-geiger-counter/">Richard Mudhar’s blog</a> where he tells the story of the <em>Maplin Geiger Counter</em>.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.balena.io/blog/content/images/2020/07/mudhar-example.png" alt="An excerpt and image from Richard Mudhar's post"></p>

<figure>  
The original Maplin Geiger Counter. Perhaps some of the design cues are visible here?! (Credit: <a href="https://www.richardmudhar.com/blog/2019/09/maplin-geiger-counter/">Richard Mudhar</a>)  
</figure>

<p>The kit that Richard has built above features both an electromechanical counter on the left, and two rings of LEDs reminiscent of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dekatron">dekatron tubes</a> on the right. This display has the neat design feature that as the rate of count increases, the display becomes more noticeable.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.balena.io/blog/content/images/2020/07/dekatron.gif" alt=""></p>

<figure>  
The spinning light effect of the Dekatron is something I wanted to replicate. By Hellbus - Own work, CC BY-SA 3.0, <a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=4741470">https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=4741470</a>.  
</figure>

<p>I liked the idea of combining the modern technology on the inside (Raspberry Pi, Grafana, etc.) with the timeless look of brass, copper, toggle switches, dark hardwood, and glass on the outside. The idea was now to build something that looked old and had that distinctive steampunk style, but was up to date and Internet-connected.</p>

<p>In addition to the total absolute count like the old Maplin counter, I wanted to offer a live display of the counts per minute (CPM) reading, and what better way to do this than with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nixie_tube">Nixie tubes</a>, to get that nice warm orange glow and keep things looking cosy.</p>

<p>I started scribbling down ideas and thoughts of materials I wanted to use alongside shopping lists for parts, and possible designs for the case.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.balena.io/blog/content/images/2020/07/notes.jpg" alt="Original shop notes!"></p>

<figure>  
Notes don’t survive well in a machine shop, but these are what’s left of my original sketches.  
</figure>

<p>This process was very much led by an image I had in my mind about how the thing should look and feel and so I just had to make it real… somehow.</p>

<hr>

<h2 id="thebuildspanidbuildspan">The build <span id="build"></span></h2>

<p>With some thoughts and ideas scribbled down it was time to get started. As this is for the most part going to be a bespoke, hand-built item, and made up as I go along, it’s not necessary to put everything in CAD. There are of course some core items that exist already and cannot change size; the Raspberry Pi and radiation detector board, for example. These are off-the-shelf parts that have to fit in the box no matter what, and start to dictate the size of the final unit.</p>

<p>Almost all other parts are completely hand made, machined and fabricated. This was necessitated by the desire to make everything authentic; I didn’t want to build things just for looks, I wanted any design choices made for aesthetic reasons to also be functional; by this I mean when I put 18 screws in something to make it look good, they are going to be 18 <em>real</em> screws that you have to take out to gain access!</p>

<p><strong>NOTE:</strong> Each of the build log images link to a separate gallery when clicked. You can look through the images that way if you prefer, or read on in full detail.</p>

<h3 id="thefrontpanelspanidpanelspan">The front panel <span id="panel"></span></h3>

<p>I started with the front panel of the housing, I knew I wanted two toggle switches; one for power and one for sound (to disable the clicking noise), along with 3 nixie tubes to display the CPM up to 999. Normal background radiation is in the range of about 25-75 CPM, so I figured if background radiation is above 999 CPM, we have bigger problems than worrying about enough digits on the counter.</p>



<p>The two front panel pieces are made from 6mm thick mild steel plate, cut to size with an angle grinder and then milled to dimension with the help of Bridget, the Bridgeport. Holes are then cut for the nixies and the toggle switches.</p>



<p>I manufactured labels for each by hand-punching lettering into 0.5mm thick brass sheet, polishing and fixing with M2 screws. The steel pieces are coated with a clear lacquer to prevent corrosion.</p>

<h3 id="workingwithwoodspanidwoodspan">Working with wood <span id="wood"></span></h3>

<p>Wood isn’t my favourite material to work with, I mean it just changes shape of its own accord! Who can work with that?! Anyhow, it’s very pretty, and so it was decided that the outer box should be made of hardwood. I started with a scrap piece of mahogany, cut it to halve the thickness on the bandsaw, and then set about planing and shaping the sides of the box to fit the dimensions of the Raspberry Pi (3A+) and the radiation detector.</p>



<p>The dimensions of the front panel along with the steel faceplates were planned out in Fusion 360 so that I could print a cutting and drilling template. This was taped onto the planed piece of mahogany, the holes for screws were drilled, and the openings for components cut out.</p>



<p>The pieces were cut at 45 degree angles to enable a mitre joint in each corner. The joints were reinforced with biscuits (mmm biscuits), and then the 4 sides were glued and clamped and allowed to cure overnight.</p>



<p>The top and bottom of the case are made from the same scrap mahogany, but planed a lot thinner - approximately 6mm, the same as the steel plate.</p>

<h3 id="topbrassspanidbrassspan">Top brass <span id="brass"></span></h3>

<p>I had the idea that it would look good to hold the box together with a totally unnecessary amount of screws, 36 to be exact; 18 on top and 18 on the bottom. To prevent the screws damaging the wood surface and to add some extra detail to the top of the case I decided to make a brass plate that the screws all go through to clamp the top cover down.</p>



<p>Some pieces of 2mm brass strip were cut, mitred on the corners and soldered together. Once soldered, sanded and polished, the joints are barely visible.</p>



<p>Holes for screws were then drilled, and the brass plate used to secure the oversize lid to the box whilst it was sanded to size on a drum sander. I later learned that using a drum sander for this was a mistake as it marked the sides of the box, but you live and learn!</p>

<div>  
    <p><img src="https://www.balena.io/blog/content/images/2020/07/top-brass-7.jpg" onclick="openModal();currentSlide(22)"></p><figure>  
Finished case and lid woodwork with brass frame temporarily fitted  
</figure>

</div>

<h3 id="imitationdekatronsspaniddekatronsspan">Imitation Dekatrons <span id="dekatrons"></span></h3>

<p>My attempt at imitating the Dekatron tube effect starts with a piece of 50mm stainless steel (or aluminium) bar. The bar is turned on a lathe down to 40mm, and to have a cavity for the electronics. The work is removed from the lathe and parted off on a bandsaw before being returned to the lathe to have a hole drilled in the rear for cabling to drive the LEDs.</p>



<p>The part is then put on the milling machine to have 10 holes drilled and M2 <del>taps snapped off in the holes</del> threaded ready to fasten the faceplate.</p>



<p>The brass faceplate is made from the same 0.5mm thick brass sheet as the labels from the faceplates. Each piece is drilled with 20 holes (10 for LEDs, 10 for fasteners), and then hand stamped with the numbering for each LED.</p>

<div>  
    <p><img src="https://www.balena.io/blog/content/images/2020/07/dekatrons-7.jpg" onclick="openModal();currentSlide(29)"></p><figure>  
The wired LED faceplate ready to be screwed into the housing.  
</figure>  
</div>

<p>The LEDs are wired with a common ground and connected using a piece of recycled floppy disk drive ribbon cable. All the work is then carried out a second time for the ‘X10’ display. The eagle-eyed readers will notice that the second display is made from a different material than the first - this is due to the fact I snapped both a drill bit and a tap off in the M2 holes - working with stainless steel with these small tools is very difficult! I ended up making the second from aluminium, which machines like butter, in comparison.</p>



<p>Throughout the development of this project I found myself continually swapping fasteners and trying different combinations to see what looks best. The end result is a mix of M2 and M3 metric machine screws in both brass and stainless steel, cheese head and countersunk head, all slotted. You may notice that in earlier photos some of the parts were assembled with Allen-head cap screws but these were later swapped out. Ebay is usually a great place to get small quantities of fasteners of all different shapes and sizes.</p>

<div>  
    <p><img src="https://www.balena.io/blog/content/images/2020/07/screws.jpg" onclick="openModal();currentSlide(30)"></p><figure>  
A mix of fastener types used for this project - various M3 and M2 machine screws.  
</figure>  
</div>

<p>The wood screws used for the top and …</p></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.balena.io/blog/show-tell-a-steampunk-desktop-background-radiation-monitor/">https://www.balena.io/blog/show-tell-a-steampunk-desktop-background-radiation-monitor/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.balena.io/blog/show-tell-a-steampunk-desktop-background-radiation-monitor/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23756964</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 08:33:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Google offers free fabbing for 130nm open-source chips]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 955 | Comments 346 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23755693">thread link</a>) | @tomcam
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://fossi-foundation.org/2020/06/30/skywater-pdk | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://fossi-foundation.org/2020/06/30/skywater-pdk">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>Did you ever dream about creating your own chip?
I mean, a physical chip.
One which you can hold in your hand, and which does exactly what you’ve designed it to do?</p>

<p>Until today, there were two major road blocks: you had to get access to a process design kit (PDK) from a chip manufacturing house (a foundry), and you had to have enough money to actually pay for the manufacturing.
These times are over.
Today.</p>

<p>Today, in a FOSSi Dial-Up talk, Tim Ansell of Google announced <a href="https://github.com/google/skywater-pdk">SkyWater PDK</a>, the first manufacturable, open source <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Process_design_kit">process design kit</a>.
What differentiates this PDK from previous attempts is the fact that it is manufacturable: with this PDK, you can actually produce chips with the <a href="https://www.skywatertechnology.com/">SkyWater foundry</a> in the 130nm node.</p>

<p>That leaves you as chip designer only with one road block: money.
Manufacturing chips is expensive – even for more than a decade old nodes like the 130nm node, you need to spend at least a couple thousand dollars.</p>

<p>You know what?
Don’t worry – Google and efabless have got you covered!
They are providing <strong>completely free of cost</strong> chip manufacturing runs: one in November this year, and multiple more in 2021.
All open source chip designs qualify, no further strings attached!</p>

<p>Learn more about all of that by re-watching <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EczW2IWdnOM">Tim’s Dial-Up talk</a> or click through the <a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/e/2PACX-1vRtwZPc8ykkkgtUkHkoJZrP9jKOo3FYdKqbg-So0ic6_kx7ha1vHnxrWmuxWkTc9GfC8xl0TfEpMLwK/pub?start=false&amp;loop=false&amp;delayms=3000">slides</a>.</p>

<p>This is certainly a dream come true for us at the FOSSi Foundation.
We helped the Free and Open Source Silicon community, our community, grow and tackle huge challenges over the years.
An open, manufacturable PDK was the main blocker in a fully open flow between RTL and a physical chip, and we’re extremely excited to see that blocker removed.</p>

<p>As always, removing one roadblock only highlights more challenges:
RAM, ROM and flash compilers, analog blocks, optimizations to various tools, and much, much more.
Now is the perfect time to get involved in the Free and Open Source Silicon ecosystem – or learn more about the accomplishments and challenges ahead of us.
A good starting point are the next Dial-Up talks.</p>

<p>Head over to the <a href="https://fossi-foundation.org/dial-up/">Dial-Up web site</a> for a listing of the upcoming talks on OpenROAD, cell design, OpenRAM, and Magic, an old, but surprisingly up-to-date tool!
To stay up-to-date with the latest developments in the FOSSi ecosystem <a href="https://librecores.us17.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=5d525b453672149a60c198960&amp;id=1241c8638b">subscribe to El Correo Libre</a>, our monthly newsletter bringing all the important news bits directly to your inbox (or <a href="https://medium.com/librecores">read it online</a>).</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/EczW2IWdnOM" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

  </div>

</article>

	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://fossi-foundation.org/2020/06/30/skywater-pdk</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23755693</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 04:26:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Faces of Microsoft (2017)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 137 | Comments 64 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23755238">thread link</a>) | @beefhash
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://www.typemag.org/post/the-faces-of-microsoft | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.typemag.org/post/the-faces-of-microsoft">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>

		
			<figure data-blockname="pull_quote">
				<p>‘Why do we need more fonts?’ asked Bill Gates. ‘We’ve got a	serif, a sans, and a monospace font. Why do we need more?’...</p>
				
			</figure>
			
			<header data-blockname="article_title">

				
				<h2><a href="https://www.typemag.org/category/3">History of type</a></h2>
				

				

				<p>The people and the rich story of type at the first big tech company.</p>

			</header>
			
			
			
			<figure data-blockname="single_image">
				<a data-lightbox="type-mag-slideshow" data-title="Steven Shaiman, the first program manager for type at Microsoft. He’s been on his own since 2010, living in the Pacific Northwest and working on family enterprises with his wife and five children." href="https://www.typemag.org/images/uploads/MS-Type-Mag-2017-05-Shaiman-Steve-47.jpg"><img data-src="https://www.typemag.org/images/uploads/MS-Type-Mag-2017-05-Shaiman-Steve-47.jpg" alt="" src="https://www.typemag.org/images/uploads/MS-Type-Mag-2017-05-Shaiman-Steve-47.jpg"></a>
				
				<figcaption>Steven Shaiman, the first program manager for type at Microsoft. He’s been on his own since 2010, living in the Pacific Northwest and working on family enterprises with his wife and five children.</figcaption>
			</figure>
			
			<section data-blockname="body_copy">
				<p><span><img src="https://www.typemag.org/images/uploads/win31-datetime.png" alt="" height="300" width="300"></span>Gates was having an informal meeting with Steve Shaiman, a cheerful gnome of a man with a head of frizzy hair who was general manager of Microsoft’s hardware division, and with Raleigh Roark one of the two people who had started the division. They were talking about fonts and applications, especially Word.</p>

<p>Roark gave Gates his answer: For printers, basically. This was the era of desktop publishing and proliferating office applications, and users needed more than just the bitmapped system fonts on their computers to get their work done. Courier, Tms Rmn, and Helv were not going to be enough. </p>

<p>Bill Gates is known for asking hard questions, but also for accepting hard answers and acting on them. As soon as he got his answer, he pointed at Steve and told him: “Now you run type!”</p>

<p>That’s the way things worked at Microsoft in those days, says Shaiman: whoever knew the most about a subject tended to end up in charge of it. So he ended up starting Microsoft’s first fonts group. It was Spring, 1989.</p>
			</section>
			

			





			
			<section data-blockname="sub_heading_1">
				<h2>The conquest of TrueType</h2>
			</section>
			
			<section data-blockname="body_copy">
				<p><span><img src="https://www.typemag.org/images/uploads/win31-phone.png" alt="" height="300" width="300"></span>STEVE SHAIMAN was on a business trip to Atlanta with Nathan Myhrvold, Microsoft’s celebrated head of advanced technology, when they got an unexpected phone call. Myhrvold had with him a satellite phone—an early mobile phone, “which in those days,” as Shaiman put it, “meant something you’d carry in a suitcase.” The unexpected call was from Apple.</p>

<p>At that time, Adobe Systems dominated the digital font market, with its PostScript technology built into Apple’s LaserWriter printers, and with PostScript firmly established as the preferred format for high-quality fonts. Microsoft needed to find its own format and its own fonts if it didn’t want to be dependent on Adobe.</p>

<p>Like Microsoft, Apple was trying to find ways to license the PostScript language from Adobe, or to find an alternative. The Apple call was about font technology: Apple was developing its own font format, TrueType, as an alternative to PostScript, while Microsoft acquired a program called TrueImage, a potential PostScript clone, which Apple was interested in. How about a trade?</p>

<p>Shaiman says that his and Nathan Myhrvold’s reaction was immediate: “Sure!”</p>

<p>Ironically, once Microsoft got hold of TrueType, they loved the concept but didn’t like the way it was implemented. Although they ended up only making slight modifications to the version that shipped with Windows 3.1, when it came time for the next version of Windows, they ended up “throwing out Apple’s code and rewriting it from scratch.”</p>

<p>When Microsoft and Apple publicly announced their collaboration on TrueType at the Seybold conference in September 1989, the announcement was handled in a contentious and aggressive manner that antagonized Adobe and famously brought Adobe’s John Warnock to tears of frustration. Steve Shaiman feels now that it was a poor way to do it: “We couldn’t have done worse.” Although they were demonstrating what they felt was better technology, they made the mistake of shoving it in Adobe’s face. “What we really needed,” he says, “was a good PR person who could have helped us come up with a less aggressive approach.” But the deed was done. The “font wars” were in full swing.</p>

<p>The key developer of Microsoft’s new code was Eliyezer Kohen, whom Myhrvold met at a conference in Switzerland. Eliyezer was, as Steve Shaiman put it, “really, really smart.” He had a PhD from ETH Zurich, where he studied with Hans Eduard Meyer, the designer of the font Syntax, and Niklaus Wirth, designer of the Pascal language; and he developed his own technology for creating scalable fonts. Eliyezer, according to Shaiman, was “a Turkish Jew with a German wife, who wanted to move to the United States, as one or the other of them wasn’t welcome in any country in Europe where they might find decent working conditions.” Microsoft happily brought him in.</p>
			</section>
			
			<figure data-blockname="single_image">
				<img data-src="https://www.typemag.org/images/uploads/MS-Type-Mag-2017-03-Hitchcock-Greg-135.jpg" alt="" src="https://www.typemag.org/images/uploads/MS-Type-Mag-2017-03-Hitchcock-Greg-135.jpg">
				<figcaption>Greg Hitchcock’s journey to Microsoft was a bit circuitous —he studied geography with a focus on computer cartography, and immersed himself in computer science.</figcaption>
			</figure>
			
			<section data-blockname="sub_heading_1">
				<h2>Even a DOS screen needs a font</h2>
			</section>
			
			<section data-blockname="body_copy">
				<p><span><img src="https://www.typemag.org/images/uploads/win31-dosscreen.png" alt="" height="300" width="300"></span>GREG HITCHCOCK was one of the early members of what he calls the “virtual team” that Shaiman and Dennis Adler put together in early 1990 to deal with fonts. Hitchcock is tall, blond, and slow-spoken; he doesn’t fit the image of the high-energy Microsoft employee, and he may seem unassertive, almost tentative, if you see him only in a neutral context. But when you see his attention snap to the subjects he knows and cares about, he is forceful and precise, and very, very knowledgeable. His memory is encyclopedic, and he has been at the heart of Microsoft’s typographic development for more than a quarter century. Today he manages Microsoft’s Advanced Reading Technologies (ART) team.</p>

<p>Although Microsoft had been dealing with fonts in one way or another from the very beginning (even a DOS screen needs a font to display its text), Hitchcock feels that the story of typography at Microsoft really begins here: When the first outline fonts were created for Windows 3.1, in 1990.</p>

<p>It was all brand-new technology. All fonts up until then had been bitmap fonts, crude forms made up of coarse screen pixels in a vague approximation of what real letters looked like. Although Microsoft’s new effort was driven by purely practical needs—mapping the screen fonts on a computer system to the fonts available on a printer—Hitchcock feels that it was also the beginning of thinking about screen fonts as something useful and readable in themselves.</p>

<p>The members of the virtual team came from all over Microsoft: Dennis Adler (Fonts), Jean-François Peyroux (OS/2, and later Windows), Michel Suignard (Windows International), Greg Hitchcock (OS/2), Eliyezer Kohen (Fonts), David Weise (Windows), Tim McCaffery (Windows), Raleigh Roark (Hardware), Gabe Newell (Printing), and later Ben Bauermeister, an outside consultant, whose “PANOSE system” for classifying typefaces by their visual characteristics (rather than their historical roots) might provide a roadmap between screen and print.</p>
			</section>
			
			<section data-blockname="sub_heading_1">
				<h2>Monotype send out S.O.S.</h2>
			</section>
			
			<section data-blockname="body_copy">
				<p><span><img src="https://www.typemag.org/images/uploads/win31-shake.png" alt="" height="300" width="300"></span>STEVE SHAIMAN hired Dennis Adler to manage the fonts groups.&nbsp; Together, they talked with several potential sources of font libraries and font technologies, including most of the big guns in the field. Linotype, the venerable manufacturer of hot-metal typesetting equipment, which owned the rights to, among others, the very popular typeface Helvetica, was being hard-nosed. “Fonts were seen as incredibly valuable at the time,” says Shaiman, “and Linotype’s attitude was, ‘What’s Microsoft going to do for us?’” So they were asking an enormous price for licensing the fonts. And Microsoft didn’t want to license the fonts; it wanted to own the rights. (When Shaiman told me this, he laughed and proclaimed: “Microsoft doesn’t rent things!”)</p>

<p>Monotype, on the other hand, was much more receptive. Monotype was Linotype’s great rival; between them, the two companies had essentially created the business of mechanical typesetting in the late 19th century, with their competing hot-metal composition machines. But the Monotype Corporation had fallen on hard times. The typography division, the only part of the company working on digital fonts, was making money, but the larger machinery business was hemorrhaging cash, and the parent company was about to declare bankruptcy.</p>

<p>Out of that debacle rose a new type-only company, Monotype Typography Ltd, which was essentially the old typography division reconstituted as an independent business.</p>

<p>The new company, with its focus on digital fonts and information technology, was headed by a German, Rene Kerfante, who had joined Monotype in 1987 to head up the typography division, and an American, Ira Mirochnik, who had been Monotype’s chief financial officer. They were both quite ready to negotiate a deal with Microsoft.</p>

<p>So it was Monotype that began developing a set of “core fonts” for Microsoft: Scalable TrueType fonts that could be shipped with Windows and used freely by every Windows customer. The new fonts had to mimic the established core set of PostScript fonts, which included Times Roman and Helvetica. Since Monotype had originally developed the Times fonts back in the hot-metal days, that part was easy. To compete with Helvetica, though, they chose to adapt an earlier Monotype design with similar characteristics, called Arial.</p>

<p>Designing the outlines for these typefaces was the kind of task that the Monotype drawing office excelled at. The hard part was the hinting, the software instructions that control the rendering on various devices. That was what would make the fonts look good on screen.</p>

<p>Monotype had a team in the UK working on font hinting, but they were running into trouble. Although they had an auto-hinting program, called TypeMan, developed by Apple’s principal TrueType developer, Sampo Kaasila, the process was proving to be long, slow, and laborious. As Greg Hitchcock describes it, Monotype in desperation Monotype “sent out the bat signal.” In response, in September 1990, he and Eliyezer made the first of many trips to the UK to provide hands-on help and supervision. This was the start of a back-and-forth pattern for Greg—three weeks in the UK, one week in Redmond—that lasted for the next nine months. Their main job was hinting type, working in little rooms in archaic buildings at the old Monotype works. …</p></section></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.typemag.org/post/the-faces-of-microsoft">https://www.typemag.org/post/the-faces-of-microsoft</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.typemag.org/post/the-faces-of-microsoft</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23755238</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 02:53:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[It's Talos all the way down]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 61 | Comments 17 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23754536">thread link</a>) | @classichasclass
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://www.talospace.com/2020/06/its-talos-all-way-down.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.talospace.com/2020/06/its-talos-all-way-down.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<div id="post-body-6179143665681918893"><p>
Still can't bear the sticker shock of your very own Talos II, or even a itty bitty Blackbird? Why not do what we all do for the machines we can't own and emulate one instead? (And then decide you like it a lot, and save your pennies?)
</p><p>
QEMU 5.0.0 offers a machine model for the bare-metal PowerNV profile, to which the Raptor systems and other OpenPOWER POWER8 and POWER9 designs intended for Linux (i.e., not PowerVM machines) belong. Using the Talos II firmware image (mostly: one snag to be mentioned), you can boot the machine in QEMU and from there bring up an operating system in emulation. In this article we'll prove it works by bringing up <a href="https://voidlinux-ppc.org/">Void Linux for Power</a> (hi, Daniel!) in a variety of configurations. A set-up like this might be enough to test that your software or open-source package builds and runs on OpenPOWER, even if you don't own one yet. In a future article we'll talk about how you can boot your own code on the metal so you can port your favourite OS or build a unikernel.
</p><p>
(For the purposes of this article I'll assume an audience that isn't as familiar with OpenPOWER terminology as our usual readership. Kindly humour me.)
</p><p>
The emulation is imperfect, both if you're emulating it on a real Raptor family system or on an icky PC. While QEMU can emulate an AST2500 (i.e., the ARM-based Baseboard Management Controller, which acts as the service processor and provides the video framebuffer), and QEMU can also emulate a PowerNV system, it doesn't do both at the same time. That means the very lowest levels are actually being simulated here -- you can't watch Raptor's pretty Hostboot display, for example, and only the barest functions of the BMC are simulated enough to allow bring-up, not including the framebuffer. In fact, the hardware profiles we will use here do not in general match a real Raptor system either: we're just virtually plugging in PCI devices that give us necessary functionality, though of course none of the peripheral devices in a Raptor system is Raptor-proprietary. Finally, even though I have tagged this entry with KVM, KVM currently doesn't work right with the QEMU PowerNV machine model even though I'm pretty sure it should be technically possible. Sadly, I tried in vain to do so, could never get KVM-HV to be happy, and ended up kernel panicking the machine with KVM-PR. <a href="https://gist.github.com/classilla/0b95d7bea3e9a270385a2360fbcf7f40">See if you can triumph where I have failed</a>. In the meantime, naturally you can do everything here on a T2 or Blackbird as well because that's how I did it writing this article, but there is no special acceleration for those systems right now.
</p><p>
The first order of business is the first order of business with any emulator: get the ROMs. Fortunately, no one is going to bust you for pirating a set of these because we're an open platform, remember?
</p><p>
The two pieces required are Skiboot and Petitboot, both of which live in the system's PNOR flash. <a href="https://github.com/open-power/skiboot">Skiboot</a> contains OPAL, the OpenPOWER Abstraction Layer. It comes in after the BMC has turned on main power and started the Power CPUs' self-boot engines, which then IPL ("initial program load") Hostboot for the second-stage power-on sequence. When Hostboot completes, it chains into Skiboot, which initializes the PCIe host bus controllers (PHBs) and provides all the basic hardware calls needed by a guest kernel to support the platform. You can think of it as something like an overgrown BIOS. This is the lowest firmware level of an OpenPOWER system that QEMU currently supports emulating.
</p><p>
Skiboot lives only to service a kernel, so it immediately starts one. This initial payload is the bootloader for <a href="https://github.com/open-power/petitboot">Petitboot</a>, which is also stored in firmware. Petitboot has a small Linux root (Skiroot) and acts as a boot menu, finding bootable volumes on attached devices or over the network. Having found one (or you select one), it chains into it to start the main OS, and from then on Skiboot will provide platform services via OPAL for this final guest until the system is shut down or restarted. Because it's in firmware, Petitboot is always available, which can come in really handy when you're trying to do system recovery.
</p><p>
The first, best and most dedicated way is to <a href="https://github.com/open-power/op-build">build Skiboot and Petitboot yourself</a>. They are open-source and the process is relatively well documented and automated, and you should know how to do this if you own an OpenPOWER machine anyhow. If you aren't doing this on a real OpenPOWER machine you'll need a cross-compiler, but most Linux distros offer such a package nowadays. Do keep in mind that if it looks like you're building a tiny Linux distro, well, that's because that's exactly what you're doing. The advantage here is you can fool around with the firmware at your leisure, but it requires a bit of an investment in disk space and time.
</p><p>
The second way assumes you have a more casual interest and would prefer to go with something prefab. It's possible if you (or, you know, your "friend") has a Raptor-family system to extract the necessary components right from the BMC prompt. Log into the BMC over SSH (or via <a href="https://www.talospace.com/2020/04/what-to-do-when-bmc-wont-talk-to-you.html">direct serial connection</a>) and type <tt>pflash -i</tt>. You'll see a list of all the partitions stored in the PNOR flash. The ones we want are <tt>PAYLOAD</tt> (which contains Skiboot) and <tt>BOOTKERNEL</tt> (which contains Skiroot and Petitboot). The exact addresses may vary from system to system and firmware to firmware.
</p><p>
<tt>root@bmc:~# pflash -P PAYLOAD -r /tmp/pnor.PAYLOAD --skip=4096<br>
Reading to "/tmp/pnor.PAYLOAD" from 0x021a1000..0x022a1000 !<br>
[==================================================] 100%<br>
root@bmc:~# pflash -P BOOTKERNEL -r /tmp/pnor.BOOTKERNEL --skip=4096<br>
Reading to "/tmp/pnor.BOOTKERNEL" from 0x022a1000..0x03821000 !<br>
[==================================================] 100%
</tt></p><p>
We skip the first 4K page to avoid the wrapping around each partition. <tt>pnor.PAYLOAD</tt> is actually compressed and needs to be uncompressed prior to use, so:
</p><p>
<tt>root@bmc:~# cd /tmp<br>
root@bmc:/tmp# xz -d &lt; pnor.PAYLOAD &gt; skiboot.lid</tt>
</p><p>
Finally, <tt>scp</tt> both <tt>skiboot.lid</tt> and <tt>pnor.BOOTKERNEL</tt> to your desired system from the BMC.
</p><p>
Admittedly we just talked at length about the two ways most of you <em>won't</em> get the firmware, so let's talk about the third method and the way most of you will, i.e., you'll just download it. Currently there is an irregularity about Raptor's present Skiboot build for this purpose: it only boots if you are emulating a single <em>POWER8</em>. That's not a typo. If you use it to boot an emulated POWER9, the guest will simply panic, and the guest will go into a bootloop if you are emulating multiple POWER8 CPUs (necessary if you need a larger number of PCIe devices). This is undoubtedly a QEMU deficiency which will be corrected in future releases. In the meantime, if you just care about playing around using a single POWER8 on a terminal, then Raptor's builds (either from BMC flash or downloaded) will suffice. However, if you intend to emulate a POWER9 or SMP POWER8 system, <a href="https://github.com/qemu/qemu/blob/master/pc-bios/skiboot.lid">download QEMU's own pre-built <tt>skiboot.lid</tt></a> and use that instead.
</p><p>
For Petitboot, we will extract that directly from Raptor's PNOR images. Assuming you didn't get it using the process above, <a href="https://wiki.raptorcs.com/wiki/Talos_II/Firmware">download the current Talos II PNOR image</a> and decompress it. In the <tt>shell_upgrade</tt> directory you will see the <tt>bzip2</tt>-compressed PNOR image. Uncompress that, leaving you with a filename like <tt>talos-ii-v2.00.pnor</tt>. <a href="https://gist.github.com/classilla/4a2c907d0acec5b537cd4992a00801c3">Download my <tt>pnorex</tt> extractor tool</a> (it's in Perl, because I'm one of <em>those</em> people) and run it on the PNOR image:
</p><p>
<tt>% pnorex talos-ii-v2.00.pnor<br>
Version 1 PNOR archive with 33 entries.<br>
Extracting PAYLOAD at offset 8601.<br>
This is a xz format image.<br>
Wrote 1020K successfully.<br>
Extracting BOOTKERNEL at offset 8857.<br>
This is an ELF executable image.<br>
Wrote 22012K successfully.<br>
Extracted 2 partitions successfully.
</tt>
</p><p>
If you will be using Raptor's Skiroot, then uncompress <tt>pnor.PAYLOAD</tt> to <tt>skiroot.lid</tt> as above: <tt>xz -d &lt; pnor.PAYLOAD &gt; skiboot.lid</tt>
</p><p>
Now, with <tt>skiroot.lid</tt> (for this first example, either Raptor's or QEMU's) and <tt>pnor.BOOTKERNEL</tt> in the same folder, grab an ISO you want to boot. I used the prefab one Daniel offers on the <a href="https://voidlinux-ppc.org/">Void Linux for Power site</a> since I know it boots fine on OpenPOWER hardware. For our first example let's do a simple example of booting Void from a CD image on a POWER8 using the serial port. Our QEMU command line:
</p><p>
<tt>
qemu-system-ppc64 -M powernv8 -m 4G -cpu power8 \<br>
        -nographic \<br>
        -bios ./skiboot.lid \<br>
        -kernel ./pnor.BOOTKERNEL \<br>
        -device ich9-ahci,id=ahci0 \<br>
        -drive id=cd0,media=cdrom,file=void-live-ppc64le-musl-20200411.iso,if=none \<br>
        -device ide-cd,bus=ahci0.0,drive=cd0
</tt>
</p><p>
This configures a single-processor POWER8 system with 4GB of RAM, no graphics, and an Intel AHCI host controller with a single CD-ROM drive attached. The serial output should go to your terminal. It goes a little like this:
</p><p><a href="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-3VII_RkIwcE/XvFb7tRycOI/AAAAAAAABs0/yyvLDu_1liEFaU2wpoZWtrf-au1P1YiDACLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/Screenshot%2Bfrom%2B2020-06-22%2B16-44-48.png" imageanchor="1"><img data-original-height="645" data-original-width="578" height="320" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-3VII_RkIwcE/XvFb7tRycOI/AAAAAAAABs0/yyvLDu_1liEFaU2wpoZWtrf-au1P1YiDACLcBGAsYHQ/s320/Screenshot%2Bfrom%2B2020-06-22%2B16-44-48.png" width="287"></a></p>
<p>
Here we are with Skiboot chaining into Petitboot. You can ignore the errors; there will be a lot of them since the platform is still incomplete. It will take a little bit of time to decompress the kernel (much slower than it would be on a regular system). You will notice a single device attached to the three available PCIe host bridges on the single POWER8 CPU, i.e., the host controller itself. Don't you just love that the vendor code for Intel is <tt>8086</tt>?
</p><p><a href="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-3IKOOE6kD80/XvFb7uxi8sI/AAAAAAAABss/yKU2WHvBCbgDmXPvyFdSvsCu7yLHnnGuACLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/Screenshot%2Bfrom%2B2020-06-22%2B16-45-08.png" imageanchor="1"><img data-original-height="645" data-original-width="578" height="320" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-3IKOOE6kD80/XvFb7uxi8sI/AAAAAAAABss/yKU2WHvBCbgDmXPvyFdSvsCu7yLHnnGuACLcBGAsYHQ/s320/Screenshot%2Bfrom%2B2020-06-22%2B16-45-08.png" width="287"></a></p>
<p>
This is Petitboot. When the bootable choices appear, cursor up to the starred option and press E before it autoboots, because we need to tell Void its console is the on-board serial port (otherwise it uses a VGA console: not sure whose bug that is).
</p><p><a href="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/--dDE00hPAsk/XvFb7k5ug4I/AAAAAAAABsw/KD1kofJkAdIusk9rtl8WyjlknApxQRouQCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/Screenshot%2Bfrom%2B2020-06-22%2B16-45-43.png" imageanchor="1"><img data-original-height="645" data-original-width="578" height="320" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/--dDE00hPAsk/XvFb7k5ug4I/AAAAAAAABsw/KD1kofJkAdIusk9rtl8WyjlknApxQRouQCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/Screenshot%2Bfrom%2B2020-06-22%2B16-45-43.png" width="287"></a></p>
<p>
Add <tt>console=hvc0</tt> at the end, cursor down to <tt>OK</tt> and hit RETURN/ENTER a couple times to boot.
</p><p><a href="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-h6UHepGrXLo/XvFb8GHW5jI/AAAAAAAABs4/STBtGNaljU4-3EvsmhlstoBbIpU0aLaKgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/Screenshot%2Bfrom%2B2020-06-22%2B16-47-38.png" imageanchor="1"><img data-original-height="645" data-original-width="578" height="320" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-h6UHepGrXLo/XvFb8GHW5jI/AAAAAAAABs4/STBtGNaljU4-3EvsmhlstoBbIpU0aLaKgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/Screenshot%2Bfrom%2B2020-06-22%2B16-47-38.png" width="287"></a></p>
<p>
A successful login on your emulated baby POWER8. Ta-daa! To rudely pull the plug on the QEMU session, press Ctrl-A, and then X (<tt>QEMU: Terminated</tt>).
</p><p>
Let's now load out the POWER8. We would like to add a video card, an Ethernet card and a USB controller to our existing system, but POWER8 Turismo chips only offer enough PHBs for three PCI endpoints. How do we solve this problem? Easy: we'll add another processor!
</p><p>
At this point …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.talospace.com/2020/06/its-talos-all-way-down.html">https://www.talospace.com/2020/06/its-talos-all-way-down.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.talospace.com/2020/06/its-talos-all-way-down.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23754536</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 01:03:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
